along some fellow everybody and welcome
to our
presentation called burning house car
edson introducing introduction into the
two won't be called a low-key
on november research team
bridge produced america
on showing you today
al-mal saw
the guy called an array
all my colleague on him and then and
myself whipsawed kalter right off
alone
subhuman park
noticed that my name was not on the
agenda but it was there any other manoff
unfortunately i don't have the into the
area to some ah...
family reasons so
uh... and then you have uh... then
you're liable talking to talk today
signed up yet thanks for showing up well
and i hope you enjoy the next yr
of good art
wherein along rio psalm metre p_x_
security researchers working for
our company called urine w dead space in
germany
uh...
the company's mainly during penetration
testing security researching security
analyzing
developing concepts like that
and sorrow
there is a treadmill fiddling around
with nobody was so so i'm trying to do
some nasty stuff done
devise a system
protocols and that's
pretty much making the majority of
holidays and ur
so
the convoy hanlon one was larger
companies based in germany heidelberg
for some of you may know that
i want to
well-intended too much about that
uh...
it's slow one hundred sar main
understanding is that being said call
appropriate
they fear of google
mitigated controls saw
home
telling companies want to do real
licensing about their business attitudes
uh... soderberg
out of the also ever been all along
maybe also some of you know this already
it's called insinuated on that
and elsewhere for
but compared with the black eyed by the
room small conference which is also also
germany the source you
uh... i also saw them
zope
they're going to put a dent uh...
why don't you want to start your can you
do a visual cues
and why does the world need
another tool
doing nasty sings in an advert
uh... next find would be the tool itself
uh... for that that then you will
tell you some
architect just all forms of how it was
coded because he wants the main code
after two
so you can
tell you they control staffer
and the last part of that they're not
highest some aggressive facts which are
also implemented these are the school
but uh... you'll see it
but what they see here
arm
alpha
most guys if you should recognize this
screenshot
it's pretty much on your last chart
last time so i need to really
manure and company and that hurts our
customer care networks
undi fire up a sniffer it's also the
kind that by paul bc stuff like that
so it's nothing special
vodka one special we see here is a
little arbonne infrastructure talking
proper cults
on the talk
pretty messy this lots of graduates solo
rogers talking infrastructure
infrastructure protocols in the wrong
networks
so most guys no reason for example to
talk
was gash in the kind that bird but uh...
you still see this stuff
aural this was that's very often and
some
our scenario
this kind of like that
if it ever reported by the security
assessment i would tell our custom into
kenya
got some problems if you're in some sort
of protocol seconded easily been settled
our
security concerns about that turns out
this can cause serious haunted network
form this and soft
to customers telling us a case just
erratically
soviet ek
uh... some you know your realtor
all traffic in the matter
and then it's that's where the problem
comes up because they're pretty much
though not that much tools
you can use to show them the stuff
so
most likely it is security incidents
dimensions our customers
their rules
going to be kurds in any way that just
ignore it because it's trust theoretical
stuff
that was so idea reacted tools always
thought about okay
softer techs are nothing new with their
own widely known that those somewhat
uncomfortable protocols can be attacked
very easily
but i will be will try to do is soooo
close the gap between between a tear
ethical
attacks and uh... provide the preppy
practical tools for that so you can
perform these attacks in the news ebay
so you can show this to customers okay
here's the problem model one two three
mosque legs or arms or some commands
and i'm not
i can redirect traffic project some
awesome rogers one hour
so that's the reason why we part
providing new tool for that attacked
to close the gap between the theoretical
attacks
many basic research attacks aren't a
practical stuff make them
and respect us this is a tax we're not
just a radical if you can show them
today i'm so in one or two minutes can
perform an attack you'll just expendable
grade that's your problem
most likely james to staff
there are some tools at the same in the
pasta one very popular too
la many from a few
i'm sure some of whom notice will go to
cocaine a novel
and the pretty much change today
poem
people look at some special effects
because so since the release of
that kind of towards that x
can easily be performed everybody
you don't even have to know a pic
breaks in the background because it just
test so and to some information press a
button and then
that they caused by the don't ask even
to understand what's going on
on in the background
so relief that this works
changed lot of things fall
of people or custom marsala people are
looking on
are
on one of images if they'll practicality
doable if they're very
well it's just too radical stuff
somebody's telling your canada is a
problem but
just not to listen away no easy way to
exploit these were abilities
travel there so there are two incomes in
two places home
because of the loki
and i will tell you some
saying about this will not
so chest to complete his assigned us a
small home a few of
tools are only exist in the wild
that can do similar things but most of
them
huh
already complicated to use and as such
we called you a process for the old
already
um... which can
and the sun routing protocols also about
mostly only in discovery mode so
it shows is some information on what
throttle protocol implemented and i've
met burt
for the crimes act if she's quite
something
and i don't really great tool this study
is in young it's mainly
uh... ridgeway led to expats on i'm sure
at least some of you alls modus tools
that's also one of the tools that pretty
much the
changed lots of saying so close the gap
between juridical attacks and uh...
practical effects
because made use of the fire about
before the mowing deep details are
writing complicated scripts whatever
uh... some other told songs like
educating nemesis escapee
they don't know if you noticed was fired
may want to answer where youth scape
into pretty much all for cool you can
use a lot of raja protocols also with
that thought
it doesn't hurt him in any state machine
so it is still have to write
complicated scripts
all maternal specialized attacks
an f_ immersed jeff in
good afternoon miss much time to make
them
some integrity
you can do it with that but it's pretty
complicated you have to write scripts
and all that stuff
but it's not easy to use
uh... better tower belonging
legislation provides only provides some
on
and we are
also you can easily use it you don't
have to use our common in the face at
all
the initial idea you might know he was
subsequent by and some of our own
written
kamon trend towards
mature already released in the past for
example
of one woman two years ago then you and
then released a
who had to talk about their kid has to
be gpc puritan also raised some audience
look month rent will spot
still not just say they're not u_s_
pretty much because may be too
complicated to use them
it's not easy to trust so
revenues fell over
clicked some buttons and perform a text
so the initial idea was to just combine
these tools in them
and then
let's call it the infrastructure proper
contexts weeds uh... home
combined is seven easy glued to was
small band makes who's more usable so
the people also use it because uh...
driving school nobody also want the
people to use the tool
miles with your spent lots of time
collectibles
in the meantime it's not just a
collection of other tools
implemented again in the street
edsel
lots of a lot of more in the meantime
could soar as a model architect to
daniel does something about the modern
architecture major
so you can easily implemented new
attacks that you're out and protocols
uh... are able to use
some low-key modules mission on the
modules
for example
use some ninety-five trek module to are
correct your invoice bear fronting for
the court indication passed on to
something like that
so we can combine different modules on
that stuff
there's also a lot of protocols
implemented already they are already
working really find will see that some
slides later
for because they are
nearly every part of collison
infrastructure comical on some of them
hard
alexei laying there on market was
extended warranty but we still estimate
that more deals because starr
the other motives depend on that
so you don't have to fire up a
command-line and love spoofing the
background before you can actually
perform another check
so the ones edsel low-keyed tour
be able to
perform the whole attack of itself don't
need any other tools and mark
at least for that kind of attack
uh... lagi also includes a new russian
office will call them p last when it was
also really is better
lekha talk in the past coloring appear
less uh... security
misunderstanding to different that's not
that's the only problem of implemented
this uh...
as module if they're not true
on
poses a special reason though that i
will tell you about that later but if
you install the low-key you also have
four
this requirement is so awesome
part of a democrat
dom
so first of all hello
home
so i would be a first shot all of you
and introduction into though main
program
so personal level effect the
architecture than i will tell something
about all the modules that are there and
off the wall to have a look and uh...
and gory and the house it's know how
it's
okay so first the architecture alum
loki
mainly those main program which which is
called low-key at government may re-open
module a p_i_ so every module
just meets don't need to deal with any
networking stopped on the to deal with
farm lot of graphical stuff is all
handled by domain program
it just focus on your protocol you want
to implement
so
first i have made some library
extensions to mo
for example gets i could to boost
firewall in working with
with the united bottom get away from
this again because i am notice tickets
not possible to rolled all patches to
some him
system libraries
or in the meantime you don't need any
library extensions and more just need
until ivory dependencies and the main
program
okay so they rock a lot of hockey
protocols already implemented
uh...
nancy the whole bunch of lists and let's
begin with bach akhioc isn't
anything you
there are more a bunch of tools cleanup
spoofing bypass renny mentioned on
implemented it as well just to give
uh... the sweet and which would fit and
perform the whole attack from the salt
to the beginning beginning
and if you need to be in some kind of
man the mill position too
performed some attack on the rotting
further called you can use of this well
so i mean there are two modules the the
edgy api and the w house if you want
which are not released yet because there
are some
legal issues with from cisco on that
proper calls
because of the idea p and w c_p_r_ pple
cisco proprietary on don't get ccp there
is also a page and application from
cisco so we don't get into any legal
trouble the swine we won't release that
modules now
meant
orchid com i'll give you shot all of you
of all the attacks norwich nokia is able
to do so first terrace diablo guild as
you can alan they'd offered can drop
spoofing the can-do op standing and are
implemented also
an offline mechanism
has sold there is some
module for p if the which is a brand-new
protocol the r_c_ just showed up
uh... begin offering june
uh... which is
someone
and from a call for doing that aren't
hot standby arun failover mechanism
renny will tell you something more about
that for holy crap
uh... ok are also implementa the
bcp impart of mile tool the beach pcl
iight david's crack graphical user
interface
so you can do
and ella rejection with a truly can
inject routing information into
and pgp domain
there is also module four
the aged piano which has a set will not
be released now
made in the future not quite sure yet
bottom without madhu you can
also inject ah... near g_o_p_
kaplan's values which are in fact
routing information and i also
implemented stew
older attacks against their g_o_p_ which
are at the enough indicate the parent on
authenticated denial of service
and then there are two more guilty for a
just sake and
matches up you're going to
which is on
just hot sent by protocol forearm
quietly address us bound with uh...
looking tools week europe able to take
over one of the psychiatrists
so i'll name
there is another module for the leap you
bussell called lady distribution
protocol which is used with
in big until aspect on that works
you can hook into the l_d_p_ at
process and can inject
label napping messages
also able to
attacks some hollow
layer two or one p elapsed time
goldstein
and establish your own time uh...
and all the time to stop that they'll
l_d_p_'s able to
from
if you want to go deeper into all the
l_d_p_ nicholas stop i recommend you
to take a look at all last year black
had talked
exactly that from
that
dot topic which covers l_d_p_ pgp and
p_m_s_
so there is an anti last month in a
swell which can
rewrite the uh... makiel s labels which
also can't discover different and p_l_o_
s
traffic possible
and uh...
jerry there's also like the rain is that
the uh... activists on program
which gives you
partner of machine
some kind of again as you can enable
networks
so you just pop up and
virtual tunnel interface
more and more traffic that do put into
the tunnel interfaces will be
u_s_ labeled and thrown onto the network
okay that resembles p_f_ module
refusals p_f_ module you can't hook up
into an arose p_f_ rotting process you
can inject post p_f_ routing information
and uh... also implemented and i was
given the five authentication tracker
so even if you're roberto you will see
you later
we will have denies them on this one
uh...
are older and report your
this will small like
some kind of ocm
typing lesson on the part where it was a
real easy protocol
you can do right interact with diverse
world you don't have to do any handshake
though so just thrown rocks on the cable
param
that we would get into the rafting trip
but if there is a tis the indy five
madhu with which you can correct the
piracy com twenty three found
pigeon forge
to c_p_r_ vindication option
so which is mainly used by the gpm belly
p
for authentication pair for
authenticating the neighbors
so i'm going to see one of these
packages you can also do
i work with some fruit for striking on
the passport
there are fremont yields which is the
the rpm european b_-three
which are also for our kids wrestled
standby and fast handover
so you can't just take it over one of
these
hot standby i_q_ dresses as well
and there is the w_s_o_c_ ki
on module which most
the main part of our last like a talk
then
europe this year
uh... which is that
wireless lan context control protocol
which is also arm
the cisco proprietary protocol for a
building opp
wide distribution system alan
we take log
work into hannah's is this protocol and
do some tripped analysis on the
authentication mechanism hand
and
it came all the it's all based on lead
authentication and as we all should know
elite isn't really secure
so
the and if you still small doable
you will get the
palace masak he off
wireless clients
bomb
mo he also has the graphical user
interface
it's faced auckalnd jija kate
i'm using party to kate
because it's a really easy into two
program and parkland
i don't like should you can see into
place it's a pain in the ass
wrong
student program
passed some popular vote
jiji kidhu tu k of window routines which
are
and the main window there is a
configuration we know there's a lot
window and stuff like that
but the modules themself
uh... i decided to use late for the task
because with late you can use the
designer in the face and click a button
here iclicker
some input line they ran off the water
will get a nice xml file and that will
be
possum runtime
but that means also that you can change
yumaed you would do it on the run time
patent
yeah let's say under on time off the
main program you always have to agree
loads
the whole module to get the new perfetti
isn't the place but its really easy to
and wolf all new modules as they can be
real ordered on runtime
and so it's really easy to
fix sandbox or do some testing arms
prudence in your coat
must streams of low-key but you will see
it in on the
action intersect
apollo handlebar to ready again
for aside then you know that as you can
see there are lots of part except amend
it already in different modules
along with some of them to come in today
that the
listed what color because there are
already colin and i will talk scientists
up just in to credit
clever more usable to
we told you lots of riff that model if
that were on the left at what about the
uh...
okay what can we do what kind of but
extended to moved further thought who
also wants
for some reason why soups and warm the
technological call a benefit that
dresser someone cannot afford
attacking raj protocol
so to give you an idea about that let's
do not official discussion of some after
some of that excite implemented in
located
uh...
that's s
just a possible to call them
and circumstantial
so arm i don't know how deep are you are
in school network protocols project
protocols so whatever
solo
i will give you a solo if you about that
roger prodding particles in general
i'll use between never brought us to
exchange information about the connected
met her it's about
how they can reach other net birds
of father magnets are way for example if
it's a conduction forum for another
ought to use this one too
reach on that
so brought improbable as do this dynamic
early so they can ek baar baar link
facial if an interface based on a lot
lines broken contests which over to
another one so the network still
reachable
two kinds of fraud saying that you can
use this monitor if you can use steady
growth by the large networks of several
hundred several sultans of notes of
progress of metrics
the kind you assist eddy crawled so it
would be
really pains that you know if you need
some protocol are handling urology
information that that information
that's suffering
unfortunately the internet with not the
american refund russian articles
so their defense flavors of rotting
protocols for style the interrogated
project proposal interrogated protocols
also decided pm
they're mainly used in zags
so-called onto mama systems
on so you would find protocols like this
inside a corporate network for example
mountain
any
scada frederick and usa
this whether it's one of the most famous
of these kinds of protocol sealaska
module
if u
go to a website ten different uh... big
mavericks who find that at least five
six seven times
using those pictures emotional
tropical so insides
corporate networks inside
those metrics
we don't communicate this interrogated
protocols
mcfarlane adverts therefore
the father the mains with the internet
at work
the other kind offer rotting from a
colleague senator david protocol slum
jessup mainly want to take a protocol
it's called pgp
the internet users uses
use it to exchange so
information about the connecting that
hurts so they can be reached really okay
that's all talk with senator serologist
texas forming fails
well that's the wrong you will find that
the internet
ventana dropping stuff is handled by the
cheeky
and some really loves corporate networks
you can also find be cheap eats some
guys uh...
implement this also lol using this kind
of interrogated protocol in his speech
against at the corporate network
for the rotting protocols doubt
different grades to the to the american
general
totally different catcher worries
uh... concepts behind his lodging
protocols
watch all of us who are listed this
inspector
rotting protocol a distance vector
protocols category
uh... chronicles like grip bitches
used anymore
al-mal
really really rarely used
and it's an on-site g_o_p_
uh... protocol to this inspector
protocols sewer
many exchange information has been a
barrage of so-called holiday
arrangements mattress overall trade
maybe tell us what would be i can reach
them at night
for nineteen what one one too
ones exei tussier o well white-out three
austria this matter also sits three
blocks away from me
uh... so if you don't have to buy the
pastor last night's bette midler justice
mister archer level
managed to get the traffic dept
as a deadly apec itself
uh...
services
yeah pretty much distance vector
red snapper it can be reached
with that's just what this is how far is
the debate
uh... the other one stealing state
protocols of software stayed in newborns
by going to get five scientists
on the don't exchange information
bombard
all the networks they know
they just
exchange information about the dialect
directly connected networks
not reached using another auto
so the total immigrant
all at once we links
on
therapies remembers and this is all my
neighbors
so often initialization of links that
protocol harry
parts of a new simplified butlers
expanded on a smaller direct
every participating ross perot knows to
complete medved a lot
they don't relay a on distance
information but they know
uh... by their own if the slings broker
i can reach that never grow up
the other way also
won't start come with a different kind
of fraud and protocol
but exchange lake state information
former neighbors
what my purse i have gone back to
connect the total
and distance vector protocols exchanged
informational which never do annoying
although original for is at the rate
different kind of information of six
changed
uh... september surpass ekta protocol
that's used by the gpm
all my dog collar to see here in detail
because of the talked of color of each
of you today
so it's not necessary but it's a little
bit similar to that this inspector
critical
well tested on exchange information
about metrics but the information about
alton on assistance with
many networks
so that i have a kind of fraud and
protocols and the purpose of fraud and
protocols in general
by severe doable
technological because of what has
already begun
alone
on the top in attacking a secure your
product protocols
that pain
uh... talk at therefore in two thousand
eight so by a cappella bimodal
are more support the black it was always
my mental told me just mention it was a
father who has to be to create a
arm
the ross perot some that's a incidents
on when something bad happened so
routing protocol
but said a youtube pakistan incidents a
some of you know
remember that parks and tried to
like you to buy
absurd to sing
though you'd you'd never inside the run
armband edit some heroin was introduced
in the colin some that uh... nobody
could reach into many more
on and are also some other incidents
than something get wrong referral to
public almost like they are human errors
what's happened there
almost a does not too much discussing
about your brother protocol security in
general
there are some
there are some morrissey all it's called
generic trips of portraits of fraud and
protocols
which color so can't book and but that
can happen but that's a second happened
project protocols
on this and i'd carefully craft almost
perfect original ability on one of those
there are small so presentation balter
the support of proof of concepts on
attacking always get metrics also
injecting roland was
possess more proof of concept program
which uh... was hard to use and realty
expressed chesterton some special
scenarios
and there's also i'm mighty if american
troops there was some magic
i_d_f_ lurking group up
my handling rotting protocol security
but they're concluded a miracle
i think it was uh... last year beginning
last year
that's pretty much so the things that's
already happened about against logic
protocols
so what's all it's a look at the
definition i've worn off though one part
of this error seether covering genetic
substructure protocols
i could not just three darn but
well everybody kind neighboring salford
at and sop in total
attacks
pads
kind of a dagger server traffic
redirection
but in the larger scale a typical
low-fat website
for example amount spoofing attack greer
x traffic between two opposed to maybe
between the sop meta-analysis
of if you take rotting protocols who can
redirect all networks
and not only a traffic for singer
analysts and minedu necessary massive
fraud protocols of course you can uh...
performed an out of service attacks so
if you
'em
manipulate the rotting information
so it can't hurt anymore
and so that's the kind of denial of
service and uh...
dot what he can do is routing protocols
asin jacket
incorrect brawls
soul which will happen then the traffic
being directed to the wrong raucous not
so they're all just a should go to so
maybe could be a laptop
and you forwarded to a
the real world and so you can now
eavesdropped attracted to men in the
middle of tech actively
all that stuff that needs so traffic
redirection issah
answer
blow that up mainly the bad things that
can happen dressing reaction
the throw eavesdropping or men in the
middle attacks
and analysis attacks
level
well let's go to the first tropical and
the first sar demonstration the
afternoon
arm
always bad stands for ropes or the
spouse first class are the toilet itself
one of the most widely used to them
sprouting from a cold since its
corporate address
it also belongs to the uh... cut here
filling said protocols of already told
you this this also
if there are taking injections on what
we will try to do is inject
a redirect are all cheeky
the beckett's for that for a metric
should end up with a special rogers
redirect to go up
a laptop so we are able to
use of the traffic problem in the middle
of tax stuff like that
businessman turned actually analyst p_f_
mentored upon
due to the into your sketchy right now
but
alm if you have fun bose p_f_ management
verdicts
medford the different matter it's not
only in zaidi less care frederick can
have different types so and there are
some types of metrics for example the
socal totally stop in that spirit
bitches metric which only can have one
roger so all systems on this matter
again
only half of the photographs
this is a possible boom
to inject ah... other also those petro
but won't accept this in general but
that's fine if i am so you contact us
proforma takes
within such than that
but nearly every other type of my broker
lugar
they also some
protection mechanisms servitude prevents
though
false ross will be detected one to serve
the so-called those p_f_ aipac mechanism
this many years so if you sir
deferments air
are for most definitely grotto called
roger i a m
they perceive some some routing
information telling the raw today
i can reach disavowed not dark but this
road closed slow
responsible himself followed that
virtually no say there's something wrong
uh... so he will reject the wrong time
self and prevent the redirection
um but thats
in most cases that that's not really
protect against up false large objects
so it's mainly against miss configured
rajasthan are
uh... added to that
that's the part of the first day we will
take place we have some network setup
it's pretty simple it's up to rogers
connected with one advert in the middle
of a out that says that that bomb at
bird
and if an attacker this laptop sitting
in the middle
and so
fiddling around logical to call to
redirect traffic but uh... daniel telusu
details about the pictures
arquette arm
what you see here now is the
kamon final one of the two routers
hissing the front here
and what it will
do first this show you
revered rotting table
which looks like that
okay we we got some rocks into the
one or ninety two one-armed sixty-eight
nap weed out some
involved one or it's a new to dot
sixteen routes
but don't mention all the different
routes that
dung
important thing is that too
don't see any let's say around ten dash
zero network
so if there were default drawl it all
he traffic going to the still in that
book will fall over at the photo
orchid sold there is no route into
trendnet
i think we should change this because
along to be
the tendency or network myself
so what it'll do this
just lunch up
bulky
which is this nice too
so and novel will
just selected interface a listen to
prepare different animals on the same
setup so you will see some
uh... beyond politics here and i kept
different elected rep so so far for that
the mall i need
mind real you get zero interface and
when i click on ok of those who will
just start listening for packages on
that interface
so i just see that there are some off
these taps blinking so
it also disputed
discover some routing protocols
which in this case this
os p_f_
because this deals gap thi mot obvious
archit hum so we get to
hall speaking i was p_f_ in that work
okay let's just hooked up to them
i won't just change people indication to
mail on this there are
using non-profit vacation
after what's called
starts participating into the
post p_f_ process
i'm just starting to send out hello
packages
and when one of these rather see it
might help a packages coming in
they will perform deals deft hand shake
with
and once i'm in the state full
i got albeit routing information from
the proper still about y all
a list yet
so you see that out all the routes those
two uh... relatives exchange
between each other
their own some different kind offer
brought status
uh... renny mentioned there are some
stop networks there are trying to
networks are upon two point links but
there is no totally stop network so
it looks like we are and quite a good
position to perform and
injection attack
what to do next this just
go through the injection tap and
chapin asset
i wanted to show up
the ten network
let's say it's uh...
square sixteen
and its own rock link so it's directly
connected to my
morality or
i'm not really a router but i a m
telling all the uh... most fear from
target by coming into the network
ones that these dropped
the ming said update gat
thrown alter the oscar protest
hands-on
batman
in a second or two you will see right
there is
meyer are showing up
sold the relatives just
uh...
repeating that information to me saying
okay i understand you know there is a
route into the temple square sixteen at
work
when we laid-back and to the their
office
command-line who first you will mention
there is
okay some new post p_f_ neighbor showing
up
which means i successfully perform piano
locals p_f_ handshake i'm not part of
the os p_f_ network
and if we take a look at the
vaulting table off the waltz
you will see there is a neural tube
showing up
forgot tents for sixteen network
which points to my local
so every packet
which should be relevant to the ten
square sixteen network is now redirected
to my notebook
and i can't do with that
traffic whatever law
eichenbaum sniff it they can perform an
animal attack second just
redirected to some other routes open
arm too
keep the traffic in-flow to look at the
traffic to its final destination
the important point is i would get all
the traffic
the first part
reading it will not continue with
next part of
says israeli cabinet has to check the
baron urologic garages in the south
africa
anticipating rogers uh...
rich if you do it in both directions
madrid is a neurotic dust into the
brothel rental
overall gpa anat bird
originally based behind that brought her
into the other direction so every
traffic between these two networks to
the redirected over
taking system in this case outside
notebook
so you can do with the traffic but
everyone
log racing is some sensing almost an
on-site she appeared protocol
top priority targets of this inspector
protocol
altered so still used in some locations
so
according to his chin so much sexist
assault so companies so realistic into
cisco by mister to several steps
irecruitment there so that
uh... that's a good chance they're using
an on-site g_o_p_ as a routing protocol
while you can do that only if there is
no need for
install parade signify the manufacturers
so costs are the men effect rooms one
speak
and i thank you
c_f_o_ mixed in moment you can just a
political by then plans is goin moments
you of those finds missus feinstein has
such a kit that you can critical
they are also some security discussions
back in two thousand five about the
security in hindsight chippy matched
metrics by a person standing mylist i
don't notice anything more happening on
the topping there was no
the tools being able to attacked the
perform these attacks which are
discussed at
arms so
that's also another reason why we
implement that they're not
amended and implemented to soften and
located
and small who label ceo similar
demonstration to the lisbeth
demonstration but the just using a rod
kal
the poem extend
let's switch over to my notes would-be
gun
so i mean that's still the same
river rock last month on the face
want to take a look at the rotting table
again
you will see there is no route to the
tends were sixteen amp with any more
because i disconnected my own
rule and the
or spirit
state just chuck volunteer altered iraq
at the pit
and this letter indicates red rock star
from connected to a spare frank nicholas
a day
northside chippy
silva let slums of looking again
and
this time al-mal start sniffing on that
defendant the face which is just uh...
another be long on the setup
and in this deal on the wrist no laws
have spoken
want to see if they're just discovered
some brought into the cold which is the
enhanced idea pete
okay we see there are two whole speaking
and on-site g_o_p_ they're both in the
autonomous system one so they're part of
one rotting infrastructure
the first thing on
i have to do is
participate in this for months i g_o_p_
optimum system so i have to send out
hello packages again
both rather will perform
some kind of handshake
with my program
you see in the background ok verison u
consulate if universal went up
which is my notebook
and you also see there are
routing information delivered by the two
routers
not have to joyce and april one two
inject them in some rollup all want to
check
and eckstein rock
i'll just do the same
past the demo reform
all along
configure and internal rolled which just
points to my notebook
i p address
but also
decide to take slash sixteen network at
my destination again mr
handled c romantic
pollen jacked this route
both routers
just a mock downtown after watts
sending out those updates
so uh... you see one of the relatives
instantly repeat that brought
information
to my system
parent
look on the
rocking to google
zero one story
slow if we had
take a look on the rotting table
whom you see there is a new route
showing up
to the ten dots year-old slash sixteen
edward
so we also successfully injected
faves routing information into the
browsing process
so again all traffic to the ten slash
sixteen network will be redirected off
relative to my host and i can do
whatever along with that traffic
specter any and
the next time a description
sorry i just saw a cashier stressed out
uh...
they're a sovereign
routing protocols like well as pap tests
of each like that that's so because some
going to tell you about the future here
armpits are some routing protocols
might have some authentication features
so
daaru like borrows after some cherokee
password you have to know
um... still be able to inject drugs
because they are
raj information will be authenticated
not uh...
logoff metrics are really using bad then
if they are using that
they are most likely stuff like that
i secure cisco
whatever because
even
and all that i'm going to change because
of parents they are trying to broadcast
communicating i'll definitely definitely
each other
uh...
ads would be difficult judge to kiev
ruidoso
if they use erotic authentication that's
most likely to be a
read password i'm pretty much amazed
what kind of roads people in bedford
password sometimes sheet of its
community string pre ship k pass
whatever
on at the same problems that uh...
repair easily correctable
arm
mother that's a
really new saying they had to be able to
breaker that seventy five fax or
something like that
but as i told you at the beginning we
want to stop to it
i want to be able to combine different
modules so you can't trust the
open-ended authentication future in low
key and lou
take the packages truck crack password
basement liston
again be able to inject broads
it's pretty much so similar for this
regarding protocols
i'd say it was preface widely deployed
to
some also useful if indications are next
in the show is sir
on demonstration
coldecon inject the whole can't crack
on
the passwords or other those baffled
indication ki
enough to extract it's the same
procedure in two thousand first those
cash payment to inject erotica ask
that's no problem so
at his cock home
so
the same rough again
combo left
a look at the configuration first
soul
now will show you the company recent
poll
the interface i'm going to tach in a
second
which is
before our sympathy
person from its hero on them
beeline twenty and you see off
configured
post p_f_ message started authentication
on this interface
solon every os p_f_
packets and album this in the face this
authenticate that
the secret string secret
so
went to try to hook up
low key to that
post p_f_ rotting domain
with all the indication my package will
my packages will just get dropped
soul
of people holed up into that nothing can
a lunch low-key hand
the first preprint network
from after start listening
more powerful some seconds
double show up son
you're looking for the call which is the
os p_f_
and this time you see both hosts use
the cryptographic authentication
i need a password to
and to perform deals gap handshake with
these two holes
so well
www trying office
just to select
somewhat list
use this one
you can easily gas
the password is in there because it's
just a demonstration
is i used to brute force year earlier
will sit here until next week so
hold true to their motion or put the
right past winter worked fine
but just to show you how it works will
select one of these holes
and with my world file
but just tried to
yeah let's say
brute force
the and if i a secret
and after a few seconds barabar
for thousands
arm passwords and that was filed
so after a few seconds
martin not even a few seconds
the tools fines deride secret
so you see it a prom it secret like you
we can see in the configurations well
with that information
are easy
and enter it here
performed deals p_f_ handshake again
you'll see ok the status changing
deals p_f_ handshake is
uh... on its way and
after a few seconds
colby in stateful
get all the routing information
i will show up as an
mural time disrupting domain
and also i can easily inject whatever
uttam information uil
want inject
prevent wassup
one of two features ah... implemented
multiplied for performance reasons
uh... enzo visited there are dollop
mitigating controls provided by the
roger critical itself
use authentication to be sooner more
figaro it's whatever
by associated with in the in the typical
in my amendment
if there is uh... multiplication
it has a big password and then it's just
a mod a matter of time
from forces and again be able to
there on the fraud commission perform
some protection yet these
attacks can also be parfum performed
offline
so just need to sniff one alum
authenticated packets all authenticated
os p_f_ packet and with good one
single pack attic and perform this
attack of
i told them you don't need to stay
connected to the network it just me that
single pakistan after what bruce forcing
against the password and
after some time uh... you will find the
right passwd
the amount that's contributed so his
charges from some attacks of arkansas
for a commonly used so in carrier did
very wrong protocols
uh... manning those patent on such a p
din
along with those also hope so
circumvent several implemented
publication message for that
so arm
depart in the process much less than we
pray king stuff so
assume told you the idea behind look
you've also
close the gap between ten a radical
stuff and protocols practical stuff but
no longer for the reasons i again
breaking records but only also for
reasons of make them more secure
disbelieve major customers so other
people believed that's that's a problem
so they fix the stuff
let's also have a look at what actually
can be done against that kind of attacks
saw
does not on the program also should be a
solution
all-male
and if you select the solution for
problem arsenault
always uh...
mention about the operational impact the
cats so if it gets
if it's just improves his security a
little bit but operational
impact so
who lost office gets really complicated
whatever
balance maybe that's a good idea to go
to implement such and such a feature
summit seven out of the south
all they can be at usdoj indication of
just saw extractable bob's
amount of time it takes high depends on
the quality of the
what indication keeps calling two
password so if you use authentication
trevor particles body month indication
and u_s_ authentication
uh... and have
some root password
and also road don't forget about the use
of seeing some friends in paris with
some pride to the move somewhere else at
your office
will still bezel configure motherland
felim before that but it can be a pretty
pretty secure saying
just have to think about how to
implement that and it's not
that's part of implementa not an
occasional cabbage for anyone
configuration alumnae children
to set the kind of pressure
arnold
whereas in the category of texas
controls the canal soulless from rotting
protocols have been also configure
spectacle static peers
so that's based on a mac address
so i manually set my neighbor autos
and i will not accept any rules any
rollins and roads
from i'd get this
system and you know like kind of texas
lista que these routers camps and
routing information
i live here this is still on so
he would not be able to of abroad and
would not accept watching information
from his laptop
find such a scenario that so
dos one wrong turn away so we can use it
on campus that may be considerate
office i'm watching it
protocol cesa mechanism called pasok
interfaces
if you configure most p_f_ charging
process on the cisco router
you had your interfaces
to the routing process and raja process
all
automatically take stocky addresses from
the interface
okay i noted that eric idle propagated
to my neighbors
if it's a client medgar
dost menino needs
so
uh... speak both spanish actively on
that interface but they're still need to
activate it because i was so
medved won't be propagated to the
neighbors
and that also one configuration command
analysis co-author
say okay this is a passive interface
travelgate inadvertence
altogether rogers but those p always
careful
there on top of the column that network
so
if someone tries to send raji
information though this in the face
but just discovered on accepted so
that's also a good sir
madam and to prevent signs i control
swirls
of course you can use as a nation
mechanisms like using different
broadbrick also left one px
rock injected it doesn't affect the
whole network
about that so i want to features ah...
that certain it's a beautiful
reoperation issue
phones have two men
this estimation brought her to call it
swanson bed of cerca aliens are not such
a pianist
although you something else in this part
then it gets really complicated
thereafter
redness retro so after knowledge from he
trotted because of its many hundreds
appoint
or span of a little better
what's also along with that as uh...
hockey best pure filtering and put some
other excess list
uh... not based on the rogers protocol
but based on sun
firewall rules uh... access list
subinterfaces stuff like that
and secure and so
calls coming in from wrong hosts
more i can just as i a m not furthering
om i'm
accepting out there so this would have
met for about not halt like he just did
it though
introducing a new medford or something
like that
licenses and of course includes a
a trip to stop using ipsec between roger
spot
assume ten
imagine that with the increase
operational
stuff made it to operate such an attack
the and it's more likely to have some
availability problems because of some of
my basic number two probably
stuff going wrong
and interfering
more impact on your america but ability
in you met with adult
on our part of this was a bit of the
exhaust lauck stuff like that
on so you see if somebody's injecting
routing information but
uh... as everybody knows
logging and taken moments ago there may
be is logging but does anybody look at
log soul
last time
probably not
low
there's some other stuff more of us off
really also implemented unloaded alm
that same some additional protocols not
only raji protocols
unlikely to be our p it's be a feel of
the peak
uh... will tell you something about
chris too
so if you are appearing on
maybe some of you know that's that's
just some kind of first hall program
route
redundancy protocol so you can have
would say f climb advert that's are
altered
this let's say i have martha nike so it
has wrought fails to
of another country anything to be out of
the anymore bathroom a safer product
lawyer just put it to rochester
alm
having their own mike addresses sharing
one russia lucky address and if the one
rafael seattle takes over
on
and uh... yet
thus assistance to communicate
on what it will go dear also has trash a
great action
soviet also participate in that we are p
process
between the rajas and get the massive
uh... at all the traffic from maybe
declines and
forwarded to the real
two-year-olds are to intercepts traffic
again so it's another possibility too
alone
redirect traffic in an advert
armpits really similar to cisco stage
has our people to call but this one the
seminars and smarter
proper terry
there are so many seed most some some
final one
based
file also uh... on market platforms
on the u_s_ we are p four items and see
pretty much looks like that you have
fought
some kind of toronto stifle their own
appeared restless their blood pattern of
the tragic
and their share of russell appear dress
alan alda clients use that dose like
address es let's add default-gateway
but said this brought us this i give s
as a certain there it's a bit slow p
address and it failed to gether won the
takeover
and the cat scans to communicate
that for that to her capsized exchanging
some analyst on my arm still there are
still there
and this general rather offered on seed
packets like that
after sometime in just a look at it but
you look at best
yeah their son
uh... this also game on this so i will
just sick of that uh... they mow
radios
some kind of priority to figure out
who's a master who is that if roger
and the highest the baddest priority is
to tools by five
and unfortunately conquered figure this
explicitly the highest number on system
it was two five four
onto fifi phone against
in a special set up off the r_p_a_ use
automatically
for months
and the next day we will see the phone
triggered our action using
the rpm outside like that
used to rogers with his ugly addresses
that's all i don't know if so
looks like here
now this never attached palm
and overseeing all as to how they became
the master office we are p construction
and redirect check
so home this is still the same brothels
and i got
some
beer appear at the configured on this
device
bogart five years their one hundred to
dot too
and as you see the device and actually
connected to this in the state back up
the masa relative is
the second problem from which is the
and one hundred thoughts twenty
so it got and high priority configured
bart we don't care about this
priority
soul
launched its rule out the plan
and
connected arrived at work
you would see their response sent by
blinking and there are some
the r_p_a_ connections there's a bill to
the two
so in this actually is the connection
didn't
it's handled by the one hundred book
twenty and but lucky is the year one
hundred book too
they've got the priority two hundred
fifty four
so what i will do next this
doing
uh... a lot of peace from the one
relative to the bush like pete
one of these things are unable to take
over that i can trust
and you will see they respond we want
paying missing and all the other
packages got directly for what it to my
tamu to paying on the boastful cokie
address which is steep one hundred book
too
are worried people and
sometimes
soul and one of those things are running
i'll just take over the i_q_ address
so now you see there is one thing makes
missing parent after waltz all those
allies simpy packages are now on so far
my local host
not by the second trial tool which the
people ma city bus
we can easily prove dust
we take another look on the
i'll put a few shobhit r_p_a_
and you see the masa rolta naal isn't
the second
rockton front but this my notebook
which got the i_p_o_ dress one hundred
both one hundred
also look priority race up to the
maximum value which is to two hundred
fifty five
so uh...
associates
than the previous the to overtake them
hum
hi available archaea dress if you see
those
the repeat traffic in your client
network
though uh...
for the arcade there are also like the
somewhat to propose them they are
somewhat in the case mechanisms but
they're very moved in a
new version of standard
bacall slow downtown last fall some
areas and they mentioned okay
issues that seem all that you have to
not a service by your own by
authentication averting properly or
something like that so both of the
rockies think they're the master
have to say my paragraphs and unknown
that's atmospheric on occasion that
matter
but just removed it plan does not
not really authentication
tropical anymore
europe along
last probably a study of the on
have to speed up a little bit subtle
scraps from babbitt also don't make a
beam on that but unfortunate implemented
if they're that's called by their action
of forwarding detection
on it's now let's say an add on to the
russian critical because to me the photo
foster
hold on
missing earnings route
also that's a repair time for network
protocols
so if the link co-starring and that was
erected for withdrawal certain
destination it takes some time until the
relatives sar
noticing that the link a stalin if it's
a director different much limoges
because it will depend of the lead us to
link in email but it's been if it's
behind another road to the don't get
their information it entirely uh... take
some uh... some
based on the depends on the
configuration can take some seconds can
take some minutes
armed but there are
and some of my once they are
requirements to do the sell-off faster
and actually there are two critical some
support that
so there was some kind of had on you can
use a different bargain protocols
they can sense
similar them uh... hello packets s uh...
roger sent to each other they can send
like something like a little packages
averaged fifty milliseconds
alm
so they can
repaired a mattress i think i can stick
and really detected really fast that's
eight hundred milliseconds
and uh... special for months on the
fraud
so you can
realize sir
repair time seniornet represent hundred
milliseconds architect wanted
milliseconds depends on how foster
artists are speaking a protocol
uh... was normally also implemented in
hardware because softer still not that
fast we can also speak that's because he
brought the speaks never wants to give
the name of the affluent as big a
default also subrata
i want to be good for us
arm
yes on nafta real
cast philip texan lifted is kind of
political
read something like that
and they sent every fifty milliseconds
cess mpeg adjusted a neighbor us both of
them do that
arm
and if there are no pegasus packages
coming in for a configurable
but says three packages missing who can
configure that
baton rogue throughout the southern link
is considered their fate rocket special
thomas approach
on and that's also
or it's
time because they've got some garcia
stand that it's just two months ago
but uh...
then you're just retro somber sunblock
and so i guess in your new protocol you
haven't heard
dropping for the calls in just a looked
at the packet former dollars easy and
uh...
book three or four hours later
it was implemented
thought we were probably not find it in
the white already because it's a
previous stand that
by the bristol shows will show up in
some
arm environments having
hi requirements if a law
times which cannot tolerate uh... duncan
from a minute dot something like that
most likely this tropical show up there
low-key kind of the syntax to it
so what's going on with locate locate
this uh... still broken program so they
are
although there are lots of protocols
already implemented though
the upcoming features which many are new
protocols
uh...
already have a to-do list of stuff like
ayaz ayaz are cheer d_p_s_ olympiad
tumne
given command has to complete a sweet
though maybe a dual also had trouble
calls already sapporo disappointed by
other
uh...
programs like me to be empty g_p_ a
texas friend entry etc excuses p
aren't there are several tools already
supporting that but
death to complete the state to reform
sweet tech infrastructure protocols who
met them also
and
whatever infrastructure public roles we
need to her
support of techno level maybe and
implemented
their sons observers of just since many
of the assignment research a protocol
nobody can detect this note to let it
should be possible
first troublesome him out and then maybe
oh who implements the hostel
yeah and of course italy but fixes
wall-to-wall arm asturias today mall are
for the first time in the wild
except for men since
tool or modules
lipset somali delicious of the companies
and yet
maybe a little may two month conversion
this zero two four
and then something very compelling about
the source codes palm and we also build
some
went to and somebody into pegasus on
to be easily unstoppable
so if you want to there are just uh...
trust science also mobutu leftist
revolution
greta pegasus and saw them in a
committed compare artist
merited will also be uh...
ministers normac resumed on the job of
that yet
but maybe we'll do that too
concludes
arnold
road let's let's call it in your
children infrastructure technology throw
up
and you truly closing another gap
between juridical attacks make
intractable usable
i don't know attacks on the list
catherine how touchy appeared less most
secret that that is potentially a
technical but now you can use it
therefore
some ostriches in easy tool
on
and another thing we want to say okay
knowledge positive effect is critical so
protection infrastructure but they're
always think about the operational
impact
housing department does it mean for the
guys operating and that like a few
implementing a secured future sent on
susteren command area sing some small
black and white papers tell u recommend
you to do
uh...
so let's get a good mixture of
improving your security
but though in sfo
are high enough european operational
successes
and although baltimore cause
infrastructure module
wanderlust infrastructure
go often write their own loca models who
can write them in python
but difficult to freshly effluent
tropical but
who can implement other modules may be
an attractive for other
hashes sort of whatever you need
and of course not
have fun in the black cat
thanks to todd thanks for coming around
hope you enjoy the book
oil uh... thankfully for contributing to
be a fifty pm verdict was part of his
diploma to use
arm to figure out that stuff and flow
called all summer i came here to talk
technical presentation depicted a little
bit duvall has pictures and stuff for
the s quiet conclude this week with
samples the sex of the skies
who contributed did stuff