so welcome to the 145 cyber war and
peace talk today given by Chris Sumner
Chris started his career back in the
dark ages of 1999 doing security
management for a fortune 100 company
moved from there Chris began to work
personally on data visualization and as
you'll soon hear actually has an
interesting story about Tony Hawk so I
thought that was pretty cool today he'll
be talking about using data
visualization tools in social networks
so please join me in welcoming Chris
Sumner thanks very much can everyone
hear me all right just want to make sure
before i get started because i'm using
this mic thing here that lets me walk
around all right we're good all right so
thanks for the introduction and Chris
Sumner I started my career a little
longer ago than in 1999 but got into
security full time around then so first
of all thanks for coming today there's a
another talk about ATMs and so I'm
pretty stoked that we've got such a big
audience actually thanks very much so my
talk today is on social networking and
data visualization and extending data
visualization tools to enumerate social
networks maybe a little bit quicker than
them by hand or in a non visual way
before I start I've got a disclaimer
that I need to were to share I'm
speaking for myself not as part of my
company so if anybody knows who I work
for then it's important at least let you
know that oh this is you know on behalf
of me doesn't reflect the opinions of my
the organization for which I work so
okay so what are you in for today first
we're going to start with a brief
introduction to social network analysis
and brief intro to visualization about
10 or 15 minutes I'll go pretty quick
there's a white paper with a lot of the
science behind it
able and then going to take a look at a
case study with Twitter and a tool
called multi go and then finally we'll
wrap up with case study and it's a
little bit darker involving Nigerian 419
crime versus multi go so the goals of
the tour today really I guess firstly
its to to share what I've been what I've
been doing a high level and give you
some appreciation of the possibilities
of data visualization in this kind of
field so hoping that some of you will go
I that's pretty you know that's pretty
neat I can apply this in slightly
different contexts you know and maybe
encourages folks to go and explore a lot
of the data that's out there so that you
know you can apply it over in a work
situation or for you know analyzing
networks yourself so who's to talk aimed
at just want to be clear on this in case
people are you know coming over already
got you know a significant level of data
visualization knowledge or significant
level of social networking data mining
knowledge so really if you fit into this
category you should be in for a good
time I can't promise that but see me
afterwards if if it wasn't if you fit
into the the next category here where
you're either you know really really
experience we've had some good
experience with data visualization or
with social networking analysis then you
may get some some crossover and see how
it can use different techniques in kind
of different way and if you fit into the
to the latter category you probably get
what I'm talking about already but that
may still still be something you know in
it for you so that's really what the you
know who the talks aimed at so briefly
Who am I I'm obviously I'm Chris Sumner
but I signed up to Twitter last summer
and like a lot of people who sign up to
Twitter the name that you want has
already been taken by somebody else so I
ended up choosing the sub my sister
because my
game at school and for ever since has
been sucky and you know it's one of
those things that I sort of kind of
regret now and you know never mind so by
day a work in corporate corporate
security actually do program management
around security development lifecycle
and outside of work I'm interested in
data analysis not usually social
networks but looking at large datasets
visualizing that to help me understand a
little bit more about the data at a high
level before drilling down and since
last year really got into social media
in a pretty big way and also def con
chapter called DC 4420 in London a quick
note if you're you know if you've not
been to a local DEFCON chapter really
worth going it's like bite sized bits of
DEFCON throughout the year so you know
you don't get that post DEFCON
depression thing going on if you get
that like I do and a strange sequence of
events led me to appearing here so I
you'll obviously see why shortly so okay
the introduction piece social network
analysis a target-rich environment is
over a problem or an opportunity
depending on which side of the you know
table you you're looking at it from
social network analysis has been around
really since since the Greeks but this
guy here Jacob Marino was pretty widely
credited of being so the originator of
this diagram which should be pretty
familiar with by the by the end of the
talk this kind of thing so that was
published first in New York Times in
1933 and really he saw led the field in
understanding dynamics of social
networks so a little bit more about that
in the white paper and then a
target-rich environment this was
something that I kind of figured would
be the case but had never actually
looked into until I decided to you know
submit a paper for the talk a read a
report that was out this year or late
last year by Cisco stating that there
was something like 21 exabytes of data
flowing around the world per month and
the amount of data that's available now
thats or personal information
photographs and stuff is just like
exploding so you're getting more and
more data out there from more and more
people which is you know pretty pretty
interesting if you like exploring data I
should probably get out more so Facebook
recently actually if you look at the
white paper it says 350 million users
and then before I got here said it's you
know hitting 500 ish million users of
course you know some people may have
more than one account although that's
you know sort of forbidden but you know
such as life then there's something else
interesting there's a bunch of studies
that have been going on Stanford have
done quite a lot on this looking at what
people say and actually what people do
so I kind of turned this the privacy
paradox and it's where the students
interviewed mostly said yeah I take
privacy very seriously yet when you know
they analyzed the behavior of these
students on social networks like
Facebook they did the opposite of what
they said they want to do so for example
89% used their use their real name 60 or
61 percent have an identifiable photo
online and so on I mean recently you
know a lot of the privacy concerns
around Facebook a lot of people are
still what I term promiscuous you know
they'll be friends with anyone they'll
post anything up there I mean it's a
data miners dream actually and I'll talk
a little bit more about that because
there's some seriously cool stuff going
on in this space and then finally saw my
personal favorite really there's a great
paper it's a pretty pretty big paper by
a guy called Daniels olive and called
her you know I've got nothing to hide
and over misunderstandings of
the sea and that kind of goes along with
the whole privacy paradox of people
putting more and more stuff out there so
we've got social network analysis and
now we've got a target-rich environment
so previously you know and when the
Greeks are looking at this sort of stuff
you know it's all by hand and now
obviously you've got a stack a great
stack of data available that you can
explore very very quickly as will see a
you know a little bit later so what's
the problem well your searches your
online activity isn't all that and you
know anonymous essentially and that's
probably not a great surprise to anyone
in the room but you know there was so
the cater for this lady Thelma Arnold I
won't read the AOL number but in a
roughly two thousand six AOL published a
you know a bunch of their sort search
strings and think it was again it's the
new york times they must be into social
analysis they'd actually gone taking a
look at the data for this AOL use of
4417 what have you and they're
determined that it was just lady in
georgia this Thelma Arnold because of
the searches that she was looking
because that you know she was looking at
dog kennels and stuff like that for you
know you can see she's got a dog so all
of this stuff that's out there this I've
got nothing to hide what could possibly
go wrong isn't all that anonymous even
if the data is a non mais de neve real
names taken out it's still highly
possible for people to link that back to
it to an individual so we've got a lot
of data and you've got a lot of noise
really the opportunity here is how do
you find the interesting stuff just a
little bit quicker and you can do that
as I hope to show today quickly is by
you know data mining techniques like
screen scraping I don't know if anyone
saw the Michael shrink talk at Def Con
last year if you didn't go on to the
archives and have a look at that because
that's an absolutely fantastic talk
around you know obtaining data through
screen scraping obviously you've got to
be aware of the robots.txt and what have
you
named entity recognition and data
visualization I'll talk just briefly
about those two right now so named
entity recognition is really parsing
data to it extract and classify
information it differs from saw
meta-analysis because it classifies the
you know the data are not one particular
type very similar but it's like you know
it's like different so here's an example
Greg brought 300,000 shares of the gap
completely random idea here in 2010 and
this is what it ends up looking like
this it's kind of a the example was
pretty much from Wikipedia but now what
you can see here is that you've almost
got saw an XML format where it's picked
out the name a quantity an organization
and earned a date so very high level
that's what it's like you know have a
Google around for named entity
recognition you'll see a lot stuff from
the university of stanford and the
university of illinois and there's some
online online tools open Caillat for
example that's got an API so you can
pass data to that and you know and use
it and we'll see a little bit more about
the power of what you can do here data
visualization quick show of hands
anybody read this book or familiar with
a tool called piece of software called
processing a couple of people may be
processing it and I mean first of all
this book is is fantastic Ben Frey
really has done a great job and outlines
process for data visualization acquiring
data pausing it filtering it essentially
getting you data into the to a neat
filtered form and then rendering it and
then allowing you to interact with that
model so almost a three step process get
the data tidy it up output it to some
sort of file or you know XML CSV
whatever and then render it so iterative
and he talks about that in this book and
uses the processing software which you
can download how to play with it
is fantastic but it's this last point
really that wanted to home in on which
is where you see a big gap in a number
of tools out there is interacting with
the data so the whole process of
generating a data set and down
interacting with the data and do you
know doing that in a sort of a loop
means that you have to leave the
graphical user interface whereas what
I'm going to talk about today shows you
at all where you don't leave that don't
necessarily leave the GUI so for tools
there's a number of them I just put a
few one here I could you know you could
go on as a great website out there
called sec this org it's got a whole
bunch of tools on there I picked a few
that I liked and it played around with
but going to focus on multi go so the
first question really is well will you
know what what is multi go so I'm going
to go through this bit pretty quickly
because I'm going to talk about it and
you'll get the idea through the rest of
the talk but briefly it's a tool for you
know information gathering and seeing
visualizing information in a graphical
graphical way there's a infrastructure
components and I'll show a quick example
of that so you can look at dns records
IP addresses urls mail records what have
you and there's a human part where you
can look for mentions of people
telephone numbers and you know what have
you and link all of those sorts of
relationships together i'll show you
more about that but it's just a quick
snapshot but the most exciting thing
about multi go is it's extendable by
design so whatever you get out of it
just quick show of hands actually who's
use multi you go and you will get this
and right now so it's extendable by
design so you can write your own what
called local transforms to go and do
whatever it is you want i'll talk more
about that and show you what i did in
in our case study so if you haven't used
multi go here's where you go and get it
perturb calm written by a couple of guys
in South Africa Roloff and Andy Mohawk
great guys actually been a very great
help to me and if you didn't know
there's a twenty five percent discount
during this or conference week if you
type in the coupon code black hat at a
multi go there's a community edition
which is kind of scaled down but it'll
let you have a play around with it and
there's also a full client version which
is usually about four hundred and thirty
dollars so twenty five percent off so
this is what the first screen is you're
going to you know see when you when you
saw fire it up once you've got your
license key in and and and all of that
so completely this is this is kind of
what you what you'd see so pick a domain
I know that the text is going to be
smaller that's not really that important
but I picked out six domains completely
at random so I went for you know leg at
calm high-tech hustler com security geek
calm and you can see it what I wanted to
do was briefly demonstrate what the tool
allows you to do so I figured it'd be
neat to see out of these domains you
know who's sharing MX records so you can
see this I've got security geek down at
the bottom which is my website and then
you've got a number of these other
entities all sharing the same MX records
from from godaddy well you can explore a
little bit further and actually last
night I was playing around with this
looking at say the the websites that are
associated with those addresses and then
looking at the email addresses that were
found on those websites and then looking
at the email addresses on those websites
that appeared on other websites and you
could see interesting relationship
because a lot of the email addresses
listed on all of those sites also
appeared on attrition org so if you knew
nothing about you know what's been going
on
at least on Twitter with regards to
discussion around lagaa you'd have
spotted that that relationship pretty
pretty quickly so moving a guess neatly
onto to Twitter I mention it I sort of
joined Twitter about about a year ago
started following two people initially
one was ryan Russell it's pretty
interesting guy he and another chap was
was this guy here Tony Hawk us
skateboarder so what Tony likes to do I
didn't follow him for this reason I
found that out while I was following him
on Twitter he likes to get skateboards
that look a little bit like like this
with his sort of signature on it that
hopefully one of you is going to take
away today he likes to basically hide
them and send out tweets with clues as
to where he's hidden these things around
the world and he was doing this thing of
starting this this this event a
worldwide Twitter hun he said I need
some trustworthy volunteers send me a
tweet of where you live and why I should
trust you so I thought well I'm not
going anything to lose right part from
140 characters I've send him a tweet
saying I'm in London and you can trust
me because I'm you know I'm a gentleman
or what I will happy sunday on
cyberspace you can be a gentleman and
they really knows right so so to my
surprise I've got got selected and he's
like okay you know we're going to send
you a package and you know the deal is
that you'll hide it somewhere in the UK
and you'll send us a clue to where
you've hidden it and we'll tweet that
clue out Tony will tweet that clue out
to you know all of his followers so that
you know this point I was pretty amped
as you as you are you know sort of
childhood hero and I'm pushing 40 I
really should be a little bit more
mature than this but
I was I was really stoked and my wife
was actually pretty stoked as well but
for different reasons she'd seen Tony's
house on mtv cribs and thought that was
really nice house and I was just like
Ron you know tony hawk pro skateboarder
so colleague of mine going by the name
of patio door was like okay Chris let me
get this straight you know you work in
security you've been a security manager
some dude on Twitter who claims to be
Tony Hawk is going to send you a box to
an address that you gave him and you're
going to hide that somewhere in the UK
and no problems there whatsoever it's at
that point where I was like yeah maybe I
should look for another career actually
I clearly not cry out for this you know
and the other day actually was saying
yeah just think about it you've got a
whole nother angle for your talk really
look how easy it is if you want to get
people to do something you know you
don't have to pay them or anything you
just pretend to be someone sent them a
box getting to hide it somewhere job
done so i was a little bit paranoid but
I was like no it really is Tony Hawk
he's verified by twit is anybody here
from twitter by the way but if you i'd
like to buy you a really big drink was
no no one that's a pity so i went ahead
of it anyway because i figured well you
know yeah it's got to be really some
twitter and he's got the little blue
tick so what you know it's got so this
is the box that was sent to me in the in
the post so i sent this clue to to Tony
which I thought was pretty awesome
actually so guarded by a fearsome troll
Northwest from a house where you might
have to pay money to pass an escape book
skateboard park so the money to pass
house toll house there's a toll house
near where we live if you go Northwest
you pass a skate park and where we're
might be guided by a fierce and troll
but under under a bridge so I thought
awesome clue bridge
it occurred to me that people might spot
a package and think that ok some sort
that somebody's you know from a
terrorist cell is trying to blow up one
of the most important bridges in the
village so I had some concerns about
that but I went about it anyway and
suddenly clue out now this guy here is a
bit of a legend actually he'd been
following Tony Hawk as well and was
really more excited than I was that
there was going to be this Twitter on in
the UK so he actually drove up in the
morning to the you know so Beijing stoke
the town where I live in basingstoke and
he camped out basically all day waiting
for Tony to send this tweet I mean I
could have actually gone and taken the
board to London so they're they're years
camping out in his car and eventually
after an epic quest he found it I'd took
the liberty of adding a little bit of
camouflage to the package so that random
dog walkers wouldn't wouldn't find it so
that was his tweet that Kevin camo
netting Europe a bad man but as you can
see he was really amped to get the to
get the Tony Hawk package and this is
this is what was in it I added the UK
flag because well I felt like it on the
somehow the hackers for charity that all
sticker got on there too Tony likes
hackers so I obviously with you all
established them on Twitter so I've got
a life I wanted to see a map of where
all of these packages went who hid them
and who found them so I thought that'd
be fairly straight forward thing to do
on a nerdy Sunday afternoon I thought
right well all of the people like myself
who hid decks were all friends on
twitter with the hiding it account the
finders all were meant to tweet I found
one when they found one so that should
be easy to find you know easy to analyze
as well and Tony sends out found
wherever by whoever
the hashtag th-th so there's a problem
with that not all of the hiders were
friends of hiding it some of them were
tony hawk's personal friends almost none
of the finders actually followed the
instructions they will put the USB stick
that came with the package in their
computer but none of them followed the
instructions and Tony himself really
didn't follow his own instructions I
verso skateboarders what you're going to
do so I thought right I reach out to
Twitter because I don't know about you
guys but instead of doing Google stuff
now now I asked Twitter and you know you
get a nice very you know response from
that so I asked why does anybody know
the quick way to get information you
know out of out of Twitter nobody
mentioned search because I should have
looked at that so see previous comment
about needing to find another career and
I got a response room from this guy
who's part of you know turns up to the
DC 4420 the DEF CON chapter meetings and
he said multi go can do that you know
and I'm thinking you know more tiga
what's that so you know we had some
discussion he said oh it's data
visualization go and have a look on data
visualization awesome how did I not know
about this brilliant so i downloaded
multi go had a bit of a look at it i
thought right so here's my hypothesis
which for the record my hypothesis for
anything generally you know disregard it
i figured that the hiders and the people
that found the skateboards would have
some sort of social interaction like hey
congratulations i hit the board or you
know something like that and i thought
by finding those interactions socially
I'd be able to arrive at a google map
and that would be a piece of cake so
started off by getting a list of the
hiders in in twitter with multi go so i
Wiss through this a little bit but give
you some idea of what we did so
first issue that you've got is that you
have to derive what's called an entity
these things here are entities so
started off with a phrase it's called a
phrase and i typed in at hiding it which
you can see sort of arrowed arrowed up
there and then when you right click on
that you get a number of options that
are particular to the entity that you've
got on one of them was you know
searching Twitter so this is what a
transform looks like a built-in
transform that means it comes with the
tool you can look at all of the tweets
that have the phrase hiding it in so I
did that and you get a bunch of these
things called twit apps or Twitter
affiliations they look like purple
prickly things I think now in version 3
of the tool it's a different logo but
you get the idea so these are tweets
actually is essentially and from there
you can convert that to previous on two
twits actually this is how you convert
the tweet to an actual person or Twitter
affiliation as it's called in in multi
go so you right click on that and then
do do that conversion and you can select
that for the whole array of people so
you don't just do you know for one at a
time you can just select that that whole
bunch and eventually then you'll arrive
here with you know with Twitter no the
Twitter affiliation entity so that's
basically how to get the derived that
the node it's in the the white paper
sort step-by-step so if you want to
experiment with it the other way you can
do it which is highlighted by the red
box in the corner it sort of take one
that you've already having to modify it
that tends to to work as well at least
for twitter so now you know we can we
can get going actually really start and
take a look at well who are the friends
are
hiding it so again you've got this
concept of a transform and you're
looking at the friends of this person
and you can generate that get a nice big
list with little thumbnails of you know
what the people look like and then you
can perform that operation are you know
on all of them people again so you can
select all there's 83 there you have to
trust me on that you can select all 83
and run the same transform on all 83
people so I picked me that's that's me
right there and if you see the top
right-hand corner there's a little red
you know red box that gives you the
ability to navigate so if you've got big
graphs you can navigate around the
around the graphs using that box and
then home in on it and the the screen in
the middle so I chose I wanted to see
all of the tweets that I wrote I mainly
shown you one I could have applied that
transform to every single entity at the
same time so I did that and then then
that's when I noticed that things
weren't happening quite as I expected so
I'd get like 12 results but I know I you
know I know I tweeted about I had 50 or
something tweet so I was like what's
going on this is kind of weird actually
quite a lot of exploration on why that
was weird I thought well maybe it's
because I'm relatively new and not that
interesting so I try you know Tony Hawk
so you know I looked at his tweet
nothing at all so I emailed the guys in
South Africa who wrote the tool by now
they must have been thinking I wish this
English guy would just go away and they
tried to reproduce it and have the same
challenges and digging a little bit
deeper we noticed that twitter has got
some limitations in search so it's
pretty well documented you know out
there what Twitter search was the API
came from another
organization called summarize and it
indexes or maintains the index at least
for about two weeks roughly and some
people aren't indexed to also the
challenge i had was Tony Hawk wasn't
indexed at all and I was only getting
the tweets had written in the last two
weeks so a bit of a challenge there and
that is where this thing came in handy
because roll off the guy who essentially
set up at server from San supposed he
said dude you should try local
transforms you can write your own code
I'm thinking you've got the wrong guy I
don't write can't play around with pearl
now and again he said but you know if
you can write you know if you can call a
script or a program and you can pass an
input and you can generate output to
standard output then you can write a
local transform which was which was
pretty pretty interesting and compelling
so I set about it by thinking right well
I try this with with pearl and have a
look at the Twitter API now I bought
this book but actually I didn't really
use it that much because there's a you
know a huge set of Twitter API
documentation online which you can
search for but it's not one API it's
three API so forget the Search API that
we mentioned from summarize and just
focus on the other REST API which allows
you to use commands you know call calls
like this essentially and this is where
you'd be you know extracting the tweets
from somebody and you've got an entity
value there which is the person that
you're looking to to grab the tweets
from if anybody wants the you know the
code for playing around with this sort
of stuff I plan to just put it on the
you know
on my website which is security geek but
that either threes so you can you know
you can do a lot playing around with
that's not all plain sailing either
there are some things which I wish were
implemented in the Twitter API that
there are like searching by date and
stuff like that you kind of have to make
that yourself but purlin lwp you know
really work pretty well so there's a
couple more gotchas here as well though
you've got this 202 limit so when you
you know r under the API call you'll get
200 tweets back so if you want to like
look at 400 tweets for example you
that's to API calls well that was an
issue you couldn't search by date so I
couldn't say I want to get all of the
tweets between these dates I had to
derive the dates by looking each tweet
has got an ID associated with it and you
can see a time so you pull a tweet with
an ID look at the time and you know and
then sort of figure out well let's say
there's you know excellent go to another
tweet ID guess that say okay well this
is between two dates that that kind of
works but there's a maximum history I
haven't actually tested how how rigid
that is but 3200 tweet history and
you're limited to 150 API calls per hour
by default so as you can see if you've
got 100 people which is quite easy in a
graph like this because you're exploring
vast sets of data and you're running
those transforms on all of those people
in this rather small example here you'd
have 100 people I'd be looking at making
38 API calls per person end up with you
know 300 API calls that's already blown
my my limit with with Twitter so I'd
have to do that over two hours and
that's where white listing comes in you
can go from 158
i calls to 20,000 in an hour so you have
to apply for that via twitter but they
were pretty good with that said you know
I'm security consultants and looking
into you know data analysis and what
have you and I'd like to be whitelisted
please I thought that'd take forever or
I've getting know and you know and they
said yeah sure he here you go basically
which then meant that I could run some
pretty large graphs so ok back to the
back to the story I wanted to see who'd
actually won these you know when these
skateboards so what did I picked out
Tony Hawk and then I ran the tweet the
the transform that I've written to pull
out the tweets of people he mentioned
here so these are all of my local
transforms get tweet one two and three
and date search between certain IDs and
pull out all of the tweets that had
either the word found in there or had
you know and at mentioned so Twitter
user names are at username so you can
pull them out with a regular expression
really easily and basically I display
those and discard everything else they
had written so I wasn't particularly
interested in what he'd had for
breakfast but I was interesting if he
was you know corresponding with someone
through Twitter so this is what it what
it ends up looking like so for example
one of those at one on the top left hand
corner that was found atlanta at you
know blah blah blah basically and that
would have been a similar story for each
of those so potentially in that set of
data are the people who will need
skateboards as you go a little bit
further and run the you know run more of
those transforms on a wider and wider
data set then you can start to see
relationships building between these
people who's spoken to who in this case
you'll see Tony's talked to a few people
and those people have also been people
that were hiding stuff so there's some
relationship obviously there and as you
go further than you know the map get
a little bit more complex if you you
know if you're looking at it closely top
right-hand corner to navigate again it's
a you know great way of tackling that
and you end up with one of these which
is a big graph I decided I'd have a bit
of a go at running more and more
transforms so I set off a you know a
transform on a big data set and went out
running about half way around late at
six mile loop it occurred to me that
this was all happening on some servers
in South Africa and they might be
getting a little bit pissed off so
around back home pretty quickly and saw
this and you can't do a lot with with a
map like that really so what you need to
do is prune that basically and you can
look for you can look for entities that
don't correspond of anybody else and
just cut them out so pruning your data
set is a you know sort of big activity
in a multi go but you can get that then
down and you can get a pretty nice graph
and here you can see you've got hiding
it it's the the dot at the top left hand
corner you've got Tony Hawk you've got
somebody following at hiding it you've
got somebody who Tony's mentioned and
you've got some car you know
correspondence between those two so
there's something going on there and you
can explore them and just end up with
the data set people who've been
communicating there's another view here
that you'll see in in multi go and just
to highlight where the lines are there
you can see pretty much the same sort of
thing again if you're looking at guess
you know right now you might be thinking
about how does the speed things up while
you apply edge waiting then you can see
essentially who are the who are the top
talkers in that Twitter event and here
you'll see Tony or hiding it in to run
case but you know what on earth if I've
been going on about well if you look at
look here then you'll see there's mean
as its of a guy Stephen Gill and missed
your own case well Jerome case you might
be scratching you had thinking what
your own case well I didn't even know he
had you know a Twitter account and this
guy was the guy that sent me the the
skateboard tiny hooks or right hand man
dude he's got a Twitter account he's
tweeting and and you know before I used
this this graph i didn't i didn't know
that it hadn't occurred to me to look so
if you're analyzing an event you can see
perhaps who are the most interesting
people at the event so you could apply
that here to you know to black out for
example or to DEFCON or what have you
and see maybe where the big bus was
without actually having to attend so you
know you don't need to be limited to to
Twitter you can just search you know
websites for fur names for example so
this is what the guy is a look like I
put that in so lessons learned they've
got three lessons learned the first one
which the perturbed guides really
instilled was plan what you're what
you're doing have an idea about how
you're going to go about it before you
go about it otherwise you can generate a
lot of a lot of mess the next thing if
you're using multi go is if you've got
this this setting here for speed and
accuracy if that bar is over to the left
you get less results so it's good for
testing out your transforms and when
you've got that working and you're happy
with it slide it across to the right and
if you're ever thinking I'm not getting
many results what's going on then it's
probably because you've got that bar
slid over to the to the left and the
third third sort of slide with lessons
learned is that these local transforms
you can apply these to a great deal more
than Twitter right you know you can
apply them in any context the guys that
but over there even analyze like
spider-man movie who's talking to you in
what the relationships are there if
you're in an enterprising you want to
use this perhaps
you know vulnerability testing fantastic
we'll have you consider the server
platform so you running transforms in
your own enterprise and if you're going
to explore Twitter then I'd seriously
recommend taking a look at applying for
white listing so did it help me get a
map saw sort of but not really my wife
was expecting our first child so what we
ended up doing was we you know we went
to the hospital waiting for the chap two
were to arrive took a bunch of printouts
and stuff like that and did it all by
hand in the end because I totally failed
and ran out of time but you could see
some of the relationships but this this
was what we ended up doing in the end so
I just wanted to come clean with that
but I don't know how many of you've seen
this because this is a similar concept
but using processing by a guy called
juror if you've not seen this go Google
around for just landed the concept here
was that people on Twitter you know
saying are you know I just landed in Las
Vegas wheels down Las Vegas you know
made it to Las Vegas or what have you so
what he did he analyzed he got the
Twitter profile of where they identified
the location use something called meta
Carter which pulls out the location and
gives you a geographical grid reference
so you know and looks at where they
landed where they said they're landed
whether you know saw whether where the
name was passed that through meta Carter
and got a grid reference map that in in
processing and generated this pretty
neat visual of where people were going
and flying to within within a data set
so i talked about multi go but you know
you can apply this with different tools
also with with twitter you know use the
the api stuff and i'll share this this
isn't digital equipment corporation it
said disasters emergency charity in the
in the UK and they were looking at
analyzing their social media activity
for the haiti disaster
they wanted to see how many tweets they
were making how many of those tweets
were being retweeted and stuff like that
so with those same API calls i was able
to apply that generate you know generate
these graphs but if you're looking at
that in a sort of more professional way
check out row feeder by a guy called
damon portese it's a really sweet
product so onto onto another use case
really probably focus a little bit more
on the Nigerian crime aspect here rather
than rather than multi multi go just but
uh this guy's pretty famous in in
Nigeria's wrote a song basically about
419 scamming called I go chop your
dollar and he's pretty popular so I got
involved with this because a friend lost
a laptop to a scam on a certain auction
site and wanted to well you know work
with the police and try and you know get
the laptop back basically well I don't
know how is in in the US but in the UK
the police are quite disjointed in their
approach to this sort of thing so
depending on who you call first your
crime log can get held up so if you ever
send anything to a legitimate dress
better to try and call the police in
that jurisdiction rather than your local
one I explain a little bit more so quick
disclaimer some of the names dates
images and stuff have been changed to
set well basically so they get bumped
off on the way home so this is my friend
who lost her lost her laptop she put it
on an auction site this actually
sequence of events is pretty pretty
common for scammers right now but I'm
sure they'll move migrate get a little
bit bit better it got bought quickly the
Buy Now price so
that sorts of may be a telltale giveaway
that you're about to get scammed she
exchanged emails with with the buyer and
it seemed okay at least the she'd
checked I should actually go on to check
that the address she was sending it to
was a valid address and it was so she
was in a little bit skeptical and then
she got a notification from paypal
except it wasn't from paypal at all and
then she got a notification for our she
sent the laptop to a valid address and
then she got notification that the
account that she had been dealing with
that the auction site had been
compromised you know so it was then that
it dawned on her that you know she'd
just sent this like expensive package to
a valid address and began panicking a
little bit and you know contacted the
police because you knew I worked in
security and had a relationship with
with the police locally she asked if
there's anything I could do to point her
in the right direction or point the
police in the right direction to people
that could help so another hypothesis as
I thought well if you've got the if
you've got the scammer dude and you've
got the address that they sent the
package to then should be possible to
get reacquainted with the laptop and
hopefully ensure that justice is is done
notice that there's no cake there so
first of all where is our scammer so my
initial thought was well the first thing
I want to do is is you know get the IP
address and see if they're based in the
UK or something like that so the trouble
was scammer users you know web-based
mail so getting headers was somewhat of
a challenge but I figured that this
might be a reasonable approach so you
can sign up for a free blog site with
with logs and post an image up there
let's say then you can send the spammer
an email as rather compelling email I
hey I've got this other laptop do you
want to check this out and embed that in
the email they click on the email and
essentially after some time you'll get
the you'll get the IP address from from
which it came now you might also want to
go and see Jeremiah Grossman talk
because I think he's talking about some
browser exploits that you can you can
use that'll pull out data from you know
from the sort of auto populate forum
thing go see his talk I've not seen it
but that's what I'm reading that will
give you things like first name last
name all sorts of interesting stuff so
we got the IP address but if you see
what he's doing maybe there's more you
can do and unsurprisingly the IP address
turned out to be in this place Lego sin
in Nigeria so it's like yeah okay that's
definitely it's come to a legitimate
address in the UK but whoever this
camera is his I'm a routing is traffic
through vegas or is there and i figured
that probably actually is there so we
had NS as the nigerian scammer he also
likes her american comedians and he was
going by the alias of Larry the Cable
Guy or something like that had an email
address and then we knew that the
package had gone to somebody called
Alice it was placed in a town in the UK
called Newcastle I don't know in the
u.s. if you've got a site like this but
192 dot com enables you to put in names
of people and it will give you the
addresses that they not only live up but
the previous addresses they've lived out
and a whole bunch more other information
so the thought would put the name of
that person in it will show that they
live at that address you know and who
else they live with and you know so job
done but it didn't work because the
person who was at that dress had
probably been been
been renting so you didn't get the you
know didn't get the real name so that
that approach initial approach failed
then figured well just some information
gathering on google see where these
people have got you know profiles so be
bone myspace and of course facebook
whole bunch of stuff out there so you
know there for well maybe have an
explorer with with multi go so this guy
here dominic white or at singe on
Twitter's wrote some really useful
facebook transforms for Marty go
Facebook have got it in their terms of
services you know not to do this I want
to be you know clear about that but he's
got some and they're published out there
written in Python using mechanizing
beautiful soup to you know interact with
with facebook so figured okay let's
let's take a look at that and we've got
three results back for Alice actually
we've got a whole lot more results back
for Alice but you don't need to to see
that because the purpose is really just
to show you the approach we took so but
which one is the real real ass well did
a transform of facebook to facebook
friends and saw you know that she had a
number of friends they all have a number
of friends and then it's like yeah but
which one's a real one let's take a look
at the location of those people so ran a
cobbled-together transform which
identified the location based on their
facebook profile as being here you'll
see that she had a lot of friends in
lagos and a lot of friends in
Newcastle's so it was a good chance that
that was going to be the person out of
all of the Alice's that we were you know
we were looking for so an awful lot of
stuff in the public profile as well see
if you actually get quite a lot of
information it certainly looked like
this was our man well I lady so at this
point I mentioned that you know
facebook Terms of Service do read them
there's this guy here Pete worden who's
done I don't know how many people are
familiar but this blew my mind actually
he built his own sore facebook profile
search engine which was used a hundred
machine cluster running Hadoop for about
ten dollars an hour and he crawled
Facebook this was I think maybe a year
and a bit ago something like that and
ended up obtaining 220 million profiles
from from facebook in about 10 hours
that cost him about one hundred dollars
so the ability to crawl and obtain vast
data sets is is has never really been
been easier but he ran into a lot legal
trouble with with Facebook and they're
pretty clear so really the talk is aimed
at sharing this particular we
particularly with folks in law
enforcement who'd be able to you know
approach Facebook legitimately to do
these kinds of searches so don't go and
do this without asking nicely and bless
you want to get on the wrong end of
Facebook he'll think you're a little bit
more a little bit more thoroughly than
nigerian scammers even in terms of
following up so yeah he got 220 million
which boggled my mind really did all
sorts of announces with it check out
Pete wardens website and you can see
some of the some of the stuff he's done
they're amazing so okay so information
available to all so if folks have got
you know you guys probably know this
they're previously set to everybody then
bingo you're in you can crawl pretty
much anything fascinating and lots of
people do that if not you can only do so
much without being a friend sort of so
how do we get to the the good stuff in
people's profiles well there's a couple
of ways you can approach this so the
social zombies talk that's been at
DEFCON
you Connor and whatnot you can create
bad applications facebook applications
and get people to use them and then you
can use Facebook query language pretty
well too you know obtain this data so
there's at least two talks on the social
zombies topic you know go and check them
out for ideas or you could make friends
with people and then adopt singes
approach with Python and mechanized and
for that one see Satan is on your your
friends list and actually there's a talk
later this afternoon think by Tom Ryan
might give some good ideas you know as
well or you can follow this guy on
Twitter he's got a website's well the
Harmony guy you know he's identified you
know number of floors over the last year
what you know with Facebook but if
you're smart there's you know there's
probably other ways you can you know
approach it so I opted for an easy
approach of sort just making some new
friends really so the idea here is that
you'd create a credible account and
again take a look at the talk a bit
later on tonight for maybe more about
how you're doing that and then build up
your identity slowly so you've got you
know something credible some
interactions on your wall photos and
stuff like that don't go directly for
your target because they'll be like how
somebody's trying to friend me who's got
nothing on there you know for facebook
profile and they've got no friends so
the approach is really joined sort of
groups university schools similar to
once at your target has got friends of
friends and then finally home in on on
your target if they've got over a
thousand friends and a lot of people
have then basically they're easy and
their friend anyone so they're great
targets I also found that
demographically at least between the UK
Nigeria Nigerians at least that I made
friends with were a lot more eager to
become friends and people
in the UK and take your time so i think
the talk tonight will show how this was
done over like 28 days I didn't have 28
days so and I wasn't really that
bothered about being noisy or not so I
basically went through all that in about
two hours and it still worked much to my
surprise so if you're impatient like me
can can work so you can automate this as
well if you've seen the tool imacros by
I opus it was in Michael strengths
talked last year don't have a look at it
it's brilliant but you need to be
careful on how quickly you're adding
friends and stuff like that especially
like on Twitter because if you see
something adding friends at a rapid rate
of knots and you'll get your account
suspended and you have to wait for ages
and then you'll have no friends when you
get back and stuff like that so so okay
making friends you know with people on
facebook so this was this was one of the
responses i got at which point i thought
i've been busted basically so I said I'm
a friend of Alice's just getting started
with facebook because I didn't have a
lot on there I might have added a few
too many people something sorry and and
that was it basically yeah well you know
alice is my best friend so you know
we're cool brilliant so you know that
was pretty much how it went only a few
people ever came back and said hey do I
actually know you and you know usually
yeah that worked most of the time or you
could see parties that had been to on
their Facebook profiles and whatnot so
yeah I was at this party but I was a
little bit drunk so I might got your
name wrong so this was how went about
getting a map of interesting people's
get the friends in you know this is
essentially the pseudocode for you know
running you're running your sort of
multi go approach get the location if
the location is
of Nigeria Lagos in a bunch of other
Nigerian places then scrape or past the
the wall posts download them download
photos if the wall posts containing
trusting phrases and you you know you
get to see a lot of those then download
those and if there if they you know
basically tick any of those flags and
pipe them back into timati go and add
them to the to the map so like we did
with the Tony Hawk thing where we just
wanted to tweets where he said you know
and his name we just wanted the
interesting people back from from multi
go that may have had something to do
with being a nigerian scammer so you
know this is essentially what it looks
like get friends of people you'll see a
big map start to emerge you do that
multiple times you end up with something
a little bit more like this the bigger
dots are more interesting so you do a
bit of pruning that we mentioned the
small box at the bottom of the UK people
and you end up with a relationship that
looks a little bit more like this so the
big dots are the major players they're
all interconnected around the the edge
and connected between themselves and
then they got people that they connect
to in the middle so the idea here is
that you can then start drilling down on
these people and exploring further so
he'd get interesting facebook updates
like 7k in five days which is kind of
interesting you know and looking through
the profile tits it's easy to see that
these guys are you know living living a
high life out there in in Nigeria and
who can blame them with fast money and
fast chicks and stuff like that they had
lots of photos a little bit like this
one that's not actually a ps3 but you
know you get the idea on their wall
posts and what have you and they're very
keen on sharing their
you know their wins let's say lots of
pictures of Western Union celebrating
with with champagne and what have you
more screenshots of stuff on western
union seems to be popular with nigerians
nigerian scammers i should say because
you know that wouldn't be fair on the
rest so that it's compelling why do they
do it you can see that they can make an
awful lot of money here 700 to six
thousand dollars this was a facebook
profile as well a wall post yeah let's
go scam more people these guys are
communicating on Facebook very openly
and you know communicating with each
other so how about something a little
bit more dodgy well there were pictures
a little bit like this although not like
this because if you google you know a
duffel bag with money then you'll see
where it got the image from but there
were similar images let's say some of
the images might looks a little bit more
like this so you know they got all of
this one you saw publicly available you
can go and check that out quite quite
easily on on their Facebook profiles
more more wealth so then things got a
little bit more dodgy and that's when I
thought well actually maybe I'll stop
digging around and just leave this up to
the professionals they had they had
pictures of guns not this gun but they
had pictures of guns with the people who
are in that you know sort of facebook
profile so you could see names and faces
stuff like that was like oh that looks a
bit serious so obvious question in my
mind was well are there links with
terror so I did some digging around and
if you're interested in Nigerian crime a
really interesting company ultra scan
advanced global international based out
of Amsterdam they do a lot of research
into this sort of thing got a lot data
on it and they've got a 2009 report
about scamming go and check it out what
they did actually identify direct
relationships between 419 advance fee
frauds and you know
and antara before there was only
indirect sort slipstream money now
there's you know direct links so okay
the true identity of our scammer let's
say I was to set up an email address
that was similar to the the person who
obtained a laptop in the UK send out a
note saying hey you know this is this is
Alice this is my new email address would
you believe it facebook is acting weird
can you descend me a wall post because I
figured that you know with all of the
people that she was friends with that be
one of them would be our our man Larry
the Cable Guy so to my great surprises
like yeah sure so so message back saying
thanks hot stuff why not and he then
said as a bonus say hi to you know xxxxx
so Oh bonus because I've seen pictures
of Alice with xoxxxx I didn't know they
were together the conversation continued
a little bit more and it seemed like he
does more of the dealing with xxs and
you know then then then with this Alice
so I was a bonus really so got a
facebook update like this which was very
similar to this but you know but not
this I was a amazing one of that worked
brilliant so now we've got some more
connections you've got connection now
between Alice and thus Cameron Nigeria
which we didn't have before so this was
of course interesting to the police who
you know how'd anecdotal evidence or had
an idea that this was happening me but
didn't have anything to actually tie or
you know together so then they had this
link with this UK scammer who was also
you know closely related to Alice and so
what that actually happened is you've
got well let me show you on the next
slide really you've got scammin networks
so organized slightly you've got 62
scammer networks in the UK alone
according
the ultra scan international 419 report
and what they have is sounds potentially
a bunch of light cells in different
countries who will then work with local
people and use them as places where they
you know sort of ship their their goods
to valid addresses and they'll just you
know use this people and then burn them
out and get more people that's kind of
how it works Spain's got the highest
number of scamming networks with 72 and
the USA trailing with 53 but don't feel
bad about that folks from the USA
because you've got more than double the
amount of people than anybody else
you've got about 2,300 people make up
those 53 sort of crime cells so places
we had lots of Nigerian university
societies things like that probably
great places for targeting people you
are 916 of these around the world
sixteen thousand members and the raking
about 9.3 billion dollars in 2009 so
it's big business people are falling for
it all the time and there's all sorts of
different scams romance scams people
fall for that a lot cars that kind of
thing so okay so you've got the scammer
you've got the person that this went to
in the UK you've got a whole bunch of
information the police can't really do
anything because they've got stuff that
they you know they seen on facebook and
difficult to prosecute and not so
interested in you know the people at the
end so how do you get your money back
basically well what you could do I
suppose hypothetically is you could pile
all of the information that you've found
and put it in a blog post and also
create maybe a facebook fan site and
encourage all of their friends to join
and I mentioned that a you know email
alert the scammers and say hey go just
let you know I set this up and you know
in a couple of days time or something
Google bit of in dates this and you'll
never get rid of it very easily you
could do that right hypothetically and
then you could follow up with a call i
don't know about the US but in the UK
you can just buy a sim cards with cash
and Agrium amicable
terms you know that could work so okay
yeah we want to give you some money back
it's been a little misunderstanding
that's uh you know how do you get the
scammers dollars into your bank well
cash obviously is going to be tricky
because where are you going to exchange
the cash oh yeah meet me here yeah just
be me and don't bring anybody else
especially not those people with guns
because they kind of scare me and then
bank well what do you do the bank give
them your bank account details not so
smart probably paypal again that would
be linked to an individual not a great
idea Western Union you're going to have
to give them a name or a fake ID or
something not a great idea probably the
only one on that list that make any
sense if you were to do which I must
stress I didn't would be amazon gift
certificates because you can get them
then email to like just an email address
and nobody's any of your wiser job done
you know you're limited to was it five
hundred dollars or something like that
that'd probably be the only way you go
to a scammer and say actually here's how
it like my money back or you could say
just go to the police and hand by the
laptop we don't have the laptop so
health warnings yeah i wouldn't
recommend do it or completely you know
anonymize this if you are going to do it
are you limited to generally to public
information read the Terms of Service
because they Facebook are very tight on
that wealth of information but they're
very tight so really law enforcement or
if you're you know in a corporation go
through legitimate channels you know
tough friend up with your own account at
your own risk you'd need to be nuts to
do that really but then setting up the
second account would also be a violation
of terms of service so you perhaps
wouldn't want to do that either so maybe
you could convince another friend who
just happens to you know live in the
same house as you have a different name
to do that work with law enforcement and
keep on the right side of you know where
things are at and if you wanted to do
any of that you'd have to break terms of
service so
you know so wrapping up the talk mining
data has got more accessible than ever
before visualization can help you home
in that's the key point really because
you might be sitting here thinking why I
can do all this stuff anyway but it's
going to help you home in on interesting
relationships and finally things like
you know getting the metadata or named
entity recognition that can help you
really classify information combination
of those three is going to speed things
up so like I say took me a couple of
hours to get a bunch of friends took a
couple of hours to you know pull down a
bunch of information see where the
interesting pictures were you know go
back dive down into those link you know
keep building it of the the network
following these people this is all on
the you know the on the CD and I'll put
it on the website as well tryn to multi
go perturbed obviously singe mobic sand
carmel ownage these guys are pretty into
multi go social network folks Tom East
and he's not here digi ninja they those
guys did social zombies the Harmony guy
I mentioned with he did like a month of
Facebook vulnerabilities last year and
social media security those are great
people to follow and to you know to
check out and then data mining
visualization you've got Damon Cortez he
needs a guy that does row feeder and
what have you've got Neil cotton and I
don't know if anybody has ever used
Twitter and put in anything that's
mentioned Full Metal Jacket well if you
do that then you get the drill sergeant
from full metal jacket coming back at
you with some aggressive language and
you know made me laugh actually out loud
and he's the guy behind that and as a
bunch of other data mining stuff and
then Pete worden the guy who you know
nearly got nearly got served by Facebook
and escape that by the skin of his teeth
some great stuff there so that's about
all i've got to say about that except
i've got a signed tony hawk skateboard
here and don't want to take it home so
you know I don't know how should I do
this really you know I mean hands up
who's on Twitter he roars we've got the
ability to get on Twitter I mean yeah
should I give it him for asking nicely
what do you think what what was so that
show hamster says yeah give it him
that's like three I'll hide it somewhere
you'll have to follow me at the at the
sub meister on on twitter yeah i'll hide
it somewhere it's going today i'll tweet
it out at some point in the next couple
of hours and have at it people thanks so
many questions