so I'm taste opportunity to thank
b-sides champion for having me along and
also take the opportunity to say anyone
here from NCSC thank you very much I've
been working with a lot of small
entities very recently and they've been
Dossi understand the whole what I asked
me on getting involved in as well so the
feedback from the ground level guys who
really try to defend their businesses or
even just themselves they really need
that direction so the stuff that NCS you
are doing I just want to take that
opportunity so thank you very much for
that so I'm Matt Heinz and I'm here to
give you a introduction to threat
intelligence this year I've been going
to a number of other b-sides events and
I've been providing a workshop titled
wTF is CGI or cyber threat intelligence
I'll use the term cyber threat
intelligence and threat intelligence
synonymously throughout this
presentation like I personally feel that
CGI exists within the wider threat Intel
and you have a fiscal element as well
but that's one of the presentation so I
did the workshop with the intention to
tell the community what I feel
threat intelligence should be I have a
perception that there is a incorrect
understanding of what it is from either
a lack of understanding what
intelligence should be and also maybe
what's being given from a marketing
perspective so I gave the workshop in
trying to give my view on what it should
be to help the community so we think
intelligence we have to think military
intelligence so you probably can't read
at the back what we've got here is some
perceptions what strangest think I do a
guy with a an assault rifle on my family
thinks I do a bunch of screens in a
command center James Bond what my
recruiter said I would do Jason Bourne
what Hollywood thinks I do what I think
I do presenting to generals to stars etc
but in reality what I actually do is I
do PowerPoint so what your perceptions
hopefully some of you saw the agenda and
and knew this was up and maybe you
already have some perceptions of what
threat intelligence
is maybe you just think it's another
acronym certainly a lot of them in our
industry maybe just a marketing
buzzwords something to actually get hold
of your budget and spend something maybe
it's just googling maybe you got some
threat Intel analysts who just kind of
go on google and tell you bad stuff is
happening somewhere doing something
maybe it's repeating news personally
this is something that I've got a bit of
a bug about I often see people
presenting or providing intelligence and
all that kind of telling me is something
that I would read in the news so a hack
has happened somewhere and this is
what's happened very high-level that's
just news that's not really intelligence
doesn't allow me to do anything and
we'll go into in a bit maybe it's just a
threat Intel feed maybe it's pointless
bio C's because got a nice small
audience I'll try make a little bit
interactive so do feel free to two inch
at any point on that point is anyone
here who just purely has a threat
intelligence feed into their environment
very cool so so I see that quite a lot I
certainly see things like Google's DNS
being a bad bio see the realities is an
indicator it can be an indicator but on
its own doesn't necessarily means benign
but from the workshop what I found
actually most of all people didn't
actually have an idea they didn't
actually have any perceptions they
didn't really know what threat
intelligence was which gives me sort of
two things from that one is that's great
we can build on that and there's an
understanding or this is a want to know
what it is so we can we can work with
that
and the other takeaway that I had in the
the workshops that I was doing is people
wanted to know more so the workshops for
two hours basically was an introduction
it's coming the bits we're going to talk
about today but it also did some
exercises and tried to get me start
thinking like an analyst an intelligence
analyst but also a little bit of social
security research and hunting
capabilities and in that two hours
people said it just wasn't enough so and
the other day what's the whole point of
this what's the benefits to me my
organization its knowledge injection or
also not just 19 Jackson but your
hypothesis is injected into your team
well why is that you're getting to
direct the forces so you've got your
sock guys or get the incident responders
or your your penetration to your red
teaming or or your forensics guys you're
helping them to actually look at the
most likely avenues of threats not to
waste time that actually is not really
applicable to your organization you get
to really focus on something so in this
in relation to an incident response if
you're guys something just gotten bang
and everyone's hands on deck in the
tryna understand what's going on time is
a big issue you want to actually get
them looking in the right location and
in a particular piece of malware a
particular attack to focus on what's
actually applicable and ultimately what
you're doing is you're reducing their
time to recovery that's one of the key
benefits of threat Intel to your IR team
but that's tactical intelligence I'll
talk about that in a moment
you have a couple of other areas
operational and strategic and that's
helping with the preemptive stance of a
force things gone bang
you'll be injected with knowledge and
understanding a theory on likely threats
and you actually put in the right
controls you spending the right money in
a time and the effort and the limited
resources we all have in the right
places ten times multiplier hmm threaten
tell is definitely a force multiplier
it's there to actually feed into other
teams on its own doesn't require any
value but with other teams enhances
those teams there's a paper that came
out or maybe it was a sales go up blurb
that basically did say it's up to ten
times not sure I quite agree with that
volume but I certainly do think it's
multiples so therefore threat Intel is a
team sport and when the analyst
intelligence analyst try to communicate
with your other the wider teams or vice
versa
let's not have that us have more of this
okay so I'm Matt Haines I work for Sky
Blu
I have roughly about 15 years of IT
experience I started from the ground
picking up a call I was and reset
passwords going right through to working
in the CTO department for a government
body if you want to follow me I'm always
ranting on mr. MD Haines
and I didn't actually say
during this presentation I'm happy for
pictures to be taken there's a couple of
models coming up and and other bits so
quite have to have photos taken so
intelligence what is it we got our raw
data like could be our network traffic
it could be just packets on that what
we're sniffing what we need to do with
that is we need to actually parse it and
understand it and process it once we've
processed it we actually then have
information we can then start
understanding what's going on and the
information element is kind of when you
start seeing it in newspapers we need to
take that and when you start analyzing
it we just start asking ourselves or so
what why is that applicable to me what
does that actually mean and the best way
I can describe intelligence is imagine
you have a puzzle you don't have all the
pieces of the puzzle we start to put
them out you can already start to
hypothesize and what that picture might
be maybe it's a picture of London maybe
it's a Red Bus
you don't need all the pieces to say
well clearly that's going to be a bus
and you can have a degree of likeliness
on how many pieces you have this is the
intelligent life cycle you start with
the direction so maybe the boss the
manager the general whoever is basically
said I want you to do something crack on
something as high as defend the
organization is a bit too fluffy it
doesn't really help constrain your
investigation but something like tell me
about eMeter how is that a threat to me
you can start to drill down into that so
the first thing you do with that is you
go and get all the articles you go and
understand what Emmet has been up to
you're going read papers from other
people maybe get a piece of malware on
your analyzer or send it to your reverse
engineers and they understand it and
they supply you with some information
and once you've got all that when you to
analyze it so what we want to do is look
at the evolution we might look at
previous campaigns previous waves and
think okay that's what they were doing
the past that's what they're doing now
so where they likely to be in the future
but once you've done that once you've
analyzed at all great you've got some
intelligence it doesn't do anything
until you tell it to someone that's when
you've got disseminate it so a lot of
the time we generally get that is papers
I know one Germany has that much time
to read a 30-page document what
sometimes you have alternative avenues
to disseminate that intelligence so it
might be a case of an audio file it
might be a funky diagram it also could
be just walking over to your sock and
just saying we've had this intelligence
and it could be a one-liner once you've
fed that into your your your wider team
they have a better understanding they
start to narrow and you'll continue to
iterate through so the intelligence
journey breaking down three areas
operational tactical and strategic
operational intelligence the way I see
it is generally your day to day
activities something has just happened
in the news something that's just
occurred from some organization you then
need to analyze it and go okay how is
that applicable to me and how do I feed
that into the general day-to-day
activities and keep processing it
tactical something just gone bang I
didn't really think people take this as
the IR situation instant response one of
the big lessons or one of the big
exercises or qualification did you get
in in CTI
is sand four five seven eight they very
much focus on tactical but for my
experience and organizations none really
ever does that I do either operational
or maybe to a lesser extent strategic
and strategic is what you probably
envision it's the long-term view so what
you want to do there is you actually
have a good understanding of where the
threats are today maybe where they've in
the past but sort of looking in the
future and as far as you can with that
so when you're supplying strategic
intelligence maybe to the sea so and
above they need enough time to be able
to absorb and read that and react upon
it so we're not talking generally a
month or so we're talking months and
months or it's not over a year as an
example if you think about it if I said
to a C's oh we've seen this these guys
knocking off front door we're but defend
against them at a moment we like current
controls however they know they're not
winning so they're going to evolve and
if they evolve what do they have to do
to get around our defenses they know
this we can work this out
so they can use this type of probable
attack in the future so the CT so the
CCC so you has to get that understanding
absorbed that Intel and then react upon
it they might skim across budget wait
for the budget get sign-off pass it to
the program manager a project manager
architect who then designs sends off the
procurement gets the kit wait for that
to come in get it built get it configure
go through change control get it
operational that could take in large
organization six months eighteen months
quite easily so talk about couple of
methodologies so we talked about the
intelligence lifecycle principles and
controls when we're producing
intelligence we want to utilize these
principles now this can sometimes vary
and where you've been schooled in an
Intel compute
there's no point providing a
intelligence report that's kind of
half-finished it needs to be accurate
it's really really easy to lose
confidence if something is slightly
wrong and it takes a long time to build
up that confidence especially from an
Intel perspective and timeliness so if
it mentioned that from a strategic point
even if you gave a report to a C so
about a new control and you gave them
two months it might not be enough time
objective so don't let it be by us try
to actually include other people in your
wider team and just say you know am I am
I actually being biased on this is this
a few actually realistic and trying to
other views usable give it to people who
can actually do something with it so
that strategic report no point giving it
to your sock guys because they yes you
need to know about what's happening
today and tomorrow but then you don't
want to go give a yar overall to your
seaso because they're not going thing
with it and in relevance no point
talking about a particular technology or
a threat to a technology when you don't
run that technology so just think about
the relevance and of course with the
when the actual produced of the content
needs to be clear if you relevant this
be utilized brevity so to get straight
to the point
I think about security so if you're
writing something of intense purely or
something so clearly that's going to be
something of interest to you do you want
the attacker to know that that you're
interested in that and in ease of
assimilation so that's the dissemination
part
a large document might not always be the
easiest way to disseminate so the
probability yardstick and the words
estimated probability this is basically
how we sort of communicate that
likeliness it's pretty can you read that
on the back Kwasi yeah I don't need to
explain that I think that's pretty much
self-evident so when you get hold of a
written tell report when you read it
just be mindful that when they use words
and terminology is that's part of their
assessment so when they say something's
going to happen then like it's a is
likely probable etc and then there's a
NATO grading or the Admiralty code
system so when you read social media
tweets or something online hopefully the
majority of Isis ago well that's yes or
no maybe that's kind of right and that's
how we grow our sources do many more of
human activity so for example Shipman
walks in tells me something's just
happen around the corner I don't know
this guy I have no idea who he guess our
grade him as an f6 if Donald Trump said
that he could have gone by the NHS I
would probably grade him maybe a d3
maybe a one alright
so cuz you've got a nice little group
I'll actually make it a little more
interactive who kind of a one's hand up
a second everyone put a hand up a second
cool right put your hand down if they
know what awesome is if you don't know
what is
okay complete hands down now right
Sigyn who knows my second is someone
shout out cool go some scaly backs in
the room human human intelligence yeah
document who do you know what that one
is
no social media yeah absolutely so it's
kind of a sub under awesome maybe maybe
not I don't know if I agree I'd say it's
more closed-source taken people don't
know this one so technical or
intelligence let's say maybe you're
maybe in Israeli or US body and you want
to know how a nuclear reactor works or
centrifuge that's taken yeah do you know
how something works
pyaare or ir s-- anyone no realize
[Music]
awesome yep so that's kind of like what
Emily what the commander wants to know
what the boss wants to know that's
that's crucial okay as an intelligence
operators you need to know what the boss
wants to know it's really going to tell
you but if it doesn't tell you all she
might tell you are you gonna work it out
and the last thing you wanna do is going
to tell the attack of it because if the
attacker knows that they might go oh
that's interesting or maybe focus on
that or maybe they'll start sending red
herrings to to cause problems with that
ml's coa MDC la yeah absolutely yeah
most likely most dangerous course of
action well what does that mean so
absolutely yeah so who can think of some
normal organizations what might be the
most likely course of action from a
threat yeah I completely agree with you
phishing is probably one of them and
then most dangerous or deadly yeah yeah
so and I pass I mean it depends on the
organization it might be different to
where you where you work the personnel
say phishing most likely most dangerous
putting insiders what I would go with
Styx
you think that's a lot just put it in
there it's just basically a format that
they utilize for sharing information
intelligence and then IPB intelligence
preparation of the battlefield I've only
really seen that in the military space I
kind of do that when I go into an
organization I want to know what the
attack surface is what technologies they
have understand where we currently lay
or lay the land in the military space
what you do is you'd have a map of the
ground and then you actually line them
up where the rivers are and whether you
can actually talk move things and where
the tanks are etc can't the same thing
but from the cyber domain it's great
work who's it for
once again we're doing all this type of
activity we're not the benefits are but
who is it for everyone quite frankly so
it's you empowering decision-makers
that's what you're doing and the sock
are going to be responded to phishing
emails from the user they're going to be
reacting a comment alerts so for example
I've seen it before
if you know about ma tête I believe is
eMeter when it performs a c2 connection
it actually replies about the 404 now if
you don't know that you actually might
look at logs and go we've not been
affected because the server's in the ARP
and we're getting a 404 but in Tallaght
we don't know very well but actually is
what it does so you might want to tell
the male reverse engineer so you might
we'll tell the IR team about that so be
stuff instant responders absolutely need
to notice all way up through to see
those sees those need to know what's
going on because they need to actually
help the plan and prepare for the
controls okay so knowing the enemy and
know yourself I I personally feel that
threat intelligence is all about sort of
security research and understanding the
threat and that's why I absolutely do it
I actually love it so I'm learning from
the attackers as they evolve I try to
get to know them better than they know
themselves as an example we had a large
financial organization we kept seeing
these guys knocking on our front door
most of our controls were Germany
blocking them along that attack type
chain kill chain sorry but what we did
is we looked at them and what the
motives were and how they're evolving
what they're utilizing and they were
doing a lot of crime as a service and
then we started look at well who were
they using and how they evolving and
again then they know that are failing
they're not being successful so they go
talk to evolve they've got to utilize
new types of attacks so what we did is
we hypothesized and predicted
successfully two months of what I did
that start utilizing tor for C 2's so
they give us two months head notice or
start putting in new rules to detect
that type of activity and that's kind of
where this is all from knowing yourself
is another thing I don't know anyone who
matches a really good asset management
system but you're very much reliant on
your your wider teams your blue team's
your architects etc to have that you can
get that entire piece we're in a good
state so conscious about
I've rushed a little bit but there's
three things I'd like you guys to take
away from this the first is threat
intelligence is more than a food it
sounds though that the room that's kind
of not the issue which is great that
definitely seems to be an issue I've
noticed in the community where I've been
meeting people recently and that's been
very detrimental to the threat Intel
community they've received feeds they
haven't got good results they've been
responding to things that are completely
benign and they've been ignoring things
that may be a bit too specific so please
take that away the second thing is this
is not news so news is great but just
have an understanding news is the point
where you start from and they need to
hypothesize off that go why I was like
relevant to me why is that important
where do i evolved from that whether the
threat evolved from there and then the
third thing is empower others it's a
team sport it needs to empower the other
teams if it doesn't do that it kind of
fails in itself so that's the third and
final thing so generally expect better
yeah cool right okay I got link thank
you very much