[Music]
okay thank you for thank you for waiting
and I'm happy to see you see you all
here
yes and I guess I will need to hurry up
for and not be boring so the the the
title of my presentation is these are
the droids you're looking for
to be honest I was really on offense to
how to call these presentations is it
I found in bug report is it Android
it is hard but I hope this works
my name is erina Cavatina I work for
Google and I'm currently part of
Google's internal detection and response
team working with digital forensics and
it's Incident Response but over my over
11 years in Google I've worked with
multiple project dealing with anti-abuse
security malware in Google so basically
over the over this time if it's bad and
it's it's targeting Google or Google's
products I probably worked with it
very modest as for my passion for
Android I've been analyzing Android
malware for over five years as an
Android security analyst my phobia is
reading Android bug reports for fun
because I have no life for for all the
people around me I'm that Android person
also somebody somebody called neurons
and working at some point but it never
took off and and what am I gonna gonna
be talking talking about today well all
start about to just hit hitting the
common ground trying to understand what
is Android anyway we will move into app
level security because I'm because we
will be mostly talking talking about
performance on an on a device I will
probably mention a bit about about a bit
about root
I will introduce you super sophisticated
tools that I use in my everyday work and
then we will move on straight straight
into the thing the exciting things that
a humble bug report can tell and
probably will find also some some things
that you will never find in bug reports
and may and if you have time will maybe
work on some practical examples and if
you are like me is person with 30
30-second attention span you probably
want to have something to have your
hands on while you're listening or not
listening so I prepared for you a folder
with goodies honestly it's not malware
so here's the link I'll also the it this
link will also be on most of the slides
you can go to the - to the folder where
I prepared some bug reports for you to
take a look at I will be I will be later
showing you things about them and there
are also some handy cheat sheets that
you that that you can take take with you
and let's yeah I like putting putting
this warning on after this talk you
might actually become that Android
person person patoot to whom everybody
runs for advice because believe me I've
been answering I've been answering
questions for my friends family and
neighbors and neighbors neighbors about
androids about what's going on on
Android device and now I'm kind of as a
as I'm as I moved into Google's internal
security team I answer it for all of
Google so so what are those questions
that I that I answer on well almost
daily basis well not every day actually
yeah one question why is this app trying
to send a text message well it was a
system a system worrying that but you
but the user got confused because who
knows what happens on that black box
called Android
how did suddenly an app got on the
device when the user did not install it
that was a real case well app was pushed
by system level or cheese or tea service
it wasn't nice or what the hell actually
happens because sometimes because
sometimes users that really really get
confused as to what actually happened it
happens on happens on device happens on
the screen why is the device suddenly
vibrating or losing battery or losing or
all other stuffs and basically the
crucial question is is my phone heckard
and to answer and to answer that of
course I'm kind of always happy to take
a look at the phone to just to see what
to see what you see what's happening
there to break it a bit well like like
every like everybody I guess in this
room I like breaking stuff but when you
actually helping it want to help users
break in the breaking the device by
breaking breaking into it is kind of not
nice because you want to want to want to
the device to stay useful but but if you
want to ghost won't want to go step by
step onto on to being able to diagnose
problems on problems on device which
sometimes does not belong to you and
sometimes it's not even geographically
here crucial knowledge is is to know
what an app can an app do on Android and
what are all those and the underground
and the water current occurrence that
that are present in place on Android how
we can monitor devise a device in real
time in in real time just to look under
the Android under the hood a bit how
much information you can get out of
Android device without roots
or result without access to device
itself actually and yeah as I look at my
slides now I got another question to
myself when I was when I was making
those slides is it actually an iPhone on
the slide but all right let's let's
let's let's move on and first take a
look at Android at Android system as
such I guess who here never never ever
came across any Android device ever no
nobody okay so it's at least at least
everybody knows work everybody knows
Android so basically basically Android
is based on Linux scanner kernel which
[Music]
and on we on this on this level it deals
with Hardware of a device a hardware
level level in Android is actually very
important and very challenging because
as Android is currently running on
phones tablets cars TVs my treadmill
runs Android I'm not kidding you so this
is this is immense amount of hardware to
adjust the system to so so so the
architecture of the system supports
supposed to be supposed to be able to be
flexible enough and secure enough at the
same time to in order to deal with this
this diversity of different of different
hardware hardware so as we move up the
stack through the hardware abstraction
levels through nativeness through native
libraries and and all the way to the to
the android rounds and where where apps
were apps run and if we look at even
even and even directories of on android
device are similar to single to linux
system it depends on the device
massively but certain but certain
folders are mandatory no Android device
can function without them and it's all
very similar to Linux apart from one
thing which
which I will be will be talking a bit
later and and with all that we're the
apps well apps are all sitting in there
nice and boxes in Android runtime and
crucial crucial part of Android is not
only all the apps are running in their
own runtime but every app is treated as
a separate user of the system with it's
all privileges and it's all and it's all
access levels and if we talk about about
an athame of android tablets it's
simplistic model is the app basically
consists of four decks code manifests
and resources and Android manifests is
crucial because this is where all that
app can do is defined and here here are
the key terms which which I will be
operating talking about Android apps
which are permissions in turns brought
broadcasts and activities from basic
basically permissions many people most
people probably know about the concept
of permissions is there is the absolu
quest to access certain api's and
they're not not granted they are not
necessarily always granted interns is a
message that that a data protocol quest
actions from component of an app and
activities our main building blocks and
broadcasts is the way apps communicate
basically intense is the is what the app
intends two days hence the name
activities is what the app actually does
permissions is what the app is allowed
to do and broadcast is how how the app
is communicating about it and if you
look at this simple classification of
app of apps that you will find an
Android device those will be system apps
which will be in system directory
they are normally pre-installed and part
of in part of the system
can have very privileged access to
devices key features and they normally
cannot be cannot be removed by anything
other than other than flash flashing
device with new system or with system
update user apps those among those most
common apps that sit into the data
partition and they can be pre-installed
or installed on by user itself
they are basically very limited and and
they access is limited by granted
permissions and I'd like to mention the
route apps because they are those are
apps that rely on presence of root user
but that's the thing about Android that
by default most of majority hopefully
hopefully there should be all
out-of-the-box user devices don't do not
have prote user and that is done for a
reason because with big big power and
root is very powerful on Android with
big power comes big responsibility and
mobile devices turn into breaks really
nicely but even without even without
without root system some system apps are
pretty overpowered for example this is
our favorite favorite over power system
app called Google Play Store which has
which has a service called Google Play
protect which is pretty much it's a very
old system I'm I'm delighted to be part
of this part of this product for six
years
it's the built in an type of perfect
Asian service it used to be actually
called verify apps but it's it was
rebranded as play protect a couple of
years ago so basically what it does it's
it has the power over apps that no other
app even anti-malware app like and
mobile antivirus has because it can
block installation of apps that are
known to be harmful it periodically
periodically scans and
some harmful apps and for absolute
cannot remove it disables them so that
it they just sit there doing nothing and
probably you surprised how it can be
super powerful but not being able to be
able to remove well unfortunately
sometimes in very rare rare occasions
there is something not very good in
system directories of some devices of
some manufacturers and as I already
explained system apps cannot be cannot
be just removed even even by a Google
Play Project which is the system but not
a rota and I'm really hopeful that 99%
of users will never actually will never
actually even know that play protect is
there because you will only know about
it if there is something bad and on on
the phone present and 99% of users well
normal users not not crazy users like me
who just find small or everywhere they
will never see any notification from
play protect with that in mind a bit
lurks about the rule about the root as I
said root is very powerful and sometimes
people have a have a good a good reason
to use root for for example people that
that are power users of Android that
want to do to tweak with the system
itself play with the OS with different
features even develop and introduce new
features to their to their OS there are
basically there are basically good and
bad ways to root the device good way is
for people that like just like play
playing with the OS and for search and
geekery Android being very developer
friendly there is a way to flash flash a
customer own unlock a bootloader and
flash a custom ROM on the device which
has root user
but even then no please know what you do
in and
hope it's not your favorite phone don't
do it in your main phone and something
that is kind of a bad way of a bad bad
way of routine is are using routine apps
and exploits because most routine apps
just use routine exploits so they will
be by every anti-malware this service
including Google Play project they will
be treated as malicious and one and also
for for user devices once for most
manufacturers once you break the
security model by by routing device you
kind of on your own like it's instant
void of warranty and if you break the
device it's yours so please don't please
don't do that but luckily for most of
the users there is no need to root the
device and for for research researchers
and responders and for instigators like
me there are plenty of ways to get at
least some data from a device without
relying on on overstepping the
boundaries of the system and for and
getting back to the question of
compromised devices or devices with
strange behavior present and users
freaking out not not knowing what to do
what is happening for for a researcher
for the researcher the first question
would be how to get into it and how to
get logs which will be challenged what
is actually happening there well here is
my super favorite and super
sophisticated tool set that allows to do
to do most of the stuff for security
research it's basic I'm really happy
that Android SDK actually and SDK tools
are not only for development they
provide very very useful tool set that
can be can be used for development but
can it be also used for debugging for
monitoring for tracking network activity
for for for jumping memory vitiate which
is which is useful when when you're
trying to understand what the hell is
happening in the black box
ah but also bad news first
unfortunately most of the blocks on
Android are not easy to get even if you
even if it's your own device even if
even if you have full access to it
pulling some file databases and logs
from your own device it's kind of
relatively easy but if it's someone
else's you're likely out of luck
especially if that someone else is not
is not cooperating then probably you're
and from from and from a locked-down
Android device which is in which is
encrypted by default and there is no
decryption key you pretty much will be
better off just getting logs out of an
actual logs log of a wooden variety so
yes so so but what you can use which you
can't have access to device what you can
use you can use Android debug bridge
which is part of Android SDK tools which
you can pull individual files for
investigation open shell and browser the
device lock and lock features make the
device dance a bit a bit I want to be
going going on a lot about what's about
the commands that are used by Android
debug bridge and how to get it in your
goodies folder I prepared a full a cheat
cheat cheat sheet of useful Android
debug bridge commands which which if you
want to play a play around with it play
around with it please do and here we
come to the main hero of today's my
today's talk to my favorite thing thing
about a favorite thing to read before
bed is Android bug reports and how to
read them once again please pay
attention to the goodies and actually I
wanted to actually play a game a bit
as I keep repeating that I have goodies
you can go to the goodies folder and
download the bug report called bug
report insomniac and answer try to try
to go to this bug report it's actually
from this device this device is unique
it's been my testing device for for many
years it's in a lot of malware so the
answer the question just named the place
where it was were that bug report was
taken just name of the place and email
that even emailed the name of the place
to these devices in email address which
you can also get from the bug report and
and and probably told the easy if name
name of the place will be in message
subject and of course I winds will flow
as we speak because there is more there
is more than one way to do that to try
to just find the location of the device
so let's dive into let's dive into the
magic world of Android bug reports a
humble bug report is not just a snapshot
of a device frozen in time
it's can't it can tell a story about
about the device and this story can be
used it can be used in forensics
investigation and in most cases a simple
bug report is more than enough to
diagnose most problems it it includes it
includes a variety of data a wealth of
data from device such as location and
global environment settings features
alerts include including including
system alerts and errors account sense
and uploads apps the apps app data and
their security it was it it was it also
includes a lot of service logs reports
messages full syslog and a lot of system
dumps have to take up how to take a bug
report well there are several several
ways most simple way is to go to
developer options on the on the device
and there will be an option to take a
bug report it is of course it is you can
do it if you have access to the device
like the UI is not worked if you if the
device is connected to connected to a
machine via ADB you go go adb bug report
and and enter the name of output file
but actually my favorite way of taking
bug report and probably the easiest is
just it depends on device but you
basically just simultaneously click
press all the three buttons volume up
volume down and and power and the dip it
generates a bug report for you in recent
device bug report which will be a big
packed folder but basically your your
your your main up object of interest is
the text file code called bug report
whatever takes see so and the bug report
can only answer three questions first
thing will be what is happening now a
snapshot of device what is happening
what was happening on it it's exactly
the moment the bug report was taken it
will it will be a memory dump pulled up
dump of memory of all these services
their device state in settings active
active settings and the the damp of
services will be very exhaustive device
location and environment he repeated
active broadcast and much much much more
so so for the software for example if
you want to know the the settings of the
device in your bug in your bug report
file file search for damp of service
settings and there will be three types
of settings such as global settings that
which includes battery or in terms
two Bluetooth settings security settings
such as locks clock screen if the
passport is set screen time out if side
Loney gene is enabled in Selenas status
and many and many more security settings
and and system settings which include
like volume and hardware settings and
much much much more sometimes it will be
it will be important to know those
settings just to understand the overall
state of device what is happening now
the where device is there are three
things that can point a device location
first
first is the geofence which is GPS
location of the device second is Wi-Fi
network which Wi-Fi network connection
and radio States which is connect
connection to mobile services and
there's this there are some things to
think things to start looking for just
to get you comfortable dealing with bug
reports and by the way there is a cheat
sheet for for bug reports as well and
your goodies folder you can find focused
activities with the app that occupies
the screen or you can get snapshot of
memory and see what apps are active
which app is draining the battery in so
on and so forth get broadcast history
which is which is actually a which is
actually very very useful for diagnosed
since the system slow slow down or super
aggressive apps and also getting for
about all the packages or on the device
and for and those are snapshots in sides
so for what about short term insights
the battery port will will will include
locket for for certain term normally
normal normally a couple of days of what
what was happening on device most most
interesting part at least at least from
apps safety point of view is app manager
message
in in locket for example as I already
explained of a focus stack which is
focused which desk is coming from the
front which activity is crashing or not
responding and which processes are
starting you can learn more about that
manager by just probably googling all
those all those commands + 2 + 4 + 4 +
find in full full a full list on Android
Open Source Project with with with those
messages and to demonstrate about an
easy example well I couldn't I couldn't
probably have having a single
presentation without ransomware examples
let's look at how how we can find out
find around somewhere up on device well
it's not really not really not really
difficult to find it because if
ransomware comes comes even though runs
aware on Android is very 2015 if the the
screen will be will be totally over or
overtaken so and on all the androids the
user will be completely completely
confused and not knowing what to do and
[Applause]
actually this is this is a screenshot
from an actual device with ransomware
and you have a full bug report and
you'll get this folder so if you if you
want to dig around that with that one or
feel free to do so
so let's try to just find this the name
of the app and we will do it by grouping
am focused activity and in bug in that
bug report and here it is a short
timeline of apps that were occupying the
screen and here you see Google and
Android Google quick search box which is
a default Google search Google search
box system app spiking for domination
which is weirdly named up with weirdly
named activity and this is this is our
this is basically this highlighted with
yellow this is our and somewhere
so we found the name of the app we will
we will further investigate more of us
but let's move into more short term
inside which is historic broadcasts
broadcast as I have mentioned they are
the way apps are communicating in the
and and a lot of active broadcasts that
haven't been sent my must must must must
mean that there is some sort of some
sort of overflow of activity that can
help that can happen that can be due to
some malicious apps activity some badly
coded app activity or just just
generally for for default because of the
phone being overcrowded and sluggish
durable there off and another another
interesting short-term inside is service
dumps there there are there are probably
hundreds of them that will be in in a in
any bug reports you can check how many
different service dams in your bug
report just by just by reference dump of
service but some some of the most
interesting are of them are surface
flinger which is what is on the on the
screen and actually all the activity on
the surface of the screen connectivity
which is a history of short history of
network connections content which is
which is a great way to to see sinks of
different accounts on the device for
example if the device has a Facebook
account Google account
Wikipedia accounts and those accounts
are sinking you will you will see
they're sinking logs and will be able to
get a summary of all those account
through content service service dump of
content accessibility enabled
accessibility features and if they're
used and the big service dump of all the
activities or all the activities in
turns and broadcasts on device so that
that can be attributed to their apps
that are using them and in another
interesting service dump which can
really
tell something about device is damp of
service notification and notifications
are those those notifications that you
get in tray of device when you pull it
down there will be a lot of them if for
example there there are a lot of a lot
of very chatty absent device if you if
you can kind of parse this code yourself
a bit you can see at the bottom of it
there is if there is it you can even
understand that it's the this this
notification is a stopped media player
on Android device that wasn't raised so
it has some apps previous previous track
pause next and thumbs down and for
example if you have chat messages
sometimes those chat messages
notifications will be it will be in this
dump of service so so sometimes it gives
a lot of insights for example if if your
device is easy is really overcrowded
with us and now come good for the
exciting stuff geofencing which is which
is devices exact GPS like allocation eg
geofence is define identity I with with
it with the GPS GPS card coordinates and
it's circle diameter sometimes those
circles overlap geofencing log is
limited to 200 records and sometimes can
actually show tragic trajectory with
which the device was moving and which
which objects were coming into this
geofence for to friend geofence
geofences for in the bug report research
for a registered geo fences and there
you will you will see circle coordinates
Circle IDs and in the short log with
with transitions and with with exact GPS
coordinates of the device and and on
this law in this log there will be even
not only location changes and creation
removal of geo fences but also location
relevant information such as Wi-Fi can
and disconnections which also can detail
tell a lot and now we move from
short-term so far I've been talking
about things that people think that
normally think that Bob report is
limited to which is short snapshot of
what was happening on device within
hours maybe maybe one day or maybe just
now but the real long-term is in sites
that that have very useful information
that can be very invaluable for
Diagnostics of what happens on device
and I in particular I'd like to talk
about three long to a long term insights
which are actions about accounts account
creation and modification Wi-Fi networks
and Android device stores information
about every Wi-Fi network it ever
connected to and app and apps installs
and apps information and I'm not insured
sure that the digging inside for digging
into bug reports the deeper for
different use cases a researcher can
always find find more more interest in
long-term information but let's so hard
just talk to talk about this dump
if you look for dump of service account
you will see pretty much pretty much a
full history of when when accounts were
created and removed and removed on
device and well this this snapshot is
from device with only one account but
sometimes sometimes
devices have more than one account and
as you see it is historical it's from
the started from the recently from the
from the recent hard reset of the device
app's history is very interesting
because bug reports contain very full
information about every upon device and
it's not just name of every app but apps
user ID install time data location how
it was installed installation packaged
apps permissions
up status and current state because apps
can be in different states states and
sometimes if if an app is it is in stop
state you will see you will see you will
see the app that stopped it so to do to
do this to get a lazy way to get a full
list of apps apps on the device is to
grab package from the bug report or just
search for a search for package and the
name of the app in in in square brackets
and you will get a full info about the
app in this format and where interesting
stuff as for example this is for a root
check app here is the code pass here's
the here's the code pass for it and and
you see you see there is full
information about site such as version
name and target SDKs and you and use
their user ID you in in both formats
it's which screen it supports you will
see you will see on top there is first
install time the time when the app was
installed and installed and and when it
was updated and and you see install
package name you commander it mean it
means that the app was installed from
Google Play and below you can see all
the permissions of this app this this is
this is every area can be got for for
every for every part up a bit more
details that installer package will
won't be present if an app was site
loaded or pre-installed or post via ADB
permissions there will be status not
only if the app respected those
permissions but if they were granted
because some permissions are never
granted and just if the app is in stop
state stated will it will show as
stopped state is true and let's get back
to our or our our run somewhere and see
it because we got it it got its name
lights go and find information about it
so
so this is this is the information about
this app you can you can see where it
was a word was installed you can see
that there is no installer installation
package which means it's not coming from
play and I admit I just pushed it on via
by adb to show it and if you start
browsing the this bug report you will
get more information about about about
broadcast and in terms of this app and
you can for example find its activity on
locket for example it was trying to
overtake the camera at some point and
another long-term inside the last for in
my talk is Wi-Fi networks if you search
for jump off Wi-Fi config store you will
get all the Wi-Fi networks they up the
device have a connected to and when it
when it first connected to it which is
also kind of valuable information and
sometimes there is some other stuff for
example you looking at Shetty's apps and
found some found some interesting
insights about the usage of the device
would it's actually used for or
sometimes it can out your music taste or
lack thereof that's that's actually from
my from my from my own devices bug
report
I found the media's media session with
the name of the track I was listening
and that's all I wanted to tell you
about the wonderful world of Android bug
reports and how it can be useful in your
investigation and in helping probably
help in people yeah yes and I guess we
are running to the end I think I will
only have time to actually give you give
you a actually should it check of the if
anybody emailed me alright
yes we got a we got we got a person that
that that that got its sylveon shining
it high Nagar
got got the reply right
yes yes as I said we we're dumping the
dump in the the geofences with foreign
GPS location of the device then we go to
Google Maps and here is the hotel where
I stayed in Syria so thank you very much
for your attention and I hope you will
find this information useful I will be
hanging out around here so if you want
to talk about it chat about something or
want more bug reports that is come
please come over camera and and it was
not it was nice presented to you thank
you for being a great audience we have
five minutes for questions any questions
so thank you for the talk I was
wondering when you analyze apps from the
Google Play Store do you find any
malicious apps that route the device of
the victim and actually steal data did
you encounter that yes there were some
those apps luckily most of them were not
in play and luckily they do not really
work on recent devices because I think
starting from L
it's not really easy to not not much
routine exploits that the apps use work
but he has there were a couple of
malicious families I think they were
also in the media a lot but they but
they are pretty much dead now
hi I have a question about Google Play
protect 2-step questions first of all do
you analyze any signature of apps or
maybe it's about how app behavior or
maybe what data did they collect and
second question do you analyze only apps
that's installed by Google Play Store or
maybe from another sources as well well
good questions thank you there is there
is a gender analysis pipeline which
analyzes like billions of billions of
apps and and does reakless amount of
scans most of it currently currently dun
dun dun automatically use a user using
machine learning and stuff but there is
there is also a big and growing team of
reverse engineers and malware analysts
that analyze that analyze apps the duma
the do reverse engineering and analysis
and and signature making for apps both
in play and outside of play and play
project is moving to the stage where
it's able to protect users from both
that they both use google play or prefer
to sideload apps from third-party stores
I have one question you were mentioning
the fact that you can do network
activity tracking using ADB are there
any plans to have something like that as
an app on the device built into Android
because most malware could be detected
due to the network traces yeah yeah I
know that it's kind of a bit tricky and
but I know that there are there are
quite a few quite a few apps that allow
to do to do that let's chat about it
offline because I actually have one of
the apps here on this device
all right I think we can okay thank you
very much thank you very much
actually I want to ask whether the
introduction of bundles has made
detecting malware by play protect before
publishing harder it's an it's an
interesting question of course of course
the mobile developers always want to
kind of hide it but this is why this is
why we have reverse engineers and and
security engineers and all the people
that that that try to that try to try
try to mitigate this the this extra
difficulty of analyzing apps okay thank
you okay times up you have six minutes
of break before the next talk please
like around of applause
[Applause]
[Music]