welcome to the contribution
from myself and my daughter here you
will see the agenda for today
it's the introduction to social
engineering and
peace respectively beekeeping
we will cover different topics today for
you
and we will show you the bee house
for instance we will talk about
fake honey
i will give you some links for fantastic
recipes
you can make with honey we talk about
intensity levels
which is a really important topic
we will also cover engagement management
abed attack vector development
approach selection method hi
my name is tom i'm working in infosec
for over 25 years
i'm a hard ex cyber risk tutor
and i'm from switzerland and my most
favorite topics are
social engineering and honeybees it's
one of my hobbies
so today i will walk you through this
pancakes con 2020 quarantine
edition through both of my favorite
topics
hopefully you can get something out of
it you can have some fun
and it's worthwhile your time
[Music]
hey
hey i'm avers
and i am a hacker
fire alarm what
[Music]
yeah just just set a fire alarm no no
no no it's okay what
angle is sick
yeah no worries
this must be my offer someone daughter
hey verse
this must be my daughter cannot be
someone else
[Music]
so hi
welcome to my bees so the first thing
you do is
you go to your bees you approach them
but then you stop
to stop in front of the bees and first
determine
if they are friendly today or if they
are not
make sure you check this out first
so it appears to be they're quite
friendly
no attack so far let's see if we can
catch one which has the
pollen on its legs there is one
you saw that one very quickly went
inside the height
there's another one fully loaded with
pollen now i can introduce you
to some of the basic tools
this is a smoker no it's not what you
think
it's for give a little puff to the bees
they stay a bit more calm that's for
grabbing the hives take them out and
have a look
and this is also a tool we use for
beekeeping
but you will see later
[Music]
okay
[Applause]
[Music]
um
oh
so this is now honey fresh
from the bees as fresh as it gets
[Applause]
if you ever have the opportunity to eat
fresh from a honeybee height it's
amazing
[Applause]
unbelievable
there are three types of bees in every
colony
you have the drones the workers
and the queen bee the queen bee is the
most distinctive bee
she's the biggest she has a very
distinctive abdomen so she's easy to
spot if you know what you're looking for
she can lay up to 1 500 eggs a day
and she gets to tell all the other bees
what to do
so let's talk about drones drones are
the male bees in the hive they have
one sole purpose and that is to mate
with the queen
worker bees feed the drones throughout
the entire
season just so they can then try and
mate with the queen
if they do so successfully they die if
they don't
the worker bees who've been working
their asses off the whole
season will kick them out and let them
starve to death
now to the work bees
the work bees are the females the girls
and of course they're the ones doing all
the work
they tend the hive they tend the queen
they live roughly for 63 days
that's their cycle and then they die
leaving no offspring worker bees lack
full reproductive capacity
okay so here i have
a jar of honey it's 500 grams
let's put that in some context
one worker bee in her whole lifetime
can produce a by about five grams
so roughly one teaspoon that means
for this jar it takes 100
worker bees whole life
to fill it that's pretty impressive
considering that their brain is only
a sesame seed big
from the bees and ready to talk to you
about social engineering
the basics so
pancakes con 2020 quarantine edition
and let's get started talking about
my most favorite topic social
engineering
so social engineering is often seen as
fishing spearfishing or whaling as you
can see here
but i believe it's much more than just
those topics
covered social engineering we're in
social engineering
we actually talk about shoulder surfing
pretexting
ego whaling the use of ego as an attack
vector
actually because ego is one of the best
attack vectors you can use
it's about the use for instance of
authority
for your attack vectors it's tailgating
it's liking it's baiting etc etc
you can also look in the book you will
receive the ebook for free
and you can have a look there i have
sorted this out there in much more
detail than we
can cover here within this short amount
of time
as for social engineering i believe
there must be a better definition what
social engineering actually means and
what it entails
so i have a definition for social
engineering myself
it's the elicitation of information from
systems
networks human beings through methods
and tools
but what is social engineering still no
answer about social engineering actually
is
as a matter of fact i will compare it
with this for me it's actually finding
the gemmy the crowbar the emotional
crowbar
to attach and then push who can become a
social engineer
i believe everyone can become a social
engineer
it's not just like technical people or
people from other fields
i think it's a good mix it's also a good
mix of skills and knowledge
you need to acquire or you can acquire
or you can bring to the table to social
engineering engagements
or to attack vector definitions so for
instance
if you like to work with people you
maybe can work in the front line of
social engineering
if you like to work on tools and
programs and processes
you can work in the background of social
engineering attacks
so what are you looking for as a social
engineer specifically so that you can
leverage so that you can use your
crowbar
or your chemi so you're looking for out
of character
behavior for instance or you're looking
for emotionally
loaded areas so there you will have the
most success because
there you can generate leverage and
actually use your attack vector
a general attack vector or one you have
specifically designed
for maybe a person an event or even a
company
i found one of the most important skills
for a social engineer
is actually observation mirroring
and then adopting and this because
if you are working in different places
of the world in different cultures
you need first you need to see how it
works there
for instance also at the party how do
people eat behave
do they shake hands or not nowadays
probably not so
you need to get the gist of the culture
so these skills are actually
very important for a social engineer
also if you want to blend in
if you want to disappear in a crowd and
not stand out
then probably you observe first and then
you start mirroring the behavior
of the other people around you and then
you adapt
to the behavior
this is actually more of a technical
expression
what i believe would be just fantastic
if you could download this
um to the human beings as a software
release
that would be absolutely fantastic but
of course
that won't work
so let's look at the at the history
of social engineering or let's say corn
artists
that we had here we have some examples
of some cone artists we have frank
abignale
you know that maybe him from movie catch
me if you can
i actually met him in australia once
he's
quite the likable guy then we have
different prospects here we have kevin
foster
bernard madoff or bernie madoff
the so infamous ponzi scheme
then if you go further on this side
yep let's we have
william cloner victor lustig
charles ponzi and william thompson
and by the way the ponzi scheme is not a
pyramid scheme
they are different for what they do
so from this side here i thought i want
to talk to you about
victor lustig because he is quite
interesting
it's also interesting because uh lustig
or lustig
means funny in german so it's victor
funny actually and i was reading his
story i thought that's quite interesting
what he actually pulled up so he was
basically the guy
who in 1925 sold the eiffel tower twice
back then it was the leftover of the
world
australia and he went then to the
authorities and said he can sell
the eiffel tower for scrap value
which then some investors believe to
make the deal of their lives
and invested in the scrap metal value of
the eiffel tower
then when he sold it the first time the
people he coned
were so embarrassed to go to the police
or talk to anyone
they didn't tell no one so he then
thought
all right if that worked once let's just
make it work twice
and he actually sold the eiffel tower
twice the foie
then on this side here you see what's
called romanian box
and i think what he did there was even
more astonishing
so he created a quite complex and nice
looking wooden box
with a lot of hands on it with this box
he make believe his victims believe that
they can make
copies of one thousand dollar notes
of course victor lustig manipulated the
machine
and he put in a one thousand dollar note
and the second one
so when he had his first client he went
to them and said
a copying process takes about six hours
so he went to them said okay he's now
making a copy of a
one thousand dollar note he made the
first copy of the one thousand dollar
note
and they were waiting to make a second
copy of the one thousand dollar note
after then the client have two real one
thousand dollar notes
they really believed and were hooked on
this principle of this machine that this
machine could make
copies of real
banknotes so of course the
the tricky part here was the six hours
so these six hours
allowed victor lustig to actually then
remove
himself from the scene and he could flee
and of course the buying price of this
me of this machine was astonishingly
high
so i thought this is really a guy who
pulled this in 1926
actually with the romanian box which is
quite astonishing
and also it shows a bit how people think
and how people
react so people do really believe
things which are too good to be true so
it's quite amazing
let's have a look at the engagement
management method so the book was not
just written for fun
it was actually written with the
different purposes in mind
so for instance it should help you as a
maybe new engineer entering social
engineering
it can help you as a company maybe
making more business
so maybe instead of just offering pen
testing services you can also offer
social engineering services so it
i know it looks quite complex and it's
not quite a good
picture but you will get a better one
but this actually shows
each process you should actually engage
in
if you're doing social engineering
engagement and how you should manage
your engagements
i prepared this process and basically
project management methodology
because i've been involved in many many
penetration testings and security audits
and gap analysis all over the world
and risk management is one of the most
important topics there
so if you have a big corporation who
wants to do penetration testing or for
instance
now social engineering testing services
you need to have a method in place
so you can work with them so you can
reproduce
the same results year over year and you
apply the same testing methodology
within maybe one engagement or
internationally
within the different areas i think it's
a very
important part of the work as a social
engineer
now i will show you something which i
believe
is at the core of this whole social
engineering engagement framework
i created with my colleague i believe
this is the most
important bit and if you don't remember
anything
about it remember this it's very easy
it's like basically an ample system so
it shows red
green orange and of course black as well
what it means if you're engaging in
social engineering services
within the green area you are okay
these are services you can execute
you know your customer you know your
project you know what you're doing
so these services can be just executed
fine
if you're engaging in services
which have a risk level of orange you
need to consider
at least need to consider from your
company perspective if you want to
engage in those type of services
the same then applies to the red
services
as a company and in the commercial
environment
actually i think there is no need to
actually think of engaging
in social engineering services which
have a risk rating of red
it's completely unnecessary but also you
can use this chart as your personal
ethics charts you can say i do
penetration testings
if i have the necessary risk letters
signed or i do
these and these services also on the
other hand you can say i will not engage
in services
which might have or bear the possibility
that i will commit a crime for instance
so
some things um what comes to my mind
just right now is um
you know lots of people engaging in
social engineering and thinking oh it's
great and i will have maybe an
id and i fake an id or i will fake a
document
to get myself an entry or maybe a badge
for that matter but the problem is if
you do this
it's forging documents and
forging documents is actually a felony
so it's a major crime
and if you have committed once a major
crime for just like a stupid social
engineering engagement
it's really bad it will stick to you it
will stick to your record
so always make sure before you're
engaging in social engineering services
or for that matter of any sort of
engagements
you are asked to do for a client what's
behind them
is there any specific risk for instance
so maybe i will talk a bit more
about that one later
then attack vector development attack
vector development
looks a bit like that so we do have
different
attack vectors which of course um are
depending on the task or on the amount
of budget you have to develop an attack
vector
and also depending on your target so on
the
well maybe it's on the left hand side
from you
is the effort at the cost development
attack vector
on this side is the importance of the
engagement or task of course if you do
have
not a lot of time and not a lot of money
to develop attack vectors
you are staying to the standard attack
vectors avs
i will show you some of them later if
you go up the curve
you have more specific and dedicated and
very
detailed attack vectors scr map is a
very specific map
we do that social engineering engagement
framework you can do
psyc profiling nlp guild e6 you do
whaling
you do can use the muscle of hierarchy
of needs for instance to create attack
vectors
and so on and so on so this chart
actually shows you
in what type of attack vector you want
to engage and of course they have an
impact
on cost
as here you can see for attack vector
development
is the division 3 on the left hand side
do you want to use a standard attack
vector which is available
which has a description which you know
the expected results of this attack
vector
which can be scaled is already developed
and doesn't need a lot of time
to being rolled out you talk about here
uh
maybe like phishing emails phishing
email templates for instance
here you see some other standard attack
vectors like impersonation
dumpster diving and eavesdropping
but with all these attack vectors and
that's also in the book then
you need to make sure about the risk
you're engaging with so for these ones i
have
a definition of risk management for
dumpster diving
um there's certain risk with it because
if you're on the property of the company
you cannot just
take their dumpsters or their garbage
out you wouldn't be allowed
it would be a crime in the public you
have to be careful
uh where the dumps or where the bin is
actually to take some documents out so
there are some refinements with these
attack vectors but these are
pretty the general standard attack
vectors
now i will show you the
let me click to the next slide here
here's the whole um attack
or attack methodology it's
pretty bad welcome back to my next part
about social engineering uh i was cut
out
battery died on me but now let's
continue with that topic
so the next topic i want to introduce
you is this
this is the whole process basically from
information collection
through information documentation
through the development of an attack
vector
through the approach selection method so
let's have a look quickly
at those individual items here
information collection so you need to
collect the information to create your
attack vectors
as a first bit so you can either buy
this information
or you can make it so it's open source
intelligence for instance
um different intelligence report you can
buy
you can send out the red team blue
teaming collecting this information
and then based on this information
you're documenting
the information so either it's
fact-based
documentation of information so
basically
raw information or it's
intelligence-based
information intelligence-based means
there has been information
and people or maybe machines artificial
intelligence whatever
has made decisions on what this
information means
so they made an interpretation of the
information
which is totally okay out of this you
have a work paper
report or you have a classification this
then flows
into the attack vector development so
because it's the basis
for developing your attack vector you
need information you need intelligence
you need okay how does workflow work at
company xy set for phishing initiatives
you need to know the organizational
structures of companies
uh money flows etc so this information
flows then into the attack vector
and in there you do the analysis and you
select
what might work best as your attack
vector
based on the topic you want to achieve
after that you have defined your attack
vector
you actually select the approach how do
you deliver this attack vector do you
have to deliver it simultaneously
on multiple places internationally is it
person based
attack vectors for christmas with santa
claus don't really work
at easter for instance and so on and so
forth
and then you exploit that's the whole
process
in one picture basically so let's
click to the next slide how do you
develop the
specific attack vector so this is then
how we develop
the specific attack vectors so we decide
is person-based attack vector or this is
a technology-based
attack vector so either you send person
in to collect information for instance
intelligence or you're sending them
files for instance malware etc
then you have open site and remote
option location
you have to go to a specific place
because it's a physical location
or you can do it remotely sending emails
sending
files making phone calls etc
then here you define the actual attack
vector because everyone would love to
develop attack vectors
with endless money and endless time but
in the business world
this is not going to work and also you
need to be risk-averse so
usually big corporations don't really
like to engage in
big risks for operations so
you then define what we call the attack
vector
principle so is it well known attack
or is it a dedicated specific attack
vector
the principle you can see here is this
bit so
either you use nestle pyramid is an
attack vector
scr map nlp galdena6 social media mice
curiosity most often it's curiosity
so for instance in phishing emails it's
a competition you want something
so you kind of um play on the
factor of curiosity of everyone in an
email in a phone call in whatever
uh winnings earnings etc deception of
course
ceo fraud is based on this principle um
it's time based so sending out phishing
emails maybe friday four o'clock is
better than sending them out
monday at nine where everyone is in the
office
you use the principle of authority of
scarcity something is limited edition
and scarce for instance
you play on the helplessness of the
victims on the politeness for instance
scanning or intimidation charity
persuasion techniques
so distance will then be combined when
you have one selected this part
with the sweet spots weaknesses and
strengths or out of character behavior
you have based on your information
collection
so of course for me for instance if i'm
heavily involved in the beekeeping and
honey and all this stuff maybe you can
send me
phishing emails about honey a new
discovery of a fantastic b
so obviously i would then be curious
about this and read it open the
attachment eventually etc
uh the beliefs and influence or
emotional and financial pressures or
out of character behaviors now this is
important too
these are the constraints because
you won't have endless time and then
this money usually so you have
during with the time you have available
create a good attack vector
also the chances of success are
important sometimes you can only make
one offs
you have one chance to get something
right another then
if it's not going to work with this
attack vector phishing emails campaign
etc you have to go for another route
or people they inform each other if they
found out about the suspicious email
they will talk faster then you can send
a second phishing email
um etc so this is now the constraints
money wise skills wise intensity level
wise of course
and then we go into this i explained
this to you before
do a you engage only in green
level services orange or red or you say
okay i only do the black stuff
who knows usually it's enough if you
engage in green level to get repeatable
and results which are relevant on a
corporate level
it's totally unnecessary to go to a
deeper more risky level
and then you have the grc which is also
setting the boundaries it's about
culture and it's about respect
so this is how you compromise an attack
vector if you once defined one
you keep it basically in your database
and you pull it up for the next time
and you adjust the settings maybe of
culture of language and of setting
and the specific sector maybe a company
or a business system
let's click to the next slide
here just a is a bit of additional
information
around personal space how that actually
works and
the part we actually call the reaction
zone
now it has definitely changed with
corona people have more distance
towards each other physically hopefully
not emotionally
but that's the basic as a social
engineer you need to know a couple of
basics
if you work with people around people
talk to people
and try to make them what you actually
want to make them
to do so you have a specific soul in the
middle where
you are the person here this is the
intimate zone
and it's about the family which is
usually in this intimate zone
uh then on the outer circle you have
like a personal zone
which friends the social zone were
colleagues in the public zone
of course it looks different now it's
definitely changed
um this but this is just roughly gives
you an idea and the reaction zone
basically just means
if you approach a person within this
zone
maybe now with corona is exactly the 2
meters or 1.5 meters they recommend
you will definitely provoke a reaction
so maybe you want that
maybe you don't want that so just keep
that in mind if you're approaching a
person it's always like
a gate and for each of these gates
you have to kind of like to get the
formal permission or
informal permission to approach a person
otherwise the person will react
fight the flight and either leave or you
won't get what you actually want from
that person so you need to ask for
permission you can be
as sometimes say coughing but it is not
a good
methodology now you can drop your keys
you can
nestle on your phone your phone can ring
and then you get
you know this person's attention and
then you can walk further but if you're
running very fast towards this zone here
you get an unwanted reaction
let's click to the next slide this is
just a bit of more theory for you but i
will go very quickly over the
sounds of approach it's very
uncomfortable being approached from the
back it's a bit different for women and
men
in the perception women have a bit tend
to have a bit a wider angle acceptable
angle
i guess it's because they're watching
out then maybe men
so best approaches in the green zone
obviously you approach the person from
the front
it's a a bit more different in this
context
military personnel they don't like to
get approached from any direction
except from the front where you're
talking to them so keep that in mind
here we just have very quickly a diagram
about touching a person
on the body which you actually should
not in no
culture or in no areas of the world this
is probably okay
but just to give you an ear totally
taboo or this areas here
for men it's a bit more in the shoulders
like
a tap on the shoulders you also can get
kills for that one but
it's more acceptable maybe around the
hands uh
you you could probably touch a person it
um
with the women different i will just
show you that
just need to click to the next slide
so click with women um
it's like this picture so it's really
only could be okay and it depends on the
culture as well
where you can actually touch another
person
but nowadays it's any way to touch
another person's
so now bringing this to um you know some
practical use this whole model i just
showed you very quickly
um if you approach a person sitting on a
desk like this
obviously never approach this person
from the back it's very uncomfortable
for my person
for the person it's not because maybe
the person's searching porn or doing
something other than illegal
it's just very uncomfortable and we'll
never have a good start
talking this person also keep that in
mind if you're maybe a team leader
of sort that you approach a person
preferably from the front
you don't see the screen of the person
you are polite to this person
and then you can have a good rapport
with this person
also make sure that you don't sit on a
person's desk
because that's a big no-go that's very
aggressive
passive aggressive move so just keep
this in mind
if you approach a person wherever you
are in whatever context you are
it's a good good thing to keep in mind
how you make another person comfortable
talking to you
then here i just work through a bit
more about the target selection for a
person company or a place
where do you get your targets how do you
get them it's about open source
intelligence it's about
making use of information available
but here are a couple of hints what you
can actually do
depending what you want to if you want
to
get in touch or get to know people from
conferences like pancakes
con for instance you go to these
conferences you see these types of
people there but also you know from
experience that maybe
people from this and this company you
should go to this pub so you can go in
there if you want information
so this is just like a help for target
selection
then i'm coming to an end and i know you
have endured a lot
for the pancakes com 2020 quarantine
edition
so now since you have been through all
this i do also
offer you this certificate for
completion
so you now know the basics about social
engineering
you have the ebook and also you get this
certificate
and you know the basics about beekeeping
so
take care of yourself stay safe
and i wish you a nice day for the
reminding of this quarantine
thanks
[Music]
[Laughter]
um
and um
it
um
oh
and now let's quickly go back to the
bread
the bread test as you can see
this one has formed a crust
it's already like hard
look at this piece of bread
you know that's more more soggy there's
a
soaked up ketchup
this piece of bread even when i break it
i can feel it with
then it looks like this so if you would
have fake honey
it would end up
um
[Laughter]
okay
so
is there is another test
we can do with fire so we just take a
match
and a piece of paper
as you can see
quickly the paper burns so
now we take a bit of honey
put it on top of the paper
oh take another match
now we will try to light that paper
again
you can see there where the honey is
paper doesn't burn
so that's the properties of honey
fantastic
[Laughter]
[Music]
okay
oh
[Laughter]
[Music]
um
[Laughter]
okay
foreign