all right this is pancakes contract 2.
i've temporarily muted the presenter i'm
sorry hilah
there's a little bit of uh refurb going
on there
uh pancakes con track 2
and this talk is oh cyber security job
interviews
and card magic so that should be
fascinating uh this is hila lucas uh
this is not her first time speaking to
an audience but it is her first time in
a webinar
and uh bear with me just one second
hey there we are so cyber security job
interviews
hillary's on a mission to create
resources to prepare for cyber security
job interviews
when i was preparing and revising for my
interviews half the time was spent
collecting resources
rather than developing my skills or
learning new things
i want to break down this barrier for
newcomers to the industry
and show them the basics of what they
need to know in order to get those first
jobs and
internships in the industry followed up
with card magic i've been doing card
magic for about five years on and off
this talk i'm terribly sorry about the
chime this talk will teach a few methods
of card handling basic moves you will
need to learn to get started
and to point people to resources for
learning more
it would be best experience if you have
a deck of cards you can use to follow
along with however
that's not 100 necessary so without
further ado
please welcome hila lucas to pancakes
con
over to you hi
um now can i'm gonna play my slides
cool so um yeah welcome to my talk
uh thank you so much to the organizers
for organizing this
uh it is really an honor to present at
pancakes con
i'm super sad i didn't have any pancakes
today however
um i'm sure i will make up for it very
soon
um so this talk is or the first part of
this talk is the talk that i wish i had
seen about three years ago when i
started applying for my first
internships within cyber security
um i um as it was mentioned
i spent a lot of time preparing for
interviews um
and in a kind of macro sense i'm
kind of wanting to make sure that cyber
security has the same resources
that software engineers have um
in terms of recruitment and interviewing
so i don't know if anybody has ever
seen a software engineering recruitment
process but especially at kind of
college or university level
there's talks workshops websites
question banks job boards
and we don't have that in cyber so i'm
really looking to to make that kind of
content
uh and make this more accessible so if
you're interested in collaborating on
that or
um think you could help please get in
touch later
so um without further ado
uh this is the agenda so we're gonna i'm
gonna talk a little bit about who i am
and what makes me qualified to talk
about this now we're going to go
over interview types how to prepare for
interviews the kinds of knowledge
that are the kind of topics that you
might expect to come up in the
interviews
i'm going to point you to some resources
that you can use
and then uh final thoughts and then
we'll move on to
magic tricks so
oh a small disclaimer this is all based
on my personal experience
um so obviously this might be a little
different for you i haven't interviewed
at
every company um this does not reflect
the views of my previous
future employers or my university um
and i have done interviews where i
signed an nda
um before taking them and i'm not
sharing any information
that um was discussed or disclosed in
those interviews
uh and one other thing i do have a
slight blue team bias so i have worked
as a security engineer um and
in threat intelligence uh so this is
yeah if you're looking to get into pen
testing i might not be the best person
to talk to you
but i will share some resources for that
as well
so um a little introduction to me
um i am a fourth year cybersecurity and
digital forensics student i graduate in
december of this year
at edinburgh napier university up in
scotland
um i am an incoming security engineer at
facebook i'm going to
join them after um i did an internship
with them
last summer and i'm going to join them
as soon as i graduate
i used to be part of the edinburgh
neighbor university security society
committee and i am now a member
um i have successfully
passed interviews at um fang companies
big four investment banks cyber security
consultancy and a university obviously i
haven't done all of these jobs
but because i've been working on this
project for a few years i just took
every opportunity i could to
interview so i could pass this knowledge
on um
so yeah i i've done quite a lot of it
and this is all for
internships or entry level positions so
do please bear with that in mind
when listening to me apart from cyber
i'm also into ted and tedx conferences
magic tricks obviously painting vegan
food and
dogs you can see my dog in the
background of
every slide um her name is paraoko and i
love her very much
i'm also a member of women in cyber
security scotland
next slide please there we go so
um these are the types of interviews
that i have come across
uh i will be diving into a few of them
i will not be covering screening
behavioral
experience based group interviews or
assessment centers
there is lots of resources out there
about those
elsewhere and they're not really
necessarily specific to cyber in my
experience
um so but do bear in mind that these are
things that you may need to
look at when preparing for your
interview so it's not always just going
to be technical questions
and that's all there is going to be a
lot more than just that um
but yeah if you would like resources for
any of those please let me know
um i will be talking about
technical interviews and coding
interviews and
a little about offering negotiation as
well
um but before i go into those in detail
i'm going to do a little bit about
interview preparation
so um if you let's say you've got a date
for your interview
uh you're a little excited um i want to
share
what steps i think you can take to
maximize your chances of getting the job
the first step is don't panic um
i found these things very very stressful
and i i know that a lot of people do
um yeah so the number one thing i think
for me
is learning to manage stress and that's
actually something that's quite
individual to everyone
so i really recommend spending some time
and reading up on how to do it and
figuring out what methods were for you
um but the other main things that you
can do for interview prep
is practice practice practice and know
your stuff so
in terms of know your stuff i found that
with each subsequent subsequent
interview
i've done better and that's because the
best way to learn something in my
opinion
is to just do it and this is a really
kind of chicken and big chicken and egg
problem for entry level
people in cyber security because how do
you get
good at cyber security for your first
job if you don't have that first job
right
so in my opinion the best way to do that
is to do
side projects you know do some coding on
the side
uh watch some def con talks attend
conferences like this
um use udemy coursera maybe contribute
to open source
uh you can also find a mentor and ask
them to help you
uh play cts do some talks in general
just gain
experience in any way you can and you
can really get creative with this kind
of thing
uh your your ex my first experience in
infosight wasn't
really to do with a job specifically it
was just to do with some side projects
um so um yeah but this
this kind of this portion of things does
get easier
the more internships or jobs you do so
don't worry you will get better
um and then the second thing is practice
so interviewing in my opinion is a skill
in its own right um so i know
people with loads and loads of knowledge
that can't really communicate
that well and i think that puts them in
a real disadvantage in terms of
interviewing because
that's one of the most important things
so
i think the best way um to practice for
interviews
is to identify the types of questions
you think are going to be
asked and then to practice with your
friends
um and yeah just make sure that you're
able to
to say what you want to say because i
at least find that even if i have the
knowledge speaking about it
is a totally different story um
if you don't have friends that you feel
comfortable
practicing with you can reach out on
twitter to
the cyber security community and i'm
sure you'll find somebody to help
if i can help i will just tweet me um
but obviously i might not be qualified
uh so i'm sure that we can find somebody
who will be willing to practice with you
if you need it
um right another kind of tip that i
found
helps and i will caveat this with
i've done this for various companies and
it doesn't
actually always work in terms of the
actual questions
but um but the themes that emerged were
definitely in the interview so
there's a website called graph store
that i'm sure
at least some of you are familiar with
and people will
actually post interview questions from
specific companies
um there so you can just use the search
function
to look for the company name and
interview questions um
there tends to be a lot for software
engineering
um for bigger companies not necessarily
for cyber security
but there are some um and obviously
use your critical thinking like you're
probably not going to
have to you know reverse a linked list
or anything
uh in a cyber security job interview
although it might happen
uh but yeah this is a good resource and
obviously
it's going to work much better for
bigger companies
but yeah just check it out it's it's a
good place to look
i'm sorry um
now the next thing is uh kind of
looking at the job description so
um geography job descriptions can be
very vague
um and a lot of them actually have a lot
more in the description that is actually
required from you once you get to doing
the job or even the interview
so don't let yourself be intimidated by
the job
descriptions but i do suggest being able
to talk to all the kind of keywords
in a specific job profile it won't hurt
to learn about these things if you
haven't heard of them
oh and i guess this should go without
saying but if this is what's deterring
you from
applying for a job um please don't let
it like
there's a lot of research that shows
that women for example don't apply to
jobs where they don't um
fulfill every single requirement in
their job descriptions and men do so
yeah keep that in mind a lot of people
will so you might as well
um yeah so here obviously you can see a
kind of breakdown of
the things that i would look at um in
this kind of job description
i'm not going to read out the slides
because you're all
able to read but when looking at this i
would also
try and think about a few additional
questions like
um what the company's threat profile is
what their tech stack is um and
kind of you know use this as a base to
identify other questions that you might
be asked
in your interview
so the next thing i'm going to talk
about
is the kind of knowledge needed for most
of these interviews so
um this i mean this is not nowhere near
perfect
but um in my experience all of these
topics
will probably come up at a certain point
in the interview
so i'm gonna start at the bottom of this
pyramid so
the low level ones and zeros so um at
each level i would ask
uh can i use this and do i know how this
works
so in terms of low level ones and zeros
in my opinion that's um
asking questions about how computers
actually work so
everything from computer architecture to
actually
you know i don't know binary and
more importantly being able to use this
information so
maybe you're able to convert i don't
know hex to binary or
something simple like that but um do you
know why
you would need to do that um in in the
context of your job um
so the next thing is operating systems
so
not only how to use things like you know
linux windows mac
but also how they work um so then
obviously this is a very
challenging question you know how does
windows work could take
i mean there's books written about it
right uh but having a kind of
overview of it and being able to talk to
at least a little bit in my opinion is
really good
um the next thing is networking
so how does the internet work i i'm
going to share a really good resource
for answering that question
later on in the slide so stick around
for that um
but um yeah but apart from how it works
and talking about um being able to use
networking so you know can you set up a
little server in python um
and in general just you know
understanding
what happens in networks next thing
attacks defenses detections
um so this is getting trickier to
generalize because it's very
job specific um obviously blue tumors
red teamers etc will have
will get different questions but in
general
um you know in the context of the
company or the technologies that you're
going to be using
can you identify explain mitigate
exploit detect various attacks i think
is
um a really useful question to ask
yourself
when preparing for an interview
um the next one is tools so if there's
any tools mentioned
in the job description obviously being
able to talk about
what they are if you've used them before
or if you've had a chance to kind of try
out a demo version
being able to talk about that and
sometimes
talking about how the tools actually
work
um are both um important in my opinion
i've come across a lot of those
questions
um and then at the top of the pyramid
there's like job specific stuff now
obviously
i can't really predict that that will
probably be based on what's in the job
description
um but you know there will be other
stuff apart from
general concepts that you will be asked
most likely
um a little note about approaching
technical interviews
um so for me the biggest learning curve
here was that the interviewer is
actually human and that not knowing
everything is fine
um if you come across a question where
you don't know the answer
i that doesn't mean you're not going to
get the job um
and practicing your stress management at
that point is probably key
um it's really good to kind of give it a
guess making it clear that this is a
guess saying something like i don't know
but
based on my knowledge of x y and z i
think
this is how you would solve it or this
is the answer
um yeah a lot of interviews are about
testing your the depth of your knowledge
and
in this case there is going to
definitely be a point where
um where you have to say i don't know
and it's important to understand that
some interviews are structured like that
because
especially for junior positions you know
that your employer wants to know
your potential employer wants to know
how much you know
um and yeah once again they do not
expect you to know everything
um your thought process and logical
thinking is really important
whoops the next thing is coding
interview i've only had coding
interviews in two of the multiple
interviews that i've done
um a really good resource for learning
how to do them is hacker rank and leak
code if you haven't come across those
although i will
caveat that with um those are tailored
to software engineers and the questions
are usually a lot harder
um than what i have experienced even the
kind of easy level ones but it's a good
place to kind of practice them and look
at solutions
um cracking the coding interview is a
great book if you're going
in for a um you know development-focused
job
um i mean it's got a lot of information
it has a break of a book
i've skimmed through it and i have to
say that some of the stuff was
useful but um in general it goes into a
lot of details that i didn't really
personally need um and yeah i think
the last thing is like for cyber
security the coding interviews are
rare and they can be really challenging
but they can also be quite easy so
you know don't stress too much about it
um and but definitely
do you get some coding experience if you
want to go into cyber security because
a lot of big companies do ask that you
have at least a little
um another thing is asking your
interviewer questions so
um this is super important um
examples of questions that i would ask
are like
will i be the only woman on the team or
uh what is
the team like i like going into the
wikipedia for a company if it's a big
one and looking at the controversy
section and asking about that
um but that's um that might be a little
um cocky for some people i suppose
um but i think it's um it's a really
good
um opportunity for you to see if you
would actually enjoy
working with the person that's
interviewing you if they're gonna even
be on your team
um and you know if you care about
working from home for example
you should definitely ask about it
because some companies are really
flexible and some aren't
um good kind of on
on topic and timely question would be
how did they handle the coronavirus
celebrate
um i think it's just important to
remember that you are it's not just the
company that's interviewing you
you are also interviewing the company
and you have to
gauge whether you would like to work
there because it's a waste of your time
as well as theirs if you don't enjoy it
once you're there
compensation questions now uh i whoops
sorry
i'm not a lawyer so i
please don't ease this
please don't justify doing anything with
my slide
but it's really important in my opinion
to talk about salaries
um and put them online it benefits the
entire workforce to know what
we'll earn uh i know that it is taboo in
some
cultures especially in the uk for
example but i do think that it's
important to talk about it so
my two senses please do talk um also in
the uk it's illegal for a company to
tell you that a salary is confidential
under the equality act of 2010 some
companies do
i personally have chosen not to work for
a company that did that
um yeah i think it's really important to
know your rights
um in terms of kind of
you know asking for a salary it's always
good to ask the
company to give you a range first um
and if that doesn't work find a trusted
peer mentor to speak to
and i encourage negotiating uh
but it's good to have another offer if
you are going to negotiate
now resources all of these links uh i
would
i mean if you would like to scan them uh
with your phone please do
um otherwise hello lucas.com
[Music]
links i will have links to all of these
so the first question bank is just a
list of technical interview questions
the seven day preparation planner is
kind of a cute little
planner of things that you should do on
various days when you're preparing
the week before an interview then i've
got a non-technical question bank
ltr uh learning the ropes 101 is a book
by andy gill
this is a cool little primer to
red teaming jobs um i've read it i think
it's a really good resource
it wasn't that relevant to the things
that i was
being interviewed for because it's
mainly for fan testers and offensive
security professionals
but if you're into that side of things
definitely check that out and you can
get that for free or for a donation
um so yeah it's a good resource and then
the last one is what happens then this
is the resource i was referencing
whenever
i said um i was talking about networking
um this is a great place to learn about
how the internet works
answering that question um is
is difficult but reading through
everything that's in that github repo
is a really good way to start so
uh yeah final thoughts uh
bring the water to your interview uh i
think that's super important i've
forgotten to do that some a few times
and it wasn't good
um minimize stress on the day so
uh you know come early prepare your
clothes in advance etc
it's easy to forget these things
especially if it's your first interview
but just ensure that the only stress is
coming from the actual interview not
from any
external factors if you can um learn to
manage stress
i've already talked about that the more
interviews you do the better you will be
so i've done a lot and i've definitely
noticed that my confidence has gone up
and i've gotten a lot better at asking
questions so
in my opinion you know if you can you
don't want your first interview
to be for your dream job so yeah
i think it's really important to do as
you know as many as
your time allows for um and yeah
remember that the worst case scenario is
that you interview somewhere else
so with that
magic time so i'm gonna try and turn on
the camera
um there i am now i really hope that
people can see me
um would can is there any way i can find
out
if it's working i'll just go ahead and
ask can anyone see
the camera at this point in time
it's not yet okay okay
so people can
right um well how about
um so i what i was going to do is start
off by demonstrating
a magic trick um how about i
show you the agenda um
no could i help you could i have you
close your slides
that might help
there's some resources as well but for
now
this should work right so um
how about i start talking and then
i wait for maybe two minutes to see if
the
video pops up for more people um
so uh card magic i started doing card
magic when i was about 16.
um i learned to from first from
a friend and then from some books um
i think it's a really really cool quote
the organizer has stopped sharing your
webcam sorry
that was a misclick that is fine
i will try to reshare uh
can you stop sharing the slides oh
hey that looks a lot better okay
is that working uh
it looks like it might be for people
i personally can't see the video on the
train so i can't
be reliable but it looks like okay other
people say you're good
okay cool right so um
what i'm going to do is i'm going to
start off with a demo of some magic
tricks that i am not going to teach
because they might be a little too
difficult to teach in
15 minutes then i'm going to show you a
trick
with an assistant who uh which i'm going
to actually teach you
and then i'm going to share some
resources and final thoughts and if
there's any time left over i'll show you
some more tricks
um so i really hope people can see me
otherwise this really doesn't make any
sense but
um i'm going to tell you the story of
the first time i saw magic so
um long story but i was face painting
somebody who was playing with cards
and he was shuffling in
quite a few cool ways i had never seen
anybody shuffle cards professionally i
was
you know 16 at the time had never been
in a casino or anything
but he was doing all this cool stuff and
i was really intrigued and i thought it
would be awesome to like
learn that um so i was face painting him
so i told him that he should show me a
magic trick or i'll screw up
i'd say and he said fine um so he told
me to pick a card
so i did um it was not the four of
hearts
but for the purposes of this
demonstration that does not matter
so he took my four of hearts he put it
somewhere
into the middle of the deck like this
he snapped his fingers and the four of
hearts came up on top
i said yeah you're not tricking me mate
that's too easy
because you've just got two fours apart
so he told me to write my name
oh great my pen doesn't actually work
i've got another one that's fine
i've claimed prepared this one also
doesn't work
could you pass me a sharpie from overlap
thank you sorry
so i wrote my name on the card
and he showed me the trick again so he
took my fork
uh put it into the middle of the deck
like that snapped his fingers
and the card came off on top now i was a
little angry at this point because i
really don't know not knowing how things
work so i asked him to show me how it
actually works
and he said fine i will so what he did
was he bent the card from the side
i'll show you why it's because that
means
if it's bent you can kind of see the
card like that so he let me watch in
real time what actually happens when he
puts the rest of the deck on top so
he put the rest of the deck on top and
told me to pull the invisible string
at the top of the deck so i did one two
three
and i don't know if you can see that
well but that bank card actually came up
on top again
now uh i was impressed but i wasn't
pregnant i
did not enjoy being tripped and some
people don't which is fine
but i said find g something with a
different card so um
i picked a random other card oh another
four nice that was not on purpose
and he said you know what you picked
this for but i actually want to keep
going with the other one so he just
wiped the card like that and it turned
into my
original four now
um i don't know how you guys are feeling
about this
but i didn't like it um my last
um the last trick that he showed me was
actually to do with a number
so there are currently 250
attendees watching this so i'm gonna
take
two plus five which is seven so he
he asked me to rename a random number um
i would name a random number but it's
easy if it's me
but i'm just going to show you that if
you go one two
three four five six
and seven that card was actually my card
no um i
i was pretty impressed and i asked this
person to teach me something he said no
but then later on he got a bit drunk and
did teach me something so i went home
learned to message him on facebook
because this was a long time ago um and
and asked me to and ask him to meet up
with me to
to to watch what i had learned um
i showed him he said it was terrible and
taught me how to do it better and shared
some resources
the same ones that i'm gonna share with
you um so that was the demonstration i'm
now going to
just check how much time i have left
cool
i'm now going to teach you a card trick
that you can
prepare at home if you do have a deck of
cards please use it to follow along
you won't need the whole thing you can
just use half if there's like two of you
or something the whole thing is fine as
well
um so um this
trick is a kind of mind-reading trick
and i'm going to show you how it works
so i have an assistant here dan
right here so he's the person that i'm
going to
show the trick to so could you just pick
any part
cool no please remember it i'm gonna
turn around if you could show it to the
camera
and don't let me see it and then put it
back against your chest when you're done
so i can't see it and let me know when i
can turn back
okay cool so um
say stop wherever you like but right
into the top
right okay and put your card just there
so uh now i'm gonna just found the cards
out like this
and i would just like you to confirm to
um
the you know to the audience to me that
the car is in fact
the card rather is in fact somewhere in
this deck
they wait until the end or it's yeah
right no funny stuff yeah cool
i'm gonna give these a shuffle and i'm
gonna read your mind so
um i'd like you to imagine the cards
just here focus on it really hard okay
now don't tell me i'm going to say a few
things don't
respond i'm just going to read your
facial features and try and figure out
which part it was based on them right so
it's either a red card or a black card a
red card or a black card you're slightly
smiling when i say
red so i know it's a red card it's
either
a diamond or a heart a diamond or a
heart okay i know it's a diamond
because once again just like smile okay
in diamonds we've got easter king so ace
two three four
five six seven eight nine ten jack but
somewhere there
seven eight nine ten nine nine was it
the nine of diamonds
it was yay that's the trick and i'm
going to teach you guys how to do that
oh thank you i don't need you anymore
um so
um i really want to share how important
presentation is
and that's kind of why i chose this
chart because the method is actually
quite simple
it includes a little bit of misdirection
it doesn't include very much
card handling which is great for
beginners um
and then the fun part is kind of making
it into a mind reading trick
obviously i can't read minds nobody can
read minds
uh there is the concept of cold reading
you can go and learn about that i don't
know if i believe in it still
um but this is how the chart works so
you ask your audience member to pick a
card
let's say they pick this i don't get to
see it i don't have to see it
i'm just going to put it there then you
turn around ask them to look at the card
to memorize it make sure you tell them
to memorize it
you always have to be really explicit
about what you tell your audience
otherwise they won't do it
um so then you ripple through the parts
like this
and this might not be so simple for some
people i recommend holding the cards
like so so i'm over here
fingers like this if you've got smaller
hands
you can use uh bridge sized cards
instead of poker sized cards that's just
a wee tip
um but hold the cards like this and use
this finger
and this thumb to grab them there and
then use this
index finger to kind of riffle them up
you can also do things like this
or this but that's too difficult for now
so just do this and tell them to say
stop for every what they want
so they say stop here and now
i tell them to put the card here now
this is where the misdirection happens
so the way this trick works
is that i remember a key card this is
the card that is going to be on top
of the other card and whenever so
if i show this to you with this card
face up so this is the secret card that
i don't know
so if i put this card face up i remember
the jack
which is here i put it on top of the
deck
then when i shuffle through what i'm
looking for
is this jack and i know that the card
next to it is going to be the secret
card
so let's try that again
so this is the selected card of course
my card
uh this is the select card i say
oh sorry i've got a little confused with
the cards there
cool um i say say stop
they say stop this is my key card i say
place the card here
and this is a really important move
because you're hiding the fact that
you're
looking at this card by pointing
so you're going place the card here
because obviously you don't want to go
say stop they say stop and you go
okay put your card there because that
kind of gives the trick away so
you say place your card there they put
their card there
you put your card on top now if you're a
little advanced you can now
shuffle in a way that will not disturb
those cards in the middle so
a way you could do that is using an
overhand shuffle where you take
a bit of cards from the top all of the
middle cards
and then just shuffle the rest of them
something like that
but you can learn all about that in your
time if you want
um and then you're just searching
through the cards and looking for your
key card
um and i know that my key card is the
five of spades so i know that the four
of hearts is then
their card so what i've done at that
point is and i asked them to verify
that the card is in the deck right
because your audience is always
suspicious of what's going on
and all i need to do is find out what
card it is that they picked
so at this point i know what the card is
and now it's completely up to me how to
play the
mind reading thing if you want you can
just take that card out and show it to
them and say that's your card
but that doesn't really build suspense
and magic in my opinion so a better way
to do it so i'm just checking the time
here
a better way to do it is to kind of put
on your mind-reading hat
and you know really go all out with the
theatrics
um it's up to you how you can do it you
can use a pen and paper you can do what
i did
um you know you can hold up red objects
and black objects is
really up to you um right i've got four
minutes left so i'm gonna
switch over to my slides again
and switch off my video
can i find out if this that's
working i see slides now
cool right so yeah these are the
the resources that i recommend so um
in terms of free resources 52 cards and
disturbing
reality on youtube are really fantastic
for teaching tricks
and these two books the royal road card
magic and that's card card technique
are kind of the standard in terms of
learning magic i really recommend the
royal route card magic as the books that
i
um started with if you are going to buy
it please buy
from you know not amazon um
i think it's about 12 pounds uh which is
what 15
or something like that um you probably
can find
um a free version somewhere not when i'm
advocating for it but if you are
strapped for cash
you know there are ways um
expert card technique is also great um i
would start with the royal road first
though
and the royal road is really like
standard uh
i think anybody that's interested in
learning magic should
read that book um and most importantly
practice what that book says
um if you are rich you can also buy the
video version of the royal root card
magic
um i've heard it's fantastic i have not
bought it because it's about
90 pounds which is you know over a
hundred dollars so
uh not for a student like myself um you
can find
links to these things at hella lucas.com
links which you can see in the bottom
left-hand corner of the slide
um this study guide again the study
guide
again this isn't links i didn't make
this this is something i found
on the internet i didn't use the study
guide when i was learning
i'm not sure if it was around at the
time but it's got a really
good list of kind of basic techniques
and shuffles and
stuff like that that uh that you can
learn
uh if you're into this i would really
recommend using the study guide and then
buying
uh the royal world card magic or doing
both at once
um the study guide covers some of the
stuff the royal road does
um a question i get a lot is what cards
do i need so the cards i'm using are
bicycle cards you will see a lot of
magicians using these
uh the reason is that they've got a very
nice kind of coating which means they
are easy to
to fan and to shuffle and to kind of
manipulate
you don't have to use these cards by any
means you will find
the card handling a little easier if you
do i think um one thing
um to know uh if you are a student like
me you can also get the bicycle
seconds which are like the factory
seconds they are significantly cheaper
than the standard ones
if you do get into this i mean you can
go through about a deck
like a week or something just if you're
performing and you're destroying cards
or you
you know get the cards although i
suppose with social distancing in place
right now you're probably fine just
using the standard ones because you
won't be going out anyway
um so yeah um but either of these works
um you can also use just regular playing
cards that you can pick up in any
uh shop um but these ones will make your
life
easier and yeah i just wanted to share
the reason behind
people and magicians using these so
often it's because of the finish
they're just nicer to handle um they're
not kind of
magic in any way although you can get
through that
um final note this stuff is really hard
uh you're building
muscle memory in your hands that isn't
something that you can just learn
that is literally you know your body
adapting to do things
um you know you'll have to build
strength in your fingers and
stuff so yeah just give yourself time to
learn that
and i really recommend practicing
presentation
in front of a middle mirror and then on
willing humans
um you know it's it's it's easy
ish well it's difficult to learn the
tricks themselves but then it's a whole
never
another level of difficulty to learn how
to present them in an entertaining way
uh it's not something that i have really
um
practiced that much but the real like
really good performers
also know how to make most simple tricks
into something that will blow your mind
um watch the masters i've listed a few
there
um i think they're great and if you're
just sitting around practicing
watching somebody that is really really
good at magic is very motivating
um a lot of places will have local magic
groups but obviously
right now is probably not the best time
to join them uh but yeah there's the
international brotherhood of magicians
um yeah brotherhood sad oh well um the
magic circle
university societies and meetup.com all
will have local chapters in um
or at least some of them will have local
chapters um
so yeah i recommend those um if you can
at this time
support your local magicians and magic
shop haven't really figured out how
especially your local magicians maybe
pay them to teach you or something but
yeah this is going to be a really hard
time for the magic community
uh because it's difficult to do the
stuff of a video
um and if you're not a cis fan this is
your space too like they're
the like women in cyber security are
scarce women and magic are even scarcer
like it is
really bad so yeah please like
feel welcome to be in that space um
it's really important to have
representation
so i am out of time
and yeah thank you for your time i can
take some questions i think i've got
like
a few minutes if there are any please
find all the resources
and under links and yeah that's my dog
yeah there's uh just a couple questions
uh one is asking do you like camera or
copay cards do you like one more time
sorry
do you like kim kilo echo mic or copay
charlie oscar papa echo golf uh
cards i'm not familiar i assume those
are brands
i i'm not sure what that means so
i'm sorry i don't know
these things these things do happen uh
and there's
uh someone else uh
seeing something about wax braiding is
that something there
wax braiding that might be to do with
the finish on bicycle cards
um it sounds like they could be what
those cards are covered in but i'm not
sure
um i i i think it's clarification of the
prior
question apparently those kind are made
from the plastic
composite material uh i think the being
the standard playing card type
oh right okay yeah so plastic cards are
great
if you perform outside because they
are more resistant to like water and
stuff but um
yeah for um for kind of inside
and practice and stuff paper cards are a
lot friendlier and they hurt your hands
less as well which is nice
right on all right well thank you very
much for presenting
a very informative talk and uh
you did have your twitter handle on
there earlier so thank you very much for
presenting for us at pancakes con in
track two
and i'll put the video and start setting
up the next talk
but uh at the moment you're all set
thank you very very much
thank you bye
alrighty so pancakes come