show banter for the 177 now wow
people that are that are logged in um i
just saw you what it's been uh
a week and no gosh i i believe it was
three years ago we saw each other
it feels like at least um
right yeah i think uh crisis time
yeah yeah yeah in fact i believe it was
only uh yeah only two weeks
right yeah the beginning of march which
feels
so long ago now there was there was a
i think it feels like that was like a
distinctive
point um and then like
the monday after that it's just like
okay the world is now changed
yeah yeah right i don't know if i told
you or not uh when we were there like
i actually like made the decision
on the fly that i was i was not flying
right from from nova i drove 10 hours
home
oh no oh yeah i canceled like so right
after we stopped talking i
um like it hit an inflection point and i
i had uh i basically called the car
rental company and had uh
well that morning i called the car
rental company and had you know
basically
uh changed my rental to drop off in
augusta
because i was already up there you know
in the northern virginia area for a uh
columbia maryland for a thing um and i
changed and canceled my flight because
i'm like i'm not getting
i'm just not doing it and uh since then
i haven't been back out like that was
the last time i was in public without a
respirator
really yeah i so our
our conversation actually prompted me to
uh do a little more prep like personal
prep like
uh i thought like oh my gosh what would
happen
if i could not go out for two weeks
what do i need right and like a lot of
what we talked about
helped me like get a leg up on
what i would need well then i'm glad we
had that conversation although
and and i guess now this is going to be
wildly public um but
uh actually no never mind i i i almost
i i'll i'll dm you later how about that
yeah yeah i now realize now that we're
in pre-show venture i'd better uh yes
anyway um yeah so yeah and the attendee
account is climbing
rapidly uh 300 now all right so i was
just gonna say uh so john strand just
finished his keynote
and track two is now uh
in their pre-show setup so
uh let's give people the extra two
minutes
uh uh because as you can see the uh
numbers are climbing and so happy to
have all these attendees here
definitely definitely i'm like uber
excited about this and hey for those
that are like joining this
and thinking like hey where is the
original speaker who is supposed to be
here
um they have a uh
basically have an issue with uh uh
basically an issue a coronavirus related
issue and so there's a
i had to sub somebody in and the irony
of that is not lost on me that we're
having this conference in the first
place because of that
and and literally it just i mean yeah i
i can't say enough about everybody that
that's here
and and everybody that helped put this
together and alyssa
and you know for moderating and just i
mean this volunteer effort from the
community to make this happen just but
just been phenomenal
thank you by the way alyssa for being
here to moderate because wow
yeah i'm happy and um all right it seems
like the
numbers of folks coming in is getting a
little steady
um my clock is still reading uh 10 45
a.m eastern standard
up just hit 10 45 eastern standard time
so um i know i'm personally really
excited for this
uh and i don't want to delay it any
further so here's jake williams with
his cti and analysis pitfalls and
paramedic lessons learned so uh let's
get ready
let's let's do this um okay so let me
make sure that we are
play and go can you see my screen still
yep winning okay well let's let's do
this um okay um so for those that don't
know me my name is jake williams
mal or jake on twitter i own rendition
information
security renditions rendition infosec
man it's been one of those days
um i i actually was not slated to speak
here originally
um but was one of the helpers i was
actually moderating track one
um and uh we had an emergency this
morning uh where a speaker had to drop
out
due to their own uh well you know the
whole reason that we're here in the
first place right that we can't do it in
person con
because of coronaviruses so here we are
um you know so i'll tell you these are
not my
best slides ever particularly for the
paramedic part otherwise
um we're just we're just gonna rock
through this because that's it right
um so i wanna walk through uh some of
kent's analytic doctrine
and uh i've given this talk longer form
a couple of times before
i'll try to find a link for one of those
uh later today in fact you can even see
down here on the bottom i had so little
time
like the old copyright 2019 is on there
like just the whole like set man how bad
right but
let's talk about kent's analytic
doctrine because it's it's a rockin uh
absolutely rockin analysis platform or
analysis uh
paradigm and there are so few people
that actually follow this and i'll tell
you it drives me nuts because
um you know if you worked in
intelligence for any period of time and
for those that don't know
i did uh for 18 years as part of the
intelligence community
and cancer analytic doctrine is
something that we uh well that we do a
lot with right
it's something that you learn as an
analyst and some people don't know it by
name but
um they learn the analytic principles
and and what i've seen
uh in infosec as a broader community is
that
we are trying to reinvent the wheel on a
consistent basis right
um where we say well i mean this is
un unprecedented how many times were the
word unprecedented in the last couple
weeks right but but we run into all
these problems right we're like well how
can we do this analysis because
we've never had to do analysis like this
before and it turns out the cancer
analytic doctrine
from world war ii era right it turns out
that it still applies we don't have to
reinvent the wheel
everything isn't new right it says
doctor has been taught to formal
intelligence analysts
for decades right now i'm not going to
say that you have to use these analytic
principles
what i will say is that the entire
u.s intelligence community and many
others around the world do
now if you come up with your own
analytic principles if you're like screw
can't right first off don't don't say
that but if you're like
hey you know can't uh totally didn't
know what he was doing
i can do better right one or two things
is happening either you are a true
visionary and and i
can't discount that possibility an
infinite realm of possibilities or
you're doing it wrong right now i'm not
a betting man but if i were
i can tell you where we'd be going right
um for whatever reason
a lot of folks and i say that for
whatever reason i mean i know the reason
right a lot of the folks that are doing
cti
uh all of a sudden uh they get drug into
and other infosec analysis in general
they basically have a lot of technical
skills but they're missing the analytic
skills and
and people get so mad when i say this
like you're missing analytics skills
part what are you saying about me but
but listen i mean
we can apply a model to this and make it
go and trust me uh doing this
uh will indeed make it go so um nine
steps to success right these are the
nine
principles of kent's analytic doctrine i
will absolutely make the slide deck
available in fact i'll make the full
slide deck available
i had to cut some stuff out of this
because the time but i'll make the full
slide deck available
after uh basically after the
presentation these are the nine steps
success screenshot this slide if you
take nothing else away from that
screenshot this
uh print it out put it in your cubicle
well when you go back and have a cubicle
in the meantime put it on your desk at
the work from home and ask yourself
consciously are you doing these things
right
um so number one focus on policymaker
concerns avoid a personal policy agenda
apply intellectual rigor take conscious
effort to avoid analytic biases consider
outside judgments right this is a big
one for us because everybody in infosec
knows it all right um and look i'll tell
you too the longer you spend an info
second the more experiences you have
the more likely it is you're like yeah
i've seen that i've got that right but
you have to really consider outside
judgments because
nobody is basically it's the whole uh
all of us
is smarter than one of us no sorry one
of us is wow anyway look
bottom line i learned teaching sans over
a period of many years
that collectively the students in the
room
knew way more than i did right and and
on any given topic there was someone in
the room that could best me on a given
topic
that's just the reality of it right and
so you have to be ready to consider
those outside judgments
systematic use of outside experts this
is a huge one collective responsibility
for judgment
effective communication and then candid
admission of mistakes
big big one there because nobody likes
to say and i was wrong let's dive into
some of these right i want to start out
here by mentioning cti has a credibility
problem right i speak to a lot of
executives i do a lot of board briefings
i actually have one tomorrow um but uh
remotely of course
um but there's a lot of reasons for this
right as far as a credibility problem
but i'll tell you that using models are
going to help alleviate this because
because it just will right you want to
adopt and adhere to models
that are going to remove these
credibility problems and the reality
here is that models are going to
help get consistency and it's a show
your work kind of thing because if you
don't show your work
and you just go to an executive and you
say here's what i think or a decision
maker doesn't have to be an executive
a manager a decision maker we are we do
analysis we are in
in the business of decision support we
are providing folks with data
to help them make a decision and so when
we then
when we then have to uh basically and we
then have to
provide that data but we don't show our
work uh it is a reality
that uh folks come back and they're like
well you know
why do you think this and the reality is
too they can find another analyst who
thinks something different
right and so i want to make sure that i
can say here's my work here are the
steps that i took
here's the model that i followed and
again we'll get more consistent results
for that
so let's talk about the doctrine right
number one focus on policy maker
concerns this is tough right because
at the end of the day every organization
is funded by somebody i'm going to give
you a very unpopular
very unpopular piece of advice and
people argue with me all the time about
this
infosec is a cost center infosec has
never
saved an organization a single dollar
they
only cost infosec only cost the
organization's money
now now listen i know we can talk about
cost avoidance and we can talk about
but listen my friends this is not how
executives work when they employ a
safety program
for cost avoidance they don't then say
look at all the money we save
and when you go in there and you start
talking about like hey
right we are we're saving you money
right that's a huge huge thing right
look they they immediately are losing
credibility with them and you have to
come in and say
and focus on specific concerns at the
business unit level right all the way
down to the bu the business unit level
right
i always ask for feedback on my
reporting how can i make this product
more valuable to you do not ask for the
love of goodness do not ask did you like
this product
avoidance of personal policy agenda
listen my friends
i i can't do objective reporting on i
have a hard time
doing objective reporting um on uh
incidents that have threat actors around
russia because you may or may not know i
kind of have a history there
um and uh good old russian intelligence
there and the shadow brokers folks and
and all that and look i have a hard time
writing about that we know that
i recognize that um and i get other
analysts to help you see my work
or just do it in the first place because
i know
specifically here i have a real personal
policy
agenda and i know that i have a problem
being objective here right so
find your own personal policy spaces and
either don't do that work or get other
analysts right diversify here get other
analysts on board to help you with that
but recognize and tell them be honest
with them and say look like
i can do analysis i can do a lot of
analysis but this analysis
now that i can't be unbiased about this
and and
and that's just a reality and it's one
that i wish wasn't the case
i would love to tell you like i can
totally be that guy and i cannot run it
but you have you have to be honest with
yourself right
one of the ways you can do this of
course is ask an unbiased reader to
assess whether
they think you've included any agenda
points in reporting now
now that unbiased reader i have to tell
you may themselves have other biases and
they may be like yeah you totally are
putting
kind of like the cnn versus fox news
thing right you know we're like
folks look if you're a big fox uh fox
person you're like well cnn clearly is
the
you know whatever they're clearly fake
news and vice versa right so you might
have some
some personal policy agenda kind of
thing without realizing that unbiased
reader made so
so just be really careful there but but
this is a big one a personal policy
agenda
absolutely destroys the credibility of
your analysis it destroys the
credibility of your reporting
and the problem is that once you lose
that credibility on something it may be
something small
when you go back and try and do
something big right
you've already lost that credibility and
that is not a win it's just not a win
at all right so an actual rigor cti
reports are going to rely on analysts to
fill in missing information
and unfortunately this creates a huge
consistency gap in cti analysis or
analysis in general
i've never performed an analysis ever
where i've had all the information it
doesn't happen and i tell people
regularly
if you don't like ambiguity cyber threat
intelligence
is the wrong and i mean the
wrong profession for you in general
analysis is probably the wrong
profession for you because you
are not going to have all of the data
you're never going to have all the data
and you
still have to go in and fill that in now
when you do that when you make
assumptions sometimes you're accused of
making stuff up right um and and some
folks accuse folks of that right
look here's the deal i always tell
people right
always tell people when i've made
assumptions and what those assumptions
are
so there's a couple things here with
intellectual worker first off use models
use structured analytic techniques
richard hoyer
on the uh psychology of intelligence
analysis it's phenomenal buy the book
right you have time on your hands go get
the book bottom line
huge one there use models you will get
more consistency
give credit to others right but
communicate the models that you're using
so i want to talk about conscious effort
to avoid analytic biases
most cti reports that i read today they
are chock full of analytic biases most
cti analysts are not trained in another
biases however
and this is critical your executives are
because most of them have mbas and
that's just a reality
right it's your executive directors and
even a lot of mid-level managers right
and the gmat the the test that you take
to get into an mba program
it turns out that the gmat actually has
a section on analysis and argumentation
and this should surprise literally
nobody that's watching this
what do you know um there's a whole
section in that
on analytic biases so they've been
trained on spotting them
and if you have not you are probably
putting them in your writing now i have
bad news for you
even when you learn the analytic biases
it is really hard as it turns out
to find them in your own writing i know
this because i train other people on
detecting analytic biases
and i still end up with them in my own
writing and so what i need there is good
peer review i need
to train my team on the analytic biases
because i want my team to
find them before i'm publishing a report
before i'm creating those talking points
that decision support to my executives
and directors all right so train your
team
if you build up this big team around
this is a rising tide raises all ships
kind of moment
build that team up around you right and
they are going to help you
dramatically right i see a question here
where it says diversify diversify your
peer review
a thousand percent diversifier peer
review right because that's going to be
huge within this but your peer review
has to know what your executives know
and that's again the analytic biases
side
we want them to be able to pick those
out and be like hey you just use a straw
man there's a texas sharpshooter
you're cherry picking data this is i
mean this is important you need to be
able to do that right
so huge huge huge there one of the ways
that we do this
is through doing peer review of
published intelligence reports
do a lunch and learn literally sit down
everybody's got a copy of it they come
in
over some pizza and then you fire away
and beat up on that report
game on willingness to consider other
judgments you are not always right
i am not always right period there are
others on your team with different
experience that may lead them to a
different and even better conclusion
i have a quick story here all right
quick quick story here about
um this woman that we hired out of fedex
and i don't mean fedex corporate i mean
fedex kinkos or now fedex whatever drop
and ship fedex office i think
um holy goodness uh so we end up doing
this
uh like she was doing a bunch of
shipping for us she was awesome
uh like shipping for us like when we
went and dropped stuff off and uh we
realized she had great attention to
detail and we're like hey
do you want to train to be a sock
analyst and what do you know she had
already taken like one year of college
and then dropped out
whatever but around cyber security and
then all of a sudden we ended up with
this problem
an incident with a logistics company
and what do you know like all of a
sudden she knows stuff
that like we didn't right because i
don't work in logistics
right but she had and wow mind blown
like she was amazingly helpful
right now i want to tell you though that
you know
it takes a lot to come down and be like
hey um
other judgments here she's like yeah i
mind you brand new soccer analyst three
months into the job
right and she's kind of running point on
not the forensic side of this incident
but like
coordinating the incident understanding
like you know some of the what was at
stake and just unique insights here you
have to be willing to consider other
judgments
period right so getting through this
i want to come through to systematic use
of outside experts right
if you're awesome cti someone else in
your org is probably better than you at
many technical topics
period one of the best things about
conferences and we will eventually get
back to in-person conferences
freaking network if you see me at a
conference and you see me in a talk
it is almost certainly because it's one
of my friends that's giving the talk
you will not see me in talks generally
right the vast majority of the time you
will see me in lobbycon
and you will see me networking with
people and there's a reason for this i'm
building up my rolodex right and if
you're one of these young guns who's
like what's a rolodex i mean my contact
list right
i'm building up that contact list so
that i can phone a friend so when i run
into a problem
i can pick up the phone twitter dm email
exchange those business cards it's
absolutely huge build that network of
experts out
right um i i just cannot tell you enough
what a
big big deal this is right uh facilitate
that easy access to outside experts from
da
whatever right um but uh you need to
facilitate that up front if you have
super
you know like you want to make sure that
you're not from daying something
uh then get some people nd aid with you
right this is uh build that rolodex of
exports as you can call
i'll tell you too that um one of the
ways that i fix this
in my own organization is that uh you
know like
when people think they're only going to
get like a shout out like
or a bonus or whatever if it's them that
does something
then that's the individual wins and i'm
gonna tell you like when you start
focusing on team wins
right like the the whole team one kind
of thing that's when people stop
worrying about the did i do it or did
somebody else do it right like whatever
that piece of analysis is there so
that's a big one for me uh focus on the
team wins i mean yes give individuals
credit by all means but but then you
talk about like how the
whole team came together and again it it
really takes some of the wind out of the
sails right where people would otherwise
be or sometimes otherwise
are a little bit uh yes anyway
uh collective responsibility for
judgment you may disagree behind closed
doors about the analysis but when the
report is issued the whole team stands
behind it right the whole team
period stands behind it when you can't
reach a consensus
have the dissenting parties document
their alternate opinion writing just
like in our court system
just like in our court system dissenting
opinion goes into writing put an
appendix by all means
but and this is absolutely key you do
not sharp shoot once the report gets
released
you don't like it's not one of those
like well you know
i disagreed and i'm no no it's the whole
team stands behind it
right i i cannot tolerate that on teams
uh once you've released the report
everybody's lockstep right that
this was the collective judgment again
you may not have agreed with it
but it is the collective judgment and
that's the party line right now
we're kind of seeing a little bit of
that to the detriment uh obviously
you know we hope that the judgments are
good we're seeing some of the must
adhere to the party line uh being a
detriment here in some of
our uh you know some of what we're
seeing in the world now but rock on
again you don't play that game come to
that judgment uh
collective responsibility for it and
again walk down that party line again
you see here or the fixing it team wins
right when you do team wins versus
individual wins
that's it right that that creates a big
uh you know a big incentive to be
you know to begin to contribute to the
team rather than trying to contribute to
you communication communication
communication your analysis
is worthless if the audience can't
understand what you're saying
and how you reached your conclusion oh
my gosh if there's
one thing you can do to really change
the game here for you it is put time
into your executive summary
and create one slider presentations
illustrations help you'll notice
that a lot of my slides here have
illustrations right because i have a
graphics artist on retainer
i subscribe to multiple services that
help me go find these illustrations and
stock art and all that all right put
time into these right a picture's worth
a thousand words
and the executive summary is the only
thing that most people read
in the vast majority of the time it is
way way
way way too technical get a reviewer
with similar experience to your audience
right find an executive
find a mid-level manager look cyber is
sexy right now it just is
and people want to help out with it and
that's it right so
find a reviewer it's well worth i mean
just
well well worth your time right um so
make that executive summary
non-technical too
and the other thing i try to ask folks
to do is i try to get them to back brief
me
my reviewer i try to get them to back
freak me on like what did you hear
right like what did you take away from
this and i want to share a quick story
with you where um i got some iocs from a
gentleman
many years ago and i'm shaving the story
way down if you've heard the full
version it is way funnier
uh but but just for time i'll just tell
you here that uh communication
is is a thing right because i asked this
grc person for some indicators of
compromise he agreed to hand some over
and one of the indicators that he handed
over was small kittens
and i have to tell you when i looked at
this indicator list and they were all
bad indicators meaning they were all
useless indicators um because he was grc
i get that i'm not judging governor
source compliance by the way um
obviously if i'm asking grc for iocs
right we've reached the bottom of the
barrel right and that's where we're at
right sometimes best bad plan wins
this is my best bad plan and i got back
small kittens and it taught me a lot
about communication
because i asked him uh well first i
asked my analyst sitting beside me what
do you think he means by small kittens
and uh and he says uh yeah uh
anyway uh i don't know all right did he
have a stroke i'm like i don't know
all right so i go ask another analyst
what does he mean by small kittens and
the guy says and i'll never forget this
my other animal says
do you think he means me cats and i'm
like no no i don't
i don't think he means me me cats
because he wrote small kittens
then i started following the logic and i
think we're playing like beautiful mind
home edition here right
and straight up i hit back to the guy
and i'm like hey did you mean
me cats and he's like yeah many cats
small kittens
communication was lacking here right
what happened was somebody briefed him
and said mimi cats and he did not
mentally understand what mimikatz meant
but his brain did what our brains are
tuned to do
and his brain said ah word association
that sounded like miniature cats and
later when he couldn't remember many
cats
his brain did other association and said
small kittens for the win
and so we got small kittens and small
kittens were absolutely destroying the
network and i would pay good money to
know what the mental picture was there
obviously where it's never going to
happen but if you ask him did you
understand what i said he would say yes
because mentally
he thought that small kittens many cats
were running around the network
obviously we did not convey here because
it was too technical
for the audience right dump the techno
jargon get rid of it and even when
people think they're dumping the techno
jargon
they're not get a review or a similar
experience level technical experience
level
to your intended audience let them
review it let
them tell you that you're good or not
you can't be the arbiter there right
you can't be the arbiter of will this
person understand and look the worst
thing that can possibly happen is you've
communicated something
you think that that they understood and
they didn't understand
right so canada mission of mistakes
my friends you will make mistakes coming
back to earlier
analysis paralysis and the fact that we
have
the fact that we have a lot of cases
right where
we have to operate with incomplete
information also known as
all of the cases we have to operate with
incomplete information
nobody likes to do that but but you have
to right
and and there are times you're going to
be wrong you're just going to be wrong
and and when that happens you have got
to turn around and re the people that
you gave decision support advice to
you have to go back and adjust that and
say listen
we made some assumptions here and they
were wrong we we
did the best we could with the
information we had and we were wrong
and here's our new assessment i'm going
to tell you the first couple times you
do that
generally my experience is you take a
credibility hit with stakeholders you
just do
and that sucks it's not fair by the way
it's absolutely not fair
right you did the best you could with
the information you had and intelligence
and
intelligence analysts know this and
intelligence stakeholders
know this and in business people totally
don't track this
and it's okay all right you're gonna get
over it trust me
just and somebody put in chat here mia
culpa would need it it's not even a mia
culpa
right it's a educating and
making sure that people understand you
are operating without
if you were clear in your communication
in the first place they already knew you
made assumptions because you told
them where the assumptions were at and
you told them what they were based on
and that's all in your report but then
you come back and you're like hey
these assumptions i made based on my
best judgment based on my analytic
experience
they were still wrong foster
a culture on your team or issuing a
corrected report is not a big deal
it is way better you are you are
creating a
better scenario giving the updated
decision support
right then you are letting them roll
with
bad and and still thinking you're
awesome right the first couple times you
do it i'm going to tell you
like it's a hit it absolutely is a
credibility it's a personal ego hit
it's a credibility hit within the
organization but i'm going to tell you
that
once somebody makes a a judgment on your
updated
decision support trust me they will come
back around
it's it's a it's kind of one of those
like you're coming up in credibility and
then it's like the first couple times
you want these you're dropping in
credibility and then you skyrocket
you skyrockets people know your leaders
know
that they can count on you to level set
with them even when
poop goes wrong right okay so real quick
here
i'm going to close out this analysis
portion with if you only remember
one thing and i'm going to come back to
this come back to the slide up here for
a second
right the nine steps success right one
four
six and nine those are the big ones if
you can't do nine and i get it right
start with the first start with four
one four six and nine
right policy maker concerns focus on
what matters to them not what matters to
you i don't write reports for me
right i mean if if i could that'd be
great i'd have more fun with it right
four avoid the analytic biases six
use outside experts you are not an
expert in everything
i am not an expert in everything right
candid admission of mistakes
build that credibility right because
again like the worst thing that can
happen is
you're like well i don't want to look
bad so i'm not going to give them the
updated assessment
and then somebody later right a week a
month whatever later makes a
decision that impacts the business based
on the old data that you have not
amended right
and just because you know something
changed does not mean your stakeholders
know that something changed
right you may be like well that's big
news i don't need to like let them know
that no no you absolutely do right this
is you know again
it's field of view by us there right
you're like everyone must know what i
know that got updated and
don't do that right on the effective
communication though i'm going to tell
you
i learned a lot from colin powell and
there's a couple of different versions
of this uh this quote going around
but it's tell me what you think tell me
what you know but for god's sakes
always tell me which is which and i just
cannot be
any uh cannot be any heavier about that
you know make sure that there's a clear
distinction between what you think
versus what you know and make sure that
your stakeholders understand
which of those it is so
because pancakes con is a two track or
kind of a two whatever
you know talk here i'm actually going to
go through some paramedic lessons
learned
for those that don't know that was
actually my first job right so way way
back in the day
it turns out there are actually a lot of
paramedics in security and incident
response emt
firefighter what have you um i i can
give you like a partial list of ones i
know about uh matt linton
um is a is an emt matt blaze is another
emt
uh matt blais does a bunch with the
voting stuff matt linton's over at
google there's a bunch of other i mean
just like lists of folks that have been
in first response
uh first responder search and rescue
that kind of
those kind of scenarios like i even have
the tattoo you know
like the uh yeah for the good old
paramedic days and
anyway um so paramedic lessons learned
right
um so this stuff by the way i threw
together this morning because this was
totally impromptu
that i was going to give a talk this
morning and rock on
game on we're here um but lesson learned
number one your personal safety matters
most
you cannot help a patient uh or anybody
else for that matter if you get hurt
yourself and these are life lessons by
the way i want to clarify too
um while i'm going to talk in the
context of paramedic you know an
emergency response and the whole
in crisis response uh this stuff applies
unilaterally right so your personal
safety matters most you have to stay in
the game and so
you know the way i transition this to
incident response is
get sleep right because if you don't
sleep
and if you fall out of the game if
you're so critical that you can't go
home
you gotta work 23 hours a day right by
the way it drives you nuts every time
they have a white house press briefing
over the last couple weeks
he's working 24 hours a day he's getting
like no sleep and i'm like god please
get sleep
you need sleep right kind of thing
bottom line your personal safety matters
most right
you can't help a patient if you get hurt
yourself um and you sure can't help the
next patient and the next one on the
next one
and you're consuming more emergency
resources if you get hurt yourself not
only
are you taking yourself out of the game
right you and somebody that has to care
for you too right
you have to have to use personal safety
first and i'm going to share a story
here that
i don't think i've ever shared publicly
before but i'm going to anyway
um my mom used to be a paramedic as well
while
she was a cardiac attack uh virginia
that's an emti
for those that uh you know are outside
of virginia
and know virginia's got a weird
licensing model um anyway
uh so uh but we used we used to uh roll
together
in the buckhannon uh emergency rescue
squad there
uh buchanan ems and uh we rolled out and
my mom
has three boys i'm the oldest of three
and uh she's got a soft spot for a
soft spot for boys and uh this kid took
his car out
and his parents of uh his parents were
actually gone
uh getting uh basically driving down to
greensboro to buy him a car
and bring it back for him and uh he took
their car out
on one of these windy roads wasn't you
know speeding around
on a 16th birthday wasn't wearing a
seatbelt uh or may not bend exactly his
birthday whatever but like
wasn't wearing a seatbelt gets ejected
from the vehicle um swerves to miss a
deer hits the bank it's ejected from the
vehicle he's pinned
or at least partially pinned under the
vehicle and
uh i rolled the crash truck my mom
rolled the uh
rolled the ambulance um actually one of
my brothers with one of my brothers i
was also an emt
and i it was the last call i ever ran
with my mom i just thought i i can't i
can't ever run a call with you again
um because i i put an airbag if you're
not familiar with these these are these
basically help you lift a vehicle
uh or can lift move whatever they are
very powerful airbag so the compressor
air power is phenomenal
um and uh put an airbag and and i i had
unpinned the uh person but but you need
cribbing right because that airbag can
pop
the compressor can this the valve
there's all kinds of stuff that could go
wrong and so every crash truck has
cribbing with it um
and cribbing is is basically lots of
lumber that you use to go pin stuff
and you know get stuff in place and and
she
literally like dove into this ditch and
dragged this kid back out from under
without
and i'm horrified i mean i just was
horrified and
and i i then realizing this kid needed
airlift because we're an hour from i
mean almost an hour from the hospital
45 minutes from hospital at that point
um
i i moved to the local high school like
i redeployed uh to the high school and
set up the landing zone for the uh for
the life flight
um and uh and all that got got them you
know coming in and my mom you know rolls
in afterwards and
and uh just i mean the kid died the next
day anyway there was not
realistically i think we kind of knew
that that was that was going to be the
case
um just just based on you know his
condition but um
i told her then and we never ran a call
together again um because
i i can't i mean like there's this is
always important but when it's family
it's it's just
it's critical important right it's your
personal safety matters the most
um always be calm even when you don't
want to be always be calm
right and uh this is something that i'm
having to practice with my kid right now
um you know is to be calm even when you
don't want to be put a brave face on
stuff even when you don't want you know
even when you don't want to
when you freak out so do your patients
right if you've got kids if you've got
significant others if you've got
whatever it is around you right um
you've got
to be calm right you just have to be
right put that brave face on stuff
go break go go in the toilet you know go
in the bathroom turn on the fan so
nobody here run some water
and and ball right language
sorry freaking ball
by all means right uh and and and look
that's fine that that's okay
right even when you feel like freaking
out though don't put a brave face on it
and and go do that another time right
that's that's just the reality of how it
works right so
uh when you freak out so do the people
around you they're going to read your
body language they're going to read what
you're what you're doing what you're
the way you're acting you gotta you
gotta do it right so
anyway it's never as bad as it looks
right this is the uh this is another big
one for me it's never as bad as it looks
okay
sometimes it actually is right um i i
have countless like
gore or whatever stories um you know
here and
but i'm just gonna tell you like uh you
can't let the patient know that all
right so
even you know and again this kind of
pivots off of off a number two always
remain calm right
but but the reality is you are gonna
have time to decompress later
um you know this this too shall pass um
you just put one foot in front of the
other and you keep
right on moving and that's that's that's
just it right
uh put one front one foot in front of
the other uh keep on moving i'll tell
you that my military experience
really helped with that you know i i i
can tell you for sure i know exactly
where my breaking point is
um because uh they they
took me right to it uh intentionally so
right there's
the there are folks in different
programs um that uh the the whole
purpose of the program is is to
push you farther than than than you
believe is possible
um and i'll just say uh you know there's
know where your breaking point is at or
at least nowhere
where if you don't know where break is
at least know where
know where the furthest you've ever been
is all right and uh just just be ready
to roll to that and and
and use that as use it as an anchor be
like yep this sucks but
it wasn't as bad as that right um yep
this is bad but it wasn't as bad as that
story i heard this other time yeah this
is bad but it wasn't as bad as
and keep right on rolling right because
again no matter how bad uh it looks now
it's just not as bad as it looks sorry
just keep putting one foot in front of
the other
do your thing and decompress later
and and this one's important right this
i think um and this is the last slide
that i've got here and i might kick a
couple of stories here if i've got time
or answer questions or whatever
um so by the way somebody mentioned that
they're not
seeing slides only my slides are showing
right
uh just just to confirm here alissa can
you confirm my slides are showing
because i see somebody saying they only
see a webcam
okay confirm rock on okay i just i'm
looking in questions and i was like oh
no
kind of if i've been going this whole
time and enough slides what's going on
okay
cool uh so full screen there that may be
the issue
um so okay so lesson learned number four
is it's okay to not be okay
all right i posted this on twitter
yesterday i'm just gonna throw out here
i was not okay yesterday
um and uh i i may be better today right
we'll see um but uh it's okay to be not
okay all right um you know there
you know there there are times you're
going to see and experience
stuff and i think that you know
certainly as a paramedic i i saw and
experience stuff that that i'm just
going to
you know say nobody should have to see
and endure things that nobody should
have to endure
right and over time it eats away at
everybody
and there are people in here who are
like manly man and
not me kind of thing and i'm gonna tell
you too i was that guy
i was absolutely that guy i'm like i
will never you know like i
i'm it doesn't matter right like people
dying doesn't matter right uh you know i
i yeah
anyway um and and it eats away at you
over time right
decompress find somebody to talk to be
open about your feelings right and just
be like
yeah this this is this is hurting me man
you know and and we
i mean just reality right um
yeah um reality-wise uh it's it's gonna
you know i i think just the reality is
that before this is all over
you know i mean i think we're all gonna
know somebody and and that uh you know
that didn't come through and um i'll say
uh you know i'm seeing in the chat or
former leo had to do cpr on a four year
old didn't help
right um yeah no that sucks it sucks
brother i'm here
right i i yes um you know i had a
question for my kid
uh you know a few months back and she's
like hey did you have you ever done
because they were talking about cpr
and you know cpr on the high milk
maneuver at school and all that and
she's like did you ever have to do cpr
on anybody i'm like
yeah she's like how many times i'm like
i lost count right like i
i just lost count she's like how many of
them made it i'm like not as many as
died right i mean just
reality right um and uh you know it's
it's it's
that's crappy right and it's it it kids
it's horrible with kids it's horrible
with people that have
you know that you know have families
it's just it's bad right
um you know and uh but the reality is
it's okay to be not okay
find someone to talk to today right and
that that probably is is a great spot
for me to kind of
you know to kind of close out with and
just say like um you know
if you're okay today and you're like
yeah i don't i don't need this right
um you do you totally do i i i was that
guy
right and and maybe this is life life
lessons but like you know i was
certified as an emt at 16 paramedic at
and uh i i i thought
cause you know your prefrontal cortex
isn't isn't fully
fully developed there right i was like
oh yeah not me not me
that's that's stuff other people need
right to talk to a counselor right that
other people need to
you get it get it today find find that
support network today
before you need it right because when
you need it i speak from experience here
because i didn't find one until i needed
it um and and i was
so far overboard with needing it that uh
i
yeah um i i was in a pretty dark place
and uh
everything that i'd bottled up right
just just hit it once and uh that that's
not where you want to be right and so
um you know yeah find somebody to talk
to know that it's okay not to be okay
um you know i know earlier i was like
put a brave face on things
and that that's that's for family that's
for patient that's for
right um your family by the way probably
is not who you want to use as a support
network i'm just going to throw that out
there right because that's that's where
the brave face needs to be
um you know my personal opinion right
but the uh you know if i find that
support network where there's somebody
you can talk to and just be like yeah
dude
i i i need to chat i need to i need to
vent i need to get this out whatever
right um so anyway um look uh this
conclusion slide obviously doesn't
include any paramedic stuff um it's
don't reinvent the wheel with cti
analysis uh
you know because we talk about cti and
intelligence analysis
cti analysts can make the same use of
cancer analytic doctrine the traditional
cti
or traditional intelligence analysts
have for decades and adopting nine or
even just four right
uh of those steps in the doctrine are
gonna help cti teams perform with more
consistent analysis those top four again
um were basically focused on policymaker
concerns
right that was number one number four is
the uh avoid uh conscious analytic
conscious avoidance of analytic biases
uh number six was systematic use of
outside experts and number nine was the
mia called them right or the
more more appropriately the candidate
mission of mistakes let people know when
you've made a mistake and you can
typically it's not your fault right if
you've done good analysis if you've
applied the models correctly
it's not your fault it's it's just the
lay of the land it's the way this stuff
just the way this stuff works right um
so
i'll say one more um you know less uh
you know as far as like the
uh you know put a brave face or always
be calm i mentioned that
that one of my brothers uh was also an
emt um
and uh i thankfully was not running this
call with my mom i cannot even imagine
um and uh my uh one of my other brothers
was an emt
um and uh we i got a call um and we uh
we you know we we dispatched it was for
a rollover vehicle accident
um and uh as i'm driving up i'm like man
that is and i remember saying i totally
remember saying the words that is
up right like to to the uh the i was
driving uh
i was the advanced life support person
on the truck um so i was driving there
knowing that i was not gonna drive to
the hospital i would be in the back of
the truck
and uh i remember saying man that is
effed up um
i you know pity the person who's and as
we roll up further
um you know i look at the car i'm like
man that's that's a that's a dodge neon
i'm like man that's the same kind of car
my brother has
and then i realized that's my brother's
car
and he was involved in a roller roller
mba motor vehicle accident
and uh and and mind you he's an emt
and he knows how bad this is and this is
i mean
he knew how bad it was and uh um
i mean he made it okay and he's he's all
good but uh yeah
i i will tell you that i decompress
later right but but like
you know the especially with him knowing
how bad it was it was
it was everything i could do to stay
calm um and
uh yeah and roll through that so um it's
but but but i'm telling you like he came
back after the fact he's like dude
you know he's like i i thought i was
gonna die and he's like and i may well
have um
and uh he's like i i cannot thank you
enough for
for literally just saying thank you for
you know he's
like thank you for you know for uh uh
you know just being calm about stuff
and uh yeah because you know again yeah
this stuff happens and
again we're gonna have to be there for
people that we know and and love and all
that so
anyway um so that that's it uh my time's
kind of expired here um melissa are we
gonna do questions or do you want to
bounce the next is the next presenter
here or
how do you want to play this i'll do
questions in the next presenter shows
yep so uh um checking some of the
questions
and i think from the only one is
uh folks were wondering if rendition
security uh
edition infosec is hiring um
well uh we we are uh how about at the
moment we're cautious uh
because you know we don't know what's
happening with the economy right now um
but uh we're still closing you know me
and john strand we're talking about this
in pre-show we're all still closing work
um i guess the short of it is uh
by all means submit a resume um but uh i
i
just to be straight up honest i i don't
think i'm holding the trigger on the
majority of
folks we have in the pipeline now um and
the majority of folks we have in the
pipeline
i see a question that just came in can
you give an example of an analytical
model or an analytic model
um and yeah totally uh so
um yeah somebody asked about group chat
how do you make the group chat visible
get on slack
that's where to be for to see
everybody's questions uh only the
organizers can see the questions it's
just it's a weird
it's a weird setup with go to webinar um
so
anyway um can i give an example of an
analytic model yeah totally
um i mentioned uh you know richard hoyer
um
has the psychology of intelligence
analysis right so
so definitely that's a big one and here
because you just can't make this up i'm
like looking at
looking at this book this is another
outstanding one um from clark
right like it's actually sitting on my
desk right like and you can see kind of
well worn in the
you know there but uh uh well like so
well worn that it's like tearing on the
cover
um but uh target-centric approach
intelligence analysis has a lot of
models
i wouldn't start with this one i really
like foyer's books better because it
breaks it down on what they call sats
or structured analytic techniques right
you have to use them all
one of them that's a great uh that's
such a great one here
um is or i think is a great one um is uh
ach i mentioned in the slides that's
analysis of competing hypotheses it's a
little bit longer but
i also like decision matries that's
another one covered another structural
analytic technique
um but yeah those are all good examples
of analytic models and by the way
applying kent's analog doctrine itself
is a model right if you say these are
nine things that we consciously do
right nine steps that we take not only
steps we take but all of our analysis
adheres to these principles
that's a model right so that's what what
i mean when i talk about models
right so anyway
is our next speaker here yep the next
speaker is here so thank you very much
jake uh i know that was personally
enriching
for myself and uh i'm actually planning
on
reviewing the talks and send it to
multiple people so really appreciate it
awesome hey thank you so much for doing
this alyssa and being out here uh
we really really appreciate it so um i
will uh
yeah i'm seeing some questions about
write a list of books for beginners or
the slides
get in slack i will absolutely have this
in slack all right so
again thanks to everybody peace out i'm
gonna jump back in and help moderate
track one again
as i was originally planning to do so
thank you much
all right