and you will probably need to unmute
yourself
but i can see your desktop and your
webcam
are you able to hear me
all right it looks like we're having
some technical difficulties she'll give
us just a few moments
okay can everyone hear me sounds perfect
okay i'm working on the video portion
now so bear with me
technical problems always crop up it's
fine
i think it's because we have so many
interested folks which is fantastic
it's a good problem to have i completely
agree with you
okay so i'm gonna keep uh
waiting to see if this will pop up for
video
in the meantime i can introduce myself
really quickly
um so my name is moore 1204 other folks
call me mel
i'm an application security engineer at
a software startup in north carolina
um so really excited to talk a little
bit about threat modeling
which is a way to preemptively look
through
your software applications and design
to determine whether or not there are
potential security vulnerabilities
before they ever get to production so
it's a really great exercise
it doesn't look like i can actually show
my screen for some reason it's just
showing me a spinning wheel
so that's a little bit unfortunate um
but i can try to talk through
[Music]
um
oh great fabulous all right well i'm
going to present then i just can't see
that you can see it
so let me go ahead and present and we'll
get started can everyone see my slides
yep they're showing up just fine awesome
okay
all right so we're going to talk about
two things today threat modeling and
self-drafted t-shirts
um so you can see my tagline here is
model your threats and then model your
new t-shirt so we're really excited
let me go ahead and move through so
let's talk a little bit about what
threat modeling actually is
um and bear with me i just found a typo
so just uh
gloss over that but we'll talk about how
threat modeling
it sort of works to identify communicate
and understand
potential security vulnerabilities in
your software um
and this is a source from owasp that
gives this specific
definition or more of an academic
definition of what threat modeling is
but generally speaking it's just
documenting or diagramming
and hopefully mitigating potential
security vulnerabilities at the design
phase of your software development life
cycle and realistically you may use
threat modeling as well
to go through your legacy software but
the hope is that you'll catch these
types of things before they ever get to
production
so why might you want to threat model
well you can identify design
flaws in your software before they go to
production in theory
um you can help identify flaws in your
legacy software as we talked about
before
you can potentially train your teams to
think about security vulnerabilities as
a part of their design process so this
can be
operations it can be your future teams
it can be your sres it can be your
software
folks on the front and the back end and
it can also be your security team so
they can get more
skilled at finding potential security
vulnerabilities
as well and also it helps to improve the
design process as a whole over time so
folks will get
accustomed to doing threat modeling as a
part of their software design process
and hopefully become better and better
at
finding potential security
vulnerabilities before they become an
issue
so here's a little bit of a brief
history of threat modeling
obviously lots of these things are
relatively new in the grand scheme of uh
the history of the world
um but in the software world um threat
modeling is something that's been
utilized since the 1970s if not using
the term threat modeling specifically
so in the 70s christopher alexander used
the concept of threat modeling even
though it didn't have that term yet
to find potential threats in common
architectural patterns
um so there's lots of papers on um
there's one specific paper that
christopher alexander wrote but also
lots of papers as contemporaries of him
that are really interesting to read and
in the 1980s
uh robert barnard introduced the concept
of attacker profiles
um so that was uh another uh iteration
on the things that christopher alexander
had done in the past
and then in the 1990s things really
started to take off with the advent of
regular use of the open internet so
edward omarosa
introduced the concept of threat trees
which i'm sure some of you have
become accustomed to are familiar with
and then our
very famous bruce schneier
introduced the concept of visualizing
attack trees with nodes and leafs
and he has a lot of really great papers
and blog about
threat modeling and really interesting
if you're interested in getting more
information about that and then uh
microsoft introduced the thrive strap
model or the strides
threat model that we'll talk about in a
few minutes and microsoft is kind of
known
for i guess operationalizing this a
little bit more than other folks so
we'll talk a little bit about that
threat model process
in the next couple of slides
so there's more than one diff type of
threat modeling framework
i've listed four here i am most familiar
with stride so that's the one we're
going to talk about
um but fast seems like one that might be
really interesting to explore in the
next couple years
um in particular because we're looking
at um threat modeling not just for
our software and our infrastructure but
also
across the entire sdlc are there places
where we're
maybe in our ci cd pipeline that we
haven't considered
could potentially be problematic and so
i'm actually keeping an eye out on the
vast threat model
for the future but currently we're using
strides so we're going to talk about
that
so what is stride it's an acronym that
stands for
spoofing tampering repudiation
information disclosure denial of service
or escalation of privileges so
we're looking at five
or six different areas that we want to
focus on
threat modeling in particular and so
i'll talk a little bit about what
spoofing is
it's basically pretending to be someone
you're not tampering is
tampering with data it can be tampering
with network packets it can be tampering
with
um login pages for example
and repudiation is not being able to
prove someone has or has not done
something
and that really centers around logging
and monitoring
there's information disclosure which is
basically providing a
authorized user with information that
they shouldn't have
or shouldn't have access to denial of
service is pretty straightforward it's
you know obviously not being able to
access a resource
so you should be able to because either
you're overloading the network or
overloading your resources and then
escalation of privileges
is pretty uh pretty scary type of thing
where
you shouldn't have access to something
and you're able to give yourself a
accelerated access to a resource or a
series of resources that you shouldn't
have access to
so here's a very very simple um
network or diagram that we're going to
use to go through an
actual stride threat model um this is
obviously a over well overly simplified
um
service that we've outlined and this
comes from the threat modeling book
that adam shostak wrote in 2014 it's an
excellent resource if you're interested
um if you're interested in um
actually getting really really deep into
the stride threat model in particular
um lots of interesting resources with
regards to brainstorming uh
ways that you can threat model there's
all different types of
really great templates as well so um
this is
this comes from that book very very
simple i've probably never seen
a production service it's quite this
simplistic but for the
um so we can utilize the um
the time that we have we'll just pretend
that this is a thing that
folks could actually have in production
so when you think about threat modeling
you think about what could potentially
go wrong
um so uh here is a list of questions
that we've come across
um when we look at that in engineering
diagram or that data flow diagram
to determine what we need to think about
when we
redesign our software so spoofing
is thinking about is it possible for
someone to pretend
to be someone they're not to gain access
to our web server or a data center
is it possible from a tapering
perspective
for someone to be able to edit the data
in our database when they shouldn't be
able to
um repudiation is can an
authorized user maybe brute force login
page and we aren't doing anything with
regards to logging to make sure that we
know
that's happening um can a user
request information from a search query
that they shouldn't um be able to do or
maybe they get more results than they
should
have access to um or do we have for
with regards to the denial service do we
have um
limitations or throttling on api
resources which
isn't shown in this particular diagram
something to think about um
do we limit the number of times a user
can request a login page
incorrectly those types of things and
then elevation of privileges
is can our customer access our database
directly from the open internet that's a
pretty
bad thing to do um do we prevent them
from doing something like that
um so these are the types of questions
that you go through when you talk about
threat modeling
um and it's really a um kind of an
uh an alternative to um a really
positive attitude that most developers
have which is that
okay we got this thing to do the one
thing that we want it to do
this is a way to say well how are how
are all the places that we want this
thing to do
the thing that we want to do like a
login page um are there ways to break it
are there things that we aren't thinking
about that we need to
um include into our design process um
that we wouldn't necessarily think about
because really we're most concerned
about making sure it works
so threat modeling is a great resource
to kind of turn that on its head and
think about
how we could design our software better
so here is a workflow to go through the
stride threat model in particular
typically you'd want to start with an
engineering diagram or data flow diagram
like we saw before
almost all of our production software is
going to be way more complex than that
but you can start with components of
that instead so you break it down into
pieces so you can think about
maybe you only are focused on the api
endpoints for a particular service or
microservice that you've put in place
so you don't have to do the entire sdlc
in one
go that actually i would not advise uh
on that
so um you know start small with the data
flow
diagram of something that you want to
threat model
and then along that trust boundary which
are um
you know we saw that trust boundary was
the dotted line um on the little
services so the data center had its own
um trust boundary in the database it's
not
open to the internet had its own um
dotted diagrams so
um you think about along that truss
boundary um
are there places um that
we need to be concerned about um and we
can go through the stride model and say
um are there places where we this could
potentially be spoofed are there places
where
um we're introducing the opportunity to
be vulnerable to denial of service for
example
and then write out specifically how the
vulnerability could occur
and call out those susceptible systems
that you've outlined
and then for those out outlined
vulnerabilities you're going to want to
write security tickets jira tickets
whatever it is that you use to track
this type of
type of work and include it in the
design for the feature
and the my my recommendation is to
ensure
that your um your feature teams are
actually incorporating that as
acceptance criteria uh for actually
shipping that feature
and and ensure that those tickets are
being addressed by your development
teams
often that they may decide this is not
part of the
um you know the ga of that particular
feature and
it's important to reiterate how
we want to ensure that these things
these security
vulnerabilities are addressed before we
actually um submit this and put it into
production for
for users to utilize and then another
thing that's really important to think
about is
incorporating regression testing into
the now fixed vulnerabilities
and the reason that you want to do that
is to make sure um in new features that
you're not actually
going backwards and reintroducing these
security vulnerabilities in a future
release
and finally hopefully you'll sleep a
little bit better knowing that these
specific vulnerabilities didn't make it
into production
so here are three tool free tools you
can use there are obviously paid tools
that you can utilize as well
um so there's the microsoft threat
modeling tool that's based on this
threat stride that model that we talked
about today
um it is windows only so that's a little
bit of a disadvantage for those
linux and mac users but there's also
the um a new tool that owasp just
released as a 1.0 uh
called threat dragon it is
um a tool that you can download mac or
linux
i assume it probably works in windows
but i haven't tried it
um but it's a really interesting kind of
flow diagram that you can utilize and
you can actually pull that down as a
json object and include
it in your release so you can reuse it
and re
and add new things to it in the future
as your
software features change and then
you can also just kind of go really low
key and do a lucidchart plus
webform template and incorporate that as
reports and we've done that in the past
uh where i work so
it seems to be working pretty well
obviously automation be fantastic but
this is a great start
so that's sort of where we're at with
regards to threat modeling
um i'm gonna go ahead and start talking
a little bit about self-drafted t-shirts
if everybody's ready to go to the next
slide
okay so self-drafted t-shirts are
actually pretty easy to create
um if you just have a little bit of
patience and um
um kind of work through some of the
challenges of learning how to sew
if you don't already know how to sew
this is a great place to start
because it's pretty straightforward
you're really only sewing a few lines so
nothing too complicated and you're
starting with a template that you know
already works
so one of the things that i always find
really challenging is finding
really great fitting t-shirts and for
those of us that are um
kind of female presenting in the uh
infosec world we know that a lot of
times we go to conferences and
um the t-shirts are just not quite the
right fit
so i uh decided to learn how to create
my own t-shirts um or really modify the
t-shirts that i do get from some of
these conference talks so that they will
actually fit me in a way that i
prefer so i showed you an example of my
favorite t-shirt this is not my actual
favorite t-shirt but
my favorite t-shirt is a rolling stones
t-shirt um so just
uh just suspend your disbelief on that
um and it's honestly really hard to find
the right t-shirt fit even
if you're not talking about infrastruct
conference t-shirts so i always try to
modify and tailor my clothes when i can
i'm so i'm going to show you how to do
that so there's a couple of ways that
you can
draft a new your new favorite t-shirt
start with your favorite t-shirt so i've
shown you one here it's just the inside
out of a t-shirt that i have i don't
know if you can see my
myself here um but if you can um so this
is inside out and i'll show you kind of
when we talk about how to
assemble this um how you can
sew these seams together so what you'll
do
is we're going to either remove the
seams here
basically disassembling my favorite
t-shirt or
you can trace around the t-shirt with
um some tissue paper and it's a lot
harder to do because you can see
um i don't know if you can see my screen
here but
um you have this um kind of crew neck
here and that's a little bit hard if
uh you haven't done it before to
replicate um
but we'll talk about um how we might go
about doing that in just a few minutes
um so i'm going to show you how you can
do both of these things they're pretty
straightforward um but um
we'll go through it now um so here's a
list of the things that you're gonna
need to make this happen
um you're gonna need your favorite
t-shirt which i have here
um i would purchase a jersey knit fabric
from either the fabric store for those
of us who are not um
shelter in place just yet or an online
store so you can probably find it from
amazon or joann's or
any number of really great online fabric
stores
or you can do what i mentioned before
with my info
t-shirts and do a t-shirt that's too big
and then you just trace along that and
actually
pull in the seams you're going to need a
pair of sharp scissors
so that you can cut your thread and or
the seams on your t-shirt
you're going to need some tissue paper
for tracing some straight pins or safety
pens
some needle and thread that matches the
color of your t-shirts in this case i
have a gray t-shirt so i need to get
some gray thread that matches as closely
as possible
or really sorry to interrupt but could
we possibly try to get the webcam
working
oh is it not showing uh it's still
spinning i can't seem to
i'm gonna click it one more time because
it we were
thinking that we probably should have
been seeing something the way you were
talking
yeah and it's uh it basically is just
the spinning wheel i can't seem to um
to show my webcam i'm not sure why
um we gave it a shot
yeah sorry about that um but i will talk
as if you can't see me instead
uh okay so you can't see my gray t-shirt
but i have a great t-shirt in front of
me um in front of my face that you can't
see
um so apologies for that um but thank
you for bringing it up that you can't
see
um so what you're gonna wanna do um you
have the option also
i did talk about kneading needle and
thread and a permanent marker so that
you can trace
around the perimeter of the pieces or
the whole t-shirt
we also uh optionally can do a seam
ripper which is a little bit easier than
using a pair of scissors to cut the
seams
um or you can also use a sewing machine
or serger if you have something
of that um and that will make it a
little bit easier as well
but we're going to assume that you
probably are not going to go out and buy
a sewing machine or serger if you don't
already have it
you can do this by hand as well just
takes a bit longer
all right so if you choose option two
which is to um
um use the pieces of your uh t-shirt
um you're going to um if you have a
t-shirt in front of you this might be
easier to visualize but
if you turn your t-shirt inside out
there are a number of seams that you'll
see
and it's just held together by thread
so you'll just rip out those seams
very carefully with a pair of scissors
or seam ripper
and if you have a commercial t-shirt it
will have serger seams
so it looks like it's looping over the
fringe of the seam itself
so you'll want to very carefully take
the
edge of your scissors and slide it
underneath the thread and just cut it
through
and just be super careful because you
can cut the
fabric itself and then you'll end up a
hole in your
with a hole in your new favorite t-shirt
um which in if you or your old paper
t-shirt which you may not want to do
um if you ever want to reassemble it and
um still wear your
old favorite t-shirt um okay so
you'll um remove those seams
uh remove the seams and then um start
with the sleeves
the side seams and then the sleeves
and then put the two sleeves aside when
you're done um
and then you're going to cut the
shoulder seams which is going to be
from the collar to where the sleeves
were located
and then when you're done you should
have four pieces so you have the two
sleeves the one front piece with the
scoop in the
front and then the back piece which
should have a tag attached
okay so the next step is to trace this
shirt
um so you want to find some tissue paper
or newspaper if you want if you don't
have tissue paper
and you're basically just going to line
out
the pieces of the t-shirt onto the
tissue paper
and you're going to find your permanent
marker
and lay out your t-shirt onto the um
the paper and then essentially trace it
you can use uh straight pins or safety
pins to pin it to the tissue to make it
a little easier
um that's essentially what you're going
to do and then you're going to cut out
the fabric plus the tissue paper pieces
and then you're going to
[Music]
take the you're going to take the tissue
paper pieces and separate it from the
old t-shirt pieces
and put it on top of the new fabric that
you bought and then you're just going to
pin
those tissue paper pieces to the
fabric and you're going to do the same
thing where you outline the perimeter of
that and then cut it out
and then the next step is to assemble
the t-shirt
and i'm just making sure i'm good on
time um so
you're going to take um the shoulder
seams first
and line them up um inside out
basically so the the piece the part of
the fabric that you want to be on the
outside when you actually wear it
um you're going to put those uh two
sides together
and um pin the shoulder seams together
and then sew
right across from one end to the other
and you're gonna do the same thing for
the other side of the shoulder seam so
there should be two shoulder seam
shoulder seams and you're gonna sew them
both um
separately inside out and then the next
thing you're gonna do
is pin the sleeves to the armholes
and so you'll want to make sure that the
shortest
part of the shoulder or the sleeve
itself
is going to go to the bottom that's
going to be the bottom part of the
sleeve
and then you're going to sew that around
the perimeter of the sleeve hole that um
from the shoulder seam down to where the
side seams will be sewn
you're going to do that for both both
sleeves
and then um after you're done with that
you'll pin the side seams together
and you'll start from the bottom so that
if you do
make a mistake and don't line the um the
sleeves together just right then you'll
be able to
accommodate for that and kind of pinch
it into the um
into the the hole here where the
armpit should be
and so that's pretty much all you're
going to need to do to get a really
basic outline
of a new favorite t-shirt that you know
will fit just right
there's optional finishing that you can
do i would definitely consider
especially depending on the type of knit
that you get
creating a hem at the bottom of the
t-shirt so that you'll just fold it over
and then sew along the bottom there you
can also
hem the sleeves and there's a lot of
different tutorials on how to do that
you can also do really fancy
hems if you wanted and this might be a
good place to do
contrast stitching which is basically
choosing a color that's completely
opposite of the t-shirt itself
just to make give it a little pizzazz
and you can also order a knit collar i
would not recommend making one yourself
unless you're an advanced sewist
um it's actually pretty difficult to do
in my opinion but maybe
other folks are a little more talented
than myself um and you'll just use that
um to get that kind of ribbed collar at
the top
um and then you or you can use bias tape
which those of you who know what bisap
is it's a really fantastic thing to do
and the other thing i didn't mention
that you can do is
include a little pocket if you wanted so
i have the t-shirt that i have right
here which you can't see unfortunately
has
a floral pocket that i put on the front
here um so that's really a nice little
um
contrast to the gray t-shirt um
so that's pretty much all i have does
anybody have any questions
not sure if i can see them or not let me
see i did see one question that rose to
the top that was not about the webcam
and it's uh do you think that it'd be
smart to develop a tool similar to
stride or threat dragon
i don't see why not absolutely
especially if it's um you know
non-microsoft friendly absolutely i
think that'd be really great
which industry tool do you think works
the best
uh so as far as um that's a good
question and we actually only use open
source so
i don't know that i can answer that
intelligently but i know that there are
lots and lots of tools out there
that range in price that other folks
could probably pipe in and
provide some guidance on all right and
somebody was asking if you use fortify
we don't but i know that other folks in
the industry have used it
okay i'm switching those topics i guess
when making your own t are you removing
the color from the equation
uh yes so that's the stuff that i didn't
include here but
some t-shirts do have that collar and
you would definitely want to remove the
collar
um and then if you're able to get um for
your new t-shirt
um a collar that you can order online
you can usually get them from
um kind of nice they're they're
considered notions so if you go to like
a an online fabric store and try to
order one
you should be able to find them or
amazon also um
but you'll want to if you do want to
have that color you'll definitely want
to
include that in your new t-shirt but yes
that is something that you'll
want to remove unless you want to
not include a collar and that way you'll
just have that extra
inch and a half or so of give at the top
for your new t-shirt
all right let's see if we have anymore
and it doesn't like
look like we do so thank you so very
much for this talk that's fascinating
i didn't even think that you would need
to take a t-shirt apart to be able to do
that but it makes sense because i feel
you on that t-shirt fit thing from
conferences
oh yeah awesome