my name is phillip hodges and i will be
presenting research done with douglas
stabila on algorithm substitution
attacks including a formalism for
detecting such attacks with state resets
and asymmetric methods for subverting
symmetric encryption
first i will define an asa then i will
briefly discuss motivation for
considering this kind of attack model i
will talk about some past work on which
our work is heavily based and then i
will discuss the two parts of our
research state resets and making asas
asymmetric
so firstly what is an asa
an algorithm substitution attack or asa
is an attack on a cryptographic scheme
say asymmetric encryption scheme se
where a component of the scheme is
substituted for a malicious version
in essence this model is going to
broadly capture what might happen if the
attacker is able to substitute the
secure algorithm a user intends to use
for another algorithm of the attacker's
choice
this model captures any of a very broad
range of methods of undermining
cryptography
in our case we're mostly going to going
to consider symmetric encryption
specifically the encryption function
se.inc
from the symmetric encryption scheme se
is being substituted with an algorithm
sub dot inc
which will run instead on every
invocation of the encryption function
we call sub.inc the subverted encryption
algorithm
the co the goal of the attacker here is
going to be full recovery of the key
used for symmetric encryption after
observing some number of
ciphertexts now you might think that
this would be easy because we're giving
the attacker a lot of capability
indeed with no other requirement it
would be trivial the attacker can simply
substitute in an algorithm which outputs
the key k on any input
in practice however this would be
obvious to the users decryption would
fail for example
the algorithm users would likely notice
and they would stop using their
encryption
the likely enormous amount of effort
that the attacker put into implementing
this attack would yield nothing
we could require that the asa create
valid ciphertext so that decryption is
always successful and the users would
still be able to communicate
in fact we'll go a little bit further
than that
we want an asa to be undetectable to the
users
to define undetectability we will use a
detectability game this is a simple
distinguishability game where the user u
plays the role of the adversary tasked
with determining whether or not the
oracle they are given access to
is the subverted or unsubverted
algorithm
if u has a strong advantage at this game
then we say that the asa is detectable
if not it is undetectable
note that i've introduced another
component to the asa
the key k bar
k bar is generated by a keygen algorithm
specific to the asa and used by the
subverted encryption algorithm
while kbar could be considered part of
the description of sub.inc it will be
useful to us to parameterize the
subversion key k-bar
it is worth noting that we're referring
here to black box cryptography indeed
this area of research started with a
paper by adam young and moti jung in
1997 warning against black box
cryptography
in practice a user could detect an asa
by reading the code of the algorithm
that they're using to see that it isn't
what it's supposed to be
however there are many situations where
such a thing may not be possible
furthermore
it can be difficult to ensure that code
perfectly matches a specification and
code vulnerabilities can go undetected
for years in the best of circumstances
so while this model of black box
cryptography does restrict the detection
capabilities of the user it is certainly
still worth exploring
with all these requirements it is no
longer a trivial question of whether an
asa exists that both recovers keys and
is undetectable
so there are two questions
first why do we care about asas
and second do undetectable asas exist
so now i'll talk a little bit about
motivation answering that first question
so a quick timeline
very quick in fact
in 2013 snowden revealed a vast amount
of classified nsa material some of which
disclosed that the nsa works to
deliberately undermine cryptographic
standards when it is of benefit to the
us
in 2014 the first research on asas was
published
the first works in this area were
heavily motivated by the threat of mass
surveillance by powerful adversaries and
asas were their way to model the
undermining of cryptography towards that
goal
so i'll discuss some of those past works
uh and our research draws quite heavily
on those so i'll go in some detail so
that uh
the the improvements that we've made
will be will be evident
so in 2014 belary patterson and rogoway
renewed interest in this area and and
they coined the term asa
they proved this theorem
for any randomized coin injective
symmetric encryption scheme se there
exists an undetectable asa against se
that recovers keys efficiently
they constructed an asa that works
against many symmetric encryption
schemes
their idea was to resample the
encryption
c
of sc.inc with fresh coins until a
certain condition on the ciphertext is
met shown here for a secret counter t
and a pseudorandom function f
if the ciphertext satisfies this
condition then we can see that the
attacker who knows k bar
will be able to learn a single bit of
the key k by recomputing
f of k bar and c
after observing many ciphertexts the
attacker can learn the entirety of k as
t is iterated through
every index
one might also imagine that we could
prove that this asa is undetectable
since the distribution of the
ciphertexts will be the same as for the
unsubverted algorithm i'll go into a
little bit more detail on that later
so here is an implementation of bpr's
asa idea
note that the index t
for the key k is kept as state and
incremented on each encryption
the value s
is going to be a fixed parameter that
limits the number of ciphertext samples
drawn during a single invocation in this
main loop
as we can see the subverted encryption
algorithm resamples c using fresh coins
until the result of applying the prf
f
on c
is equal to the current bit of the key k
in 2015 dellari jaeger and kane improved
the asa of bpr by removing dependence on
state and improved their analysis to
avoid the coin injectivity requirement
relying only on high min entropy of the
original encryption
their main idea was to include index t
in the prf output
sample c until the two outputs of the
prf w and t
yield correct information about the key
k that is k at t is equal to w
key recovery looks a little different
from bpr's asa
since the leaked key index t is random
we cannot guarantee that the key will be
fully leaked after a number of
ciphertexts equal to the length of the
key as in bpr's asa
however we can do a coupon collector
type analysis to see that with high
probability every index will be selected
at least once after a modest number of
ciphertexts and therefore k can still be
recovered by the attacker
here's an implementation of bjk's asa
this is very similar to bprs but due to
the fact that the index t is no longer
maintained as state this asa is both
simplified slightly
and stateless
this is undetectable for generally the
same reasons as bpr's asa was
undetectable but i'm going to talk about
this one in a little bit more detail so
we get an idea of what undetectability
looks like
here i've written the detectability game
that i had earlier with the asa
substituted in
this the proof of undetectability
pursues proceeds with a sequence of game
hops based on indistinguishability
between the games it can be seen
relatively quickly like this the first
game hop replaces f
by a lazily sampled random function the
second replaces the lazy random sampling
by true random sampling
then since the loop condition
no longer depends on c because of the
true random sampling
then it doesn't depend on the choice of
r
and that means that
the distribution of the ciphertext
produced by this function is going to be
the same as the distribution of the
ciphertext produced by the original
encryption function and hence there is
no way to distinguish between the two
cases b equals zero and b equals one
this is the exact relation that we get
in the proof the red part is from the
first game hop
and the blue part is from the second
the blue term is
a bound on the probability of seeing two
repeated cipher texts during the game
with lazy random sampling
n is the total number of oracle calls
and ada is going to be the min entropy
of se.inc
recall that s is the maximum number of
loops that the subverted encryption
algorithm will perform before returning
a value
while much of our work is comprised of
extensions on the two papers i've
mentioned so far there is a lot of other
research in this area that is still
ongoing this includes asas on macs
signature schemes and chems among other
things as well as counter measures where
different approaches have been taken
based on designing non-black box schemes
this includes so-called split programs
reverse firewalls and self-guarding
schemes
now we'll discuss the main contributions
of our paper
there are two areas that we made
contributions to
handling of state in the detection game
and asymmetric asas
so stateful asas may behave differently
than stateless ones and hence become
detectable if their state is reused or
reset deliberately
so which asas are detectable in this way
and and how do you formalize this and
should all realistic asas be stateless
these are some of the questions that we
have tried to answer the second
contribution is to the development of
asymmetric asas where knowledge of the
key k bar embedded in the asa is not
sufficient to recover the key k
this would be desirable to the attacker
since k bar is not securely held and
anyone who knows kbar can exploit the
asa to recover k
a third party
might be able to find k bar even if the
user is unaware of the asa
we will show ways for the attacker to
prevent that outcome
so we'll start with the issue of state
resets
bpr noted in their paper that a reset of
the state will lead to increased
detection ability for an observer but
this increase does not appear to be
enough to lead to actual detection
on the other hand bjk claimed
of the bpr subversion that a state reset
as can happen with a reboot or cloning
to create a virtual machine
leads in their attack to detection
this seems contradictory so which is
actually the case does state reset lead
to detection or not for bpr's subversion
bjk in their paper defines strong
undetectability which effectively
forbids undetectable asas from having
any state at all by providing their
state to the user in the detection game
if there is any state the user will
detect the asa and if not
well they might not be able to
in 2019 bayekedale designed a stateful
asa targeting a signature scheme they
proved that even if the state of the asa
is cleared during the detection game
the asa is undetectable so state resets
cannot detect their attack
now this notion of state reset doesn't
quite reflect the vision of bjk who
described state resets which might
happen when cloning a virtual machine as
well as resetting one
in that case state could be set back to
any previous point in time rather than
just to a null state at the beginning of
the game
in 2020
chen huang and jung designed a stateful
asa on key encapsulation that recovers
the exchanged key using two consecutive
cipher texts
their approach to state was to argue
informally that because the state used
by their asa is limited that is it
retained only information from the
previous invocation
their analysis need not include state
resets
now this was a reliance on only informal
arguments to justify using small amount
of states without really specifying what
a small amount of state is
so the question is how should we address
state the research thus far has been
inconsistent
stateful isas have been completely
discounted by bjk as more easily
detected and other works such as chen at
all
justify their use of state through
appeals to practicality and
believability rather than formal
analysis
so we propose a middle road which comes
from formalizing exactly what kind of
state reset capability we imagine the
user or detector having
bjk suggested that state resets could
occur from cloning or rebooting of
virtual machines and we could imagine in
a cloud setting that a user with black
box access to encryption functionality
could have access to these
functionalities as well
the buyer at all paper addressed reboots
but not cloning we will address both
giving the user or the detector in the
detection game the ability to reset
state to any previously used state
so here is our state reset detectability
game called sr debt
in this game we are allowing for sub dot
inc to be stateful and we are explicitly
tracking the state on each invocation i
with the variables tau sub i
the reset oracle allows you
to set the next t tau i to be the same
as any previously used state
without having direct access to that
state at any point or even knowing if
the state is being used
biaekedal used a model like this where
the only valid argument to reset was j
equals zero corresponding to clearing
state back to its initial value
aside from those changes this game is
the same as the previous detectability
game that i showed
so let's explore how this compares to
previous definitions a little bit
so here are three existing definitions
of detectability along with our
definition from the previous slide
placed to demonstrate which definitions
imply which other definitions
so if an asa is undetectable according
to bjk then it has no state
therefore it will be undetectable with
our notion of state reset as the reset
article will have no effect
as i stated earlier our definition
implies the definition of biac at all
since their state reset is a special
case of ours
finally any of these definitions implies
that of bpr since bpr's definition does
not account for state at all and so the
asa is allowed to have any kind of state
more surprisingly no two definitions
here are equivalent
that is
there are separating examples at every
level
more
moreover these examples are not
artificially constructed but are in fact
the asa is in many of the papers that
i've discussed so far so let's see what
happens when we apply our new
detectability definition to these asas
so it turns out that if we allow
resetting state to any previously used
value
then the asa is from biakedal and chen
at all are quite easily detected in
practice a user would have to run the
scheme in question
inducing it to store non-trivial state
cloning that state and having it re-run
using the same state
would produce the exact same result
while in an unsubverted scheme new
randomness would be sampled causing
random output no matter what cloning
occurs
this is easily translated to a detection
strategy in the sr debt game
however the asa from bpr is actually
undetectable we rewrote bpr's asa using
bjk's framework and adopted bjk's proof
method using using game hops to the bpr
asa
then we showed that the proof goes
through completely independent of the
presence of the state reset oracle in
other words resetting state provides no
assistance in detecting bpr's asa at all
so what does this mean
we think that the following two points
should be heated for future research in
the area for researchers who avoid or
discount stateful schemes it should be
made clear what detection threat model
they are working in and why state is
unrealistic
for researchers who develop stateful
schemes undetectability should be proven
in a formal model including some version
of state reset or detection methods in
such a framework should be acknowledged
more importantly for our work is that
we've shown that stateful schemes can be
undetectable and knowing this supports
the development of our stateful
asymmetric asas on symmetric encryption
in the next part of the paper
so let's now discuss asymmetric asas
i'll talk a little bit about the comp
concept of no bus
so no bus stands for nobody but us the
designer of an asa who wishes to exploit
a symmetric encryption scheme would have
a strong incentive to ensure that other
third parties do not have the same
ability for exploitation
if we assume these third parties are say
nation state intelligence agencies then
we can imagine they might have the
resources to reverse engineer the asa
essentially the designers would want to
ensure that exploitability of the asa is
not contingent upon possession of a key
that the designers can't maintain
control over
the solution here is really to replace
the subversion geek k bar
by a pair of asymmetric keys xk and ek
if only ek is embedded in the asa then
this is the only value recoverable by
reverse engineering
if xk is what is required for
exploitation
then our imagined third party cannot
exploit the asa because they will not be
able to recover xk
we call asas that use two keys in this
manner asymmetric asas
again we ask
is it possible to implement a successful
asa in these circumstances
well it turns out that some of the asas
i've talked about already are asymmetric
so the answer is certainly yes
however you may remember that these two
asymmetric asas are
detectable by state resets
in fact all of the asymmetric asas that
we've seen in the literature are
detectable by state resets
furthermore although bpr specified
definitions for asymmetric asas on
symmetric encryption specifically they
did not provide a construction and to
date nobody else has either so that's
what we did
so there are two different reasonable
requirements that we could have for our
asymmetric asa and this distinction
hasn't been made in other literature
the first type is the simpler one where
we simply say that the asa must be
completely undetectable
regardless of whether the detector is in
possession of the embedded key ek
in the second type we relax this
assumption slightly
we consider two types of adversaries in
the detection game
before
we were modeling users you as
adversaries in the detection game who
did not have possession of an embedded
key
we could carry that assumption over here
then we ask what actual requirement do
we have against the third party
adversary which we're now going to call
v
so we'll require in the type 2
asymmetric asa that the asa is not
exploitable by v
i.e
it is secure
i will present both a type 1 and a type
2 asymmetric asa this differentiation
might be small but the relaxed
requirement for the type 2 asa does
allow for some advantages i
unfortunately won't have time to cover
these advantages in detail here
so this is the detection game we will
use for our new asas
as written it describes both regular and
augmented detectability games and of
course includes a state reset oracle
the augmented game includes the boxes
while the non-augmented one does not
for type 1 asymmetric asas well where we
require undetectability against
adversary u in possession of ek we will
use the augmented game
for type 2 asymmetric asas where we only
require undetectability against you who
does not possess ek we will use the
non-augmented game which is identical to
the game that i showed earlier
we'll start with our type 1 asymmetric
asa
the idea here is relatively simple
bpr used a technique like this one
to find a ciphertext c
which leaked information about k
we will modify this only slightly by
first encrypting k under a public key
encryption scheme to get
kappa
but then using the exact same technique
to leak kappa
since the attacker has xk they can
decrypt kappa after recovery but nobody
else can
i'm going to claim that key recovery
follows it should be clear that if bpr's
technique works
it works for values other than k
and so this leak will work even if it
may take more ciphertext to do so
now how do we make this undetectable to
someone with ek
using ek
you could test the output of
f of e k and c
if this is anything but random then the
asa will be detectable
therefore all values of kappa
of sigma
must be random and furthermore we must
never reuse them
to achieve this we can use an in dollar
pka scheme and compute fresh encryptions
after using all the bits of the
encrypted key
an in dollar scheme is one whose cipher
texts are indistinguishable from random
so here's the type 1 asymmetric asa a
sub
the first section consists of
bookkeeping to compute new encryptions
of k into kappa and iterate through each
one bit by bit once we have leaked every
bit of kappa we recompute a new kappa
the second part is just bpr's leaking
technique
applied to kappa
it's worth mentioning that the in-dollar
property for pke can be achieved with
ciphertexts of lengths less than 400
bits at a 128-bit security level so this
is certainly an achievable property for
our application
using a similar game hops to bjk's proof
of undetectability for their asa plus
one more for in-dollar security of pke
we showed the relation here
bounding augmented undetectability of
rasa
this is very similar to the bound that
bjk achieved but note that we had to
model f as a random oracle rather than a
prf because of ek being known
which wasn't necessary in bjk's proof
our type 2 asymmetric asa will start
with the technique used by bjk instead
which we illustrate here
in our isa we encrypt k again to get
kappa and use bjk's leaking technique to
leak kappa
since the attacker has xk
they can decrypt kappa after recovery
and as before no one else can
and again as before we observe that key
recovery works here because of the fact
that the underlying leaking mechanism
works no matter what the leaked value is
through a coupon collector analysis a
400 bit value could be recovered with
high probability
after observing less than 3000
ciphertexts
in this case since we're discussing a
type 2 asymmetric asa the
undetectability requirement does not
impose that k needs to be
indistinguishable from random since our
detection adversary will not have ek
so this is our type 2 asymmetric asa the
description is similar to our type 1 asa
but the bookkeeping related the
encryption of k to kappa is simpler
since we no longer need to re-encrypt at
any point the looping component uses the
leaking mechanism of bjk
we now consider the undetectability of
our type 2asa
recall that we consider only
non-augmented detectability against user
adversaries that is the adversary does
not possess ek
it might not be surprising that the
results and analysis of bjk's proof of
undetectability carry over here almost
exactly
since we are using the same leaking
technique as them
just on a different value
note also that despite the state being
kept by our asa the state reset oracle
given to the detector in the detection
game
gives no advantage in detection
let's now consider the second
requirement for our type 2 asymmetric
asa
we require that the asa is not
exploitable by a third party who is in
possession of ek
to do this we will show that the asa
itself is still a secure encryption
scheme
we'll consider in cpa security
in order to discuss the security of a
sub 2 we define the security game in cpa
prime
shown here
this is a modification of a typical ncpa
game to handle the key generation and
state required
for a sub 2.ang
we showed that the security of asub2 in
this modified security game is bounded
by the ncpa security of the pke scheme
and the ncpa security of the underlying
symmetric encryption scheme
as it turns out the choice of ncpa
security as a notion is quite arbitrary
and using another notion of security the
proof still goes through with the
security notion on the leftmost and
rightmost terms modified accordingly
in the final section of the paper we
consider generic modifications to
symmetric asas to make them asymmetric
asas the modifications that i showed
earlier are actually independent of the
leaking mechanism being used so long as
such a mechanism can be used to leak an
arbitrary value we call this property of
asas
that they can be used to leak an
arbitrary valuable flex an arbitrary
value
flexible
we can apply these modifications to any
flexible symmetric asa to obtain a
flexible asymmetric asa
some of the asas we've seen today
including bprs and bjks are considered
flexible and others are not
that's all i've got
thank you very much for watching