hi my name is benoit and i'm going to
talk to you about ctet plus a beyond
birthday bound secure tweakable and
ciphering scheme using a single
pseudorandom permutation
this is a joint work with jordan
virginia
in this work we're interested in the
problem of full disk encryption
in this context we want to encrypt data
that is divided into chunks or sectors
of a size that is a few hundred bytes to
a few kilobytes
the problem that we have
is that there is no room to store
additional data like a nonce or a random
iv or even an authentication tag so we
have to work around this limitation
and what we want to do is to encrypt
each sector independently
of course having a different key for
each sector is very impractical
so a good solution is to use a tweakable
block cipher
tweakable block ciphers are a key
primitive that generalize standard block
cipher by taking an additional input
that is called a tweak and whose goal is
to bring variability to the block cipher
we can assume that t is public or
controlled by the adversary without
decreasing the security of the tweakable
block cipher
and we want that a secure tweakable
block cipher gives us a new independent
permutation every time we pitch a new
tweak
we do have several examples of natively
tweakable block ciphers like the deoxys
block cipher
however for the problem that we have
this tweakable block cipher are not
sufficient
because
existing ones use a small size of blocks
like typically 128 bits which is not
enough to encrypt a whole sector as a
single block
the solution is to use a tweakable mode
of operation for a smaller primitive
like a block cipher or a tweak of a
block cipher with a small block size
and in that case the simplest
construction is to use a tweakable block
cipher
and in order to encrypt
each block of a sector m1m2 m3 you just
use as a tweak
the concatenation of the number of the
sector that is i
and
the position of the block in the sector
so one two
three this simple construction does have
some advantages first it actually
provides independent encryption between
sectors and it's also very fast as every
block in a sector is encrypted
independently from the others so it can
be decrypted in a single two cable block
cipher course which is very efficient
however it does provide
the anniversary with a good granularity
for example assume that an adversary is
able to monitor the changes in the
in the ciphertext
if only a single block is
updated for example m1 then a single
ciphertext block will also be changed
which can which can allow an adversary
to monitor very closely uh what kind of
changes uh were done in the plain texts
and
this can be bad
uh from a privacy point of view
the current standard for this encryption
which is aes xts
uses this construction combined with the
xcx transformation applied to the aes
note that xcx has a security up to the
birthday bound which means that the
construction is secure as long as the
number of current blocks is small in
front of 2 to the 64.
as60s uses two aes keys k1 and k2
and if you want to encrypt the js block
in the ith sector
you first encrypt i using
the key k2
you get a mask that you multiply
by
alpha to the power j where alpha the
primitive element of gf2 to the n
this new mask is sold to the plain text
mj
then you give that as an input to aes
with the key k1
you saw the mask a second time and you
get the ciphertext cj
this construction actually has two
issues the first one is the small
granularity issue that i mentioned
in the previous slide
and the second one is that big data
centers most likely hold more than to
the 250 bytes which is very close to the
birthday bound of 2 to the 64.
the solution to the granularity issue is
to use wide talkable block ciphers which
use whole sectors as input blocks even
if they are based on a tweakable block
cipher or a block cipher with a small
block size
using such an algorithm if you have for
example a single bit change in m1
then
all the ciphertext blocks c1 c2
3 and so on
will be affected
unlike before where only c1 would have
been changed
several such constructions already exist
and they can be divided into three
families you have encrypt mix encrypt
hash encrypt hash and hash counter hash
roughly for a hash encrypt hash and hash
counter hash
you first give your input sector as an
input to a hash a kid hash function that
also takes as input a tweak
you get a new sector that is encrypted
either with the ecb mode of operation or
the counter mode of operation
and this
new sector will be given to a new hash
layer that also takes as input that week
and you get the corresponding encrypted
sector
for the encrypt mix encrypt
family
it works in a similar way but you first
encrypt the the sector with the ecb mode
of operation
then you have a linear mixing layer m
that also takes as input the tweak and
you have another ecb encryption layer
all those constructions require either
two aes call or when a one aes call and
two field multiplications per block and
they also have in common the fact that
they are secure up to to the 64 queries
so the birth they bound
this construction all solves the
granularity issue but they do not solve
the birthday bound issue
if we want to get a security beyond the
birthday bound we actually have to
increase the number of layers and the
two two-round spn has already been used
as a tweakable domain extender
for block ciphers
it can be seen as an example of the hash
encrypt hash encrypt hash paradigm
and it has already been proven secure up
two to the two to the two n divided by
three queries as long as uh t and t
minus one uh satisfy some
some properties namely we want them to
be almost super blockbuster's universal
and uniform which we shorten to sbu
in more details it means is that the
probability over the random choice of
the key k
to be able to fix any output block of t
to some predetermined value u should be
close to 2 to the minus n
and similarly the probability of the
over the random choice of the key to be
able to create some collision between
any two output blocks of t should be
close to 2 to the minus n
we already know of an example of
efficient linear two cable sbu layer
which is the the following one so
in this example t uses two
128 bit keys k and k prime one 128 bit
tweak t
and one w times 128 bit sector x that is
divided in w blocks x1 x2 up to xw
and in order to evaluate
t
on the inputs
t and x
you take the scalar product of a vector
of growing powers of the key k k k
squared up to k w
and of the vector of all the x i x or t
values
this scalar product is sold to all the
blocks x1 x2 up to xw
and then another value that depends on k
prime and is multiplied by the power of
alpha a primitive element of gf2 to the
n which give us the output value of t
note that this construction is
invertible as long as the xor of the
powers of k
xor 1 is different from 0
and as long as this is the case the
probability of collision is smaller than
w plus 1 divided by 2 to the n minus w
so very close to
2 to the minus n
and this construction is linear and it
requires
roughly one finite field multiplication
per block
which is actually quite efficient
our first contribution in this work
is to introduce ctet plus which is an
optimization of the two round spn that
they presented earlier
first we will use the same permutation
in both non-linear layers of the
construction
and then we also remark that it's
possible to use a much more efficient
linear middle layer instead of using t
for the three linear layers
namely we show that
in the middle linear layer c can be
replaced by a much simpler linear layer
l which doesn't rely on a keyed matrix
multiplication
and that the resulting construction is
still secure up to 2 to the 2n divided
by 3 queries as long as both t and t
minus 1 are sbu
i won't go into the details of a
security proof but as usual it
relies on the h coefficients technique
and basically it boils down to comparing
the interpolation probabilities between
the construction and a uniformly random
tweakable permutation
assuming independent s-boxes
the strategy works in two steps first we
show that with a high probability
it's impossible to get a collision
both in the input of the first linear
layer s1 and the output of the second
linear layer s2
and under this condition
we simply lower bound the number of
possible intermediate values for the
outputs of s1 and the input
of s2
and show that
the number is sufficiently high to make
the interpolation probabilities close
enough
since we are in the single permutation
case where s1 is equal to s2 it's
actually possible that
an input to the first xbox layer is
equal to an input in the second
xbox layer so we have to take care of
this internal collision when computing
our interpolation probability which
makes the computation slightly uh more
complicated with when compared with the
independent
s box case
if you want more details on the proof
you can have a look at the the full
paper where you can find all the details
our second contribution is the design
and implementation of a concrete
instance of ctet plus
with this in mind we can identify three
different strategies to get our instance
the first one is to simply use the full
aes 128 bits with all 10 rounds
in that case we can easily claim 85 bits
of security by using a simple
security reduction and the generic
security bond
a more aggressive option would be to use
a run reduced version of aes that has
roughly the same security as the final
construction so that would be roughly
seven rounds of aes
and the third option would be to
directly prove the security of the full
construction using
a round reduced version of aes with
strictly
less than seven rounds
we actually chose to follow the third
strategy
and introduce our actual instance
aes6 ctedt plus
which combines the cte plus construction
with a round reduced
aes with only 6 rounds
overall our construction takes as input
a 128 bit tweak
a white block of w 128 bit words
and relies on six 128 bit keys
two for each t linear layer
one for the l middle linear layer and
one for the aes box
our security analysis allows us to claim
127 bits of security for aes6 cte plus
we rely on two complementary arguments
to justify our claims
first we have the generic security proof
which justifies the fact that the
generic structure of the instance is
sound
and it proves that
the construction will resist generic
attacks with very high probability
second we provide dedicated crypto
analysis to justify
why our instance is secure even when
when the s box uses only six rounds of
aes
as far as script analysis is concerned
we identify two main possible attack
directions
the first one is to use the weakness of
the s-box and to extend it to the full
construction
and the second one is to directly attack
the structure of our instance
the first strategy is difficult to apply
for two distinct reasons
first
the aes has very strong arguments
against basic attack vectors so for
example even four rounds of aes
give significant security uh against
differential linear and algebraic
attacks
so extending these basic properties
cannot lead to a break of our instance
moreover even if there exists attacks
that are able to break six rounds of aes
those attacks actually
require the ability for the adversary to
set
either the input or the output of the
aes block cipher
which is made difficult by our first and
last linear layer as we are going to
argue
indeed given the fact that the key k
prime 0 is simply sort to each block of
a sector
it is easy to see that setting a
specific value for s bits of the input
of an s box requires guessing the
corresponding
bits of k prime 0
moreover thanks to the matrix
multiplication the only way to set a
specific difference at the input of an s
box with probability 1
is to
use the same input difference for all
the x boxes
this means that if an adversary wants to
exploit different input patterns that
have a high probability to go to the
next round
it will first have to guess
the key k0
these two facts either make attacks
against the aes boxes much more
expensive by requiring a key guess
or they greatly restrict
the different strategies that an
adversary can use in choosing state
differences
all in all this prevents the extension
of attacks against the aes boxes to the
whole construction
let us now take a look at two structural
attacks namely yo-yo attacks and
truncated distinguishing text
let us start our discussion with yoyo
attacks
indeed when we remove the outer linear
layers our construction boils down to
two rounds of spn which can be
distinguished in four queries with the
yoyo attack
so how does this attack work
we start by choosing two different plain
texts p0 and p1 with a specific zero
difference pattern for example
only the first blocks of p0 and p1 will
differ and all the remaining blocks will
be equal
and then we ask for the corresponding
ciphertext
then we swap some words between both
ciphertext c0 and c1 to get two new
ciphertexts c tilde 0 and c tilde 1.
and finally we ask for the corresponding
plain text p tilde 0 and p tilde 1.
it can be seen as that pitila 0 and p
tilde 1 will automatically have the same
zero difference pattern as p 0 p 1.
this can be seen as follows
the only difference between c 0 c 1 and
c tilde 0 city 1 is the swap of some
full words which means that after
applying s minus 1 to both c 0 c 1 and c
tilde 0 cited that 1 we will still have
the same relationship than before
applying the xbox layer
similarly
thanks to the linearity of l
after applying l minus 1 this will not
break the zero difference pattern
between c tilde 0 tilde 1 and c 0 c1
and this same relationship will still be
preserved after an application of
the xbox layer
this means that p 0 p 1 and p tilde 0 p
tilde 1 will still have the same zero
difference button
this argument can easily be extended to
a version with one more linear layer l
let us see what happens when we try to
apply this technique to our construction
first we have to build a pair of
messages with a specific zero difference
at the input of the first aes box
as we have seen earlier this requires a
guess on the key to the first linear
layer
and besides
when we want to swap some ciphertext
word
this also requires a guess on the key to
the final linear layer
all in all the fact that the two outer
linear layer use secret key actually
saves us from your attacks
let us now quickly discuss what happens
with truncated distinguishing attacks
first let us remove the first linear
layer of our construction
let us pick
two plain text blocks
the first one starting with x1 x1 and
the second one starting with x1 squared
delta
x1 delta for some delta different from 0
and such that the remaining words are
the same between both messages
when applying the first aes box layer
only the first two s-boxes will be
active
and
we can propagate the difference to a new
one delta prime that will be common
between the first two words
after applying the l linear layer we
will still have the exact
same difference patterns albeit with a
new difference a big delta
which means that once again only the
first two aes boxes will be active
after the final application of t
we can see that we'll have the same
difference on the last w minus two 128
bits words
this allows us to distinguish our
construction from a random permutation
with high probability because this
pattern occurs with probability 1 in the
case of our construction
and with negligible probability for a
random permutation
however this attack requires the ability
to set a very specific difference
pattern
at the input of the first aes box layer
which as we have seen is prevented by
the first linear layer because it
requires a key guess
so once again the linear layer protects
us against truncated differential
distinguishers
as a conclusion i would like to quickly
compare our construction with existing
ones
and discuss a bit about our
implementation
as far as generic security bounds are
concerned only two constructions are
beyond the birthday bond secure our
construction cte plus and also the
tweakable two-round spn construction
that i mentioned during the talk
we have implemented both constructions
using six rounds of aes as the s-box
and we can see that ctet plus is roughly
0.4 cycles per byte faster than the two
round spn that was mentioned during the
talk
this improvement mainly comes from the
fact that we replaced the middle linear
layer by a much simpler one
if we instantiate city plus with the
full aes
we can see that the resulting
construction although beyond birthday
bound secure is much slower than other
birthday bound secure schemes such as
eme xcb or tet
however replacing the full aes by six
rounds of aes in ctet plus allows us to
be roughly as fast as eme xcb and tet
finally if we compare aes6 ct80 plus
with xts
we can see that xts is roughly twice as
fast as our construction
however xts is only secure up to the
birthday bound
and it is also insecure as a white two
cable block cipher that uses all sectors
as a block
finally let me highlight a few remaining
open problems
first we currently do not handle
variable input length and partial blocks
while this is not an issue for this
encryption
doing so could open up new applications
for our scheme
second it may be possible to improve the
performance or to reduce the amount of
key material of ctet plus by switching
to a more efficient or more simple sbu
layer
thank you very much for your attention
if you have any question or comment feel
free to contact us by email