hi everyone thank you for tuning in to
this presentation the title of this talk
is exploring differential based
distinguishes and forgeries for escond
this is a joint work by david jarrod
tommen perrin and myself tren transdun
this is the outline of this talk
we will start off with some
preliminaries followed by the
introduction of constraint programming
and the parameters that we have used so
that we can find good differential
characteristics
for the ascon permutation
then these differential characteristics
are used to obtain distinguishes
forgeries and collision results for
ascon
we will start off with a brief
description of s-con
s-con is a family of authenticated
encryption scheme
in the current lease lightweight cipher
competition two instances of the family
nascon128 and s128a are among the
finalists
the encryption process as well as the
various parameters of s-con are shown
here
as our work focus more on finding the
differential characteristics for the s1
permutation
we will now take a closer look at the
wrong function of the sql permutation
itself
the state size of s-con is 3-0 bits
it can be visualized as a 5 by 64-bit
array
there are three sub-functions in the
permutation
pc refers to the addition of constants
which we will largely ignore here
since the difference is not affected by
this sub-function
ps is the substitution layer which
consists of 64 parallel 5 bit s boxes
acting on each column of the state
the s box is shown over here
p l is the linear layer
given by the equations over here each wi
corresponds to the if row
of the state which has 64 bits
in a previous world dope running at all
introduced a 2 in their paper titled
heuristic tool for linear cryptanalysis
with applications to scissor candidates
the idea is to first choose a linear
characteristic with some variables
already fixed
then from the remaining unfixed
variables they would guess one of them
and add them into the linear
characteristic
now
we will propagate what are the
additional constraints that were caused
by this move
suppose that there is a contradiction
between the new constraints and the one
that we already had so far
we simply backtrack and choose another
variable
if there is no contradiction caused by
this move we continue guessing
now we can actually draw parallels
between this dedicated heuristic and
what constraint programming is doing
this is also why we think that using cp
can help in the case for ascon as well
so here is a short introduction to cp
cp is a form of automated method that is
used to solve a wide range of
combinatorial problems
in the case of cryptography it has been
used mostly to find differential
characteristics on word-oriented block
cycles
in addition to that there are a range of
solvers along with their own search
techniques and strategies available that
can be used to get the best one for each
use case
we will now move on to the search for
the differential characteristics of
score
in this world we are using the mini zinc
language and shelf solver for our cp
program
and the objective function
is to minimize the minus log two
probabilities
to represent the individual s boxes in
the substitution layer we employ a table
constraint for each of them
the table in this case
ddt contains all the possible
transitions from every input difference
the first parameter in this case will
have to choose from one of the possible
transitions in ddt
the input difference and output
difference bs and es
are written as 5 bit arrays instead of
the integer values
to represent the linear layer which made
up of rotations and xors
we simply write functions for them
rotations are just a renaming process
and for xors we use a sum with modulo 2
to simulate
now the state interacts in the following
manner
we start off with bs0
the initial input difference
then we apply the ps layer
to the s0
then a pl layer will bring it to bs1 and
so on and so forth until we reach the
end round input difference
note that in cp we do not necessarily
have to propagate from round zero first
we can easily start in the middle and
propagate in both ways for example
this is usually controlled by the third
strategy
in our case these are the parameters
that we use in our search strategy
in search for the best differential
characteristics for four rounds for
example
we fix the s boxes at round two first
followed by that of in round one
zero and then 3.
this means that we force the search to
start looking at variables at round 2
first before deciding the variables to
fix at the other rounds
for the variable choice we set it to be
random order
this means that within the xboxes in the
same round we don't follow a specific
sequence of say fixing the first xbox
first followed by the second one and
then the third
but instead it will just be in a random
order
for the constraint choice
we set it to be in domain min
in this case we are telling the program
to search for the smallest value in the
domain first
since
1 represents an active s-box and a zero
represents an inactive s-box the solver
will try to set it to be inactive first
to further restrict the space of the
search we have a two-step procedure
the first step is to just use a single
linear layer of the s-con permutation in
cp
and find out all the possible active
positions
of x-boxes in a single round
we then restrict the number of hdfx
boxes in the output to be exactly k
next we will hard code this
characteristic found in round 1 and 2.
note that since we will have a lot of
characteristics
we will have to run them all
these are the results that we have
obtained using cp we are able to match
the probabilities compared to the best
differential characteristics found using
a dedicated heuristic as we can see for
round four and five and k equals to
three
now with an automated method available
we proceed to generate distinguishes for
the xcom permutation
first of all we would like to propose a
categorization for distinguishes
they will be the key permutation and
unkit permutation
for key permutation
we can assume that the key is added in
every rung
without the key we will not be able to
know the information as we propagate
through the rounds
this is similar to an analysis of a
block cipher
for the unkit scenario there is no key
involved this means that we can actually
start in the middle and propagate
outwards
we can view them as a black box and a
non-black box respectively
this is important as in the case of an
ankit permutation we will be able to
utilize the degree of freedom to fix
some constraints
and reducing the overall complexities of
the distinguishes
however we could we cannot do it for the
key permutation
here we will explain what we meant by
utilizing the degree of freedom in more
detail
as the probabilities or the
uncertainties for differential
characteristics come from the s-boxes
this means that there are certain
restrictions or constraints on the input
and output values for the xbox
if we can start
say at the output of a certain s box or
some middle points we are able to fix
some of the bits that satisfy these
constraints in advance this can ensure
that the required difference will always
propagate through
this will then
reduce the overall cost of the
distinguisher
here is a background of the limited
birthday problem
in the limited birthday problem we ask
the following question
what is the probability of a difference
in d in
that can be met to a difference in dr
in this case d in and dl are both
subsets in the possible input and output
difference space
for an ideal permutation the course is
given here
to find a distinguisher
we will have to achieve a cost that is
lower than this
now we will try to build a limited
birthday distinguisher for the ascon
permutation
first we choose a differential
characteristic
we pick one differential characteristic
that has the most number of active s
boxes like in the same round this is so
that we can maximize our degree of
freedom to fix most of these active
xboxes
so that we can actually reduce the cost
of these distinguishes
then we extend the characteristic
forward and backward with probability
one by allowing it to be truncated to
form d in and d out which corresponds to
the input and output differences
note that d in
and dr are only used for the computation
of the complexities
so only their size matters
therefore if d in or dl are too large or
too complex to compute we can opt to
compute a lower bound for the size of
their respective complements
forming an upper bound for the size of
dn or dl
these are the results of our limited
birthday distinguishes on scone
permutation
next we move on to the boomerang
distinguishes
once again when we are dealing with an
unkid permutation we can start from the
middle
in the case of four rounds we start at
sp4 given over here in the diagram
in the case of 5 rounds we chose to
start at sp5 as there are more
constraints in the r4
here is a summary of all the key
permutation results for ascon
in the next slide we will have the
summary for all the unkit permutations
now we will talk about the forgery
for a forgery in an iteration phase of
s-con ae
we focus on just a single block of a
reduced round pb
the idea is to generate good
differential characteristics that have
input and output difference only in the
red part
for ascon 128 it corresponds to the
first 64 bits or the first row
for sql 128a it corresponds to the first
128 bits or the first two rows
for the finalization phase we want to
have a differential characteristic that
has an input difference only in the red
part
and for the output difference only in
the first three rows
as the last two rows are used to produce
the tag t
to achieve all this
we added additional constraints to our
cp model and try out multiple other such
strategies as well
in particular for the finalization phase
we also combined the probabilities from
various differential throws as for the
very last round we only cared about the
difference
at the last two rows
the results here show the best
differential characteristics that we
have found with the required
restrictions
the ones highlighted in orange are the
best results that we eventually use to
construct the forgery as well as the
collisions
this slide shows the forgery results
that we have obtained
next we will move on to the collisions
for collisions if you reduce the number
of rongs to 2
we managed to find one with a complexity
of to the power of minus one zero three
this is in comparison with the previous
best result of to the power of minus one
two five
the idea is this
for the two round characteristic that we
are using we have 54 constraints in the
first round
and one zero two constraints in the
second round so this is the total
probability of the characteristic that
we are using
as we can only control the messages in
the red part
the first 54 constraints
have to be addressed using m0 and m1
only
for the nyx 102 constraints
this can be addressed by either m0 m1 or
m2 over here
the procedure is as follows
first using m0 and m1
which in total have 128 bits of freedom
we can easily construct to the power of
92 possible pairs of messages
out of this to the 92 pairs of messages
two on average to the power of 38 of
them will actually pass the 54
constraints
in the first round
next for the remaining to the above 38
pairs of messages
for each of them we can apply 2 to the
power of 64 pairs of messages
with this particular delta in
so in total we have 2 above 38 times 2
of 64 which will give you to the power
of one zero two
pairs of messages over here
now this to the power of one zero two
pairs of messages on average
will there be one
pair of message that will actually
satisfy the second round
of constraints
therefore
on average we will obtain a pair of
message that has the desired data out
over here
therefore if we add delta out to this
pair of messages we will eliminate the
difference and therefore will construct
a collision
now we'll move on to the summary
in this world we use an automated method
cp to actually model the ascon
permutation
and it actually performs as well as the
dedicated heuristics methods
it can also also be easily tweaked to
find characteristics for various
scenarios
the advantage of cp is that the
formulation is intuitive and therefore
it's actually less prone to errors this
is in comparison to mlp where we are
only restricted to using only integers
and inequalities
we have also found new distinguishers
for the sql permutation
and finally
improve some of the forgery and
collision results
this sums up my presentation and i would
like to thank you for your attention
if you are interested in our work you
may wish to take a look at out at the
full paper that is published in toss
these are the references for this
presentation