are connected abroad so
welcome to
so uh welcome all to fsc 2022 in athens
so i'm very glad to be here and that you
all here to present for this conference
because as you know this conference
has a kind of long long history so
probably not if you all of you are aware
so originally fsc in athens was planned
to take place in march 2020
uh so this basically means that the
bunker place or the venue place and
everything was already booked in 2018
so then time count of 7 years and
already like bought in 2019 that's why
you have a 2020 logo actually
on uh on your lanyards
and then even we open the registration
and actually some people registered and
had a lot of participants
until february
and then
you can
all know what happened right
so
we had to cancel the event but we said
okay
summer will arrive the virus virus does
not survive at two hot temperatures
especially at the temperatures so we
will just wait to die and then we have
fse again in november
so that was the plan
so we were thinking opening the
registration and then you also know what
happened so second wave
so we had to cancel it again we had it
in hybrid mode and then we kind of
gained a wisdom and said okay we will we
will wait to see what happens and we'll
try again in march 2022
so we are here today
and of course this conference would not
have been possible without the hard work
of the program chairs and editors of
tusk so i would like to thank some
italian uruguay tondo and mark manning
for their very good job
that permitted us to have today at the
at this episode
57 papers very good quality to be
presented
into 10 different sessions so we also
have two very nice invited talks so i
talked by or dunkelman on tuesday and
another one by christina berger on
thursday
okay i will present you a little bit the
numbers of uh
of the participation so first i will
start for all the people that are abroad
that were not able to come physically to
efficacy and
are registered to us online so we have
in total
uh 112 participants so mostly regular
but also some students and they are
coming from 29 countries and as us not
surprising but you can see that uh
asian countries particularly uh
china and japan
are the countries with the most uh the
highest number of
uh
of attendees
so considering their own site
uh
so you'll see that
the room is kind of uh
it's not it's not any title there are a
lot of people here so we have in total
76 participants uh from 17 different
countries and actually also some
countries out of europe that is quite
surprising
and we're very happy about this so you
can see that the french delegation is
the biggest one
so we would like i would like specially
to thank them without them the room
would be much happier so they have their
proper logo for this
um
of course we have to thank our our
sponsors uh so one silver sponsor the
tii and uh three normal sponsors that
helped a lot to take some of the
expenses
and now will come some practical
information for first for people who are
on site
so if you are not living in this hotel
and you want to connect so you can use
this public wi-fi
royal olympic then there is a password a
royal uh with uh
uh big
yeah all written like this and you
choose to log in as one resident and i'm
sure normally this should work
important information concerning food so
we will have some coffee breaks and
lunches so all
coffee breaks will be taken inside this
room so the people that will bring the
coffee just in the back of the room
and lunches were all be taken
on the seventh floor same place as
reception yesterday to the restaurant
part
so basically they're all at the same
time 12 45 except of wednesday okay
wednesday it's a little bit half an hour
later
so we will also have a conference dinner
the conference dinner will take place on
thursday
at 7 30 local time
it will be held in the dionysus
zonas restaurant so it's a restaurant in
a walking distance from here so you can
see here it's basically like 15 minutes
to walk there so we can otherwise go all
together or you can go by your own the
important is to be there for uh 7 30.
yes
sorry
oh because you don't see me okay
okay
thanks
so we have also a small social event the
social event will be a visit of a guided
visit of the museum of ancient greek
technology this will take place on
wednesday afternoon and since the museum
is quite small we can go go there we
cannot go there all together so there
will be three groups uh one group from
three to four another one four to five
and last one from five to six local time
enter to know which group you are in
just look at your badge
and you have a small color so pink
color it means the first group
then a green color second group and blue
color it's a third group um
please do not you can change if you
wanted groups between them but the
number has to be constant that you can
basically exchange with someone else but
not decide by your own to go to a
different group because we don't have to
be more than 30 for each visit
so if you have some funny or interesting
on break or like the results you want to
make them know there will be a ram
session for this and uh crystal barley
and leo perhaps will be the the ram
session chairs so the information for
submission is already on the fsc
uh website so you can go there the
server is open if you want to submit
your proposal and the deadline is
tomorrow
at
9 00 pm athens time and you have also
here the utc time if you so remote
participants are invited to submit so
also their presentations so uh christoph
and leo um
let me know let me know that there will
be some prices so as we are in greece
these prices will have greek names so
you have the aristophanes price for the
final stock
the electoral price for the most tragic
performance
and the od sales price
not for the longest stock right but
the one with the most mythological
references
so if you want more questions you can
ask to christopher and leo
um
so uh just a small information about
the registration yesterday you've got
some small bottles so what are these
bottles so basically inside there is a
sweet liquor that's only produced in
greece in particular in an island of
greece that's called hills
um so what you got inside it's um it's
it is based on a resin that comes from a
tree that this tree is only planted on
this island heels
and
these bottles were ordered like in 2020
so they're waiting for your service so
please drink them at your own risk it
should be okay but well
i don't want to have the responsibility
for this
okay so for physical performances um if
you are presenting
please come and put your slides with a
usb to the conference computer it's not
possible to use your own computer
because we have everything the sound
everything that goes from here
um if you don't have a usb stick you can
also send
your emails to this address but please
do this not the last minute because it
will be complicated
uh so do not speak too close to the
microphone it's not right to true
anymore you can speak because the sound
is not that
high and of course be on time for your
session
another problem we have
at least for at least for today
is that we don't have a sound if you
speak from the audience who cannot hear
you so that means that if you are
talking and you have a question please
repeat it so people also can hear it we
hope to resolve this problem for
tomorrow but for today it's the best we
can do
okay for remote attendance
uh some just guidelines so uh of course
you can follow the conference or zoom if
you're registered or otherwise on
youtube you can ask your questions on
zulip and we have for every session we
have
we have also a remote chair
that
so
do you hear me from zoom
yes
okay so you also uh okay great so you
can have a remote chair that will take
your uh their questions on zulig and uh
and take care of them
so please use your real name in zoom
follow the acr code of contact and of
course mute your microphone where you're
not speaking please be there also on
time one time meaning 10 to 15 minutes
before
the beginning of your session
and if you have any problem of virtual
nature please send an email to kevin and
kay through this address
so basically um that's all i wanted to
say i would like to thank
all of the people that made this
conference possible and there are a lot
of them first of course the program
chairs that without them would not have
any paper to present
um kevin and kay that do a really great
job to help us
with
with all the virtual conferences um
brian and douglas uh that help us with
all the practical financial stuff and
then really do a very good job and of
course the efficient theory committee
the svr emergency committee and all the
session
moderators for this conference all phd
students particularly from ireland
website that helped yesterday with
registration and was helpful for the
sessions and of course all of you
authors speakers and attendees to be
here
um so i think it's i would like to say
some words on the program
thank you very much uh christina so uh
first of all it's uh very nice to see
you
after all all this time so uh yeah i'm
very happy to be here and to see you
and uh let me say just a few more words
about the program
uh so chrisenia basically already uh
said most of it i'll
first repeat a few things so
we have all together 57 papers to be
presented in 10 technical sessions the
first session will be the next session
the award paper session and then we will
have
nine additional technical sessions and
then in addition to the technical
sessions we have uh
three so-called special sessions so we
have uh two uh invited talks the first
invited talk will be given uh
tomorrow on uh
by ordon command and the the second will
be given on thursday by a christian
rehnberger and
we will also of course uh have a rum
session on on wednesday as christina
mentioned
and uh
and besides that uh so in the afternoons
we will have a in-person workshop so
this will be a workshop
uh that is uh
basically will not be
live stream or recorded um
so it will be as i said
just for the
local attendees and the goal of this
workshop is basically to allow students
to present
the work from the last two years
and uh in uh you know in a convenient in
a comfortable manner
of course in person
and
by doing this we hope the to be able to
fill kind of a gap that was open
in the last two years by the pandemic
and uh
yeah so i hope it will be a very good
opportunity for the students uh you know
to to kind of see how how a standard
conference looked uh like two years ago
for those who did not have the
experience
and uh yeah basically i think that's all
i wanted to say and
yes i think we can start with the first
session that would be the award paper
session
this one works
um
you have muted yourself christine
we have to put some slides on so i like
slides are missing
so
or just
would you send it by email to me finally
i we don't see them on the usb stick so
that's sent them to me
if you can go to no because you have to
report it here
yes it's better
you are muted
um
so welcome to the first uh technical
session of this fsc
so it's a special session we will have
the all the papers that receive the best
paper award
and so we have three papers that will be
presented
and so the first one
it's called coaching the fastest
boomerangs and the obligation to skinny
uh so first congratulations for your
best paper
and i'll let you present the results
thank you very much for the introduction
i don't know can i make the talk in
french
since so many people are french yeah
okay so
let's go so this talk is about
something
christina
no this one didn't work the last oh okay
okay okay
i don't know why okay if we need to
yeah
well um
[Music]
okay so this one is about
the woman distinguishers which were
introduced by wagner in 99
and the main idea is to combine two
short differentials as it may lead to a
better probability than using only one
long differential
characteristics
to compute the probability of the
corresponding boomerang
we used to use an
independence assumption
and unfortunately this assumption does
not hold in practice
indeed
we found several examples of
non-returning boomerangs
and
the problems
occurred at the junction of both the
lower and the in the upper trace
so there were some attempts to refine
the probability of mourns for instance
the ladder switch or the sandwich
but in
carlos sid and his quotas introduced the
boomerang connectivity table bct
which is mainly a unified view of all
the previous works and
which is a pre-computation
of all the possible boomerangs through
one single single s-box so you have the
formula
of uh of the obesity right here so it's
very close to
how we compute the ddt for instance for
oneness box
so originally to search for the best
boomerang distinguishers
against one given cipher the idea was to
first search for the best differential
characteristics on r1 runs to search for
the best differential characteristic on
earthworms and to combine them to obtain
an optimal boom wrong characteristics
characteristic on r1 plus returns
and
we were able to compute the
it's probability here
like like this
so this uh this process was optimal okay
because if you improve the probability
of one of the differential
characteristics you will
improve the probability of
of the corresponding
but now we know we have to refine the
probability
of of the boomerang many mainly because
of
of the middle rounds
and
actually the the process didn't change
change so much so
we are
still searching for best differential
characteristics we combine them and we
just refine the probability of the
corresponding compound the problem is
that this process is not optimal anymore
okay because
it is not true that the best
differential characteristics will lead
to the best boomerang distinct
non-distinguishers
so that was the starting point
of our work and our idea was to directly
search for boomerang
without searching for differential
characteristics
so
what we proposed was to use a three-step
approach
to a search for the best possible
boomerangs against against a block
cipher
so first
we propose a
milp model to search for truncated
boomerang distinguishers
then we
use a cp model so a constant programming
model to search for the best instant
sessions of
the previously found truncating boom on
characteristics so if we combine both
the first and the second steps we obtain
an algorithm to search for the best
boomerang characteristics against a
block cipher
and then we
added a third step to
evaluate more precisely the probability
of boomerang distinguishers by
computing cluster of boomerang
characteristics
so this work was applied to the black
cypher skinny but it is highly adaptable
to many other ciphers
so why skinny
first skinny is a very simple easy to
understand block cipher
and
all of
its internal components are very easy to
modalize so for instance the mixed
column matrix is a binary matrix which
simplifies a lot
the milp mobilization
similarly the tweaky schedule is linear
which also simplifies
all the models
and
the agility of the
skinny s-boxers are very interesting
regarding
differential
cryptanalysis techniques because
they contain a lot of different values
okay so searching for the best
differential characteristics against
skin is very interesting so it's the
same for for boomerang characteristics
so here are the results we found
for the block cipher skinny in the in
all the different versions
so as you can see we have found a lot of
newer distinguishers in
a lot of settings
and in particular we did improve all the
previous
results against this block cipher and
the most
interesting result is probably this one
because
for 18 rounds of skinny 128 in the tk2
setting
we did improve the probability of the
best woman distinguished by a factor to
the 30.
so that's all the results we found
with our approach
so how we did that
so first to search for the best woman
distinguishers we need to be able to
compute precisely the probability
of
of such things
and
to do that we need many differential
tables and the obesity is not enough
right so we had to use three more tables
the ubct for upper bct the lbct for
lower bct and the obesity for extended
bct
so they are all
particular cases
of boomerangs through one singular box
and they
all correspond to a one particular case
about which specif or which differences
are set to specific values and which
difference
says are
led free
are free
okay so the ubct and lbct were already
introduced in some previous works they
are also known as
bdt and bdt primes
while the ebct was
also introduced
in a previous work by um
miniet al about festel
boomerangs against festel cipher and it
was introduced as a future watch so
that's what we
so now given
for instance uh a woman characteristics
like
like this example here
it's very easy to compute his
probability
using all those
previously introduced tables
and also including the ddt
which i did not mention
so to compute the probability of a woman
characteristics all
we need
is to
know which differences are set to
specific values which differences are
set to zero and
which differences are free
so for instance
if
we look at this particular xbox for both
the lower and the upper side so here is
the upper trail and here is the lower
frame
in this particular case
for the upper trail
both the differences at the input and
output of the xbox are set to specific
values
while for the lower trail they are set
to zero and so in this
case
the table to use to compute the
probability is uh
it's only ddt d2 so we only have to
compute the probability of
the transition d to 2
through 1 s box
but if for instance we look at
at this particular s box as box so the
two two threes in that case we also set
to specific values
both the input and the output of the zx
box
on the upper trail but also
the
difference at the input of the s box in
the lower tray
so in this case it's uh
the ubct table which has to be used to
compute the probability of uh of this
particular part of the boomerang
characteristic
so
what is very important here is that
knowing which
differential table
has to be used in the
computation of the probability only
depends on
two specific
values so it depends on which
differences if the differences is set to
a specific value or not
and
it also depends
in the case that the
difference is set to specific values
whether it is zero or uh or not zero
okay
and
so
it allowed us to propose a
milp model to search for truncated the
boron characteristics
so the idea
is to
start from
milp model to search for differential
characteristics for truncated
differential characteristics on the
block cipher okay we have
many such mip models for many ciphers
and
for such model we typically have
variables
that tell us whether a variable is
active or inactive
and
what we did was to use what we proposed
is to use twice
such miap model one for the lower trail
and one for the upper plane
to add extra variables
into this model to
know whether
differences are set to specific values
or if they are left
and so of course we had some extra
constraints uh
about uh controlled variables and uh
and the relations between active and
control variables
we also had extra constraints related to
tables to know which tables are involved
in the computation of the probability of
a truncated difference of truncated
boomerang characteristics
and
otherwise it works exactly as
when we search for
truncated differential characteristics
so in truncated differential
characteristics we will search for we
will count the number of active boxes
and here it's exactly the same but we
will count the number of ddt of bct of
ebct
and and so on and the objective function
of the model is only a weighted sum of
this number of
tables which appear in the computation
of the probability okay and it's
weighted by the maximum probability
of
each
of those tables
one of the main advantage of this model
is that we don't have to introduce any
middle rounds for the boomerang okay
because
there are some attempts to search for
boomerang by dividing the cipher in
three parts and
to search for an optimal differential
characteristics in a
in one in in both
in two parts and to uh to add some bct
in the in the middle round
but here there is no need to define any
middle rounds and
actually our model automatically
switches to uh
differential characteristics to the
search of truncated differential
characteristics it means that after
if you
run it for
enough friends
it will automatically tell you that the
best
boomerang characteristics truncated
boomerang characteristics for this
number of fronts is to set one trace so
let's say the lower trade to only zero
so no difference in the lower tray
and only differences in the
upper tail which
it's completely equivalent to searching
for truncated differential characters
so
so that's our
milp model to search for
truncated woman characteristics
so we applied it to the block cipher
skinny but we did not did not apply it
directly so before that we made some
some simplifications
so
we noticed that
the maximum probability exponent of uh
many tables like the ddt obesity etc
were the same so we group all of them
into a one table which simplifies
the
the constraints and we also use the
queen microscopy algorithm to reduce
the number of inequalities of our model
and at the end we obtain
this table
okay which counts uh with it's uh counts
the number of active s boxes but like
the number of bct
ddt and so on and for instance how to
read it
so if we take this 40 here
it means that for 24 rounds of skinny in
the tk3 model
the best
boomerang characteristics
have probabilities at most to the minus
80.
so it's very similar to a
to a
truncated differential characteristics
to counting the number of active s boxes
and if you look at the
estia line
you will see that some of those values
are exactly the same as the one given by
skinnier designers
on the website and for the number of
activist boxes for truncated
differential characteristics
so
now that we have
many uh good
truncated boomerang characteristics the
goal is to
instantiate them and to find the best
possible
sessions
to do that we use
the
constraint programming model highly
inspirated from
another works we made with the
with the
other authors which were published at
acns 21
in which
we we found that a constraint program
programming model which must much be
better than a
milp model to
instantiate differential characteristics
truncated differential characteristics
so we use
essentially the same model to instant
boomerangs and
why it is
much faster than milp
i think it's because
the ddt is highly non-linear and
if you want to describe it using only
linear
inequalities it's very hard it's too
inefficient model
while
for constraint programming model you can
directly add
a constraint table
okay so basically for some variables you
will directly
tell the model that
all those tuples are
are possible and the other ones are
forbidden
okay so
that's uh but the model is very easy
and
so so we we run this model against many
of our truncated one characteristics and
so we were able to find
the best possible transactions of all of
them
and actually the model was
efficient enough enough so that we run
it
okay so
it was very fast so we were able to use
it to start looking for clusters so
basically we first search for all the
the optimal
boomerang characteristics and then we
search for
similar uh for for other woman
characteristics with the same difference
as the input output and the key okay so
we start clustering and for the best
best cluster at least the beginning of
clusters we found
we
performed the precis cluster analysis to
study precisely the
the probability of the corresponding
boom wrong distinguisher
and so basically from a woman
distinguished characteristics you can
erase all intermediate differences and
replace them by all the
variables that will be
involved if you want to compute the
probability of the boom distinguisher
unfortunately this
this probability
is very hard to compute okay there are a
lot of
internal variables so it's very hard to
compute directly so we first propose a
new algorithm to
reorder the formula so to uh to have the
depth of the formula as low as possible
but
it was not always enough and we had to
manually
approximate the formula in many cases
so here are the results and some of the
results were practical so we
experimentally verified the probability
of several of them so as you can see
for uh here for three of them it's very
close the the actual probability is very
close to the to the expected probability
but
sometimes there are
a gap
between the probabilities and we believe
this is because we only consider the
case where both sides of the boomerangs
follow the same differential
characteristics but it only they only
have to follow the same differential
so to conclude in this work we propose a
new uh
mil pcp uh adoc approach to search for
long distinguishables we found many
results against the block cipher skinny
but there are still some open questions
related to this work so first our milp
model generates a lot of redundant
solutions so solutions that would lead
to the same woman distinguishers
as i said we assume that each boomerang
follows the same differential
characteristics on both sides and we
still have to uh
to add some approximations
in the in the
computations of the probability
so the source code of uh
of all what we did is available at
this address and they are also a
pdf with all the figures of all the
boomerangs we are claiming the paper and
and feel free to send me an email if you
have troubles making the code work i
don't know okay thank you for your
attention
so other any questions first in the room
hi
uh thank you for this very intimidating
job it was really interesting
have you tried
to generate the big model for eight bits
playing cyphers
or other experience
i'll just repeat your question for some
people so the question was if they tried
uh
generates
the
models for 8-bit cycles
so
and and for any other rsbn cipher
no so i i don't really understand
because
for milp model it does not depend on the
size of the xbox okay because we applied
our milp model for skinny 128 which use
8b test box
so so
for
for this part it does not matter and for
the cpu model it works for both the
4-bit and 8-bit test box
now for the second part of the question
though we didn't try any ozone block
ciphers with this model i i know that
some people are i'm
looking at aes with this model
i don't know
okay
and i have a second question
uh you say you use the music and use the
queen not just here algorithms
university questions
so first which music model do you use a
music server
and also does the queen master just be
algorithmically
important complexity lanes
[Music]
okay so
the question was
about
the use of a queen musketeer algorithm
and
i don't remember the beginning of the
question but
how the name of the mip solver so so we
use the gurubi
for
mild solver and
okay for the quinmacross algorithm it
was only to reduce
the number of inequalities
related to
which table
has to be added into into the objective
function and actually it only saved like
three two uh twin equations of our two
inequalities over 15 or something like
that so it's not
a lot of improvement but since we added
we had to use it for a
large number of fronts i i think it's
still very interesting to use it
thank you very much
probably very last very quick question
from either remote on this no
okay so we can just thank patrick again
thank you very much
[Applause]
so what did you send the slides
to
it
so just take two minutes to
to find in the slides
yeah sorry
uh i think it will sit there because
so the second
uh the second paper that received the
best paper of words it's about the
crypto analysis of low amc instances
and uh
so congratulations for your paper and
cashier will present to this uh i said
right yes the paper
thank you
thank you for the introduction uh
excuse me you're still sharing the
slides from the previous talk
oh it's not sharing the screen okay
resume sure
no resume
no
is it good now
yes
okay so good morning everyone um
okay the laser pointer i don't think
it's working so i'm cashier from epfl
and uh i'm here to present the joint
fork with surety panic but
in it
called kryptonitis of low emc instances
using single prentice ciphertext paper
so okay first let's motivate the problem
and see why do we care about single
plaintext ciphertext
uh cryptanalysis so it all goes back to
a post quantum signature scheme called
picnic so low mc is used as a backbone
scheme
as a backbone cipher in picnic so picnic
is a pq signature scheme it's a special
variant of z cable so z cable is a
mpc and head paradigm type proof of
identification that uses
a transformation like fiat mirror or
something
yes
really okay
don't see
okay can we check this
here it's good for me this is just first
page
no idea okay
this is just your first picture yeah can
you try the second one okay
do you see that
okay
okay where on the computer you mean
yes
okay
okay this is really laggy okay
so okay sorry for the
thing that happened okay
so the yes so
as i said it's based on an npc and head
paradigm and then
currently is an alternate candidate in
the third round of the nist pq
standardization process
okay so let's see how the mpc and
the head paradigm works so i took a help
from my co-authors so in an npc in head
paradigm we have two parties let's say
we have approver and a verifier
and then
my public key is going to be a cipher
text a plain text and a description of a
cypher you can think and my secret key
is going to be
the encryption key that encrypts that
plain text into that cipher text and me
as the approver i want to prove that i
know that secret key so what i will do i
will simulate an npc computation on that
cipher and then commit to the
computations that are done and send the
commitments
then the verifier will ask for some
openings i will open and he will check
local consistencies but okay this is not
very important but the most important
part is that
my key consists of a single ciphertext
and a plaintext
so if i want to do a queue recovery on
picnic by doing the key recovery on low
mc i'm only given a single ciphertext
and only one plaintext
okay
so okay
as we know whenever we say the word mpc
we don't like many multiplications
because multiplications are very costly
which means that
if e has many multiplications then my
whole signature scheme will be really
slow
that's why in most of these paradigms
they use
encryption schemes they use block
ciphers
that are
that have really low multiplication debt
and low mc is specifically designed for
that
so low mc is a really simple spn network
uh proposed by albrecht catell
it was designed specifically to be used
for mpc computations on
fhe so
it has a really simple s box it's a
three bit to three bit s box which you
can see it written there it's a really
simple quadratic function
and
later it's only followed by an affine
layer and a key addition and
the good point is
okay so the good point is the s-box is
the only non-linear part so because both
key schedule are linear is a linear
function and also the affine layer of
course as the name suggests is linear so
the only nonlinear part comes from the s
box
and then it's just a minor detail that
there is a
additional key addition in the first
round
okay so just let's set some notation so
whenever i say s i would mean the number
of s boxes that i have in round n is
going to be my block size and r is going
to be the number of rounds that i see
you can see the circuit on the
right side
and you can notice that the domain of
the s boxes are disjoint so there is not
a single wire that goes into two s boxes
at the same time
and looking at that and knowing my s box
is three bit to three bits i can see
that
three s should be less equal to n and
whenever
it's equal i will call it the full layer
s box and whenever it's less i would
call it a partial day
okay
so let's talk about some previous some
prior work that was done before this
paper was published there has been
many other results
after
so it's so most famously i think we can
refer to reichberger's attack from tosc
which
also was optimized at crypto 21 using
some algebraic techniques but these
attacks don't really apply to the picnic
scenario and the reason is that both our
difference enumeration type attacks
and we don't have differences when we
have only a single plaintext and cytotex
okay so as i said these
do not
uh sit in the scenario that we have so
one might say are we fine well not quite
so let's talk about our attacks so in
this work you propose two attacks one is
a full that's a linearization attack and
the other is a meet in the middle attack
both of them use
both of them are in the given ciphertext
plaintext scenario and only use a single
ciphertext plaintext pair
both of them can break the full xbox
variant up to two rounds and the partial
xbox variant up to point eight and over
restaurants
so
the linearization attack is actually
faster although it's simpler
but the good thing is we were able to
improve the
meet in the middle attack in some uh
work that we did after to break more
rounds
okay and here you can see the
complexities for instance if i have the
full xbox variants 429 bits blocks
the complexity of break units using the
linearization is 2 to the power 91
encryptions
and also for the linearization
you can see that it's 2 to the power 109
okay
okay so let's talk about the attacks so
let's have a closer view at how the low
mcs box operates low mcs box is written
on the right as you see
so as you can see it's very sparse
and it's the only non-linear part
of the
whole circuit so the question the
natural question is can we linearize
this s-box using just a few guesses so
an obvious way to do it is guessing two
of the input bits so if i guess amb for
instance then everything will be a
linear function in c
but that's not very good so the question
is can i guess one bit
depending on the input of the s box and
linearize the s box
and the answer is yes so what we show is
that for any guess of a quadratic
balance function in the input bits i can
linearize the s box
so let's do like a toy example to see
how this works and take the most famous
three bits balanced quadratic function
that we know which is the three dot
majority function
okay
so let's see i guess the majority and
the majority is m the majority of the
xbox inputs
so let's see what happens so i'm going
to look at the first output bit which is
a plus bc the only nonlinear part in
that is bc
and one can easily verify that if i
compute 1 plus b plus c times m i will
exactly get bc
so if i guess m and i know what the
value of m is i have bc as a linear
function of 1 plus b plus c if m is
known to be a constant
so yes i can write my output bits using
the majority guess as linear functions
in a b and c if the majority guess is
not
okay
now mounting the attack after knowing
this is pretty natural
so okay first let's talk about the
general case of this result so simply
this is the full theorem that we have
that we say for every balanced quadratic
boolean function that we guess in the
input bits
i can write my s box in the following
form
which simply is that i can linearize it
in a way knowing the majority knowing
that value of f for
the input
okay so let's see how the attack works
so the attack is really simple the idea
is for every single round that i have on
my cipher i will guess the image the
input majority
of all the s boxes that i have
and linearize all the s boxes and then i
would get a linear equation i form a
linear dependency on p t and k is equal
to my ciphertext
so let's see how i can actually compute
this equation so let's take
one round i call the input to be i let's
say
knowing the majority guesses i can write
the output of the s boxes as a linear
function and i
the affine layer is not doing anything
much it's just like adding one more
multiplying one more refined matrix
to the value that i had before
and then the key schedule is also linear
so i get something in the end of the
round that is linear in the inputs and
the keys
okay
so
doing this for every round i can get
that type of equation that i want and
what happens after i just solve this
equation for k
but after i solve this i should make
sure that the majority guesses that i
did were actually legit so
the key that i guessed is actually
consistent with the majority guesses so
i need to check the consistencies by
doing one more encryption
simply
okay so let's check the complexity of
this attack i have 2 to the power rs
possible majority so r is the rounds s
is the number of s boxes in each round
so for each majority guess i have to
create this linear equations i have to
solve the linear system and i have to
check whether k is consistent with the
majority guess
okay the first one is n encryptions
approximately the second one is one
gaussian elimination or as we have an
argument that's n over two are
encryptions
and the last one is just one encryption
so that's my total complexity
and because i have that two to the power
rs
term there if i go to three runs and in
the full s box setting for a full layer
s box that my
s is n over three
then the best i can do is
break up to two rounds of my full layer
variant
and 2.8 and over restaurants for my
partial layer variant okay
so
let's go to the meat in the middle
attack
so the idea here is i will linearize
everything other than the first round so
i will keep my first round as is and
linearize everything that comes after
then i will be splitting my key my k
into two parts k1 and k2
and then try to form some equations uh
such that the left hand side but only
depends on k1 and the right hand side
would only depend on k2
and having this i can because k1 and k2
are like almost we can think of them as
half the size
i can try to do like a meat in the
middle type of attacks like try to find
collisions for these
okay so let's see how i can form the
equations
so the idea is i will look at the states
that is the output of the first round
and the input to the rest of the rounds
okay so let's look at the backward
direction because we have
linearized all the rest of the rounds
so exactly i will write my k
k1 to be first half of the key
my k2 to be second half of the key
and then w to be that middle round
so i will guess the majority of the s
boxes for the input majority of the s
boxes for all the rounds other than the
first one
and then i will linearize all those
rounds and get this type of an equation
just as i had before so i have a linear
equation in k and c t is equal to w
this is exactly what we had in the
linearization case and now because my i
can write my k to be k1 plus k2 and l is
a linear function i can get an equation
of this form so w is a linear function
in k1 plus a linear function in k2 plus
some constant t
okay
and now let's see how the other
direction works this is also
very easy so what i will do is that i
will propagate my circuit in the forward
direction
and try to get a quadratic equation of
that form
and one might ask why can i get that
because i have those my functions are
not linear anymore because my x boxes
are quadratic but the point is if i take
k1 and k2 such that their lengths are
divisible by 3
no bits from k1 and k2 will pass through
the same s box so everything will still
be separate from each other
okay
so i can write exactly an equation of
that form so some quadratic f of k1 plus
some quadratic g of k2 plus c is going
to give me exactly the same w
and now i'll just have to combine the
two together and i get an equation of
this form
which f and g are quadratic and a and k
are
linear
and from here it's pretty obvious what
should be done so we just have to do a
collision search for k1 and k2 on these
values
so i will just compute f plus a plus c
for all k1 values that i have then i
will compute g plus b plus t for all k2
values that i have
keep two lists of these
and then find the collision between the
lists
okay
so let's check the complexity so let's
see what do i need for each majority
guess i have to form these quadratic
equations
and then i have to evaluate uh f plus a
and g plus b on those smaller spaces
that i have and these we also
have to can optimize it using
trees or so i have 2 to the power r
minus 1 as majority guesses
and forming equations is not really
costly compared to the next part which
is going to be approximately 2 to the
power and over 2
encryptions
okay and i can get rid of a factor of
square root of n over two using three
sorry yes
okay and this is going to be my total
complexity
which again allows me to break up to two
rounds of the fullest box variant
okay so i'm gonna quickly go over to how
we can do a meet in the middle for the
partial layers box
it's a bit of a different scenario
and then conclude the talk so okay here
again i want to split my key into one k1
and k2
but here the point is like i kinda
cannot do the same because i have many
more rounds and my degrees will start to
get really high
so what i will do i will have k1 and k2
to be the round keys that were used
in
like some rounds in the beginning and
some rounds in the end
so the idea is i will split my rounds
into three parts so i have r1 runs in
the beginning as you can see on the
right
i have r2 rounds in the middle and r3
rounds in the end
so for the runs in the middle i will
again guess the
uh input majorities for all the s boxes
that i have and i will linearize them
completely
and then i would do something similar
for the first and last uh rounds that i
have
uh
similar to what i did for the fullest
box player
okay
and so i will call k1 to be the keys
that we're using the r1 rounds and k2 to
be the keys that we're using the r2 r3
rounds
and then try to do some kind of a meet
in the middle for k1 and k2 but the good
thing is i can actually argue that i can
consider k1 and k2 to be of short length
and why is that that's actually an
argument that was done in uh wreck
burgers that requires attack from 2018
the fact is that although i have these
really i hope the pointer is visible
although i have these really
key additions that are being done here
as long as a key bit is not passing
through an s box i can just apply the
affine function and push that key to the
next round
and i just keep doing this
and uh
and push that portions of the key to the
last round for instance and just have
smaller keys for each round which are
the size of the input bits of the s box
so for each round
the length of my key is the size of the
inputs of the xbox okay
so what i will do is that
for the first r1 rounds that i have i
will push all these keys forward
so for all these r1 rounds i will have
really small keys and also i can do this
in the backward direction so i will do
this in the backward direction for the
r3 runs somehow so k1 and k3 now will
have only 3s r1 and 3s r3 bits
because that big key is now in that
those middle rounds that i was
linearizing
okay
so
now
let's see how the attack works
so i will write my
so i will
denote the output of the r1 rounds as w
output of the input of the r3 rounds as
v and now because those middle rounds
are linearized w and v have like a
linear relation between them we will see
it a bit but most importantly i can
write my w as a quadratic function uh
i can write it
as a quadratic function in k1
and i can write my v as a quadratic
function in k2
and then
v can be written as a linear function in
wk1 and k2 because of linearized those
rounds
and again i derive to an equation of
this form so
okay okay yeah it's just one slide okay
so i get that l plus q and k1 is equal
to l prime plus q prime and k2 and then
again i do a meet in the middle because
i have this type of approach
okay and then
so there's written that r1 and r2 should
be approximately n over six
for the attack to work okay
so let's conclude this talk so we
proposed two attacks the first one was
the linearization attack
it breaks up to two rounds for the full
sbox variant
and
0.8 n over s runs for the partial sports
variant you can see the complexities
there
we also have a meet in the middle attack
that breaks up to two rounds for the
full xbox variant
and point eight and over restaurants for
the partial box variant
the bad thing is it's slower the good
thing is actually it can be combined
with another beat in the middle let me
do in a
work after this and can break more
rounds of low mc as well
okay
and
okay okay and thanks for listening and
the take away message is be careful when
you plan it
thanks a lot
[Applause]
oh okay
so thanks a lot are there any questions
are there any bark are there any remote
questions
okay there's a question from christians
[Music]
uh so the memory is not very nice
because you have to keep those very long
lists so you can think that you need
like 2 to the power n over 2 somehow
memory to do it
but okay we have like some
work that we're actually doing now it's
not available yet but exactly we
address the memory issue how we can
optimize it but yeah it's not really
memory efficient for sure yes
are there any other questions from the
audience
okay so
okay thank you very much
and we can move to the next step
it goes through this one
so next paper um so also best better
award
it's on wikis and reduced aegis and
javascript
uh so willie mayer will present the
standards and congratulations for the
best paper awards and so let's use yeah
paper
so this is trying to work with who can
you
takanori is obe and jose sakamoto
normally uh phukang would give the talk
and actually these are his slides
so a brief overview so
i would like to talk about cryptanalysis
of which is mainly
first i give a description of this
cipher
and then the attacks and very briefly i
also talk about cryptanalysis of joshin
and then i come to a summary with a
brief discussion and conclusions
so some background on ages 128
ages 128 belongs to the aegis family
so there are different variants
so depending on the key size and also
some other kind of issues
this family has been designed by wu and
prenel
and has been submitted to the caesar
competition
actually aegis has been selected
in the final portfolio of the high
performance applications
in the caesar competition for
authenticated encryption
so we find that aegis is a still a novel
and efficient design
that uses the aes round function as the
main component
there is something surprising here
and there seems to be no cryptanalysis
of the aegis initialization phase
thus far despite the quite long history
of the cease competition there are
actually two very interesting papers for
the keystream phase but nothing
on initialization so we are really
wondering whether it's too difficult or
just not interesting but we find it
interesting because it's a dedicated aes
based cipher so it's non trivial to find
out its security especially regarding
initialization
so a brief description of hs128
as we can see we have five uh blocks of
words uh everything you can see here is
128 feet long and a is just an
abbreviation for one round of aes
where we omit constant or key addition
the key is introduced in the first part
here so
so actually it's depending on the
parity of the round number it's either
kx or n or k
so when if i resort
so it
it's
shown here x are zero is x are zero
minus one plus a k
a of x r minus one four plus k
and the other
words are updated in a similar way
so when if r is even uh also the nonce
comes in so we have an ounce of 128 bit
as is quite common for this type of
ciphers
so the total number of rounds is 10
and the initial state
we can see that
[Music]
only x0
depends on the nouns
x1 and x2 are constant x3 depends on the
k and x4 also depends on the k
the output after our initialization
rounds
is assumed to be visible to an opponent
which is theta is x r1 xor xr4 xor xr2
and xr3 so there are quite some
deviations actually
from aes despite using it
around as a
component
therefore we have been looking
what is known about aes a lot is known
there are
really many papers
of course there is a well-known
foreground integral distinguisher there
is even a five round multiple of eight
distinguisher and a bit more recently
there are the four five or six round
yo-yo or yo-yo like distinguishes
so
which of these distinguishes could be
applied to
the ages 128
initialization
and
we recall the observable output theta
we thought that the integral
distinguisher is more suitable
because we can independently
study the integral property
of each of these blocks or words
and also of this and operation
we guess that the other attacks may
require
[Music]
to study into possible interactions
between words but we don't say that
other
kind of known
results wouldn't apply
so our main strategy is to write down
and study the integral properties of the
expressions
after our rounds
independence of the nouns and the secret
key k
one wonders whether one would also look
at boolean expressions maybe like cube
attacks or something like that but we
thought that the expressions are really
complicated and also the state is very
large compare
as you compared to maybe
cube attacks on stream sizes with small
state or something like that
so
we are looking at
at expressions in terms of the 128-bit
words as a union because as a unit
because uh
the diffusion
uh
between words is not that strong if you
look at the
definition of the of ages and its
initialization
so
actually it's an exercise to write down
the expressions
in terms of
n
after five rounds so well if you have
considered this well is it nice or
actually i should explain this red a's
if one would write down step by step we
have noticed where the new
terms come in after i trading one more
round so this a means that comes
in the last step from the fourth to the
fifth round
but still it doesn't look very promising
so
what can we do here and also we have
this
non-linear part
x5 2 and x3 so
we need to do something better
so we recall the initial state so we
have this what we have seen before
and then we write down for each
around the expressions
so
of course what we can do everything
which is constant we just abbreviate
with an
another constant we have already the
constants c0 and c1 and then we just
count up for new constants
so if r is 2
we have
other things which are constant
and so this is the expression that
doesn't look very complicated we need to
look at the details
we just at the moment it suffices if you
look a little bit at the global picture
if r is 3 it's
even already a bit more complicated but
an interesting thing is that the
underlined expression
can be
simplified by
adding a condition on the k on the key
so and this is a crucial condition now
if a of k
plus c
of the diagonal part so i should
explain this notation we have to state
after applying a and we just look at the
main diagonal and if this coincides with
the main diagonal of k
of course we should say that
we represent
a 128 bit word
as we do in aes as a six as a four times
four
bit array where each entry is 16 bit and
in this language this
expression 1 makes does make sense
so if he
as
if we assume this condition then this
whole underlined expression we have seen
here becomes constant of course
these are just claims here in this talk
these are all based i should say on at
least five properties which we had
proved first well
when you verify these things they are
look quite easy i would say but uh first
it was not so trivial to find out these
proper
properties
so we can introduce a new constant
and then
after three rounds things
look not so bad so it's
it's okay for doing some further
analysis
but
we have to do some other things so yeah
further introduce another variable t
which is c 0 x or a of k plus n
then x 3 looks quite simple so that's
really really simple
so
why is it useful to
introduce another still another variable
so as we see it makes all our
expressions simpler and maybe easier to
study another trick is we can get one
more round in a kind of non-trivial way
actually remember that for block ciphers
maybe we can just add one or
more rounds by uh partial key guessing
or whatever this is not the case here we
have to do something quite dedicated
so uh
often we now
had
started t rather than n but also that
it's not quite trivial because we have
to swap uh between t and n
n is visible but t is not is only in
place implicit
so if we go for four rounds
then we have this expression here so i
skip it but for five rounds it still
doesn't look very
very promising so even after only two
more rounds we have some relatively
complicated expression and we wonder
whether we are capable of now applying
an integral distinguisher
so
we focus on each word separately so x51
is the simplest it has this form and we
can actually prove then the
sum over uh
two to the eighth values two t of zero
zero then the sum is zero so this is an
integral property
and actually it's a it's it's not
detailed here but it depends heavily on
the definition of t and its properties
and
how going from n to t back and forth
so secondly focus on x54
so this is still quite complicated the
first the summoned
a of a of a of t plus something that
that it's not so difficult we can derive
an
integral property
based on the well-known three-round aes
but how about the second
more involved summoned
so if we look in it in form of a picture
it doesn't look very promising so first
we have a for all c for constant
and
then but further
after three rounds it seems we might
lose track
so we look at it in more detail
we
consider the function g
g is actually the function that's
the argument of the latest a here of the
leftmost a
and
then when
it was proved in the paper again if t00
takes all
possible 2 to the 8th values for
for each i and j the same value of g ihj
will appear an even number of times so
we have finally after the x4 we have
even and after applying another round we
have still balanced
so we have still an integral property
which is expressed in the
low
low abundance equation here on the
on the side below
so
finally we need to focus on
the
and
part
so the a of t
that's okay but then we have the all
underlined stuff
and it suffices to look at the sum of a
of t and a of a of t plus c
uh there very sum again over all a two
to the eight possible values of t zero
zero
so uh we could prove that
it has indeed uh an integral property
but only if you restrict on the columns
of the state 1 and 3 but be in your
column 0.
so this is again
illustrated by a picture here actually
it's equivalent the formula and the
picture
therefore for five round ages
we have this nice
integral property
and we could even derive an ordinary
using the definition of t
so that when we sum over the full
diagonal of n of the nons then the sum
over the values of theta is still zero
so we get an alternate distinguisher
then we have the weak key condition
actually in order to go back and forth
between t and then we need to introduce
a big key condition
and we look at this there are two to the
24 possible values for the diagonal
imposing this condition
and and this can be pre-computed in a
table
so
we first started
because we can
weak keys can back and forth we can
study the distinguisher in terms of t
rather than n and
and using the relation
t
the other the definition of t
and we can
recover the value of the full diagonal
of k
so we again need a big key condition and
uh
it's it's going rather step by step
that's in your here actually it's a bit
more complicated and what is given on
this formula
about it
ends up
with a
key recovery attack with data
complexity 2 to the 32 and time
complexity 2 to the 72
and the number of keys because we have
imposed the condition of 32 bits so this
means we have
2 to the 96
big keys
we obtain a valid key recovery attack
because the complexity 2 to the 72 is
quite lower than 2 to the 96.
actually there would be four classes of
weak keys instead of the main diagonal
it could also use the other three
diagonals
so
[Music]
a very brief
comment on
the ashing so we applied similar ideas
but the technical issues are a little
bit different especially one special
thing is that we have to impose
conditions on the constants which rather
which is rather uncommon
so
actually our attack only works if one
would choose weak constants
but fortunately the constants chosen
in dashing don't
fulfill these conditions so i skip this
part and come to the discussions and
conclusions so maybe
studying ages and tagine like ciphers
we have to impose weak key conditions
otherwise we didn't succeed in any
attack but still in this setting we
reach half the number of initialization
rounds maybe we
one could say well it's not very
exciting on the other hand it's quite we
think it's uh
nobody has done it before and i find
it's non-trivial
so
uh for the touching there seems another
issue that will actually run around this
kind of useless because we can
skip it to some extent
so what we can say finally is that this
is a rather dedicated analysis
so it does not follow immediately from
known results on aes
so therefore we thought that it's
an interesting contribution and maybe
there could be other kind of analysis of
similar
ciphers so thank you
thanks a lot will
um are there any questions
are there any questions from
um but i have one question actually so
that you have three constants
and you actually need them for your
attempt to work right yes
due to your
strength a good very good question but
actually it's quite open because it's
please repeat the question
ah yes whether
this
restriction on constants whether it's
due to our attack or due to the scheme
due to the design
so
actually
i cannot really finally answer this
question because uh our
attack is rather dedicated and maybe
somebody else would could come up with
another attack actually we also
tried some
divisibility properties
uh
maybe there is something but our
conclusion was that the basic
the visibility property methods
wouldn't work but there
maybe there is some follow-up work
which can
break more rounds or resolve this
relevant question for dashing
are there any other questions
i have a very short one and i didn't
understand you said for taxi there is
one round that is kind of uh useless is
this for this attacker in general for
all kind of attacks that's a again
very interesting because if somebody
else would like to uh do
another design
so
definitely issues check our work and of
course
try to see whether other kind of similar
attacks might work
thank you
thanks a lot
um so this is the improvisation so we
can thank again all the
and now we speakers a coffee break of
half an hour
uh
yes so we can stop and come back so
people that are presenting the next
session physically
please find the session share and come
here to put your slides on before it