welcome to our presentation of highly
secure non-spaced max from the sum of
tweakable block ciphers this is a joint
work by once choi pyeong hakli and jo
yong li from the south korean kaist
akiku inua and kasuku minamatsu from nec
and yusuknito from mitsubishi electric
message authentication codes are
symmetric key algorithms to provide
authenticity for messages for this
purpose high efficiency high security
and non-misuse resistance are
desirable high efficiency of course
helps reduce the computational effort
high security guarantees allow designers
to lower the primitive size
moreover if nances are present they're
an easy and effective means to extend
the security guarantees
however nonsense may repeat accidentally
during the use then the study of the
security degradation when nonsense
repeat becomes important
the combination of universal hashing
with a few calls to a block cipher for
producing a pseudorandom output is well
known for its high efficiency
these construction includes for example
a well-known hashden prf construction or
the wegman carter shoop
trigger block ciphers are also well
suited for achieving these goals
even small tweaks can already help
designers to achieve that independent
calls to different permutations even
small tweaks already help to achieve
independency of the different
permutations that are used in a scheme
this can provide clean designs with easy
domain separation
larger tweaks can be used additionally
to possess either more message input or
to take the nons for higher security
at fse 2017 koyati at al presented four
elegant non-spaced macs from universal
hashing and a single block cipher call
two constructions possessed high
security and employed a tweakable block
cipher with an n-bit tweak
those were called nonsense tweak and
hashes tweak
nat nonsense tweak simply used the
message hash as an input to the block
cipher call and the nones as a tweak
therefore it achieved optimal security
if no nonsense repeated
however its security degenerated to n
half bits when nonsense repeat up to 2
and a half times
on the other hand hash's tweak was
stateless deterministic
it replaced the nons by a second
independent hash of the message and
therefore provided n plus d half's bit
security independent of nonsense
nevertheless it also did not have any
security benefit from the use of
nonsense
nat and ajt pose interesting research
questions of how one could strengthen
them with minimal changes
our goal would have been optimal
security for non-respecting adversaries
and as high as possible security if
nonsense would repeat
we wanted to extend the security of
nonsense tweak when nonsense ignored for
hashes tweak our goals were
higher security guarantees when nonces
are respected
we identify a few design principles that
helped us on our way to achieve our goal
in general ambit tags limit the security
of max to n bits since the adversary can
always simply guess the tag
moreover the sum of independent
permutations is well known for providing
up to n bits so this construction would
help us on our way
when nonces are respected using the nons
as a tweak in a tpc helps us since it
transforms a trigger block cipher into a
prf
when nonsense repeat on the other hand
there will be hash collisions
after two and half queries for an ideal
single hash
moreover given two parameters the nonce
and the message
both of them must be input to the hash
function
finally in many cases the tweak size
will not be larger than the block size
since we will need two hashes
to overcome the birthday bound from the
collision of a single hash we will also
need two trivial block cipher calls to
possess the hash and the nouns
in conclusion we propose two
constructions for our purpose
nut 2 and extended hashes tweak both
will be variants of the double block
hashed and sum construction however we
will have a nonce that can be used to
extend the security
our first instance will be nonsense
tweak two
it sums two instances of nunza's tweak
under independent keys
the nuns is therefore used as a tweak
input to both tweak the processor calls
as a result
nuns streak 2 preserves the optimal
security of nat when nunses are
respected
we can illustrate this as follows
here the light graphs represent the
security of nat and the bold craft stat
of our construction
for simplicity we assume ideal
primitives here and that the tweak size
is equal to the block size and n is 64
just for an example
when respecting nonsense the security of
both construction is roughly identical
and limited by the number of
verification queries
in the middle there are a few
non-repeating queries in the order of
square root of the number of total
authentication queries
then
our construction provides n
instead of
2n by 3 bit security and
even higher security for fewer
verification queries
when all mac queries finally use the
same nonce our construction still
provides 2n by 3 bit security compared
to n-half for nat
moreover given at most 2.5 verification
queries we showed even a bound of 3n by
4-bit security
our second proposal is called extended
hash as tweak
it adds the result of processing the
nuns with an independent tweakable block
cipher call to hash as tweak
furthermore it concatenates and hashes
the nonce and the message instead of
only the message for generalized tweak
length our construction will be stronger
than hit when nuances are not always
misused so whenever mu is smaller than q
for hash's tweak the bound is limited by
two
n plus t half queries and does not
profit from nonsense at all
the security of extended h80 depends on
the number of non-repeating mech queries
and on the number of verification
queries
for two-to-nine verification queries it
provides also end with security
for fewer verification queries its
security exceeds that of the original
stweak construction
when non's repeating macquarie's read
quicker more our construction slowly
approaches the original hashes tweet
construction
this means it still preserves its
original security but has benefits if
the nonce doesn't repeat too often
our constructions both need more
operations than the original non-systec
and hash has tweaked designs
both need two to block cypher calls
instead of one note that this call may
be performed in parallel to the first
trigger blocks of a call
nuns's tweak 2 needs twice the number of
operations in addition in the hash
functions compared to the original nat
extended hit
needs to additionally process the nons
in the hash functions
nevertheless as we showed before we
believe our constructions are close to
the minimum number of computations
necessary to achieve our design goals
in the following we provide a few
preliminaries for our later security
analysis
we use mac security as the
distinguishing advantage of telling a
part two worlds
the real world consists of two oracles
that wrap the real authentication and
verification algorithms
the oracles of the ideal world always
return random tags or always return the
inbuilt symbol
the adversary can ask at most queue nuns
respecting and view non-repeating
queries to the authentication oracle and
at most weak queries to the verification
oracle
the proof of nat2 builds on pateran's
mirror theory
we build also upon the extensions of
mirror theory by kim and al whose work
had added inequalities to patagon's
theory
this work extends theirs to show a three
and by four bit security bound instead
of two n by three
moreover we employ the expectation
method a generalization of patterns h
coefficient technique
mirror theory tries to derive a bound
for the minimum number of solutions for
an equation system
such a system models all outputs from
the sum of independent permutations
here the equalities represent the
authentication queries
given that an adversary shall also not
be able to forge the inequalities of
such a system represent the relations
that must not hold so that the words
remain indistinguishable
those relations of values can also be
represented as a transcript graph
the nodes are the outputs of the two
independent permutations collected in
two sets
the edges are connections of outputs and
a trail is then a sequence of edges
labels are tuples where the first values
map two subsequent values and sign
indicates if it's an equality or
inequality mapping
the sum of all edge label values of a
trail is then defined as the label of
the tree
nice graphs will later represent a good
transcript without bad events
we call a transcript graph of k
components nice if it is cycle free
non-degenerate that is the sum of labels
in a trail is not zero and if edges are
connected by an inequality they are not
simultaneously connected by inequality
given a nice graph the extended mirror
theory allows us to lower bound the
number of solutions for a random choice
of variable assignments
in detail the graph will be decomposed
into such components of at least two
images of single edge trails and of
isolated vertices
in conclusion the paper will arrive at a
bound in the order of q by 4 by 2 to the
3n
the details of the proof of that theorem
can then be found in our paper
let's come to the security analysis of
nat2
for both constructions we use the edge
coefficient method and here in
particular the expectation method
this means we introduce a number of bad
events and upper bound the probabilities
to occur
then
we consider the expectation of the ratio
between real and ideal world
probabilities of
transcripts that have no bad events
in the following we study bad events
where the distinguisher wins whenever
these occur
for the bound of good transcripts we
will make use of nice transcript graphs
the graph is used to model the outputs
of the permutations and their relations
in particular the edges model the
solutions under a fixed nonce value w
we consider four sets of bad events
first collisions between non-repeating
macquaries
there for example simultaneous
collisions between both hash outputs or
so called alternating hash collisions in
sum we arrive at the following bounds
for those events
where we make use of a lemma by
nandi at al for alternating hash
collisions
moreover we consider partial collisions
between nun's repeating macquaries where
the tag is involved
and
get a second bound on those
where
the two to n results since we are in the
ideal world and there is probability of
total minus n to collide in the tag
third we consider collisions between
non-repeating macquaries and
verification queries
and finally we introduce a parameter l
and upper bound the probability that we
arrive at too many partial collisions in
either u or v that is in the hash values
for good transcripts we can now use
theorem 1 on the ratio of the
probability to idealize transcript
graphs
the proof details are a little involved
and we refer the interested reader to
the details in our paper
finally choosing an appropriate
parameter of l we arrive at a useful
bound that we have seen already in the
diagrams before
quickly also a few notes on the analysis
of extended hash's tweak
this analysis was a little easier than
that of nat2 but still needed careful
attention
we follow a similar strategy by applying
the age coefficient technique
though we could use two proofs once if
nones are respected all the time and
approve if they are not
for the former we could apply a simpler
proof for the wickman-carter-shoop
construction and arrived at the bounce
that upper-bounded the probability that
a fortress and the probability
of a simultaneous collision in both
hashes
under non-misuse we considered six bad
events in total
that were collisions between macquaries
collisions between a mac and
verification queries in hashes or the
tag
and
an upper bound that too many values we
occurred
therefore
we arrived at the following bound that
is in the order of n-bit security
depending on ideal hashing and ideal
primitives of course
the good transcripts could then be
bounded by taking mostly the number of
verification queries into account and
adding this to our previously
known bound for bad transcripts
in total
instantiating
the maximum number of collisions for
value v
with a practical and appropriate value
we arrive at the following bound
in summary
we proposed two highly secure non-spaced
macs
those took nancy's tweak and hashes
tweaked by koyati at al as a baseline
and introduced conceptually simple
changes
they possess almost full security in the
non-respecting and beyond birthday bound
security in a nun's repeating model
neither nancy's tweak non-hashes tweak
could achieve both properties
simultaneously
when nonsense are guaranteed the
security levels of our constructions are
comparable to those for nonsense tweak
and hashes tweak
respectively moreover
for repeated nonsense the bounds of our
constructions can be strictly stronger
nat2 improves it from n half to two n by
three bits and even two three and by
four bits if not too many verification
queries are asked
extended hashes tweak can extend the
security from n plus t half to n bits
future work can be to study the security
of the constructions in the idea cipher
model the search for matching
distinguishes or to consider further
mixed constructions
that was it we thank you and are looking
forward to your questions