[Music]
hello everyone my name is jin yang
in this video i will present our work
about improved case standard attorney
and distinguished attacks on snow way
this was one work finished when i was a
phd student at luandu university and it
was a joint work with thomas johansen
from doing the university and alexander
maximov from erickson research
so my presentation would follow this
outline i would first
give a short introduction to the
confidentiality and the integrity
protection 5g
and the stream sign for snowy we have
designed for that
then i will present our two guests under
determine attacks against norway and our
linear narcissist results of it
and finally i will give a short
conclusion
so let's start with the introduction
the confidentiality and integrity
protection in central networks protects
the data transmission between users and
base stations by encrypting the data and
adding authentication text
this is like adding some security tunnel
over the wireless channel as shown in
the figure so each user and the base
station will share a secret key and if
they have some data to be transmitted
they will use this secret key as one
input to a 3gbp standardized algorithm
to encrypt and authenticate the data
so in 4g there are three such
ciphers which are 3g suk and as
so they are all used to provide a
128-bit security level and are usually
implemented in hardware because that can
provide high speeds
so they work very well in
4g but how about 5g
when we come to 5g there are some new
requirements on the confidentiality and
integrity algorithms the first
requirement is about the speed so they
should be able to provide a speed of not
less than 20 gigabits per second in
software
the reason why we consider software is
that
this the confidentiality and integrity
protection in 5g
is likely moved to the cloud and
implement it in software
besides the 5g downlink big data rate is
20 gigabits per second
the second requirement is about the
security so they should be able to
provide a 256 meter sector level to
resist against content equip nurses
for the 4g algorithms snook 3g and sukuc
might not be the best candidates for 5g
the first reason is that there exists
academic attacks against them that are
faster than exhaustive case search
and the second reason is that their
speeds in software are mostly below 10
gigabits per second while 5g requires 20
gigabits per second
so uh based on the refresh motivation in
2019 we designed a successor cipher of
sun3g called snowbay intended for 5g use
the picture shows the structure of snowy
and we can say it follows the design
rationale of sonos 3g with a linear part
and a laning part
the linear part consists of two afters
we call them f a and f b
they are all defined over the finite
fields of size to the power of 16.
each f has 16 stages
and
so this gives the after 512 bits in
total we can regard the f just a state
as for 128 bit
registers that is for example the lower
part of after a is regarded as a zero
while the higher part of airsoft left a
is denoted as a1
so these two electrons
fade into each other for example a0 is
fading to b15 and b0 is faded into a50
so we have carefully choosing the
feedback polynomial such that such a
construction can provide the maximum
pure
we also consider the implementation
efficiency and the cryptography
properties
so each time for updating uh the after
cracks eight times and after that to 110
bit
tabs t1 and t2 are sent to the fsm
for the fsm it takes t1 and t2 and the
inputs
then outputs or keys in word which is
also 128 bit
it also has three registers r1 r2 and r3
they are all 128 bit
then we use two aes encryption runs as
large s-boxes to update the registers
for example r2 is updated from r1
through one aes encryption
and also r3 is updated from r2 so
another as encryption
while r1 is updated from r2 r3 and t2
through operations like xor addition
and a permutation
sigma and here should say the expression
of sigma for example
the first byte the fourth byte is moved
to the first position
while the first byte is moved to the
fourth position and so on
when we use norway
to encrypt data we need to first perform
the initialization phase
during this phase the cipher loads the k
and iv to the f charge then runs the
cipher for 16 watts without gaining
giving any output
after that the cipher starts to produce
k swim words so in each iteration it
first outputs a 128 bit casement works
then it updates the fsm part and then
updates the after part
after
that it enters the next iteration until
all the data is
encrypted we also proposed an aed mode
to also
provide authentication for the data
since no way has been published
there appeared
some
crypto nurses results
which include gasoline return meal
attacks new nuclear nurses integral
attacks differential attacks and so on
so in our paper we proposed two guest
and return attacks of complexity to the
power of 384 and to the power of 378
which are lower than existing results
we also proposed a distinguishing attack
but against a simplified version of
snowy with complexity to the power of
one advantage of our distinguishing
attack is that it
does
not need the long key streams but only
need
many shortcut streams
so next i will present more details of
the two guest under determiner attacks
the basic idea of a guest to
determine attack is to guess some
variables determine others based on
perhaps some publicly lower relations
in an external evaluation report of snow
wave the authors proposed a gas under
determine attack
so regard the
internal state of snow b as 7 128 bit
variables
then the first guess 3 variables r1 r2
and r3 and based on the guest values
they can determine the values of b0 and
b1
and a0 and in the end they need to guess
the final variable a1
so the guess and the determining process
it can be illustrated as a tree and each
branch is the
guest under determining path
since the gaussian basis involves four
variables so the complexity is 2 to the
power of 512.
so in our paper we have one observation
that if a variable appears twice in an
equation with some nonlinear operations
in between then this variable may have
zero solutions
then for these guess under determine
paths we should just truncate them
instead of going to the end
so in our first guest android determine
attack in the first step
we need to guess uh r1 r2 and r3 uh with
complexity to the power of 384 and this
step is similar to the existing
gas energy terminal attack
then we can determine the values of b0
and b1 and a0 and a1 remain unknown
the second step is to determine the
values of a0
we found a conflicting equation for a0
which is showing
in the block
so we can see a0 appears twice in the
equation
and there are some longing operations in
between like modular additions
so the question becomes how to
efficiently get the solutions of a0 and
we don't want to loop it because that
requires high complexity
in our paper we proposed a 10-step
algorithm to get the solutions of a0 the
basic idea is to divide a0 into bites
and then categorize them into 10 groups
of equations and get the solutions
recursively with considering carries for
example
the figure shows how we compute the
solutions of each groups
we compute the solutions from right to
the left
when we compute the solution when we get
the solutions of the equations on the
right we can automatically get the
values of the carries and this values of
carries will be used to solve the
equations on the left
for each group of equations we can use
lookup tables to get the to quickly get
the solutions and the maximum size of
table is 2 to the power of 68
to 256 times 20.
we experimentally computed the value the
uh the probability of finite solutions
which is 2 to the power of minus 3.91
and the average number of guests
valued guess than the determining pass
is one
so till now we have uh on average true
to the power of 384
solutions and a1 still remains unknown
so our last step is to determine the
value of a1
and luckily we can
find another conflicting equation for a1
as shown in the block and we can see it
has quite similar form to the equation
for a0 and we can use the same way to
derive the solutions of a1
the results are the same so that is
there is
on average one vanity gas and determine
pass
so
you are first to get some determine
attack we guess the values of r1 r2 and
r3 determine the values of b0 and b1 and
solve the a0 and a1 using the 10-step
algorithm with little complexity
so the total complexity is 2 to the
power of
384 we were wondering if we can exploit
more k-swing symbols to further reduce
the complexity and in our second gate
standard deuteronomy attack we
also used the k-spin word z at clock t
minus 2.
so we found another conflicting equation
for another intermediate variable b0 at
t minus 1.
we computed the probability of finding
the solutions of b zero at
t minus one which is two to the power of
minus five point eight four
so on only a one b zero at clock t minus
one has solutions we will proceed with
guessing the three variables r1 r2 and
r3 so the
complexity is computed as pz times to
the power of 384
and which is
2 to the power of 378
but uh but this attack uh leaves a table
of size
two to the power of one hundred and
twenty eight
so uh to summarize our guest under
determine text we found three
conflicting equations for a0 a1 and
another intermediate variable
and if we found there are no solutions
for these area variables we don't need
to go go deeper but it's just a twist
bike to get some other values for
example
at this question determine
pause we found that a0 does not have any
solutions then we don't need to go to a1
we just twist bike and go to another gas
under determining path
by doing this we can reduce the
complexity from two to the power of five
hundred twelve to two to the power of
three hundred and seventy eight
next i will show our
linear cryptanosis of snow way
actually we were considering a
simplified version of snowing in which
the 32-bit adders are replaced with the
x or operations then the only
longing operations in
in this version is
xbox
so we consider three consecutive
casement words and the expressions are
shown here
b 0 b 1 a 0
are the contribution from the f sharp
and we want to cancel them out
so to cancel out a b 0 and b 1 we only
need to apply two linear uh masks to the
t minus one and they team specifically
or apply the mask l beta and edge beta
so
when we add the three key spin words
the ao beta b0 and h beta b1 will be
cancelled
then we need to cancel a0 remember that
the expression of sigma is shown here
we can introduce term by space to um
the based on sigma for example the
um
the byte e1 is uh computed as w1 uh xor
w4 this is because uh the the fourth
byte is moved to position one while the
first byte is moved to position four so
if we add these two
bytes
uh sigma a0 plus a0 at this position
with these two positions will be
cancelled cancel out
so through
this term bytes the after contribution
uh
after contribution is cancelled
so now each ei byte only contains bytes
from r1 r2 r3 and their s boxes or
inverse x boxes and now it is possible
to explore or buyers locally that means
we only need very short key streams so
we can introduce our noise and which is
the linear combination of the 10 bytes
and the ci's are linear masking matrices
that we want to explore
so we can expand the expression of the
noise n and a and b coefficient
matrices are the coefficient matrices
so each row of the two vectors
did not actually denote to one xbox app
summation for example the first
row
the r1
at byte 0 and s r1 at bat 0 denotes the
denote denotes one x-box approximation
and the uh coefficients of the x-box
approximation is determined by a b and
also c
in this case there are in total up to uh
48 s applications
and if a same column of say a and
say b here are zero this
as corresponding xbox app summation will
be cancelled
so now our goal is to choose a linear
masking matrix say to cancel as many
xboxes as possible
note that if t s box approximations are
can be cancelled then c a and c b at
these two columns should be zero
so we can choose different k columns of
c a and c b and construct a matrix
and we want to find a non-zero matrix c
such that 3 times k equals to 0 that
means the x boxes are cancelled
so what we need to do is to perform
gaussian elimination on k and at the
same time perform the same operations on
the
identity matrix i
so if the last w rows of k are 0 the
last w of i becomes the
same mask
so then the value of w is also
determined
in our attack we can cancel
nine x-boxes and w equals sixteen
we have computed the bias is true to the
power of 300 minus 303 and also then we
can have a distinguishing attack
of complexity to the power of three
hundred minus three
i mentioned our distinguishing attack
does not need any uh long key streams
and this is because the after
contribution a0 b0 b1 appears twice uh
in the
in the expression of three key string
words and then we can just cancel them
locally
then it becomes possible to explore a
biased combination between the three
registers in the fsm
on other hand the last lfc variable a1
does not appear at all
in the express in the expression of the
three key spin words
so in our proposed snowy very
interesting vi
based on this observation we made
one modification
the two figures shows uh
modifications in the after part of of
snowy
and the
the
medications are called uh colored
uh the red one denotes some medication
which is relevant to our distinguishing
attack so specifically we have moved the
tap position of t2 from the lower part
that is a0
to the higher part of left a that is a1
and in this case the value of a1 will be
sent to the fsm
quickly and
then will appear in the key stream word
and
it only appears once in the expression
and this means that the company linear
combination of the three key stream
worlds will become balanced and then it
we cannot
explore our buyers anymore
so
finally i would like to give a
conclusion
snow whey is the cipher designed for 5g
and it is currently under evaluation in
the sage group
in our paper we propose to two gas and
determine attacks against snow bin with
complexity to the power of 384 and to
the power of 378.
we pointed out
in our paper that the complexity of the
guest and determine attacks
should be determined by the number of
the full guest under determining path
and based on this we designed
guests
and determined strategies to explore
conflicts and truncate some guests and
determine paths
our linear hypnosis results into a
distinguishing attack of of a variant of
snow bay with complexity to the power of
and this attack results in one
modification in snow weight eye
in the end i would like to mention our
latest attack
against novi
this work uh was published
in the europe conference this year it
was a correctional attack and the
complexity is to the power of 240.
this attack does not uh pose a direct
rate to the practic practical use of
snow way because the length of the k
swim key streams in snow bay is limited
to to the power of 64.
but it still indicates that snowy can be
improved
so in the um in a 3gb document draft
about uh
ang snos reggie and snobby
uh it writes sa3 kindly asks sage to
assess the research paper mentioned
above and determine any implications as
norway
and subjected to the outcome of the
previous action sa3 kindly asks sage to
proceed with the development of 256 feet
of encryption and integrate
algorithm specifications based on snowy
so this means this indicates that snow
they might need some further
modifications
and als and also it still indicates that
snow way can still be promising for five
to use
so with that i would end my presentation
thank you very much for the listening