hello everyone i'm lauha from ting high
university one of the authors of paper
improved premium attacks on foreign
224-256
this paper has been published in tosc
volume 2021 issue 1. on behalf of other
authors in this video i will give about
20 minutes presentation to explain our
work in this paper
as the title indicates the analysis
object of this paper is foreign low
capacity chart and the attack type is
limited to pre-image attack moreover we
focus on linear analysis which is
commonly used in pre-image fields
we improve the linear analysis by a
technology named freedom use strategy
which will be mainly discussed in this
video
this strategy works for partial
linearization part and it can be
directly applied in any full linear
structure
then we choose the currently best linear
structure for low capacity chart
proposed in ls19
as a result we reduce the attack
complexity by factors of 2 to the power
of 15 and 2 to the power of 21.
an important note is the complexity here
and even in the whole video refer to
guess times instead of catch up running
we just neglect the cost of solving the
linear exchange system in total counting
this page briefly summarizes sound
related work in pre-image fields of
round-read sketchup
firstly in ms-13 the authors provide
pre-image attacks with sat
this kind of tag can outperform exotic
search in catch up reduced to three
rounds
then the authors further applied
rotational group analysis in mps13
this kind of attack even works in
foreign high
as far as capacity know this is the only
work that provides pre-image
analysis on foreign 512 since linear
analysis can hardly deal with it
in gls 16 a two-round full linear
structure of ketchup run function is
proposed this structure can be directly
applied in sri lanka chalk while attacks
for foreign still requires another
process of partial linearization
in ls19 the officers developed a linear
structure via an allocated model this
model works extremely well in sri lanka
chalk and even helps in providing the
first practical pre-image for surround
cat chalk 224
however their partial linearization
strategy for foreign head shock is still
inefficient
our work directly inherits this
developed model and just makes efforts
in partial linearization
the complexities of pre-image attacks on
foreign chart 224-256
are summarized in this table
from the comparison you can see that for
foreign chalk an efficient partial
linearization strategy can even bring
more gains than a developed linear
structure so partial linearization is
indeed a major problem
before getting into the main part we
first learned some preliminaries of
hedgehog about calculating output and
some important notations
as we all know techchuck was the winner
of shasta competition and finally
standardized in 2015. the designers
adopt a new proposed iterative
construction and sponge
in this video we will now present the
execution of general sponge for more
details please refer to the ketchup
reference we only focus on a certain
case that its integrity core can check
the permutation is executed only twice
as shown in the figure below
this is exactly the attack model we use
in this paper
as for the cache authentication it runs
on a 1600 bit inner state the inner
state can be organized as a 5 times 5
times 64 cuboid and each bit is indexed
by a triple x y z where x and y vary
from 0 to 4 and z varies from 0 to 63.
according to the character reference the
cuboid can be cut into different parts
nand rows columns lengths or slices
under certain x or y or z as shown in
the figure
then each execution of ketchup f
consists of 24 rounds of wrong function
are and each r includes phi step sita yo
pi chi iota we understand not all
listeners are familiar with the ketchup
function so we fade the concrete
formulas out and try to hide the
properties of those steps
well zeta is the diffusion layer by the
sum operation among 11 bits row is an
inland rotation permutation pi is an in
slice swap permutation chi is the five
bit quantity xbox which is the only
non-linear step into chart f and iota is
a constant sum layer which can be
ignored in linear analysis
after finishing all k chaff executions
the digest is output from the first l
bit of the final state
the counting order is z x and finally y
the directions are given in the figure
we set this page here just to emphasize
that in case charge 224 digest from the
fourth line correspond to d from 0 to
31.
the last part of preliminaries is quite
important because it involves the
meanings of those notations we use in
this paper
without learning these notations those
construction figures of linear structure
or freedom rule strategy might be hard
to understand
first we need to mark the execution
status of a middle state we use a
capital greece letter with the
superscript to denote the state exactly
after the corresponding step here alpha
is among theta rho pi chi iota and i
starts from one we pronounce it alpha is
for example pi third which means the
state after the third pi step is the
last linear state in the linear
structure in particular iota zeros
denotes the initial state after
absorbing the message block
then we can further denote one bit from
a certain state with the triple index in
the subscript we pronounce it alpha eyes
x y z for example chi force zero zero
zero to chi force four zero thirty one
corresponds to the output of foreign
charge 224
here we inverse the last iota step
before searching the pre-image
we may also use star symbol to denote a
part of a certain state the start symbol
here means all legal values for example
pi 3 star y z is a 5 0 pi third x star z
is a vibrate colon pi third x y star is
the 64 bit length and pi 3 star star z
is a five times five slice
column sound is significant value in
zeta steps we use single s to denote the
column sound so that we can simplify
some calculating formulas
this symbol is marked by a certain state
with x d which denotes the sum of
corresponding 5 bit column
now we can start our improve linear
analysis of chart
first of all we should expand how linear
analysis works in cachacaron function
it is self-evident that the core of
linear analysis is to construct linear
relations between input bits and output
bits suppose we have input m of o and we
may need some link variables l to
connect input and output
we set some conditions in m to linearize
parts of l and then set conditions in l
to linearize part of o
there is also another way where we start
from l linearizing forwards and
backwards here we only focus on the
direct linearization
as long as we linearize any beta in o we
successfully construct a linear root
from the encryption function then we can
satisfy some conditions in linearized
output bits and each condition brings a
gain of 2 to the power of 1.
all these conditions above compose a
linear equivalent system which
corresponds to a 0 1 matrix
actually the linear equation system may
have no solution or multiple solutions
here remain again that we neglect the
cost of solving it we are only concerned
with the number of solutions in total
for matching the entire output
for the analysis objective chart things
become a bit different in linear
analysis circuit chart i mean present
linear analysis l becomes a full linear
state and o becomes the output of last
pi step in other words it constructs a
losing root since l is not partially
chosen and o is not digest
under these analysis for m to l we need
to design a linear structure and from l
to o we need to perform a partial
linearization
we will better reduce those locations in
mml so that we can send more equations
in o because the total number of
equations is limited by the length of m
moreover since the linear root doesn't
pass through the last quadratic x box
one equation thing o may not bring again
2 to the power of 1 after constructing
the linear route gain analysis will be
further required
therefore the improved linear analysis
of hr consists of three parts linear
structure partial linearization and gain
analysis
first about linear structure we have
stated that we inherit this part from
ls19 where a two-run linear structure
with 194 degrees of freedom left is
designed via an allocating model
in this video we just simply introduced
the principle of this structure for more
details please refer to the original
paper
to construct a linear structure we must
let the linear root pass through chi
which is the only nonlinear step in
ketchup f
it is easily known that chi keeps linear
when the input doesn't contain
neighboring variables for example if
only zero y z and two y z are variables
all five bits outputs can keep linear
under this law the linear rule can
easily pass through the first chi step
then we must deal with linear generation
to avoid neighboring variables appearing
in the next kind
we need to choose proper constant to
prevent generation in chi and fix column
sounds to prevent diffusion in sita as
for your empire these two are b2b
permutations and will not generate new
variables
this figure shows the two-run linear
structure for ketchup 256. the structure
for ketchup 224 is just similar
here each square represents a 64-bit
length the initial state contains 10
variable lengths leaving 15 constant
lengths among those constant lengths
eight lengths are restricted because
they are out of the range of message
block as marked by diagonals
the linear structure starts with 320
columns equations to prevent diffusion
in the first data step here rc is short
for random cost which supports a random
space for searching the pre-image
the constants of the first chi staff are
all fixed by the form of variable 0
variable 0 1 so that the first chi staff
will not generate new variables
similarly in the second data step 128
equations are set to prevent diffusion
finally the linear rule passes through
the second chi step and reach pi third
it can be proven that the rank of
equation matrix is only 446
returning two degrees of freedom thus
this two-run structure leaves 194
degrees of freedom actually to make
those constants of 0 and 1 in the first
chi step the length in the initial state
must satisfy specific conditions however
some conditions only involve restricted
parts and cannot be satisfied by setting
the message for this reason an
allocating model is applied to generate
a qualified inner state
it should be noted that the complexity
of matching such conditions is much
smaller than searching the pre-image so
we omit this part of complexity in total
counting
after linearizing state pi third we can
continue on partial linearization first
we need to understand the effect of one
constant in pi third each constant in
the 100 and 600 bit inner state can
linearize two neighboring bits on its
left like the example in the figure the
constant of pi 3 3 1 d can linearize chi
3 1 1 z and kaiser to 1 d
then since the target bit in pi force
comes from the sum of 11 bits in chi 3
and among these speeds only 2 are
neighboring it is easily known that the
partial linearization of a single bit
requires at least 10 constants as shown
in the figure this is indeed the most
efficient strategy for a single bit
yet for multiple bits this strategy is
apparently inefficient because it weighs
almost half of those linear speeds in
kaiser
actually those wasted bits can be
utilized by simply adding one constant
as shown in the figure by adding such a
constant we can draw another group of 11
linearized speeds and finally reach a
target in pi 4. a restriction of this
2-bit strategy is the locations of two
targets are relatively fixed for example
if the first bit is pi force 1 0 z plus
44 the second bit must be pi 4 2 0 z
plus 43 the numbers here are decided by
the offset of real step
based on this 2-bit strategy we finally
adopt the freedom rule strategy that
makes full use of those linear speeds in
kaiser with the chosen starting column
each term we let one colon coincide with
the colon of the previous term which
means we can get two linear speeds by
adding only six constants yet the
restriction of this strategy becomes
even stricter because the locations of
all linearized speeds are directly
determined by the starting column
this table shows a comparison between
old strategy and freedom real strategy
within identically 194 degrees of
freedom
the oil strategy says 10 times
unconstant for unlimited speeds
practically 150 for 17 while the three
and rear strategy says 5.6 times
unconstrained for two times the linear
speed practically 173 for 56
the efficiency gap is quite apparent
advantage of old strategy is that the
location of each linear base can be
arbitrarily chosen
such attackers can choose the site that
linearly match the digest with a gain of
almost 2 to the power of 1.
yet under freedom rule strategy the
location of each linear bit is
relatively fixed thus there is a gain
loss since some bits may not linearly
match the digest the gain may be 2 to
the power of 1 2 to the power of 0.5 or
even no gain
these conclusions will be further argued
in game analysis part
now we expand the principle and effect
of freedom real strategy which is the
main technology we use in this paper
yet a question is if we spend 173
degrees of freedom in setting constants
how can we get again over 2 to the power
of 21.
actually we propose another technology
named zero coefficient to reduce cost by
using this technology we find and
construct 11 linear dependent bit pairs
so that those constants only cost 162
degrees of freedom
to expand the principle of zero
coefficient we first recall the two-run
linear structure we have contracted a
linear route from chi 0 to pi 3 and we
are about to set several constants in
piscer to perform partial linearization
one step backwards each bit in python
corresponds to the sum of 11 bits in kai
second in the form of two columns and
one solitary bit although we pan chi
second or yellow actually some of the
lengths may be constant or variables
depending on the input of step chi
now let's consider special case of a bit
pair in the stem column of chi second it
is found that if the two slots are bits
are both constant then no matter where
the two columns are the corresponding
bits in c has third become linear
dependent because their components are
just the same
this zero coefficient pair finally
reaches pi third and in this case we can
set two constants by spanning only one
degree of freedom
this is the key idea of zero coefficient
of course these two constants cannot be
set randomly they must be equal or
contrary according to the linear
relation
as for the construction of zero
coefficient pairs we need to meet some
restrictions to ensure the constant
attribute of corresponding bits and the
constant attribute is decided by related
bits of the xbox input
to fix the input bits we even need to
trace back to the column sum in chi
first
notice that setting column sound will
now cause degrees of freedom because
column sounds belong to the b tar of
equation system a times x equal to b
this table shows the details of all 11 0
coefficient b pairs on the starting
column pi 3 for star c
from the table we can see that these
speed pairs can be constructed without
constructions
so far we have finished the partial
linearization part of our improve linear
analysis for low capacity chart
by spending 162 degrees of freedom we
can linearize 56 bits in pi 4.
yet because of the last long linear chi
step those spacing pipe force may not
linearly match the digest so we still
need to perform again analysis to
calculate the expected gain of those
linear speeds
in get analysis part we adopt a bit
recovery model to select effect
equations usually the number of infected
equations is larger than the number of
degrees of freedom left so it requires
another process of freedom return to
make up the lack of freedom
this table displays the details of all
56 linearized bits under starting column
pi third for star d
it is concluded that those speeds are
distributed in 38 rows which can be
divided into three classes according to
the number of linearized bits they
contain
our b recovery model also works
differently in three classes in rows
containing one bit the principle is
quite simple for a certain output if one
bit is identical in all possible inputs
it is regarded as a recovery bit and we
can see an effective equation on it the
gain of such equation is 2 to the power
of 1 because it compresses the whole
space into half size with all qualified
cases conserved
when the analysis object is charged 224
seems to become a bit complicated
because an uncertain bit may cover three
out of four cases which brings the gain
of only two to the power of 0.5 as shown
in the example
though it is also in fact equations with
a better give priority to those
equations that can bring a gain of 2 to
2.1 since the space for equation setting
is limited
then in use containing two bits it
depends on the number of recurrent bits
if there are two recurrent bits the gain
is of course two to the power of two if
there are one recovery and one uncertain
bit the game may be 2 to the power of 1
or 2 to the power of 0.5
if two bits are both uncertain we can
still set effect equations on the sum of
two bits as shown in examples
similarly for k chart 224 the equation
may only cover three out of four cases
though we have multiple choices in this
situation no single equation can bring
again over two to the power of 0.5
as four rows containing three bits this
situation is quite complicated but
fortunately we only need to analyze a
specific case for ketchup 256.
in this case pi force40z will never be
recovered so it is quite similar to the
case of rows containing two beats though
three bits are all uncertain we can
still set effect equations on the sum of
two bits as shown in the example
it is concluded that this kind of row
can always bring a gain of 2 to the
power of 2.
we have explained how to set effect
equations on linear space in pi force
the number of vector equations depends
on the locations of linear speeds and
the digest we are about to match
yet in some good cases the number of
factor equations may exist degrees of
freedom
besides making full use of freedom we
can also perform freedom return to fetch
more space
the principle of freedom return is quite
simple recall that in freedom of
strategy each time we add one colon and
one solitary constant to linearize two
bits
actually the solitary constant
corresponds to one of the two linear
speeds if we find no effective creations
can be set on such kind of bits we can
return the freedom by deleting the
equations of setting solitary constants
since we linearized 56 bits in pi force
28 of them may return freedom among
these speeds six have been bound in zero
coefficient pairs and cannot apply
freedom return
this table summarizes the situations of
freedom return for remaining 22 bits
under starting column pi 3 4 0 z
it is concluded that seven degrees of
freedom can be returned in average
finally by carefully calculating the
probability of each combination we get
the analysis results as below
for foreign chart 256 it is
theoretically concluded that 34.5 effect
equations can be set in average under
starting column pi 340z here this shows
a characteristic of rotational symmetry
varying from 0 to 63.
yet for a certain digest there must be a
best starting column that brings the
greatest game we also run an
experimental test and has concluded that
for about 74.5
of random digest the total gain can
reach 2 to the power of 38.
for foreign 224 it is directly concluded
that 38 effect equations can be set in
average under starting colon pi 3406
which is exactly the best starting colon
yet the total gain is 2 to the power of
32 since some of the equations cannot
bring again of 2 to the power of 1.
the experimental result shows that for
about 61.3 percent of random digest the
total gain can reach 2 to the power 32
for more details such as distribution
table gain list and calculating process
please refer to the original paper
so far we have displayed all the
contents we need to explain about our
work and now let us make a summary
in this paper we provide improvement
attacks on foreign 224
256 through linear analysis the grouping
analysis consists of three parts as
listed below about linear structure we
inherit this part from ls19 which is a
two round structure with 194 degrees of
freedom left
our main improvements are reflected in
partial linearization part
we adopt the frequency strategy where
multiple bits can be linearized by some
common constants in addition through the
technology of zero coefficient the cost
of setting constants can be further
decreased
in final gain analysis by applying bit
recovery and freedom return it is
concluded that the total gain of our
improved premium tax can reach 2 to the
power 32 and 2 to the power of 38
respectively
that's all about our presentation thank
you for listening
you