hi
i am avijit dharta
i am going to present our work improve
security bound of ewcdm and dwcdm
it's a joint fork with nilanjan dartha
and kushankul datta
we are all from institute for advancing
intelligence tcg crest
this paper mainly studies different kind
of non-space map constructions
therefore we begin our talk with the
popular non-space mac construction which
is known as wetland cutter mac
so wegman cotton mac was proposed by
wegman and carter
this mac
takes the message in
which is hashed through a hash function
h k
and the hash value is then randomly
masked to generate the tag
to generate the random string
we apply a pseudonym function on
distinct nouns n
[Music]
this mac
gives optimal security bound
in particular
when all the nonces are distinct across
different queries
then it achieves
epsilon times qv security bound where
epsilon is the almost zero universal
probability of the underlying kid hash
function and qv is the number of
verification attempts that an adversary
can make
however
an inherent drawback of this
construction is that
if the nonce is reused
for once
then the construction does not give any
security
so security of this construction is
completely lost in the non-missive
scenario
to solve this problem
one natural solution was to encrypt the
output of the wegman quarterback and
thus the resulting construction is known
as encrypted wegman quarterback
the security bound of this encrypted
rickman cutter mech is as good as the
wegman cutter
in particular it gives the optimal
security bound in the non-suspecting
setting
and additionally it gives beyond above
the bound security and the non-mission
setting
however
the pseudo-random function is rarely
available in practice
so therefore
one can think of to replace this pseudo
random function with a cellular random
permutation
now if you replace this pseudo-random
function with a pseudo-random
permutation
then the resulting construction will not
give adequate security
in particular if you replace this fk
with an block cipher e k
then in the non respective setting the
security of the resulting construction
will drop down to the birthday bound
because
if you replace this fk with ek
then an adversary can make
too many queries where all the nonces in
these queries will be distinct and the
message will be same
therefore all the queue inputs to the
second block cipher call will be
distinct and as a result of that all the
tags that he will obtain will also be
distinct
all the q distinct tags can be
distinguished from the uniform random
tags if if the adversary can make at
least 2 power n by 2 queries
therefore the prf security of the
construction
will only give the better route security
as a possible possible remedy of the
solution one can think of to instantiate
this pseudo-random function with the
popular sum of
some of pseudo-random permutation
and we know that the sum of
pseudo-random permutation
is a very good prf in particular it
gives the optimal security amount so
therefore if you replace the pseudo
random function fk with the sum of prp
construction then the resulting
construction will give optimal security
mount
but
this construction requires three block
cipher calls
therefore we ask that can we reduce the
number of block cipher calls
to answer this question in crypto 2016
cogniti and syrian proposed their
construction which is known as encrypted
wegman cutter with tv smear construction
in which the pseudo-random function of
ewc mac is instantiated by the key
dividement construction as follows
this mac
gives 20 by three bit max security in
the non-suspecting setting and n by two
bit security in the non-specific city
in this paper
cognate and syrian have conjectured that
their construction is secure even if the
adversary can make up to two power and
many queries in the non-suspecting
setting
they have also conjectured that if the
two block cipher keys become identical
there also the construction will retain
the same security in the non-suspecting
setting that means that the single kid
ewc dm construction will retain two
power to n by three bit security in
non-suspecting setting
in crypto 2017
manning and navs they proved the optimal
prf security of ewcdm construction in
non-suspecting setting
however their security proof was
essentially relied on patterns general
mirror theory technique
however the proof of general mirror
theory technique by beta rain
for two power n bound is still a matter
of defense
in dcc 18 cognate and student they
acknowledged that proving the security
of single kid ew serium is very hard
therefore we ask that can we design a
launch-based bbb secure mac with a
single block cipher
in crypto 2018 dutta at all proposed
their construction which is known as
decrypted wakeman carter with davis
mayor
in this construction notice that
the second block cipher call of the
ewcdm is now replaced with the inverse
of ek
so therefore the construction
essentially boils down to having a
single block cipher key
the authors have proved that their
construction is 2 1 by 3 bit max secure
in the non-suspecting setting and m by
2-bit max secure in the non-misused
setting
however
their construction
can take 2 and by 3-bit nonce
that means the launch space of the dwcm
construction was only restricted to 2
power 12x3 many
possibilities
however the security proof of the
construction was essentially reliant on
couple of assumptions of the underlying
hash function in particular
the underlying hash function needs to be
2 power minuses 2 power minus and
regular to power minus and 3 way regular
and it has to be 2 power minus n almost
all universal
in this paper we ask that can we improve
the security bound of ewcdm and dwcdm
because till now what we have seen that
these two constructions are secured only
about two and by three bits secured in
the non-stroking setting therefore we
study that if it is possible to improve
the security bomb of these two
constructions
to analyze the security bound to to
having the improved security bound of
these two constructions we first
discussed
the extended meter theory technique
so in extended media theory technique we
deal with
a system of equations and a
non-equations
so in the left hand side of this figure
we can see that there is a system of
bivariate defining equations
and in the right hand side there is a
system of bivariate affine non equations
and this system of equations and noun
equations are defined over say are many
variables
the goal of this extended mirror theory
is to lower bound the number of
solutions to the system of equations and
non-equations such that
all the variables all these are
variables they will be distinct
we can view the system of equations and
non-equation in terms of graph
when we represent the set of variables
as a set of vertices that means all the
variables can be
casted to a set of vertices
if two variables are associated to an
equation say p1 plus p2 equals to lambda
then we give and solid
red edge and that edge should be
undirected between the corresponding two
vertices
similarly if the two were two two
variables are associated through a
non-equation say p one plus p two is not
equals to lambda prime
then we put a dashed blue edge which is
obviously leveled and that should be
undirected between the corresponding two
vertices so for example here the
equation if we have an equation say p 1
plus v 2 goes to lambda
then we put
our solid red edge between the
corresponding vertices v 1 and v 2 with
a level c lambda
and if we have a non equation say p 1
plus p 2 not equals to lambda prime then
we put a dash blue edge
between v 1 and v 2 with the
corresponding label lambda prime
as an example we can see that we have a
system of equations that p 1 plus p 2
equals to lambda 1 and as a result of
that we put a
solid red edge between the vertices v 1
and v 2 with the corresponding level
lambda 1
and we have another equation p1 plus pc
equals to lambda 2 therefore we put
another edge between the vertices v1 and
v3
and the corresponding level lambda 2.
similarly we have a system of equations
and non-equations say p1 plus p2 equals
to lambda 1 and therefore we have put an
edge between what is vertex v1 and v2
with the level lambda 1 we have an
equation p3 plus v4 equals to lambda 2
therefore we have put an edge between v3
and v4 with the edge with the level
lambda 2 and we have a non-equation say
p2 plus p3 which is not equals to lambda
3 and therefore we have put an edge
between the vertex v2 and v3 and that is
a
dashed blue h with the corresponding
lambda 3.
so in this way we can cast a system of
equations and non-equations to an
equivalent graph
we say
that
a graph is bad if it satisfies either of
these following three conditions
the conditions are the following if the
graph contains a cycle
if
if you take any path in the graph let
the path be p
and if you sum up the edge levels of the
edges which are involved in the path
and if the sum is 0 then we say that the
graph is bad
and finally
if there is a cycle in the graph say c
that involves exactly one non-equation h
and we denote this non-equation edge
with a blue dashed edge
so if the cycle involves a non-equation
h say e
then
we will consider that graph to be bad
only if
the level of that non-equation edge
is the sum of the levels of the path p
where p is basically c minus e
so c is the cycle and e is the
non-equation h
so if you consider the path p which is c
minus e
then and if you take the sum of the
edges some of the levels of the edges
which are involved in the path p
and that thing is assigned as the level
of the non-equation age then we will
call that graph is bad
in this paper we have shown
this extended mirror theory result for
two types of graph
the first type is for a general graph
and the second type is for a bipartite
graph
we have shown that for a fixed good
general graph
the number of solutions to the
associated system of equation and
equation is at least 2 power n following
factorial s over to power mqm
times 1 minus some error term where s is
the number of vertices and q m is the
total number of edges
here qc is the total number of edges of
the sub graph of the graph g which is
generated if we just remove the non
equation edges from the graph g
so the sub graph
the generated sub graph say g prime
is generated out of the graph g
by deleting only the non equation edges
from the graph g
similarly we have shown
uh the following result of the extended
meta theory for a bipartite graph that
for a fixed code bipartite graph the
number of solutions to the associated
system of equation and non-equation is
at least two power n following factorial
sl times two power n following factorial
sr over two power n q m times one minus
some error term where sn is the number
of vertices of the left partition and a
sr is the number of vertices in the
right partition of the bipartite graph
and 2m is the total number of edges
similarly qc is the number of pages of
the sub graph which is generated out of
the graph g by deleting the non-equation
edges and here obviously this q v is the
total number of non-equation edges which
are present in the graph g
okay now we discuss briefly the what is
h coefficient technique so h coefficient
technique is a very powerful
combinatorial tool which is used to
bound the distinguishing advantage of
two random system so here we are
assuming that this two random system is
basically
uh this two algorithms this sign signing
algorithm and the verification algorithm
which are present in the real world and
in the ideal world we have
uh two random systems say the first one
is the random function and the
second one is a reject symbol
or the uh about oracle
okay so the signing so here is an
adversary that adversary is interacting
with the pair of oracles either in the
real world or in the ideal world so if
the adversary is interacting with the
real world then it has access to the
signing model and the verification
article and these two oracles are
basically the keyed oracles and the
adversary does not access to this key
does not have access to this key
and if the adversary is interacting with
this ideal world then it is actually
interacting with this random oracle and
the about oracle
so if the adversary is interacting with
the real world then if it queries with
the message m then the signing oracle
will get back will will
return the corresponding tag and if it
is interacting with the verification
oracle then the verification oracle will
either say yes or no depending on
whether the tag message tag pair is a
valid or not
in contrast if it is interacting with
the ideal world then if it queries to
the random oracle with say message f
then the random oracle will randomly
sample the tag
and if it
interacts with this about oracle with
the message tag pair m comma t then the
idea this this about oracle will always
return about
and the distinguishing advantage of this
adversary a to distinguish the real
world from the ideal one is defined
something like this
and to upper bound this advantage using
the edge coefficient technique one needs
to do this following three things first
of all
they have to identify the bad transcript
then
we need to i we need to up or down the
probability of the bad transcripts in
the ideal world and then if we fix a
good transcript then we have to lower
down the ratio of the real to ideal
interpolation probability for that good
transcript
[Applause]
so in detail so we denote this x re
which is the probability distribution of
the transcript induced in the real world
x id is the probability of distribution
of transcript in the ideal world and
math calculate which is denoted as the
this disjoint union of these two sets a
good t and bad d so that t is basically
the set of all that transcript and good
t is the set of all good transcript
so what is transcript so transcript is
basically the
summarization of the summary of the
interaction between the
adversary and the oracle
so having defined this wisdom state the
main theorem of the excavation technique
which says
that
there exists a positive number positive
real numbers epsilon ratio such that the
ratio of the internet of the of the
interpolation probability in the real
world and the ideal one is lower bounded
by one minus epsilon ratio and there
exist another positive real numbers
epsilon band such that this probability
that x id belongs to the set of that
transcript is upper bounded by epsilon
bar
then we can upper bound the advantage of
distinguishing these two random systems
real and ideal which is upper bounded by
the sum of these two quantities epsilon
ratio and epsilon band
[Applause]
okay
now using this h coefficient technique
we will prove the uh
we will we will prove the security bound
of ewcd
so one can cast the uh system or one can
cause the errors if evaluation of awcdm
to a system of equations and the
non-equations so in particular if you
have we we have the system of q and many
mac equation and qv many verification
equations
and one can naturally cast the system of
equation and non-equation to a
corresponding graph
where this lambda i is basically the sum
of noise and the hash value of the
message similarly lambda i prime is the
sum of the
nouns and the hash value of the message
where ini prime and the mi prime is the
credit uh
noise and the message in the
verification query
okay
now after this interaction is over the
trunk the transcript will be generated
and we then we will
partition this transcript into two sets
the bad set and the good set we say that
the transcript is bad if you take any
two queries
such that their t value collects and the
lambda value coils
look look at this equation that if you
cast this equation in terms of graph
then
we will not get any cycle
because
this n1 and n2 so these are all distinct
right
so if you take any two equations and for
these two equations if their t value
matches and the corresponding lambda
value matches
then since p 1 is a permutation then
therefore this end value will be matched
but since we are proving this security
in the non-respecting setting so this
situation cannot arise in the real world
so this situation can only occur in the
ideal world therefore that event will
distinguish it from the random system or
from the ideal world
so therefore we take this
we take this event to be bad
number two is that once we cast this
equation in terms of graph it will
basically leads to different components
and we bound the size of the component
in particular we say
that if the generator if the if the size
of the generator component is at least q
m to the power 2 by 3 then we call the
transcript is bad
and finally if we have a fortunate
attempt such that
the the corresponding uh nonce and the
tag collides and also the hash value of
codes that means suppose an adversary
queries which say n prime t prime and m
prime such that m plane is
is matched to some previous varied nodes
t plane match with the corresponding
obtained tag and eventually the hash
value of the message which is queried
with the message m prime that has also
been collided
if these three things happens then we
will say
that the transcript is bad
so if the transcript is not bad
that means for a good transcript and if
you have a good transcript then we can
also generate a good graph i mean we can
also generate a graph and that graph
will be good graph so one can easily
identify that the structure of good
graph will be something like this that
means it will be a cyclic
and the size of the components will be
at most q m to the power two by three
and therefore we can apply the military
for this code graph and obviously one
one should note that these graphs are
actually the bipartite graphs
so therefore we can apply this mirror
theory for the bipartite graph to lower
bound the real interpolation probability
next we come to the overview of the
security proof of dwcm
so as we have written down the mac
equation and the verification equation
for ewcdm we can similarly write down
the math equation and the verification
into it verification equation for the
wcdm
so again we have this qm mini mac
equation and the qv many verification
equations
and generally one can ah cast this
system of math equation and the
verification equation in terms of graph
again we identify the bad graph and the
code graph
so we say that a
graph is bad if
any of these following conditions is
satisfied so the first condition says
that if the component size of the
magraph is at least 5
if it contains a cycle
or if it contains a path of length 3
such that their level sum is 0
and if there is a
graph
of
if there is an edge with a level 0 if
there is an age in a magnet 0.
there are some of the additional uh bad
events so for example if the map graph
contains a cycle that includes a dashed
blue edge
there are other another additional bad
events that means say for example if we
take two macquaries
such that their tag collides and the
lambda value also collides or the
nonsense the tag collides or and the
lambda value colors
the number of pair of mac queries such
that the n and p collides or t the
the two tag collides it's at least q m
to the power two by three
or there's a mac query such that the tag
is zero
if none of these bad events happen then
the corresponding transcript will be
good and if you uh
cast this transcript in terms of graph
then we will land up with this good
graphs
and therefore we can apply this meta
theory for the general graph to lower
down the real interpolation probability
for such good graphs
next we look at some of the glimpses of
the bounding bad events
so we first say that there's about so so
there is a component of size at least
five
so if we have a component of at least 5
then
we will we will have this many
possibilities
and we have shown that bounding of this
event is to power qm over 2 power 3 n by
where qf is the number of uh total edges
of the map of the of the corresponding
graph
the second even is a bounding cycle in a
mag graph so in order to bounce cycle in
a magnet we have these four
possibilities okay we will not have a
cycle of length five because we have
already bounded that the component size
is of at least five so if we have a
component of size five then that
actually reduces to this first event
and we have shown that the bound of this
event is maximum of this
the third event is that the bounding my
graph having a path of length three with
level sum zero so we have these two
possibilities
and for that again we have our desired
mount
for bounding my graph that that contains
a cycle which actually includes a dash
blue edge that means we have a cycle
but that cycle includes exactly one
non-equation edge or a dash blue edge
and we have this so so in this case we
have categorized it into three steps so
first the bounding self loop and
parallel images for this we have so self
rule is for one possibility for bounding
parallel edges we have this following
two possibilities and for each of these
cases we have seen that this bound is in
our desired range
next we bound the triangles
so for triangles we have these three
following possibilities and for each of
them we have shown that this bound is
again in our desired range so in
particular the bound is qv times epsilon
3 rate
the maximum of qb times epsilon 3 day
and qm over 2 power 5 n by 4.
finally we have the
we have this case of bounding the
squares because
again we are essentially uh bounding the
background which will contain a cycle
that includes a
dash blue h so we will have a bounding
we will have this structure of square
and we have this following three
possibilities and for that we have shown
that our bound that we have obtained is
in our desired range note that we will
not go for will not go beyond this
because if we go beyond this then again
that will include uh
that actually reduces to those
possibilities
to component of size at least five
okay so finally uh we want just to make
a remark that how our proof is different
from the original dwcm proof ok so in
the original dwcdm proof the authors
have
authors have casted the system of
equations to a graph in a different
terminology so they have
they have represented a vertex to be an
equation and they put an
edge between two vertices
if the corresponding equations share a
variable
but in our setting what we have done
that we
we have represented a vertex as a
variable in of the corresponding system
of equation and non-equation and we have
put an edge between two vertices if
these two variables are associated by an
equation
so if we cast their representation in
terms of our terminology then the
corresponding bad events that was
generated in the original database cdm
proof is of other followings that the
windows graph contains a cycle any
components in the induced web contains a
path of length at least three and
induced graph contains a cycle that
includes a non-equation edge whereas in
our bad events we induced a graph that
contains a circuit but the second
condition is different that we are
actually allowing
the
we are actually allowing the path of
length at least three but not beyond
four
okay so here we are actually align that
the path can be three
or more than 3 but it should not go
beyond 4.
moreover the induced graph contains a
cycle that includes a non-equation age
okay so to conclude this talk we have
shown the 3x4 bit security of ewcdm and
dwcm
ah
in fact the optimal security of these
two construction can be proven
if you use the general result of
patterns mirror theory
but again the
the correctness of the general uh
general result of media theory is not
established yet
uh proof of this optimal security of
dwcdm requires underlying hash to be
regular so for ewcd if you want to prove
the optimal security of ewcdm then the
hash function i mean the almost all
universal property of the other lane
hash function is sufficient but if you
want to prove the optimal sequence of
dwcm then you require this assumption
that the underlying hash function should
be ky's regular
and finally one can improve the security
amount of 1k dw serium from
from 2n by 3 base to 3 by 4 bits using
the similar technique that we have
employed in this paper
and
thank you for the thank you for
listening to this talk and if you have
any query you can directly send an email
to any one of us thank you