hi i'm going to talk about lmda uh low
memory databases authenticated
encryption with
wanted
security i'm using knighto and decision
to work with you sasaki and target
scholar this is the summary of our
results to obtain a low memory
deterministic authentication action with
one that is security we design a new tbc
based da mode lta
lndi has
two np state and achieves the
innovative data security when using an
end with tbc
due to the battery bound for internal
state size the set size is optimal
and lmda is designed to have no trick
schedule inverse
and so reducing hardware cost
mobile lmgae ensures low memory for
threshold implementation
or ti which is a side child attack
quantum measure
then we design a new tbc to be skinny
three skinny is a variant of skinny
where are three bit tweak space is added
in order to meet the lmd structure and
whisking is designed to minimize the
implementation cost of the key schedule
impulse
and combining lmda with twiskini we
obtain a low memory dae with 128 bit
security
finally we give a hardware
implementation of our dae
and so we compare our dae with state of
gbc based on north based authentic
actions php and pv birth
the memory sizes of these
schemes are the same as
rda but since the six key tweaky inverse
cost is small
the harder size of rda is fewer than the
those existing schemes
and for
threshold implementation the higher size
of our scheme is fewer than php
i'd like to first talk about the
background of our research
lightweight clock photography has been a
hot topic in cryptography for more than
a decade the motivation is to design
cryptographic algorithms that achieve
efficient performances and provide data
security for
resource constraint devices lightweight
includes a lot of meanings such as raw
memory power consumption latency and so
on
the
so the target of this stock is raw
memory memory size determine the overall
height cost in lightweight
implementation
so by reducing memory size the hardware
cost is radius
now nist is holding a lightweight
cryotherapy sensation process for
authenticated exhibition
the stabilization process the demand for
replacing aesthetic skins such as sgcm
and optionally considers
security against side channel attack
news selected 10 finalists which
includes different types of primitives
due to the divine design diversity many
candidates have more than
64-bit security for their size
authenticated encryption provide
confusion essentially on integrity of
data and many schemes are designed to
have nonce as well as key associated on
plaintext
nouns is an input to authenticated
function and
a non-repeated value in encryption
procedure
this property is
offers a scheme with us but beyond
possible security or with low memory and
use of nasty requirement of needs
standardization process
on the other hand there are several
issues or not implementation
for example north is repeated due to
tiny north space
north is fixed to some constant and so
on
in addition north requirements requires
extensive non-volatile memory so
cae solves the
these problems and
they provide confidentially integrity of
data without knowledge
and this talk focuses on design of raw
memory dna with 120 bit security and
additionally consider a side chain
attack quantum measure threshold
implementation or ti
tae takes key
data on plaintext
and in order to ensure the security in
this setting algorithm must ensure that
each bit of the input
must affect whole output
so dae skins
have the subtype structure which is two
parts and
marks the entry structure like this
figure
and several da schemes have been
proposed from these
primitives block cipher trigger block
cipher and publication
so in this slide i explain feature
primitive meets or goal around 28 bits
here raw memory on their ada
in order to achieve 130 bit security the
key size must be
130 bits and the step size must be at
least 256 bits
this size is from the busy attack on the
internal state
for block cipher in order to handle a
256 bit state the block size must be
at least 256 bits on the other hand
block ciphers have been designed to have
at almost
250 128 bits block
and in ti the normal stage size is
totaled while the linear state size is
doubled
since the block size is equal to the
nonlinear size
in ti the state size of block cipher is
large and so block cipher does not meet
our goal
publication
as the block cipher case we need 50 to
56 piece permutation that is no near
size is large
so publication does not meet our goal
the last primitive is or process thicker
block cipher is a extension of block
cipher
the angel input called tweak is
introduced which offers distinct
permutations by
thereby changing the tweak
as block cipher uh single block ciphers
have been designed to have at most
180 bits block but the tweak contributes
to
design bbb secure known north based aids
mobile
cbcs offer ti friendly modes such as
psv and tv plus because the block size
is small and tweak and key are processed
by linear operations
from these features we choose tbc as a
primitive or rda
to design a 130 bit secure on different
radio with 2560 states we need to design
dea mode that for the security level s
the memory size is three speeds and the
block size is
speeds
for existing dvd based daes none of the
is satisfies these
requirements
the first schemes
zae is highly efficient dae that is it
is paralyzable and
has efficient mark structure
but the vae requires a large memory size
and
the rim these two schemes are not space
schemes and achieve envy security in the
non-respecting setting but these schemes
fall into possible security in the dna
settings
where the nas is fixed
so
this skins
also require a large memory
so we design nbc security with 12-bit
state chrome and pro dbc
we first design define a state of this
function shown
here the function is designed to have
only linear operation except for
a thicker block cipher since we consider
lightweight schemes
and in this function firstly twins
state is updated by data blocks d1 and
d2
each block size is at most
n-bit
then
tvc is performed
and finally
the tbc
output and the remaining energy state is
mixed by this linear
function dr is a three bit domain
version so iterating the
this function
offers 12-bit state
schemes
for the speed of the scheme using this
function when the data block side is
through to end bit
the dae becomes fastest but
unfortunately if the
size is greater than and width there is
due to half of an attack
for example this is the one
instantiation of the state of this
function where each data block size is
uh n-bit
if the quotient of this
tbc output occur in this part due to
the difference of this data block
then
since we can set the same difference
to this data block
we can find a quotient
uh in this part
uh
by the two to half of n3 complexity
so the maximum state sub block size
of the state's update function is n-bit
so we design a dae using the state
update function with any data blocks
size
lmda follows the ship type design that
is it has a mac and then x structure
this is the mac part and this is the
english part
the mug part process is associated
a and pretext m
then using the tile
from the mac from this part the
encryption part generates the key stream
rt
to encrypt the plain text each part is
designed by just iterating the state
update function with end bit data block
in
mda the pump station
pi
is introduced in the lower part of each
state update function and we can choose
arbitrary permutation so choosing the
tweaks featuring the publication we
don't need to implement the inverse of
the tweak scheduling which reduces the
implementation cost
regarding security lmd achievement
security when using a amid block tbc the
security is the indistinguishability
between lmda and
ilde
in the real world adversary interacts
with
regression and the degradation of lnda
and in the higher world a busy interacts
with around a bit local and reject
oracle
the
random bit work return the
lambda bits random ciphertext and
list oracle returns the dx symbol
and
here i explain an indication of the
security proof due to the data structure
each tag is random as long as no state
coordinates
in the marked part
so in this case quarterly requires two
to
end integration queries and since the
internal state size of ldae is 12 bits
and the internal state
its part is applied appropriately
updated
so the complexity of the interactive
collision required to do n
query complexity
for each encryption query
this structure ensures that each tbc
input of this part can be seen as a
12-bit random value so no tbc input
collision occur up to 20k complexity
and so
each dbc output to
define a key stream rt campaign as
random party
therefore everyday is
indistinguishable from uh iglda after
today complexity that is the llca
achieved innovate security next i
explain the underlying cbc of rda the
underlying tbc of lmdae needs to support
a one 30-piece block one 20-bit key
rounded bit tweak
and additional 3-bit tweak for the
domain separation
skinny e18
256 almost meets the requirement of
lngae
however the tick space is
three bits short
the l6 tweak enabled to convert the
using tb6 to slightly and large the
tweak size
so
we determined to combine these two
approaches
however l6 tweak was designed to
minimize the number of computations by
increasing the
state size which is not suitable for
lmdae hence we modified the llc tweak to
be
hardware friendly
in the original l6 tweak a small tweak
of
ctr1 bits or is first expanded to theta
two bits
then the expanded tweak is injected to
three three bytes of the data state in
every theta four rounds
the tweak expansion require an
increase of the state
also the
sparse tweak injection requires
different operations depending on the
number around the mamba
in our design we don't
expand the small tweak
and in every run
lfsr is applied to the small tweak and
it is injected to the data state
we apply
exactly the same operation for every
round which contributes to lower memory
size
this page shows the round function of t
skinny 128 to 56 most of the run
functions are the same as skinny
with the red blind area
being the elastic twig
uh portions that handle the actual
sleeve tweak
without uh touching the three tweak or
the domain inspiration processed by
the elastic tweak the security of
trifini is the
same as that of skinny the optimal
locations to insert the tweaks was
chosen by evaluating the number of
active x-boxes in
milp for various choices
and also
in this table sufficient active xboxes
are guaranteed
so i explained higher performance of
rtae we made hardware performance
evaluation by implementing lmda with
twiskin
since there is no
comparable tbc based
vae we compare the performance
with non-space masking friendly schemes
using
skinny namely php with
the skinny np brush with skinny e
for
fair comparison we implement the
previous scheme with the same design
policy tools and standard cell rivalry
this figure is the
data path diagram of the lmda circuit
the design follows the passive
architecture command for lightweight
block cycle implementations
the data path is basically
a skinny implementation with a few
additional
gates needed for mdae since we said pi
are the skinny tweaky scheduling we can
eliminate the
circuit for the inverse operation which
was necessary for the conventional
scheme
we also implemented a protected
implementation with threshold
implementation in addition to the round
function that needs three shares we also
protect the tweaky
array storing secret
but we use only two shapes because the
tweaking schedule is linear
so this table summarizes the such area
of lmda and conventional schemes with on
result ti in another equivalent gate
count
this table also shows the total memory
size in bits because it has great impact
on such area
in the results without ti
showing this part lmda achieves a
smaller circuit area
although the mirror size is the same as
in all the schemes this advantage comes
from the tricky implementation we could
eliminate several 120 bits
factors needed for
inverting the tweaky schedule
with dr uh in this part
the non-space piv and
piv parts become advantageous in memory
size because they have a large public
memory that needs no such attack
protection
since
optimization is not available to
dae but everyday size is still
comparable to pip because of the fg
implementation
this is the conclusion my talk we
proposed low memory da with 150 bit
security on ti friendly we designed
tbc-based dae mode lndae
when using an n-bit block tbc lga has
8-bit security and 12-bit internal state
mdae does not require the inverse of
tweak
tweak scheduling of the underlying tbc
we then propose twiskini it is the
variant of skinny where favorite tweak
space is added
it is designed so that the cost of key
scheduling inverse is small
finally we gave a hardware
implementation of our da and compare rda
with the state of the earth cbt-based
unknown space authenticating action
php and pv plus the memory sizes of
these schemes are the same as
rda but
since the tweaky impulse cost is small
without ti the hardware size of rda is
fewer than
those existing schemes and with the eye
the harder size of our scheme is here
than plb
okay for thank you very much