hello everyone
i am
today i will speak uh
the on the paper
on length independence security bounds
for the pmac family
this paper has been co-authored with uh
vishuddhi chakraborty ocean
so
this is the list
what we have done in this paper
first of all we have identified in uh
flaw in nato's paper uh which he
submitted and which was accepted in 2ac
in 2019
and
he proposed a
construction of
a variant of pimac
and
we identified a flaw in the proof
security proof of the construction
and we also posed an equivalent
problem
ah which is to be solved in order to ah
solve the
claim
in the paper
ah secondly uh we
we have shown uh length independent
security bound for simplified p mac or
sp mac
with a weaker notion of
security for the hash function
and thirdly
we have
proposed a
variant of p mach 1
we name it as p mach 2 and we show that
it achieves a length free security
so
to begin with let us see
the comparison table the comparative
table
here we we can see that there is
something called pmac3 there is
something called np mac npmac is nothing
but
the
variant of p mac which we have just
mentioned
it is called npmac and pmf3 is the
new variant of pima which after we
pointed out the flaw in the npmec and i
though
proposed another construction called p 3
but if we
consider the number of masking keys
sorry if we consider the number of
masking keys we see that our
construction p mac 2
in this paper it is an improvement over
p mach 3
[Music]
or p mach 1 also because it achieves a
length free security bound as well as
the number of masking keys is minimal
here
so
this this is the table of comparison
now
uh
this is the pictorial view of the
simplified p mac or xp mac
here the message blocks are absorbed
with
the
tau in the tau output so tower outputs
are adjust the masking values
so
mi it message block is
stored with the height masking values
and it is fed in the
block cipher here uh
pi the permutation pi and after uh
we collect all the output
outputs of the
of these block ciphers we just sort them
and the last block is also solved here
and this is just
fade into the last block cipher pi prime
and we get
the tag output
so
pipe and pi prime are random
permutations here and
tau is the masking function
so uh
let us see what what are the popular p
mac variants
that we get from spmak first of all the
original p mac is
where the grey code based masking is
used
uh next p mac one where
the power of two
is used as masking and in case of npmec
or the pima construction
that's knighto proposed here
something called two powering up masking
is used as the mask
masking function
so precisely mathematically this is the
expression of the masking values the tau
y is just
2 to the power i times
pi of 0
and this is the masking for p mach 1 and
for n p mac this is the 2 powering up
masking
and why we see
the reason behind the name this is 1
power of 2 and this is another power of
and this
2 powers are
first multiplied with l 1 and l to 2
fixed values and then they are solved to
get the
masking
value final masking value
so
let us
come to the analysis of npmec
here the
most important claim that naito has used
in the paper is this claim
he
claims that uh these
this system of equations
uh are
this
or the these two equations are
linearly independent given ah
this a comma b this set is not equal to
c comma d this set what is uh alpha beta
gamma delta alpha is just 2 to the power
a beta is 2 to the power b
gamma is 2 to the power c n
delta s 2 to the power d
so if we consider these two equations
the these are indeed linearly
independent as
neither claims but
we show that this claim is wrong by
this slide explains it
the condition of linear dependence it is
equivalent to
this condition as stated in the green
box
but according to naito uh he
says that this is
the
fact stated in the red box this is the
equivalent condition of linear
dependence
but this is not true
okay for
it is true if
only
c2 is equal to c1 what is c2 let us just
see this is c1 and this is c2
okay so if c2 is equal to c on this
knight then knighto's claim is okay
otherwise it is wrong
so
uh now
we see that
uh from the green box we get
this
equation also
so
let us just see
one more time this green box
from here we can
arrive
from the condition of linear dependence
uh we can arrive at this equation
so
we
show a counter example here
for the gallery field of
order 16
we first define the multiplication by
this
polynomial
and
if we take
a b c d as these values
we see that this satisfies
this equation that that means
uh
these two
equations generated by abcd
are
linearly dependent
but
if we calculate the c2 value and the c1
value we see that c2 is not equal to c1
so
this
this is this does not happen
a equal to b old is equal to d we can
see just directly from here that u is
not equal to b or b is not equal to c
okay so uh
this is the counter example to the claim
in the paper
in nato's paper
for of npmac uh as we name it in pmac
so
now
uh what is the equivalent problem that
we
pose here we pose that
to
uh
solve the difficulty or
uh what do we
need to solve in order to fix the error
in the proof
we have to bound this uh
abcd number of abcds such that this
happens
just recall that alpha is nothing but 2
to the power a beta is not nothing but
two to got b gamma is nothing but 2 plus
c
and delta is nothing but 2 to the power
d
so
we have to bound the number of abcd such
that this happens
and this is the
crux
problem of the
paper uh if we want to show the security
uh
by the bound security
of the construction this is the cracks
problem this is the equivalent form of
the
cracks problem
uh
so
now let uh let us come to sp mac
here we define a concept of two eyes
almost or universal
hash function
how is it defined uh
first we define uh
an event
called a is just this this event and
then we
define another event b
this this row is just used for uh
defining the events and this is the
actual definition of 2 y is x u
so what it means it means that
probability of a the probability is
considered
for
probability is calculated
for the number of keys over the
key
over k
so probability of a
uh
is less than equal to epsilon and
probability of a and b is less than
equal to epsilon square
so is this b is this probability of a is
less than equal to epsilon the
probability of a and b this joint event
is less than equal to epsilon square
priority is considered over
k
so
this is uh if
the hash function satisfies this
equation then the hash is called
epsilon two wise axu
hash
so
this is an interesting observation about
the
security notion we have just defined
ah we see that uh first of all this is a
weaker definition
than
uh the four wise
independence of hash independent hash
function
as
gassy
it will defined in their paper
we easily
see that uh any forward-wise independent
hash function is epsilon 2 x u where
epsilon is 1 over 2 to the power n
so the this notion
of two y's a x u is weaker than 4y is
independent
but next we
show that the converse is not true that
means that there is some function for
example
this tau y
where
3 power of twos
uh three powers of two are used and this
is actually called called three powering
up mask and it is used
in pimac two paper by nine night though
so for this masking function this is uh
two wise uh axu but not photo as
independent so the concept of two wise
axu is strictly weaker than four is
independent
so
uh
what it means we'll see later we
we
in the end we'll show what what it means
actually that we
we gain
we just we there there was previously a
result for four wise independence
independent hash function that s p mac
achieves uh
length free birthday bound security here
we show that for two ways x you also
that is for a strictly weaker
version or weaker notion of
than the
forward independent hash function we get
the similar bound so this is an
improvement uh
over the result
so
the what is the
here is a schema
a brief schema of the proof for sp mac
first of all we define an input
collision graph
for
any two messages m and m prime
uh
and after defining the set of vertices
the set of vertices is just
the
m comma 1
to m comma l m
and
together with the
m
elements m m prime comma 1
to m prime comma l m prime
and the age
are from a
age is formed between m comma a and m
prime comma a prime if this happens that
if the
ah
block cipher input in this position if
the block cipher input collides then an
edge is found between these two
uh
vertices
so this is the definition
of the age and the vertices of the graph
and after that we define
uh cross cancelling masking
when the induced graph is evenly
partitioned it is called
the masking
for which it happens it calls it is
called the cross canceling masking
ah
evenly partitioned bin means uh the the
components if you consider the
components the every component
has size even size
so
then we call that
the graph is evenly partitioned
ok after that we define a covering
collection of edges and it is defined
for
evenly partitioned graphs
and the main
lemma that we prove here
is
actually gives a relation between the
cross counseling
masking and the covering edges
actually it
bounds
the
cross cancellation probability
by the
probability of forming covering edges
and we show that the final you show that
the advantage is this
and this is uh l free bound if we
just
look a bit deeper and calculate uh
a bit you see that this is a this is an
l free bound
security amount okay
so
now for p mac 2 this is the pictorial
view of p mach 2
uh first we
get l l is just a pi output of 0 and
l is used as a
this in the masking
and alpha
this alpha value a alpha is just a
primitive element
of the field alpha is ah
multiplied here
in these places in the construction and
we after
getting all these
all these
things done we get the
tag output
t
so
we see that p 2 is actually less than
prp
why because
this part can be seen as an
as a hash
part and this is a
prp so
the aim is
fed in the hash part and then the output
of hash part is fed
uh in the prp and we get
the final tag or the t
so
p make two the problem
is
becomes simpler because p mach 2 here
can be
dealt with
in the hash then prp paradigm
so the proof idea of p mac2
if we look at the proof idea first we
define a generalization of the cross
canceling
cancellation probability for more than
two messages the generation is defined
as theta prime
and
for
similarly for
probability of collision
for more than two
hash outputs it defined as the call
function
call of m one to mq
and here we see the most important
result
here the call
value is less than equal to theta prime
value plus something
ah
where and also the advantage from the
hashtag prp result we can
state that the advantage uh of the pmac
2 is less than equal to call plus
something so here the advantage
the
together if we consider these two in
equation inequalities together we can
see that advantage is dependent
only on the theta prime so the main task
is to bound the theta prime part okay
so um
here
okay so finally we get the collision
probability is less than equal to q
square plus sigma by 2 over n
by 2 to the power n
plus mu where
mu is something which depends on the
range of l
we see here that mu is q
over
2 to the power n by 2 if l is less than
equal to 2 to the power n by 4 and mu is
sigma to the power 1.5 by
2 to the power n if
uh l is greater than 2 to the power
n by 4 and less than equal to 2 to the
power n minus 2
and if we simplify this we
see that the main gist
uh
of this
inequality is that we get a length free
bound for
l get less than equal to the power n by
4 and we also get a
then free bound for
l greater than 2 to the power n by 4 and
less than 2 to the power n minus 2
when sigma is less than 2 to the power
two n by three
so
with this extra condition we
uh
uh maintain we retain the length
freeness of the security bound for more
than
in two different by four
length of messages
so this is the final result for pmac2
so
this is a summary or conclusion
of
all the results that we have
uh done in the paper
first of all we have
shown that the proof is wrong
in nato's paper but we don't know
whether there exists any proof or not so
it's an open problem still now
to prove or disprove the security bound
as claimed in nato's paper in tosc 2019
and secondly
for sp mac uh it had a
length free but the bound security for
four wise independent hash function
but in this paper we show
a similar result for a weaker notion of
security
for hash function this is called epsilon
2x u hash function
so
this is an improvement
in terms of the
security bound
the security notion
of the hash function and
lastly
we propose a
variant of p mac 1
we name it as p mach 2 and we show that
it achieves the length free security
bound
whenever l is less than equal to two
super the l is the length of the
higher
highest length of the message
messages
whenever the highest length of the
messages is less than equal to the power
n by four
so
uh these are all that we have done in
the paper
uh and thank we thank everyone for
listening and watching the
presentation
thank you very much