hello i'm amit kumar johan
i am presenting our work
quantum's restart collision attacks on
double block line testing with ground
reduced aes256
this is a joint work with i will say
kumar and sumitra
has functions are an important and
ubiquitous cryptography building blocks
that are used in designing message
authentication code signature schemes
etc
in post quantum era many public key
schemes that huge hash functions are
proven to be secure in the quantum
random oracle model
recently few works have also been
studied
have also studied the dedicated attack
on the block cipher based hash functions
such as workful grosstal in various
quantum attack settings
further double clock length has
immediate value stimulus method for
constructing your compression function
with a two n bit output from and
bit block cipher for example tandem dm
microsdm hero function etc in this work
we study dedicated quantum coordinates
on hero series comparison function
there was a design a detailed
compression function f that makes two
calls to an and with block cipher e that
produces the output as follows f on
input s0
comma x1 comma m
outputs d0 comma v1
using the function f0 and m1 where the
functions f0 and f1 are defined as
f0 on input at zero comma h one comma m
a equal to e
of s zero zero with h zero where h one
concatenation m one is the key
input to the block cipher
similarly we define defined f1
how to find collision on scf
so just uh recall the fact from the
channeled paper uh canada paper in 2014
suppose that a collision for zero is
caused by the player at zero from h one
comma m and h zero zero delta x zero
comma x one comma m
further assume that delta x zero equal
to c then a collision for f one is also
caused by the same pair
so using the same fact the goal of
finding collision forces of reduces to
finding collision on zero
for which we can proceed as follows so
first find a colliding pair of inputs
secondly output the pair
only if delta is zero equal to c
otherwise return to step one and repeat
the process
so what are the generate methods to find
collisions so for a concrete hash
function h the generic collision time
attack complexity is big of 2 to the
power n by two
using birthday bound
a dedicated collision attack is valid
only if t less than two to the power n
by two
the dedicated method to find collisions
generally uh consider differential
cryptanalysis
uh to find collisions for example md5
whirlpool has hirosa etc the idea behind
is to build a differential trail such
that non-zero input different delta in
can propagate to zero output
differentiate out with a high
probability
typically differential trails for hash
function consists of two parts control
part and uncontrolled part control part
in which complex trail is
efficiently satisfied by using degrees
of freedom secondly uncontrolled part
where fail is satisfied
probabilistically
usually controlled part is satisfied
with negligible cost so the attack
complexity is mainly dominated by the
trail probability p of the uncontrolled
part
so the attack is valid if and only if t
is equal to one by p which
is greater than 2 to the power minus n
by 2.
next we discuss the quantum script
analysis and quantum settings so there
are two kind of quantum attack models
one is cuban model other another is q2
model in q1 model adversary is allowed
to make classical queries plus
he has also given the power of quantum
computer in q2 model adversary is
allowed to make quantum queries plus
he has also given the power of quantum
computers in general q1 model is more
practical than q2 model because for
block cipher it is hard to make quantum
superposition queries to the online
encryption oracle while for the hash
function we can make quantum
superposition queries to the hash
functions offline
so how to define quantum superposition
queries so let f be a boolean function
so the superposition or equal of f is
the unity transformation you have that x
on n plus one cubic system which sends a
standard basis vector x y to x y over or
fx
as a linear operator ufx on the
superposition states as
uf on the summation of o
or over all the x ax vector x vector 0
equal to the sum
over all the n's ax x vector x and
vector f x
so we can efficiently implement uf in
the quantum circuit model as long as
there exists an efficient classical
circuit
that could do itself
quantum random access memories qram
can also be seen as the
quantum analog of the classical ram
given a list of classical data l with
vectors x i of length m
the q rank for l can be modeled eigen
unity transformation such that
uh
q ram on input address resistor
and the output register y
maps to
input register
address resistor i
and
output register by your xl
similarly on the quantum superposition
exercise we can define the
action of infinity transformation uqrm
however there are some problems of qrm
it is unknown however king qram can be
built
or at least in case of large urms
secondly a qram of size om can be
simulated with the quantum circuit of
size big of n that is
size of qram equivalent to the number of
keyboards in the circuit so attacks with
a small column or even without theorem
are actually more practical
next we discuss governs algorithm which
we use extensively in our work so given
a search space of 2 to the power an
element and a boolean function f the
goal is to find x such that f of x
in the classical setting we need about 2
to the power and steps but in the
quantum setting
grover's algorithm needs about square
root of 2 to the power n grover
iterations
so one can find such an x using gravers
algorithm in square root of one by p
time with quantum computers classically
one can find such an x and one by b
times so therefore we can have a
quadratic speed of
four differential capital capitalists
in the quantum setting
in the quantum setting the transistor is
attack is valid if and only if t equal
to square root of one by p
uh in case of genetic methods for
example bst the time and query
complexity is 2 to the power n by 3 but
the number of qubits required is very
very large
2 to the power n by 3
in this setting attack is valid if p is
greater than 2 to the power minus 2 n by
now we discuss our results so we apply a
quantum version of the ground attack to
find collisions on hero size compression
function when the underlying block
cipher is instantiated with aes256
our rebound attack covers standard of
scf aes 256 in the quantum attack
setting
our dedicated quantum collision attack
are actually faster than generate
quantum collision attacks
even when small theorem or no theorem
is available
our attacks are also valid in the
setting of time space tradeoffs we also
propose a mil pbs method to
systematically explore different trails
for rebound attacks with multiple
inbound features
rebound attack is based on defensive
grip analysis
it
divides the cipher into three parts
outbound phase one inbound and outbound
when r1 phase two in in one phase
we perform a match in the middle to
generate the starting points in the
output phase from the starting point we
compute forward and vibrate directions
uh but in the outbound phases
we also remark that if the probability
of the outbound phase is p one has to
get at least one by p starting points in
the inbound k
with p greater than two to the power
minus n by two
the assumption here is that that delta x
input different delta x in the inbound
phase
propagates to delta zero with
probability p one
and output different delta y and line
one phase propagates to delta zero with
probability p two the delta 0 is matches
with probability p0 so therefore
the differential quality of the trail
becomes p1 into p2 into p0
we can use this
idea of rebound attack to find
collisions so we fixed uh delta x and
delta y
then where delta x
propagates to delta 0 with probability v
1 and delta y propagates to delta 0 with
probability v 2
we then compute
uh
x and x dash from delta x
and y and y dash from del from delta y
that satisfy this inbound differential
and then we compute m from x
c formed by f m dash from s dash and c
dash from y
and finally check if and your m dash
equal to c 0 c dash in the output phase
classically we need to try
uh
about
one by p of times
uh to have a match
but in in quantum sorting we need to try
one over square root of p outputs
so here is this uh 10 now differential
trail for area 256
so
here this round three round four
we have in one phase one in round six
and seven we have in one phase two
in round five we connect these two
inbound phases
and from uh
this delta six seven
we move to round ten
uh big probability two to the power
minus 16 from z 3 delta g 3 we move to
round 1 with probability 2 to the power
minus 16
and we also have the probability of 8
white cancellation in x and w 2
which is 2 to the power minus 64 so
overall
probability of the differential trail
is 2 to the power minus 96
we then use this trail to mount rebound
attack or scalp 256 that returns a pair
of collating inputs h 0 comma x 1 comma
m and f 0 delta 0 comma h 1 comma m
we also need a condition delta h 0 equal
to c
to
have a complete attack on cf
where we consider c has eight non-zero
bytes at some particular positions and
this can be achieved with probability
two to the power minus 64. therefore the
overall complexity of the attack is two
to the power
now we give
the quantum collision attack
using rebound procedure
in our attack the rebound attack
has multiple inbound phases
so for the first inbound differential uh
delta in one delta out one with the
input output difference
for the second and more differences the
input output difference sphere is
denoted by delta into comma delta 2
we then define a boolean function for
the full inbound differential f
for full
inbound differential edge
f
such that f 32 cross f 248 grows up to
48 cross up to 32 to f in a base such
that f outputs one if and only if the
starting points computed from the
uh
the input output difference and in the
inbound phase full press the backward
and forward output differences
we can produce
such that scf collides where h0 and h0 s
are obtained from the starting point and
h1 comma m is obtained from the keys
derived from connecting rounds
uh in inbound phases one and two
by applying reverse algorithm with the
quantum oracle uf for f we can find a
collision with
approximately pi by 4 into square root
of 2 to the power 160 queries
to estimate the overall complexity of
the attack
we need to
find the exact complexity incurred by
the implementation of uf
so how to implement the quantum oracle
uf we
uh define a function d i that computes
the actual input output data we are
respecting the differentials of each
xbox s by accessing the pre-computed dtt
that is stored in qram
so here in the algorithm in the
implementation of uf the input is
this delta n1 delta into delta over 1
delta 2
comma vector y and output is basically y
is updated
with your f
on input output differences so we
perform uh then one phase one for i
equal to 0 to 15 in
the differential delta x x 3 delta w 4
and compute the corresponding
differential then we run d i
uh
which gives
the output as for i comma x four i just
delta x four i
similarly in the
in one phase two we con
get the output x7 i comma x7i delta x7i
we then compute delta x 5 from delta w 4
and delta by 6 from delta z 6.
we connect these in one phases 1 and 2
in round 5
so
we run d i 4 each delta x 5 to select
the corresponding difference of delta y
5 we compute delta x 6 from delta y 5
then for
j belonging to the positions 8 9 and 15
we run dj on input delta x6 j comma
delta by 60 if delta x6 and delta y6 are
compatible then we return the x6i comma
x6y0 delta x i as the output
and further the output
x 5 i comma x 5 i delta x 5 i
corresponding
output
we then compute the bytes of
the x 5
we also compute the bytes of k4 from
the corresponding bytes of w4 and x5
following the other details of the
algorithm we finally compute the round
keys k0 k1 and so on k10
we now create
starting points drive from the input
output differences
first we set x 4 as x 4 0 to x 4 15 x 4
dash
as export 0 0 delta x 4 0 2 x 4 15 0
delta x 4 15 similarly we set x7 and x7
dash
now if x4 and x4 has fulfills the
backward output differential then we
start one bit flag as one otherwise zero
if x7 and x7 does full press the forward
orbital differential then we set one bit
flag flap to h1 otherwise we set flag to
zero
if both flag points
then
we update the output resistor as y zero
one otherwise
y remains invariant
for the complexity analysis of the
attack first
the complexity of the computation of
paranormal es is approximated by 200 as
well computation secondly the complexity
of one asset to the qram that restores
the table of input output differential
is equivalent to one as well as
computation one absolute x evaluation
further required two to the power minus
six point six four down down a year 256
computations
oh overall by counting the xbox
evaluations
the complexity of uf is two to the power
five point four six ten down the years
for two previous computations
since
the complexity of finding the collision
is
approximately to the power 85 5.11 10
down areas
competitions
in summary
uh
we have uh we consider two attack models
one is view first we have two attack
settings with qram and two second where
you attack setting without qram so we
just discussed the 10 round attack in
queue for setting where the time
complexity will be 85.1
and the the current size it will become
16 which is required to store the
deleted level
uh in the q2 setting we do not use any
qram
rather we access ddt using grover's
algorithm
so the the complicity time complexity of
that is is increased little bit
and it becomes 86.11
and in the tsto setting if we have a
quantum computer of size available as
available then we can have
uh the tag with time completed by eight
point six one over square root of s by
two to the power four
if we apply the
the cns algorithm
uh uh generally
on all the elements then the complexity
to the power one zero two point four
uh in conclusion uh the the classical
security of primitives does not imply
quantum security it also implies that
different settles with the low
probability in the classical setting can
still be meaningful for quantum
computers we improved collision attacks
for scfas 256 to 10 rounds
in the quantum setting
while uh in in the classical setting
there are just a nine and
the attack on
up to nine rounds
uh as a future work finding more useful
differentiators with low probabilities
in various other kind of attack
techniques can be an interesting problem
to investigate in the quantum setting
thank you for your attention