welcome to my presentation on the
tightness of the suffix kit spongebob
this is a joint work with chris of the
brownie
and one of the most efficient ways of
building an a mac function or a prf is
using the full state keyed sponge the
idea is that you take a sponge function
and the sponge function uses a b bit
permutation
and
you can absorb data with b bits at a
time the idea is that you initialize the
state with a k bit key
and filled with zeros then you permute
the state using this permutation and
then you can absorb plain text b bits at
a time so you absorb the first plaintext
block you permute you absorb the second
plain text block you permute etc then to
the last plain text block then you make
one more permutation call and you output
the tag
so this is a very efficient prf or mac
design
and it has received quite some research
quite some analysis has been done on
this function and it is very efficient
because you compress with b bits at a
time where b is the size of the
permutation
on the downside this function in general
does not offer mode level protection
against side channel attacks
this construction is not leakage
resilient as we would say
um
as a matter of fact the attacker can be
quite powerful because if you have the
key and filled with zero super mute you
permute you get a secret statement the
attacker has full freedom to add values
to the secret state namely the block b1
can be chosen by the attacker and the
attacker has full freedom to manipulate
the state and this way it can enable
enable dpa differential power analysis
um
one way to solve this
is to somehow limit the power that the
attacker has over evaluating secret
states in this case a secret state here
can potentially be evaluated up to two
to the b
times
for two to be different messages if we
limit this a typical approach to do is
using the gtm like construction
here we start with a key and then we
have some
initial value or a noise and we look at
this nonce bit wise if the first bit is
a zero you evaluate the block cipher a
block cipher on the key and zero if the
first bit is one you evaluate the block
circle on the
key and
an encoding of one and you go on like
this so then you look at the second bit
third bits up to the last bit
and suppose the last bit appears here so
it's a one then you evaluate the last
box i have a column input of the key and
a one and this gives you something you
can do a key stream with or
attack
so far so good but
can we do this with a permutation and
one way to do this with the permutation
is by using an approach that was
described by taha and shomo
in general the idea also appears in the
isab authenticated encryption scheme
the idea is as before we have a b bit
permutation b
we initialize the state with the key bit
key k bit key
and filled with the zeros then you
permute and then you absorb a nonce but
this nonce is not absorbed all at once
but you also absorb it bit by bit
so if you absorb the first bit you
permute second bit permute up to the
last bit you permute
and if the nonce is always unique very
likely the state after absorbing the
nodes is different for different
nonsense and this means that at this
point you can absorb with a higher rate
here we do it arbits at a time
but you can absorb with a higher rate
starting from this point
and the trick here is basically that in
the first part the power of the attacker
to evaluate states secret states
multiple times is limited because it can
only absorb one bit at a time
and here we typically don't have
a state that repeats a lot
and as a matter of fact the leakage
resilience of this scheme follows from
the leakage resilience of the duplex
that christopher and i proved three
years ago
and but on the downside the sidechain of
resistance actually relies on the
uniqueness of the nouns if the nouns can
be repeated
then you could have repeated states here
and the attacker again has its power
back
okay one alternative way of doing this
is the hashtag prf construction or more
general it's called hash than mac but if
you take a hash function here the idea
is very simple so the plain text is of
arbitrary size it can be hashed to get a
digest of 2k bits
and then you evaluate the function g
that should be leakage resilient on
input of the secret key and this 2k bit
state to get a tag t
and why do we need 2k here because we
aim for k bit security
and a hash function allows for
collisions so if you the attacker now
makes
2 to the power k evaluations it likely
finds a condition here but if you take
only a cable state here it only needs to
make two to the k over two evaluations
to find the collision
so now
leak is resilient wise or side channel
protection wise this is quite nice
because the first part is not keyed the
only part that needs to protect it is
the function g on input of a 2k bit
input a k bit key and output of a tip
attack
okay um only the last part needs to be
protected and if we map this idea to the
sponge we end up with what we call
suffix keyed sponge or sucks
uh sucks was proposed um in general in
the context of leakage resilience by the
brownie keto for isap v1
and the idea is that the plain text is
first hashed using a sponge
so just a plain sponge to process the
plain text
this gives you a state u at the end and
only the outer k bits are then
transformed using a leakage resilient
prof g
on input of a k but key the k outermost
bits are transformed to get a k
bit replacement basically for the outer
part
the nrb minus k bits they continue and
due to this you don't need to have a 2k
bit input to the function g but only a k
bit input you make one more permutation
call again and then you get the tag
and three years ago we proved that sucks
is leakage resilient under the
assumption that g
and the last evaluation of b do not leak
too much information about the secret
data
um
now in this work we focus not
necessarily on leakage facilities but
really on black box security and in
black box security g can be a very
simple function it can even be the xor
but it could be a more evolved function
as well
so what's actually the security of sucks
and if we take a simple case where g is
an xor and where k
is a smaller than r then this is a
well-known construction but tony had
already described it a long time ago
and this construction the security of
this construction follows from the
indifferentiability of the sponge hash
function meaning that if
if the permutation is strong enough and
the mode is indifferentiable from a
random oracle then we can use this
result to prove that this function sucks
as a prf
however this result does not work if g
is a prf itself or if the key k
is larger than r
and in this case um
two years ago
three years ago we proved that sucks is
a secure prf in detail we proved the
following bound
um
it will appear a couple of times later
on in this presentation as well it
consists of three terms this one
basically corresponds to
a problem if the attacker finds an inner
collision in the hashing part because n
is the number of permutation evaluations
that the sp that the attacker can make
and after the birth they pound
in approximately two to the c over two
evaluations it could find an inner
collision on the hash part and if the
attacker finds an inner collision on the
hash part
we're doomed because the attacker can
find a full collision for the value you
and hands create a forgery
the second part roughly corresponds to
problems where the attacker guesses the
outer part of v and the last term of the
boundary roughly corresponds to the a
problem if the attacker guesses the
inner part of w
and this result holds under the
assumption that g is 2 to the minus
delta uniform
meaning that for any input
the probability that it goes to a fixed
output for a given for a random key is
at the most 2 to the minus delta and g
sub b at most due
should be 2 to the minus epsilon
universal
meaning that for any two inputs to g the
probability that they collide taken over
the randomness of the key is at most 2
to the minus epsilon
and this mu term is a bit of a um scary
term maybe but it roughly corresponds to
um the probability that the largest the
most likely largest multi-collision
so mu b minus k k or in general mu b
minus c c
is the smallest natural number x
such that the probability that you have
a multi collision of size more than x
is at most x over 2 to the c
and here the attacker makes q random
drawing so the probability that after q
drawings you have a multiplication of
size larger than x is at most x over 2
to the c
and here the idea of the denominator to
the denominator 2 to the c or in this
case
in the power 2 to the k
is that this
loss is negligible compared to the term
where the multicollision is used
okay it's a scary term but in practice
it's not that big so if you look at
oscon like parameters so in ascon we
have a permutation of size b 320 bits
we have a capacity of 256 at a rate of
64. we take a key and attack of 128 in
this case we can take the xor sg
so the key is just absorb by
accelerating into the outer part
it's 2 to the minus k uniform and zero
universal and we get a bound of this
form so two n squared divided by two to
the 256
plus five n divided by two to the one
twenty eight plus sixty seven n divided
by two to the one nine ninety two
if you take a prf as g and a prf is 2 to
the minus k uniform and to the minus k
universal we get a comparable bound
and we see that this multi collision
term is 5 here and 67 there where i
would like to note that the first two
terms in the bound are typically
dominant also in this example the third
term gets a bigger term mu
but it has a huge denominator so this
term is not dominant in the bound
now the question is
how good is this pound how good is the
pound that we derived three years ago
can we find the tax in both cases can we
fight attacks that match these bounds
or can we maybe improve the bound of
three years ago and in this work
we investigate this problem and in
detail we find
attacks matching the bounds
so in this work we look at the tightness
of this bound
first for the first term it's not
surprising that this term is here it
corresponds to inner collisions in the
hash part and if the attacker finds an
inner collision
which it can find with 2 to the c over 2
evaluations then it can form a full
collision
after hashing and it can use if to break
the scheme
so that term is not surprising
now the second and third term are maybe
more confusing due to these
multicollisions and in this work we
investigate the tightness of these terms
by mounting attacks
first we look at the case where we take
the xor sg and we derive two attacks
one is a multi-collision attack that
matches the third term
and one is a multicollision attack that
matches the second term
now we look at a general case where we
have a b reference g
and we mount a multi-collision-based
attack that matches the second term
and noting that the third term is kind
of independent of the function g it
doesn't use
a g
okay let's start with the first attack
so we take the xor sg so this is the
picture that we've seen before this is
the bound that we've seen before with
the difference that the last part is
highlighted
and now g is an xor so you simply xor
the key into the state
and the attack goes as follows so first
we make q
construction queries for different plain
text
and this results in different tags ti
and it results in different
states after hashing ui so we have queue
construction queries for different
messages this likely gives different uis
and it gives tax ti
now among these queries we try to find
the multi-collision in the tags let's
call it t
[Music]
so we have mu evaluations mu messages
that led to the same t
but with a different inner part of w
now what we're going to do is we're
going to make inverse queries to the
permutation for guessing the outer part
the inner part of w
so we make inverse queries to p on input
of the tag
and we vary the inner part of w we call
it zj here and at some point we will get
a match at some point we will get an
answer of this which is of the form
y which is the outer part of v and
right b minus k u i so at some point we
get a hit
between the inverse here
and the inner part of u
because the inner part stays unchanged
here and once we have this hit
what we learned now
is we learned the outer part of v for
this message for this plain text that
was
fed through the sucks construction
so we find a match this means that we
found we recovered the outer k bits of v
we already know the outer k bits of u
and then we can do the xor and we get
the key
and once you get the key the scheme is
of course broken
roughly the idea here is that the
multi-collision in the tag gives a speed
up of the factor mu
inserting the right most
b minus t bits of w and once you find
the rightmost b minus t base of w
you recovered the
leftmost k bits of v and from this you
can recover the key
because you also know the leftmost k
bits of u
the attack is not very efficient but it
does match the term in the bound so if
you take a an example with b5256 k128
the attack has a complexity close to
generic so it's a huge online and
offline complexity
but what i said and usually b is much
more than 2k anyway so this term is
never dominating in the bound
now the second attack a multi-collision
on the right most b minus k bits of u
and this is a more interesting attack
because in this case we make offline
evaluations of the permutation for
different plaintexts so we vary the
plain text here
to get a mu fold collision in the right
most b minus k bits of u so in this part
we get a mu fold collision we call it u
star
they all have a different in our outer
part left most k bits here so we get mu
different plain text that result in the
same inner part here but a different
auto part here
what we're going to do now is we're
going to make in a forward query to the
permutation here for this value u star
but for varying z j
and
we make these evaluations but we also
made the construction queries for this
mu fold collision so we can see if we
find a match in the tag
so we found the value u star we know the
mu value is t
and then we're going to vary the left
most k bits of v we permute and
hopefully we get a colliding tag and in
this case we very likely found
the outer part of v
the other part now the outer part of v
and once we found this it's the same as
before so we recovered the outer part of
v we already know the outer part of u so
you can add them and you get the key
so also here the idea is that the mu
fold collision on the right most b minus
k bits of u
gives a speed up
of mu and searching the leftmost bits
of v
and once the leftmost k bits of v and
once you have this you can recover the
key
now if you take a typical example of say
25272 or maybe b is 320 bits
with an aim of 128 bit security we get a
complexity an online complexity of
roughly six or two and an offline
complexity still close to generic
so it really matches the term the
corresponding term in the bound
16 and over 2 1 28 or 5 and over 2 120 a
so of course there is a very small loss
but
um
that's due to a bound in the multi
multi-collision
so far so good these attacks work if the
g is an xor the idea is that you make
evaluations that give you the outer part
of you
and then you do the multi-collision
attack to find the outer part of v and
because g is an x or you can add them
and you get the key
now if g is a prf the attacks don't work
anymore the reason is that if g is a
pure f or in general if g is hard to
infer
invert even if you have u and v
you cannot recover the key not
necessarily recover the key
still it turns out that these multi
collisions they can be used to mount a
forgery against sucks
and the idea is as follows and the idea
is slightly more complex
so the first step is as before we try to
find a multi-collision on the inner b
minus k bits of u so you find to try to
find mu evaluations mu plain text b
and we make offline evaluation so just
permutation calls
of these plaintexts let's find a
multi-collision a mu fault collision on
the
right most b minus k bits of u
for each of these mu plaintext
independently we try to find the
collision on the outer k bits the
leftmost k bits of u possibly with a
different
inner part
okay so we have a new collision on the
inner part and for each of these plain
text in this mu collision we try to find
a separate collision on the outer part
we're going to use that collision later
on
now for this new construction queries of
the multicollision we compute the
corresponding text
so we compute the corresponding text we
know that these are mu different tags
very likely
but we know that they all had the same
inner part here the same right most b
minus k bits
what we're going to do now is we're
going to recover
the leftmost k bits of v so we're going
to vary
leftmost k bits of v we call it c j here
we evaluate the permutation until we get
a match against t
and in this case we found for one of the
plain texts in this mu fault collision
we recovered the leftmost part of v
um but the cool thing now is that we go
back to the individual collision that we
found in step two so for this
plaintext we recovered
the leftmost k bits of v but we also
know a different plain text that happens
to have an identical
left most part of u
and because g is hard to invert we
cannot recover the key but still we know
that for this colliding message it has
the same left part hence it will have
the same right part left part of it has
the same left part of u
hence it will have the same left part of
v
and and the right part well we can
compute it because we can make this
evaluation offline and hence we already
know what tag this plain text will give
so we mount a forgery
so the trick is that we have a
multi-collision
using this multi equation we cover the
value v for one of them
and for this one we will find a normal
collision on the outer part of you and
hence we can find a forgery
this is in general the collision
structure that we have so on the left
part of the slide you see the multi
collision so we have mu evaluations p1
p2 up to pmu that all collide on the
right most b minus k bits it says b
minus s but in general it's b minus k
now for each of these plaintexts we find
a separate collision on the leftmost
bits
okay and in general if you look at the
attack and it turns out that i'm gonna
go over it quickly we get the same
numbers as the attack that we had for
the xor of g
and this
corresponds to the fact that we
defining the separate collisions don't
add too much work
to conclude we proved tightness of the
attacks it turns out that the attack
complexity is similar if g is an x or if
g is a prf
the multi collisions
that we saw in the security bound that
we found in our security proof there are
no artifacts of the proof they actually
have a meaning because there are attacks
that match these multi-creation terms in
the paper we elaborate
in more detail about in into the attack
complexity so we actually compute a
success probability of the attack
um there is still a very small loss in
the bound due to the bounding of
multicollisions in general and this is
only a very small constant loss but
still to be interesting to see how we
can improve this
this concludes my presentation
thank you
for watching
you