thank you very much for inviting me it's
the first time I've been to an icann
event since forming it I figured that by
now it was safe and I wouldn't have too
many things thrown at me but i'm not
sure i'm here today to talk about
ancient times when dinosaurs ruled the
earth it was a time before facebook
before Twitter before Wi-Fi and even
before google it was a time when you
could download a movie through your 56k
dial-up connection if you had a few days
when your large heavy cell phone did not
speak internet and when two-thirds of
the people in the world could not make a
telephone call because they didn't have
a landline coming to where they live it
was a time when there were more people
on the mini tell in France than on the
internet in the whole world okay and
when all the people on the internet in
Korea could fit into one small hotel
room I know because I met with them and
they're only a couple it was also a time
when adults still knew more about
information technology than their 10
year old children which has not been the
case since then so these ancient times
that i'm talking about warrant millions
or thousands or hundreds of years ago
there were 15 years ago in 1996 15 years
ago in early nineteen ninety-five then
President Clinton had asked me to head a
cabinet-level group in the US government
to help decide what steps he could take
if he were reelected in 1996 to improve
the US economy and our initial meeting
we listed ten different things to look
at that we thought could be important by
the beginning of 1996 we had actually
decided on a different list basically
what we had decided was that there were
three technologies that had been
developed recently that could offer the
potential for huge economic growth the
internet the sequencing of the human
genome and advances in renewable energy
and of those three we
thought that the internet could move the
fastest and so by then we had decided to
focus on the internet and trying to
create a global environment where the
internet could take off and be a true
economic force the landscape we
confronted was fraught with opportunity
but also with tremendous uncertainty
many entrepreneurs and companies wanted
to invest huge sums to build the
internet economy but they were worried
by the lack of a predictable environment
at that time some of you may remember
there were proposals in the EU in Canada
that attacks every bit of transmission
on the internet and they were being
taken seriously there were proposals to
put tariffs in the World Trade
Organization on commerce done by the
internet many governments including the
US government were looking the sense of
the Internet regulators in the EU and in
the u.s. wanted to have government said
technical standards for the Internet
regulate the use of digital signatures
restrict the new field of Internet
telephony set rigid guidelines and who
could and couldn't deliver Internet
services and regulate prices for every
internet activity much as was done with
telephony there were no agreed-upon ways
to protect intellectual property that
was the landscape we confronted many
foreign governments didn't wanna dot did
not want to adopt the internet because
they viewed it as under US government
control and there were a large number of
lawsuits which I'll talk about in a
minute working their way through
different courts around the world that
would have broken up the internet and
put jurisdictional restrictions on it
that would have prevented
interoperability across countries or
even States and many of the judges who
were sitting in judgment on these
lawsuits had no clue what the internet
was the security of the internet was
very uncertain some of the root servers
were in University basements where
anyone could walk in and pull the plug I
know because I visited some of these
sites unannounced and just walked alone
into rooms where they were housed we
realized that the internet had enormous
potential to unlock human freedom
economically politically and socially
because its very design empowered
individuals by allowing them to
meant their ideas directly without
having to go through established
hierarchies and bureaucracies the
potential seemed limitless but we also
realized that the future of the internet
was very precarious balanced on a
knife's edge between two extremes that
could delay its Advent or even destroy
it on the one side if the internet was
too anarchic with no guidelines that
could degenerate into a constant state
of unpredictable wild west shootouts
scaring away the decent folk who wanted
to invest in help build it on the other
hand if the normal forces of bureaucracy
took over with a mass of government
regulations and slow intergovernmental
bodies governing the internet the
creativity of the internet could be
stifled we had to find a way to allow
the internet to operate in a constant
state of creative chaos but with some
ground rules that would give those
invest in huge sums and at some degree
of predictability there needed to be
enough coordination and rules so that
the internet would be secure stable and
resilient but this had to be done in
such a way as to allow as much freedom
as possible for the users of the
Internet to create standards content
modes of access and economic activity
without government interference so we
established a policy framework to try to
accomplish these goals in 1996 and 97 we
passed an Internet Tax Freedom Act at
allowed internet comments developed free
of taxes we kept the Federal
Communications Commission in the United
States and the ITU globally away from
regulating the internet and Internet
telephony we got agreement the World
Trade Organization not to put any
tariffs on electronic commerce we struck
down attempts to impose censorship on
the internet instead empowering parents
and other consumers with controls they
could exercise to block content they did
not want to see we allowed marketplace
solutions on privacy to emerge we allow
the Internet users to set standards we
establish a global agreement to protect
intellectual property but in not too
restrictive away finally we recognize
that there had to be some coordination
of the Internet in order to ensure
security stability and resiliency the
question we faced was how to do this in
a way that could operate with internet
speed be representative of the wishes of
the Internet community and its various
constituencies be acceptable to
governments and allow for the rapid
growth of the internet that we hoped
would happen after a two year process of
consultation with stakeholders all sort
all over the world we formed i can now
for those of you who are not around then
let me talk about what preceded item at
the time iono as it was called was
housed in a small office at the
University of Southern California and
run by a wonderful man named jon postel
under a contract university had with the
US Defense Department which had been
involved in starting the internet I'm
not sure this is true there some of you
who may remember but legend has it that
at a meeting of the Internet Society
when the internet had less than a
thousand members someone suggested that
they needed a person to keep track of
everyone's address and John raised his
hand John for those of you who remember
him had a long scruffy beard wore
sandals and hippy clothing and was a
rebel and a free spirit at heart because
of his appearance it took me hours of
pleading to get him through security at
the White House when I invite him to
have lunch and I remember when I had the
honor of speaking at his funeral I
thought that day when he was at the
White House having lunch with me with
all these self-important cabinet
secretaries sitting around that a
hundred years from now nobody would
remember any of those cabinet
secretaries but they would remember Jon
Postel is one of the inventors of the
Internet
it was John that decided what top-level
prefixes were four countries and who in
each country should have the
responsibility for administering the
internet and he did all this from a
small office where the piles of paper
and books lying around reflected both
his brilliance and also the creative
chaos of the internet to get from the
door to the one visitors tear in his
office required agility and
extraordinary balance just to navigate
around the rubble on the floor I often
thought when I visited his office about
how some of the big corporate Titans
they were about to invest billions in
the internet would have felt if they
knew that all the routing for the
internet was taking place in that office
the a root server was run by a company
called network solutions in Virginia
which under a contract with the Commerce
Department had a virtual monopoly on
assigning domain names they received the
addresses from John and entered them but
at the time John and the leadership of
network solutions does not really like
each other so the right rapport was a
bit tenuous I remember when the idea for
I can first arose and it came after a
particularly difficult week where the
following occurred the head of DARPA the
Defense Advanced Research Projects
Agency which had the contract for the
iono called me saying that no longer
would let the contract for I am and when
it expire they wanted out the president
University Southern California called
saying that they could not take the
lawsuits that were being directed
against them and wanted out of their
contract our legal counsel described
over 50 lawsuits all over the world that
could tear the internet apart a
delegation from the international
telecommunication union after a dozen
years of opposing the adoption of the
internet protocols approached us
demanding to take over the internet a
delegation of us congressmen and
senators insisted that the US government
had created the internet and should
never give up complete control of it
several delegations of representatives
from over 100 leading IT and media
companies and 10 trade associations
visited saying that internet technical
coordination and security had to be
brought into a more predictable global
environment before they would invest
money in it and EU delegation said they
would pursue their own regulation of the
Internet routing system of
less the u.s. changed its policies
representatives from the internet
society that I had dinner with told us
that the Internet Society controlled the
internet and they would resist any
attempts by the US government or any
government to take control and the US
government security test was on the
internet the luda report to us saying
that is currently organized the internet
was in danger of disintegrating from the
lawsuits and lack of agreed-upon
coordination mechanism and in addition
to that my kid caught a flu which I also
caught so it was a wonderful week so we
clearly had to do something we clearly
had to do something now the idea of
ICANN might have been a result of that
flu but I hope not but the idea of ICANN
was unprecedented but we felt it offered
the best chance to allow for the
internet to flourish if we left the
coordination of the internet DNS to an
intergovernmental body we feared that it
would get bogged down in bureaucracy and
approvals would move at a glacial pace
personally I'm a believer that
governments play an important role in
societies and I'm a supporter of the
United Nations I work closely with UN
agencies my current work leading efforts
at the Clinton Foundation on global
health and climate change but the slow
and bureaucratic processes of government
and multilateral government bodies are
not the best way to coordinate a
fast-moving creative chaotic medium like
the Internet they moved too slowly
they're too risk-averse they officially
represent only governments and not other
constituencies and just in general
they're too cumbersome on the other hand
the internet could not be coordinated by
a normal private entity there must be
public accountability to Internet users
and investors there also has to be
accountability to government's the idea
of setting up a private nonprofit
organization that would be organized to
be a grassroots organization of
technical experts accountable to
Internet users and constituencies and be
recognized by governments but not
controlled by governments was risky it
had not been done before on a global
scale we knew it would be difficult and
somewhat messy but we thought that it
offered the best chance of
success it would have a government
advisory group that could ensure that
the views of collective governments were
at the forefront but they could not
control it it would provide a strong
focal point to take all the inevitable
lawsuits that would continue to come
with any decisions made about the
routing system for the Internet it would
be flexible enough to evolve as the
internet evolved it would be at the same
time strong but not too strong it would
have its own independent funding source
from an assessment under name name
registrations but it would never get too
big and its legitimacy would have to be
renewed regularly by its ability to
persuade the various constituencies that
it remain the best solution this was the
idea that became I can we identified vin
surf as someone to lead it initially
because he had credibility with all the
constituencies I'm not sure he's ever
forgiven us to that this day but we
thought it was the best shot that the
internet had now not everything has gone
as we had planned i can has made some
mistakes as an organization it's far
from perfect but overall we think the
idea has worked the political policy and
technical controversies that's
threatened to strife alors even ruin the
internet in its infancy in the late
1990s did not ruin the internet the
internet is flourishing when in the late
1990s I used to make speeches around the
world touting the future of the Internet
I was widely mocked for predicting that
by 2010 there would be 1 billion people
using the internet and Internet commerce
would exceed a few hundred billion
dollars a year experts and political
leaders alike said I was wrong it would
be impossible to go from 16 million
people which is where we were then to 1
billion people in just 15 years they
argued would be politically and
technically impossible for the Internet
to expand that fast I was accused of
being a big thinker and a dreamer well I
was wrong but not because of what the
critics said I was wrong because I did
not think or dream big enough today
there are almost two billion Internet
users there are over 3.7 billion IP
addresses and / 129
the name names and electronic commerce
has grown to almost a trillion dollars
per year the Internet has spawned the
complete revolution politically
economically and socially and it has all
worked pretty smoothly the technical and
diplomatic work of I can and I ETF and
other bodies have enabled this enormous
growth to occur with hardly a Grich once
one has not read stories of legal or
political battles or technical
difficulties bringing the internet to a
halt or preventing it from growing I
want to pause just to reflect on that
that is extraordinary if you think about
this enormous growth and the way it's
spread around the world and all the
commerce being done and so on and even
though inside of I can it must seem like
you're having a controversy every week
the fact of the matter is the Internet
has flourished it has grown and
flourished and i can tell you sitting
where we were in the late 1990s that was
not at all a foregone conclusion in fact
it seemed like a likely thing that could
go bad and not happen now would things
have worked as well if we had not
created i can and did the other things
we did maybe you know you can always
speculate but the reality is that for
all its shortcomings i can has not
prevented this resolution and by most
accounts it has played an important and
positive role in helping to enable it so
the reason for my history lesson today
is to remind you all that the internet
almost broke down before it really took
off in the late 1990s and it almost
broke down in legal political and policy
disputes that could have fragmented it
inhibit its use and the very least
delayed it and made it more difficult to
access while icon has its faults I urge
you to work actively to improve it
rather than tearing it down or allowing
it to be replaced with a more stifling
bureaucratic alternative now I remember
my last day at the White House that
friend of mine said the good news is
that for the first time in six years
you're going to be able to say what you
really think
the bad news is that for the first time
in six years nobody will care what you
really think but at the risk of having
that be true and have you not care what
I think let me just finish by offering a
couple of suggestions and I offer them
in the spirit of the success that I
believe i can has been and the greater
success that it can be I think there are
things that I can should do to work
better and that the reaffirmation of
principles issued in September of 2009
offers a good basis for making these
improvements and I think having talked
this past few weeks to people that I can
people at the US government elsewhere I
think that people are aware that these
improvements can be made and are working
to do it and I would just give support
to that effort one is I can always needs
to work hard to be more international
and in particular will include more
people in its leadership and management
from developing countries around the
world the Internet has become much more
widely distributed since we were
involved 15 years ago and will become
even more widely distributed still and
as somebody who now is working on AIDS
in Africa and elsewhere and interacting
a lot with governments in poorer
countries it's crucial that they become
more and more a part of this structure
as much as possible number two I can
must take great pens to operate in an
efficient manner it's a public service
organization with the technical mission
that should be frugal and it must always
have humility in the way it's works its
leaders must avoid trying to build an
empire I think you will be best served
by doing what you need to be doing to be
focused on but not build something that
is too big an empire because a bigger
Empire becomes a bigger target number
three
I can must be incorruptible and fully
transparent in what it does Seeking
consensus and explaining its decisions
fully there are too many disparate
interests on the Internet to avoid
controversy okay you're going to have
controversy you're going to do things
that are unpopular by definition not
only is this a very diverse community
but it's a diverse community of people
with strong personalities that's
something I learned very early on and so
you're going to have lots of controversy
lots of people shouting at each other
lots of ideas lots of ideas and you're
never going to be able to get full
consensus but you ought to try to get as
much consensus as possible all the time
and where you don't have consensus you
need full transparency and
accountability and explaining your
decisions because that way even if
people disagree with it they can
understand the logic behind what you did
so consensus will not always be possible
but you must do the best to seek as much
consensus as possible and then explain
your decisions fourth I can should
always look to empower Internet users do
not make a rule that limits what people
can do on the internet unless it's
absolutely necessary for the Internet to
function in a predictable safe and
secure way and finally I'll offer this
to my successors in the US government
that they should exercise their role in
full consultation with other governments
and in a light handed matter now I think
if those kinds of principles are
followed and I do think there are people
of goodwill at I can and in the US
government and elsewhere interested in
following those principles I think I can
will continue to flourish and the
internet will flourish I can processes
will always be a bit messy grassroots
democracy is by its nature contentious
but I can can and must improve we should
all work within it to improve it rather
than try to tear it down or replace it
with all its faults it is work the
internet is flourished the wonder of the
internet is that any individual in the
world has an idea is free to introduce
that idea to two billion people without
having to ask for me
if he or she can gain a following that
individual can build a huge business
introduce new art music or literature to
the world form a global social movement
or improve the way the internet itself
works the internet gives anybody in the
world a chance to change the world you
as current stewards of internet
coordination and policy have a
responsibility to ensure that parochial
commercial or political concerns and
technical problems are sorted out so
that the world remains safe for the
internet and so that the human freedom
and empowerment the internet brings can
continue to flourish I wish for you to
have the wisdom tolerance and patience
to do your job well thank