so hello I am Antonio Sanchez and put
that my friend might the same come here
for personal reasons but what and I'm
I'm going to % f2 Yara it's a model for
Jana to use rather well anybody does say
now yeah you know you know what you
don't know well yeah is basically a
putter searcher you define a pattern
string excellent small or whatever and
you come look for in a in a binary or in
a text file or whatever so the the basic
basic instructor off yeah
basic view sorry messy mode you can look
for restraints and small patters but
there have some has some modules to
extend the functionalities for instance
has PF a model model and so under one
model that was created in kudos project
[Music]
later this is something an example of
underwater model it's very it's very
simple here identifying experience we
only defined we only call underworld
model with the we can we don't look for
with one book for Facebook application
with the name and the package name
doesn't have doesn't have Facebook
katana is the official package name and
the certificate was different it's very
simple
of course hmm
I think that everybody knows dollar is a
strong open-source reversing framework
hats that's for a lot of a lot of
binaries architectures well with both
this was things we thought that could be
a good idea marching in Guam and create
a model to use radar inside of a VR and
well the installation is very heavy or
very simple whatever you want and you
need to change some things of data to
compile the model of Rada inside jar or
simply you can use air to PN
pancake accepted yesterday the pull
request and so well at this moment we
use Robin to our gratitude to extract
information from the binary here we
start import section on sports libraries
resources on banner info and a lot of
houses different houses with us to all
this information can be instructed to
from rather simple the command line but
we use these two these two tools well
now I want to to to present a bit each
it's it's part of the module we finally
with a couple of demos demos well you
know that with regard you construct
sections and this module
use the name flat size built on sighs
some physical others of the of the of
the name of the story of the section the
section has a standard name but not
always
has that name for instance well we can
use in in functional mode and in
condition we put only our to section
there a name could be under string or
rackets and the flux and sting or our
recipe we don't like damn we can put
empty a sting and the finding in a right
section well will be show later there's
life we have the name the flats the size
the vector size of the physical others
calling coming in a function we we have
less information because it's more more
difficult to parse in the model well
this is a simple rule that works in this
case we are we want to find a section
called bad section that's X with the
flower executable it's very simple here
we have a section important where we
look for a section in the right mode in
the right mode we need to to create a
loop this is the way that to create
loops in ingeras no user-friendly but
there's another one but it's the simple
way we look in the against the number of
sections to look for a section that the
size is greater than thirty eight
kilobytes don't like the flaps writable
and the section name contain text could
this is some more complicated route in
this case wheels we use a math math
module also including India and the same
week we create a loop only conditions
will have no strings we create a loop
that contains not not yes under entropy
of the section from physical others with
size size goes big Ritter down 1.5 1.5
that that the reason we use the math
model to calculate the entropy in the
inside a section of the section sir well
sing a section we we support imports now
only supporting in function version have
in mind a ordinals being type an unnamed
the three mystery could be a stinger or
ranks an original could be on the
integral for instance if we want to look
for a binary with that import you were
to well do not file we can't create this
kind of of of condition sorry it doesn't
matter for us by being by mother and
type this mother and the under name
could be worth URL don't like to fight
could be also a Ragus with slash started
slapping user slash or create process a
in this case become we can do for
instance
Mena's one for orally not as a mother
what I mean listen mother
this case could be for create process a
or create process W both both function
matches with that well also we have a
Super Sport symbols in this case with
with functions very simple the name and
the type would be string or radix this
is an example we will see in the end
oedema after also in in arrive format
like like sections this is the the rice
the right way we are looking for a
function called writing 50 file we
generate the loop the name contains rate
encrypted files function built or others
and physical address that's the
conditions all of this is in the
documentation and in the github repo all
the demos all the library is the same
with we only look for the name as string
or array with missing also we have the
binary information of course in brother
do come
in rely we have a lot of information
about the binary itself that information
could be could we use inside the inside
yeah big and know me sick they will
start can are you stay this is very
simple or to the model info
informational and canary true or false
Yara doesn't support boolean conditions
we need to replace with one on C work
see one nonzero number for resources
well we have a lot of resources in the
in a binary well only px px the type and
the language with the fusion for
instance in this in this in this case we
are looking for Strings resources with
language chains and here the same in
array right mode with side greater than
two kilobytes
Chinese classes the the Rojas - there
ain't a lot of classes right now and we
can use inside the inside Jared - Jared
have a module called hush but it has
less less algorithm than brother so
that's the reason why we include well
some we are we are use cases when when a
burner is packet
the beautiful size is greater than the
size real size on decent of the sorry of
the asexual so this this condition
having in mind that could be used blood
library and get brothers to to load
another library to hide the malicious
behavior we can generate one rule very
simple with with the model but using
jarrah
itself in raw mode it's more complicated
well in this case we look for a section
with the virtual size for greater than
normal size in this part to the flux
contain executables the entropy screed
are down 7 ok longer the pathetical kill
our business from remember yes tactical
malware analysis normally have the
function like a sport well export
function like low-level cape bar proc
and low-level most proc import function
like set window hood cakes mr. hot case
and for persistence usually have this
digit string set window who hate hook x
so is commonly used in spyware to
receive it they put the gaybar inputs
hot case for for combinate
kiss clip table frock is for the special
field
cell like like a culvert to when you
press ok
you execute that function the rule is
very simple in this case we include the
string for first time to take out the
room alter all of the world binary well
the important export that we find a
previous step approach the flag to
finish before the demo you have upx
pocket it's very very simple to the
degree that you only need to look for a
px under Sections you can see wrong EBX
work is the morning so well there is two
ways to to launch that module we can
land with her previous JSON JSON file
JSON report generated I have that this
model is the script sorry to generate I
run run into Umbra has to to generate
the information let's aside to the
module and you can run itself for
instance
we run we run Jarrah against we flip
that I'm going to show you the that's
the rule
we look for an expert with cut name that
type function or in a rice mo iterating
about the always Portland I'm having
that conditions it's more or less the
same we include picked all other sound
fiscal others we're on the province of
brother we in detect either take the
both roofs and there is another way to
execute this is in this way gerrae
directly called Roderick and br-2 P or
to buy it's not a lot it's not very
quickly for for memo reasons we are
discussing with with bank angle to
improve data under other ways generating
the report of binary
this is the complete information about
the binary that we use in the in the
model and the way to lunches
but it's very very quickly why when do
you need to use one of them or another
one when you need to run yellow or the
same rule set against Ben the binary
several times I recommended this this
this method do you generate the report
with that paper and then lunch several
times with that column with this comment
if you only only want to run one time to
test something you can running with that
is it generates the the JSON inside the
binary so it's slow in this case is more
visible
is generating all the information with
brother inside jar they take a lot of
time if you want to to execute only one
time it's fine
but ik but take a look
if I might it works
yes
in much with to to function on the
planet what would you rules the final
here to look for resources icon type
language Japanese and this is in a
remote in that cases if you want to
execute one more than one time is your
command able to to generate the report
say store and execute several times with
that that's it well all sorts of
documentation anything did happen with
the docs we started some months ago
we're open to - already - any idea no
idea about include things or with new
things sense - new log I'm pocket for
the for the feedback
[Music]
[Applause]
but