[Music]
[Applause]
[Applause
] Good afternoon everyone, it is a pleasure
for me to be present at this edition
of the 8.8 event.
I come to Ecuador. I am a
systems engineer specialized in forensic computation
after  say security I have another
profession and angled had a part of the
credit as well that some colleague
handles some certifications and management
is a combination of a
forensic computer network
to focus where we left it in that
type of network
and your summer under this light is to
follow him  And think between changing news
and news regarding the forensic field,
my emails for any
situation later will have them already
positive and in the end that of the
presentation
I am going to deal with today is a
forensic issue in another facet than the previous
companion process  el amigo del coco his
themes can be the initial part
my theme to focus the part after
security incidents in which they are
reflected  procedures and techniques of
forensic investigation in order to
find allies that allow us to know
what happened to those who intervene
many the legal part if it is necessary to take
into account if you want to take it to
the judicial or later part once
it has been delivered  that
the shots are found is because the
main part of this talk is to manage a
vision of how the university
the forensic investigator acts on his
mentor is that I wanted to investigate
an attack by Marc Guasch, not a
banking institution, in this case we will
focus on putting together a timeline  a
timeline
this step is one of more investigations
two days of investigation time are handled
later detailing
and we try to answer the questions
that are commonly handled at the
investigation level
how it happened
when how where and why
this part we do it now  whose
investigation and we always in the
wasted part the poor
security
We investigate our neighborhood neighbor
who are the attackers of the neighborhood residents
because we have many
similarities in our knowledge
that the other researchers like,
the typical ones of whether the
curious or the Gijonese
of that person are
an attacker in this case, how are they how
they act that what they do as they proceed
randomly in three income of the sites if
they do not know how they dress
some use their hat
very well because others use this
gray hat
others use their white hat
others
today we create a black that is too
big in our  diversity gentlemen
others on the other hand using a hat
on the other hand they do not know how to use the
hat
and still want to ride a horse
history
without knowing how to use a hat correctly
all the characteristics of the types
of attackers that we have the part in the
digital part
in the financial type  When we find
attacks of this type, that 4% is focused
on the use of the ma  nual malware
rankings and this is because the
economic returns are much more subtitles than
any other type of attack using
other types of technical goods
the trojan horse is already short there
will be no subscription terminals
forgive the malware handle malware assets
one by the by  way of eating with
some of the attackers
we are going to analyze a
research case and he is going to use these phases
in Felix's hands, investigating a little and
knowing what happened, how
the lessons were given, activities and based
the school activity, we found that
We will go on to recreate the sequel of
events that we have in the fields in
utilitarian fields of investigation,
as all churches offer, we begin with
a first phase that is to
inform ourselves what happened at the
time of what happened
always security in which it is a
bank aunt  has 800 thousand dollars at the
good time for several transactions
that were
made which has been transferred to accounts
banking more than 700 thousand dollars that have
been withdrawn the
audit officials have been the different
accounts that is money in the same way
as the same being separated from the job
once the financial entity
detects the loss of two thousand
dollars not
in  The two that manage both of their
transfer systems detect
which users from which users were
carried out
this equipment was isolated from users, it was
intervened or separated until
the investigation of the case begins and here
we have the identification of the case the
identification of the case was  part of
forensic investigation we detail everything
we need to know to
start the investigation
here they let us know that all this type
of transfer took place on April 10,
2015, which was the year we
were in progress from 4:00 p.m.
to 7:00 p.m.  hours with being a minute
were those three hours in which
different
to different types of
normal accounts  badly from the part where I come from
which is Ecuador and
nearby countries and many banking entities still do not
have a zero part of this type
of technology, researchers
prepared for that simply because
the insurance companies are in charge of putting the
money currently in the insurance that they
require  The rest is much more
detailed to be able to determine the
amount that they are going to return because it
will depend on whether the user had
participation or the type of people it is,
it is not that they participated although any that
this type of task
initially we have everything that they are  the
transfers when some of those
that occurred on the date
of April 10 that we saw, we are going to work a
lot for the dates because the time
we still have here which were
English sent funds to the accounts and
the two authorization networks
with this initial training  we started to
create our research service
and to be able to say
and we have generated a timeline
previous
in real time and we made all the
general indications, we have a date that
is April 10, which was the day of
the transfers and different times
that were those that each
of the financial movements were made
with this information prior to the team
that  They isolated, we generate an image,
so normally
we generate it with more than a forensic provider with chain of custody fibers,
it is always a procedure that
every entity must have in order to
alter and above all the reliability of
the data that is there and to
be able to make them sound without any chance  The
evidences go to the legal part in the
later ones
the water of more force
once we have the image is by
inheritance of we verify the scene and
we prepare to resolve to implement everything
we normally feel we take to
do an analysis of this type to
know the  scenario we want that we
use it and so that we are going to
deliver it we prepare a lot of coffee is a
project that will take us a lot  time
as well as the attackers take a
long time to carry out their investigative activities,
equally the forms the
same time much more of being able to
find or give rise to doubt and
allow us to appear the case in the museums
and we started the forensic analysis
and the initial environment was  a
windows operating system windows xp operating systems are cared for
within a financial institution
when these types of scenarios intervene
in windows and they are victims of the
actions and we focus on the
analysis of
certain information systems step I
create interviews recreate all the events
that  They have come to know what we can
get and population to be the
activity that I think happened on that
computer then from where you produce
the financial actions
initially this download of the file of
internalizing this file that has all
the activities of the users
each user has  that file inside
your portfolio is what allows us to ge  Nerar
in the repudios within the activity
of users a computer team can
have 10 users for each one it will have its
own writing but it will allow to
identify and separate what was
what each one of these did and how we are going to
collaborate
we analyzed opening the
security events is  It is important to know that
all the activities that are operating viruses are selected here, it
is important to perform
indexed searches with keywords, it is very
important to carry out at the same time because it is
another procedure that we do within
forensic investigations, whether they are
initial penn
or putting an incident of  this
type of security
and a browsing and internet file
that is also important to investigate
is not a source of the cookies that we have
from the equipment is a very
important factor for an analysis of this
type of attack such as an
external attack on financial institutions
where  it was possible to enter a virus because
by all the sources by which
They entered this type of
activity,
we have the casinos inside the
windows folder, so the
happiness movement in that type of magician is 32
remaining,
among other beers, we have been looking
well, it is because we started the nobody that is
why a forensic image is a
device  that allows us to create an
image can be to paralyze the
research process the objective of creating an
identical copy of a hard disk is to be able to
help the original so that we can give
errands and be able to work a copy the
copy can we can make the
changes that are necessary to  to be able to
find any type from there
once we have our own because
we will begin to work within the
investigation
well
let's see that the first source of
evidence that interested us is external that
we have it within the
user folder of each of the users
because it is important  this file because it
is the user activity log file
and it is imp  ortante we
already detected the name of the user in which
the transfer is seen if you want to be able to
analyze and see what activities it has in
that part for that we export we export
this file using the images and
we give it with puppets, import it and we
can open it with other  With other types of
tools such
as wing 2003 it
is a tool that uses to open
this file in this install and
allows us to see many
important activities of what the user can
have
among some of those when he said we saw
this user we export
with this tool known as the
windows 7 recovery
we have a tab to be your accesses
and what are the applications that start
when windows starts when the user
is logged in other users
but three users that I have, imagine being
able to enter the machine and this
application is not going to be run when the
teacher is  installed inside the
user so he wants as the code
will totally start when  ndo these
angels in session
and then we have the initial applications
in another when one starts
it is in a process of the
right cb that is a normal process of
windows it is used to call some
services but seeing that it continues
reforming difficulty we
realize that already  not to a 32-point file,
that is, finding, it can be said that
in this case we find every
file the point of bs
we see that it is a point file from the
32-point file bbc they are found in the entire
windows
folder.  To see
physically or logically where
this is hosted, what else can be
entered easily? It says in this file
well within the windows registry
we can see the following note we do not
enter the folder with the options
to find in windows and we can come
and continue  the following routes
finding misinformation of the
applications that start when we saw
when his excessive nephew
well  out of all the folders r.unido
we find countless
files that in magazines are doubtful we are struck by
the professor files
on names suits point plus a point
bar says let time continue to
dance to you and what includes a valera
look is a  In a synthetic way that is
doing many activities, especially
these people have done,
but we bank officials know
because they invest in a god of dollars for
three months for their security is the one
after they are violated and they
are almost always focused on this type of
finding a way because
to  Wherever they can today, they are with this other
past, this other of 22 million, in the
end, they were achieved for 4 million
dollars, they did not take out to an
Ecuadorian municipality with the millions of dollars in
one day
they took out powerful weapons they
left us losses in the street
because right point  that point
we are to analyze our
and knew search
a virus
was a water what had been
installed of the equipment
is another  at the same time the difference between a
judicial expert opinion
if there is evidence expressed that one of
the parties says and we put it
here we started from scratch they simply
thought that the only
initial information was that the user that they are from
this machine making the transfers
but as when it happened how they are  and
because they did not know the importance of the
answer in this case also because
after a few days the investigation was done
but it was possible to determine
many many things
well let's see some files found
in this folder be
glad to have the point of times
the native point point  of bs they are not
files
of not drinking and writing they are written they are
programs based on visuals and it is a
totally Windows file uses it
to enjoy certain tasks and
attackers take advantage of to
camouflage them
in this type of language because they
do not have the same application  to
say that twice is an application
that runs that type of files will be
axis  cutad because the
contractive of the visualize them
because they give us dividends etc
because many of those times that if they are
detected by an antivirus but they do
a previous analysis of the banking system
if the banking system has a 1
an antivirus of x if you know the spirit
of  total elvis
have crossed over to enjoy
dotcom dot com is a website where I
upload a file and it tells me that it
needs individuals, no
and that is a tool for
both security and
criminals because they want to
attack a company  that the antivirus
has where it has sometimes worked
in another way and it has been verified, it is detected
, the recipe has not been guaranteed, it does not
detect it perfect red little for the
attack,
in this way, this
type of security and other causes
for which the
banking entities begin to violate  Ecuador have suffered this
type of attack
and
the details of saying poor of that level
some statistics of a website
due we see that in the ecu  The
example of which I am taking
is 7 percent of attacks of this
type or it contains 7 percent of attacks
of type bs and if I have a relationship
with many other countries it is one of the
largest we do not have that Peru does not exceed
Mexico  it does not exceed but at the population level they
are three or four times
as large
we have that when it is much more than
egypt india colombia bolivia guatemala
then right now they have found there
for their meditations
in this area in that kind of details
well i
think they make 32 assets quickly
It is a general way not to go into
script details and we see that in
general the execution of a
two-point process
we see that the
windows folder enters the folder you call the
point s rights files
and this file is executed in a hidden way
It is found in all the
folders that we saw in the first image
to know that what it does is file
has three children with it is the quadrant
of the windows product of
final borders with him at the end to know
what you have interactive, we can see it
from some free tools,
others for payment, in the machine we
do not have free web applications and
we decided that what one of these does within the
system
is all health and is more
good is what. is
this site is a point file
that website wants to generate a sport
in a sport in which it will be
presented in html css format but
all the activities or all
the changes that the file generates in  the
windows registry
which assets have
file activities exploitation the process are
activated when this file is executed
on the machine
and thus we have a file point after
point pk
results of this analysis deactivated
point is when we have an active point
of sin which has left  from analyzing
the network traffic
we know that there is a connection not or
that it is a file generates a collection
where in the report the
network activity and analyzes  When the file is pasted
we see that it connects to an
IP address that the function of asset
point
is the function of the file
is that they give it an external cure that
was not detected
or to the state where it went to the state
by the entities systems
financial
that is the first part of buildings is
what we receive the first first
view
in the first instance now let's start with an
investigation to find out what the
deterioration is like because they are there because it is
not your turn to start an
investigation yet,
having to do so on the afternoon of the 10th.
April 2000 of this year the recent attack
I am not doing a line of work
of alestis show work
so we decided it was decided to generate
a window of time that is to say a
border a kind of sean and others
we did a search for files with 30 days
before and five  days after the date
on which the activities took place
to know that what we found
we lengthened the search and won the
window  45 days 60 days back and
later and deer cases but
we started to generate searches by opening
the time windows it is important
for a researcher to
generate the time entries because the
2015 university is an infinity of
information, something that to be able to analyze
and that is not  It is very feasible it will take a
long time but I am going to reduce to a
window that already with film analysis
we
can eternity we can work the most
correct programming we analyze this type
of search and we find ourselves, for
example, if the afternoon is April 10 on
26  From April
we found that a dll file was executed,
the point of bs another type of
scripting applications because I had the
machine I think that if the script and
from April 26 to March 26 it will have another
connection or it called a connection in this
case
to  the 199 116 60 points 16 and even
but what are
the ports to scan
the 1 maroto valley
until you can scale until you can
establish the condition
But for the questions to
appear, they will find, you can do
another search with a keyword that
would not be a deceased at the point of bs
when we executed in this file we
got a lot of information from the chrome browser, we
exported the chrome logs, we opened
with a program
that we  attend the pre-salt made
the website 2.0 for young
insecurities
we can see that it is used for 33
the thumb after the city and he
i
but a download from
and the ip address
then the acid lll 33 points of times
what it did is download these  three
those three initial elements
at the time that April 26 was the
date most back against,
well what does each of these three
files do,
we see that the file
on 6.3
executes the
inside of the windows enclosure the
pérez file point of which is  They like that
file point that what it does is add
certain values to the windows style
and analyzing active profile point 6 we
realize what it does is  Within a
month I write at the beginning it was
the one of the 32 does not load the service it was left
I can congress to decimal Cáceres
files of that part we detect that
from that aggression ips download the
file quota group point that was the one that
adds to the same decision of the  user
the execution of the file must have
an initial point of sale that comes
we are not closing the circle
scale the
football that you do not say something only that it is 2011 does not
add
malicious that the machines capture all
the information that the user generates in
files of  text and later to
use details to process or specify
an attack
well what was said about that file not
in the same machine
find this file size not if
we see that on
March 29
it is generated and capture
user information dry what he did  all
transfers
and we see that the same March 29 capture
by such businesses of mangoes that they
use for all transfers
before the username and the
co  The password
that is used for hostile countries
at that point we lack new doubts
because there is a lot of evidence it
is evidence the museum evidence for
a researcher in this type of cases
in which there is no experience we do not
differentiate between the novice attacker to
a professional attacker by  the amount
of evidence left by the equipment
because the attacker
but professional always complies with
step number seven in the afternoon fingerprints
knows where he enters where he generates the
fingerprints and does not erase
then he enters when looking at the network to a
machine he must know where it is generated to
choose or  designate is a machine to be
able to play and not be detected is not what
you do but in this case there is an
inconsistency a very sophisticated attack
to think that some data is again
in
evidence which made us think good how the
file must feel the point  It must
be the team,
it is needless to say that how
the points file was enjoyed we have also
executed
and how they were executed or  Another type of
applications,
the instance, as there are many evidences,
says that they left hypotheses, we do not want
hypotheses,
I told him that it is a lot of evidence that they
left on purpose to be able to remove
legal responsibility from the user of the
machine or the bank, it is something
that was consulted
I was not
and that was not me, it
was to be has collaborated with all the
evidence found in the team
because it was an attack but with some
participation within it
so that part of the search we left
a side apart from the posters because they
knew how to handle it etc.
We focus on the analysis of the 32
kilos file to know how the same equipment and
how the point file is executed how the file was
executed?
of 32
points of bs what is the charge of the
ip address 229 116 points 60
we did a search for the
japo rostrum  This
is one of the
platforms that was used in this
analysis as well as other commercials that
may have much more because they are
in search looking for this.  active of the
'red'
some results
and among those
well what we have the files
documents points
the first social we had because
it found where the
point files were now not covering
point
d and we see that they are located
within windows the country
and  We have natural folders folders
that are created if these are
personally where all
the files that we open from pain
the post manager are housed in a document an
attachment that generates the
active temporary folders and deletes the operational mail we
still cannot.
I had a lot because we knew that that
file was in this part of
here and well
that I denied you  vo
said they have d & s shares and 12
income points
now we go for one that was opened and
was opened twice because we have the
document point time document home
but not
doing a search using that is
much more powerful that allows us to
recover some deleted data  With
the email that has this attachment
we give the problem you have to
points
and we see that the mail comes
from Spain Spaniards to be
about 2000 points is on March 25,
2015 for together with his quote
an
ordinary man among the good  and the assets
that you have discover the points but the
contents are recovered all the
files first double click to
follow the next steps
we have been executed of
course that eating is finding about it
and we would have
with this activity we started integrating
a little more than more did the  user
and we continue to take the file,
these files are very important if you
want to leave your user because  It is
reactive It is essential to be able to
locate the work
we see that within the
recent objects here we have the path within
it
of users
we have folders of all the assets
that are opened by the user and we have
from Greece
and we have for each asset that we have  a
better value with information that enzyme
that will allow us to say which assets
were recently used and
we see that the file from the point
should that was accessed by executed in
this case by the user by user
we do not have in that game
also already with this  You can say
what we needed to tie up the dots at the
time point what we did not have
within the general systems of
developers and it was executed because
we also found within the
recently opened files it
offers them
in the
middle of uses and in the example of
pride mean the three
most recently used Indians in the
windows registry and look at them prepares  r
all the sites where
recently human information is recently used
by users
in this group point that
is also by executed
since we had to know
[Music]
a little research has passed,
transfers can be made from
four of the  late to seven o'clock at night
then we decided to analyze what happened
after 7 o'clock at night the user
was present in history on the
machine and while managing the equipment, he continued his
activity
we had files that were worked
after what ended and the
attacks such as open documents
Edited photographs run sent
decided that is, if there was activity
that frustrated his house he continued working
normally after work
then since he was the intellectual author
because an accomplice that part but Suarez
then here when the user was already intervened
later called again
to face not for  the central part of the
bank appeared the g  Atitos of the
owners who attended the positive
of the partner
not that not the kings or the characters of
studying positive
and that they did not know dark that what it seems
I think that first what it seems
reaching the part of the times that they
can or criminal responsibilities or  Not
in this part of activities to the user
and to verify the two months and two
of the bank's servers, we see that it is
exactly like this, gentlemen and
the IP addresses were reflected, which led to the
concession of both one
and his
206 were detected but not detected legally
for the
security devices but we were not
arrested here here are
security maps we have to focus a little
more you are not on security at the
top a little forgotten you have not completed
a little more your security systems
against this activity we can recreate
a lifetime of research
idealism and reactivation of the
relationships events each of these
lines of research has its own
their situation and for each one that
we raise the death of evidence
fully put
we see that already recreating the line of
investigation we see that we can say
with 85 days of the glass arrives an email to which they
can take care of the points of it
is two points ls  On March 26,
the point of bs
116 60 116 on March 27 of the
address and Pérez will be other natives
of poor domes
we have on March 31 the pursuit is executed
that generates
that the file of from the one of two
persists in the  reggae says one that
asks when user logs in
we have that the goal of the system on
March 1 a grant 200 is created
and in which the file is downloaded
from that other agent from the forest April 4
to headquarters for the last time to the file because
this has no longer been
number
10 on April 10 the attack is consolidated
[Music]
the team of the keys
and then building our
experiences asia
around here some graphs of conduits of the
attack in  the email to the
user to choose our said that it does not
have a manual
this is the solution to an
address to an external server where
the attacker is located
the attacker of the computer
this manual instead have August
connection time to another absent others
and from that  IP address from this
server using the
user's computer since
bank transfers abroad are generated
this would be a graphic technology of
how things happened within an
attack an extra malware attack,
saving
in this part of the conclusions no
and now commented that  It was totally
violated
and antivirus
are very useful tools in the
security issue, they already need other types of
special security or the
forensic security that is being implemented to
webber the banking entities, not with
software that allows monitoring
each of the processes of services and
connections  performed by the user with
one comparing with previous
configurations  as authorized by the bank
that is what I have come to share with
you an experience of this type of
attacks a Chilean with some statistics
on the part of the knowledge of the same and
all the preventions of the case so that
national moments come
to try to be attacked by  that type of
attack
thank you very much for your attention
thank you very much someone has a
question two questions are going to come out
hello
the question is regarding well here it
equals and this happens I do not know if they
agree on the amounts that I was returning
there
but it gives me the impression of  that the
banks there use the second of the
certification factors, as in the
case that although it is true, there is the same
now that for that they put some
more barriers that could make it more
difficult
with which we live no no because the
attack is recurrent old type
is  Suppose that they are not using this
type of security,
the query
was seen there that the equipment seems to be
very
or is complex, now we are going to stop  to be able to
comment on the god they did to that is
prior to the fact that hissing is detected by
the antivirus that the entity has if it
garcía those analyzes that it is company to be
able to know what type of that it is going to
use they analyze or do tests they
create the framework of the programming of the
platform to know what activities it detects
when they will be in the bank because it
uses it and new ones and detected because it
is already with the previous tests performed
ok to the last one now
hello
and
within the presentation you showed
when you look for fabric to read within the
million files in the  windows and
aversion to assets in the rare world
complete 2014
and then later associated with the
son's email on March 23, 2015 how to make
that relationship let's say this active
next to 2014 by the email that arrives at
that time
one of the first things  that makes the
increase of it in the part of the
dates of arturo salah won him what do not
coincide
a sequence
of events that we saw then
independently  nte of the dates that are
presented, it is
recorded
until this growth,
this is the way, all of the air
that the people received was analyzed, it is no longer
concentrated and that is what I understand
we analyze since they appeared
fully in accordance with the laws
so you can follow it
And to you,
if everything is fine, thank you
[Applause]