all right thank you so I'll be talking
about our work on asymmetric message
ranking for end-to-end encryption
nowadays more than a billion users are
communicating on platforms like whatsapp
signal and Facebook secret messenger
these services provide confidentiality
and integrity meaning the platform can't
read or modify messages and additionally
they aim to provide deniability it
shouldn't be possible for other parties
to attribute messages to a sender even
in the event that the recipient is
compromised or is maliciously leaking
messages another security property that
we might desire of these messaging
systems is metadata privacy in which the
identity metadata of who is
communicating with whom is hidden from
the platform most work on this last
property metadata private messaging has
been confined to the research community
but just in December of last year signal
deployed a limited form of metadata
privacy that they call sealed sender so
in signal sealed sender the sender
identity is hidden from the platform
when a message is sent
so all these security properties are
great but what about abuse
there are countless different forms of
abuse that surface on these online
platforms to name just a few
Alice could be a cyber bully or an
abusive ex-partner harassing Bob with
abusive messages or perhaps a spammer
sending annoying or potentially even
dangerous bait messages in the hopes of
link clicks or actually even more
recently we've seen in the news about
the prevalence of these misinformation
campaigns which have contributed to
political instability and in some cases
even inciting riots and lynchings so in
response to maintain a healthy platform
and hold users accountable these
services have chosen to introduce
content-based moderation
where Bob can report a message from
Alice to a moderation system that in
practice typically involves a
combination of machine learning and
human review in order to judge whether
the platform's content policy has been
violated in this case punitive action
against Alice could be taken such as
banning her from the platform
so in fact content moderation has become
a very big priority to some of these
services for example Facebook employs
over 15,000 content moderators and while
that stat is over all of their services
it still illustrates the point that
content moderation has become an
integral part of their platform however
end-to-end encryption in privacy
complicate the story of content
moderation the moderator doesn't see the
passage plaintext until Bob reports it
so they can't determine whether Alice
actually sent the message or if Bob is
just saying L sent it so in this work we
ask if we can balance the need for
accountability via content moderation
with the privacy goals that we desire of
metadata private end to end encryption
and ten encrypted messaging so we're
able to answer this question in the
affirmative doing so led to us
introducing a new primitive that we call
asymmetric message shrinking for reasons
which will become clear momentarily and
this asymmetric message franking can be
paired with existing metadata private
messaging services to enable content
moderation and even more than that our
primitive is useful just beyond this
metadata private setting and also
enables moderation in the setting where
the moderator is decoupled from the
messaging platform for example in
federated meta messaging services or in
communities that span across messaging
platforms so we provide formal
accountability and deniability security
notions for the content moderation
setting and report on the design and
evaluation of a construction inspired by
DES
to verify our signatures to get started
let's back up and look at the existing
tools supporting cryptographic
verification for content moderation this
prior work coined message franking is a
technique originally built for facebook
secret messenger which supports content
moderation in non metadata private
settings to provide a little bit more
detail
recall that in modern end-to-end
encryption Alice and Bob generate a per
message shared secret key via some key
agreement protocol such as signals
triple diffie-hellman handshake and then
that symmetric key is used to encrypt
the plaintext in the non metadata
private setting Alice then sends this
ciphertext to the platform over a
channel that's authenticated and bound
her identity so this means that the
platform knows the cipher text is being
sent by Alice and that it should be
delivered to Bob for example on Facebook
Alice is logged into her Facebook
account so in message franking then the
platform simply stores this identity
information along with the cipher text
to report a message Bob will provide the
symmetric key material and then the
platform can use that key to decrypt the
cipher text to learn what message Alice
sent Bob and this this all works fine as
long as the underlying symmetric
encryption algorithm that's used is
committing meaning that Bob can't
provide a key that opens the cipher text
to a second valid plaintext and so
actually this is still just a little bit
of a simplification of the message
franking solution but it illustrates the
basic idea unfortunately this solution
doesn't work when we consider the
metadata private setting so in the meta
data private setting while the plaintext
is still bound to the cipher text the
identities no longer are
so the moderator doesn't learn who sent
the message at this point there seems
like there might be an easy fix can we
can we bind in Alice's identity using
the same committing encryption strategy
Bob can then verify the bound identities
correct and the moderator will use the
bound identity to attribute the message
unfortunately there's a subtle attack
here in which a third user Charlie can
collude with Bob to frame Alice as
having sent a message she didn't
actually send and since the platform is
meted a private the moderator can't know
the message originally came from Charlie
and not from Alice and so we consider
this a break of accountability and at
its core the problem with these
approaches that rely simply on symmetric
techniques is that Alice's identity
isn't cryptographically bound to the
message content we'll need to use a
different strategy for metadata privacy
for the metadata privacy setting or more
generally for settings where the
moderator doesn't learn the sender's
identity so at a high level our solution
of a symmetric message franking is a
specialized digital signature scheme
that reintroduces the send your identity
binding using public key identities and
while at the same time simultaneously
achieving the accountability and
deniability goals of our content
moderation setting so then to send a
message Alice will first sign a mess
sign the message using her secret key
and then encrypt the message in
signature under the end-to-end
encryption symmetric key so our message
franking protocol is going to be
decoupled from the end-to-end encryption
algorithm Bob can then choose to report
the message by sending the message and
signature to the moderator so you might
notice right away that accountability is
easily satisfied using just standard
digital signatures both the moderator
and Bob can verify that a message is
from Alice however
the same verification algorithm can be
run by anyone and so thus Ellis's
messages don't have any deniability so
we're going to need to use other
approaches so as a starting point for
our solution both technically and
conceptually let's consider designated
verifier signatures so designated
verifier signatures are this cool
technique in which the signer can
designate a specific party and an only
that specific party to be able to verify
the signature accountability is met
since the designated verifier can't be
fooled by forgeries but there also
exists a forging algorithm that even
without the secret signing key can
generate a fake signature that's
indistinguishable from a real signature
to any party that isn't the designated a
verifier and this provides deniability
in the cryptographic sense and that
there's no cryptographic reason for
anyone to believe that a signature is
authentic because it could have just as
easily have been a forgery and this type
of denial of the deniability seems
particularly important in the wake of
recent data breaches in which breach
signatures were used as cryptographic
evidence of the breaches authenticity so
now let's consider using designated
verifiers signatures in the following
way let's have Alice sign her messages
with the moderator as the designated
verifier so we'll add a public key to
the moderator which Alice will use to
sign her message and then the moderator
can verify the message using their own
secret key and then by the designated
verify property of the signature others
can't be convinced that a message is
from Alice since it could have just as
easily been from a forgery
however unfortunately by the same exact
property Bob also isn't able to check
whether the signature will be accepted
by the moderator and so that means that
Alice can evade moderation by sending
Bob
signatures so to complete the
accountability picture we'll still need
something more specifically we need some
way for Bob to be able to check whether
the signature will be accepted by the
moderator so then in a symmetric message
franking we do this by adding Bob as a
designated verifier of a proof that the
signature to the moderator will accept
so what does that look like now all
three parties will get a public key
Alice signs messages specifying the
public keys of the - verifying parties
which are the receiver Bob and the
moderator the first verification
algorithm is run by the recipient to
verify that the signature will be
accepted by the moderator and the second
verification algorithm which we call
judge allows the moderator to attribute
a message to the sender informally then
our accountability notions restrict how
these three algorithms interact with
each other receiver binding means Bob is
bound to only be able to report messages
that he actually received from Alice
he can't frame Alice by generating a
message that passes judge that she
didn't actually send and in sender
binding this means that alice is bound
to messages that she actually sends to
Bob in that messages she said she sent
can be reported and traced back to her
she can't send Bob a message that Bob
will accept through his verify algorithm
and then we'll later fail the moderators
judge algorithm so that covers our
desired accountability goals but what
about deniability for this we reason
about deniability by thinking about who
can create forgeries that are
indistinguishable from real signatures
for example if we consider our earlier
scenario where Bob is leaking Alice's
messages to the public
if there existed of forging algorithm
that Bob could run using his secret key
that produces a signature
indistinguishable to Alice's real
signature then the public would have no
reason to believe the message came from
Alice because it could have just as
easily been from Bob's forgery so we
want the public who only has access to
public keys to be unable to distinguish
between these two worlds one where one
that uses Alice's real signature and one
that is Bob's forgery another scenario
we might care about is if the moderator
leaks Alice's messages here we require a
forging algorithm that takes the secret
key of the moderator and to make things
even more complicated what about when
the moderator or the recipient are
compromised and their key becomes public
we may we may want to maintain
deniability even in the event of certain
key compromised scenarios so to capture
key compromise we would want the
distinguisher to not be able to
distinguish even when given secret key
material and so you can see that when
considering all these key compromised
scenarios this quickly blows up into
combinatorially many possible forging
relationships some of these forging
relationships have interesting
implications to give an example relating
to the previous presentation consider
the relationship where a forger with
only public keys fools the distinguisher
that even holds Alice's secret key this
implies that when maintaining
deniability Alice won't be pressured to
reveal her secret key in order to show
her innocence since her keys not going
to be of any help anyways in other words
this forging relationship implies that
Alice doesn't have the ability to
repudiate messages
the other hand other relationships
contradict directly with our
accountability goals for example if the
receiver Bob was able to create a
forgery that fooled the moderator then
it would be a direct violation of our
receiver binding property allowing Bob
to frame Alice for messages she didn't
actually send so ultimately we explored
this whole this vast deniability space
in this table I'm showing the keys
available to the forger on the left side
and the keys available to the
distinguisher on the top and you can see
that some of the forging relationships
are explicitly ruled out by our chosen
accountability goals which I'm depicting
with these little symbols we ended up
picking a set of three deniability
relationships corresponding to forging
with no secret keys forging when the
receivers key is compromised and forging
when the moderators key is compromised
so as an added benefit our chosen dime
deniability targets imply the rest of
the forging relationships that aren't
ruled out directly by our accountability
goals as shown by the the blue shading
on this table so the choices that we
made represent only one possible design
point in this deniability space there
are many other reasonable trade-offs
that can be made depending on your
desired accountability goals supporting
reputable signatures would be such an
example as motivated by the previous
talk okay so to summarize so far we've
seen the accountability and deniability
goals for a symmetric message franking
but not how to actually build a scheme
that achieves them this was challenging
because we have so many security
properties that we need a balance so
next let me give you a high-level
overview of our AMF construction our kin
consists of a proof of knowledge of a
carefully chosen expression of discrete
log relationships which relate the
public keys of the parties involved
the signature proof of knowledge
notation will use to specify proofs of
discrete log relationships follows the
Chemosh Dowler style so for example this
is the notation for a standard Norrell
signature that's proving knowledge of
Alice's secret key this relationship as
well as those that are used in our
construction can be proved using an
interactive signal protocol with a
three-phase commitment
challenge/response
and then we can turn this interactive
protocol into a signature using the
standard Fiat Jameer transform by
generating the challenge using a hash
function that also binds in the message
and so with that here's our construction
and at a high level as per our earlier
intuition the construction is made up of
two components the first Clause is kind
of an embedded designated a verifier
signature to the moderator and the
second clause corresponds to a
designated verifier proof to the
receiver that the signature will accept
so now let's look at what makes up the
designated verifier signature - the
moderator it consists of a disjunction
of two clauses the first Clause is what
Alice proves to the moderator and so you
can notice that it mirrors the Schnoor
signature that I put up earlier in which
Alice is simply proving knowledge of her
secret key and the second Clause is what
allows other parties without knowledge
of Alice's secret key to forge so other
parties will construct this J value in
different manners the moderator will
only accept the signature if the J value
is constructed in a in a very special
way specifically if it's constructed as
a diffie-hellman triple with its own
public key the moderator is public key
and this ephemeral EJ value and so
assuming the ephemeral information that
constructs EJ is discarded only the
moderator is a
to check the validity of this
diffie-hellman triple and it can do so
by using its secret key and so this is
what provides the designated verifier
property so zooming back out to the full
expression and then looking at the
designated verifier proof to Bob
we see that it's constructed in the same
form the first clause is what alice is
proving to Bob and the second clause is
what allows for forgeries and so
remember the goal of the designated
verifier proof to bob was for alice to
prove that the designated verifiers
signature to the moderator will accept
and we can see that that's exactly what
she's doing here she's proving to Bob
the diffie-hellman relationship of J EJ
and the public key of the moderator okay
so in summary our construction provides
a way for the moderator to attribute a
signature to Alice for Bob to verify
that a signature will be properly
attributed and provides a variety of
different forging algorithms for various
key compromise scenarios that gives
Alice a level of deniability for more
details on how these different forgeries
are created please take a look at the
paper and the paper also has the formal
Theorem statements and proof showing our
construction meets our desired security
properties and so although this proof of
knowledge seems large it's actually made
up of very standard discrete log proofs
that can be implemented quite
efficiently we implement our
construction in Python and using the pet
Lib library and find that our solution
leads to short signatures for signing
and fast verification times well within
the bounds of what we think is practical
and we also wanted to see how this would
work on existing platforms recall that
since a symmetric message franking
doesn't require metadata we can add it
as a third party service on top of
legacy systems so we provide a proof of
concept integration with Twitter private
messages
that uses key base to manage the public
key identity bindings for Twitter
identities and then the in our in our
integration the service also uses a
machine learning system called
perspective to automatically score
message toxicity levels and so we think
this proof of concept provides a pretty
good example of the types of things you
can do with a symmetric message ranking
so in conclusion we introduced a
symmetric message franking a new
primitive for cryptographic content
moderation in the metadata private
setting we introduced definitions and
strategies to formally reason about the
trade-offs between deniability and
accountability in this space and lastly
we gave a construction conceptually
based on designated verified signatures
thank you happy to take any questions
all right thank you we'll have time for
a few questions again please come to the
mics we haven't looked we haven't gone
in that direction
no and just to check you have a single
scheme to despise simultaneously
simultaneously all three kind of
deniability properties that's right
those three different ones that those
two those three targets that we chose
all right and then II for the questions
if not that's Thanksgiving again thank
you this goes recession