you so hello all I'll talk about
attribute based encryption and it's
generalizations for non-deterministic
finite automata from the learning with
errors assumption it's a joint work with
photographer and shota Yamada and this
got initiated well why shota was
visiting ID Madras back last year so
let's start with the notion of attribute
based encryption introduced by SIA and
waters in 2005 where it's a
generalization of public key encryption
and where the goal is really to provide
an expressive access control over
encrypted data we have seen this from
this morning so the setting is like this
that let's say we have a server where we
store encrypted files these files are
encrypted with respect to public user
attributes and accordingly there should
be a key Authority which should be able
to generate restricted secret keys these
restrictions come in terms of policies
or boolean functions embedded inside the
security keys in such a way that these
keys would be able to decrypt any of
these ciphertexts
if and only if the attributes with
respect to which the files were
encrypted satisfy the embedded policies
further we want to also ensure that any
set of colluding users should not be
able to decrypt any of these files as
long as at least one of these users are
not individually authorized to decrypt
them so this is actually formalized by
the following set of 4 algorithms can
set up encrypt keygen and decrypt so it
takes the second the setup takes the
security parameter and our outputs a
public key and a master secret key the
encryption takes the public key and an
attribute X and of message M to output
the cipher text encoding the message
with respect to the attribute X the key
generation algorithm takes the master
secret key and a circuit F to output the
secret key corresponding to this
functionality and the secret key when it
acts upon the cipher text to the
decryption box it outputs the hidden
payload M if the attribute if and only
if the attribute satisfies the function
and security goes like this for any
couple of a challenge attribute and a
pair of messages m0 m1 and all the
secret keys for functionalities FC
by the adversary their cipher takes the
pair of the ciphertext for these pair of
messages m0 and m1 with respect to the
attribute X should remain
computationally indistinguishable as
long as these secret keys are
individually unable to decrypt any of
these ciphertext cipher texts so this
notion of attribute based encryption has
seen an elegant sequence of works from
2005 onward with restricted
I mean constructions for restricted
circuit classes till in 2013 mode one of
it all first showed how to support all
circuits from the learning with errors
assumption now even if learning a B for
all circuits was realized and circuits
are a powerful model of computation they
have their own inherent drawbacks namely
they have I mean sockets always provide
fixed length input support and their
description changes based on input
lengths they also incur worst-case
runtime based on all inputs of certain
lengths so naturally our attention turns
towards uniform models of computation
like at finite automata or Turing
machine or Ram where we have arbitrary
length input support with a fixed
description size which also incur input
specific run times
moreover we if we have an a/b support
for I mean a B for supporting a uniform
model of computation then that gives us
the flexibility of giving out a single
key power functionality because the
description doesn't change now based on
the input length so the question is now
that what do we know so far about a B
for uniform models from standard
assumptions so as we talk so as we saw
in the last talk the construction the
first construction probably why was
given by Brent it was for a B for DFA
with unbounded attribute lengths and
unbounded number of keys from the q type
assumption
it's a parameterised assumption
subsequently in 2017 Agrawal and seeing
gave a construction supporting I mean
for the same primitive with unbounded
attribute length support from the lwe
assumption but restricted to the single
key setting so and concurrently just
now we saw the the work by Gong it all
it constructs the same primitive from
the standard K linear assumption static
assumption with unbounded input length
and unbounded number of keys in this
context our work constructs a B for
non-deterministic finite automata with
unbounded number of keys and unbounded
length attributes from the learning with
our assumption our construction works in
the symmetric key setting but I mean for
all these years after from 2012 there
was no progress on how to support
non-deterministic finite automata and it
was explicitly left as an open problem
by Brent in 2012 so we construct it for
the first time and we also additionally
leverage our techniques to generalize it
to predicate encryption bounded key
functional encryption and usable
garbling for NFS from lwe additionally
we show a barrier in obtaining fully
collision resistant Fe for DFS in that
in the in the sense that it implies it
IO from standard assumption so it's it
highlights a barrier in obtaining fully
collision resistant DFA Fe so we also
have a concurrent work with Gong at all
and subsequent to our work also I'm
taking the techniques from our work
which constructs the same primitive for
DFA based on the same assumption but we
have very different techniques while
gong at all achieves key policy ABV our
techniques are generic and run in a
modular fashion which which allows us to
get both ciphertext and key policy a b
and this will appear in TCC this year so
in context of the current talk i want to
highlight this fact that our
construction doesn't only support NFA
but it also supports this generalized
class of uniform circuits with bounded
depth actually so NFS are a particular
instantiation of this class and we can I
mean NFS are more practically relevant
actually so we will restrict our
to NFS only for this stock so let's look
at the techniques to construct this
primitive let us look at how do we model
this secret key a B for nfa it's done in
the same way just that only there will
be only a master secret key which will
be used for both key generation and
encryption the main differences are that
the attribute length will be of an
unbounded attribute will be an unbounded
polynomial length and the key generation
takes the NFA description as an input
more importantly the key generator
doesn't know the input length now and it
has still - still output a secret key
which should work with arbitrary input
lengths security is modeled in the same
way as before so let's look at how do we
construct it we have a two step solution
to construct this pivot of the first
step consists of constructing this
yellow box yellow and the red boxes
where we have an a B for NFS scheme with
unbounded attribute length and width
bounded size NFS and the red box
constructs a B for NFA with bounded
attribute lengths and unbounded size
interface and in step two we have a way
to combine them to get both unbound
unbounded in both these coordinates as
in unbounded attributes and unbounded
NFA machines so let's for ease of speech
I will refer to this yellow box su comma
B the other one has B comma U and the
green one is you just you so let us look
at how to construct this u comma B
primitive so since we are working in the
symmetric setting let us take the master
secret he has a PRF key for now so the
naive idea to construct such a primitive
will be you just take an NFA and convert
it into a circuit and employ an a/b for
circuits scheme since we know how to
construct them but the thing is that key
generator doesn't know the input length
and therefore it cannot just convert it
into a circuit so at this point we note
that the attribute length which is as
which has unbounded polynomial length is
upper bounded by two power lambda where
lambda is the security parameter now
based on this what we can do is that we
can have a circuit heavy scheme and
instantiate to power lambda many key
pairs from the circuit a B scheme where
each such key pair will support inputs
I mean attributes of length I
ranging from one to two power lambda and
then we can encrypt a message under the
proper public key based on the length of
the attribute for the key generation we
will convert the nfm to a set of two
Paul lambda circuits where each such
circuit will be capable of handling
input length I ranging from again one to
two power lambda and use these a B
master secret keys to generate a B keys
for each of these circuits individually
and get them in a bunch to output as the
secret key for the NFA machine M
why does decryption work because
decrypted knows the length of the
attribute at least it can choose which
particular secret key to use
corresponding to the machine I mean
circuit equivalent of the NFA and
decrypt to get back M if M except 6 now
the first problem here is that the key
size is actually too long it's
exponentially in security parameter and
to reduce this we use a simple trick we
handle the inputs of length the
attributes of length only to power I so
we instantiate the a B scheme instead of
2 power lambda times we instantiate it
lambda plus 1 times where we handle
attributes of length 2 power I only as
in when when and if and when the
attribute comes during the encryption
algorithm deity which see the nearest
power of 2 and padded with sufficient
number of bots and we encrypt the
message under this new attribute for key
generation we convert this machine m to
a set of lambdas circuits lambda plus 1
circuits which are individually capable
of handling inputs of length 2 power I
and then use the a B master secret keys
again to generate keys for these
circuits so while this works now the
next problem is that I mean we have
reduced the number of keys to a
polynomial count but the next problem is
that each individual circuit a B
secretly can can have an arbitrary size
I mean they can blow up by too much we
don't have a proper bound on the
underlying circuit sizes M hats of
equivalent NF is I mean the NF is
equivalent circuits so they may have
arbitrary sizes we need to bound and
somehow so to bound them our first idea
is to use these
by Boni at all from 2014 euro crypt
which relies on lwe which says that it
can ensure that the size of the circuit
every secret kiss grows only with the
depth of these underlying circuits now
once we have only this depth dependency
we need to have a bound on the depth of
these underlying circuits so a knife way
to convert any nfm to any circuit will
actually I mean it can be done like this
that you can track all the inputs States
while reading every input symbol and
this can actually lead to a circuit of
depth polynomial in the length of the
input and that's what we don't want so
we actually employ a divide and conquer
strategy from the literature complexity
literature to evaluate these NFA em and
this ensures that the circuit that we
have here employing this divide and
conquer technique the the depth of the
circuit scales as poly logarithmically
in the machine size and the input size
which in turn ensures that the circuit
every secret key grows only as a
polynomial in the security parameter the
third and the most crucial probably the
problem in our naive way of constructing
is that we had an inefficient key
generation note that our u comma b key
generation algorithm takes a machine
name and converts it into a circuit but
this circuit may be too large for even
the for the keygen to even read it
actually and idea it the time for keygen
should not also depend on the input
length now so the solution to get to get
around this the solution is to somehow
redistribute the computation in a way
that we delegate the inefficient part to
the encryption and decryption algorithms
of the u comma B primitive now why
encryption and decryption because these
two are the only algorithms that can
still run in time polynomial in the
length of the attribute so thankfully
functional encryption comes to our
rescue here
so EFI as we already have seen in the
previous talks it's a generalization of
a b ii and where secret key corresponds
to a circuit and ciphertext encodes the
message which i mean
these secret keys when used to decrypt
the ciphertext reveals only the function
of the plaintext
and nothing else in our context we only
need a single key secure functional
encryption which can be again
instantiated from the works of gold wash
return and Agrawal and based on lwv can
be still based on lwe so let us see how
efi helps this helps us here to delegate
the computation of nfe to circuit
transformation and a B secret key
generation so the idea is that instead
of converting to a circuit the key
generator now takes the input machine
and encodes it into an EFI ciphertext
parallely the encryption algorithm takes
the attribute and the message m and it
converts I mean it generates an EFI
secret key for a circuit which embeds
this input length
I mean attribute length hardwired in it
now given these two are available to the
Decrypter it can run the efi decryption
on-the-fly to get back C sub X of M by
the functionality guarantee of Fe where
C sub X of M is described as follows
it takes the Machine M as input it
computes based on the hard-wired input
length of the attribute it computes a
suitable AV keep here which can handle
inputs of length X mod X and convert the
NFA m do a circuit actually inside the
circuit to this circuit M hat which has
input length mod X and then use the ABI
master secret key to compute and output
da B master a B secretly for this
circuit now once this is output by the
efi decryption the encryption algorithm
also actually encrypts as a part of the
ciphertext it actually outputs the a B
encryption of the message M under the
proper public key under the same public
key actually with which Dima for which
the same master secret key was used to
compute the secret key for the nfa sir
circuit equivalent of nfa and when these
two are available to the Decrypter it
can actually run the a/b decryption
algorithm to output the message if I'm
accepted X now while this template works
we still need to be a bit clearer
all about the implementation of EFI here
we don't need this I fir text to scale
up with the input size again otherwise
we fall in the same trap again so for
this we use a we use the single key
succinct Fe scheme by goldwater at all
where it's ensured that Fe cipher text
scales only with the depth input and
output of the circuit and not with the
size and we carefully bound the depth
into input and output to be polynomials
in security parameter and as a result
what we have here is that the u comma b
key generation and encryption algorithms
runs in time proportional to the size of
the machine and the size of the
attribute further we have the Decrypter
generate the a/b secret key on the fly
which is needed for the final decryption
and but at the same time because this Fe
secret is supports the circuit and this
circuit takes the NFA machine as input
the machine we need a bound on the
machine that's why we have support for
unbounded attributes but with bounded
size machines so we need a bound on the
machine and this works this is the
high-level idea of how we construct the
u comma B scheme so as a summary let us
look at the problems and their solutions
that we face from the nice solution we
had an exponentially long key for which
we used attributes of length through
power I the individual any secret keys
could be too large to handle this we
instantiated with a suitable a/b scheme
and ensured that the circuit depth is
polynomial in security parameter thirdly
we had an inefficient key generation
where we used the succinct FE scheme to
delegate this inefficiency inefficiency
to the encryption and decryption
algorithms so now let us look at how do
you construct this B comma u primitive
note that this attribute length is now
bounded since it is bounded it it can be
known to the setup algorithm and
therefore it is thrown to the key
generator and the encrypter and
therefore we can actually employ a
circuit every scheme directly to convert
nFA's into circuits and instantiate it
just we need to ensure that because we
are we have we want to handle unbounded
size NFS we have we need a depth
guarantee on these
over NFS of any arbitrary size for that
we can again use the same divide and
conquer technique to have a depth
guarantee on these circuits so once this
is done we now see how to construct this
new primitive unbounded length inputs
and unbounded and FM machines the high
level idea is again to break up the
computation in two parts where the size
of the attribute is greater than the
size of the machine and vice versa we
are working in the symmetric key setting
so therefore we will again have a master
security as a PRF key which can now
inherently define a sequence of master
secret keys from the underlying u comma
B scheme each such master secret key is
capable of handling in a phase of size i
ranging from 1 to 2 ba lambda parallely
this we can have a PRF key which is able
to define all these master secret keys
from the b comma u scheme which are
capable of handling inputs of length 2
power lambda as an input attributes of
length 2 power lambda now how does the
encryptor and key generator work let's
look at them parallel e because
encryptor knows the length of the
attribute but it but not the size of the
machine and key generator knows the
length of the machine but not the
attribute what encrypter can do it
samples master secret keys from this u
comma b scheme mod of fixed with NFS of
size supporting mod of X I mean 1 2 mod
of X and generate ciphertext under each
of these master secret keys accordingly
the Decrypter can actually sample a
secret key with the size of the machine
m from the unbounded scheme and we can
once we know that the size of the
attribute X is greater than the size of
the machine we know that one of these
ciphertexts actually corresponds to I
mean was generated with the master
secret key capable of handling NFS of
size m and therefore we can actually
pair this key with the one of that one
of those cipher texts so what what what
if the other thing happens as in the
size of the machine
grows more than the size of the is
than the size of the attribute then we
just roll this swab the role of the two
new comma B and become a new skin so
where the key generator now produces
modern secret keys modern secret keys
each capable of handling I sized
attributes where I ranges from 1 to mod
of him and encrypter gives a ciphertext
with the b comma u scheme which is
capable of handling on the mod excised
attributes so once this is done the
decryption compares what I mean
compares the length of this machine and
the length of the attribute if they may
attribute size is greater then it uses
the unbounded scheme to combine it
unbounded attribute scheme otherwise it
uses the unbounded machine scheme to
combine these ciphertexts and attributes
this ciphertext and secret keys and run
the decryption so in summary we we run
these two underlying schemes u comma B
and B comma u in parallel to make the
decryption work and to which supports
both unbounded X unbounded attributes
and unbounded him now using the same
techniques we can generalize it to get
predicates encryption bounded key
functional encryption and usable
garbling for NFS from learning with
errors assumption and last but not the
least let's see how to get io from the
secret key D FF II the high level idea
is to again look at this way look at it
this way we if we have an NC one circuit
we can actually use Barrington's theorem
to convert into a branching program and
then leverage the similarities between a
branching program and a DFA so while the
input length is fixed to convert it into
a DFA actually and once we have this
tool with us if we have a secret key Fe
for DFA we can employ this tool with
this thing to obtain secret key Fe for
NC one circuits and this as recent
results have shown this is good enough
to imply in distinguishability office
keishon which actually highlights a
barrier in obtaining fully collusion
resistant
functional encryption for DFS
so let me conclude by saying that we
have the first constructions of a/b and
it's generalizations of NFA from ender
we also illuminate a barrier and our
techniques are new we hope that they may
find more applications in similar and
different contexts we also want to see
how to support during machine and RAM
and last but not the least again our
sirs primitive is restricted to the
secret key setting we want a
generalization to the public key one so
thanks for your attention if you have a
question please come to the microphone
okay let's thanks this all speakers
again
[Applause]