hi everyone so this work is crypt
analyzing and I saw Jenny based crypto
scheme called psych so we take a bit of
a long road to get there and to put this
in context right now nest is
standardizing post quantum crypto
schemes just to say that something is
post quantum means that it's secure
against a quantum adversary meaning that
any algorithm to break it is infeasible
to run on a quantum computer to even
make a statement like that to claim
something like that we need to be able
to decide how much does it cost for a
quantum computer to run certain things
so everyone in this field sort of has to
have a model somewhere in their head
that says what a quantum computer is and
is not capable of so how do you imagine
a quantum computer what does it look
like what can it do is it actually just
a classical computer but maybe you've
sprinkled in some magic quantum
operations in addition to the other ones
and so maybe you think you'd like to do
a bit better and so you think there's
this enormous body of literature already
existing on quantum computers and you
want to draw from this so here we're
going from realism to generality in
these models as cryptographers we can
draw from these very general results in
complexity theory and query costs but we
end up having schemes that are too big
because this is too conservative so we
think maybe instead we draw from these
realistic approaches where people are
worrying about what can we run on
quantum computers very soon on immediate
technologies but these results don't
worry if a new quantum computer will
come along that their algorithms don't
run on because they'll just write new
ones
but if cryptographers we need to worry
about that because if our security was
invalidated we might have an insecure
scheme so cryptography is need to be
somewhere in the middle and that sort of
gives the the overall context for what
we're going for with this work and how
we tried to analyze psych so in this
talk I'll give some of our motivation
and what we tried to do with our new
model for quantum computers
and then introduce the main contribution
of our paper this memory peripheral
framework and this framework
accommodates different cost models we
provide two we use those cost models to
analyze psyche and I'll conclude after
that so the first thing we want to be
able to do is to fairly compare a
classical and a quantum algorithm so we
want to be able to say if something is
easier to attack with the classical
algorithm or easy to easier to attack
but the quantum algorithm and sometimes
with algorithms that have both classical
and quantum components and this is a
problem that has come up before and is
well known so there is this quantum
collision finding algorithm by press our
Hoyer and tap that requires a lot of
classical memory with quantum access and
Bernstein argued that if you fully
account for the memory costs then
actually a classical algorithm is less
expensive and another thing we want to
incorporate into this is a view that
gates are processes so in a quantum
circuit diagram you have different wires
and they represent qubits and time goes
from left to right so when you look at
this what's happening is each of these
symbols represents a gate that is
applied to that qubit at that time these
deliberately resemble classical circuit
diagrams where each wire is a bit and
time goes from left to right the thing
about the classical diagram is the
diagram represents this formal boolean
circuit model that doesn't account for
space at all but typically we equivocate
between time and space because we think
well we can take the circuit and we can
print and non-print it on to a physical
chip and when we do that the signals
will propagate from left to right
through the gates as time progresses so
time and space intuitively feel
equivalent here and we don't usually
worry about this but that's not formally
implied by the model and it's especially
not implied by the models quantum
computing where this may not hold
because the technology may not have this
property and right now the promising
quantum technologies do not look like
the classical two dimensional circuits
it's that the qubits themselves are
stationary they're not a signal moving
and you have to apply a gate to it
so we want our model to accommodate that
and finally we want to include error
correction so in classical computers
there's we have error correction and
usually we don't worry too much about it
because it's not that much of an expense
but in quantum computers it's a bigger
deal and in fact quantum errors are just
fundamentally more complicated than
classical errors so we need to include
this in the model if we want an accurate
reflection of cost so this leads us to
our memory peripheral framework and the
main idea is we want to model a
computation as having some physical
memory and some memory controller that
acts on that memory so as some examples
a Turing machine fits in this if we view
the tape as the memory and the head as
the memory controller a random access
machine also fits in this the CPU is the
controller and the RAM is the memory for
quantum circuits we can use a random
access machine classical as a controller
and use qubits as the memory we have
three main premises for these one that
the memory is a physical system that can
change over time to that the memory
controller interacts at the memory
number three that the cost is the number
of interactions so I'll go into the even
more detail so because it's a physical
system memory is a physical system it
will change over time and we can model
this in different ways we can imagine
that when we're not intervening with it
when we sort of just let it do its own
thing it sometimes might change and this
could be noise and could sort of degrade
over time or it could even do
computation if we've set it up very
carefully alternatively it could change
because our memory controller has done
something to change it and we consider
these the costly changes to memory more
specifically we model a quantum computer
as a parallel random access machine that
has these qubits associated with it and
so take the RAM model take your favorite
instruction set and add in some
instructions that are effectively apply
some gate to some qubit at some time and
the effect of this is now a quantum
algorithm becomes a classical program
and so this is what this looks like this
is one way that you can imagine what a
quantum computer looks like you have a
big lattice of qubits and to every qubit
or maybe every small group of qubits
you've associated a classical controller
and that does things like corrects
errors applies gates performs
measurements and all of these classical
controllers are coordinated by some
central memory controller and viewed in
this way this gives a cost of quantum
algorithms in the number of interactions
so a quantum computer will definitely be
very expensive to build it'll be
expensive to keep it cool and maintain
it and we ignore all of that we only
focus on the cost to the classical
controller and the computations it must
do and you can think of this as an
opportunity cost
we have this big classical computer that
we need to run the quantum computer what
else could we do with that classical
computer if it wasn't busy running the
quantum algorithm and so this is a very
a general framework and we could fit
different cost models and different
assumptions into it and so we provide
two different assumptions which lead to
these two costs what we call the G cost
and the DW cost in both cases we imagine
qubit memories and standard quantum
gates and the difference between them is
our assumption on error correction
whether it's passive or active and
passive error correction is roughly na
involved o non-volatile memory you can
imagine if you have a piece of paper you
write a bit on it you keep the paper
cool your bit will last for a really
long time similarly if you have a
magnetic disk you can write a bit to it
and just keep the disk cool and you're
fine active memory needs to be
continuously refreshed to preserve it so
DRAM is a should be a very familiar
example and quantum surface codes are
another example on the slide there's no
examples of a passively corrected
quantum memory and this is not a
accident so imagine this quantum
computer and has a - of qubits
in some number of dimensions and these
qubits are limited to local interactions
in this lattice to try to correct
their errors and so can we build
different kinds of memory in this we
know how to build actively corrected
memory and dimensions 2 and higher
surface codes are an example of this we
know how to build passively corrected
memory and dimensions 4 and higher with
a similar construction to surface codes
but dimension 3 and under is an open
problem and there are actually an
impossibility result for a large family
of error correcting codes that include
surface codes and three dimensions is
almost totally open the thing to
remember about this is the dimension
that we're referring to is the lattice
of the lattice of qubits in the computer
the physical dimension of the computer
that we built we're limited to three
dimensions that's the universe we live
in so if we want to make a passively
corrected quantum memory we have to
solve this issue and right now this is
open so if we want to take this g cost
and assume a passively corrected memory
we have to make a pretty strong
assumption that our universe even allows
this to happen and that at some point we
will figure out how to do it but this
might be possible so we can make this
assumption so we don't need to spend any
computation to preserve memory we only
need to spend computation to change it
and this is one Ram operation per gate
is what this would be equivalent to so
the total cost is just the number of
gates so we called it G actively correct
memory is going to be more difficult
because at every qubit at every time
step we have to do some computation to
fix the errors that have occurred so we
end up with one where I'm operation for
qubit for time step so the total number
of RAM operations for the algorithm is
the depth of the number of sequential
gates times of the width the number of
qubits and DW cost so looking at these
we might look at high memory algorithms
to try to see somewhere where these two
will be different and I saw Janine based
cryptography is where we looked and so
to give a very brief overview of I saw
Janine based cryptography we have a
large prime P maybe it's got 434 bits
and we have a public parameter a zero
and a public
he over a and we it lives in some graph
and this red path is the secret key you
can find this red path you've broken the
scheme so this is vulnerable to a meet
in the middle attack we look for paths
going forward from the public parameter
and paths going backwards from the
public key and we look for a collision
between these two paths so hence the
quantum algorithm that was previously
viewed as the best attack is a generic
collision finding algorithm by canny so
it uses a random walk on a Johnson graph
so a Johnson graph is you take a set X
and you make vertices out of every
subset of a size R and they're adjacent
if they differ in exactly one element so
if you take a random walk on this graph
this is completely equivalent to taking
your set removing an element at random
and inserting a new element at random
and that will be one step so for tenis
algorithm you make one Johnson graph out
of the set of paths going forward from
the public parameter and another Johnson
grass out of the paths going backwards
and so you take it random walk on both
and every time you insert a new element
you look for a collision in the other
set and you take this whole thing and
you make it quantum with a standard
construction very similar to Grover's
algorithm so what happens with this is
that the lengths of the random walk the
random walk gets faster if the sets are
bigger and Kenny optimized for the query
optimal where you actually have to
balance that with the set up cost to
originally construct this list and
balance that with the total length of
the walk and this is where the size of
the set is proportional to the number of
queries which is proportional to the
time for I saw Jenny based cryptography
for psych these are all equal to P to
the 1/6 so previously the security was
given as P to the 1/6 of the for the
prime P but this is these use a lot of
memories this algorithm and quantum
memory is unusually expensive so in
imagine you've got this array of memory
and these cells at the bottom you can
imagine maybe this is a full chip of
memory or maybe it's a hard drive or
maybe even a tape
and you've got some circuit to access
them so we have a classical query we
want the ninth element of memory we can
follow this red path and at each point
the memory controller can look at the
input and say I only need to take the
left path I don't need to go to the
right I don't need to use any of those
gates I don't need to turn on any of
those memory addresses and so on and
only needs to spend log and gates to
accomplish this task with a quantum
query it might be in superposition and
so the classical controller cannot tell
what memory access they need to return
because they cannot read anything about
the input without destroying the input
so what they have to do the memory
controller has to apply gates for every
possible input because they don't know
what they're getting and it might be a
superposition of every possible access
so this is now a linear number of gates
in the size of the memory and this
should actually be very familiar to
cryptographers because making a fairly
loose analogy here a quantum state is
kind of needs to be side-channel
resistant because if any information
leaks about the state that will decohere
and destroy the state so the circuit
that we use to operate on that state has
to you in it again waving my hands here
be sort of perfectly physically
side-channel resistant and so we need
circuits like this one that works for
all possible inputs and so this can give
us a cost for memory in terms of gates
if the memory is idle if we're not
actually accessing it of course if it's
passively corrected it's free and it
wouldn't be free if it's actively
corrected and for random access we pay
at least a linear cost in both of these
cost models but for Tenney's algorithm
it's actually even worse because we need
some structure to this data to
facilitate insertions and deletions and
for quantum algorithms we need
interference we're doing a random walk
on this Johnson graph and what we need
is that for a particular vertex the
representation of that vertex in our
quantum computer cannot depend on the
path that we took or else it will not
interfere with other paths the light to
the same vertex
but on a Johnson grass a vertex is a set
and a path of the sequence of insertions
and deletions so we need insertions and
deletions to lead to the same
representation of the data our favorite
data structure classically to represent
a list to represent a set is a binary
tree that would we would implement as a
linked list but this doesn't work
because we have fragmentation we have
the layout changing depending on the
order so for history independent data
structures the previous quantum approach
was what's called a quantum radix tree
where you take a binary tree and make a
superposition over all inputs but we
could also have used a sorted array and
so if the elements in an array are
physically in order usually we don't
like this because if we want to insert
it in the middle we have to move
everything after that element down but
we're already paying a linear cost for
memory access so this becomes more
appealing so this is the data structure
we provided in our paper we call today
Johnson vertex and it's just a sorted
array and so to insert into this I'll
walk through what this looks like we've
got all these elements on the bottom
here and we also have an Ansel array of
all zeros so the first thing we do is we
fan out an input X so we use this tree
to copy X to every element so this has
logarithmic depth and your number of
gates we end up with X in every element
and we compare all the elements
simultaneously with the one above them
to see if the element is larger than X
and we end up with zeros and ones in the
top row the shift between zero and one
happens exactly where the elements in
the array became larger than X so that's
exactly where X needs to go so we use
those bits to control a swap that goes
up and to the right and that ends up
shifting the right half of the array up
and to the right and then we swap them
back down controlled on the same bits
and now we have shifted half of the
array down and it's only took two steps
of depth and we've inserted X into the
right spot now we need to uncomputable
we fan out
X
and we have nothing so we have correctly
inserted into our array with this
structure and so this is actually this
Johnson vertex is actually the lowest
gate cost to do the things that we need
a quantum data structure to do for these
random walks so we go back to Tiny's
algorithm and previously was the speed
of the one six query cost they used P to
the one-sixth memory and so immediately
this has a DW cost of P to the one third
but using our data structure we show
that the gates are actually also P to
the one-third now maybe this isn't fair
to Tony's algorithm which was optimized
our queries so if we re optimize for G
cost or DW cost we can bring both the
gate and DW costs down to P to the 1/4
but this is actually the same as
Grover's algorithm up to paly
logarithmic factors so here what we've
shown is that Tandy does not provide
anything beyond a poly log advantage
over Grover for either of these costs to
give a little more intuition on why this
makes sense we use an argument of grover
and rudolf and they say that if you've
got this big quantum computer so for
Tenney's query optimal algorithm we've
got P to the one-sixth qubits we're
ready to apply any gate we want to any
qubit we want at every time step so we
could do anything else with these qubits
that we wanted we could group them
together into a little arrays and run
Grover on each of them so now we've got
P to the 1 6 copies of Grover's
algorithm they're all running in
parallel and we do the math on this and
they find the iso journey in time p to
the 1/6 so this is the same time as
Tanya's algorithm so this is saying is
that this hardware to run the query
optimal version of Tani's algorithm
could be repurposed to run Grover and
get the same time but it's actually even
worse because if you remember a quantum
computer has a classical controller and
so it will have P to the one-sixth
classical control processors associated
to all the qubits what if instead of
running the quantum algorithm we sort of
turned the qubits off and we repurpose
the controllers to run vanish at Wiener
so this is a lot of classical
controllers this is P to the 1/6 when
they run van oorschot wiener they won't
find the Asajj in the in time P to the
1/8
so our conclusion here is that if you
had an adversary who actually built this
enormous quantum computer to run tanny's
algorithm they have implicitly built
such a large classical computer to run
this quantum algorithm that they'd be
better served just using the classical
computer to begin with and so this is
the big conclusion of our paper but our
main contribution here is this memory
peripheral framework and so what we want
you to take away is thinking of quantum
computers as peripherals to classical
computers and thinking that everything
you do on the quantum computer was
controlled by the classical computer and
you can think in terms of those
classical costs which are now directly
comparable to any classical algorithm
and so from this you can give a linear
gate cost to memory access for quantum
algorithms and even further if you're
skeptical about this passively corrected
memory you can use this DW cost and give
it cost of the identity gate so that's
everything thank you for your listening
[Applause]
if you have any questions so please come
down to the front to the microphone now
if there are no questions we'll move to
the second talk let's thank the speaker
again
[Applause]