thanks for the introduction so this is
during the walk without going nowhere
the seawater and the
protein I'm Kafka Minamata from anything
cooperation so the topic way is OCB - so
it is an authenticated encryption and
authenticate the encryption is a
symmetric key function for
confidentiality and authenticity and its
syntax consists of the DD barrier words
so we have key here nonsense
print exam and associate data a which is
a part of the input that is not
encrypted about must be authenticated on
taking the DD topo at an encryption
alpha and input to the encryption
function upon the authenticated
encryption it creates a cipher text and
authentication toggle T and the topo and
a city will be sent to the receiver only
sipping it the decryption function
checks if the whole input is authentic
or not and if it is authentic
there are print X will be returned the
other wiser error message will be
returned so we have some popular a
schemes most notably the tuna stole the
commended mode of operation GCM and
cesium and also either one nine seven
seven to define the six schemes and
there are some internet standards
specified by RFC s such as the GCM and
the church a 20.per a ones 305 some so
on and we all listen to activities on
the competition of dollars let's get the
encryption called the scissor define the
six schemes okay so she be it's a more
cell related a mode of operation having
strong features such that now it is a
later one it allows a later operation I
mean that and it is also faster the
encryption only mode such as counter
mode and it is paralyzed abow and it's
other provable security reduction to the
pseudo randomness of the underlying rock
cipher or she be had the three versions
the first version
proposed by a longer way to are at CES
2001 and the second version which is our
target was proposed by log away our two
age equipped mm OH
four and the finally the oshi b3 was the
proposed bike robits on the rollaway in
FSC 2011 okay and all more all families
of LCB has been extensively studied from
security perspective for example the
tightness of security bans had to be
investigated and the limitation against
announced missiles and other type of
missile attack has been investigated
necessity of the strong pseudonyms of
the enduring rocks I ever had mean
yesterday
and finally therefore OSHA p3 that
abound improvement regarding the
decryption decryption complexity has
been shown there are many more works and
we did works the or she be as a familiar
with the mode as a one of the most
studied a mode of operation so we have a
strong belief on its security but he
turns been wrong yeah ok so in this talk
I showed some structure weakness CC b2
which is the independent of the
underlying block cipher and it's block
size and it has been overlooked for
around 15 years since the proposal based
on this we derived the several divesting
attacks for authenticity attack we
proposed both eg station and the new
booster forgeries for confidentiality we
start with a basic distinguishing attack
to more powerful the plaintext to who
protects to recovery and all attacks
have very small complicacy and the
success probability
almost 1 ok before showing the attacks
let me show some practical impact of all
our attacks all these out first of all
what should be two rather one of the six
algorithm defined in either and since we
announced their attacks in the last year
last autumn in the last year as already
they declared a profile removal from
genders okay and the other JavaScript
crypto library called sjl which uses OCB
- so instantly usable CBS joshiya may be
affected but it is hard to see the real
impact because the use of s this year
does not necessarily mean the use double
she be - okay and we understand the
fiction crypto is not the easy and time
conscious time-consuming process and
fortunately or unfortunately we don't
find any other significant or er what
the use case beyond that so let me
describe there what should be to here's
a picture and you can see that there
them
these are message Brock's and the deeds
here the ciphertext blocks Nancy's here
and target here as you can see there
it's like ECB mode of operation however
the other masks are prior to the input
and output of the block cipher brother l
ensure value of the mask is derived from
as an encryption nos d2l means and a
field
gaurav here the multiplication by X and
the three-year means a to L plus L and
different from the other blocks the only
does last for the last block we did
something different by using a counter
model like encryption taking the rocks a
crying input being the lengthy
information of the last block and the
other no output mask here and instead of
having a dedicated map function or CB to
computer checksum which is essentially
the sum of all message blocks and the
encryption of the this check sum with
special mask bar you produced a tag you
can notice that an attack may be
truncate to some Talbot's
and if associate data is present we
first compute a team at fight
prep in mark is a parallelizable macro
mode of operation and the result will be
sure to the T here to form the final but
this is the only if the ad is non empty
in case it is empty we do nothing so
here the picture is yeah just like this
one
and the for simplicity we assume the on
truncated tug and empty ad for most
cases okay let me move to the forgery
attack its description is quite simple
yeah rudimentary simple
so we first take another arbitrary now
sign here and protects the am here to be
encrypted M consists of two blocks the
first block is that a lengthy
information of the setting and bit
string and m2 is arbitrary and we by
encrypting it will receive the cui the
c2 and the T here from the encryption
righto T will not be used who are tax so
you just remember that memorize that
Anna she won the future are expressed
with these formulas okay so this
immediate our route to create a forgery
by using the same nouns T here announced
here and forge a ciphertext C Prime and
for the air for Gentile T prime here she
prime is just one block consisting of
the sum of C 1 and length information
the T prime with the sum of a C 2 plus M
2 then there's only one block so the
decryption is essentially a counter more
the decryption so C prime is here and
because it is an ax bit we see a cancel
here with this block blue line and this
group encryption part encryption block
type output so we see the decryption
will return to our Plus legacy formation
because it is one they are the one block
it's also used as an a checksum here and
we note that this special mask for tag
generation 2 times 3 times L is equal to
the 4 L plus 2 L so we see a counter
again here this bar total result is here
which is an encryption of the whole
block length information which is
exactly the same as T prime so we get
the accepted this with probability 1
okay
this attack can be extended to along a
message there the idea is essentially to
craft their own leader for arbitrary
wrong message we just crafted l-last to
ciphertext blocks and the idea is pretty
yeah the same so I'm skipping it and
this attack is also extended to break
the confidentiality then at the real bot
notion here as a privacy CCA whose goal
is an distinguishing the parable
encryption the decryption
wako from the pair will random
encryption and what should be to
decryption of course we have to add
water is not a road to make a tree beer
credits to win then attack is simple we
just mount and minimal forgery and see
if this is accepted okay as we have seen
that in the left of world case the this
will be accepted with probability 1 what
are the only a negligible probability to
we to make a folder to be accepted in
the right world because the encryption
is just a London just returning the
London borough okay and of course and
the object note that this decryption
worker is in fact not necessary just on
the verification worker just returning
the 1b tomorrow for the returning the
authenticity of the who input why not
it's just enough for our attack ok so
what will happen after the minimum
forgery then as mentioned other words we
received in prime which is as some of
the tool plus links information and the
tools just it's just a multiplication
with coil with a constant so L will be
learned so this will also leave visible
boy the rock cycle input out to peers in
addition to that this NL
ok and in the end we get on a low block
cipher encrypt Roxas and this will be a
lower more powerful attack ok so let me
move to the description that Universal
forgery the attack consists of two
procedures there are first sample
is to correct a set of random input
output pairs of a block cipher by just
using the minimal forgery with the
sample set of random nouns and the other
routine in cipher obtains rocks are
input-output pairs x 1 y 1 2 X my M
whose arbitrary chosen X I so these are
Lawson and to mountain low block cipher
access this is the possible by picking
some known I appeared from the leads out
of some prepared and the using we
thousand am an ass and a pair of now
said mask because NASA mask a
corresponding mask is known we just pick
a X I arbitrary here and observe the two
il to get an a corresponding plaintext
message here and from the decryption
encryption raka we learn the CI here so
we learned why I here okay also the
returns he'll abuse y one y sequence
okay so the goal of the universal
forgery is to simulate OCB to encryption
work Oh so we first set an arbiter
target and there are Odawa observer here
and call sample pairs and the core in
cipher to determine all we put out two
pairs of a block cipher that will happen
encrypting this target body with the OTP
to encryption and we will learn the seed
error here and the resulting in the row
adora see there are P Dora will be
accepted as buried and it will return
names in Deraa
which means that Ana success of the new
bus or forgery and as I'm after
activation data this third step needs
much boolean type of course because the
reason can be obvious from this picture
so the lower part shows the PMAC
paralyze of mac mode for in case of the
ad present and the upper part here is
the Oh Shiva to encryption so we need
first we first need to determine the
this mask out to burials using the
fasting cybercorps feature determine the
input to the deep blue boxes then we
learned from the output of the secondary
in cybercorps to date it enough to
determine the input to the dis green box
so in the end of the three and cypher
course are shown to be sufficient for
any target to mount a universal forgery
okay okay then we moved through the
applying text to recovery the attack
mode is here something similar to the
attack against the ANSI standard de mon
coeur de X Prime so first other words we
had some endurance Tourister sister
sister at an encryption unknown stir and
add worry Edward wreak an access to both
encryption on the decryption Oracle but
nonsense that can not be great to
encryption worker because it has been
used and not must be respected of course
there are trivial decryption query is
not our old we did restriction the
Gauri's to recover m stir okay the
attack idea is to swap the broke of a
sister to create some friction or so
that the decryption sideral with
nonsense to really build a master how
this is possible
okay here's the target ciphertext sister
here insta here and we first recovered L
star using the sample period and a
cipher as I explained in universal
forgery
then we tick certain J's and case
ciphertext Bob rocks and the sword with
some nasty are use as we already learned
Elster and swap them and decrypt it then
because of the masca counselled though
we see the swap of the block cipher in
put as well how these brokers were just
swapped so it will desert in the DD
print text Bronx JSON the case bro okay
because these offset here and to some of
the masks are equal they will be counted
in computing the checksum so this means
that these orange blocks
share the same input means the share the
same output that means that on a weekend
the decryption will be accepted we will
then we learn that these print text
blocks as we already knew that stir this
will mean the recovery of M star that's
a goal so this attack with almost
priority one well there are some
negligible we are bad events here but
it's just negligible okay
and then this other can be accepted to
some yeah directions and buttons keeping
here so in the remaining I would like to
describe how this happened who was it -
who are scheme or provable security of
course they are the flaw in the proof
yeah otherwise yeah this is not possible
so to understand this it's important to
understand that that all should be to
conscious over to tweakable block cipher
code called XE X and X see both using
the mask two times I said to mrs. J
times L as a function of a tweak in IJ
here and the XCX apprised mask for both
sides who are the how to achieve the CCA
security
well the XE applied the mask 0:02 only
the input the side okay for achieving
the F XI and these two modes are
combined by now introducing additional
bit of cheek called tag be here and be
Cobra means the use of the XE X and the
beaker zero means the use of the XE and
this combined mode is called a target eb
c XE extre okay and the definition is
here former definition is here and the
hole and showing the security of XE
exter rollaways paper the toggle
expecting of the buzzer is defined who
is an advisory and just forwarded these
are two conditions first the no
decryption query it's possible and B
core 0 because that means that the XE
cannot be accessed from the backward
direction and once a query with tweak of
BB T is made then never query the
complement to be with the same T for any
T and the ratio that XCX
Tereza Security BC against any yeah
computational restricted toggle
expecting other burglaries okay and we
introduced an intermediate scheme c2c b2
which is a century abstraction below c
b2 using the TBC so citrusy b2 so that
then i will she be to using the block
cipher e is a clipper into the citrusy
b2 using the XE a toaster using block
cipher e and with this equivalence there
we can build an hybrid for adult I did
awesome 5000 cb2 and this equation
showed that the security of all CB 2 is
essentially bounded by this salmon with
the security of XE a coaster for us the
security of the citizen is to using the
idea rights the tweakable block cipher
and Rorick Ram data this hybrid holds
for some Congress picnic advisory that
can simulate a but it turns to be wrong
simply long because as we have seen in
our minimal forgery it cos x DX star
with one tea and the tea for some tea
here that query by or it's a second
access rule hope Douglas peeking out the
bursary okay so that's it the
authenticity game who sees us the abused
xx turns out the role in the proof so we
have investigated their effect to
creating schemes of our attacks but yeah
this it turns out that our attack is
very specific to OCB to so the other
schemes are safe for example what should
be one or should be three are safe and
other related schemes such as oto and
OPP are also safe because they do not
use XE extra what they use the exist
about they are they do not misuse so we
can fix OC b 2 in steroids the most
obvious one is to apply the XE X instead
of X C for the last message block
the resulting skin also b2f it's
probably secure in your paper
the proof is our paper and it is secure
because it correctly use those extra
there are some other other options for
fixing but it means still some truths
yeah of course we can just avoid the
using or should be too busted by
switching it to the DCM over CB three of
course okay to conclude main message is
pretty simple over CB is a totally
broken
and seemingly small for in the proof
fled of the surprisingly powerful
attacks and the fortunately
unfortunately I'm not sure but attack is
very specific so not applicable to our
CP wide or should be sweet and I've
learned mentioned that the stress that
and a general structure was she be sleep
sound insecure what resin runs you so
simple even the most promising spew can
fail so creepy tree is hard okay and
every detail proof is very important for
assuring the whole security and activity
protein purification is important of
course proof verification for approval
security scheme is a usual little
rewarding but this time as a barre okay
that is Sansui attention
any questions you'll have to come to the
microphones near the stage please yeah
we we first found the gap in the proof
then we try to fit yeah we first believe
that what should be to secure Indian so
we try to put the proof pattern but
eventually we found or she be - yeah
insecure and that data story any other
questions
okay let's thank the speaker again
[Applause]