thank you so this is joint work with
Casper claim last in the SP buisness and
also from University and so welcome to
the other half of the world of NPC
information table secure NPC and in some
sense that this talk is going to be
about how different that half of the
world is from what Abby just talked
about and this point or I guess it is
indeed very different in in in in some
ways at least so as we all know
information to medically secure NPC
protocols there's a great low
computational overhead no afraid see
here best possible security guarantees
what's not to like but as we also know
they're not so great because you have to
have many rounds and large communication
complexity at least as far as we know
from the protocols that we know about
and a very important long-standing open
problem is whether that is inherent
those costs so so in this talk we we
have some of the answers the spoiler
here is that the communication it's
indeed inherent at least for some
functions but we don't have anything to
say about the rounds um so just to be
explicit about what is what do I mean by
communication overhead so one trivial
observation is that if you don't care
about security of course you can compute
any front any function with
communication complexity with the size
of the input you just send all the
inputs to one guy he computes the
function and then if everybody gets
output of course you should add the
total size of the output because he
needs to send the outputs back to these
guys but we'll only talk about functions
with very short outputs here also to
avoid cases where the communication
complains D is is large for trivial
reasons just because someone has to get
a large output we don't really want to
look at that so the question is if you
take the information theoretically
secure protocol must have communicated
more than the inputs nice it's the most
basic question there's also probably a
much harder question that says what if
the circuit size is much bigger than the
input size must you then communicate
more than the circuit size of the
function that's that's not something we
can say much about we can say some
things though but but it really is a
different question so our result so the
model first we consistently secure
protocols
synchronous network and passive security
Semyon security
we assume secure point-to-point channels
using the standard model here where the
length of the message that you send
always leads to the adversary this is
very natural because if you ever gonna
implement the secure channel you'll be
using whatever using you shouldn't
expect to be able to hide the length of
the message from the adversary there are
two months we can say that honest
majority where the number of players n
is 2 times corruption twice to all t
plus 1 and also dishonest majority with
pre-processing there can also get
information theoretic security and here
n can be T plus 1 while we show in both
models is that for any number of players
n and for infinitely many input sizes s
there exists a function f with input
size s bits so any protocol that
computes F securely has to communicate
at least some constant times n s bits so
that says that there has to be this
function did this factor n overhead
compared to the input size okay and
because it just to make sure this is not
because every player has to compute long
input because has to receive a long
output because the outputs are in fact
very small boys true it happens to be
the case that our functions have very
small circuits in fact linear size
circuits in the input size so the
results also therefore say obviously
that some functions require
communication n times the circuit size
of the function so what this means
intuitively at least is if you have a
general protocol construction that can
compute any circuit securely and if it
does the same the same approach to every
circuit whatever that means then it must
actually always have that factor and
overhead because it has to have it by
these results when it computes that that
function that we construct so in from
that intuition at least it seems that we
always talk with this with this overhead
here at least for the for the public for
cost that we know about for honest
majority we have a matching upper bound
n times the circuit size that's
motivated by the fact that previous
results were off by effects a log n for
circuits that say for boolean circuit
service over small fields for the
pre-processing model there was always an
upper bound shown in a paper from 2
and 13 by UCI eval so the upper bound is
n times s bits of communication
this requires exponential size
pre-processed data but if you can live
with that
then the pre-processing case this is
actually settled the answer is n times
input size good
so we also extend this to self optimal
try so okay so far majority
what about N equals to T plus s where s
can be greater than 1 so the question is
what is smaller now and then the bound
is what it was before but divided by s
now and this is nice because this
exactly matches what we can get from for
other balance using packed secrets yeah
so packed secrets and it's this
technique where you can share a vector
of sequence but this yes is still only
one field element and in this way you
can do a bunch of arithmetic operations
in parallel for the communication cost
of one essentially so this this this
gives smaller communication but but the
price is that the twice old must be
smaller the quatrain one must be smaller
and this exactly matches lists is this
know about that we get here okay so
before diving into how we do this we
just mentioned some some some related
worked as first of all this work by SIA
dial from 13 they prove lower bounds for
two parties in the pre-processing model
and and this upper bound for the
multi-party case that I mentioned then
there's a work by I think data and and
the prop cans they do a lower bound for
three parties and perfect security I was
actually the first results showing that
communication sometimes has to be larger
than the inputs but only that particular
case would three parties and so on
there's a work from yo crypt 16 myself
Nilsson Ostrovsky and and Rosen where we
saw a lower bound on the number of
messages so some functions require you
to send N squared messages everybody
have to talk to everybody else so to
speak this of course means you have to
send and squared bits also in particular
but that that's that's much smaller than
than than our lower bound when the
inputs are large and then finally there
is another work from 16 and where we
showed some lower bounds for gate by
gate protocol so those are protocols
that work the way we used to that you
compute a circuit you do every gate by
itself doesn't support
already one fairy multiplication gate
and for that class of protocol she would
get very strong lower bounds but of
course only for that class of protocols
and we want to do something for
arbitrary protocols okay so a starting
point for the results is to look at two
party private information retrieval so
just to remind you what is what that is
that's a server that's a client the
server has the bit string X the client
has an input in index I that points to
some position in the string X and they
talk that's a transcript T that's formed
and at the end of the day the client can
compute the ice bit of X while a service
not supposed to learn anything here and
and the only very well-known and
straightforward fact that I need about
this situation here is that if this
protocol is perfectly secure then from
the transcript the client can always
compute all of X no matter what about
the protocol does this is very intuitive
if you think about it I mean because of
the privacy requirement right if the
transcript misses information about some
part of X then the server could conclude
that that's not the part that the client
wants right so that this cannot be all
the way it has to be there somehow okay
so that that's the only thing I need you
to remember from this slide that in in
perfectly secure to body pier the client
can always compute the service input
from the transcript so now let's go to
the honest majority oh by the way I
forget this yes so in the following I
only talked about perfect security all
our songs hold for statistical security
also they're essentially the same you
take the perfect secure result and you
take a few small Epsilon's and subtract
here and there and then then you get the
results I will distribute small Epsilon
afterwards you can do it yourself anyway
so honest majority three parties it's
the first step
so the function we consider here is is
the following so there's going to be two
parties on top there's nu P and Luci and
they have each one bit string as input x
and y and Charlie Brown has no inputs
but gets the inner product of those two
bit strings as the output okay
and so we assume that there's a
perfectly secure protocol for the
product function which secure against
one passive corruption
good so you run the protocol and then
there is some messages sent between
party 1 and party - that's called t1 -
that that transcript there which you can
think about it as a random variable and
similarly we have t1 3 and T 2 3
that's inputs in the other two parties
so the first pretty obvious observation
is that since P 2 has no outputs should
learn nothing new from the protocol then
of course in particular t1 2 has to be
independent of X the input of the other
guy right because you're not supposed to
learn anything whatsoever this is
perfect security that's pretty clear so
then with that information we now
consider what's gonna happen if we run
this protocol with a particular choice
of the input Y so let's set Y to be the
all 0 vector except that's 1 in the ice
position ok so if you do this then of
course the inner product of x and y is
going to be the ice bit of X right
obviously so that means that we can now
construct ourselves a two party peer
protocol because we're simply going to
glue those two parties together there
and consider them as being the client
and then of course we have the snow base
that server has input X and now these
two guys together we'll learn the ice
bit of X with that choice of y ou but
what did we say about to party peer we
said that that from the transcript of
the protocol which in this case is t1 2
and T 1 3 the client can compute the
service at the service input X right so
it means that you can compute X from T 1
2 and T 1 3 however we just also said
that C 1 2 itself is independent of X so
from t1 - you have no idea what X is you
bring in c1 3 now all of a sudden you
know what X is so that means that T 1 3
must have contained enough information
to determine X right so therefore just
well Huntress intuitive it has to be at
least as large as X I should pass
mention for those who know about the
technicalities here what we actually
show he has bounced on the entropy of
say T t1 3 and this then implies that
the average communication her place
there must be at least the entropy but
that's that's a detail ok so that's fine
and then from this we can lift ourselves
one step what and do the the yeah okay
just this is two takeaway message from
this slide the guy who gets the output
must communicate a lot this is the only
thing you need to remember okay so now
the general case so here we have two T
plus one parties first we have like TN
connections of Snoopy they look an awful
lot like each other but that's a good
reason for this you'll see so they call
P 1 1 up to P 1 T we have also T Lucis
TPP 2 1 up to P 2 T and we have one
Charlie Brown which is P 3 so 2 T plus 1
parties all together okay and the inputs
that we have here is each party has each
of the top bro parties have a bit factor
as input again X 1 up to X T and also y1
up to Y T are also bit vectors and and
then in addition every party has one bit
as input okay then we b1 1 up to B 1 C
and and so on and and B 3 for Charlie
Brown okay and the way we define the
function is as follows so we define a
value Z which is you concatenate all the
X Factor's concatenate all the Y vectors
in you take the inner product that's
called set and then the outputs are
defined as follows each party gets as
output that in a product times his input
bit so the input bit selects whether you
learn something or whether you learn
nothing okay and now again the that's
that's the function that will prove a
lower bound for we assume the secure
protocol for this function that secure
against thicker options now okay
so again we're gonna hard coat the
inputs in a particular way so that
things will behave nicely
one thing we can do is we can set all
the bij so all the input bits for these
for these top row guys up there will be
0 and only Charlie Brown's input there
will be one it's the only one who
learned something in that case um so
then we can we can get to party protocol
from this right because we're gonna glue
all these Snoopy's together all the
Lucy's together and then Emma get a
three party protocol where because the
original protocol allows for T
corruptions then any one of these three
parties now can
corrupt so that exactly mirrors the
situation from the previous slide it's
exactly the same thing
so remember the guy who gets the output
has to talk a lot right so so in this
case when we hot code the inputs in this
way this guy must communicate at least
order s bits whereas it's a total input
size so the combined length of all these
vectors okay but we can enforce glue
parties together in all kinds of ways so
we can also do something else like we
can say let's set now B 1 1 2 B 1 so the
first inclination of Snoopy gets the
output and nobody else gets anything and
then we also said why want to be one
I'll tell you why that is in a moment so
now we glue plants together like this so
we glue all the t minus one lasting
condition so if no get together with
Charlie Brown and all the losers are
glued together now what is going on the
protocol of course computes the same
function as before namely it
concatenates all the X's all the Y's
does the inner product but now because
y1 is said to be 0 that wipes out in
fact effectively the x1 right so so what
it does is in fact it computes the inner
product of X 2 up to X T concatenated
and Y 2 up to Y T concatenated a little
bit shorter but it's actually the same
size as before so and and and that's the
inner product that the first incarnation
of Snoopy well get and now it's exactly
the same situation again as the previous
slide so so therefore ap11 numbers
communicate orders bits and as you can
easily imagine we can do exactly the
same thing for all the players
so therefore in conclusion what we get
here is that so suggest to summarize
what I just said for each party it holds
that I can hard code the inputs in a
particular way such that this guy gets
the output and that part in that case
must communicate some constant times s
bits but the point now is that the
communication pattern included length of
the messages cannot depend on the inputs
right because Peterson is model even an
adversary who cops no one will see
although the entire communication
pattern can can do traffic analysis and
that shouldn't reveal the inputs so that
means if sometimes some guy has to talk
a lot he has to do it all the time if
the fact but it talks a lot depends on
the inputs and it does here so so
therefore the total communication in
fact has to be I'm again in time such
bits okay
so note also that the function of course
this is just inner product so so you can
certainly compute that using order s
Elementary bits so the bound is also n
times the Circa size of the function s
as I promised before okay good so that
basically sums up what we do for the
honest majority case whether twice world
is full threshold for the for the case I
don't have time to talk in details about
the case of sovereign threshold and the
case of dishonest majority with
pre-processing it's basically very
similar ideas but slightly could
technically slightly different details
if you have I guess I can say that if
you have suboptimal threshold what
happens is that you can start gluing
parties together in small groups and
then you so so we kind of do the the the
transition from the multi-party case
that there's three fatty case which is
still what you would use to in in two
steps first you glue some parties
together then you get something which is
essentially full threshold for this
conglomerate of parties and then then
you go to the last step that was
probably not very clear but I think from
the paper has hopefully clear okay let's
talk about the upper bound so a Faunus
majority there is in fact this this
result from crypto oh seven well why I
showed with with video spinel sin that
any arithmetic circuit can be computed
with passive security and honest
majority in it for 2d was one big
communication that's order n times
circuit size field elements so you might
say but that that's exactly the lower
bound isn't it so there's already a
matching upper bound but there's a catch
namely that this only works if the field
size is larger than n
so if I want to compute the boolean
circuit say I can still do that with
that protocol I just need to run it with
an extension field I need to make it big
enough that that I can have n evaluation
points in the field and so this means
that I would have to put in a log n
factor into the communication complexity
of this thing for a boolean circuit so
if we can get rid of this thing by using
tool from last year there is something
called reverse multiplication friendly
embeddings that's something that that
appears in the paper by crane medallion
in crypto last year it's basically the
idea is that it's a way to take to
implement many parallel multiplications
in a small field by doing just one
multiplication in the bigger field so
basically what would you do is you take
your your two vectors that you want to
point wise multiply and you encode them
using a special encoding function into
two field elements in the bigger fields
then you multiply in the bigger field
once and you get something which
essentially encodes all these parallel
multiplication results that they wanted
so so then what we do is you combine
these two things you basically run the
old protocol from row 7 over the bigger
field and this then does what you want
essentially you have to do some
unpacking at the end but that turns out
to be only for one big field or method
you have to do something non-trivial so
so that basically gives you the the
corresponding upper bound ok so let me
go to open problems and field work
so there's ongoing work where we try and
be very happy to receive any inspiration
for this that it would be nice to have
lower bounds for also let's say
naturally occurring functions that is
functions that we haven't especially
engineered to be able to prove the lower
bound and and and them a my base in
which functions naturally behave in sort
of similar ways to what we engineered
here so that that would be interesting a
really tough question but also a
immensely interesting question is what
is the circuit size it's much bigger
than the inputs is there a lower bound
and the grows with the circuit size this
is a question of a completely different
nature than the one we had to resolve
which has to do with the input size I
mean for one thing if I give you a
function a bit for most functions we
don't even know where the circuit size
is right so without some kind of
assumption we will certainly get nowhere
here and even then I think it's it's
it's it's really totally different
techniques that you would need to do
this for the pre-processing model there
was this open problem left so the
existing upper bound says enzymes input
size
that's for optimal threshold and a c
plus 1 m but what if we have suboptimal
threshold then our bound degrades a
little bit it divides NS by this little
s that appears so this here gets divided
by there's a lower bound gets smaller
when this ratio get smaller and and we
don't know whether we have an upper
bound that can match that thing there
okay and finally something which used to
be an open problem but I think is now
actually closed so what about a lower
bound for perfect malicious security and
any it was three three three plus one so
you might think that okay Melissa's
security should be easy because that
implies passive security just apply our
bound and this doesn't work here because
the threshold here right there is is is
inferred and we do something for n over
two it's right so get smaller the
boundary great so if you go all the way
down to n over 3 our bond sells we have
essentially nothing so it turns out that
there is a different argument that
explicitly exploits the fact that we
have malicious security and it gives the
same result there are some details we
have to check but it seems to work out
and then you get the same result in time
circuit size as we have a passive
security and by coincidence which is
almost too good to be true the next talk
in the session coil it out will tell you
that that's exactly the upper bound so
that's that's quite amazing but yeah so
that's what I had but that I also think
for your attention
go ahead so you use the fact that the
communication channel leaks the size of
the messages do you think the bounce
still holds if you have some sort of
idealized channel that doesn't link I
think so
so do the bounce still hold if if the
message links do not leak I think I
think we were maybe a bit lazy I think
we can still prove something even
without that assumption then then we you
have to have an adversary that that
corrupts some of the players and and
watches what is being sent and I'm
pretty sure that could be worked out so
my question is the theorem statements
you said are about average communication
the average complexity of a protocol
right yeah so could it be that that
average is basically due to you know low
probability events having extreme
communication ie can you make a
statement about the variance and and
argue that there can't be some protocols
that are actually pretty good but their
averages are large for obscure reasons
that's a good question I don't have a
good answer to that that that would have
to be I think a different study I don't
see anything that we have in the paper
that will tell you directly what the
answer to that one great thank you even
[Applause]