thank you very much for the introduction
it's my great pleasure to be here today
and present to you my joint work with
Vinny le and Blackie I about continuous
space bound at non-mobile codes okay so
let me begin with a short motivation
imagine that you have a small memory
device that performs some cryptographic
functionality so that means that some
secret key is stored in the memory of
this device so on this example you can
see digital signatures and the security
property of digital signatures guarantee
that no one can forge a signature okay
but what happens if now an adversary can
tamper with in memory of this device so
it changes the secret key to some
tempered secret key Prime it turns out
and in this case some information about
the secret key can be leaked and even
enough information to recover this
entire secret key so the unfortunate e
would be completely broken in this case
so what can we do about it and we are in
the session of non moba code so we gonna
one way how to protect against memory
tempering is using a non mobile code for
this example for space bounded tempering
so roughly what would happen here
instead of storing the secret key on the
memory of the device we would store an
encoding of the secret key and as you
had heard from the previous speakers the
property the non malleability property
would guarantee that even if someone
tempers not with the memory no
information is leaked about the original
secret okay so a space bound the
tempering was first time considered in a
paper that was presented here in crypto
two years ago and what what is actually
space bounded temporary we restrict the
tempering function just by the resources
of the device
more specifically we say that the space
complexity of the tempering function and
the space complexity of the decoding
algorithm are bounded by the memory of
the device and this actually implies
that the tempering function can decode
and it's not so difficult to see that in
this case full normal ability is
actually impossible to achieve so to
this end the definition of leaky normal
ability was introduced where it's
allowed for the tempering to leak some
small part of the input just a small
part and for many applications this is
completely fine for example for leaky
resilient signatures okay so the prior
work introduced the January construction
generic space-bound at normal bar code
and it was based on non interactive
proof of space that was the main
building block however it had one
limitation namely that the size of
leakage was growing linearly in the
number of temporary rounds and this
implies the tempering is a priori
bounded why is this well we leak every
time for every tempering round we have
some leakage so eventually we would leak
the entire secret key so the protection
given by the non moba code would be
completely meaningless and what was less
as a open question is to achieve an
unbounded polynomial unbounded tempering
and this is exactly what we focused on
in our paper and what I will be talking
about today okay so our goal is to have
a space bound at non mobile code for
unbounded tempering and we actually
looked at the generic code construction
from the prior work and we kept the
construction at it as it was but we
instantiated it with a stronger building
block in particular we defined something
we call proof extract ability of proof
of space and we show two different
approaches how to construct such a proof
of space and we end up with several
construction that have different
parameters but I will tell you more
about that in my talk ok so before I get
to the code construction let me be a
little bit more precise about what leaky
non-mobile codes are it's not a formal
definition but just to give a high-level
idea okay so we have a coding scheme
that consists of encoding and decoding
algorithm and consider a polynomial
time algorithm polynomial time adversary
that is space unbounded okay so we have
no restrictions on space and it can
prepare a tempering function that can be
arbitrary but space bounded and this
tempering function now tempers way the
target code word C and tempers to a code
word c1 the adversary then learns the
result of decoding of c1 and we say that
our coding scheme is el leaked and non
malleable if there exists a simulator
that can simulate this tempering
experiment without knowing the original
secret but getting a small hint okay so
it can get L bits of leakage and then it
has to simulate the tempering experiment
this definition can be generalized for a
repeated tempering so after the first
round of tempering as you saw in the
previous slide that ver Sri is allowed
to pick another tempering function which
now tempers with this c1 to c2 and again
adversary learns the result of decoding
of c2 okay so now we are prepared to
have a look at the UH non mobile code
construction so as I said before it's
based on non interactive proof of space
so non interactive proof of space is a
primitive between two parties so we have
approver and a verifier improver has a
lot of memory and it wants to convince a
space bounded verifier about this fact
so what he do what he does he takes some
unique identity it generates a proof and
this generation requires a lot of space
and sends over the identity and the
proof to a verifier and the verifier is
able to verify that this is a valid pair
so that was just on very high level and
the code construction is now very simple
if we want to encode a message and we
just run the proof algorithm of the
proof of space we generate a proof and
our code word consists of the message in
plain and the proof attached to it the
decoding while we first parse the
codeword into a message and the proof we
run the verification algorithm which
does not require a lot of space right
that's the property that we get from the
proof of space and if everything is fine
me out put a message and otherwise we
get an invalid code word okay so before
I show you why this is a leaky non
mobile code and why we actually have
bounded tempering in this case we need
to have a little bit closer look at the
building block at the non interactive
proof of space or nipples for short
in particular let's have a look at the
soundness property order the property
that guarantees that prover cannot cheat
so if the prover does not have enough
space you should not be able to convince
the verifier right so how do we
formalize this it's a experiment or a
game and we again have a polynomial time
space and bounded adversary that can run
some arbitrary pre-computation so for
example prepare some identity proof
pairs and the adversary now prepares a
space bounded temporary function that
tempers with the target identity and a
proof and now if the result of temporary
is actually a valid pair then the
extract ability tells us that this ID
till dies either the original identity
or one of the pre computed values in
which case we are able to extract from
the pre-computation this ID tilde so
given a short hint we are able to
extract ID tilde or said differently
space bound that algorithm cannot
generate a valid proof for a new ID ok
so let's have a look at the code
construction rights actually leak in
unknowable so just a sketch of how a
simulator works there are many technical
details missing but just to give a
high-level idea so the simulator gets
the first temporary function and it asks
a leakage Oracle for a short hint and by
extract ability given this short hint
it's able to extract the identity so
it's able to extract this SK 1 and now
for the next round of tempering well it
does exactly the same it against asks
for a hint the leakage Oracle simulates
the tempering depending on the result
returns back a hint
we extract SK 2 and so on and so forth
so as you can see for every tempering
round every tempering we need 1 leakage
query and this is exactly why we don't
achieve unbounded temporary so this is
the problem in the private work so can
we do better and the answer is yes and
it lies in stronger proof of space so
what do I mean by that in particular in
our paper we define a notion of proof
extract ability and as the name suggests
we don't want to extract only the
identity but also a proof ok and that's
exactly what's happening here instead of
extracting only identity ID tilde we
also want PI tilde or if you look at it
differently we just want to say that a
space-bound that algorithm algorithm
cannot generate a new valid proof not
even for old IDs ok so the code to
instruction is exactly the same as in
the prior work but we have proof
extractable non-interactive proof of
space and this helps and this helps and
let me show you how so the first round
of temperent the simulator gets the
tempering algorithm again asks the
leakage Oracle to simulate the tempering
experiment inside and return back a hint
given this hint we are able to extract
identity and proof which means we have
the entire code word C 1 so fine the
first round we managed to simulate but
that was the same is in the prior work
as well but now comes the difference
when we get the second tempering
algorithm now we don't have to ask a
leakage query anymore we have the C 1 we
can just simulate the tempering
experiment without further leakage and
that's exactly what we wanted so as you
can see the number of leakage
it's now independent of no number of
tempering rounds okay so the big
question here is now okay how can we
extract proof extractable nipples and in
our paper we consider two different
approaches and I will tell you a little
bit about each of them I can
unfortunately not go in detail but just
to help give you an idea so let me start
with the uniqueness approach so we say
that nipples satisfies you uniqueness if
a valid proof like if the identity
defines uniquely you bits of a valid
proof okay so your bits are uniquely
defined and the N minus you the
remaining bits we don't know and it's
not so difficult to see that extract
ability and uniqueness together actually
imply proof extract ability so what's
the main idea behind it so if the result
of tempering this I detailed up hi Tilda
is actually a valid pair then by extract
ability we are able to extract this ID
tilde so I detail that we have so now
the question is how do we get PI tilde
by uniqueness or u uniqueness we know
the new bits of the proof so but we
still don't know n - view bits so in
other words if we get as a hint the hint
that we need for extract ability plus
the unknown bits we are able to extract
entire identity in a proof so obviously
our goal here is to come up with a
non-interactive proof of space this that
satisfies is high uniqueness as possible
okay full uniqueness would be ideal but
we want to achieve as high as possible
so first of all we looked at the prior
work and saw that the non turn
interactive proof of space had zero
uniqueness so technically yes we do get
approved extractable Nepos but with very
bad parameters so we also considered a
heuristic
construction based on memory heart
functions so let me give an a rough idea
how our approve algorithm actually works
so on input identity we first hash this
identity and then evaluate a memory
heart function that's a function that
requires a lot of space to compute so
this would be fine we have memory
hardness so it's the prover has to use a
lot of space but we don't have the
efficient verification so to this end we
actually run a verifiable computation to
produce a very short proof that the
computation was done correctly so that's
the high-level idea we get a partially
unique Nepos the details I refer to do
paper but I want to point out why did I
say heuristic where is the problem here
with this construction and it lies in
the memory heart function because we
have memory heart functions in the
random Oracle model or in our idealized
models but in order to run verifiable
computation we would need to instantiate
the random Oracle with a concrete hash
function so that's why this construction
is just a heuristic ok so let's have a
look at the other approach how to
construct proof extractable
non-interactive proof space in
particular from challenge hard crafts
that we introduced in our paper so here
i have to also give a small warning we
have to slightly weaken our ad versatile
model but in a realistic way and I will
show you in few slides what this means
or what I mean by this so first of all
in order to explain challenge heart for
us let's consider a directed acyclic
graph ok so we have a directed acyclic
graph and we have a hash function H so
if you want to computer H labeling of
such a graph we want to assign a label
to each node and we do it as you can see
on the picture for example this black
node if you want to compute the label
where we look at the labels of all the
children of this node
and we hash it together okay so now we
are prepared to actually explain what a
challenge heart crafts are so we
consider directed acyclic graph and we
divide the sinks of this graph in
several sets we call them target sets so
in the picture they're just too but we
randomly select one challenge node from
each target set and we say that a space
bounded algorithm can label all the
challenged nodes or all the challenged
nodes only with negligible probability
okay so the space bounded algorithm it's
very hard to actually label all the
challenge nodes and this should hold
even if some of the labels are given for
free to the space bounded algorithm not
all but some okay so how does this help
us to get proof extract ability
high-level overview of the construction
details are again permitted so we have a
hash function H that depends on the
input identity and we first of all
compute a labeling of our challenge
heart breath then we use a marquetry to
commit to this labeling and we hash the
route to generate randomness and define
two sets of nodes first set is so called
check nodes and the purpose of these
check nodes is to verify that actually
their labeling was done correctly so we
open we provide the opening path for
this node and its children and we check
that the local correctness of the
labeling the second set is the challenge
node so one node from each target set
and this is for the FIR guarantee that
it was memory harder and it was face
exhausting to do this computation so why
is this proof extractable just main idea
well either the adversary pre computes
the entire labeling and
rocketry so everything was precomputed
and in this case we are able to extract
ID tilde and PI tilde from the
pre-computation or the adversary did not
do everything in particular he did not
compute the route and did not have to
route so he did not know the challenge
notes and in this case we used the
challenge hardness to say that the
tempering algorithm has a negligible
success probability to answer all the
challenges correctly ok and here it's
actually important that the tempering
algorithm has a bounded description and
if we go back to the application that I
showed you at the very beginning
assuming that the description of this
tempering function can be absolutely
arbitrary might seem to be a bit of an
overkill so requiring that the
description of the algorithm is bounded
is not such a very unrealistic
assumption ok so what remains to discuss
is how do we get challenge heart graphs
what are they how do we get them so
first of all we looked at stack of
localized expander graphs from brandon
Devadas from 2016 and we extended the
construction to achieve noise parameters
for challenge heart graphs so high level
idea of the construction we group the
sings of the solo of the stack of locked
localized Express expander graph and we
put a gadget graph on top of each booth
you can see on the picture how each
budget graph looks it has several lines
and how do we now connect this gadget
craft to our sinks while we take the
first sink and connect it to the first
node in each line we take the second
thing and connect it to the second node
in each line and so on and so forth ok
so we also evaluate that graph
construction given by Paul and then
later used by
the Italian they're proof of space
construction and actually it shows that
they also satisfy challenge hardness in
fact with better asymptotic parameters
than the extension of sollux however the
constants are large so if we evaluate
for concrete security the extension of
Solex performs way better okay so we
have the I discussed now for different
constructions for proof extractable
non-interactive proof of space which
gives us four different constructions
for our non loaded code so let me
conclude my talk with a small overview
so what we wanted to do was generate
space bounded non mobile code
construction for unbounded tempering and
what we did we took the construction
from prior work but instantiated it with
proof extractable non interactive proof
of space and as you saw on the previous
slide there are four different
construction with different advantages
and disadvantages here you can see an
overview in the paper you can see both
asymptotic and concrete parameters and a
more detailed overview here is just to
give you an idea how practical or
impractical constructions are so if you
look at the first line the pipe which
represents the prior work we are in
order of terabytes it's not very
practical on the other hand if you look
at our memory heart function based
construction we are in order of
kilobytes so the gap is huge and
somewhere in between we have the
challenge heart graph constructions and
here you can also see that the Select
based one outperforms the original
construction from the proof of space
paper okay and what we leave as an open
question for further us a future work to
design a fully unique non interactive
proof of space because that would lead
to a memory to a non mobile code with
very nice parameters
okay so that's everything thank you very
much for your attention and I'm happy to
answer any questions questions Hey in
continues normal abort codes usually
there is this problem of self destruct
meaning that as soon as you get an error
you should stop but it seemed that you
never mentioned it yeah I did not
mention it but yes we do need
self-destructive that you need that
essentially always for continues yes we
do need self-destruct when you say the
bounder you bound the size of the
adversary what what is this like by a
constant or it's something it's I'm
sorry no I mean I mean all the
parameters depending on each other so
it's a parameter and of course you have
to think to the remains which is the
relative size well it depends on the so
it depends on concrete like which of the
constructions you take so we can talk
about details later okay thank you again
[Applause]