thank you very much for the introduction
so hi everyone I'm Lisa and happy to be
here today to talk about pseudo-random
correlation generators and why they're
useful this is joint work with the led
policy for cuto nifty boy usually
scientist all so the setting we're in is
secure two-party computation where Alice
and Bob want to securely evaluate a
function on the inputs without leaking
anything more than the function output
and this is great we know how to do this
for a long time but the problem is
always efficiency so one one way to deal
with this is to push the expensive
cryptographic part to an offline
computation phase which can be done long
before the inputs are known and then one
once the inputs are known the inland
face is very efficient and has lots of
nice properties but the problem is like
or now we kind of shifted the expensive
part to the pre-processing phase so in
particular even though the parties can
generate like generate this correlated
randomness that they need long ahead
they have to store it for a long time
and it requires lots of communication so
what we do in this talk is or what we
did in wood we did in this in this work
is how to significantly reduce the cost
for communication and storage and the
correlation I want to focus on today so
oblivious transport transfer we already
seen it in all the talks before today I
flee so I'm just to briefly recall
Ellison pop executes a protocol such
that LS learns exactly one messages of
Bob and Bob doesn't learn anything about
which of the two she learned and the
correlated random strings will look then
something like like the blue parts that
you see here where you have the input
and the output of Ellison Bob and those
strings have to be long typically to
compute circuits because why is that for
example if you consider the team W
protocol and you cry - Oh T spur and
gate so for like a huge circuit you will
need a huge number
of those correlated or teased and so the
problem so this is theoretical if you
have our team we can do this but this is
very expensive it's computationally
expensive because ot is it lives in the
public key vote so it's expensive and
this is already this already has a
solution
so the solution towards this is as we've
already also seen the first talk today
is a hybrid approach where you use a few
basic tees and then the rest you do with
cheap symmetric key cryptography and
this is super nice this solves the
problem from like a computational
viewpoint but still what I said before
we still have the problem that the
communication and the storage required
is linear in the number of or T's we
want to we want to generate and of
course this is inherent if we care about
chosen ot we're actually Alice and Bob
mmm chose their messages but for for the
setting we're in for a secure
computation we actually we actually we
actually find we just need this to be
random and as you like for example if
you if you think about computation
communication for communication if you
just care about random messages you
don't need communication linear in the
number of messages you can just exchange
a short seat for for P or T and then you
can locally extend and this is exactly
what we did in this work we got rid of
this part of the communication so um
this is what we call silent or T
extension where the extension is local
so and which will make the communication
in the storage sub linear in the number
of or T's to be generated and how do we
do this what's the tool to achieve this
so this is so-called pseudo random
correlation generators where Alice and
Bob have short correlated seeds that are
correlated in some way and then they can
locally expand them to get long
correlated pseudo-random strings and how
does this help us for what we want to
achieve well if you think about it
because the seeds are only short a few
our T's are sufficient we only need a
few at East
exchange the seats and then the parties
can locally expand them so without any
communication and then if we if the
correlation we have a PP cg4 is the OT
correlation then what the long strings
will be will be many many or T's that
then can be used in by the online face
that then can be used for efficient
online computation and what I want to
stress in particular is that a PCG have
the silent feature so the the only thing
communication is necessary for is the
short seats so in particular and the
storage and the communication now only
only depends on the seed size and not or
not on the M and there's no for
expansion there's no more communication
necessary so you can even for for a
multi-party for for protocols you can
even you can even do this with many
parties even if you're not sure if you
are if you will engage in a secure
computation in the future because all
you have to do is to store this very
short seat and there has been some
construction of PSG's around for very
simple correlations like multi linear
correlations from one-way functions
already since 20 years ago and there has
been also for more complex and
correlation there were constructions but
but but but not what not really
practical and the first one that was
like a complex correlation and practical
was was from from last year a vector
oblivious linear function evolution from
the learning parity with nice assumption
and yeah and this work actually builds
on built on builds on this work so what
we did in this work was we defined
pseudo-random correlation generators so
we formally define it for general
correlations we gave connections to
homomorphic secret sharing two-way
connections and we concrete constructed
like concrete constructions for
oblivious transfer from the learning
parody with noise assumption or more
generally constant degree correlations
we gave construction for one time truth
tables just based on
my functions and for low degree
correlations in the two-party in the
multi-party setting from either the
multivariate quadratic assumption or
again the LP an assumption together with
learning with errors or rings or the
symmetric external defy human assumption
and in the talk today I want to focus on
giving the definition of PCG for general
correlations and on oblivious transfer
from the learning party with noise
assumption okay so yes so how can you
define and pseudo random correlation
generators so you have two algorithms
you have a heat generation algorithm
that that generates short correlated
seeds and then you have an expansion
algorithm that you can use to that you
can use to expand like locally expand
those seeds to long correlated strings
and of course we want correctness so we
want these two strings to be correlated
in whatever like for example satisfy the
OT correlation that we care about in
this setting and we want security and
how we define security and is that we
want and basically how we define
security is to say that either party can
can learn nothing more from from from
their own see that they can trivially
derive from knowing that the long the
old long string will be in correlation
with the other party string and this is
not the most natural definition that you
can think of because we said we want to
use this as a as a as a replacement in
protocols for secure computation so more
natural definition would be a simulation
based definition to say like for every
protocol you can you can plug this in
but unfortunately this is impossible to
achieve we show this even even for
deterministic functionalities but we
also show that the definition we give
the indistinct service the definition is
good enough for like a a lot of
protocols
that satisfies slightly stronger
security requirement this is the case
for example the tmw protocol that I
mentioned also the speeds protocol so in
many you can actually just directly plug
this dis Buddhist in and yes
so we talked about the definition and
now the not now I want to give you a
construction how can you actually
instantiate this for the correlation of
of oblivious transfer so what we
actually will give is not a PCG directly
for abilities transfer but a PCG for
correlated or two oblivious transfer
which is exactly the same like oblivious
transfer but instead of having two two
unrelated messages but will the messages
of Bob will be always that the first
message the second message will be
always the first message plus some
constant offset and yeah then you can
rewrite LS messages as as being as being
the first message plus either this
offset or not and as it Shia Cillian
Issam and patterning showed if you have
correlated or T and you have a
correlation robust hash function this
actually gives you ot so the idea is
basically just you can have and then
this breaks the correlation and then you
have just a normal or T that you want
and so if you look at this and if you
refresh that like another way to say
what correlated ot is is saying so now
like putting many together so having
like a random vector we can say so so
Alice and Bob get a secret sharing of
this choice bit of Ellis times this
offset Delta so this is another way so
what we have to generate is actually
this kind of secret sharing additive
secret sharing so in order to two
together K the PCG for that we need a
compression of the vectors so we need a
compression of Q and B for Ellis and we
need a compression of the vector R for
Bob such that Q plus R is this Delta
times P and we will show how to do this
in
three steps so the first step is we use
so-called distributed point functions to
get a PCT whenever B is a unit vector
then the next step is actually the next
step is is just V so that you can
locally like it's it's super
straightforward to go from a unit vector
to response vector and then the
interesting part is once we have a
sparse vector how can we get to AB
pseudo random vector and so as I said
the main like the main tool for it for
the first part I distributed point
function so what is the point function a
point function is a function that is
zero everywhere exactly except at at one
single point where it will be some some
some value Y and the distributed point
function is just distributing the
function between two parties such that
the parties alone don't learn about what
the value alpha is and what the value Y
is but together they can recover so they
can locally evaluate every input X on
the keys to it to evaluate the output of
the function and if you like right as
graphically then then then if Alice has
this key K 0 and and Bob has this key K
1 they can expand it and by expansion
here I mean evaluating the point
function on every point of the input so
here we assume a polynomial input space
so that you can actually do this so you
evaluate on every point on the input and
then if you add it up you get a you get
the unit vector x times the Y at exactly
the position alpha and why why are the
superior point functions a good a good
starting point for two reasons first
years if there exists efficient
constructions from one my functions and
second by Derna and shallot and it's
it's possible to efficiently do a
distributed set up which will be
necessary to set up the seed that we
actually need to expand and once we have
distributed point function then the PCG
for unit vector you can it's it's it's
it's very straightforward so all you
give two parties is the keys for the
district
point function ELISA dish newly gets
this point alpha so she knows where it's
punctured and she gets the value Delta
blinded by their by the point of the
distributed point function and this will
be good for her to replace the output
value of the distributed point function
by Delta and so what the parties will do
so this is the this is the this is the
seed and then the expansion is simply
evaluating that this rooted point
function at every point Ellis will add
at the green part at the alpha part she
will add this y plus Delta and then
because of the properties of the
distributed point function we will have
that if you add up Q and R this will be
Delta times the unit vector and so so V
is this unit vector that is that is
alpha at this point so we have a PCT we
can expand we have a PC GFP is the unit
vector but of course we want more like
we won't be not to be the unit vector we
won't be to be a random vector in the
other so how can we go from how can we
go from a unit vector to torando make
the world's first a sparse vector and if
you take a look at the correlation again
this is a this is a linear this is this
is a linear term everything is linear so
only all terms so we have a secret
earring all linear operations can just
be performed in the shares so the
addition if we want we can just repeat
the same procedure T times and then add
it all up and L is a true output above
edster her his output up and then we get
we get the same for sparse vector and
then the interesting part is to go from
the sparse vector to the pseudo random
vector and for this we use the learning
parity with noise assumption which
basically states that if you have like
an over determined set of linear
equations or you have this matrix
product with a small secret vector and
then you add the sparse noise so the
noise is zero except for a few points
then this will look this will look
random and what we actually need is the
dual version of this where you multiply
the that the left kernel of this pink
matrix
and then you will see here in this
equation what it will do it will take a
random sparse vector and it will shrink
it a bit but then you get something you
will get something pseudo-random and
this is exactly what we what we want and
why why this is so useful for our for
our construction because again matrix
multiplication is something linear so
the parties can perform this linearly
there's no no no communication required
and the main challenge you have here is
now in terms of of computation because
this because this matrix is big it will
be linear in the number of our T's and
often if we're interested in in
generating 10 million Ortiz then this
will this will be a big matrix so what
we do is we use quasi cyclic codes where
the multiplication basically becomes a
polynomial multiplication so quasi
linear in the in the number of or T's
and the security that we get is similar
to post quantum crypto systems like
pikey bike or hqc and um something
something like I also want to mention so
LP n is some kind of symmetric style
assumption for two reasons so first of
all it does not imply a public key
encryption for certain noise rates also
noise rates were for our like which you
can use for our construction and second
of all it's very efficient so so again
we get an OT extension where it like we
only use symmetric style cryptography
and now just putting everything together
and the last step is to multiply so take
this this matrix and again just locally
apply it to to to to to to the the
results we have from the previous
operation and then and then we get the q
and the B and the R this will be
actually the output of the of our PC G
and by because we have correctness of
the distributed point function and
addition is linear and the matrix
multiplication is linear this will
actually give us what we want and even
though this might look I mean a bit
small now on slides what we get in the
end I mean this is it is a big
compression like we we have a bit of
shrinkage by the LPN matrix but but it's
instead of having if the output here is
and the the keys um what we need to
exchange so the keys are only our only
lambda malla times log n so we have we
have a we have a big achievement here
and yeah to come to a comparison to
previous ot extension protocols I said
in the beginning that what we have I
forgot that
if you do it with the addition you
actually also have to factor T because
you have to 2t times but if you compared
with previous or T extension protocols I
said it's linear the number of OTUs
but it's actually even worse if you look
at the concrete numbers the
communication is like for a single T
even a bid or T you you get something
like 70 at least seventy eight seventy
eight bits per Perot T and we bring this
down with this approach to two zero to
three bits per random random or T so so
significantly less and I'm like maybe on
the downside of having a logarithmic in
the number of n in the number of output
lengths number of rounds and we don't
have active security but actually both
of this we solve in a follow-up work
with together with Peter in DES
where we get it down to two rounds so
actually the first efficient two round
OT extension we back up the
communication with a with an
implementation so there we get zero
point one communication for random ot
for generating ten million or teeth and
we also get an get an active get active
security and what does it mean for the
team W protocol that we had at the
beginning so if you use the team W
protocol with for example the ikm P you
get more than a hundred bits per n gates
so with all previous approaches and we
print it down to four so four is
actually the cost of the online face so
we make and pre-processing almost for
free in terms of communication and on
the other hand so talking about
computation so our approach needs we can
generate
about a million ortiz per second so this
is slower than i can pee but over slow
networks because we have huge it's huge
saving in terms of communication will be
output form i can pee and so how to
conclude this talk pseudo-random
correlation generators are useful so
they give multiple secure multi-party
computation with silent pre-processing
we have a silent or t extension from the
learning party with noise assumption
which is concretely efficient and the
idea is you take few beso T's and then
you locally expand and the only thing
you need is symmetric symmetric style
crypto and we we also achieve like we
improved this to actually get the two
round or T extension and also malicious
security with with the same techniques
but but getting a better better setup
face basically and from what is also
interesting to mention what this line of
four gives it gives new feasibility
results and and practical instantiation
from learning parity with nice and and
this is interesting because because
because if a in particular for the
practical instantiation we're not we
don't know how to do is from from from
stronger from seemingly stronger
assumption like you like learning with
arrows so this is actually gives
something new and yes this is there's
lots of things to do a lot of operand
problems to work on so and we have
within our paper we give construction
for beaver triples for oblivious linear
function evolution and but they're not
as efficient as the OT construction that
I showed you so like can we can we use
similar techniques can we do things to
get to get it actually as efficient as
the OT construction what would be super
cool to achieve is a PCG where we don't
have to expand it all at once but only
expand it like however much much we need
to extend
and because like a big part or like it's
very central part to our construction is
learning parity with nice so so so
further further study the learning
parity with noise assumption which code
noise combinations are friendly RL pian
okay and friendly what is what is the
best way of implementing learning parity
with noise in large scale because
generally like people look more into
when you have where when you have a
smaller or smaller than smaller matrix
but we really interested we want to have
like as big as possible because then we
can get more Ortiz what is the best way
to do so computationally efficiently and
more from the theoretical side I'm
giving a generic LP n model because our
construction and it's of course not a
blackboard construction but it has some
black box flavor and maybe giving a
model where we can capture deflect black
box flavor of our construction so yeah
that's it for me so thank you very much
for attention
[Applause]
any questions thanks for the talk
so I was wondering and if you apply this
protocol to the gmw you get very small
communication the pre-processing can you
comment on the local computation cost
for the parties so the as I said so the
local computation cost you have you have
you have a million or T's per second so
we studied so for the so for and so
forth T extension like if you just
consider the if you just consider the ot
extension part four in our follow wake
up work if if you do this over like over
over white area network with 10 megabyte
megabits per second you get almost 50
times improvement so even if you if you
factor in the the the computation you
can get improvements over like replacing
I can people can Anna as a second so um
you mentioned that for the LPN you used
quasi cyclic code for the improvement so
I was wondering like why does it not add
another coding Theory like coal-based
cryptography assumption but so does your
protocol security still reduces to LPN
itself with with no additional code base
cryptography assumption that is secure
for you using this kind you for using
this kind of code so as I said it's
similar to the assumption that that
people post like quantum crypto system
so it is is it equivalent to playing LPM
or is it not it's it's no it's not so
for for random matrices so that's not
equivalent
ok thank you
yeah let's thank the speaker again and
ever
[Applause]