hello all right thanks for the
introduction so today I will be talking
about explicit rate one non-medical code
for local tempering so this is joint
work with stevia Gupta and Hamato mochi
so let me first tell you what it's now
edible code so you have already seen
some of this from Marshalls talk but let
me just quickly review remind you so
nominal code is a primitive introduced
by it's in box keep itraq and weights
back in 2010 so this primitive is
originally motivated by tempor resilient
cryptography so imagine you have a
signature schemes where the anniversary
might be able to temper the internal
state of the Challenger and then obtain
a signature under some temper the secret
key and then try to forge the signature
under the original secret key under such
tempering attacks the classical security
guarantee of signature schemes does not
say anything about whether the
anniversary could succeed or not so the
idea is that if we use now malleable
code to encode a secret key this could
help preserve the security of the
signature schemes even in the presence
of such tempering attacks so intuitively
now malleable code is a coding scheme
such that if some tampering happened on
the code word then a tempered code word
either encodes the original message or
some messages completely unrelated with
the original message specifically let's
say you have a message that is first
being encoded and then tempered by some
function f and then you gets a tempered
code word and then you decode this
temporary code word to get a tempered
tempered message so we want to say that
to this tempered message message Toyota
could only be related with the original
message in three following ways the
first way is by identity function
meaning that the tempered message is
identical to the original message the
second way is a special symbol but
simply means that the tempered code word
is an invalid encoding and finally the
server way is a constant function
meaning that this tempered
message is being fixed to some constant
no matter what the original message is
more formally now variable code ensures
that for this tempering function f we
can we have there exist a simulator that
outputs a distribution over these three
types of functions such that the
distribution of the tempered message in
the real world is indistinguishable from
the simulated distribution so note that
this simulator only takes the tempering
function as the input and it's oblivious
to the original message so if you think
about this definition for a while you
will quickly realize that this tempering
function can now be an arbitrary
function the reason is very simple so
since this is the coding schemes the
tempering function can always first
decode the code word first and then flip
a bit of the message and then reading
codes in this way the tempered message
message Tara will always be the original
message with one bit flipped then there
cannot be any simulator that simulate
this process therefore now variable code
is always defined with respect to a
fixed set of tempering functions and
just like error correcting codes we
define the rate as lens of the ratio
between the length of the message and
the length of the codeword so higher
intuitively high rate here implies that
overhead of achieving now variability is
low so since the introduction of nominal
codes after many years of research we
find that nominal code is actually
closely related with many other
primitives in crypto for example in a
field of privacy amplification we have
this primitive called numerical
extractors and turns out that normally
board structures and now malleable codes
are very closely related and we have
many excellent research going on in this
area next in the setting of multi-party
computation we also have fun
constructions of nominal commitments
using now variable codes as building
blocks
in relatively new primitives called now
malleable secret sharing many of those
constructions of nonmetals extracts no
malleable secret secret sharings also
use no malleable code as a building
block so the research objective of this
line of research is to find explicit
construction of no malleable codes with
high rate against the sophisticated
tempering families so high rate directly
translate into high efficiency in those
applications and reductions and as a
sophistication of such tampering
families implies a stronger security
guarantee so in this talk we will be
focusing on local tempering so let me
first tell you what is local tempering
using a very simple example so here you
are we have a code word that consists of
four bits a 1 2 or so for this tempering
function we'll take this 4 bits as input
and output a tempered code word so here
the first input bit well depends on the
first output bits will only depend on
the first input bit and a second input
bit and the second output bit will
depend on the first input bit and
asserting prove it and so on so we say a
tempering function f has staudte output
locality if our output bits depends on
at most Delta input bits so here in this
example here every output bit depends on
precisely two input bits so f has F has
two out for locality analogously we say
that F has delta input locality if every
input bits influence on at most Delta
output bits so in this example here the
first bit actually influence on order
our output bits therefore this function
f has four input locality so we see a
tempering function f is that a local if
it has Delta output locality so do note
that for Delta local tempering functions
this function can actually have
arbitrarily large input locality just
like this example here
and the this fact actually turns out to
present significant technical challenges
when designing now variable code so in
this work we gave a compiler that
compiles a low rate nominal code into a
rate one normal code so specifically for
any constant C between zero and one we
gave a compiler that compiles a low rate
nominal code against local tampering
with an appropriate leakage resilience
property into a rate one now variable
code against this constant C times login
local tempering so boy it all gives the
first feasibility result of nominal code
against a local tempering our compiler
instantiated with boy dose construction
gives us a rate 1 now variable code
against C times log and local tempering
and as a corollary of our results we
obtain a rate 1 now malleable code
against NC zero tempering this is
because NC 0 tempering is all a
tempering with constant locality so to
give you a broad detailed comparison
when the locality is a constant or NC 0
tempering boy at all's construction has
a rate has constant rate while our work
has rate 1 when the locality goes beyond
constant and is smaller than the
threshold we set here our boil off
construction has a decaying rate while
our work still has Ric 1 when the
locality goes beyond the logon boy dose
construction at the rate of their
construction has is linear dependent on
the inverse of the locality
unfortunately our work does not extend
to this case so as a very cool
application of normal code against local
tempering boy at all can construct
nominal code against AC 0 tempering so
in this application here they actually
requires the building block the now
malleable code against the local
tempering to have a very high locality
so our work here does not improve the
rate of their there
easy tampering here so before I go into
our compiler let me tell you a bit more
about what do we know about now Matabele
code against local temporary so we have
very nice multicolored constructions
that tells us when does no malleable
code rate one available code exists
based on how large the tampering family
is such multicolor constructions implies
construction in the common reference
string model so firstly first at all
tells us that when a tempering family
has size 2 to Napoleon read one nominal
code exists and moreover their
construction is efficient when the
tempering family size goes beyond that
and it's actually 2 to D 2 to this small
of n Jairaj and guru Swami's results
tells us that even in this case rate one
nominal code still exists however their
construction is inefficient so a quick
calculation will show you that for a
delta local tempering family the size of
this family is roughly two to the two to
the delta x n so if you plug in doubt
err with order of log n forces also
result tells us that efficient rate when
nominal code exists in this case when
Delta goes beyond logon and is still
small of n th include Swami tells us
that read 1 now Mabel could exist
however it remains unclear if efficient
Nam Rick one now medical code exists in
this case so as a reminder our work here
shows that we can get a explicit
efficient read 1 nominal code when Delta
is smaller than as some constant times
log in so before our work in a plane
model all the known explicit read 1
constructions are actually against
functions that has implicit one and out
for locality one such tampering families
is referred to as speed level tempering
the Lee in the literature
so now let me tell you about our
compiler so fix any constant C between 0
and 1 our compiler will use the
following ingredients with appropriate
parameters first we'll be using error
correcting secret sharing scheme that
has rate 1 and the near linear distance
and also near linear independence such
error correcting secretion schemes could
be based on standard reed-solomon code
secondly we will be using a base now
variable code that is secure against
order of logon local tempering so this
the base numerical code could possibly
have very low rate and it's risk we in
addition to now malleability we require
to be resilient to a constant fraction
of leakage finally we will also be using
a pseudo-random generator against a
finite state machine by Nissen so we
remarked that other alternative pseudo
random objects potentially also suffice
here so given these three ingredients
error correcting super sharing schemes a
base numerical code and as suitable
pseudo random objects our compiler will
use these three ingredients in a
blackbox way to cut output a rate 1 now
valuable code against the C times log
and local tempering families so our
construction draws inspiration from the
following two components the first is a
rate amplification techniques by agraja
at all and second is a PRG techniques by
boy doll so let me tell you a bit about
both of them so ago I had all
constructed a rate 1 numerical code
against a bit level tempering so here is
just a very simple example to of what a
bit level tempering looks like so such
functions has implicating 1 and output
locality 1 so their compiler is
constructed in the following way so
given any message the first day first
encoded this message using error
correcting secret sharing scheme to
obtain
Cold War a next they were sample a
subset of those indices from codeword a
and for roughly half of those indices
they intentionally introduced arrows
into this codeword and for the other
roughly other hub half of those indices
they will keep those bits untouched next
they were encoded this consistency check
information using a base now malleable
code so their final code word consists
of two parts the main code were C and
the main code word C which is error
correcting code with arrow introduced
and then attack which contains excuse me
contains the consistent track
information so to decode this code word
one first decode the Irani a--'s error
correcting code and then cross-check the
information of those arrows with the tag
to see if if they are consistent so
unfortunately there are techniques here
does not extend to tampering functions
with high include locality x-ray they're
comparators not even extend to functions
with improve locality too
so in order to deal with this technical
challenge we use a PRG technique by boy
door to circumvent the technical
challenges posed by input bits with high
improve locality so on a very very high
level imagine you have a code word that
has two parts the left part and the
right part so this techniques will keep
the left part as it is and then hide the
right part among many many redundant
bits and the position of those right of
those informative bits from the right
part is hide among this string pseudo
randomly so using this one can argue
that it is very unlikely that an
informative bits from this string
actually have a high input locality so
this property turns out to be very
useful for proof so given so our
compiler first forced the framework by
Ogawa at all
we also encoded the message using an
error correcting code and then
introduced some arrows and also keep
some bits untouched and record this
information user base nominal code and
after that we will be using a PRG to
hide this in this attack among among
random amount a list of strings that
contain both the redundant bits and the
informative bits from the tag
so our final codeword consists of three
parts the main code word which is error
correcting code with arrows introduced
then a seed for the PRG and in this
string here that contains both redundant
bits and informative bits from tag so
the length of this code word is roughly
the same as the length of the main code
word so let me give you a very brief
sketch of our proof so our proof roughly
falls from the from the following way so
we first argue that the tampering
happens on the tag is actually
independent of the message here then
given this observation we we can see
that the tampering on the attack either
keeps the consistent track information
identical or fix this consistent track
information to a constant so this is
given by the property of the base
inaudible code so finally our prove our
intuition is that if the adversary keeps
this tag identical then the owning valid
tampering is to also keep the main code
word identical conversely if the
adversary
fixed the text to be some constant
string then the only valid tampering is
to also fix the main code over to some
constant so the idea is that if the
reverse rate does not temper this code
word in this way then with probability 1
- 1 - negligible he was always he will
always fail the consistency check so the
harness of this proof completely lysing
how do we prove this intuition so
unfortunately I don't have time to go
into the
tells of this proof I would we have to
discuss this offline and I will end my
talk here thank you thank you questions
yeah you said that there was a previous
result that supported log locality I
think one of the authors was Faust yeah
it was efficient so can you explain
again what is the data so they show that
it's a probabilistic construction they
show that actually with probability 1
they're probably construction will be
secured against that tampering family
however they we cannot dear analyze such
multicolor construction it's not an
explicit construction no it's not a
specific yeah more questions let's thank
the speaker
[Applause]