so welcome everyone so I'm gonna talk on
homomorphic time love puzzles and
applications so let's move straight to
what the primitive is so time love
puzzles the concept first originally
emphasized in 93 and later proposed by
River Shamir and Wagner in 96 is
basically Alice choosing to have a
solution embedded inside a puzzle and
giving it to Bob and Bob takes this
puzzle and tries to solve it for some
amount of time that's T and eventually
obtains the end solution that was
originally embedded okay so what are the
properties of such a time lock puzzle it
requires this to considerably faster in
generating this puzzle meaning that she
takes much shorter time than T that is
required to solve it and as a security
requirement Bob when he tries to solve
the puzzle and no matter how much amount
of parallel computation power he uses he
cannot solve the puzzle before time T
and this primitive has found
applications and wide ranging spheres
namely sealed bid auctions fair contract
signing zero-knowledge arguments non
malleable commitments and so on and so
forth so let me introduce some formalism
for the primitive we have two algorithms
that's the first one's the puzzle
generation that takes the solution the
security parameter and the timing
hardness as input and it outputs the
puzzle right and there's the solve
algorithm that takes the puzzle and
eventually outputs the solution that was
embedded in it and as efficiency we
would require the puzzle generation to
run in poly log T where T is the timing
hardness while the solving algorithm has
to run in poly log poly T okay and the
security requirement is that for any
depth T bounded adversary a puzzle
that's generated with solution SC
is indistinguishable from a puzzle
that's generated but solution is one
okay there are two known constructions
so far for time lock puzzles the first
one from 96 it basically relies on the
sequentially squaring a group element
from Zn star note that if the order of
500 order Phi n of Zn star is known it's
easy to compute the result here by
simply computing 2 2 over 2 power T
lambda and doing a reducing it mod Phi
of n and then encrypting the message as
shown here and if the order of the group
is not known that is Phi of n is not
known then the only way to decrypt the
message from this ciphertext is by
taking the X and squaring it
sequentially for to power T times and
this the security relies on the
sequential squaring assumption where it
says that depth T adversary cannot do
better than simply sequentially squaring
it and then recently by baton scale we
had a construction that's based on
succinct randomized n coatings where
program that does nothing for T steps is
is what is inside the encoding and
thereby you get the time parameter that
you require for a third log puzzle and
it relies on indistinguishability
obfuscation okay
time lock puzzle the reason it has found
many application in for example in
sealed bid auctions is that it proposes
a solution for fairness for some notion
of fairness which I will show you let's
consider a seed with auctions where
there is the bidding phase where the
bidders embed their bids inside time
lock puzzles and broadcast into the
network there are two ways to open the
time lock puzzle the first way is the
bidder simply reveals the random coins
that he used to generate these puzzles
thereby
revealing the bids directly and the
other way is if if there are some
bidders that are not revealing the coins
you can simply use the solving algorithm
to solve these puzzles and obtain the
bits that were embedded now notice that
one way or the other all the bits have
been recovered and now with this
information you can announce the winner
notice that the fairness that is
guaranteed by time-lock puzzle is that
before announcing the eventual result
you consider every party's input or in
this case every bidders bid okay but
there are some limitations to time lock
puzzle namely the first one is that if
you want to ignore a time lock puzzle in
the hope of saving cost and solving it
you basically compromise correctness of
the application and this could lead to
for example in the sealed bid auction
case this could lead to bid suppression
attacks where an adversary selectively
suppresses some puzzles saying that he
wants to save cost right and in the
other extreme when you have a large
number of time lock puzzles involved in
a computation this means that an
adversary could force regular innocent
players in the system to solve like in
this case 10,000 100,000 time love
puzzles this which could prove
computationally prohibitive okay so the
conclusion is that time lock puzzles
suffer from a scalability problem which
actually hinders their practical
adoption in many real-life applications
so we our goal was to solve this very
problem so consider the traditional
approach where you solve the puzzles for
some time T and then you learn and you
compute the result here we propose an
alternate paradigm where you basically
homomorphic homomorphic compute on top
of the puzzles and then you obtain the
embedded result that desired result that
you want from the application notice
that this compute phase happen should be
efficient
for this approach to work all right so
let me just drive in the fact by showing
how this would work in the sealed bid
auction case before like before we have
the bit phase where bidders embed their
bids in puzzles and then you have a
computer phase where you take all these
puzzles compute on top of them which
results in a single puzzle with some bid
embedded in it and you you try to solve
this puzzle now note that instead of Phi
you just have one puzzle to solve
eventually after time T you obtained the
bit the bid B that was embedded in this
final puzzle which happens to be the say
the maximum of all the bits that were
originally but in the bidding phase with
this information now you can eventually
announce the winner of the auction all
right
it's time to to highlight our
contribution so we form we formally
propose the notion of homomorphic time
lock puzzles give candidate
constructions for different
homomorphisms and also identify key
applications so we identify three we
give three constructions namely for
linear homomorphism multiplicative
homomorphism and as a feasibility result
we show fully homomorphic time a puzzle
and as applications go we have we
identified Evo ting and multi-party coin
flipping for our linear linear
construction contract signing for the
multiplicative construction and notice
that with the fully homomorphic you
could achieve all these applications but
we care for practical efficiency there
why these constructions actually make
sense to realize the other applications
all right just to just to clarify how
this fh TLP plays against G notice that
fhe is for as hard it's considered hard
for probabilistic polynomial-time
adversaries depending on the setting and
FH TLP is hard for an arbitrary depth e
adversary
while fhe saves communication cost in a
in a multi-party computation fh TLP is
aimed at saving both communication and
computation cost and you would require a
secret key eventually to decrypt the
final result of the fhe while in FH TLP
the final result of the evaluation
becomes public after some time T all
right so as far as formalism goes for
homomorphic time lock puzzles it
inherits the two algorithms that's the
puzzle generation and puzzle solving
algorithm from the native time lock
puzzle we additionally have a set up
algorithm that takes the timing hardness
and outputs some public parameters and
we would like to emphasize that this set
of algorithm is a one-time setup and you
can consider the public parameters as
being a common reference string if you
may all right and then you have the
homomorphic evaluation algorithm that
takes the circuit of interest and some
puzzles and computes on top of these
puzzles to output resultant evaluated
puzzle as far as efficiency goes we have
the set up algorithm that runs in poly
log T and you have the evaluation
algorithm that runs in poly the size of
the circuit of interest here okay so our
correctness definition basically says
that if you try to solve an evaluated
puzzle with overwhelming probability it
it should result in the circuit being
evaluated on the embedded solutions and
the solving algorithm when it operates
on a evaluated puzzle is the running
time is bounded by some p over the
timing hardness T and then you have the
security definition which is quite
similar to what we had for normal time
lock puzzles which is saying that
homomorphic we generated puzzle of the
solution s0 is indistinguishable from
puzzle with embedded result s1 for a
depth T bounded adversary
and then you have a compactness
definition that says that the size of
the evaluated puzzle is bounded by some
fixed polynomial on on the output on the
size of the output of the circuit on the
embedded solutions here all right let me
directly go into our linear homomorphic
construction which is fairly simple we
have this set up algorithm that
basically chooses RSA modulus n as shown
here and it generates a generator G
which is the generator for the group J n
which is the set of all elements from Zn
star with Jacobi symbol passes +1 it
generates H over here which we can call
a partial puzzle notice that this
computation can be sped up because we
know the factorization of n so this to
power T can be computed fast and the
resultant H can be computed much faster
than what it would require to solve and
then we output the public parameters
with whatever we computed here all right
and then you have the puzzle generation
algorithm that basically ok ok ok so the
puzzle generation algorithm chooses a
random R which which acts as a
randomization factor and it outputs the
puzzle you components u and V where
notice that this the component B is
reminiscent of the Pylea crypto system
ok and then you have this solving
algorithm that takes the the puzzle UV
and takes the first component you and
sequentially squares it to obtain this
blending factor and eventually obtain
the solution s notice that the
correctness of this solving algorithm
follows the banana binomial expansion as
as SN the pile your crypto system the
evaluation algorithm ok ok the
evaluation algorithm is fairly simple
you take several puzzles you multiply
the components of each of these puzzles
to obtain the eventual
evaluated puzzle here the security
argument depends on the following
assumptions you rely on strong
sequential squaring assumption that
basically says that the adversary in
this case has knowledge of the group
structure ahead of time and this
assumption has been made in recent works
then you rely on the DDH assumption over
J n which is the Jacobi symbol plus 1 of
state and star and then you rely on the
BCR assumption that is the decisional
composite residue asset the assumption
ok let me jump into an application
that's Evo ting for our linear
construction notice that here we are our
model the adversarial model is basically
a semi malicious model and this this
model could potentially be relaxed if if
we use non interactive zero knowledge to
prove the well form nests of puzzles ok
so in this case we have some set of
candidates five candidates and there are
some voters here and they would like to
vote for the candidate note that if it's
a one it's a word for this candidate and
if it's a zero it's not a word for the
candidate so the voters decide their
woods and they embed these boats inside
time-lock puzzles and broadcast it to
the network note that the the channel
here happens to be anonymous so that the
voters are not identified is it the case
that we have to solve for T puzzles
hopefully not and this where the our
linear construction jumps in what we do
is we basically take all the puzzles
that are corresponding to a candidate
homomorphic lee evaluate on top of that
to obtain the resultant puzzle which
gives us these puzzles for the
candidates well notice that the the
total number of votes garnered by this
candidate is embedded in this evaluated
puzzle for each candidate here okay
now you only have five puzzles to solve
instead of 40 right and after the
solving phase you obtain the tally of
each of each candidate and you
eventually announce the result you could
also gain public verifiability if you
run this voting on top of a public
ledger like blockchain where any user in
the blockchain system can potentially
solve puzzles we don't need a trusted
authority to do the tally okay the other
application for our linear construction
is multi-party coin flipping here the
users embed their randomness inside
puzzles and broadcast them among
themselves
we homomorphic lis compute on top of
these puzzles to obtain a resultant
puzzle that's that has T here notice
that instead of having 4 puzzles to
solve now you have just one and after
solving after spending time T solving
this puzzle you obtain the result of the
coin toss that you want to do computer
originally here it's it's a linear
combination of the randomness that were
embedded originally ok so let me now
briefly show you our multiplicative
construction the set up algorithm
follows the same as in our linear
construction the puzzle generation is is
reminiscent of the el-gamal system here
and notice that this this this
construction of mhm TLP can be extended
to XOR homomorphism if you encode the
solution s this way by having it as -1
power s and the S is nothing but 0 or 1
bits and then you have the resultant
puzzle here the solving algorithm
similarly takes the first component
repeatedly squares it and then unblind
the unblind from the second component 2
to achieve the solution the the
homomorphic evaluation algorithm is is
the same as what we had for LH TLP you
take different puzzles and you multiply
each component of them correspondingly
to obtain the evaluated puzzle all right
the security argument
we rely on assumptions as we had before
the strong sequential squaring
assumption and the bdh assumption over
JN and we can prove the security of our
MH DLP construction okay as an
application of our MH DLP let me show
you the multi-party coin contract
signing case consider that we have we
have RSA aggregate signatures where
these signatures are elements of
quadratic residue and and the
aggregation algorithm is simply taking
the signatures and multiplying them
together and reducing it to modulo N and
consider the case that this aggregated
signature happens to be the valid
signature on the contract okay so in the
the process runs and rounds so in the
first round each user signs the document
and embeds the signature inside a puzzle
of hardness T which happens to be the
timing hardness for this round and
broadcast the puzzle to everyone and in
each successive round the players embed
their signatures and new puzzles of
hardness that is half the hardness of
what it was of the previous round
so namely T is nothing but TI minus 1
over 2 if at around if an adversary
fails to broadcast a puzzle the other
users can come together homomorphic
evaluate the puzzles that were in the
previous round to obtain a resultant
puzzle which has the embedded aggregate
signature in it after solving for time T
J minus 1 which is the hardness of the
previous round they can obtain the
aggregated signature while the
adversarial player can obtain it in half
a time as the Honus guys ok
there are some extensions of homomorphic
time block puzzles that we proposed in
our paper one of them being that we can
indeed homomorphic evaluate on top of
puzzles of different timing hardness
consider the case that t1 is greater
than t2 and if if the difference in the
timing hardness between them is of this
structure we can natively combine these
paths
in this manner I shown here okay finally
as a feasibility result we show the
construction for FH TLP which is based
on probabilistic IO which was proposed
if it was used in a kinetic at all in
2015 to construct fhe
here the the puzzle of the puzzle is of
the form a ciphertext and a normal TLP
puzzle and to solve this puzzle you
simply ignore the first ciphertext and
you solve the resulting time out puzzle
here for homomorphic evaluation we have
an obfuscated program that's output in
the setup that basically performs the
the operation that we require so it
takes in two puzzles decrypts this eye
protection in this case and computes an
and of the the underlying messages and
generates the resulting evaluated puzzle
the security follows from
sub-exponential IO and sub-exponential
one-way functions and the applications
apart from being we can do all the
previous sighted applications we can
also do sealed bid auctions with our FH
DLP construction to conclude my talk our
homomorphic time lock puzzle HT LP
scales well in in multi-party settings
and actively prevents denial of service
attacks we provide we provide three
constructions for different
homomorphisms linear multiplicative and
for any polynomial size circuit
evaluation and our LST LP and MST LP
which are the linear and multiplicative
constructions are quite efficient for
practical purposes because the
homomorphic evaluation is just
multiplication of group elements and as
future work we identify development of
application specific proof of well
formless having a efficient trustless
set up and building FH TLP from
practical for building FST LP from
practical primitives as future work and
[Music]
already we have Malo Volta with my
co-author has a follower paper on FX DLP
from standard assumptions alright so if
you have questions we are in the
audience please ask us thank you thank
you for listening if you have a question
please come to the microphone hi
so for applications like auctions and
coin-flipping
are you going to end up with the thing
where the different input can now depend
on each other so if you bid B can I bid
B plus one by homomorphic Lee changing
your time lock puzzle okay so we don't
do we don't go into the detail of how
you authenticate your bids how you
authenticate your puzzles and things
like that so so my bid is because you
can in a complete system you can
consider my bid to be authenticated with
my signature and evaluating on top of it
and calling it your bid probably is
could be prevented through measures that
we don't deal with in our paper here
yeah more questions
okay this speaker again
[Applause]