whoo thank you so much for inviting me
here I'm this is the talk is going to be
about contextual integrity as you can
see and I'm so delighted to be here
because I'm absolutely convinced and
more and more convinced that the privacy
problem that we're all confronting today
is not going to be solved by one
discipline alone and the the only way we
will get a handle on it is if multiple
disciplines and even within those
disciplines multiple fields will come
together and engage and hopefully what I
strive to do in my own work is to create
some sort of bridging between the
philosophical and ethical discussion and
though to law on the one hand loan
regulation and also technology on the
other and I've had really the good luck
of working with some fantastic computer
scientists both on the theory side and
on the more systems applied side and so
I really look forward to engagement I
should say I'm a philosopher you heard
I'm a philosopher in my PhD and
philosophers find it to be a failure if
you present something and nobody
disagrees with you so I'm going to try
and leave the hope is that I would leave
about 15 minutes at the end of the talk
so that we can engage in and you should
please feel free to ask questions and
debate what I'm saying I have just
arrived from oops how do I do that
it's not responding
we're oh I'm sorry I didn't switch it on
theory of contextual integrity and I
just came today actually last night from
a small symposium that now we have we've
had the second symposium on contextual
applications of contextual integrity
where I was really delighted to see that
people came from different disciplines
and brought different methods and we
were continuing a conversation about
that and pushing out some research and
in the talk I'll kind of wave her hand
to some of what we've been doing some of
which I'm involved in myself but a lot
of it I'm pleased to say it does not
involve me so what was my way into
privacy a lot of philosophers got into
privacy maybe in the 60s and so on
because we were we were this word had
been emerging and many people engaged in
this question of how do you define
privacy my entry was not that I was a
PhD student at Stanford and I was seeing
the emergence of many of these
technologies and of course this is
really updated to sort of today mine was
not that I was rather interested in the
technologies and some of the
applications of the technologies that
were affecting our lives in all walks of
life and particularly interested in
those occasions where people said oh my
God my privacy is violated whatever was
happening the freaked out that people
were having as a result of it they
labeled privacy so I wasn't so much
interested in a philosophical deep dive
as valuable as that is into the concept
which is what a lot of analytic
philosophers do and it is valuable to
gain clarity on terms but rather I was
trying to look at the family of episodes
or systems or occurrences to which
people responded with this particular
freak
and labeling its in this way so what
I've tried to do over the years is to
say how do we achieve meaningful privacy
that is to say defining a concept that's
true to that experience defining it in a
way that we could argue that whatever it
is that people were caring about when
they said that was worth defending
because sometimes people freaked out and
you say stop freaking out that is not
worth defending but it seemed to me
there was something there and so I
wanted an approach some definition of
whatever this thing was that was not
only clear and hopefully rigorous but
also could offer an account of why we
should care about it and why we can
advocate and protest and have a reason
to defend it and then some of the things
that followed was the ability to give it
formal expression so that it could they
could potentially be some kind of
implementation and enforcement was an
added bonus because then potentially we
might be able to embed or you know
follow what later has been called
privacy by design and I want to just
take a moment to acknowledge and they're
probably even more names but many of the
people who I have worked with over the
years because when I mentioned earlier
that I didn't think one discipline is
the crown jewels and can and couldn't
solve this problem by itself there many
people and these folks come from all
walks of life and potentially you
recognize some of them so the way I want
to introduce contextual integrity to you
is to highlight four key ideas because
you know I like to think it's a big and
complicated theory there's a book you
know if you want to delve into the
details by now they're a bunch of
articles where I realize I made mistakes
in some of the previous work and I try
to correct it and amplify and so forth
but the way that might be useful is to
present you these four key ideas so that
if you're not bothered by the details
you might still find it useful to know
what these four ideas are and what I
want to also do so that you can in
addition to knowing the four key ideas
also keep in mind what these compare
with or how contextual integrity as a
theory of privacy was an approach to
privacy is differentiated and in some
ways it's kind of subtly different and
in some ways it's really different so
this is the main idea and if you need to
leave after this this is the most
important thing for you to remember and
take away from this lecture and that is
that contextual integrity or privacy is
the appropriate flow of information and
the idea is this both a positive one a
negative one the positive one is to say
as we all know information data flow is
really important and there's a lot of
benefit it's the way society operates if
you want to live in society then
information about you is going to flow
so if you want to if you want to protect
privacy you don't want to stop the flow
of information
you don't want privacy to mean the same
as secrecy which is the stoppage of flow
you want privacy rather to be the
appropriate flow of information
now this runs against some of the ways
I've heard my computer science
colleagues talk about privacy and I've
just spent about I spent about six
months at the Simon's Institution
I had really fabulous discussions with
many of the theoretical computer
scientists
often computer scientists will present a
theory or present a tool or present a
method and they'll talk about leakage
they'll say how do we prevent leakage
contextual integrity doesn't like that
word if you just use it on its own as if
leakage is a bad thing leakage is not a
bad thing it's only bad if it's
inappropriate and so even some of the
privacy engineering community have a
principle called a diamond obsession and
contextual integrity says that data
minimization on its own is not
necessarily a good thing
you need to minimize appropriately and
so if you start off with that idea
appropriate flow that is where we begin
with a definition of contextual
integrity now of course you're sitting
there and you're like well what's
appropriate flow and that now we enter
into the next key ideas of the theory
one the the and I haven't miscounted I
just want you to know but there's an
interesting connection among these four
ideas and they're two definitions or
accounts of appropriate flow one is that
appropriate flow is flow that conforms
with social norms and in the legal
domain we often hear of things like
reasonable expectations of privacy so
when we talk about a norm I've also come
to understand that computer scientists
and mathematicians use the term norm in
a different way and a lot of the
disagreement and confusion was that I
was using the term norm in one way and
other and folks were understanding it in
another way so if you prefer it could be
just rule think about it as a rule and
we we live in society there are lots of
norms that govern our behavior we you
know governing
even at this moment and some of them are
explicit some of them are embodied in
law so you'll often have a legal rule
that embodies a social norm sometimes
you'll have legal rules that are just
legal rules sometimes you'll simply have
conventions of expected ways of behaving
and so on so one of the claims is if you
you know in the early days of Google
Maps Street View there was an outcry
because people didn't like the fact that
the cameras showed various things and so
people objected to it and they said it's
a privacy violation and the defenders of
Google Maps Street View said oh but you
know we only showing things that are
public you know in public roadways and
in fact what the argue the back the
argument is no actually there is a
difference in the flow of information
that's caused by Street View because you
don't now have to be standing in front
of someone's house you can be etc and so
that particular technology had violated
people's expectations and often the
expectation that's violated is a signal
of a norm a social norm and then what I
will come to later is the fact that
appropriate flow it has a normative
content that is like an ethical or
prescriptive content that you will often
call something appropriate if you think
that it's legitimate and so there needs
to be an idea in there that also
explores appropriateness as a normative
concept so I'm going to concentrate I'm
going to start with this idea which is
that appropriate flow is flow that
conforms worth norms or rules it meets
our expectations and you see this little
word entrenched and it's quite an
important word because there are lots of
norms and I'm sure I could I could
identify some of them that are
entrenched their expectation nobody
wrote the rule down but we behave in
ways that we learn we absorb from
society and those are the norms that are
calling entrenched and those are the
ones that meet expectations so if we say
a proprietary norms and what does goes
against those of you who are somewhat
familiar with privacy policy are the
Fair Information practice principles
which were devised in 1973 and then were
ultimately embedded in the first Privacy
Act of 1974 which was basically a
tragedy because although the people the
the Commission in 1973 said here are the
Fair Information practice principles we
need to embody them in an omnibus
privacy law what happened instead was
that in 1974 the law was passed but it
only covered government held databases
and it left the whole commercial domain
I mean that was 1974 and people maybe
didn't have a sense of what was to come
but anyway it goes against the Fair
Information principles and something
that we're all very familiar with which
is the informed consent mechanism and
it's it's often operationalized as
notice and choice and we call that a
procedural approach to privacy it says
that if you follow these in these steps
then you're going to achieve privacy and
the Fair Information practice principles
which are really the fundamental of
where we are today in privacy regulation
now some people may say oh there's the
US law and in this gdpr which is the
European general data protection
regulation also still based on Fair
Information practice principles although
they act that they've added some
substance
of prohibitions into those rules but it
just says okay if you present people
with a policy and people agree then
privacy is protected it says nothing
about the substance of what the
practices are and a contextual integrity
rejects that approach but says we need
to have rules substantive rules about
what flows are and are not allowable
so why contextual integrity and so we're
diving a little bit more into the theory
itself my own approach so you can see
entrench contextual norms is to think
about society not as an undifferentiated
social space but rather as constituted
by a whole variety of different social
domains and these domains are oriented
around or you could even think that
historically anthropologically they
emerge around certain purposes goals and
values it could be we want to educate
young and what has evolved around that
is an educational domain or we have
health and what's emerged around that is
a domain a healthcare domain or there
could be a political domain how do we
how do we choose our rulers or our
leaders our political leaders what sorts
of powers they have over us and so forth
and and it so that although although I
personally had done a lot of reading in
the areas of social philosophy and
social theory and so forth I wasn't I
didn't hang the theory of contextual
integrity on any one particular but
there's a lot of social theory that
construct society in this way as
constituted by these different domains
now this is number three what we're
saying is that these contextual
informational norms and
information is information flows or
practices or policies come conform with
if they conform with entrenched social
norms we say that these flows are
appropriate
what contextual integrity goes on
further to say is that here is the
structure of the rule in order to
formulate a rule correctly a well-formed
rule for the purpose of knowing where
the privacy is preserved and I feel like
this community maybe understands this
idea better than many communities that I
I try to talk to about this is that you
need to provide values for these five
independent parameters or like three
depending on you on how you count them
actors and so just for short this is the
CI tupple someone told me that this is
how you say it and it's actors
information type transmission principle
so when you're describing a practice and
you need to figure out or show someone
that this is appropriate this conforms
to it contextual integrity you need to
specify the sender the subject the
recipient what infant what the type of
the information is and the transmission
principle and I'm going to say a little
bit more about all these different
parameters but I wanted you just to see
one quick example of what the structure
that such a description or a rule might
look like with all the parameters filled
in or values for all the parameters so
here are an assortment of the now let me
just say this that often the subject in
the sender are the are one and the same
and so it might seem like the only four
parameters listed but
in fact you know you have that I did the
the two identified and so it's not a
problem so these are contextual
informational norms the values for the
parameters are expressed as in terms of
roles so it's people not just people
it's let's say people acting in certain
capacities and the capacities are very
much constitutive of the domain itself
so if I say physician you are gonna say
what what's the domain what's the
context thank you you know it'll be
healthcare or teacher it's education and
sometimes it's this you know I'm not
saying it's all neatly tied up but the
it's it's not that the context implies
the roles the may be the purposes imply
the roles it's that the roles are part
of what constitutes a context
information type is the ontology of
attributes and again to some extent
they're connected to the identity of the
context and then finally the third thing
which is I have to say I think it's a
contribution but it also is the most
troublesome of the parameters because
this and there's lots of work that still
needs to be done on it however what the
transmission principle is is the
constraint under which the information
flows and so what you can see here is
that consent is now a transmission
principle under this structure and when
you share information with consent that
is the transmission principle but when
you are filing your tax returns and you
have to fill in a thing that says gross
annual income that is not with consent
you are you have
there's coercion or you're standing in
front of a judge your witness you you
must answer in in a certain way and they
sometimes more complicated transmission
principles so for example the police
can't just barge into your house and go
searching around if you if you're a
suspect they need to get a warrant from
a judge and then they can enter with a
warrant and that is a transmission
principle often in the privacy domain
people forget about the transmission
principle and as we can see with
something like with a warrant
that is a critical transmission
principle and we depend on that to to to
be living in a system where law prevails
okay so all the parameters matter here
was one of the excellent expose
experiences that I had as I was I was
presenting this I was part of a large
NSF grant and I was presenting early
ideas from contextual integrity many
years ago John Mitchell was in the
audience and he said oh wow we we think
we can provide a formal expression of
these ideas so what what you've what
I've already what I've shown you is
already digested through a lot of the
help that I got from the folks on this
paper and there was an Oakland paper
that was was really successful but in
sitting with these collaborators they
would just ask me questions what about
this what about this what about this and
I think that the the theory became much
more rigorous and precise as a result
but what we see here which was rather
satisfying is that and this was a lot to
do to understand data is that if you
look at actual law or actual rulemaking
in the United States a lot of the rules
and this comes directly from HIPAA a
covered entity can disclose the
patient's psychotherapy No
to the patient only with prior approval
from the patient's psychiatrist and so
you can see all the parameters being
listed in this rule that Health and
Human Services came up with and what I
think I like to present this rule
because this shows you that in some
cases it's not actually the data subject
that determines fully determines the
information flows so just to pause a
moment and say the way this all works is
that if you if you're interested in
analyzing a particular device or a
particular system according to the
theory of contextual integrity what you
do is you need to describe data flows
and and this is quite important and
quite practically relevant and I don't
know how many people in this room have
developed apps for example but we've
utilized this just in in very low-key
settings where people are developing
mobile apps and we said okay you need to
first of all map out the data flows and
and in and make sure you know you you
able to provide the values for these
parameters and then once you have a
description of the flows you can do some
comparison to make sure that the flows
conform with entrenched norms now just
to get back and I'm gonna say more about
this but I wanted to now elaborate a
little bit more when we subscribe to the
idea that appropriate flow is flow that
conforms with entrenched look and
contextual rules we've already said that
the most universal approach that this
country and GDP are to but that's a
longer story has taken to privacy
protection is through this concept of
subject control of information about
ourselves some of you at
how many of you have been following some
of the New York Times privacy project
you know I think it's a great series of
articles but we started counting and
they're about at least I stopped
counting after 20 of those essays all
end by saying what we need to do is give
people control over information about
themselves and then the only way we seem
to have to do that is notice a choice
that has a that's a problem but I argue
on the basis of contextual integrity
that saying that the whole arena of
privacy is control over information
about ourselves is to take control which
is one transmission principle and make
it into the entire domain of privacy
protection and this is highly
problematic because I argue there
multiple transmission principles and
sometimes we actually don't have a right
to control information about ourselves
second another approach to policymaking
is to kind of divide the worlds of
information into sensitive information
or not sensitive information and to say
you know privacy regulation only applies
to sensitive information as far as all
the rest of the information anything
goes
contextual integrity says no any
information and here's my claim any
information requires norms or it is
bound by norms of that constrain the
flow of that information it can be
something like your name and we've now
done some empirical research that
validates that idea and finally if
you're building some kind of access
control system you need to be thinking
about the values for all of the five
parameters not four not three not so
that to argue that
we only need to worry about sensitive
information is problematic because first
of all you're only worrying about one
parameter and second of all instead of
looking at the whole ontology you're
looking you're just dividing the world
into two types of information end of
story
now when I say that access control rules
have to govern all for the practical
situation is that sometimes access
control rules make assumptions about the
outside world and it may be that you're
not able to represent or model all of
the five parameters and you need to make
an assumption about for example let's
say you building something that's only
about men's health then you don't you
may you may not need to specify well I
don't know you may need to but you if
you if you if it's if you know that the
the the system is going to be used
within a certain domain and only certain
parties are going to have access to - -
it may be through some kind of
authentication mechanism then you can
get away with using the external device
to already constrain for example who the
recipients are and then the rules within
that system don't need to specify all
five so when I say you need to specify
all five I'm realistic about the fact
that sometimes you're not able to
represent all of those five within the
system and you need to control some of
those parameters outside of the system
and I mean anybody whose model anything
knows that it's not just a restriction
on this kind of thing so this is just a
slide that says here is the work that we
need to do having gotten as far with
contextual integrity
we need to you know I talked a lot about
entrenched norms some of these
entrenched norms are quite intuitive and
and some of them are expressed in law
and so we can figure out what they are
but because we're in this domain so some
of the some of the controversy around
Inge surrounding the platform's for
example or mobile apps we there's a mess
and some of the more predatory data
practices take advantage of the fact
that we haven't we as a society we
haven't really figured we haven't done
research which teaches us what the
robust implicit norms are and so this is
really ok read here's the code read is
what I think is mainly in the in the
domain of social scientists and
communication scholars and so on for us
to learn more about what our
expectations are and that tons of
studies now Mechanical Turk is the
favorite platform to try and extract and
be more precise about what some of those
norms are the blue is what I think
mainly is in the domain of computer
science and it could be systems people
or security folks networking and theory
crypto to not necessarily only think
about the case you know the standard
case of Alice Bob and Eve but to
appreciate and I'm sure you do some of
them much more complex circumstances so
at the moment I'm working with some
folks on on smart or autonomous vehicles
and if you think about those vehicle
communication systems I remember way
back about a decade ago working with Dan
Bonet who had some really clever
cryptographic system to say well you
don't really need to know who the driver
is but you need to be still be able to
identify
the car for purposes of coordination and
that's I think what your what this
community is really expert at is to
provide ways of constraining information
flow that respects the norms that
respect the constraints while allowing
systems to continue functioning not
grind to a halt and then you know these
other these other activities the purple
which is the red and the blue together
is ways in which I think is really
important for us to work together on a
common problem now if you're thinking
about just with the lens of privacy as
control your life is a little bit easier
when you operationalize control there's
just this one thing you have to
operationalize which is giving control
and of course as we all know that the
current notice and choice regime is
highly ineffective and we're sitting
with this policy because it's very
convenient for the information platform
providers and others you know mobile
platform providers it's very convenient
because it pretty much allows them to do
anything and what we need is
unfortunately more complicated but I
think would give us much better privacy
so some of the work we are doing within
our group is empirical studies that
question some of the ages old
assumptions about privacy and I don't
have so much time so I'm not going to go
into it and here's another way we have a
platform that tries to govern
information flow now within an
institutional setting so we don't have
to take care of all you know a ton of
values for the different parameters and
their lot there's just lots more to do
and as I mentioned other people are also
doing it now I don't know you know it's
hard to follow a particular
talk just if it's the first time you
ever encountering it but there's
something that I'm wondering maybe this
is really bothering you and that is that
the whole reason we're here today I mean
I'm here today is that it's technology
and the technology is disruptive a lot
of this technology that we all love or
love to hate has disrupted information
flows that's number one and number two
it may be that we have flows that sorry
I'm just that we just don't have norms
for and they're troubling but there
doesn't seem get to become an agreement
about what the right thing to do is and
so basically whoever is the more
powerful whoever has the neat act is
going to be the one that defines the
flows and we just sit around passively
hoping that nothing bad is going to
happen to us and there are a whole lot
of other reasons why the entrenched
approach is problematic
now I had in early days not actually
developed as part of the theory because
I was really in love with the idea that
you know society has these entrenched
norms we look at the Hippocratic oath
we've evolved these norms of a centuries
and there's the wisdom of the ages and
you know we should go with that but you
can't be conservative in that way and
say no change is possible
and everything's of the privacy
violation if it violates an entrenched
norm so we need some approach to march
into this new domain and be able to
evaluate not only our own entrenched
norms like slavery is an extreme example
but also to evaluate new practices new
institutions that are being thrust on us
where let's say Mark Zuckerberg is
saying Oh Facebook has changed the norms
and we're sitting there saying no you've
changed the practice but what basis on
what basis are you saying that the norm
has changed and so now coming back to
our diagram we're gonna look at this
number four cuz you know now we have got
a number three which is how do we look
at some new practice or even an
entrenched norm and evaluate whether
it's okay or not and I use this
philosophical concept of legitimate but
it can be something like is it worth
defending is it morally justifiable and
contextual integrity offers three steps
to thinking about this and you know it's
I have just not too many minutes and I'm
going to go a little bit quickly the
interests we need to do a kind of
economic analysis when we look at some
of these new practices and say how who's
harmed use who benefits standard
economic policy analysis and then
there's a discussion of political
principles you know does this diminish
freedom of speech and we've seen a lot
of analysis of this in in the media is
it biased does it does it create
unfairness and that's the second line
but it's really the third line that I
want to emphasize which comes directly
out of the contextual approach which is
you know contextual integrity which is
what I said at the beginning of the talk
is that context are constituted around
purposes and values so imagine the
Martian landing in a university and
sending back the description of what a
university is or what a school is
describes everything that's going on but
doesn't say what we're doing in a
university what a school is trying to do
the purposes I think we would all admit
that they're missing a major point about
these base
institutions of society and so what
conditional integrity argues is yes you
discuss interests yes you talk about
some of these very highly abstract
values but what's also important is
contextual ends and purposes and here
are just a few I'm not going to go
through them but I also wanted to show
you that this is an intuitive idea and
here in 1925 when tax returns that the
tax information that we provide to the
IRS went from being public information
to being information that was now held
in enormous confidence as we've been
learning increasingly in the past year
and a half by the IRS and Andrew
Mellon's argument was not like oh you
know people have a right to privacy in
their in their tax returns his argument
was we want people to say honestly what
they earn what they're worth and that's
important so that the Treasury could
benefit from taxing them and so one
reason why people might want to hide
their earnings is because it's being
blasted to the world imagine you know
your family your large family learns
that you really quite wealthy and how
many people will come and hit you up for
loans and whatnot so and he succeeded
that argument succeeded so we're saying
and health care is the same if someone
has a contagious or infectious disease
may not report for testing and that's
problematic not only for the person but
for social societal health and so we
insist on very stringent privacy
regulation in health care in order to
promote health and so forth now this is
here's the not part of it this is
different from some other approaches
who insists that privacy's only about
the data subject actually there are two
things
and please do those of you who stayed
are still here the first really
important point to take away is that
it's not secrecy it's a appropriate flow
and the second important point is
privacy is valuable not only for the
individual but for social integrity as
well privacy promotes contextual ends
and purposes and that's why it's
important so all those times that you
hear people say oh you've got to give up
some of your privacy in order to you
know improve health
now that you've sat in this room you
have to reject what they're saying and
say no because an adequate approach to
privacy will say that an appropriate
flow of information has to be shaped so
that it can serve individual interest
but also is well designed if it also
promotes the contextual ends and we've
been looking at some examples of that in
in politics and education and so forth
and the third wall you know a lot of
people who do differential privacy will
say you know privacy versus utility and
I hope that we can get past that because
privacy is not instead of utility
privacy conserve utility but you just
have to stop thinking about privacy as
secrecy as stoppage of flow but rather
appropriate flow and sometimes that will
serve utility so I wanted to bring up
this because many of us have seen his
images through the lens of contextual
integrity the sin of Cambridge
analytical was not that this information
was shared without consent of the data
subjects it was a problem because it has
these because of destabilize democracy
and when we try solve it we
say hey Facebook next time ask people
because you know that 95% of people are
not even reading and they're gonna just
click you need to think we need to think
about how this is going to affect these
deeply valued purposes so I mean here
are just a few little examples which I'm
not going to go through this is my last
law I can come back to those if you like
but I did want to leave some time for
discussion the heuristic that we come up
with for practical purposes is to
discover the relevant norms or
expectation contextual norms expectation
map flows in terms of the parameters
check conformance and performance
legitimacy analysis now having built the
big picture we still subscribe to what I
had said earlier about what contextual
integrity needs us to learn to be a
functioning theory and that is that
people like myself and legal scholars
and so forth
we have to understand the imple with the
Facebook Cambridge and analytical we
really need to dive deeply into the
consequences of these for individual
social values and how they affect some
of the constitutional laws in the case
of the u.s. some of the values the Bill
of Rights to which we're committed to
and presumably different countries and
different cultures would have different
norms we need to move beyond this
obsession and I can say that the number
of articles that has been that have been
written about you know let's analyze
privacy policies and compliance and so
forth is is kind of mind-boggling and I
don't think in the end is going to serve
privacy very well we need in my opinion
economic and game theoretic methods for
figuring
what optimal policies or substantive
rules because sometimes you know just
very and creative laws are not
necessarily going to give us the
appropriate flows that are legitimate
and important and then of course I think
but back to the what we can do in the
computer science and crypto community is
help us figure out smart ways to enforce
flow policy policies and express them in
technical systems and devices I guess
that's the end thanks a lot
[Applause]
um it is this on okay so it's an
interesting way of thinking about things
and I thank you for the talk the problem
that we face is that we do need control
because although you can talk about
appropriate flow there's a problem of
preventing inappropriate flow that's
very hard some other complications are
the lack of permanence the rules change
the data is owned by new people and the
interpretation of appropriateness
disintegrates over time and then there's
a monotonicity principle the amount of
information that is disclosed about you
simply increases over your lifetime so
maybe it's a secondary part of your
theory to address some of these other
problems I'd like to know your views yes
no I think those are all very good
points when I talk about control the
main and maybe I wasn't clear enough I
mean
control about information about
ourselves by the data subject and what I
was objecting to is that we're where we
are today for the most part is that we
think that a bilateral agreement between
the data collector and processor with
the data subject is what privacy amounts
to and the argument here is first of all
that is not going to be for the benefit
of the individual especially for the
reasons that he raised about how
complicated the data environment has
become and second of all because
there's the societal impact and
sometimes people don't have a right to
control information about ourselves
because it's not beneficial for
promoting societal ends and you may
disagree with me on that school because
you may just think that on the issues of
information about ourselves it's sort of
like nobody's going to tell me who I can
marry for example it's just
fundamentally my choice then we just you
know then we part company I mean I'm
just responding to some of your points
the question of change is precisely what
that second part of the theory tries to
address because norms also change over
time circumstances hurricanes we become
smarter we become hopefully more ethical
we have to have a system that allows
this change to take place and this is an
attempt to give some kind of systematic
approach to that thank you very much for
your talk a very refreshing refreshing
view and I think much more productive
and a lot of the discussions I think are
I met confused you seem to focus very
much on the flow of data and to me the
use of data is a much bigger issue
maybe you encompass it in the flow but
it wasn't yeah yes thank you for raising
this very difficult important question
so it's and it's a debate that started
out early the theory describes these
norms which are norms of flow and the
critics of that even friends said Helen
you've got to do something about use and
I said I don't need to do anything about
use two reasons one is that a physician
or the role implies use so insane
physician we have some implicit
assumption about what the physician is
doing with that data and second of all
with with the outcomes of use we can cap
that when we look at the evaluation of
the norms interest values and contextual
purposes which was fine until about ten
fifty you know okay five years ago when
actors large platforms and and
information services companies really
blossomed and became these global giants
and accumulated data from all walks of
life and didn't think twice about just
pulling all this data and we didn't know
what they were
you know we they didn't have a fixed
role in nineteen I don't know when it
was twenty five eighty five there was
the Telecommunications Act in the United
States and they've defined the role of a
telecom provider they say this is what
it is and by the way here is how we're
gonna regulate your data flow you can't
record calls you can listen to a few
snatches for quality of service you can
record metadata well I'm just calling it
metadata and so they stipulated that but
we living with this and the problem here
is that these because we don't know
these parties they're just using the
data in multiple different and I'm
thinking non contextual ways excuse me
sorry and so I now agree we need to have
use that's a long but yes I think we now
have to have a use parameter and how
we're gonna and I'm working with people
I mean how are we gonna do it I actually
think that a lot of your theory just
applies to both things and maybe have a
float or word processing of data
encompassing both the use and flow or
you can define the flow within an
organization but that's very easy to
misunderstand yes and and how to do it
is still something that I'm thinking of
but because of where we are today we
need to have a use parameter
thank you thanks ed actually to just
follow them that I was actually or
someone or things I wanted to bring up
so first I very much appreciate your
your perspective I think it's great the
thing about this as flow as a contextual
thing and to think about data as
something that doesn't necessarily
belong to one person or another you know
with it's a it's the right way to think
about it but so uses which I think the
produces two least two different
components that has to be addressed one
is the aggregation of data you know the
whole is much more than the sum of the
parts and as you say all this you might
and and the in and the no theory will be
completely meaningful without addressing
that and it's practice showed us and and
the other thing is that the flow of
information should be thought of a
circular right because it also comes
back to us it not just what flows the
way to us from us the world comes to us
right when I've been shown ads that have
you know biased or whatever that's not
what coming out is what's coming in and
and the whole thing is one big ecosystem
that cannot talk about it sounds to me
yeah so I won't address the coming in
part but I do want to mention two things
I have an article anyone's interested
it's called contextual integrity up and
down the data food chain where I look at
how we have adapted to certain this
problem that you mention everyone you
know doing machine learning and so forth
is really relevant that sometimes we can
adjust norms to learn from what we see
so I think we were very good about
Social Security number back in the day
because we saw that that accumulated a
lot of information around it and then we
could do all sorts of things and then
suddenly you know everybody was asking
what's your social security number stop
because we realize how how
wheeling that was however I think we're
moving at such a speed so in the cases
where the norms can't catch up to the
practices precisely because of what I'm
calling the the data food chain we need
to then I mean I think their flow won't
help we need to go directly to purposes
and we need to say is it worth it that
companies are surveilling every move we
make online and now increasingly with
smart cities and that in physical space
is it worth it so that I can get an ad
that even if I'm interested in it expose
myself to this how entire system and
that's the kind of question is it worth
it is it worth it to do that if it's
going to stop plagues maybe so we need
to do it responsibly we need to have
that discussion of what's worth it and I
don't think we are yet my question is
related to the information processing
issue
and I'm just wondering how you deal with
rules that might be just contradictory
to each other so you can imagine that we
think it's okay for information X to be
released to someone and we might also
really not want information Y to be
released without realizing that Y can be
inferred from X you know how you would
address that kind of issue I mean you
know it's a big problem and one of the
issues about having these platforms that
are gathering you know information 360
degrees with just no no we have this
political economy of information at the
moment which is basically if you own it
you can do what the heck you like so you
can you know buy a blood processing lab
and you can be talking about a consumer
practice and there's no sense that
they actually should be rules even
within single ownership that stops that
kind of processing and merging of the
information I mean it's sad because
we've kind of it would take a lot of
rhetorical force to push the dial back a
little bit so but but there's a little
help you can get from the extra
parameters you and that which is to say
I'm prepared to give X to a and Y to be
but I know that if they merge this data
like data brokers we have a problem and
if we think contextually in terms of
ends and purposes and values I think we
can protect against some of it but not
all of it
so thank you I don't know yeah are you a
next really interesting talk thank you
very much
um one of the one of my questions though
and perhaps it's because I'm
misunderstanding when you talk about the
attributes the sender the recipient and
the subject especially with your example
on the psychiatrist it didn't talk about
the data origin yeah so in that
particular example the psychiatrist was
the origin of the data and so clearly
should have controlled the notes yeah so
I'm wondering why data origin isn't part
of those attributes because in some
cases right it's method collection and
and other things are being protected by
the data yes
and I do think that there is a kind of
misleading way in which we think about
data as like just stuff lying around
that people go and gather when in fact
data is very much a construct and
strange you should say but we had a
small dollar grant with a few of us and
we started talking about origin it may
not satisfy you but if you if you look
for that I think we had a public head I
think it's out already but we did talk
about it's not to say that the
originator necessarily sort of owns but
that the originator of the data is a
relevant question to ask and can affect
the flows so I mean that's all I think
you're right yeah yeah so thank you for
your talk
I was wondering we were discussing how
contextual integrity chooses not to see
society as one cohesive whole I think in
your second point I was wondering how
this interacted with the lawful side of
things does it for example advocate that
different groups who have different
norms about appropriate data flow should
be subject to different laws because it
seems like that could be rather a bit of
a Pandora's box I'm not I didn't hear
every word you said but I'll try answer
and then you couldn't tell me if I got
it right this is an interesting question
because many people will say that Europe
is much more advanced in thinking about
privacy than the US because they have
this kind of omnibus omnibus approach to
saying we're gonna have one regulation
like one size fits all actually it also
devolves to something called purpose
binding and and and
purpose can sometimes map onto what I
call contextual in the u.s. we have
what's known as the sectoral approach
where we do in fact have they're just
bad the problem is that they're bad but
the general idea of having a slightly
lower level but more specific set of
regulations for some of the major
domains is I think important and the
reason it is is that someone like myself
who's a privacy theorist don't come and
ask me what the rules should be for
finance or for healthcare or for
education the people who are writing
those rules need to be experts in those
domains so that's sort of to put the
positive spin
I'm thinking of society and law does a
to law there's commercial law there's
there's private law there's public law
so even though we have the Constitution
that has some very high-level abstract
values that where the other laws really
need to you know because you challenges
to laws based on conflicts with the
Constitution
I think of privacy rules as a little bit
like that and I would like to see those
sectoral rules improved a lot and not
always have this little switch that says
these rules hold blah blah blah except
if the data subject gives permission for
something else which if you look at all
the laws that we have on the books has
this weird exception probably not in
some of like national security
regulation I'm just curious about
something which was on one of your
slides so what's a problem with the
number of spoons in your coffee what
what since they were in one of your
slides there was a problem of
transmitting the number of spoons of
sugar in your coffee that's the problem
of Otzi's actually it was just before
the sexual orientation
[Music]
no no wow I think I was saying and this
was in this do you mind that I'm just
doing this kind of thinking which is I
wanted I wanted in the work in which I
challenged this dichotomy of public and
private I was arguing that this
information that's personal because I
said like this actually many different
dichotomies and there's information
that's personal this information that
may be sensitive and but that was before
I went on and said uh actually they're
these contextual ontology something like
how many spoons of sugar you have in
your coffee
you could say is personal but it's not
sensitive unless it's a health insurance
company in the sense that if somebody
learns that you you could face harms and
this was early argumentation against the
claim that you can divide the entire
world into the public and private I'm
sorry I just blanked on that one yeah I
think you're not addressing the real
problem this is a this is the deck
chairs on the Titanic problem you know
we're asking detailed questions and the
boats taking on water and we need me
need to address Zuckerberg
[Music]
but how you know how how are we going to
do it because we're a country of laws so
we need to provide the way in with the
camera the reason I use that cambric
analytic a case is that I want to excite
people into realizing that it's not just
a question of me personally controlling
but actually what some of the companies
are doing and and Facebook is very
visible but I think data brokers are a
case in point the mobile operating
systems I mean they're quite a few
companies that are in this space their
data practices can undermine democracy
not if our regulators cannot respond to
that I think that that's that's a
problem and and that's the sort of thing
we need to communicate because that will
get us the foot in the door anyway
thanks for yeah
[Applause]