don't work with senior Park at MIT and
Harvard the subtitle of this talk is
repeatability and claim ability of ring
signatures but it might as well have
been unrepaired ability and unclaimed
bull and claim ability offering two
features so ring signature is defined by
Rivest Shamir and Taman allow or variant
of digital signatures that allow signing
on behalf of some set of parties that
have the requirements that only a member
of the set can have produced the
signature but they hide which member of
the set was responsible so parties can
independently generate secret key public
key pairs and post their public keys and
at any point afterwards a party can take
a set of public keys including
themselves and sign on behalf of that
set and the signature provides the
guarantee is that only some member of
that set can have produced the signature
but an outside adversary can't tell
which member so ring signatures are
motivated in part by whistleblowing
scenarios so suppose a official wants to
come forward with evidence of
misbehavior in an agency they can so
they may be wary of retribution from
higher-ups so they may want to use a
ring signature scheme to sign on behalf
of some set of party some set of senior
of senior officials where the ident
where this set of people sort of
provides some sort of reputation that
someone in a position of information has
provided this message but then suppose
that that someone comes to each of these
individuals in in the in the in the ring
and demands proof that they did or
didn't sign the message can can they
comply and it's not clear under under
the usual definitions so for another
example suppose that someone wants to
use ring signatures to to harm the
reputation of a celebrity or a
politician
so suppose they sign a message on behalf
of a set of parties
including themselves and including some
celebrity where the where the contents
of the message are some embarrassing
statement so of course this doesn't this
doesn't actually say anything about the
celebrity having said anything
embarrassing because anyone in the ring
could have produced the signature but it
may sort of it may they may post this on
the internet it may go viral and it
might be it might harm the reputation of
of the prominent figure so is there
anything that Alice can do to to recover
her reputation and prove that she was
not responsible for producing this
signature so to do this let's take
another look at the anonymity
definitions for ring signatures so we
have the unforgeable ax t definition and
also the anonymity definition that an
adversary can't tell which party in the
ring produced the signature so we we
want to be more specific about the power
of this adversary and what information
that they have so there's a whole
landscape of definitions for ring
signatures I'm going to talk now about
two of the of the strongest ones
anonymity against adversarial a chosen
keys on anonymity against full key
exposure so in in the adversary chosen
keys setting you have you have a bunch
of you have some honest parties that
produce the produced keys and you have
the adversary that can corrupt as many
parties as they want and can also
generate malformed keys and at the end
the requirement that you have is that
the adverse that as long as there are
some two parties that were not corrupted
by the adversary the adversary cannot
distinguish which of these parties was
responsible for the message even
stronger definition is provided by
anonymity against full key exposure in
which the adversary can corrupt all of
the parties but as long as some pair of
keys were sampled honestly even even
knowing all of the secret keys the
adversary still can't tell which party
which party signed the message these
definitions don't don't tell us the
whole picture
of whether a signatory who wishes to
later approve or deny authorship of a
signature should be able to do so and
both both versions are are very are
natural to consider and what we'd like
is a guarantee one way or the other of
whether this was possible or not so in
our work we introduced four definitions
that let's specify whether this is
possible so a reputable ring signature
scheme is one in which a non signer can
prove that they were not responsible for
producing the signature that some other
party and the ring produced the
signature unconverted an unrepeatable
scheme this is not possible even if I
did not sign the message I am NOT able
to convince someone else of this fact
and we can also look at whether I can
prove that I was responsible so so a
claimable scheme is one in which if I if
I produced a signature I can later come
forward and demonstrate that I was
responsible for that that the signature
was produced using my key if I choose to
or I can never do this and we can also
define an unclaimed bull scheme in which
no matter what I do later if I as long
as I assign this use of rings an
unclaimed bull scheme to sign this
message even if I later want to come
forward and prove that I was responsible
for signing the message there's nothing
convincing I can say that that will that
will assure you that I was responsible
for signing the message now when you
look at the idea of an unclaimed bull
ring signature scheme it seems like this
shouldn't be achievable it may seem like
this shouldn't be achievable because
suppose that you sign the you sign a
message and you remember the signing
randomness then you can always come
forward and say here's my signing
randomness you know you shouldn't do
this but here's my secret key here's my
signing randomness you can run the
encryption you can run the signing
algorithm yourself and you can see
that that this signature is produced so
in order to have a meaningful notion of
unclaimed ability we need to guarantee
that non signers can also produce fake
signing randomness that looks real so
even though I might remember the signing
randomness and be able to produce it
later anyone else in the ring can also
later come up with with with convincing
fake signing randomness and claim that
they produce this signature using this
other signing venomous so nothing so
nothing I say later this would be
convincing to guarantee that I signed
and that I produced the signature now
this this this guarantee feels somewhat
in the flavor of deniable encryption
where you also want to produce
explaining randomness for it for a for a
ciphertext but it's somewhat
surprisingly a deniable encryption seems
to require very heavy and machinery like
indistinguishability obfuscation but in
contrast this notion of unclaimed
ability were able to achieve from
standard lattice assumptions so so sort
of the intuition behind the guarantee of
unclaimed ability is that any anything
that can be produced by the true signer
can also be simulated by any other
member of the Ring and we can even
require that the simulation is
information theoretic so so in this work
we define these four notions of ring
signature schemes and we construct each
of them we can start clear involving
signature schemes and a generic
transformation from any ring signature
scheme I'm claiming bull from sis
lattice assumptions and reputable ring
signatures from verifiable random
functions and the fourth variant
unrepeatable we show is implied by the
stronger of the notion of the
pre-existing additions of ring
signatures that I presented earlier ring
signature is anonymous against Phil key
exposure so in this talk I'll focus on
the other three
to give some so our work also gives some
taxonomy of the landscape of ring
signatures we we can show that
unclimbable is a stronger definition
than unrepeatable it implies it and also
playable and reputable ring signatures
are compatible notions so we can have a
single ring signature scheme that's both
claimable and repeatable and the other
thing i want to mention is that the
claim bowl and unclimbable are not
opposites and neither repeatable and
unrepeatable you can have a signature
scheme that's neither
for instance if claiming requires
remembering signing randomness our
nation of claim bowlers is is stateless
but you can have a notion where you can
claim some of the time or only if you're
stateful so there's room for four
definitions in between as well so for an
outline of the rest of the talk I'm
gonna I'm going to talk about construe
three notions of clam bowl unclaimed
bull and repeatable ring signatures and
constructions for them so I'm going to
start with the simplest to build which
is claim bull ring signatures and we're
gonna so to remind you a ring signature
is claimable if the signature torii can
later come forward and and reveal their
identity and and prove that they were
the signer so the the intuition for this
is that if we could remember the signing
randomness it seems like if we if we
build things carefully this should
constitute a reasonable this should
constitute a convincing claim there's
two issues that we need to deal with we
need to make sure that the signing
randomness uniquely determines the
signer which since I'm going to talk
about unclaimed ability in the next
section that's not true in general
and finally we don't want to remember
the signing venomous so this notion of
clearing bility sort of seems partway
between a ring signature and a standard
digital signature so let's start by so
suppose we want to take a ring signature
scheme and a standard digital signature
scheme and combine them so if we want to
assign a message we can produce
signatures under both scheme
but in order to preserve anonymity we
can't release the digital signature
signature so we can so so we might mask
it using a commitment and then the
signature that we can produce is
consists of a ring signature and also a
commitment to a standard signature and
then the other thing we want to we have
to worry about is we don't want to
remember assigning randomness so we can
we can sort of store a compressed
version of the sighting randomness using
using prfs and keep it as keeping the
pfk as part of the secret key and then
if we want to claim we can simply D
commit to this commitment and reveal
that this signature contained a
commitment to an ordinary digital
signature that's tied to my identity
but if I choose not to do commit and I
never open the commitment that it hides
my identity so it's also satisfies the
definitions of a normal ring signature
so now I'm going to move on to the
second notion unclaimed ability which we
built from lattice assumptions so the
idea of behind unclaimed ability is that
the signer cannot later come forward and
prove that they were the signer so in
order for this to be the case non
signers must be able to come up with
convincing signing randomness so that
anything produced by the signer
something indistinguishable can be
produced by any non signer in the ring
and the key technical tool for this will
be a lattice trapdoors so our scheme is
a Arin claim involving signature scheme
is a simple augmentation of the lattice
based ring signature scheme of recurse
key ankle I so and in this scheme I'm
gonna in this talk I'm going to present
a simplified version that only allows
you to sign random messages but in the
paper we give the full scheme so the
public key is going to be a an sas
matrix
so nlw matrix with an early a random
matrix with an sis chapter and then to
sign a random vector you use the
trapdoor to generate a short vector X
where all of the entries are small so
that a times X is equal to the message y
and then you can just release this so
this would be a digital signature for
random messages but of course it reveals
which matrix was used to generate the to
generate the signature to verify you
need to know which public key was used
so it's not a ring signature scheme but
suppose that we have a bunch of
different a bunch of different public
key is generated by different parties
and we want to produce a ring signature
with respect to the set of public keys
so we can concatenate them into a matrix
and then we can ask we have a we have a
message that we want to sign we can ask
we want to produce a very tall vector
with small entries so that the matrix
vector product equals the equals the the
target message and using trapdoor
extension techniques you can generate a
short X using the trapdoor for any one
of these a matrices so any party in the
ring can do this and so basically one
way to see this is you can break up this
matrix vector product as the sum of a
bunch of products of smaller matrices
with with with pieces of the vector and
then you can say suppose I'm party to I
can take all of the other terms in the
sum and move them to the other side and
then my trapdoor to matrix 2 allows me
to produce a short vector X to that so
that this equation is satisfied even
though I don't know I don't know trap
doors for any of the other a matrices so
this allows me to so
/ images generated under different
trapdoors are indistinguishable so the
signing random is generated by different
members of the Ring are all so innocent
miserable this means that no one can
credibly claim authorship of a signature
because anything that the true signer
can produce could also have been
produced by any other member of the Ring
so what I described here is a simplified
scheme that for signing random messages
but using the same transformations used
by Burke Erskine kalai we can turn this
into a unclaimed blowing signature
scheme for arbitrary messages so now I
want to turn to the final part of the
talk where I'm going to talk about
repeatability which we construct from
verifiable random functions so in a
reputable ring signature non signers are
able to prove that they were not
responsible for signing the message that
some other party of the ring in the ring
can sign the message what was the party
that signed the message so this really
consists of two separate guarantees
firstly we want to make sure that even
in the presence of a malicious signer
non signers are always able to repudiate
in the scheme and secondly we want to
make sure that no signer can later
repudiate if they want to distance
themselves from a message that they
actually produced so the key ingredients
the building blocks for our scheme are
zaps and brf's zaps are to message
public coin witness indistinguishable
proofs and vrf serve verifiable random
functions are pseudo-random functions
that also have the capability to release
a proof of the output associated with
any individual input without
jeopardizing residual pseudo randomness
of any other input so suppose we wanted
to use the vrf to produce a ring
signature well what we might do is we
say okay we can we can use the message
as the input to the VF and we can
produce an output and then we can also
prove that
that output is correct so the the public
key would consist of the public key and
then to sign a message you can release a
vrf evaluation and proof of the message
the problem is of course that this is
tied to an identity so we might want to
try to hide which identity was used to
produce the signature by using a sap you
know this isn't going to work so and the
SAP will say this is the right message
that this is the right output for the
vrf on input the message this isn't
going to work because apps provide only
a witness indistinguishability guarantee
so if there's only one witness they
don't actually hide it they're not
guaranteed to hide anything so this
won't this won't hide which member of
the Ring was responsible for producing
the signature it does give a digital
signature but not a ring signature so
instead let's try let's try to use two
VR FS and then use this app to prove the
statement that either the output under
the first three ref is correct or the
output under the second is correct and
here like in the security proof we can
switch from we can switch from using the
vrf of one party in the ring to the vrf
of another party in the ring so we can
get the unanimity definitions of a ring
signatures this does give a ring
signature but then when we want to
repudiate we have to show that that both
of these vrf output sisk is incorrect
and to do this we sort of we we still
can't do this I mean we can do this once
by sort of revealing our key material
and showing that these are these are the
these are the wrong values that my vrf
outputs are different but then I'm
revealing my vrf outputs and anyone else
can forge the same message the same
message under my key so we don't want
we'd so this is not good we want to make
sure you can repeat it over and over
again as many times as you want without
violating an anaemic without without
violating anonymity of later messages
that you sign and without allowing the
adversary to forge on messages that you
repudiate so this isn't going to work
either
so one didn't work two didn't work let's
try let's try four okay so now the
statement we want to use the self to
prove is that one of the first to v RF
outputs is correct and one of the last
year v RF outputs is correct and then
our signature will consist of the Zap
proof and the four outputs so now in
order to repudiate we want to show the
opposite of this statement we want to
show that if I want to repeat it I want
to show that for my key either one of
the first two outputs is incorrect
either both of the first two outputs is
incorrect
or both of the second apples or it is
incorrect so in order to do this I can
produce vrf proofs of each of these I
can produce a I sorry I can evaluate the
via naívi RF on the message and produce
these output values y1 prime and y 2
Prime and then I can prove that that my
v RF outputs are different
using a zap and then the other two
values Y 3 Prime my four prime are not
used in the honest repudiation but
they're used in the proof to two hybrid
over two hybrid from one from
repudiation under one signer to
repudiation under another signer and to
show that releasing these repudiation x'
does not jeopardize the other properties
that we want so to summarize we present
four new variants of ring signatures
claimable repeatable unclimbable and
unrepeatable
that provide functionality for allowing
members of a ring to to prove that they
were or were not responsible for for
producing it a particular signature and
also definitions that guarantee that
there should be impossible we all we
give constructions of these from various
and we give constructions of these from
various assumptions thanks very much
[Applause]
right Thank You Adam we have a little
bit of time for questions if you have a
questions please step up to the
microphones in the aisle so that
everyone can hear you so the question is
can we transform the unclaimed bill
construction from sis into a claimable
one so you can take any ring signature
construction and transform it into a
claimable one but if you start with one
that's unclimbable once you apply the
transformation will do it will no longer
be unclaimed it will no longer be
unclaimed Abul so you can you can turn
it into a claimable one but then you'll
you'll lose the structure that made it
unclaimed if you have an unconditional
what they say they'll be three
signatures by the secret key for any
secret key you can find the randomness
in the group so it would be so I'm not
sure the particular constructions you're
referring to but if you can produce
randomness for any signature that that
is indistinguishable from if if any
member of the Ring can produce signing
randomness that's indistinguishable from
real signing randomness for a particular
signature than it would be unclaimed
so thanks for the question in the
designated so in our definition of clam
bullring signatures there's no
designated honest party and the
definition you're referring to my
understanding of it is that you can at
the time of signing you can refer to you
can designate some public party who's
who's identified who can who later has
the ability to Dianna Mize you whenever
they want and our signature there's no
public party there's no trusted parties
at all in our claim but the designated
party candy anonymize here so you're not
anonymous with respect to the party that
you designate it's my understanding I'm
we can talk offline signatures because
the step-out ring signatures also has
this property
so I need to I need to look at the paper
you're referring to I'm not I'm not sure
thank you all right I think to add them
again
[Applause]