thank you for the introduction so this
is a joint work we just epidemia
sedimentary and I'm gonna introduce much
mega encryption this new type of
encryption scheme and before C in the
scheme let's start with an analogy with
the real world so let's talk about a
life drop and he also have seen this
technique in movies and allows basically
spies to share signal information
supposedly it's an organization composed
by people their identities are secret
but the only thing that you know it's
their job so there are detective spies
ninja and so and so far so let's assume
now that there is a detective that needs
to give a top secret information to the
ninja so a way to do that is it live
drop they choose our public place they
meet there so the exactly knows that
he's looking for a ninja and the ninja
is looking for a detection when they
meet basically the didactic can give
this a top secret information to the
other part so it's called life because
both party needs to interact and at the
same time and from a cryptography point
of view there is a scheme that
implements a such such a light drop that
is called secure than shake it's our key
exchange protocol there is an authority
that is basically responsible to
generates keys for the parties and the
keys contains the attributes of the
corresponding party so for example the
detective has the key for the adaboost
detective that's what that already does
and then the protocol Stan can start so
for example the attacker choose a policy
on the fly and the policy is a
description that the attributes of the
party must satisfy so the the party does
some pretty horrific operation reusing
the key and the policy and send a
message to the other party the other
party does the same send back the
message and the properties that they
share a secure Channel is both policy
are satisfied so there is a model match
signature some properties that the state
for the the
the intuitive one is the impersonator
resistant that basically says that it's
impossible to impersonate another person
so if I'm a minge and I have the
attributes for ninja I cannot pretend to
be a detective because I need the
corresponding key for the attributes and
the second one is called the tech toe
resistant that is ass or what a privacy
guarantee so suppose that the protocol
fails so at least one of the true policy
has not been satisfied then it's
impossible to do then mean which of the
true and this gives privacy guarantees
because if I choose the policy ninja I
cannot say that the other parties
unhinge or no because I don't know if my
policies satisfied so there is another
technique that was used that is called
that drop and basically it's a
non-interactive live drop so now instead
of a public place there is our secret
spot that both party knows so the
directly goes there sees the rock that
they also the other party knows and put
the top secret information on the diss
rock and then leaves so at some point
the ninja will come sister rock and
takes back the top secret information so
a cryptographic scheme that implements
at that drop must be seen as
non-interactive secret handshake so an
encryption scheme that has the same
property of signalling shake and this is
what it is a matchmaking encryption so
the level there is an authority again
that generates the keys for the party
that contains the attributes but it's
also responsible to generate an
additional decryption key that contains
the policy of the receiver and then the
sender can encrypt by choosing a policy
on the fly using the encryption key for
his attributes the policy and the
message produces ciphertext and the
receiver can decrypt by using the keys
so the kiss for that was the key for the
policy and the probably is the usual one
so if there is a mood of match so both
are satisfied then the receiver can
retrieve the message that level the
algorithms are the following there is
the setup algorithm that generates the
master public key the master secret key
and the master series used by the
authority to generate the keys then
there are
Shuki gen algorithm one is for the
sender so it's responsible to generate
the encryption key for the attributes
for the underside and there is the one
for the receiver that generates the
decryption key for the attitudes of the
receiver there is the third algorithm to
generate key the key for the policy so
the decryption key contains the policy
and then there is the standard
encryption decryption algorithm so the
first one takes the encryption key for
the attributes the policy undefined a
message and produces ciphertext and the
decryption takes the two keys so one for
the artist one for the policy the cipher
to retrieve and returns either the
message or an error so as I told you
much my encryption is unknown
Interactive secured a shake so must
guarantee the same probability that
cigarette shake has for this reason we
define true game based definition for to
capture these properties the first one
is called match security and
incorporates at the same time the CPA
security of the encryption scheme
together with the Tac Toe resistant so
here the attacker is the send the
receiver as Oracle access to the keygen
algorithms and during the game at some
point produces two challenges and each
challenge contain dips the input of the
encryption algorithm so the attributes
the policy and the message of the sender
the Challenger choosing one of the two
encrypts it and the objectives to get
the bid way so it's clear that this is a
CPA security definition because the day
received so the attacker can choose two
messages and also as Oracle access to
the center keygen so can ask for
encryption key and generates the
corresponding ciphertext
but notice that basically the attacker
can choose everything so can choose the
attributes of the sender the policy and
also they the policy and the attitudes
of the receiver by making Oracle queries
to the keygen algorithms so we have a
definition of valid adversary and what
basically says that since the bursar you
can choose everything can produce a
match or mismatch and if produce if they
Tucker produces our mismatch what we ask
is that basically both challenge lies in
one of this cartel each channel lies on
this category one of these categories so
it's a mismatch and note that the
doesn't they don't need to be on the
same class that for example the first
challenge will be a mismatch of this
type while the second one of this type
and this implies that we have detector
resistant because we're implicitly say
that these cases are indistinguishable
and in the definition is also an
additional case that the case where the
attacker has a match so it can actually
retrieve the messages the message so we
ask the attacker to put true message
that are even in the challenge face so
this definition is the Capitol's the CPA
security definition and the declare
system but we are still missing the
impersonator resistant so we have a
second definition that is called NTC now
the tackle is the sender has horrible
access to the keygen algorithm and what
the tackle needs to do is to produce a
ciphertext that correctly the creeps
under policy and without having the
corresponding key so with our via keye
for some multiples that match the policy
so which may include has policies has
attributes so the first question is what
is the relation with database encryption
so there are many mainly two what would
be different of the first one is called
suffered policy so where the sender I
used the policy it just our policy on
the fly and then creeps the message and
the decryption key of the receiver
contains the attributes and there is the
opposite that is called key policy now
they send their chooses the attributes
on the fly and the decryption key
contains the policy so much my
encryption implies cyber policy B
because the only thing that we have to
do is to ignore the policy of the
receiver and this can be done by setting
the policy to a tautology so a formula
that is always satisfied and the match
very encryption also implies key policy
B if you don't need NTC D because first
of all we can ignore the policy of the
sender using this
technique but few hours you can see
there is a me this is a difference
because the the sender has an encryption
key for the attributes why this is why
they we need an encryption key because
we want identity but of course if we
don't me that NTC these attributes can
be chosen on the fly and we have
keyboards IP there is a third case third
type of attribute based encryption is
called wall policy now there are two
policies and the one of the receiver is
containing the decryption key together
with the attributes and in this case the
true schemes remains incomparable
because they main difference that the
well-polished a single key while much
mental fracture and the image file
encryption if the receiver has multiple
keys can interleave them and this is not
possible in door policy and moreover if
you didn't care about the the decryption
key that the the problem of drug
policies that doesn't achieve much
security because it's always possible to
see if a policy satisfy or not so now we
are going to see how we can build much
many encryption and higher level this is
what is the workflow of the decryption
algorithm so as to check if both
policies satisfy if it is true generator
the message of device on an error so the
first question is why we don't build
much way in kill shop for attribute
based encryption because we have
suffered policy and key policy maybe we
can use both to have much Maggie and
let's forget for the moment about this
it is all so let's assume that we want a
much more encryption scheme that
attributes are choosing on-the-fly a way
to do that is to encrypt use a key
policy ABI to first encrypt the message
and then encrypt the again the
ciphertext with the cyber policy ABI
so now we have to decryption keys one
for the attributes that is the
decryption key of cyber policy B so we
can remove the layer on the crypts on
faith and we can use the second key what
they were for the policy to remove the
last layer and retrieve the message so
from a simple article a synthetical
point of view this looks like how much
my encryption scheme but the promise
that doesn't achieve much security and
they gave you the intuition before
because basically any nothing
encryption scheme is responsible only to
handle a single policy and what that
policy is not satisfied basically
returns an error message so there are
methods the the information that the
police is not satisfied so in this
example basically when we tried to for
example to decrypt the first layer we
retrieve the method error message we
know that the policies not satisfied and
been in details these two cases so the
one that the policy of the sender is not
satisfying the one of the receiver yes
and the opposite are always
distinguishable and these are two cases
of the match the security definition so
this give us the intuition that in order
to have matchmaking to implement much
more encryption we need to check that
both policies are satisfied tonically
otherwise it's impossible to have as
much security and from the vanilla point
of view we have two results we were able
to build a much more encryption from
randomized functional encryptions engine
or interacted zero knowledge we have a
second results where we replace the
randomized function encryption scheme
with a two input for a functional
encryption so we can trade the
randomization of the function with a two
input function so let's see the the
first result what is a functional
encryption scheme
there are decryption key for functions
is it possible to encrypt a message
using a public key and the properties
that when we decrypt using the
decryption key what we obtain is the
valuation of the function we didn't put
the encrypted message and the guarantee
the security guarantees that nothing is
leaked except the output of the function
there is the randomized version
basically the same were the
functionalities randomized so when we
decrypt usually we evaluate the function
with some fresh anonymous so how we
build much more encryption we use two
functions one is randomized why miss
deterministic the randomized one has are
coded the attributes of the receiver and
takes in input the attributes of the
send that the policy and the message and
this function checks they say if the
policy studies if the sender policy is
satisfied
this is true Riaan Clips the attributes
of the the sender and the message using
the encryption the encryption algorithm
functional encryption otherwise
re-encrypt encrypts to error messages
using the same encryption algorithm then
we have a second function that as I call
it now the Polish of the receiver takes
an input the attributes of the sender
and the message so what the previous
function encrypt and thus the N checks
them but they decide if the policy of
disability satisfied if it is true
return the message otherwise the darn
error so basically what we are doing
here is we are using two different
function to check the true policies and
we are were pass information to the
second fashion encrypted fashion in
order to don't leak an information and
this allows to check both policy in
atomic way so just to conclude basically
the decryption key for data bus will be
the decryption key foe of the randomized
function encryption scheme and the
decryption key of the policy will be the
decryption key of function of the
function encryption scheme so these
construction as it is allows us to have
match security but still we miss
authenticity and how we keep that is we
use a signature interacted
zero-knowledge
at eye level basically the signature is
used by the authorities to certify that
the party has the process that
attributes so the signature will be the
encryption key and then we use known
interacted zero knowledge to prove that
the attributes that are encrypting here
are attributes that the party possess so
in other signature that correct bellezza
verifies under these attributes and what
we need zero knowledge because we need
to only can information about the
attributes because otherwise an
information about that was can give us
the carry belief a policy satisfied no
so we don't have much security so I'll
mention some of the results that way you
can find out the paper we have an
implementation of an identity based
version so basically attribute
some policies are binary string and the
policy satisfies these choose strings
are equal we put forward with with the
final definitions and were able to build
this identity based version from the
Berliner the fear my assumption there
are no more core then we we implemented
an anonymous bulletin board that use
identity based much money encryption to
allows parties to posterity messages
accorded to the entities and productive
privacy used by the match security
definition the match property and lastly
we have a an alternative version of much
money encryption where now instead of
heavy chookies we have a single kid that
incorporates together the attributes and
the policy like in world policy be and
still we have the magical definition
with the identity definition and in this
case we are able to be the scheme from
directly from functional encryption as
in even know interact it's your
knowledge so you can find the detail on
the the paper on the full version and
that's it so thank you and happy to us
[Applause]
if you have a question please come to
the microphone we have a lot of time for
questions already cut encryption it's
their functional encryption would it be
sufficient or do you need it seems like
you only need security in the case where
things don't decrypt which is usually
much easier well the problem is that we
need to policy so we will need to
predicate encryption right and the
problem is that how you how you merge
these two schemes because if you using
naive way like we use a two bit
encryption we don't you don't have a
match security that's the problem so you
need like animal like a proper of the
true scheme that doesn't leak any
information about the predicate that's
the problem so I don't think it's
sufficient more questions so I have a
question do you have any intuition
whether we can prove that it is
impossible to achieve much making
encryption from attribute based
encryption in the blackbox way or we
don't have such result I mean it's an
intuition ok if you don't assume any
additional assumption so any altered
scheme on an additional sample the
intuition is that is not possible
because it's hard to come by the true
schemes that's the end have much
security I mean I don't have been
possibility result but that's just an
intuition ok thanks
more questions
yeah let's thank speak again
[Applause]