hi everyone so I'm Ruth and I'm
presenting some work that I did together
with mahira and Buuren and our work is
called Nantes I noticed a ad revisited
so our works on symmetric encryption so
maybe when you think of symmetric
encryption you get a picture like this
in your head I think we can all agree
encryption should probably take a
message
it should probably return something and
decryption should probably take that
output and recover the message
encryption and decryption should
probably also share a key and you would
think for how long we've been using
symmetric encryption we should have
figured out by now all the other inputs
but we seem to still not have made up
our mind
so let's step through a bit of the
evolution of how symmetric encryption
has worked over the years so I guess
it's a crypto talk so I need to start
with the one-time pad and we eventually
moved on to randomized notions of
symmetric encryption and our security
goals move forward to privacy in CPA
style security goals this was usually a
company with schemes that were motor
operation oxide for things like CBC if I
can fast forward to where we are
currently you will see that standards
and protocols are using nonce based
encryption what I'm gonna call and be1
syntax and our security goals have moved
from privacy only to now requiring
privacy and integrity better known as a
EAD so your env1 schemes are GCM which
everyone knows is used in TLS and other
things like OCB and the final portfolio
of caesar and stuff like that so why did
I call this one MV one obviously because
I'm going to define and be e 2 so we
like to see our work as the next step in
this evolution we find our problem with
the syntax of NBE one and we propose a
new syntax and B 2 and we give a
slightly stronger notion of security
which is nonce hiding ayyy so I'm gonna
go into this now so maybe let's take
another step back and talk about
what does it mean to have a
cryptographic definition so perhaps you
are aware there are two components every
cryptographic definition syntax and
security
so what syntax syntax is what are the
inputs and outputs of your algorithms
are they randomized are they
deterministic that kind of stuff and so
as I showed on the previous slide we all
have the message and the output of the
ciphertext and the key and what the
syntax should really tell us is what
additional inputs your algorithm should
be getting security we usually define
this using a game and the game just
needs to have anniversary it has
Oracle's and the game decides when the
adversary wins and how well the
adversary is doing by advantage function
so let's go into how NB 1 is defined so
this was defined by raga way and others
so if we have a scheme SE 1 our syntax
NB 1 will take a message and produce
what we call a core ciphertext and from
this course I protect you should be able
to retrieve the message and a special
input we have here is what we call a
nonce
so what is a nonce nonce stands for a
number used once so it should be any non
repeating quantity and so in the real
world I guess the most common cases of
nonces are random numbers and counters
but you can also see people use things
like this sector numbers packet numbers
device identifier as nonsense so long as
it's non repeating and I will draw your
attention to the two things in yellow
that's very important for the rest of
this talk that we're supposed to be able
to pick any non repeating quantity and
that the nonce is given as input to both
encryption and decryption and I'll also
make the note that half of a EAD is the
ad part but I'm gonna leave that out for
this presentation to keep it simple you
can look at my paper if we want to talk
about ad so let's go to a high-level
idea what the security goals are this is
privacy and authenticity so anniversary
with
access to the Quique should not be able
to distinguish the outputs of encryption
from random and it should not be able to
get the decryption to return anything
but reject for those of you who like
games this is a picture depicting the
game you see the adversary has access to
two Oracle's and it needs to distinguish
in a real world an ideal world and
idealized the encryption should return
random strings idealize decryption
always returns both and I will just note
that these are the notions of security
under which things like GCM and OCB have
been proven secure and of course to
capture the idea of a nonce we don't let
the adversary repeat a nonce to the
encryption Oracle but it can repeat
nonsense of decryption however likes so
now we can get to the main question that
motivated all of our research which is
how does this nonce that goes into
encryption go over to decryption and go
into decryption and we realized that
there's a difference between how it was
presented in theory and how it actually
happens in practice so in theory it
looks something like this it seems like
between encryption and decryption it
sort of magically gets there maybe they
conjure it up on the other side maybe
there's a wormhole I don't know not mine
to judge but in practice we haven't
really figured out the wormhole yet so
we send it in the clear with the
ciphertext seems like a simple solution
seems like it can't hurt right right so
just to give you some idea that I'm not
making all this up these are some quotes
from the original rock paper that says
that nonce transmission is kind of
outside the model it's kind of out of
Bend all right but if you look at RFC
5.16 which talks about how you should
implement a EAD it says well send it
with the ciphertext you should be
alright so this is where we get to the
title of our paper which is nonsense
unnoticed which says that well suddenly
announced in the clear can compromise
privacy in kind of an obvious way
um so think about anniversary who gets
to pick the nonce and literally sets the
nouns to be the hash of the message
assess the nouns to be the first part of
the message
there's an obvious idea of semantic
security that's being salted here but
yet our formalization doesn't capture
this because the formalization doesn't
need to communicate the nonce between
the sender and receiver even if we don't
talk about message privacy we can talk
about sender privacy where nonces are
effectively metadata and it reveals
information about who the sender is and
thereby compromises user and on every
deal and you can see this in RFC five
one one six again which recommends that
part of your nonce to be made up of a
device specific identifier and this
would obviously be able to let an
adversary tell which device you're
sending something from if you're sending
the nonce in the clear and we all note
also that because a e 1 and B 1 is
supposed to be indistinguishable from
random it's supposed to give you
anonymity sort of for free but if we
then go and send the nonce with it well
you kind of defeat at the whole point so
I guess the natural next question would
be what what impact does this have on
things like GCM and TLS are we are we
completely screwed no no it's not a
problem in TLS for those of you who are
worried because in TLS the nonce is not
transmitted in the clear but it may be a
problem depending on how you use in
other users of GCM other uses of other
mv-1 schemes because the attack that I
sketched on the previous slide kind of
can be extended to any
nb1 scheme that chooses to send the
nonce in the clear and so it's not that
this problem somehow shows that AE one
security does not hold it just says that
there's a gap between how we thought
about it and how it's actually being
used so to fill in this gap what we did
was we want to propose a new definition
a new syntax and a new security
definition and after that I need to show
you how to do it how to get schemes that
achieve this notion of security so we're
gonna do this by transforms which take
existing primitives like an NB one
scheme and return NB two schemes so
let's do a brief interlude to say that
we're not alone in pointing out that
this is a issue that needs to be
addressed shortly after our paper was
published Denver NC came up to us and
said that you know he was concerned
about similar stuff when they were
writing up the call for Caesar and it
was reflected in the call for Caesar
because Caesar has sort of a public
message number and a secret message
number and this was actually formalized
as a e5 but this is different from our
formalization and I told Dunkleman and
Lux use the NBA to syntax but they use
it for to achieve RUP
which is kind of cool and we think that
the future direction of our work would
be to extend our syntax to all these
other interesting kinds of AE that's
coming up and see if sending nonces in
the clear causes any problems down the
line for any of this stuff all right so
let's return to our two parts of a
security definition and start with the
nd2 syntax so spot the difference that's
not a big difference here the difference
is that decryption doesn't receive the
nonce anymore it's only an input to
encryption and we're going to call this
C now the full ciphertext as opposed to
the KO ciphertext in particular this
means that if decryption needs the nonce
to perform decryption you need to
somehow send it inside of C and so we
have a better way to inspect how the
nonce communication is occurring let's
move on to security so security is not
too different from the initial notion we
basically just extend it to cover the
new syntax so the only thing to note is
that decryption now doesn't get an
anymore as an input and the encryption
Oracle should return a random string
that saw the lengths comparable to the
full ciphertext and not the core
ciphertext okay so I can move right
along how do we construct these AE to
secure and b2 schemes and we think that
the correct way to do this is by
transforms because if we start
constructing a you to secure env to s
key from scratch you're kind of ignoring
all the work that has been done to
standardize and optimize and prove
secure all these great and b1 schemes
not to mention other primitives so how a
transform works is it takes an NB one
scheme a c1 and maybe some other
primitives and gives you back an AE to
secure and v2 scheme it's like magic
it's great and what goals do we have for
this transforms our goals are we want
have no ciphertext overhead and we want
to have constant computational overhead
so I'll note that for the 0 ciphertext
overhead it's not a simple comparison of
the length of the call ciphertext and
the length of the full ciphertext
because that's kind of not a fair
comparison
if in usage you're sending the nonce in
the clear what you really should be
comparing is the length of the nonce
concatenate that with the core
ciphertext and the length of the
fullcycle text so that's what we're
going to define a ciphertext overhead
and this actually makes it slightly
non-trivial to achieve to achieve a to
secure and b2 schemes in practice
because after nonces are shorter than
one block of your encryption primitive
docks like for primitive so you can't
just do the trivial thing of like let's
push it through a box lifer and hope it
works ok so to give you a flavor of how
it works here's one of our transforms
which I put in a picture over there so
how the transform works is with this
equation over here where se sub H n1 is
an NB 2 scheme and it takes an NB 1
scheme se 1 and a PRF F and it all puts
an envier to ski
so the basic idea here that's occurring
is you take the first block of the core
ciphertext C star that comes out of the
encryption Oracle and you and cipher
that using the using the PRF then you
use this as a masking value to mask the
nonce okay so this is how and then
you've asked the nonce and during
decryption you can unmask the nonce
because you have access to the core
ciphertext and you can retrieve what the
masking value was and this it under this
construction we truly can say that any
non repeating non-spell have been fine
because even if you chose the hash of
the message or some equally silly nonce
you haven't been masked by this random
string and now you're golden the whole
cipher text looks indistinguishable from
random it's great so we show in our
paper that if F is a PRF and s you wanna
cheese a you on security your scheme as
a whole will achieve a u2 security and
just to show you another transform this
one may be a little bit simpler this one
uses a synthetic nonce so what you do is
you in cipher the nonce you get a nonce
n/2 and you use that with the encryption
instead this is a simpler construction
and maybe a little bit reminiscent of
SIV and it's it's more efficient to
because in decryption you don't need to
retrieve the nonce anymore it's kind of
sent with it and you can see some of the
trade-offs between computational
overhead and security here because this
one's much more efficient but the
security bound is worse so let me just
sum up all that I have today so I'll
talk deals with AE wants to kill MV one
schemes like GCM ocv and the Caesar
candidates we address a gap that we
think exists between formalisms
and usage we want to say that
communicating a nonce in the clear is
not as fine as it may seem it violates
privacy and to address this issue we
give a new definition of syntax and
security and we show that it's very
simple and efficient to construct a to
secure and v2 schemes that's all I have
thanks
thank you very much for the presentation
are there any questions
what's the question
people just pointing at each other okay
then then I would have a question please
[Music]
so you said you you leave out the
details of the AEDs like you you said
you focus on a version of encryption
which doesn't consider associated data
do you have results about IDs in your
paper and if yes can you give a brief
overview what's happening then like is
it the same just IDs edit or is there
more structure happening yes in our
paper we treat our whole formalism has
headers or associated data in it and for
the basic constructions that we sort of
give here it's pretty much a natural
extension because the headers just given
as input to your and b1 schemes but with
our we also have some advanced schemes
in the paper that I didn't talk about
here which kind of extends nonce misuse
and then it gets a little bit more
interesting how to fit the head a yeah
okay thank you any more questions and
they are in fact that there's
microphones apparently somewhere can you
it's okay I can do well it depends on
the model that you're referring to so
I'm not super I'm not super familiar
which with which 32-bit you're talking
about but what I will say to that is if
your version of encryption covers those
32 bits or nouns the 32 bits then it
needs to you you need to come up with a
formalism that incorporates that I have
a question up here so there are people
who want to use some very short nonces
they just assume that nonsense do not
repeat if you transform these short
nonce into another nouns with a in a to
the random way you have you you may have
some some problem with collisions right
so you need some collision resistance so
are you losing something this way so it
depends on which one of our transforms
you use so some of our transforms will
incur sort of like a birthday bound
problem which is something like the last
transform I showed but we also have
other techniques yeah so you're saying
that what the sender doesn't want to
leak data I understand and we're not
saying that we're not saying that
there's anyone out there who is selling
the nonce to be the hash of the message
or something equally stupid
but even something like counters right I
mean that reveals information that is
not captured in the model right a
counter with differentiate between a
stream that's sending many packets in
the stream that's sending very few
packets I I was wondering what your
constructions had to do with kinetise
paper on generic construction a lot of
what I saw in your slides looked very
similar to kinetise paper that talked
about different secure ways to use
nonces and wonder how your work relates
to that paper so like I tried to say in
our presentation we're not trying to
claim that these transforms are like
somehow new or exciting and we think
that the main contribution of our paper
is definitional but we included the
transforms which makes use of many
existing known techniques which we cite
in the paper because it seems logical
that if you present a definition you
should tell people how to achieve that
level of security okay thank you very
much
[Applause]