so today I will be talking about our
recent work on fhg in the RAM model this
is a joint work with Justin Moore Weiss
and Daniel wicks
so consider the setting where I actually
know which button to press to advance
the slides consider the setting in which
we have a data owner that has some
database that they wish to outsource to
the cloud encrypt it we're considering
in this case the server to be our
adversary and this data owner would like
to allow other clients to essentially
upload programs to the server the server
to execute them and hand back the
encrypted results so in this paradigm we
have a client who says I would like to
run a binary search program across this
database that this data owner has
provided so the client has to hand some
representation of this program to the
server for it to run and the traditional
fhe setting this program takes the form
of a circuit whether it be boolean or
arithmetic so it hands this over the
circuit by Mississippi takes in the
entire database as input and outputs
some encrypted results which is then
handed back to the client to do with
what they will I will note in the
setting the server itself can also
submit programs that it wants to run and
it will get some encrypted output with
but without the key the output is
essentially meaningless so in this
setting where we're considering a
circuit representation of this program
the runtime by necessity is going to be
at least linear in the size of the data
set
which in the case of algorithms such as
binary search which would have a
logarithmic runtime in the size of the
database is really really sub optimal so
this motivates the case of can we
consider a different model of
computation to allow for fhe
particularly if we
are able to give the underlying program
in its Ram program format essentially we
give the server some representation that
allows it to make queries into this
encrypted database get that value back
and fold that into the subsequent
computations so on and so forth until we
get the encrypted results well this is
the model that we are working in and it
much more closely adheres to the
underlying runtime of the program
offered to the server namely in this
case we are able to achieve a runtime
much much more sort of close to our
underlying log and runtime of binary
search so this is the model of
computation that we want to support in
our Ram fhe setting and construction I
will note that we differ from other
primitives sort of of this type such as
garbled Ram and that we allow any person
to come along and submit these programs
essentially and we're not limited to a
certain class of program essentially we
can say submit NEP here and have the
server essentially run this and get some
encrypted output so that being our
setting our goal of this talk is to
construct the first sort of proof of
concept construction of Ram fhe and to
run in this setting essentially any Ram
program across an encrypted database so
syntactically what does this look like
it is essentially the standard fhe
syntax or public key encryption syntax
in which we have a key generation
algorithm an encryption algorithm that
takes in the database and outputs an
encrypted version of that database and a
decryption algorithm that takes in
decrypts if you have the secret key in
addition we have an evaluation algorithm
that is capable of taking in some Ram
program P some time bound T which we
expect P to run in less than and outputs
the encrypted value of running P across
this encrypted database so here
represented as P superscript DB and this
value is encrypted using the public key
decryption then is able to take this
value in and essentially output the
result of running this program across
this encrypted database we say that
security is standard
indistinguishability CPA we should not
be able to distinguish between two
database encryptions nor should
evaluation give us any information to be
able to do that distinguishing what I've
shown here is what we call our single
hop fhe Ram paradigm which is to say
that essentially any program that we
want to run for evaluation is run across
again the same database updates are not
made as part of the program we also have
a multi hop variant which does allow for
updates in this database that are
present and can be folded into
subsequent RAM executions I will be
focusing primarily on the single hop
version today see the paper for more
details on the fhe multi-hop version so
in this setting we are able to achieve
at a high level a scheme based on secret
key doubly efficient p r-- or deep here
which are as a primitive sort of first
introduced by Kennedy at all and boil at
all and 2017 and VBB for a specific
class of circuits these are fairly
heavy-duty primitives but we were able
to show that even with assuming these it
is not a straightforward construction
and which is why this is sort of the
first proof of concept in this class
we are able to get in terms of
complexity for any epsilon greater than
zero an evaluation runtime for our
single hop case and which is T where T
is the runtime of the underlying Ram
program lambda is our security parameter
and n is the size of our database we are
able to get essentially a runtime that
only has a poly log n overhead over just
the plane evaluation of the program for
our multi hop case same parameters
except that we have an N to the epsilon
overhead as well essentially
representing the changes that you have
sort of done to the database and
ingesting those we also introduced as
part of our construction a variant on
rewind or an o RAM that we call rewind
below Ram which we believe is a
primitive of independent interest so
without further ado I want to go into a
little bit of how we actually construct
RAM for fhe so remember our setting
where we have our database we have our
evaluator that takes in a program a time
bound and outputs an encrypted result of
evaluating P over this data set we have
four primary difficulties in this
construction the first of which is
because we have RAM access to this
database inherently we have access
patterns what elements of the database
that the evaluator is actually accessing
and we have to hide these access
patterns without necessarily having a
consistent state between different
executions of different programs we also
need within an execution of a single
program the ability to evaluate or
emulate statefulness so program
essentially has States you can think of
it as the register contents or things
like that and we need to hide this
evaluation state from the evaluator or
the server who we are considering
malicious we also have to enforce honest
behavior of this event
waiter so they don't essentially twist
the evaluation of the program in order
to get information about the database
and finally as part of this evaluation
process hiding access patterns and
encrypting this final result requires
randomness so we mean the evaluator to
be able to generate that to feed it into
those two steps so those are our four
main areas of difficulty today these
three with some crypto tricks and
throwing VBB off eustachian are tricky
but quite doable this one is the mean
source of difficulty here how do we hide
access patterns without necessarily
having a consistent state and that's
what I want to focus on today which is
how do we build a tool that allows us to
hide these access patterns so to
motivate why this is difficult
consider our following case where the
program that we are asking the evaluator
to evaluate is the following if we have
we essentially read the first element of
the database and if it is less than 5 we
do some access if it's not we read the
third element and do a different access
so inherently built into this program is
some information about the first element
of the database and the evaluator even
not getting the decrypted output can
tell what is the first element of the
database or at least some information
about it based on the access patterns
alone and this will now remember our Ram
fhe security goal this will break it so
hiding access patterns is imperative if
we want to achieve security of our
overarching Ram fhe construction so
consider the case where we've solved all
of the problems VBB does everything and
so what we're going to do now is forgive
me there this some of the graphics have
gotten a little mad
stuff in the translation process so
consider this being the Oh Ram client
state so we have as part of our
evaluation process an obfuscated Oh Ram
client with some state if we want to run
the program which is going to be P here
from our previous example and all of
these accesses are now happening
underneath sort of the o Ram client here
we can say that these access patterns
are essentially hidden and not giving
the adversary any information about the
database however the o Ram client is
going to essentially run it will update
its own internal state it has to do so
in order to provide obliviousness either
push things down a path or shuffle
things around depending on your Oh RAM
construction once we're done with this
program however and we want to run
another program imagine that this is
changing different colors to represent a
new state the o RAM is now in a new
state in order to run another program
however P prime this state is going to
revert back to our original a ram state
because things are not preserved between
different executions because we are in
sort of a case where state is not shared
so in practice the state is going to be
remapped so when we execute this program
we are making essentially the same style
or the same first access in P Prime as
in the original P and so we are going to
get the exact same first access pattern
in our subsequent program execution as
we did in our initial one this means
that essentially standard Oh Ram schemes
because our state is not maintained
between two different program executions
it's not going to maintain its
obliviousness it will have the exact
same access pattern because that initial
element is going to be in the exact same
place in that initial state so we're not
providing obliviousness we are not no
longer hiding access patterns and thus
our RAM fhe security is going to be
broken if we just assume we have a
standard Oh Ram client using VBB off you
station which makes us realize that we
need an oblivious Ram with an additional
property namely we need security
so obliviousness is maintained when the
client and server state are rewound to
an initial or previous state we
introduce two variants of this we have a
initial State rewind herbal or ISRO Ram
where we say obliviousness holds if we
only rewind if we only rewind to
essentially this initial okay sorry okay
I'm not gonna mess with this anymore
so only rewinds to essentially this
initial state and subsequent executions
or access patterns essentially create
two parallel execution paths this is
analogous to our single hop and is fhu
in which this is the actual a Ram used
to hide access patterns in that
particular construction we also
introduce a notion of any state rewind
below Ram or a SRO Ram which instead of
having sort of two parallel execution
paths allows you to branch off from any
intermediate point we have here that
this is used primarily in our multi-hop
fhe scheme and we formalize this through
standard correctness and security games
as in standard Oh Ram but we say that is
parameterised through the state that you
are in
so our construction relies primarily on
secret to deep here this is essentially
in essence a read-only ORM scheme with a
stateless client and server we have a
set up
function that takes in a database output
some client key and an encoded database
which is then handed to the server
we say that essentially this gives us
the same obliviousness security
guarantees a standard Aram but only
supports reads at this point we have
constructions for this by committee at
all and boil at all based on noisy /
muted reed-muller codes and we can get
different parameters based on the
underlying reed-muller paradigms so what
we have now is essentially a read-only
isro Ram the question is how do we
support writes we do this using a
standard o Ram but the trick is when we
initialize that standard of RAM our
setup procedure takes in our database
generates our client key and generates
the encoded secret key deep your version
of our database access also now is going
to be R in charge of initializing the
standard Oh Ram our first access
regardless of whether it's a read or
write will generate a standard empty Oh
Ram and hand that to the server
subsequent accesses if it's a write will
grow that Oh Ram writing to it growing
it as needed
read accesses will read both of these
two data structures and take it from the
Oh Ram if it is present representing any
updates that have been done to the
static encoded database we get security
here because any rewind will essentially
erase that standard o RAM that is
created upon the first access and the
secret qdp error is essentially
stateless giving us rewind security for
free so in terms of our results we are
able to construct an ISR and ASR Oh Ram
scheme based on secret key deep here the
schemes inherit the secret key deeper
complexity namely initial state is poly
log in the size of the database any
state is slightly more complicated but
not much and we are able to use this
primitive now within our f8
she construction so if you remember our
four main problems we now have
essentially tackled this one by saying
steep does not matter so we do not need
to maintain a consistent state we now
have three remaining challenges the
first of which is how do we emulate
statefulness in and essentially hide
that client state what we do here is
represent the program as a series of
obfuscated steps circuits so essentially
a step circuit is going to take in the
current client state it will take in a
database entry basically a the database
entry as requested by the Oh RAM client
that the step circuit is running and the
state itself will be encrypted under a
hardwired key within this circuit we
will then sort of do whatever the
program tells us to do update the state
and ask for the next value in this
database so the evaluator is essentially
just running a series of these step
circuits up to time T we then throw a
few station EBP obvious Kishin over that
entire thing and call it a day
so that is how we are able to get
statefulness and hide that client state
from the evaluator we also need to
enforce honest behavior in order to get
correctness for our ruined below Ram
schemes and also security the way we do
this is to that step circuit we add two
things we add a Mac of the client state
in order to say that we don't mix and
match state we also over the database
instantiate a Merkle tree so when any
element that is given to the step
circuit is also given the path in the
Merkle tree which the step circuit can
now evaluate and make sure that it is
getting handed the correct database
element that it asked for so that's how
we enforce honest client sort of honest
input into this step circuit we also
Merkle tree
and then finally we have to generate
randomness the way we do that is we
hard-code a prf key within the step
circuit and in order to generate
randomness apply the PRF across the
entire execution history to generate
unique randomness for that particular
instance in summary this allows us to
construct the first proof-of-concept fhe
for ram construction in order to create
that construction we also introduced a
variant of a ram that we call reminder
below ram and we are able to get the
following parameters for our fhe for
ram's construction we provide a single
and multi hop version and for our rewind
below ram we provide a initial State
rewind Apple secure and in any state or
wine double secure already there are a
couple of open problems from sort of
introducing this as a construction and a
concept our main sort of open problem of
our construction is can we reduce the
assumptions that we rely on is it
possible to get RAM fhe from i/o or
something similar also is it possible to
contextualize the underlying noisy /
muted reed-muller code assumptions that
secret key deep here relies on so thank
you at this point for listening to my
talk and I'm happy to take any questions
if you have a question please come to
the microphone
right thank you for the nice talk so I'm
on one of the slides I was wondering
that you have the SK deep here and you
have the standard over m and in a read
and write operations in one of them you
to read from one of them you do operate
on one and in the other you operate on
both of them so how do you hide that
pattern like how can you make it
indistinguishable so essentially it's as
you would any around you do a dummy
operation so for reads you do a dummy
you read or so you do valid reads
essentially on both of the two and on a
right you have so if you want to be able
to hide we don't necessarily but it is
trivial to hide the difference between
read and writes if you're going to do a
read operation you also grow your
underlying ogram so the size of the / M
is now going to grow the total number of
operations rather than just the total
number of writes thanks I have another
question okay so do you know any of the
existing implementation of SK DPR like
who can comment on concrete efficiency
such things I know that there are a
couple of different sort of asymptotic
evaluations of different paradigms I am
not aware of any concrete
implementations of secret key deep here
it would share fairly similar parameters
as to any implementation of reed-muller
codes
less thanks to speak again
[Applause]