thank you for the introduction so I'm
going to talk about short vectors in
idea lattices ideal lattices are a
particular kind of Euclidean lattices
and let computational problems and
Euclidean analysis provide a strong
foundation for passports and
cryptography and essentially you want to
good cryptography schemes to security
rely more or less in the problem of
finding short vectors in such a fijian
lattices
how short well how approach you want the
victor fine vectors will determine the
difficulty of the problem on any lattice
you have some shortest vectors these are
the hardest to find if you're interested
in finding the shortest vectors of your
lattice you can do it thanks to the
algorithm bkz but it will take you
exponential time in the dimension of the
lattice is the point here on this graph
but you can make the problem simpler by
asking not to find the shortest vectors
of your lattice but some approximate
shortest vectors vectors that one of the
shortest but the shortest up to some
approximation factor and when the
approximation factor is large the crown
becomes simpler in particular if
interested in approximation factors that
are exponential in the dimension then
you can do this in time polynomial in
the dimension thanks to the algorithm
lll it's the point at the bottom of this
graph now I mentioned ideal lattices
ideal lattices or a particular case of
Euclidean lattices the plan with generic
lattices is that when you try to design
cryptographic schemes based on problems
in them you realize very quickly that
you're going to end up with a lot of
memory and bandwidth requirements so you
can use some lighter alternative
lattices with more structures that allow
you to build faster algorithms faster
protocols with a lighter in memory and
bandwidth and the typical example of
this or cyclotomic idea lattices so what
are psychodrama kto lattices the rest of
the talk I'm going to fix an integer M
together with a primitive nth root of
unity Omega so Omega is a complex number
which raised to the power M is 1 I'm
defining the field came to be Q a joint
Omega
it's the cyclotomic field of conductor m
it is a number field of degree fee of M
where a field is an Euler station
function this field K contains a sub
ring Z brackets Omega which I write o
which is the ring of integers of this
field so where are our lattices well K
is a number field of the Griffey of them
so it embeds into the real vector space
of dimension fee of M through what we
call minkowski's embedding and through
this embedding of the field into a
vector space the sub ring the ring of
integers becomes a lattice so o can be
seen as the lattice is this real vector
space of dimension fee of M so here we
have a real lattice but in fact we have
many more lattices because any ideal in
this ring o is also a lattice in that
vector space and these are what we call
ideal lattices so they come with all
kinds of additional algebraic structure
compared to generic lattices so they
allow you to build very interesting
protocols but of course you have to
wonder does the problem of finding sure
that just becomes simpler and yes it
does become simpler it has been proven
that we can find short to victors more
efficiently at least if you have a
quantum computer this is a result of the
long series of works culminating in
primary tour 2017 where it was shown
then that in ideal lattices you can find
in quantum polynomial time a sub
exponential approximation of the
shortest vector so you can cut the graph
in the middle and here it's quantum
polynomial time ok so the object of the
paper I am presenting today is
understanding precisely when do these
quantum algorithms start outperforming
lll and bkz because these all
asymptotics it doesn't tell much about
what's happening with concrete
parameters so how do these algorithms
work they come essentially in two parts
the first part deals with a particular
family of ideals called principle ideals
a principle idealism and I do that has a
generator meaning that a is principle if
it has a generator G which is an element
such that a is just G times the ring G
is called the generator and instead of
looking at the problem of finding short
elements in a you can look at the
I didn't regenerate to Sophie so it
sounds like you're making the problem
more difficult because now instead of
finding a short arbitrary thing you're
asking for a short thing that is also a
generator but it's making the problem
somehow simply by highlighting the
relevant algebraic structure so this is
the approach taken in this series of
work starting by with a
Kember little in 2014 so how do you do
this you look at the following problem
you're given a principal ideal a and you
look for a shortener a trope a how short
well this short you want it to have
Euclidean norm this quantity where on
the left here you have essentially the
length of the shortest vector of the
lattice and what remains of course is
the approximation factor which in our
case is a sub-exponential quantity in
the dimension so you want to find
something of that length how are you
going to do this it's a two steps
process you're given a principal ideal a
you know it has a generator where you're
not given a generator so the first step
is to find one so find an arbitrary
generator this is already a non-trivial
problem but it can be solved in quantum
polynomial time it's the result of
guessing in 2016 but this algorithm that
finds a generator finds a generator that
is usually extremely large so the second
step consists in finding your shorter
one why would you find an arbitrary one
in the first place well if you have a
generator you're in a better position
because now you have a search space
you're given an arbitrary generator G of
a so you know that the set of all
generators is G times o star where L
star is this a group of the group of not
of units of Eureka okay so you have a
short a search space you're looking for
a short element in this set here so the
way you're going to try to find a short
element in there is by transforming this
problem to a lattice problem through
what we call the logarithmic embedding
and this is what has been done
incremental 2016 the logarithmic
embedding so here's the definition I'm
not going to go through it but what you
have to understand is simply that it
behaves as you would expect from a
logarithmic map in that it transforms a
multiplicative structure into additive
structure it takes the multiplicative
structure of K star and transforms it
into the additive structure of this
vector space in particular it
transformed the group of units o star
into a lattice which we call the
logarithmic unit lattice
Lago Vista so if we apply this
logarithmic map to our problem what do
we get
remember we're looking for a short
generator of G times L we know that the
set of all generators is G times o star
if we apply the logarithmic embedding
map you are looking for a short element
in a translated lattice because the
logarithm of G times F star is the
logarithm of this element plus this log
unit lattice so now you're looking for a
short element in a translated lattice
that can be done by solving an instance
of the closest vector problem with
respect to this lattice log of F star so
we reduced our problem to a closest
vector problem it's not clear how that
helps because the process Viktor problem
is also a difficult problem unless you
know a lot about your lattice and here
we do know a lot about this lattice the
logarithmic unit lattice has been
studied very thoroughly and we know in
particular a full rank a full rank set
of short vectors in it which can be used
to solve the closest vector problem with
sufficient approximation factor and
these these vectors come from what
because I'd want to make Unix so to
understand how short is the generator we
find we need to understand how precisely
we can actually solve this instance of
the closest with the problem okay so
this is for the part dealing with ideals
that our principal so that have a
generator what about the general case
now you're supposed you're given an
arbitrary idea so it's not principal it
doesn't have a generator you cannot be
looking for a full generator we're going
to find a short vector in this ideal how
fruit well the same quantity with here
the length of the shortest vector and
here the approximation factor we're
trying to reach and to do this the idea
is to reduce again to the principal case
and so what is done in crime rate out
2017 is you find a small idea will be
such that the product a B is principal
so since B is small this product a B is
in some sense close to a it's 8 and
something small and it's principal so we
call a be a close principal multiple
once you have that you use the previous
part of what I presented and you find a
short generator
this principle ideal a B and this R or
generator is also a short vector in a ok
so how do we find these principal these
are close principal multiples first you
have to transform again your problem
into a lattice problem I'm not going to
be very precise here but just to give
you a rough idea of what are the main
steps we first need to solve an instance
of the discrete logarithm problem in the
class group of our ring in order to
represent our ideal a as a point in some
lattice L the lattice L represents the
points on the lattice represent some
ideals and we want to find to which
point of this lattice a corresponds do
this with a discrete logarithm
computation once you've done that you
can look at the sub lattice of L which
corresponds to principal ideals so P is
a sub lattice of L and it includes
principal ideals and since we are
looking for a close principal idea to a
it's only natural to try to solve the
closest Viktor problem with respect to
this point a as a victor of the lattice
l and the sub lattice of principle idea
so you again reduced to solving an
instance of the closest victor problem
you're going to find a victor in P so a
principal idea that is close to a and
again you have to wonder can we solve
this process Viktor problem again it's
supposed to be difficult if you don't
know enough about your lattice well it's
been shown that you can you can solve
the CVP using the sickle Birgit here and
spread a pretty old theorem that allows
you to build a good basis of the
so-called Stickle Burgesses which is a
sub lattice of this lattice P encoding
principal ideals and this basis is good
enough to allow to solve the closest
vector problem with good enough
approximation factor and this is the
result of her I thought 2017 and again
to understand how short all the vectors
that we find we need to understand how
well we can solve this instance of the
closest vector problem so yeah how sort
of the vectors that we find I already
told you right I mean we find vectors of
this Euclidean norm where here is the
shortest vector that could be found and
here is the approximation factor that
were trying to reach but this is not
actually
satisfying and the reason is simply this
big oh here it doesn't with this bigger
here we don't know much about what's
actually happening with concrete
parameters worse than that the bigger is
in the experiment so it has an enormous
impact so we're trying to understand
what are the hidden constants in there
and try to derive from that when these
algorithms start outperforming the
classic methods lll and bkz so we can
try to do that by simulating the
algorithm we ran the algorithm and we
see how what's the quality of the output
and we compare that to what could have
been done with a la Loba kisi the
problem is that these algorithms or
Quantum's and we cannot actually run
them and we need to find a way to
simulate them without having a quantum
computer so let's let's identify the
quantum steps so here's a summary on the
algorithm as i already told you we start
by solving an instance of the discrete
logarithm problem in the class group
this should already tell you that you
need a quantum computer to do that a
class loop is a pretty big group you
don't know much about it even computing
its structure if I was a quantum
computer if you want to work in
polynomial time once you've done that
you need to solve an instance of the
closest vector problem in the sticker
burger lattice to find a small vector a
small ID will be such that Abe use
principle so here it can be done
classically it's an instance of CVP and
this step is essentially the closest
principle multiple problem once you've
done that the third step is to find an
arbitrary generator of this principle
ideal a B this again you need a quantum
computer it might not be as obvious as
when you see this people algorithm but
trust me to find an arbitrary generator
if you want to do it in polynomial time
you will need your quantum computer then
finally to find a short generator so G
is an arbitrary generator and to find a
short one you need to solve a closest
vector problem this time with respect to
the logarithmic unit lattice and then H
is your output okay so we have these two
annoying quantum steps and then to
understand how short the output is you
need to understand first how small is
this ideal B that you find and stepped
you and how short is the generator H
that you find in step 4 so how do we get
rid of these quantum steps well we're
going to do something very trivial we
just assume that their output is
uniformly distributed now that sounds
like a really strong assumption but this
can be made rigorous actually by just
rear-end amazing their outputs every
time you have a quantum step you take
itself but Yuri randomized it to make
sure it's uniform you solve the
classical step and then you D randomized
to make sure that you got the correct
result and then we can always assume
that the classical steps have an input
that is uniformly distributed this can
be done rigorously more or less by
studying random walks in the class group
things like this okay so we can remove
these quantum steps and replace them by
random Oracle's that just give you
random outputs and then see what it
what's happening with the closest vector
steps so we have two CVP instances in
step two with respect to the stickler
burger lettuce in step four with respect
to the logarithmic unit lattice these
lattices we know explicit short basis
for them so we can actually experiment
with them we can run numerical
simulations and we can prove theoretical
lower bounds so here our results the on
the horizontal axis you have the
dimension of the lattice that you're
working on and on the vertical axis we
have a measure of the quality of the
output it's the route hermit factor it's
not exactly the approximation factor it
is essentially the approximation factor
raised to the power 1 over the dimension
of the lattice choosing this route
hermit vector allow us to have
horizontal lines for the classic
algorithms so here this line for
instance written lll says that in
whatever dimension you achieve a return
a factor of about one point zero to two
it doesn't mean that I will give you as
good of an approximation in the in
dimension because remember that this
quantity is raised to the power 1 over
the dimension ok then all they are there
are horizontal lines are bkz for
different block lengths so the bigger
the block length the cost of the
algorithm but the better the quality of
the output in blue here you have the
results of simulations for a plane
implementation of the quantum algorithms
so naive implementation meaning
implemented just as described in the
articles the original articles without
to do any kinds of optimizations and the
red lines are the same algorithms but
with a number of heuristic improvements
for instance instead of just using a
short basis of the basis of the lettuces
we are looking at we exploit the fact
that we don't only know a basis but we
know a very large set of road vectors
the number of short vectors we know in
the lettuces that were working with is
much larger larger than the dimension
and we can exploit that using
appropriate CVP algorithms and this is a
very worthwhile improvement because as
you can see the red curve is way better
than the blue curve now here the brown
curve is a theoretical limit a
theoretical lower bound on what could be
achieved by this family of algorithm
assuming that you have a perfect CVP
solver so these blue and red are
actually numerical simulations using
state-of-the-art algorithms for solving
CVP and the brown line assumes that you
have a perfect solver so it shouldn't be
possible to go below these brown lines
if we stay within the same realm of
algorithms so the interesting points in
this race are the crossover points with
the classical algorithms for instance if
you look at B key Z 120 and 160 which
are essentially the limit of what's
achievable today 120 is feasible in a
few days 160 is it's probably feasible
if you're extremely rich and you have a
little bit of time what we can see is
that our heuristically improved
algorithm will not give better results
than these until dimension about 6000
for context I think the largest
dimension of a cyclotomic ideal lattice
that appears in the next competition is
about 1,000 so this is an order of
magnitude bigger and then if you worried
about what could be possible in the
future if we have very good CVP solvers
you can look at the brown line and you
can see that it won't cross bkz 3300
until also dimension about 6000 because
e300 is
the first security level in Venice
competition okay so these are the
references I used we have a few minutes
for questions okay I'll ask one can you
comment on the difference between the
actual instances of ideal SVP that you
were studying here and the ones that and
and the kinds of problems that appear in
cryptographic systems what are the
differences yeah so in the numerical
simulations that they showed here one
difference is that we are looking at
cyclotomic fields of prime conductor
whereas usually you would use as
economic fields of power of a power of
three conductor the reason we do that is
that so we still study the case of power
of two but it's not this graph and the
reason is that power is off to are way
too sparse to get good extrapolations of
what you'll get you get here what are
the differences I don't know the
dimension is obviously way bigger than
what you would actually find in practice
in this tale at least well my question
is are our ideal lattices in cyclotomic
number fields actually appearing in
proposed crypto systems yeah VP wouldn't
actually break the crypto systems for
many reasons first moose crypto systems
actually rely on the prom on problems
that are supposedly stronger like I
ringg lwe or whatever and this is just
if you can solve this it doesn't mean
you can break the crypto system because
the reduction is only in one direction
it does that answer your question yeah
any other questions
okay let's thank Benjamin again
[Applause]