okay thank you for introduction oh thank
you
I'm going to talk nonuseful interactive
competition with Melissa afghani you
bought a new rifle and beam or time
kangan and so there are two parties
senders and receiver I was considering
the problem of like each party has the
input and they won't let the receiver
knows a function of their joint input
okay so it's called nain interactive
which means it's a two message protocol
the receiver send message to sender and
the sender returned message back the
receiver knows the output so for example
if you have the home of encryption you
get it
let the receiver send the encryption of
her data and the sender do locally
evaluation and the send encryption off
to back but how much encryption is quite
efficient so in the more practical one
it's using couple circulated ot so
circuit for any input the
receiver at the sender has the sender
can compute the cobra circuit and also
two tags for each input wires such that
if you also consider the receivers input
and keep the receiver the couple struck
head and the corresponding input hacks
they truant lis review the odd foods and
nothing else computationally so this
lead to directly lead to a protocol and
I skip work on that the sender just send
the Kawasaki team playing and also use
of your transfer to send one tag of
employer so far so good but this part
have many advantage like they enjoyed or
you can use all the different
authorizations and the different
assumptions and different models it's
quite efficient and also by like you
Vario
ruffle mod manage and emit they actually
make this protocol maliciously secure
but what
I'm going to talk about today its
reusability so this part is not reusable
what as reusable mean and the why do we
care about we'll go back to definition
you should consider that the first
message it's not sent to the sender the
first message of the receiver is just
some public message he you can publish
on your favorite social media like
Facebook or Twitter so that the sender
can just grab your message formed to
your Twitter and the send your message
and then the receiver gets output okay
for ability we want the receiver doesn't
need to post a new Twitter every time
she used this protocol so one new party
comes a new center comes he can just
read the Twitter and use the same
message and send the receiver message
and the receiver should also know the
corresponding function outputs so if you
hire about correctness and the same only
security it automatically goes through
but will consider malicious party in
particular when the standard malicious
seems become quite tricky so when all
centered are malicious in particular
they can stand model message to the
receiver and they can learn the receiver
behavior after receiver gets message and
also they can send new message
reductively we want the port code to be
secure even under such attack ok so what
goes wrong with the old protocol in the
code boat protocol when the standard
malicious say the center replaced one of
the entry tag with with some trash and
then when the receiver gets this trash
the receiver would behave accordingly
and the sender might learn that if the
sender found oh I changed this input to
trash and the receivers behaviors change
he know the corresponding input rate and
the reach valet the security but you can
do some part
like you can instead of faith the input
in plain text to the OT Oracle you feed
some encoding of the input such that
like the fill bit of the encoding
doesn't leak any information about
inputs this way you can make it also it
is should be malicious security you can
make it secure in the one shot but not
in the Ryoka setting because in the
rules were setting the sender can repeat
attack and learn every bit of the
encoding well hopefully in such case
like although a few bit of the encoding
doesn't leak me put the inputting in
total would licked it and you might want
to get some small pair but our first
time in the paper shows that it's
impossible in a sense that if you only
rely on OT there's you cannot construct
useful and I see but our first one that
hacker unbounded so it's we show there's
no information circle basically you know
to have remote we also have a serum
shows that if you are willing to assume
like the our black box emulation they
are like why function and you only
consider certain functionality like even
competition why it's simple so a
different route it's from Isaac he then
Isaac repays the protocol like the
sender would prove that his message is
on its generated but in this case the
products typically become quite
efficient because it exactly require
none black box use of odd primitives so
to get round with that we consider the
arithmetic analog of ot which is called
oblivia linear function rational or in
short in such case we there is a field
or ring F the receivers input is just
one field element and the sender's input
is two filaments the odd hood is okay
valuator receivers input and the linear
function specified as by the sender
support
the first thing we'll show is like this
functionality is complete for reusable
Isaac escape in a sense that you useful
very happy motto you can have the
information you can construct
information circle you see secure
reusable a/c and of course we also need
to construct such photo we use a PI
layer Samsom you mention later in
Sierra's model here CS means a common
reference stream so we need to trust it
setup so if you consider it assuming the
field is binary field then o le it's
actually equivalent to Ooty this kind of
contradicts with our person result we
show that such protocol it's impossible
if it's the OT happy model therefore
it's not surprising we need the field to
be super large especially large I was
the code allows it's proportional to
it's roughly the one over the field size
so okay now I will give you a quite
brief overview of how we construct s20
so the first one we want to use this as
black box and that's all we need to
construct I see we can sir what if we
only have a one shots okay one shot
means no useful okay when the sender is
malicious he doesn't actually have
well-defined input but you see security
is it there's a simulator the simulator
rates to input the sender sent to the
are Oracle and from that the the
simulator can extract an effective input
such that the receiver should output F X
Y star where Y starts the effective
input
okay I'll mention that for now my NPC
typically the receiver would abort or
some party to abort when they saw
abnormal behavior but in this
okay in the 90 of settings now abort
it's free in a sense that whoever the
receiver detect malicious behavior the
receiver can just pretend the sender's
use 7014 put this is not very important
okay so why assume you have search
simulator is still not reusable secure
the simulator absolute might be a
distribution in such case the receiver
would output also have entertained ideal
world and therefore it also have entropy
in the real world this entropy is not
coming from the receivers input because
it's secure my shots occur but it is
coming from the receivers randomness but
that's the probiotic part if it leaks
the resource randomness and the sender
repeat searched for cause the random is
liquid fruit cumulate to a degree the
protocols normal secure so therefore the
fix is quite simple we want to construct
a protocol where the simulator is
deterministic and then you check
everything it works well like if you
have one short security uses security
and the datum and simulator is
deterministic it's automatically uses a
queue for useful setting so let's start
with well let's start with so assuming
everything's arithmetic so the input for
post party it's a vector over some field
and that functionality it's a romantic
branching program or automatic and say
circuit and so once again we'll consider
more general general case by the very
end of these slides so by using
randomized encoding by a shy and cushy
oh sorry if I a new syllabus there is a
randomized encoding that the sender can
encode his input into a fix and back
such that matrix ax a times the input of
the receiver ax plus B reveals nothing
but
the output so if you only satisfied with
see me honest you can just use the oil
Yi as black box and there is what FXY
but were you okay when the sender is
malicious we want to make sure like the
matrix a and B is on its generated so in
particular we want to replace this oil
Eve that box with something we called
certified oil which is a super powerful
primitives such that if the input on the
sender said satisfies some constraint it
just evaluate a linear function but
otherwise the functionality
functionality would inform the receiver
says no like the sender is doing some
simulations so basically there are some
if there's no certified like it's just
some playing ie
but mister certified we want the we want
the sender to be able to prove any
Earth's Mac taken string on the
coefficients he troops so in particular
this implies the testing verify earnest
in or Ahmad because you can preventing
constraints but for this talk general
somatic constrains to heart we only
consider a super-simple constraint
record okay so we only consider one a a
I equals AJ for some IJ so this is
totally simplified for general
constraint it's only in the apron
okay actually even for this one we won't
fully cover it so how does it go to get
a favor of our construction to receive
her through some randomness and the fit
to one of the OE
Oracle and the sender rules
one of the coefficients and some random
one renfa element and receiver get aw
oppressor so here it happens artists
this oily output you should view that as
a commitment of a because yeah like as
you can check later the sender can open
the commitment by sending a and are to
the receiver and it's easy to track this
is statistically sound and zero
knowledge in our hyper-model and say
litter the sender want to send AP use
abs coefficients and excise the
receivers input and let the receivers
know say Si plus B so this is what the
receiver to learn in order to do that
the receiver through the new retina
simply like for this index I and he feed
something something holding to the over
you hybrid or we have a model and now
the center ok the sender to something
else
let's not check the detail white or why
we trust that we can some new or your
outputs and there is a magic equation
actually equations no magic at or it's
like if you want to see equation to hold
you reverse engineer and you'll find the
sister what you should fit into the so
let's check how well this for test the
correctness is obvious is just from the
equation here so for you to security
against the receiver when we have
receivers input the simulator
constructively send out word of the
receiver and for the wrist you see
security against the sender it's a bit
tricky actually Oh if the sender is
honest honest in the sense that if these
two coefficients
same coefficient and this too if is the
same coefficients the simulator can
instruct a efficient input but he
otherwise if the sender debate forum
hood call the similar actually cannot
extract the input so so we didn't prove
use the security yet but or we can show
that the what a receiver would output
when the sender debated protocol is a
purely random food element could we want
them even condition on the sender's view
so this is like the first half and later
we do a lot of things like because it's
this is purely random we can repeat a
product twice so that if they are they
matched and we know the sender is not
malicious but then it opens the door for
the receiver to cheat so we actually
okay we won't go to the in tower but we
go back and first ever want to get this
minimum certified oily and then based on
this minimize the certified OAE
we construct the complete certified so
this is all I want to give about the
detail of the construction of certified
or EE and our construction of SK in the
next I would give some brief overview
about how we construct the to message or
you portico okay so it's a mat analog of
ot and for ot there it's a nice
construction by Packers in northern
waters our construction have a very
similar favored wisdom so the Comintern
string can be chosen from two different
distributions and that specified two
different mode involved mode you can
interpret the receivers message as the
encryption of his input and therefore
like the okay
the simulator knows the secret key of
the encryption so the simulator can
easily simulate the receiver symbol and
the sender's message leaks no
information other than experts
so in this mode its
information-theoretic Oh secure against
the receiver in the next mode by
changing only the saris to receive X
messages actually encryption of 0 and
the standard message is a corruption of
his input so therefore in this mode it's
easy to simulate and its information
surco against Malaysia standard and the
to distribution I need indistinct for so
we also have computational secure
against others and they're all received
so for pannier group we we won't mention
the detail it's a pal ulcer so pal your
encryption it's based on assumptions
similar to factoring but we just use it
as a black box there's a key generation
algorithm we consider we call the sacred
key trapdoor because actually the output
core no one in the real world are going
to use this secret key only the
simulator are going to use it and that
there's an encryption the current scheme
and when the randomness is zero we don't
need the secretary we can directly
decrypt and more
this scheme is somehow homomorphic in a
sense that if you multiply two separate
tests you get the subjects of the you
add to you yes you multiply two subjects
you'll get separate acts of their
addition and also the randomness is the
addition of their enemies this is all be
going to need so in the first mode we
have the CRS has two three encryptions
the first one is increasing one under
zero randomness the other it's just
using fresh illness and okay the sender
simple as I mentioned it's a encryption
of his input and there are a secret
human over here and there are publicly
owned lean over him sir and the random
is
about him and yes there's this descender
chest and the bench master back and if
you check yeah everything would work
well in the other mode we just replaced
one of the CS encryption with the
encryption of zero so the two Sierras
are in distinct role and correspondingly
correspond okay correspondingly the
message will change I want to mention
something that at this time the
simulator can actually behave
maliciously you don't know whether the
randomness still satisfy the right
correlations and in this for code
there's no way to detect whether the
sender is malicious
so actually we need a different
mechanism not mentioning the talk again
to detect whether the sender's malicious
so that's all I want to talk about our
early from patio group so quick summary
of our result we showed that you cannot
construct a nasty theory in OT hyper
motto without other assumptions but you
can do the same thing for well sorry you
know T without other assumptions but you
can do the same thing you re happy model
for a small cosmetic function and also
as a side product you can get Isaac hey
for any functions of sorry for any and
for any MP language and by combine these
two with Scarpa circuit you can get a C
for any functions but this time is no
more information circle circle against
the receiver and eventually we also have
a report call from hollyrock group
assumption and by compose the result we
the result we have it means we can
construct reusable actually and as
okay Impaler model sorry
you under patio something and the in
particular our construction its
information circle secured in the hybrid
model and our oil it's one side
information circle secure basing on the
distribution areas which means the
compost the one is also one study from
is a circle secure so in particular the
most interesting one it's like you can
stare as DK that it's one side secure a
once and information circle secure
against the receiver it means we have a
whole sorry this should be status code
we have a statistical technique verify
earnest argument and another feature of
the protocol it's dark because oh it's
like automatic or analog of OT you can
actually make or the cryptography to do
Francis so in Auckland Facebook
construct a lot of randomized random or
re pairs and in the online phase you
just whatever you need oily you use this
offline computed Random randomness
information circling so therefore the
online phase is a non cryptography and
it's quite sufficient a quite efficient
the overall communication doesn't
increase yeah so that's all I want to
talk thank you much
[Applause]
is there any questions thanks for the
talk um so I was wondering can you
comment on the efficiency of your
protocol like the complexity
okay so efficiency okay uh maybe here
then Isaac a prophet is quite nice
because for each gate in the circuit you
only need to transfer a constant number
of group element but for NSC it's kind
of tricky so we have two way to
construct an IC one its informations
article but this one using the
randomized encodings of instrument
circuit which or branching program which
means it's only polynomially over of the
size of the bunch of programs and the
other one is using if you okay
the other one it's you if you use couple
circuit and you prove the cover circuit
it's on to generated in this one the
computation would because the
communication would be poly secure
parameter or for each gate so I guess
the follow-up question is that is there
do you think there are some hope of
eventually have this protocol applied or
used in practice okay compare with the
approach from like Isaac a based one for
very small circuit our port code here
might be quite efficient maybe more
efficient than in there but for large
circuit I didn't checked I didn't check
the exact number which was more
efficient but I guess we also had the
advantage of the online offline because
if you use this on my offline then like
in the online phase there's no public
encryption even if you use the couple
circuit approach which could be quite
efficient if you are using some big
device thanks
I guess let's let's keep the other
questions offline since we are running a
little bit behind schedule
yeah let's welcome the last angular
speaker again
[Applause]