hello this is a joint talk with the
elements a sonido bento very non whorish
first of all to set expectation in this
talk I will mainly focus on the
background and on our results
I will not go deep into details of how
we achieved its results you are welcome
to talk with me after all check in the
paper ok we start from the celebrated
work of Baba Tao suggesting a user can
send an execution consent the program
for an untrusted server to execute and
return the result but instead of only
returning a result of the execution this
untrusted server provides a proof of
integrity showing this result is indeed
the result of the program the user asked
for additionally it might be the case
this program has a place for some
auxilary input the prover can add an
input a secret input into the program as
well and make this proof a proof of
knowledge of an input satisfying this
program the BLS construction had many
great features I would like to focus on
two of them one of them is 16-4 if
occasion the verification of the proof
is poly logarithmic on the length of the
execution the other one is public coin
randomness it means that using common
compilers the the prover could generate
a non-interactive argument that can be
spread and published to anybody and
anybody would be able to verify it with
no trust assumptions recently there is a
lot of work on systems for designated
designated computation for a computation
delegation unfortunately none of these
works were able to achieve both suck
centrifugation and using public own
randomness two years ago sai was
presented achieving both 16
fortification and public coin randomness
but the performance of the SCI system
was not applicable for a real-world
usage in this work in this work I
present ZK start a system which has both
16 verification public and randomness
and having performance appealing to
real-life usage this is the message I
would like you to take with you today
that Stark is both 16th verifiable with
public coin randomness and applicable to
real life usage this is why you will see
this Venn diagram a lot let's continue
to some distinction of the of the stark
system from other systems in the public
coin or something for a fixation which
are not in the intersection a very major
difference is in the earth mutilation
technique used one common ultimate
evasion technique is to describe the
program as a circuit in this case the
verifier as it has to know what the
program is is not expected to be sub
linear in there secrets in the circuit
side such we cannot expect such thing
terrific ation this technique is indeed
very common in the system which which
have public coin randomness but no
success in Torah fication another
technique is very similar but it takes
the circuit describing the program at
pre-process it using some setup phase
this setup phase outputs 1/16
verification parameter that can be used
by the verifier to verify a proof
succinctly unfortunately one of the
drawbacks of this technique is that in
the setup phase information if
information leaked from the setup phase
it can be used to forge proof in many of
the setups it is suggested to use MP
seals to do the setup to reduce the
stress assumption what we do instruct is
completely different
we are not describing the program is a
circuit instead we are describing the
transition function as a circuit you can
think of at the CPU that we have in
every computer
as some circuit this circuit is constant
and has some constant complexity but it
can be used to execute both short
programs and very long programs this is
the case for Stark as well.we arrhythmia
is only the transition function and we
use it to verify both short races and
very long traces this is where the
succinctness of Starks come from I would
like to compare to other systems in
first of all asymptotically we can see
the three last lines in this table
represent the work the work in the
intersection and we can notice two great
features in this three last lines one of
them there is no red cell it seems
nothing here is really better awful the
other one there is no green cell it
means there is still a lot of room for
research okay mmm I will now continue by
showing how specifically in this line of
work we have improved from side to lib
star general and rip start with
logarithmic Ram when the last two lines
representing both lib stark are for the
following scenarios lip stark general is
for general computations using Ram
access lip start with logarithmic Ram is
an optimization that we have for the
case a program accesses only at most a
logarithmic Ram in the length of the
trace so first optimization from site to
lib stark we won
it's one of the optimization that we
introduced in Lib Stark is to use the
Frey low degree testing instead of the
Bensons to download degree testing the
Frey low degree testing was introduced
last year by the same authors of this
paper when we are going to leap start
with logarithmic Ram it might be a big
technical it not familiar for a lot but
we drop a de bruin shuffle network which
is used to verify ram access it's
consistent
I will not dive much deeper into this
because of lack of time but this is an
optimization that we were able to do
I will now dive into concrete
measurements and comparison to other
systems for the concrete measurements we
wrote a subset some exhaustive solver
this solver was written in tiny Rama
sembly and compiled both to sigh and
stark constraint systems and to leave
snark circuit the parameters of this
leap snark circuit were used to estimate
the performance of other circuit based
systems so here we can see that the lib
stark verification is more efficient
than any other public coin public owner
and onesa system verification just as we
expected and outperformed only by the
lip snark verifier which requires a
trusted setup you can see that even
though the the time it takes to verify
start proof is about a tenth of a second
and it is insensitive to the length of
the execution so it wouldn't change much
even for very long executions
let's check the argument size which is
like the proof but it is argument
because it requires some computational
assumptions we can see that the stark
proof is longer than many add then the
proof of many other systems it requires
a few hundred of kilobytes but again it
is insensitive to the length of the
computation and it would stay this way
even for very long computations about
the proving time we can see that the
prover is faster than any other prover
we compared to at least by a factor of
ten one of the reasons is that some of
the systems require intensive elliptic
curve arithmetic while proving while
stark require only
finite field arithmetic switch is much
easier for a CPU another ism could be
just engineering it might be the case
that more fine optimization to other
prover would reduce this gap I would
like to summarize by reminding again
that ZK star has both accent
verification and public coin randomness
and it's performance is appealing for
real-life usage and if this is not
enough for you
it is quantum secure as well thank you
[Applause]
questions yeah yeah any questions okay
and the work pretty yes
so the second part of this talk is about
libras seems even knowledge proves with
optimal approval computation alright
thanks for introduction and thanks for
Michael for the last pork now I'm going
to introduce Libra which is another
theological system and this is a joint
work with chehon upin bubbies and done
and I need to cry fry that this work is
different from the Facebook liberal
project and this work is submitted in
February so before Facebook the bar it
is so it's a nice coincidence as many
talk previously mentioned that do not
approve allows the prover to come in
super far about the validity of a
statement which is modeling of
statements which is a statement is
moderate circuit and in our proof system
we have continuous Sunnis and for large
properties a promise property says that
if post-party are honest then the word
fair should always accept the sunniest
properties as if Hoover is malicious
then were I should not accept acceptable
ninja buffer bridge and the Mirage says
if whoever cannot learn anything about
witness w from the proof pi and there
are three major criteria about sahaja
food protocols prove a time prove asides
and revocation time and the category we
are focusing on is protocol with
succinct proof size and fast
verification time and there are many
existing geological codes that satisfy
these properties the most widely used
one is snark and their implementation
leap snark the leap stock supposed all
kinds of functions and have constant
proof size and constant verification
time and even they are widely deployed
in the real world such as big hash
however there are still improving things
and they have a function dependent trust
they set up to address these problems
recent years there are many protocols
proposed by different groups and here is
a list of these protocols which for
implementation and categorized by the
underlying technique our protocol is an
interactive protocol based on the
framework proposed by V sequel and
foreign John at all actually all of
these protocols are following the same
framework now I'm going to introduce a
framework proposed by John at all so
first we have a witness and we have the
prove is going to commit to the
polynomial that is defined by the
witness then they were engaged
interactive proof protocol as called
Jukka protocol w fish and solid proof
and this worker will reduce the validity
of the output Y to the validity of the
committed polynomial defined by the
input W and finally it will waver I will
send a random challenge to the input and
the proof where we are open the random
challenge open the open the input
binomial to this random point with proof
of cortney's this completes the whole
framework and all constructions follows
the framework and our main contribution
is on the GTR protocol first we will
introduce an inner time Jacob pour for
arbitrary layered circuit which is
optimal then second we will add the zero
logic value add a zero g property to the
Chikara protocol without any
computational overhead so
finally we will get a new large argument
scheme with linear time prover and
succinct proof size and the verification
so for the rest of the talk I will tell
you some technical details about this
prover and about the theological
conversion for jihad protocol
so first let's discuss about the linear
time for the GK protocol is based on the
song check protocol so let me introduce
the song check first and the some check
protocol is a fundamental building block
for for many applications in
cryptography the call for some check
photo is to check the summation of the
polynomial F over a boolean hypercube
that is equal to some claimed constant H
and this is the interactive protocol and
finally it were reduced to a random
point and we refer to our need to gain
access to this polynomial evaluated at
this random point so if we have our
Oracle says the proof size will be log n
and verification time will also be log n
as use let's use the some checkers of
building block and Ness introduced a
jacquard protocol so I will use the
vector location tool to represent a set
of an asari array of variables and which
your size is log n and so first we have
to define the polynomial using the sum
check protocol
next if let's take an example the input
layer this polynomial is a multi Nene
extension of the input layer and it will
agree on the input value on pudding and
hypercube for example 0 you are in agree
one
first input and for the rest of this
polynomial
it will agree on the corresponding gate
value and to make it possible we will
use this relationship to define these
polynomials and this polynomial is
related to the previous layers of
polynomial so let me explain it in
details the mod and ad is called a
wiring predicate a wearing predicate is
defined as follows if there exists gate
g0 and is connected to u 0 and V 0 then
the motor will indicate will evaluate to
1 upon this input and otherwise it will
evaluate to 0 so in this formula if G is
a multi Kate and U is the corresponding
input the value of this the variation of
this polynomial will be the
multiplication of the following input
and the same for the Advocate so this
this polynomial you will always agree
with implicit evaluation and the
complexity of the gql protocol is a song
of complexity of all of this some Czech
protocol so in order to improve the
chica protocol it's only need to improve
the some checked protocol let me
introduce some prior work on the some
Czech protocol improvement to make it an
in-ear soundcheck protocol so taylor
introduced dynamic programming based
method in crypto 13 and the first step
of this method is to initialize the
lookup table of the polynomial over the
whole pudding hypercube then it will use
the dynamic programming to reduce the
pre no Meah
the size of the next Pannonia is equal
to the half of the size of previous
premio so the total size is linear
according to this formula and the final
block of this is this table is only
consists of one where my element
however in GQ polynomial it's not
sufficient because we have two variables
each of them have log n variable so in
total is 2 T 2 log n which is n square
and the initialization is N squared so
this is not efficient for practice use
so in our paper we propose a new way to
address this problem and based on the
protocol proposed by trainer we divide
the sum check into two phases the first
phase is only about the variable U and
the second phase is only about where
about V here we define a polynomial edge
as follows so this thing this two thing
will be equal actually so and this part
of the phenomenal we are only about you
so as tennis protocol required we need
to initialize a lookup table for this
polynomial and wii u is quite simple in
case since it's agree with circuit
evaluation so we can we can use the
circuit evaluation as a lookup table and
H is not quite not easy but in our paper
we introduced a way to initialize a
issues through an inner skin over the
circuit and since the time is limited
I will not introduce the initialization
process with you then we were wrong the
Taylor's method and then we
complete this phase reduce you to a
random is proposed by the some check
actually is the constant so this part
this middle term is a constant and the
remaining turn is the actual work for
the some check when we are doing the
same thing as a free phase one
acceptable age is defined in a lottery
and this mod function can also be
initialized in a linear scan of the
circuit and then we run the taylors
master again to complete the some check
so now we have an inner time prove er
next we are going to introduce second
technique the Zoological protocol in
this section we will introduce a comma
zero logic conversion for G cap will
occur without any computational overhead
so what they mean should let me tell you
why chica is not secure because it needs
some evaluations in every interaction
into a leak-free Gnomeo evaluation about
the some but the current layer circuit
the polynomial you are evaluate to a
random point and the run this evaluation
will become linear combination of the
value of this gate so it's not security
leak some information about the create
value and there are several prior work
to address these problems
hi Roxy kensic here is equal they use
permit anger transformation which will
incur a computational overhead because
increment angle transformation addition
will become a multiplication
multiplication will become initiation
this will incur like 10 to 100 times
lower compared
the previous geopolitical so to make GG
r GG ology which all computational
overhead we one use some new approach
that is masking polynomial and it is
inspired by the Casa at all so in their
paper they add a random masking
polynomial Delta to each to the original
function f and in this way the the some
Czech interaction we allowed leak any
information because this is a random
point number it well looks like random
however in their construction Delta is
as big as f and we notice that we need
to do come Pannonia commitment for each
masking polynomial to ensure the
evaluation of the masking trinomial is
correct so if Delta is big is
computationally hard to make the
commitment and open the commitment at
some random point so this work we are
mainly for theoretical interest and we
need many need to construct a Delta that
is small for computationally efficient
then let me give you an intuition about
how it is constructed first SD cage is
small the leakage of the whole Jacob
protocol is only point Agra mystic so to
cover the preneur mystic leakage we
intuitively only needed program is
decree sized
mask in polynomial and we have a nice
construction about this mask in
polynomial it's all of this work was
separated and the size of the pond Omiya
is only probe for in Agra mystic so it
will not incur any computational
overhead so with linear time through ver
and with the conversion for jacquard
protocol to to zero knowledge without
net any computational overhead we will
finally have a linear time through word
and succinct verifier succinct proof
size zero knowledge proof system and
concretely speaking our proof time is
the best among these potholes and our
replication times Ness and one second
and what proof size is reasonable and we
also have an open-source implementation
on github you could check it out by
yourself
and finally becomes conclusion we have a
near-term pool we have efficient geology
conversion for Acapulco and combined we
have an inner prover faster verification
fast source succinct proof size geology
probe system and thank you I'm happy to
take questions
[Applause]
questions alright
okay so let's thank the speaker again
[Applause]