right so in this talk we are going to
analyze the quantum security of Fiat
Xiaomi our non interactive zero
knowledge proof and fear charm your
signatures these objects are actually
constructed in two steps which we will
eat separately analyzed namely you have
the field Shamir transformation which we
apply to a sigma protocol i will in the
first part of this talk talk about the
security of the field Shimer
transformation where i can already give
away that the main issue here is how to
do with superposition access to the
random Oracle about which we have seen
two talks already and then in the second
part jipang will talk about how to prove
quantum security for the underlying
sigma protocols this separation was also
allows me to give a quick comparison
between the two papers in the first part
we both have a reduction the only
difference lies in the tightness of the
reduction and interestingly also in the
methods that we used and in the second
part both of our papers formulated a new
property and we demonstrated that this
property is sufficient for quantum
security but on top of that beyond
xandrie also develop some extra
technical tools that allow to prove that
certain schemes actually satisfy this
property right so first about the field
Sharma transform in a nutshell it takes
away the interaction from a sigma
protocol so given a sigma protocol which
is an interactive scheme we apply the
transform to obtain these non
interactive objects that I mentioned
before and of this transformation it has
long been known that classically it is
secure in the random Oracle model in the
sense that any security notion ranging
from computational soundness to
statistical proof of knowledge name your
favorite one if the Sigma protocol
satisfies this property then we can
prove that
the non-interactive fear charm your
transformed version does so as well well
up to recently the quantum setting
looked quite different we had only one
we are only one positive result here
namely by Dominic oon row in 2017 but
this security proof applied only to the
case where the underlying Sigma protocol
is statistically sound so only one of
the possible properties and actually one
that is not typically found in
cryptographic applications for the other
properties the computational ones for
example it was unknown whether they are
carried over proof of knowledge which
happens to be the one that is crucial
when you want to prove unfortunate efore
fear charm your signatures also unknown
and to make matters worse there were
even some negative claims as to the
possibility for a security proof
regarding these properties however the
main result of both of our papers is
that indeed also in the quantum setting
the field Charmy transformation is
secure now in the quantum random Oracle
model exactly as in the classical case
any security notion that you can think
of is inherited with the only difference
being that we now get a Q squared
security loss or if an acute to the 9 in
the paper by Leo and sundry compared to
the linear loss that we have in the
classical case nevertheless this result
allows us to conclude that if the
underlying Sigma protocol is quantum
secure then we have unfortunately our
signatures the condition in itself is
already non-trivial jipang will have
more to say about that in second parts
right so I will first tell you a bit
more about technical details of our
results for which I will have to explain
a bit about Sigma protocols and how the
field Sharma transformation works also
saying it's about how to extend this
paradigm to obtain signature schemes
then I'll give you an intuition for the
classical proof and the quantum issues
that we find in the Cure ROM and finally
the technical results that we have to
overcome these issues okay so a Sigma
protocol is an interactive proof of a
special form that does not reveal
anything beyond the truth of the
statement this letter property as you
probably know is what we call zero
knowledge the famous example being where
somebody wants to prove that two graphs
are isomorphic without revealing the
isomorphism well a Sigma protocol is a
particular kind of ceará knowledge proof
namely one that works as follows if some
proofer wants to prove the truth of a
statement X using its knowledge about a
witness W he can do so by computing
something we call the commitment which
it sends on to the verifier who then
replies with a uniformly random
challenge it always has to be uniformly
random which the proof read and in turn
can use to compute a response which he
sends over to the verifier and if this
response satisfies certain relation with
respect to this commitment and this
challenge then the verifier accepts
technical detail that I should mention
by p1 and p2 I of course mean two faces
of the same algorithm so implicitly they
are allowed to share state which is
something that will become important in
chippings part of the talk but for us
this this suffices now the field shall
transform as promised it takes away the
interaction by replacing the challenge
from the verifier in the second round
with the hash of X and the commitment
which the proofer can compute by himself
using some publicly known hash function
of which you can find the code on
or whatever the main point is that it
has to be one in the same hash function
that is known to all parties which they
then again uses to compute a response
and now the proofer sends over the
commitment and the response in one
single step so these two objects
together now make up the non interactive
proof and to verify it the verifier as
to do one extra thing namely recompute
the challenge himself which he does by
looking up the same hash function and
again checks if the proper relation
holds right so to get signatures very
simple extension of this idea namely
includes a message that you want to sign
in the hash and to make the picture
complete we have then a public key and a
secret key consisting of some X and some
W from a heart relation so W must be
hard to obtain from just X right the
challenge is now defined as the hash of
the message you want to sign X and the
commitment and the signature simply
consists of this non interactive proof
that we have as a small motivational
note I'd like to point out that we have
currently three signature schemes in the
second round of the nice post quantum
standardization project that actually
make use of this framework okay now we
get to the proof in the classical case
what do we want to do we want to reduce
the security of the non-interactive
scheme to the security of the underlying
Sigma protocol how do we do that by
assuming that we actually have some
adversary who making Q a polynomial
amount of queries to the random Oracle
is able to break the non interactive
feature scheme then we are going to play
the Sigma protocol not using the Una's
proofer but using some reduction
algorithm who is going to use black box
access to this adversary in order to
break the security
of the Sigma protocol and they are
breaking the security
it can mean anything it can mean that
the reduction can convince the verifier
without knowing a witness it can mean
that you can convince the verifier on
some statements X that is not in a
language it really doesn't matter any
trick that the non-interactive adversary
can do we will show that the reduction
can do as well in the Sigma protocol so
how does that work well using its black
box access to the adversary the
reduction is going to run a while
implementing the random Oracle himself
which just means that he is going to
execute the adversary and during every
one of these Q queries reply with some
arbitrary random challenge up until a
certain point where a randomly chosen
query where the reduction says okay hey
now I'm going to carefully look at what
the adversary is querying it will be
some X and some commitment and then this
commitment I am going to pass on to the
verifier that I want to fool then of
course the reduction will will get a
random challenge from the verifier which
it now then will pass on to to the
adversary again so technically we say
that the reduction is going to reprogram
the random Oracle on this particular
input to the particular challenge that
he obtained from the verifier then it
has to do is just simply continue the
run of the adversary now answering every
query with the new reprogrammed Oracle
and just wait until it finishes its
computation pops out some non
interactive proof come Prime and some
response and then it takes this response
and presents it to the verifier who will
accept if this commitment in the final
output happens to
be the same that the reduction found
halfway when looking at this random
query because by assumption the
adversary can produce a valid non
interactive proof on some commitment and
if it's the same then the verifier will
accept which obviously will happen with
probability 1 over Q so hence the the
linear loss in this reduction right in
the quantum setting however we require a
proof in the quantum random Oracle model
where H is still a classical uniformly
random function but now we allow the
adversary superposition query access to
8 and I want to emphasize also maybe for
the people that just did a switch break
the track switch I mean that that it's
really important in post quantum
applications to look not just at the
underlying hardness assumption which of
course has to be both quantum secure but
also we have to consider an adversary
that makes these superposition queries
and the motivation for this model comes
from the fact that as I explained H is
this publicly known as function of which
the code the code of which you can just
look up in some place which means that
in real life the adversary is not
interacting with some magical Oracle it
actually has a circuit on its quantum
computer to evaluate the hash function
which means that he can also evaluate
this function on a superposition of
inputs okay but what does that do to our
picture in the reduction if we now want
to reduce the quantum security we again
assume that we have an adversary that
breaks the non-interactive scheme this
time making Q quantum carries to eight
and suppose we want to try what we did
before have this reduction run the
adversary and try to read off one of its
queries well then we run into
what mark just called the observer
effect trying to look at a quantum query
can potentially destroy or at least
disturb at that disturb the query state
but will it also disturb the internal
states of the adversary right so if we
if we were to do such a measurement then
we can no longer in general predict what
the adversary is going to output because
its internal state might have been
disturbed too much now the contribution
of our papers is that we have a
technical result which in full
generality says that for any cue query
quantum algorithm which produces some
pair x and z where x and z satisfies
some particular relation i'm sorry i
said particularly i meant just any any
arbitrary relation with respect to the
hash of x then if we measure one of the
queries at random just like in the
classical case small caveat in Leon's
and risk analysis you should either
measure 1 or 3 but that's just an
artifact of the proof if we do some
measurement find an input to the Oracle
X and then reprogram again as in the
classical case reprogram or Oracle at
this input to some fresh arbitrary but
uniformly random value theta then we can
still continue the run of that adversary
and at the end find some output X prime
C where X prime actually equals the X
that we found in a measurement and
furthermore this relationship that did
this X Prime and C now satisfy satisfy a
relation with respect to the newly
programmed random value theta well
that's
just a little bit more abstractly the
thing exactly the thing that we need
here namely we wanted to measure one of
the queries of the adversary find some X
and commitment and continue to run and
hope that we find some non interactive
proof where the commitment come prime
actually equals the one that we found
out way in the measurement so yeah
applying the results to this situation
we find that the response in the final
output still does a good job now with
probability 1 over Q squared ok
so interesting to note is that both of
our papers obtained a very similar
result using quite different methods in
our paper we used only elementary
techniques a very basic quantum very
basic want of formalism and some simple
medical tools and we obtained this Q
squared security large loss which we
believe is optimal and the other paper
by leo and sundry used the compressed
orco framework which mark just talked
about which is a more general and strong
tool but in this particular example it
had a less tight it made for a less
tight reduction right so to recap the
take-home message from the first part of
this talk is that we now have managed to
reduce even in the quantum setting any
any security notion that you can think
of from the non interactive a charm your
scheme to the underlying Sigma protocol
which poses the natural follow-up
question how can we prove a sigma
protocol quantum secure which is what
chip Bank is going to talk about
okay okay thanks ele for the first part
and I'm going to talk about the second
part which is about quantum rewinding so
quantum rewinding is a technique which
allows you to prove special sundnes
implies soundness or in other words it's
help you to prove certain Sigma protocol
is a proof of knowledge so first we give
a definition called collapsing which is
a property for a sigma protocol as well
as the Sigma protocol is collapsing we
can do quantum rewinding in other words
it is a proof of knowledge or an
argument of knowledge now also we gave
to classical sufficient conditions which
implies a sigma protocol is collapsing
and also we prove this is collapsing
which means the Lu bishops key signature
is post quantum and it's even holds for
polynomial Q which means we don't we
don't need a large program parameter we
just need to make the parameter slightly
bigger okay so let me talk about that
our definition of soundness so for a
sigma protocol it's always easy to
generate a a pair of transcript with
commitment challenge and response
because it usually satisfy owners verify
of zero knowledge so first son is here
we actually mean there's no algorithm
without the witness can produce a valid
response after the commitment is made
and the random challenge is also
selected after the commitment and for
specialist honest which means there's no
algorithm can come out with two valid
pairs which like under the same
commitment but different challenges okay
so here's what we do for classical
rewinding assume we have algorithm for
like which breaks soundness the
algorithm has two parts for p1 its perdu
commitment for p2 is actually an
algorithm for getting a valley response
so after outputting the commitment
let's assume the internal state of the
algorithm is as team and give a
challenge it
it runs the algorithm p2 over the
statement acts the commitment and the
random challenge and it let's assume
with a hundred percent probability it
actually produces a value response
so that's algorithm for our breaking
Sunnis so if two random challenges are
given we simply copy this state as T and
we run p2 twice that is we run p2 over
the challenge CH and then and we get a
valid response for CH and then we rewind
by just restore s T and we run p2 over
the other random challenges each H Prime
in which sense we can get a two pair of
valid transcript under the same
commitment which breaks special saunas
this is how we do classical rewinding
but however for a quantum algorithm this
stage is actually a quantum
superposition so we cannot follow this
cloning technique because we know it's
hard to clone quantum superposition so
inspired from loose word the claps
fighting commitment scheme we show that
collapsing is the definition collapsing
is enough for quantum rewinding and also
we give to classical sufficient
contentions so I will introduce the
definition collapsing Sigma protocol and
I will mailing focus on the first
classical sufficient condition which is
called lousy function okay so here is
the definition of collapsing Sigma
protocol so there's no adversary' a can
succeed the following game with more
than half probability so here is the
game we have algorithm a which outputs a
commitment first
gets a random challenge from the
verifier then a propels a superposition
over or valid response that I mean for
valid means is valid respect to the
commitment and the challenge and sends
the superposition to the verifier then
the verifier flips are calling if the
coin is 1 it measures the superposition
otherwise it does nothing then a
succeeds if and only if the adversary'
can get the coin in other words the game
means like claps in Sigma protocol means
there's no adversary can guess if the
superposition is measured or not
so with collapsing Sigma protocol we can
actually do quantum rewinding here's how
we do that so assuming we have a phone
on anniversary a also with two stages p1
p2 assume it breaks honest after
outputting the commitment let's assume
the algorithm has its own internal state
which is a superposition SG so given the
first challenge it just simply runs the
algorithm over the same and adds the
commitment and also the challenge so
first implicitly let's just assume it's
a unitary the algorithm just select a
unitary based on XCOM nch and applies
the unitary over the internal state st
and and we just make it even simple we
just assume after that we got a
superposition over or valid response
then the next thing to do is just
measure the superposition and we get a
valid response and because we know the
Sigma protocol is collapsing which means
a have no way to tell if the
superposition is measured or not in
other words a measure of superposition
is basically indistinguishable from the
original superposition so we can easily
back get back to the original internal
state just by applying the inverse of
the unitary to the state and because of
the indistinguishability of collapsing
we can just go back to the internal
state s GE and by given another
challenge CH Prime we can just do the
same because we have already get back to
the internal state s G we can apply the
unitary again but under a different
challenge and by assumption that's a
superposition over all valid response
prime which is valid under commitment
and the new challenge so in which case
it produces two value pairs under the
same commitment which breaks special
saunas this is how we do on quantum
rewinding okay so this is one of the
classical sufficient condition for
having collapsing Sigma protocol which
is called lousy function is also a
generalization of Buddhist work so the
basic idea is very simple let's assume
there are collection of functions which
is defined over or valid response
respect to a fixed commitment and
challenge so for the injective mode the
function is the injective function over
the domain and for constant mode it's
just constant function and also there's
no post quantum adversary' can
distinguish which function is picked in
other words like it cannot tell if it's
a function for an injective mode or
constant mode and this is some intuition
about why lossy function implies
collapsing so assume we have a
superposition of over valid response
which is not measured it's exactly the
same as we apply a constant function
over the response and we measure the
function register
cause the second register is constant
nature that does not affect our first
register so they're exactly the same and
from lousy function we know that they're
indistinguishable so we can apply the
injective mode instead of the constant
mode and finally because the function is
injective measure the second register is
exactly equal to measure the first
register so which we have the
superposition measure is
indistinguishable from the superposition
that is not measuring okay so here's how
we rewind the Sigma protocol quantumly
we can first we can either prove the
Sigma protocol is collapsing
just follow the definition which recall
some knowledge about quantum or we can
prove the Sigma protocol has comparable
lossy functions or separable functions
which is purely classical condition for
example we prove that a little bit chefs
key signature the valid response are
solutions we prove sis is collapsing by
showing there are lots of functions and
separable functions okay so in
conclusion we show that a sigma protocol
with special sound plus collapsing
property gives you proof of knowledge
and for honest verify their knowledge
proof of knowledge plus fill Shamir it
unconditionally gives you non
interactive there are knowledge proof of
knowledge and unforgeable signature and
as example we show the Reshevsky
signature is post quantum secure thanks
and we have time for a couple of
questions just a quick question
so it's part of the Novation you
mentioned picnic dilithium and in QD s s
mq d s s is yeah she Mir base but it's a
five-run identification scheme not a 3r
and like standard Sigma's that still
work there with not any kind of loss of
parameters or we are actually currently
working on extending the proof that we
have for Sigma protocol for the three
run schemes to multiple round schemes
okay
so there's there's more that's going on
that you have to kind of handle I guess
yeah yeah it takes yeah it's a
non-trivial extension but we suspect
that it should be possible okay great
thanks so you showed that a large class
of Sigma protocols that are collapsing
or quantumly sound is it known agar and
a sigma protocols that are not quantumly
sound that are like standard classical
sound sound and such examples I'm sorry
are there in examples of Sigma protocols
that that are not collapsing and are
also not talk to my sound
you mean like is there any example which
is like not collapsing but also not like
sounding content yes yes there is some
example show in previous work yeah yes
okay last call for questions all right
let's think yellow keeping all the
you