so thanks for the introduction so I'm
going to talk about liquid resilience
secret sharing and applications and this
is based on joint work with pressure and
not anyway so David so let me start the
talk by giving you a brief overview of
threshold secret sharing so as you might
all be aware it was introduced in the
seminal works of Shamir and black lee in
the late 70s and in this setting there
is a dealer who has a secret message m
and he wants to split the secret into n
shares sh 1 2 sh n with some threshold
parameter T the dealer then sends the
Ayad share Shi to party P I so we
require a threshold secret sharing to
satisfy two properties the first is the
correctness property which states that
any group of T or more parties can come
together Eustatius to reconstruct the
secret message m and the second property
is the secrecy property which states
that any adversary whose correcting at
most t minus one parties learns no
information about the secret message so
threshold secret sharing is a
fundamental cryptographic perimeter with
numerous applications some of the
applications include constructing secure
multi-party computation protocols
constructing threshold cryptographic
primitives and so on and the security of
all these applications crucially relay
on the secrecy property of the
underlying secret sharing scheme
so the question we would like to address
today is that what if the adversary in
addition to corrupting t minus one
parties also learn some partial
information about the harness party
shares so this information could be
leaked to the adversary there are some
side channels that it might have on the
storage devices of the harness parties
so the privacy property that I just
mentioned does not give any guarantees
under the stronger adversarial model and
hence we n hence we need a stronger
notion of security in order to capture
this so this was done by two independent
works one by Bentham who died at all
which appeared in crypto last year and
other by Goyle and kumar that appeared
in stock 2018 and they introduced this
notion called as leakage resilient
secret sharing so leakage resilient
secret sharing is just like any other
threshold secret sharing satisfying the
correctness property in addition the
privacy property is now strengthened to
some
Calder's leakage resilience so this
states that any adversary who's
corrupting at most D minus one parties
learns no information about the
underlying secret message M even when
given some bounded leakage from the
other shares so let's see the formal
definition so the formal definition is
modeled as a game between an adversary
and a challenger so the Challenger first
generates the sharing of some secret
message m and let's call the shares to
be a search one to sh n the adversary
now gives a set T which denotes the set
of corrupted parties as well as some
leakage functions F is to be applied on
the harness party shares so we require
two properties the first is that the
size of the set T which denotes the
number of corrupted parties that should
be less than or equal to t minus 1 the
second property is that the output
length of this function fi should be
bounded so notice that if we allow the
output length of these functions to be
arbitrary then the the functions output
length could be as long as the share
size and if the identity and the
functions are just identity functions
then the adversity gets all the
information about the secret so here we
cannot hope to give any sort of privacy
and hence we need to restrict the output
length of these leakage functions to
have some bounded length however notice
that we do not place any restrictions on
the computational complexity of these
leakage functions so these leakage
functions could be arbitrary as long as
they have a bounded output length so
given this the Challenger now sends back
the shares corresponding to the
corrupted parties as well as the output
of these leakage functions are played on
the harness party shares so at the end
we require the adversary given even this
additional information not to learn any
in for any information about the secret
message M okay so this is the formal
definition and let me give you a brief
overview of the prior work in this area
so guruswami and voters in 2017 showed
that ramiz secret sharing when
instantiated over finite fields with
characteristic 2 is not leakage
resilient that is they showed an
explicit reconstruction strategy that
allows an adversary to obtain the entire
secret given some partial information
from all the shares in interesting work
Ben Hamada it all showed that Tommy's
secret sharing when instantiated over a
large prime order field is in fact
leakage resilient for thresholds T
greater than or equal to n minus n to
the 1/4 and in the work of Goyle and
Kumar they gave a different construction
of liquid resilient secret sharing
scheme for the constant thresholds case
so as you can see there is a huge gap
which is left so the first question that
we would like to address is that can we
construct a leakage resilient secret
sharing scheme for all thresholds and
the second question is that can be
extended to for all monotone access
structures so in this work we resolve
this question so we show a compiler that
takes any secret sharing scheme for a
monotone access structure a with some
rate R and it converts into it into a
leakage resilient secret sharing scheme
for the same access truck sure with the
following properties the first property
is that the rate of the resultant secret
sharing scheme is only a constant
multiplicative factor worse than the
rate of the original sharing scheme that
is the rate of the leakage resilience
secret sharing is our over three point
zero one and the second property is that
the leakage resilience rate which is
defined to be the ratio of the number of
bits leak to the sheer size can be made
to be arbitrarily close to one so this
in turn implies that even if we leak
almost 99% of the share size we can show
we can prove security and in the next
talk you will hear from mark about about
their construction which also gives such
a compiler okay so as an application of
our compiler we show how to construct a
constant rate not valuable secret
sharing scheme in the information
theoretic setting so as you heard in the
first talk non valuable secret sharing
is just like any other threshold secret
sharing scheme that is it satisfies the
correctness and the secrecy properties
it also satisfies this additional non
malleability property which roughly
states
that any tampering attack on the shares
either preserves the original secret or
completely destroys it so this notion
was introduced in the work of Goa and
Kumar in 2018 and it can be thought of
as a generalization of this notion of
non malleable codes and a question that
was left open in their work was to
construct a constant rate non malleable
secret sharing in the information
theoretic setting so what we show in
this work is that if we plug in our leak
is resilient secret sharing with the non
malleable secret sharing compiler of
Badri Narayan and Mises that appeared in
Europe this year we can in fact get a
constant rate threshold non-merits
secret sharing for thresholds T greater
than or equal to 4 and in the next talk
you'll also hear about giving a stronger
notion of non valuable secret sharing
from this leak a resilient secret
sharing and I hope that mark will be
able to give these details so as another
application we also give a leakage
tolerant multi-party computation for
general interaction patterns but
unfortunately I wouldn't have time to go
into the details and I would encourage
you to look into our paper ok so in the
rest of the talk I will focus on the
threshold case I will give you a
construction of leaky resilient secrets
sharing that has a constant rate but the
rate would be a small it would be worse
than the promised by a compiler and also
the leak is resilience rate that our
construction satisfied would be worse
but than the optimum of one but it's
still a constant so this is these
simplifications are just for the purpose
of this talk ok so so let's start with
the construction so let's say that we
want to secret share a message M so the
first step in a construction is to just
split this message m into n shares using
Shamir secretary so here we do not
assume any leakage resilience property
from the underlying Shammi secret
sharing scheme
ok so let's assume that each of these
shammy shares is in a finite field f the
step is to choose a random vector R from
F to the K where K is some constant
ok so once you choose this are you then
choose a random vector l1 from F to the
K such that the India product of L 1
with this R is equal to the first
jamesha is this one then you do this for
the next one as well so you choose a
random vector l2 such that the inner
product of l2 with the same R is the
second shemesh RSS 2 and so on so you
choose L 3 up to L n such that the inner
product with our as the corresponding
Shama shares okay so this you obtain L 1
2 L n and this is the second step so the
final step is to take this vector R and
you then split it into in shares r1 to
RN using Shammi secret sharing now over
F to the K okay so the share
corresponding to riot party will be Li
comma RA ok so this is the secret
sharing scheme so how do we reconstruct
you first given any t-shirts you can use
the Shamy secret sharing to reconstruct
this R then you take the inner product
with the corresponding Allies to get the
T shammy shares of N and then you use
the reconstruction of Shamir again to
get the secret message so this is how
the reconstruction works so the
interesting point is that how do we show
that traitors in fact secure against in
the leakage model so for the purpose of
the stock let's assume that the the
final t minus 1 shares are revealed in
the clear this corresponds to the set T
and there is some arbitrary leakage
function acting on the rest of the
shares so this is this for the purpose
of this talk so the proof actually
follows from several observations so the
first observation is that each
individual leakage function f does not
learn any information about the secret
vector R that was chosen in the sharing
fields so to see why this is the case
notice that each of these F is just
looks at one of these our eyes and since
R is
in fact a chemise share of our it hides
all the information about our so one can
roughly think about the leakage function
acting solely on the vector allies so
this is the first observation that the
fi of la cama ra if i does not get any
information about our so the second
observation is that the output of this
leakage function fi of alaykum RI hides
all information about the Shamy share
SSI case or to see why this is the case
notice that inner product acts as a
strong to source extractor so even given
some bounded leakage on one of the
sources here one of the sources is real
ly the inner product of Li with the
other source as which is R has
sufficient entropy so this can be
formalized to show that fi of la cama RI
hides all information about the
underlying jamesha SSI so this is the
second observation and the third
observation is that the only Xiaomi
shares the diverse area gets access to
are those which correspond to which
revealed in the clear and since there
are at most T minus one revealed shares
though it follows from the privacy of
the Shamy secret sharing of M that these
t minus one shares hide information
about so this is the rough intuition
behind the proof of course there are
lots of subtleties involved and I would
encourage you to look into the paper for
the exact details so to conclude the
main latina paper is to give a compiler
that converts a secret sharing scheme
for a monotone access structure a to a
leak a resilient secret sharing scheme
for the same access structure with the
following property so it has a constant
factor degradation in the rate and it
has optimal leakage resilience rate and
we give applications of to constructing
constant rate non valuable secret
sharing in the information theoretic
setting as well as application to
constructing leakage tolerant MPC
protocols for restricted interaction
patterns and in a concurrent and an
independent work Kumar Mecca and Sakai I
gave a strong
the notion of liquid resilience property
and they actually gave interesting
constructions based on connections to
communication complexity so an
interesting open question would be to
find other applications of leakage the
resilient secret sharing scheme and
that's it thank you for your attention
[Applause]
Marx Lincoln will continue the
presentation
okay alright so I'm going to present her
our paper which deals with a very
similar topic to the paper that we just
heard about so this is stronger leakage
resilient and non malleable secret
sharing for general access structures
and this is a paper a joint work with
debisch Agarwal even dumb guard yes /
boos Nielsen Macchio Bronski Eric Previn
- Joe
Ribeiro and me and yes so we like
already heard like why does not involve
a secret sharing what a sneaky chisel in
secret sharing in the previous talk so
I'm kind of gonna focus on the things
that you didn't hear so much yet so
nothing about secret sharing as here
before was introduced quite recently but
like a lot of papers deal with this
problem and the ideas again that you
have some file and your secret share
like you compute a bunch of shares and
now the adversary can somehow tamper
with each file independently with each
share independently and what we would
like is that the reconstructed secret
from the temperatures is either the same
as it was before or it is completely
unrelated okay so we want to prevent
that a distance formed into related
message and the first notion dealt with
the case of a single tempering and like
a minimal reconstruction set and what we
do in this work is that we extend this
non-availability notion to something I
recall concurrent reconstruction and the
idea is that in this case the adversary
cannot specify like one set of tempering
not one vector of tempering functions
but several vectors of tempering
functions and so he does this in a non
adaptive way which is in contrast to the
paper that Antonia presented so here he
like has to specify all of the vectors
at once and then the secret sharing at
the top will basically be thrown into
these tempering functions and then even
we can use different reconstruction sets
here which are again chosen on
adaptively by the adversary we
reconstruct with their for your
consumption sets it gets different kind
of corrupted secrets and again we want
to have the property that all of those
are so that for any one of those secrets
it's either the same one as it was
before or it is completely unrelated
okay and yes okay
so what we do in our paper is basically
so kind of abstractly speaking like we
construct like leakage resilience secret
sharing construct not malleable secret
sharing but the general idea of how to
construct all of them follow us the same
kind of blueprint so what we will end up
doing is we will take a secret sharing
scheme and we will take some encoding
function and we will like mingle them
together and then depending on which
encoding function you plug in you will
get either leakage resilience we will
get non mail ability so it's kind of
like a general simple approach of how to
do these things yes we get leakage
resilience so and all of this is for
general access structures and with
information theoretic security and yes
our non noble secret sharing will be for
three monotone general X structures so
that means that any authorized set has
at least size three and then we use
again basically the same approach to
show that you can also build something
which we'll call leakage or non
malleable threshold signatures which are
like skim over at towards the end of the
talk and in comparison to the previous
talk what we basically have is that both
um
so both the non mailbox you could
sharing and to leakage resilience equal
sharing that we construct has a signal
like a worse rate then the constructions
from the previous talk but in comparison
to previous talk we achieve a stronger
security notion for our non malleable
secret sharing so this is kind of how
the two papers compliment each other
okay so kind of on a very high level
what we have is we're given some secret
sharing for some axis structure and what
we would like now to do is we would like
to take those shares and somehow
re-encode them into a new share into a
new share such that we get like the
leakage resilience and non mobility
properties and what we yes and what we
want what we will basically do is think
of like we have some encoding function
which takes each one of those shares and
it will produce two different shares
okay and then again we will plug in
different encoding functions to get
different things so what we simply do is
we will take each of those shares and we
will split it into two shares with this
encoding function
and now we will redistribute the shares
accordingly as follow us so originally
the first share was this and now the new
first share will be this vector of
shares okay so what does this it what is
this it will be the green one of the
first share and then all of the other
red ones okay and for the second share
it will be like the green one of the
second one and then all of the red ones
from the other ones and we'll continue
doing this now if we want to reconstruct
say we have this first and the second
share then we can combine those two and
those two to reconstruct the original
two shares and then if this is kind of
like if the exit structure allows these
two shares to reconstruct the secret and
the whole construction will kind of
reconstruct the secret okay and note
that kind of if this encoding in some
sense requires that you definitely need
both of those parts to reconstruct what
you encode it then for the third share
for the fourth share for the future
you'd never have the green part okay so
you like they know exactly they can
exactly decode the two shares that they
are supposed to decode yes and the other
important thing is that every one of the
green shares is held exactly by one
party okay so yeah it's a very obvious
statement it's one party that has
h-bridge here so now the question is
what do we do what encoding do we use to
obtain different secret sharing scheme
so let's start with non leakage
resilient secret sharing and it's in the
same model as before so we basically can
independently leak from each share and
we would like to ensure that the secret
remains hidden even when the adverse
receives the leakage okay so what we
will use is basically a strong seeded
extractor which is a primitive that it
takes this like a uniformly random seed
as input some high min entropy string so
yeah that has a lot of entropy and when
you apply the extractor you will get
something that looks uniform or as close
to uniform okay and the strong here
means that even if the seed is revealed
this still looks close to uniformly
random and another property that we will
need for our construction is that this
extractor also has something
called proficient preimage sampling so
that means that if I have something here
I can efficiently find some uniformly
random inputs or close to uniformly
random inputs that will if the
extractors applied to it give me that
output okay and what we now simply do is
to encode one of those original secret
shares we will apply this inverse of the
extractor to obtain these two things and
so basically one of those will be the
seed and one of those will be the high
mean entropy sample and like as we've
seen from the previous samples from the
previous previous slides the Jade share
will then be kind of a bunch of the red
ones and one of the green ones this will
compose the new share and if we look
what this means here is we will
basically have one of those things will
be this long sample and the rest of
those will be the short seeds which will
in total compose the new share of our
leakage resilient secret sharing scheme
and the intuition why this is a leakage
resilient secret sharing scheme is that
even if the adversary gets to ligue
pretty much all of the red shares as I
said before the green share is only held
by one part like each of the green
shares is only held by one party okay
and what this just says is that this
just has to be some high mean entropy
sample so that means that if after
leaking some of its bits there's still a
lot of entropy left then she cannot do
anything based on the properties of the
extractor okay and we all like by
plugging in a different encoding scheme
we almost immediately get non-male the
secret sharing we just need to make some
small tweaks so the one thing that we
need to prevent if we if we want to have
non bailable secret sharing is that in
the construction that I said before
whatever encoding scheme we use it
doesn't prevent that the adverse we
could just override a share with some
default value okay so in this case the
adverse you could just go and over
eyes.the the second share here with some
default value and this could potentially
lead to a reconstruction here that
reconstructs a related secret to get
like if you want to think of a very
simple example think of a modified samir
secret sharing
okay like imagine your Shamir secret
sharing and you are given an on minimal
authorized set now what what this
modified sham your secret sharing scheme
could do is good could say okay I will
take a minimal authorized set and
reconstruct the secret and then I will
have a special kind of share and for
every appearance of this special share I
will add class one to the reconstructed
secret so in this case if I had this
kind of artificial secret sharing scheme
I could override this thing here with
this special share and this would result
in this constructing a related secret
okay
so this is kind of an artificial example
but the compiler has to deal with all
kinds of secret sharing scheme but this
problem is solved in a very simple
fashion so we just add a nonce to every
share so now rather than encoding the
first share the second share and so on
we just pick an additional knowns are
and then this encoding will basically be
the first share concatenated with our
and so on and the reconstruction
function is modified accordingly that it
reconstructs the blue shares and if the
nonces are not consistent and it will
abort and otherwise it will reconstruct
the secret because now if you were to
override a share you would need to
somehow know R which you don't so this
is kind of why the this nonce prevents
this attack and I won't go into details
like what encoding scheme you have to
use but basically it's similar to the
encoding scheme that I just showed you
for the leakage resilient secret sharing
just that it's kind of it has kind of
some extra non-male ability properties
and then these non malleability
properties directly transferred to the
secret sharing scheme and that we
construct and then pretty much the same
trick that like we did throw it like
this talked so far you can also play to
get something that we call fresh leakage
resilient or non malleable threshold
signatures so what you just do is so in
a threshold signature scheme you have a
key pair and they the key is split into
a bunch of secret like key shares and
all of those key shares can be used to
assign method messages and then these
signature algorithm produced signature
shares and from the signature shares I
can basically construct a signature for
the message that will verify under this
public key and then we introduce non
malleable secret sharing non malleable
threshold signatures where we require
that even if
the adversary' men is allowed to tamper
once with the vector of secret keys and
afterwards seized allowed to query for
signatures on messages of his choice he
should still not break the unforgeable
'ti guarantee and in a similar fashion
we get something for leakage resilient
so here he there are the secret keys the
adversary gets to see some leakage on
all of those keys and again then like in
a chosen message type of security notion
he should not be able to forge a message
so I won't go into detail how we
construct it but basically the
constructions are kind of similar to
what I showed before of how to
distribute the secret key like how to
split the secret the secret shares or
the secret keys in this point and how to
distribute them among the players so
with this we kind of get leakage
resilient and honorable threshold
signatures yes questions we have time
for questions and both authors will be
on stage to answer them as you ponder
yours I have one of mine can you speak
of applications of your schemes and how
close we are in terms of concrete
parameters to being suitable for these
applications let me think about
practicality I said so the main issue
with this to answer this why for me it's
a hard question to answer is because
like I'm not sure what you would
consider a practical parameters for the
for instance the threshold signature
scheme like for like reasonable values
of n I think it is like you get like you
get somewhat large or a secret keys then
you have an original threshold signature
scheme but they're not extremely large
like I think this could be like
practical of you if you wanted to do
something like this and you are the
questions well let's think so thank all
the speakers of this session
[Applause]