thank you for saying the title so I
don't have to my name is Tatiana Bradley
I am a student at UC Irvine and this is
joint work with my advisor stasher etske
and my colleague died your shoe I'm
gonna be talking about strong asymmetric
password authenticate a key exchange so
I'm gonna explain what the problem is
which is passport authentication over
the Internet
explain how we can use crypto to do it
better and show our protocol which we
believe is one of the best ways to use
crypto to do password authentication
better I'll show you some building
blocks and then I'll discuss some open
questions that still remain so how was
password authentication done in practice
now it's basically just password over
TLS so umm if we have a server Charles
he has a password file which is a which
has a salt and a hashed salted hash of
the password and he's going to prove to
Ada that he has the right public key
using a certificate authority and then
they're gonna use TLS to establish a
shared session key which is just going
to be a symmetric key and so all of this
has nothing to do as pad passwords yet
but then now ada is going to simply
encrypt her password under that shared
symmetric key Charles decrypt it and
checks if it is matches the hashed
password so it's very simple but there's
at least two problems with this method
one is of course that it relies on PKI
and we all know there many attacks on
PKI one example is phishing ada believes
she's talking to Charles but she's
actually talking to a malicious server I
mean if that's the case then she
basically just sends her password to a
malicious server and all of her security
regarding her password is lost the other
problem which is a little bit more
subtle is that at least for some number
of milliseconds or whatever
Charles holds the password of ada in the
clear so that means if Charles the
server is corrupted at any point while
he's checking that password the
adversary who corrupts the server learns
that password is so we'd like to be able
to do better with script oh and of
course we can because we're at crypto so
our first attempt is going to be to use
password authenticated key exchange
which is a well-established primitive
it's been studied in the game based
simulation based models as well as the
universally composable model so how does
that work we assume a DES and Charles
each have a password they inserted into
a Paik protocol and then they get the
same key if their passwords match
otherwise they get an independently
random key and you can think of this as
just like a secure computation of a
password equality function with the
addition of getting keys so what are the
good things about this no PKI attacks
because there's no PKI so we're good for
that problem with TLS and the other good
thing is that charles doesn't get ADA's
password in the clear during the
protocol because it's your secure
computation so her password is private
but of course in order to be a server
charles needs to store the password on
his server that he inserts into the
protocol so basically we have an even
worse problem with the server with the
server storing a password in the clear
because it's sort it's stored for a long
time not just a couple seconds so we
hope to do a little bit better than this
and the here we have something called a
symmetric cake and this has also been
studied in the game base and you see
models and this is a simple extension of
cake in which instead of storing just a
password Charles the server stores a
hash of that password so you can think
of F here as a one-way function we of
course have the same pros of pate normal
Paik and then we get the added Pro that
if the server is compromised then the
adversary has to do an offline
dictionary attack in order to learn the
password based on that password file but
because the function f is the public
fixed function any computation for that
offline dictionary attack can occur
before the actual server compromised so
basically the
Cerie who has some time on their hands
can do a bunch of computation and then
once they get access to the server
immediately determine what a lot of the
passwords are so we want to do even
better than that and this is where we
have strong asymmetric Paik and this has
recently proposed that you know crypt
bye-bye my advisor and my colleagues and
2018 and I the way this works is
probably how you thought it would which
is instead of holding a regular a
unsalted randomized function we use a
randomized function so we just add a
salt a random salt and now we get the
benefit that there is no possibility of
offline dictionary attack
pre-computation because the salt is per
user and it's not known beforehand so
finally we are able to use crypto and
get all the benefits of password over
TLS but none of the shortcomings so this
is great but what's our contribution
here because this is already existing so
just a recap we have password over TLS
the current de facto standard this is
nice because it's standard it uses TLS
it's efficient it's modular basically it
doesn't matter what hash function you
use it doesn't matter what encryption
scheme you use you just encrypt the
password but as I said it has the two
problems that I mentioned so opaque the
protocol proposed euro crypt proposes a
universally composable strong apec that
of course is independent of PKI
it has three rounds that is based on an
interactive assumption and what our
contribution is is that we're proposing
a new you see strong a peak and we're
able to shave off one round and we have
a similar number of number of
exponentiations but we don't have to
hash onto a group we have a number of
assumptions including ROM we also use
ggm but that is isolated into an offline
part of the protocol and we're also
proposing some new
some new primitives the you see tight
one-way function and the implicit
statement conditional secant and we're
showing how we can adapt a existing
paradigm for cakes and for you see pigs
into a strong a pig and also shave off
one half of that paradigm so it's a nice
little result there so let me get into
it explain each one of these things so
let's start with the tight one-way
function so this is in the UC model so
we have something called F stuff and
that's the idealized functionality of a
salted tight one-way function and the
salsa tight one-way function has some
passwords some secret password that it
knows and it has some notion of being
compromised and it has some notion of
having a password attack password guess
being happening against it so in the
case that it's compromised is where it's
just sends a message okay I'm
compromised and in the proof or any kind
of proofs using this we need to when we
hear that the server is going to
compromise we need to sort of generate
some kind of password file that looks
legitimate to pretend to have been a
real server that has a password file so
we have to generate that based on
usually just some kind of random
password but we don't know what the
password is so we have to generate that
without knowing the password and then
the the other functionality of the F
stuff is that you can ask it is this the
right password so it's basically like a
point function what you're saying is
this the password it says yes or no and
I learned whether it's the password and
then using that functionality as a
simulator we need to translate the real
attacker who's doing some kind of
offline local computation we need to
translate that into a password guess so
for example if the one-way function is
just a hash function it's saying hash of
password X and then we say okay since
we're a random Oracle we know what that
password we know what that password was
and then we say is this the right
password yes or no and then if is right
we pro
the password file to have to be
correspond to that correct password
guess if it's not we just give it some
kind of some kind of junk
so as I've been saying I gave an example
with the random Oracle model it seems
like with this model you're gonna need
some kind of idealized computation yeah
so this is just a description of what a
type one way function is basically you
can think of the type one way function
as being you if you make a password
the best the best strategy for learning
the password from the hash password is
simply to guess all the passwords trial
hash them and so forth so brute force
you can't like shave off a factor an
exponential factor or something but yeah
so as I was saying it's it seems like
we're gonna need some kind of idealized
model for this so the first example I
gave is the hash function and that's
what password over TLS basically uses
because the server is drawing that
hashed password then the other example
is the hash and the exponent type where
you have a group element that's the
random group metal element that's the
salt and you raise it to the hash of the
password and that and we're using a
variant of this and it's been used
before it requires a programmable
generic group model in order to show
that it's a stealth but we're okay with
that because this tight one-way function
is only surrounding the sort of offline
part of the protocol in which the
adversary is compromising the server
it's not during the actual protocol so
this this does raise some questions such
as are there can we prove a tight lower
bound for some other arithmetic one-way
functions beyond the the one I just
described there is one caveat and this
is something technical that you can read
about more and our paper but we're
actually using a variant of this hash in
the exponent which is similar to the
bony boy and signature function and the
reason for this is because we don't want
the password file to be malleable and
the reason for this is that we don't
want the adversary who steals the
password file to be able to
randomize the password file and then
pretend to be the adversary without us
being able to tell they're pretending to
the adversary so it's kind of a
technical point for the proof but from
now on in the talk I'll just sort of use
this F self as an abstract primitive
alright so I told you that we are
working with a existing paradigm the
encryption plus SP hf paradigm so let me
show you how that works with regular
Paik if we have if we go back to our
regular setting where we have a pass we
have a password on both side unless
suppose that ADA wants to prove that she
has the right password so ada sends a
commitment to her password using a
public key encryption scheme and the
public keys in the CRS so she commits to
her password using the public key
encryption scheme and then Charles
creates a statement that's in a think of
like an NP language he creates a
statement that says ok this commitment
of ADA's encrypts the same password as
the one that I have so it encrypts my
password and of course this statement
could be true or it could be false and
then he plugs the statement into this
magic s BHF box this page s BHF has two
algorithms that has the hash algorithm
and the p hash algorithm and p hash
stands for projection hash the hash
algorithm takes in a statement and it
outputs a value and a hash projection
the value is like a secret value the
hash projection you can think of it as
kind of like a key so the hash
projection you can send that to someone
and then they can use the P hash value
along with a witness for your statement
that to get that same value so what's
happening here is that Charles is
showing that so if only if ada has the
witness for her commitment can she
recover that that value and also she
can't recover it if she encrypted the
wrong password because the statement
will not be in the language so that
shows that that proved to Charles that
ada has the right password
but then Charles has to show ADA the
same thing so you just do the same thing
symmetrically on the other side and
that's and that's how they SBI Jeff the
plus encryption paradigm works what
about with a pig so with a pig we just
do a simple transformation we instead of
having Charles have the password he has
the hash of the password and he his
commitment his statement is that ADA's
commitment encrypts the preimage of the
preimage of his password file and he and
said in in he encrypts the password file
outside of the password and so forth
it's just kind of a simple
transformation so that all that's all
fine and what about for SA Pig we can do
the same thing but with the salts but
what we notice here is that because we
basically need to use ROM because of the
Stout as I said we need to use wrong for
the south
so if we use ROM we can shave off a
whole half of this protocol oh and just
to just for some context this kind of
thing can be done without the random
Oracle model in general but if we say
okay it's fine to use ROM then we can
shave off half of this protocol so how
do we do that what we did we do need to
change some things
so in particular we now have Ada and now
has no guarantee that Charles has the
right password file because she proved
that she has the password but he didn't
prove anything so we need to embed
inside of this this hash projection some
more information so we need CCA security
we need it to be non malleable and we
also need it to be able to carry a
payload an encrypted payload so because
he because Charles needs to be able to
send his password file over to Ada so
she can check that he does have the
right one and has to be non malleable so
that he can't pretend he had the
password file when he didn't really have
it
and then this sort of changed s VHF is
going to be what we call an implicit
statement sequence alright so the
implicit statements seek him is works
pretty similar to the SB HF we have a
syn algorithm that's like the hash
algorithm and a receive out algorithm
that's like the P hash algorithm the
send algorithm transforms a statement
into a key in a ciphertext the receive
algorithm transforms a witness and that
ciphertext into a statement and a key so
here it's called implicit statement
because the receiver does not need to
know what the statement is in order to
generate the value and in fact she
retrieves the statement in the in the
course of doing the receiver algorithm
and so that's great because in our
setting the receiver who's going to be
the client ADA doesn't know what the
password file is she needs to grab it
and check it and then this is a trapdoor
conditional seek him and so that means
we have a trapdoor algorithm that can
use a trapdoor and the crs to compute
the same values that ada can compute and
they look indistinguishable from a
disease this is just used in the proof
and we also have simulation sadness
which you can think of like CCA
and that's that the key appears to be
rent the key K that the sender generates
appears to be random
if the statement he sends is not in fact
in the language even given the presence
of this trapdoor receiver so you can
think of that like a decryption Oracle
and finally we have statement privacy
which says that the statement is hidden
without the witness and this is the
thing I just described is fairly similar
to implicit there zero-knowledge put it
proposed by ben amudha at all but the
new thing here is the statement privacy
notion and that's that the statement is
hidden given the ciphertext you cannot
determine what the statement is unless
you have the witness and that's
important because if the statement is
revealed then the statement reveals the
password file
then it's as though the adversary
compromised the server without even
having to do any work so basically just
by listening on the network they would
get the password file and we don't want
that to be the case all right so how do
we make the implicit statement trapdoor
cecum I'm not going to go through all
the details but you can think of it like
if you're familiar with the Fujisaki
Okamoto transform from cpa to CC a
public key encryption you can think of
it like that basically what we're doing
is we are we're encrypting we're using
that that hash value that we got that we
know is the same if those two passwords
if the passwords match we're using that
to encrypt the randomness that we use to
make the hash and also the statement
itself and also just macking everything
so that nothing can be changed and then
then a DES now knows that if Charles
sent her a valid ciphertext that he does
have a valid he does have a valid
password file and nothing was changed so
basically if we tie that all together
what that gives us is this is like the
picture before except now we're using
the trapdoor seek him and the send and
receive function instead and just to
recap we know that ADA authenticates
herself using using the basic cecum
security which is that if she is able to
decrypt the Charles's Charles's
ciphertext then she must know the the
witness and the statement must be
correct so she must have encrypted the
correct password and then Charles also
authenticates to Ada because he's
including his encrypted password file
and the payload so we we basically just
combine the the work that is done by the
SB HF which is the authenticating ADA
with the authenticating Charles into the
same cipher text so that's how we shave
it down to two rounds and this is our
protocol oh and just submit
doesn't know we instantiate the PK with
a lifted al-jamal which is just a slight
variant of elgu mall and with our own
Stan she ation of the cecum based on SB
hf we're able to get a very efficient
protocol what I want to highlight for my
summary is that we are in our
instantiation is is quite efficient and
not only does have two rounds but it
also in terms of variable variable based
exponentiations which are much more
expensive than fixed based
exponentiations we only have one or one
to two per party and so if you think of
regular definite divvy home and key
exchange you would have one variable
base per party so we're actually getting
pretty close to that plain
unauthenticated diffie-hellman and that
leads into one thing I'm particularly
interested in which is integrating this
work with TLS that's our last open
question but some other cool open
questions are whether there are other
tight one-way function constructions
like with different assumptions and
maybe we could even get rid of ggm and
wrong it's impossible to shave off the
rounds from s APEC even further would we
be able to make a seek him faster by
using DHIA s type transform instead of
fo finally could we extend it to
two-factor authentication or T peg so
yeah that's all I have thank you so much
for your time
[Applause]
all right
we gonna have some time for questions
please come to the mic if you have one I
would have a quick one regarding that I
guess the last bullet point integration
so my understanding is that OPEC is on
its way to potentially being sender dies
at least it's an working group item of
the CFR G do you have any similar plans
with that protocol we don't have any
specific plans regarding that and I am
aware that opaque is on this on the road
too but I would like to I don't have
specific plans but I would like to get
in on that if possible yeah cool okay
all right
they no other questions thinks things
are yet again
[Applause]