okay thank you much hi everyone my name
is Phil cool I am a PhD student from
Cornell University today I'm going to
talk about her work are we thinking the
classical synchronous model in
distributed consensus and our proposal
of a refinement of synchrony to make it
more robust and partition tolerant in
this talk our first give an example of
protocol that worked in synchronous
network and then described a scenario in
which with this protocol a benign
failure can cause real world financial
loss to users to show why we think the
classical synchronous network assumption
is not suitable for practical use cases
to fix a problem I will then give our
proposal of the new model with better
robustness and partition tolerance and
then give a fix to the protocol to make
it work in a new model oh okay so before
talking about any specific protocols
let me first quickly recap the consensus
goal we want to achieve all of these
public blockchain protocols like beacon
Assyrian all those pbft style protocols
they want to reach this state machine
application notion we say they want to
have honest notes agree and linearly
ordered lock to be more specific we want
to have both consistency and liveness
but consistency would mean that all of
the honest notes should agree on the
same lock and by liveness will mean that
any transaction that appeared network
should be confirmed within a short time
so now let's take a look at a very
simple voting protocol that working
synchronous network the the protocol
wrong with n nodes one of them is a
proposer and the other nodes here as if
superheroes are voters some of these
nodes can be corrupt
like interlopers crap and when some
transaction comes the proposal first
signs the transaction with a sequence
number and proposes the distraction to
the voters I think the
and seeing the proposal the voters will
vote for this proposal the important
thing here is the honest note will only
vote for one transaction for each
sequence number and I'm collecting
enough number of votes for the same
transaction the proposer used is false
to form an authorization for the
transaction and send not wretched not
reddish and back to the voters I've seen
the notarization of a transaction note
things the transaction is confirmed so
how many votes are enough to confirm
transaction if we assume that less than
one half of voters are corrupt then we
need to collect at least three quarters
of votes to confirm a transaction the
consistency proof it's just a simple
pigeonhole principle map and I will not
go to the details of it but it only
relies on honest majority assumption
however because now we need to wait for
three quarters of votes honest majority
assumption is not enough for liveness if
more than one quarter of nodes are
corrupt or if the proposer is corrupt
and they just keep silent the protocol
can stop so the challenge here is how to
achieve lightness with just honest
majority assumption here we make use of
a slow chain we use this voting process
at fast paths and if something bad
happens the first five stops people will
detect it and fall back to a slow chain
which can guarantee both consistency and
liveness with honest maturity assumption
such as Bitcoin or cerium will fall it
back one of the challenges that
different node might have different view
of the fast path lab so here people need
to reach agreement on the fast path log
and slow chain so they are required to
post all of their confirmed transaction
and to slow chain after they reach in
the agreement they can always react the
proposer or the voters to read start the
fast path so now we have a protocol with
responsiveness
with honest majority assumption now we
can guarantee both consistency and
lightness because we rely on slow chain
and if the condition is good enough we
can actually have a protocol that can
confirm a transaction with one round of
voting however as I said sorry actually
the protocol I described here is a
simplified version of Cinderella by
rafasa annealing should be published in
Europe 10 2018
it is a peer-reviewed consensus protocol
with rigorous mathematical proofs
however as I said before I am going to
describe a scenario in which with this
protocol a confirmed transaction can
somehow be undone by the network even if
none of the node in the network is
malicious so in this scenario a
transaction comes the proposal proposes
it and voters vote for it forms
notarization and send notarization back
to voters but right after sending the
notarization to card base node the
proposer drops offline so at this time
point the canvas node becomes only one
who sees no notarization the common base
node thinks this transaction is
confirmed and it tells user saying that
hey these transactions confirm someone
want to buy a Ferrari car and the user
think ok I received the money so I
deliver my car but unfortunately right
after telling the user about the
confirmation the comp is not also jokes
offline and now all of the other nerves
detect that the first pass stopped for a
long time so they decide to fall back to
scroll chain as mentioned before when
falling back every node are supposed to
post all of their confirm transaction on
disclosure and the compas node is also
supposed to do so but because it is
offline it fails to post this
transaction after a while after after a
while when the con based note comes back
online all of the other nodes have
already read bootstrap a new fast path
and that transaction is not included in
anyone elses log so in this case the
transaction is actually been undone by
the rest of network and the user lose
both car and money it sounds horrible
right what I think has been confirmed
can be undone but Network even if I
didn't do anything wrong or perhaps I
don't know I don't even know that I am
offline because I'm did asked so how can
a properly secure protocol allow this
kind of funny behavior that is because
the protocol use synchronous assumption
so what is assumed in a synchronous
network in a synchronous network the
messages between honest nodes are
required to be delivered within doubt
around if any node fails to satisfy this
requirement itself is considered
dishonest and the protocol never
promises any consensus for dishonest
node but actually this assumption is not
practical in real world especially if
you want your protocol to run for a long
time like in 10 years even Google
Facebook server can fill federal times
so how can we fix this problem this
concern is not a new concern and
actually people have solution for it
which is another timing model has been
studied for more than 30 years partial
synchrony so in purchasing prunus
network the messages message delay
between the honest node can be
arbitrarily long or actually there there
is no upper bound assumption on the
message delay so the month the short
term outage of corn-based node will only
be will just be considered as a long
message delay rather than the node
itself is dishonest so any protocol that
working part of synchronous network
currently tolerate this kind of short
term
outage or say shorten offline or say
network partition so why don't we just
switch to a part of synchronous protocol
because if we want to get this good
position tourist property in partial
synchronous network we have to give up
resilience the impossibility result in
partial synchronous network says that
any protocol work in partial synchrony
cannot tolerate one third of corruption
on the contrary there are well-known
practical and theoretical protocols in
synchronous network can work with honest
majority assumption and furthermore if
you don't care about the running time or
the message complexity you can even have
protocol in that in synchronous network
that can tolerate arbitrary number of
corruptions so a natural question come
up here as can we achieve the best of
both world can we have both resilience
and Perdition tolerance at first glance
the answer seems to be no is impossible
because to circumvent the impossibility
result in part of synchronous network we
have to critically rely on the timing
assumption in synchronous network but if
we think about this statement a little
bit more the question actually becomes
who says that the synchrony of a network
must be a binary choice who says that a
network must be either fully synchronous
or not synchronous at all can we find
some way to describe the network
connection status more accurately and
find some place in between to take
advantage of both world to be more
specific about the question we want to
answer let's first take a look at the
networking real world so your your
network there are actually three kind of
nodes there are some green nodes they
are honest and their network connection
is very good the messages between them
can be delivered within Delta rounds but
there are also some grain
they are also honest they want to follow
the protocol description but their
network connection is unstable the
message delay for them can be long or
they might even lose messages and there
are some crap knows who's our behavior
can be arbitrary so one important thing
I want to point out here is that any
oldest node might actually at some time
point experience unstable connection or
long message delay and they can recover
from the bad connection later to be
online again so the honest nodes can
actually jump between the green and
crisp green and gray set so let's take a
look at UM the two classical time model
in this graph the classical synchronous
network the protocol only care about
those notes who are forever green if any
honest note that ever jobs offline
joined the gray set they will be
considered a scrap node and no consensus
is guaranteed for them and the classical
part of synchronous network the protocol
does not take advantage of the good
connection between green nodes so it
cannot tolerate more than one third of
corruption so what we want to do is to
actually build a new model to see if we
can achieve can see achieve consensus
for both green and Bray notes while we
still leveraging we still leverage the
good connection between green nodes to
get better
resilience than 1/3 to build this new
model the first step is to actually
quantify of the network connection
status so here we introduce a new notion
to describe this green set we cut inside
honest and not and
I said as I mentioned before the green
side can change from round to round so
here we use Oh with subscript R to
denote the honest and online set in R
and R so now we have a notation to
describe it but here we still need to be
clear about what we actually mean by
saying a notice online when we are
talking about anoles online or offline
we are actually talking about the
ability the ability of the node to send
or receive the message within bounded
time so here comes our formal assumption
about this is an online set if some node
is online in R and R and it multicast
some messages in this round then this
message will reach all of the nodes who
are online in some R and T for T larger
than or equal to R plus Delta as soon as
they are online so even if the the first
node drops off lying right after is sent
the message the notes online later are
guaranteed to receive them within
Valentine so a natural question here is
if we assume the honest and aligned set
is large enough what can we achieve can
we have better results than in the
classical synchronous and classical part
of synchronous so here comes our new
model if we assume a sorry
so the message delivery of the network
is actually controlled by the adversary
so here we say an adversary respects
kyewix synchrony if in every round the
size of the honest and aligned set its
larger than flow of tight
Khai times n plus one I want to
emphasize again that in this model we do
not require any specific single node to
be forever aligned the node can come
back online and offline the only
assumption is that at any time point
this set is large enough so what we can
achieve with this new model and our
answer consists of majorly two parts if
Chi is too small like if the honest and
online set is not larger than half of
the protocol then it is impossible to
have a protocol that can reach consensus
for both green and grey yet the
impossibility proof is intuitive for the
sake of contradiction if we assume the
existence of a such a protocol we can
easily force two small partitions in the
network to reach agreement on different
output with a bounded time but on the
other side if Chi is large enough larger
than one half then the answer is yes and
actually we can fix the protocol I
described earlier to make it guarantee
consensus for both green and grey nodes
because one half is the best we can
achieve we call this property best
possible partition tolerant tolerance so
now I'm going to give a fix to the
previous protocol to make it best
possible position tolerant that protocol
consists of two routines the fast path
and the slow chain to make the whole
protocol Parisienne tolerant we need to
have post part best possible position
tolerate the fix to the slow chain it's
a little bit more complicated so as time
is limited today I'm not
to talk about the details but the whole
idea is that it makes use of best
possible position tolerant presenting
agreement as a building block although I
am NOT going to the detail but I want to
point out here is that it is technically
non-trivial not only because we need to
fix the construction but also because we
need to rethink how to define the
security prop security property in the
new timing model for example right now
we cannot ask an offline node to output
something when it is still offline and
without enough evidence so I will leave
the fix to the slow change the paper and
here I will only talk about the easier
part how to fix the first pass the first
pass is a one-way round of voting so now
let's assume that honest node will only
vote for a new transaction after all of
the previous transaction have been
notarized so if we think this is a no
try sequence then instead of confirming
all of the notarize transaction now we
chop off the last non-traditional
section and confirm only on the prefix
and when falling back to the slow chain
we still post all of the notarized
transaction until slow chain so why does
this simple fix work in fast paths the
high-level idea is that if we assume at
any time point there are more than half
of nodes are honest and aligned then
this set of honest and aligned nodes
must intersect with a quorum who vote
for the last transaction because people
will only vote for last transaction
after they have seen the no transition
for all of the prefix and they are lying
when they are falling to the when they
are falling back to the slow chain the
noting the intersection will guaranteed
these transactions these transactions in
the prefix will appear on the slow chain
so like if Congress know these jobs are
flying but it has seen the transition
for the last transaction it is
guaranteed that all of previous
transaction will be post down to slow
chain but some other online nodes so
this is the fix to the fast path and
this is all I want to talk about the
protocol and finally at last I want to
talk about two observations we found
during we investigate we were
investigating the classical synchronous
model the first one is that any protocol
that is best possible partition tolerant
is definitely secure in classical
synchronous model with ants majority
assumption but the reverse is not true
actually all of the existing protocols
we investigated are not best possible
petition tolerant so our new notion
would say this new property is actually
a strict refinement of classical
synchrony with federal business and
partition tolerance and the second thing
is that the classical synchronous
network can somehow be misleading
because in classical synchronous Network
people attempt to think that the
protocol they are tolerating that
tolerates more corruptions like the
protocol can work with designs majority
they are strictly more robust than the
protocol that can work with less
corruption like the protocol can only
work with honest majority but as I shown
in the impossibility result if we want
to tolerate designs majority we
inherently give up the position
tolerance property so it is actually our
trade off between these two properties
rather than like one side is strictly
better than the other one so this is all
I want to talk about our work today and
the proofs are the details of
constructions the proof and more results
like the MPC protocol that working this
new timing model can be found in our
paper and thank you very much we have
time for questions our microphones on
both aisles please step after them to be
heard we appear to have no questions at
this time let's thank the speaker again
[Applause]