okay I'm going to be talking about
amplification in summation in the
shuffle model of differential privacy so
I shall start by introducing
differential privacy and the shuffle
model before talking about exactly what
we've done in this work okay so in
differential policy we have a database
which has people's beta in it and we're
going to perform some analysis and the
property that we want is that the output
shouldn't tell you too much about any
one person in the database so formalize
this we imagine we have some other
database which instead of having me in
it has Elmo in it and we don't want the
adversary to be able to tell a different
dot to tell whether it was me or Elmo in
the data set from looking at the output
and so the arbitration be able to
distinguish these two outputs now of
course if this was statistically secure
with some negligible statistical
distance then by some triangle
inequality argument you can see that
even if every entry in the database was
different you wouldn't be able to tell
any difference in the outputs and thus
the output wouldn't be telling you
anything about the data so that would be
useless so we're going to have to relax
our notion of what it means to be able
to distinguish two data sets and this
definition is the definition of
differential privacy so what's this
saying we've got X and X prime to just
two databases that differ in one place
and then we're talking about the
probability that any event happens on
the output of the analysis you should
think of this Delta on the end there's
been some cryptographically small
parameter but like the statistical
distance so if you think of that as
being zero for a second the condition
become just saying that the likelihood
ratio between the case when you're
looking at database X and when you're
looking at database X primed is bounded
by e to the epsilon so this somehow says
that the adversary can't learn too much
about anyone purse
or learn anything with too much
confidence okay so how are we going to
apply this definition well originally
the model that differential privacy was
developed for is the trusted curator
model where we have some trusted third
party everyone gives all of data to this
trusted third party the trusted third
party computes some statistics on that
data with some randomness handed to them
and then releases them to an analyzer
who is also our adversary and we want
the analyzer to then be able to say
something useful about so this analysis
of the data is going to be useful but
without being able to tell much too much
about any one person because n is
differentially private then there's the
local model of differential privacy so
here we avoid having to trust a third
party we just say everyone is going to
locally randomize their own data so each
person applies a local randomizer R to
their data and the resulting message
they send to the analyzer is already
differentially private now clearly this
means that the you can't tell the
analyze are too much about your data
point there's a limit to how much data
you can get across to the analyzer how
much information and but across a large
number of users the analyzer might still
be able to say something useful about
the entirety of the population as a
whole so there's a trade-off here
obviously we'd have we don't require as
much trust if we're in the local model
but we also can't get as much utility
indeed it's a classical result now the
in the curator model you can get order
one guarantee when doing summation of
real numbers in zero one but in the
local model you can't hope for better
than square root n error
roughly speaking this is because each
person has to add order one noise to
their input and then when you add them
all up you're going to get variance N
and the standard error square root n
so the shuffle model is an intermediate
model between these two and the idea
here is that we're going to have a
trusted third party but we're only going
to trust it
to shuffle the inputs so it's going to
take in all the inputs apply a random
permutation and then show the result of
that random permutation to the analyzer
how we implement this thing where and we
don't care about we're agnostic to in
this this paper but there's some
suggestions you could use MVC or a third
party or you could use a mixed net or
something if you have anonymous channels
this kind of automatically gives you a
shuffle up okay so what are our actual
contributions in this paper so far
everything I've talked about has been
other people's work well here we look at
the question of real summation of
numbers in 0 1 and we show that in the
shuffle one message Tahoe model you can
do better then you can in the local
model but you can't do as well as you
can in the curator model and we also
managed to prove a new amplification by
shuffling result this isn't the first
time that someone's proved amplification
by shuffling result but we are able to
improve at least in in certain aspects
on previous results so real and
participation all I mean is each user
has some number in 0 1 and we want to
estimate some of them previous rules
work by 2 at all there is a slight
improvement here in the local model and
but it's not in the asymptotics sorry in
the one message model but it's not
present in there syntonex they are able
to show however that if you have sqrt n
1 bit messages or each person is able to
put square root n messages into the
shuffler and they all get shuffled
together then you can achieve the error
of the curator model so we're looking at
what happens in the case where you can
only put one message in and in that case
we're able to show that with just one
message of log n bits you can achieve a
standard error of enter 6 so this is
very intent for the third
and but you can't do better than that
this is the best you can hope for okay
so I'm going to prove the upper bound
I'm not going to prove the lower bound
because I won't have time but I'd like
to explain you know how this protocols
worked how you can get this accuracy in
the one message shuttle model so this is
our local randomizer it's pretty simple
and there are only really two things
going on here you take your input we're
going to put it into fixed point
position so this is randomized rounding
to a number in to one of the some number
at ke precision and then after that
we're going to do koe randomized
response which is to say that each
person will flip her a biased coin and
with probability gamma they will return
a uniformly random answer independently
of their input when with probability 1
minus gamma they will just tell the
truth okay and at the end the analyzer
is going to have to D by us this but
that's straightforward it's just a
linear map okay so this is our local
randomizer so why does it have the
accuracy that I claim well there are two
sources of error here one is in the
randomize rounding when we map the fix
point this incurs an error with variants
n over K squared n because their own
party is 1 over K squared because that's
the variance of the randomize rounding
and then there's the error due to the
people who are lying adding you know
inputting uniform random response and
there are KN x-ray gamma n of them
approximately and each one is going to
be adding something with variance 1 and
so that contributes variance gamma N and
I'll show in a couple of minutes that
we're going to have to take gamma to be
K over N times some function of Delta
and epsilon and if you sub that K over N
in the top there you can see that the
variance comes out as n over K squared
plus K
and so we want K to be about n 4/3 and
taking K to be n to the third gives a
variance of n to the third and therefore
we get this n to the sixth so that's
where the end of the sixth is coming
from as the standard error okay so why
do I want to take gamma to be this why
does this suffice in order to understand
why this works we're going to look at
what the adversary sees so this is the
adversary's view and the adversative
view is equivalent to a histogram they
just learned how many times each input
has been submitted the origin message
has been submitted so that's a histogram
of the possible messages and we know
that these messages have come from some
people lying and some people telling the
truth so those people who put random
responses in we can consider as this
green histogram and those people telling
the truth we consider as the red one the
adversary obviously can't see which is
which and what we're going to tell the
adversary which is which we're going to
give them a present which contains
basically tells them the set of parties
that troops wandered truthfully and
we're going to assume they also know
what everyone else's input is except for
yours and this is that does a standard
assumption and different for privacy
that we want to be able to protect
against arbitrary side information so
with this present the adversary can now
remove everyone who told the truth data
from the histogram and they're left with
the green histogram plus your data entry
assuming you told the truth
if you lied obviously your inputs
independent of your data and so no
information about you is going to be
leaked so we're only going to worry
about the case where you told the truth
okay so this is the thing that we call
the privacy blanket this green histogram
here and the idea is that your one piece
of data is hiding amongst everyone
else's data so it kind of provides a
cover for you to hide amongst these are
the two situations that the adversary
needs to be able to tell the difference
between mmm needs to be able to tell
whether or not there's been one extra
entry added to and one extra zero
submitted or one extra one submitted
so we're going to look at the likelihood
ratio here as I mentioned earlier your
differential privacy roughly says the
likelihood ratio isn't going to be
greater than e to the epsilon so it's a
physis to show that the probability of
it being greater than equal to e to the
epsilon is at most Delta okay so in
order to do that we won't need to work
out this likelihood ratio so in the case
where you're submitting a zero this is
just going this likelihood ratio is just
going to be the number of zeros
submitted divided by the number of one
submitted which is some binomial random
variable plus one divided by some
binomial random variable and this won't
be greater than e to the epsilon because
binomial random variables are quite well
concentrated about their means so so
long as these means are large enough
we'll be fine and how large the mean has
to be is going to just be some function
of epsilon and Delta and so as we want
the mean to be some constant we can take
gamma to be K over N times some function
of epsilon and Delta and if you're
familiar with differential privacy then
you might recognize this log 1 over
Delta divided by epsilon squared this is
the amount of variance you have to add
when doing the Gaussian mechanism in
differential privacy so this shouldn't
be too surprising because these binomial
random variables that you're hiding
amongst are approximately Gaussian so
that's why it's log 1 of a delta divided
by epsilon squared okay so that's the
privacy proof so now what's this
amplification thing so we've shown that
we can do summation well and the
question is can we extend this argument
to other kinds of functionalities or
other kinds of statistics you might want
to compute and Ellingson Attell proved
recently that if you have some local
randomizer with in the local model this
has epsilon 0 differential privacy where
epsilon 0
is most some constant then you
automatically get different for privacy
in the shuffle model with better
parameters you need to introduce a delta
which is nonzero but you get this scroll
n on the bottom here so epsilon can come
down by a lot if n is large and this is
a useful result and if you're trying to
prove high privacy but in a lot of
situations you don't want very high
privacy what you want is moderate
privacy and high utility so we're able
to extend this read the regime of this
result to include larger values of
epsilon zero you'll note that on the
right here there's an e to the epsilon
zero in our expression for epsilon so
this this does blow up reasonably
quickly an epsilon zero but the point is
we can now take epsilon zero to be order
log n and still get reasonable privacy
guarantee of epsilon equal to say 1 ok
and in fact even in the case where we're
taking epsilon zero to be 1/2 and Delta
to be 10 4-6 this graph shows that the
constants that we're able to get out are
better than those that come out of
Ellingson at hours result and kind of
because we're we're attacking things
more directly than they were and I
should mention though that their result
is slightly more general than ours in
terms of the systems in which you can
apply it it works in models that are
different to the one that we're looking
at here so it's not quite as strictly
stronger result ok so then you might ask
if we have this amplification by
shuffling can we do anything just by
coming up with a local randomizer some
way of computing it in the local model
and then applying amplification by
shuffling to that and kind of yes kind
of no and the randomizer that I just
showed you for use in the shuffle model
it
is a differentially private in the local
model with some small value of epsilon
and sorry some large value of epsilon so
auto log-in and you can recover the
result that I just showed you directly
by applying amplification by shuffling
however if you just take a local
randomizer designed for use in the local
model such as randomized running to zero
one and randomized response or adding
Laplace random noise then you won't do
particularly well
you'll only get either scroll down or
maybe a log factor improvement so you do
need to choose your local randomizer so
that it's optimized for accuracy in the
shuffle model rather than choosing it so
it's optimized for the local model and
then just applying amplification by
shuffling sorry so there's another
question here which is I've said in the
one message model we can do this what
about many messages so cheer at all said
that with square root N one bit messages
you could do better and you could do as
well as the Q beta model pretty much and
in a recent note which we've put online
on the archives
since submitting this paper we already
know that yes you can and there's not a
huge amount of new work in that note
because it'll be shown deed that you can
get away with order log n messages this
is order log n messages of size order
log n rather than order square root n
messages and so how do we do this it
basically boils down to some result by
issue at all from 2006 which says that
if you have anonymous channels then you
can do secure addition with statistical
security so we can add random noise to
the inputs everyone can add random noise
to the input and then apply this
protocol by issue at all in order to get
with only login messages in order to get
a private form of addition so the so
there's no need to use so if you have
login messages available then you can
get the accuracy of the curator model so
then what questions are left open well
I've said that login messages suffice is
to get the activity of the curator model
and I've said that one message doesn't
you might ask what if I have two
messages or three messages or log log n
messages we're looking into this at the
moment and but right now we're not
entirely sure but then we should
probably also be looking to do things
other than addition
you know the motivation for this model
is that we can maybe have a means of
shuffling or anonymous channels and we
can just use that to compute a lot of
different things and so we only have to
implement this thing once and then you
can compute a lot of different things
with it very efficiently this makes
sense only if you can actually compute a
lot of different things with it so we'd
need to be able to do something other
than addition in this model if we're
going to justify its use we also need to
explain how it's going to be implemented
and there's already work on people
trying to implement shuffling in trusted
Hardware which came out before all this
work on differential privacy in the
shuffle model came out and just because
they thought it seemed intuitive that
shuffling people's data before they
looked at it would improve privacy and
you know we can also think of maybe
doing this using MPC or using a mixed
net or something along these lines but
these options need to be looked into and
it has to be sufficiently cheap in order
to justify using this as a model
another issue is there's a trust
assumption here and in my proof you
might have noticed I assumed that
everyone was following the protocol and
we don't really need to assume that
everyone follows the protocol it's
sufficient for some positive fraction of
P
all that we know in advance to follow
the protocol but we need there to be
enough people following the protocol
that enough of them respond randomly and
don't tell the adversary what their
response was so it can't be merely said
send me honest they have to be honest
that there's enough of a privacy Brian
KITT for you to hide amongst so you
might imagine that maybe some MPC means
of shuffling will allow you to also
verify that this noise is being added
correctly the noise or the randomize
response can be done inside MPC rather
than being done outside of MPC and that
would remove this need to trust people
and then of course yeah so I've said the
shuffle model it will work if all of
these things happen you know if it can
be implemented well if you can do other
functionalities in it if we can remove
this trust assumption then it's great
but maybe it's not the best
functionality for this maybe there are
functionalities which allow you to do
more and are easier to implement and so
another question would be what are the
single functionality could we have that
would allow us to do a great variety of
things cheaply okay that's all I've got
to say thank you
thank you very much James do we have any
questions okay if there are no further
questions let's thank James and all the
speakers of the session again
[Applause]