thanks for coming so this is some drink
work
yeah with Danna let's NIV and you've all
the topic of this talk is zero knowledge
proof so as you know as your knowledge
proof is a two-party protocol between
approver and a verifier so think of the
verifier as taking as input a graph and
the prover is gonna try to convince the
verifier say that this graph is 3
colorable so they'll exchange some
messages and at the end of this protocol
the verifier should be convinced that
this graph is indeed 3 colorable so for
this proof system to be useful it should
satisfy a number of properties it should
be complete in the sense that an honest
provers should convince an honest
verifier it should be sound in the sense
that a cheating provers should rarely
fool an honest verifier and it should be
zero knowledge in the sense that a
cheating verifier shouldn't learn
anything about the graph apart from the
fact that it's 3 colorable so in this
talk we're going to be looking at a
different type a new type of zero
knowledge proof that we call zero
knowledge groups on distributed data so
the setting is different and that
there's multiple verifiers
and now each verifier takes his input
only a piece of the statement that's
being proved so if we're looking at
graphs each verifier state could take in
as input a piece of the graph and the
prover is going to try to convince these
verifiers
that are holding this graph in
distributed fashion that they're
actually looking at a 3 colorable graph
so the prover and the verifiers will
interact over private channels and the
verifiers can even interact with each
other and at the end of this interaction
the verifier should be convinced that
yes we're holding a graph that's 3
colorable even if I don't know what the
other part of the graphic is and we can
define natural notions of completeness
and soundness and zero knowledge in this
setting so for us we'll say the protocol
is complete if an honest prove or
convinces an honest pair of verifiers
it's sound if the cheating prove are
rarely convinces an honest pair of
verifiers and we'll say it satisfies
what we call strong zero knowledge if
the cheating verifier doesn't learn
anything else about the other verifiers
input apart from the graph the fact that
the joint graph is 3 colorable so in
essence verifier v1 only learns its
input g1 and the fact that the entire
graph is 3 colorable it doesn't learn
anything else about the other verifiers
input and we can define in the setting
kind of natural notions of round
complexity and public kindness for these
protocols as we do in
any multi-party protocol and we can also
look at the setting in which there's
more than two verifiers so any number of
verifies you like in the cryptographic
context there's one type of zero
knowledge proof on distributed data that
comes up all the time and these are what
we call zero knowledge proof saan secret
shared data the setting here is is one
in which the prover has a vector and the
verifiers each have secret shares of the
vector according to some say linear
secret sharing scheme so neither
verifier actually sees the the data in
the clear they only have shares of the
data and yet the prover should be able
to convince the verifiers that this
vector is in some language so this may
seem a little bit contrived or a little
bit theoretical but it turns out that
these zero knowledge groups on this tree
but it did actually have applications to
a bunch of different privacy-preserving
systems that are already have already
been built so systems for PIR writing
and private messaging private
computation of aggregate statistics and
private ad targeting all use these ideas
kind of implicitly and many of these
systems actually implicitly construct 0
non proofs on distributed data so the
goal of this work was to give sort of
unified definitions for this this idea
and also new more efficient
constructions for zero knowledge proof
on distributed data so in particular if
we look at the applications that are on
this slide we get kind of exponential
improvement in the communication
complexity of the proof systems and I'll
explain how that works the other thing
that we do is give a new application of
journal and proofs on distributed data
so malicious secure multi-party
computation and just to point out that
these things are actually used in
practice one of these systems is
implemented in the Firefox browser and
we're hoping support some of these
efficiency improvements that come out of
this work into that setting as well so
the first type of result I want to talk
about are new zero knowledge groups on
distributed data that we construct in
this paper so the first theorem here is
kind of a general feasibility result
that says that if you have a language
and our languages here are going to be
vectors in a vector space that are that
that's recognized by say an arithmetic
circuit of size C then there's going to
be a public point zero knowledge proof
on distributed data for this language
that has a constant number of rounds and
has communication cost that grows
linearly with the size of this
so this kind of generalizes some of the
special-purpose schemes that people have
constructed implicitly before and we
also give non-trivial extensions to the
setting in which the prover and some of
the verifiers collude so this is
essentially says that for any language
you want we can construct a zero
knowledge proof on distributed data and
I should say this first result is
actually information theoretic so
there's no assumptions required here the
second type of result we have and here's
one example is that if your language has
structure so for example if your
language is recognized by a low degree
arithmetic circuit then there's a public
coins your knowledge crew fund
distributed data for this language that
requires only kind of logarithmic lis
many rounds of communication and has
communication cost that grows
logarithmically with the size of the
inputs and this approach improves on the
linear communication cost of the prior
schemes that were implicitly constructed
I should mention there's a bunch of ways
we generalize this result and the paper
so for example you can look at a smaller
number of rounds and get a different
trade-off in terms of communication
complexity and you can also look at a
wider class of structured languages like
circuits of constant degree or circuits
with repeated structure and so on so
I'll point you to the paper for details
on on the theorem statement
so having defines what a zero knowledge
proof on distributed data is I now want
to give you a little bit of intuition
about how we construct these objects and
we do so using a new type of proof
system called fully linear PC peas so
constructing a journal and proof system
on distributed data as we do kind of
works in two steps the first thing we do
is we define this notion of a fully
linear PCP and then we show an efficient
transformation that takes a fully linear
PCP for some language and constructs an
efficient zero knowledge proof for
distributed data for that language so
after we have this first step done then
all we need to do is construct new more
efficient fully linear PCPs for
languages of interest and that that
completes that gives us new proofs on
distributed data so I want to I think
the easiest way for me to describe what
a fully linear PCP is is first to recall
what a linear PCP is so this is a notion
of proof that's been around for more
than 10 years and has been used in a
bunch of cryptographic constructions
and what it is what a linear PCP proof
is is just a vector that's what the
proof looks like and the way that you
check this proof essentially this vector
this proof is asserting that some input
X's in some language L and the way the
verifier checks the proof is kind of
unusual rather than reading the entire
proof and reading the entire input and
then accepting or rejecting what the
verifier does is it makes a constant
number of what we call linear queries to
the proof so this vector this verifier
down here outputs a query and this query
is a vector that's as long as the entire
proof and this verifier gives us query
to the oracle this proof oracle and the
oracle responds with the inner product
of the the query and the proof so this
answer is kind of a constant size answer
one field element size and after making
a constant number of these queries the
linear PCP verifier should accept or
reject so even though the the verifier
can't kind of explicitly read the proof
it can it has implicit access through
these Oracle queries and this type of
proof system should satisfy natural
notions of completeness and soundness
since your knowledge okay so that's what
a linear PCP is what a fully linear PCP
is which is the new idea and this work
is the new abstraction it's very very
similar except now the verifier doesn't
actually have explicit access to the
input either so what a fully linear PCP
verifier does is it outputs some queries
it gets to make linear queries but it's
linear queries are - the combination of
the input and the proof and after making
a constant number of these linear
queries the verifier is supposed to
decide whether this this X to which it
has only implicit access through this
Oracle is either in the language or not
and again we can we can define
completeness and soundness in to your
knowledge in this setting so if you
believe that fully linear PCP is exists
for your language then I'm going to
explain to you how you use them to
construct an efficient zero knowledge
proof on distributed data for this
language so the way this works again the
setting is that we have multiple
verifiers and each verifier has a piece
of the input X and the prover who has
all of X is going to try to convince the
verifiers that this X is in some
language so what the prover does is it
produces a fully linear PCP proof that
attests to the fact
X's in the language it then splits this
proof using a linear secret sharing
scheme into two pieces and it sends one
piece to each of the two verifiers so at
this point the verifiers now have a
piece of the input and they have a piece
of the proof and what they want to do to
check the proof is essentially simulate
the process of asking these oracle
quarry queries to the linear PCP proof
Oracle so what the verifiers will do is
they'll use common randomness between
themselves to sample a series of these
fully linear PCP queries and then by the
using the fact that they can compute say
an inner product on secret shared data
the verifiers can publish shares of the
answers to this query that the fully
linear PCP proof Oracle would have given
so what the verifier is essentially
published the take the inner product of
this query with their piece of the input
and their share of the proof both
verifiers do this and by publishing
these values they can recover the answer
to this query that the Oracle would have
given so by simulating this these
process of asking the Oracle queries in
this way after a constant number of sort
of elements of communication the
verifiers can recover the answers to
these queries that the Oracle would have
given and then they can just run the
Felipe's linear PCP verifier on these
answers to check whether the proof is
valid or not and the communication here
that was required between all of the
parties was essentially twice the size
of the proof plus a constant number of
elements for computing these Oracle
query answers so I hope I've convinced
you that if you can construct such a
thing called the full of linear PCP for
your language then you can use this
transformation I just showed to get an
efficiency or knowledge proof on
distributed data for that language so
now the question is how do you construct
these fully linear pcbs well it turns
out that many existing constructions of
linear PC peas also satisfy this notion
of fully linearity where the verifier
only makes linear access to the input so
the linear PCP is that people use for
cryptographic instructions already
satisfy this property but they have a
limitation which is that the size of the
proof grows with the size of the circuit
linearly in the size of the circuit and
in many applications we'd like sub
linear size proofs so our idea here is
to get
proofs using interaction between the
prover and the verifiers and this this
this set of techniques we have works
when your language is is simple in the
in a way I'll describe this notion of
using interaction to shrink the proof
size is used in a bunch of different
places and in kind of related ways so
communication communication complexity
protocols and interactive Oracle proofs
and some check like proof systems all
use very similar ideas to to the ones
that I'll describe so I don't have time
to go into the full details of how this
works but I want to give you a flavor of
how we get sublinear sized proofs using
interaction so taking just the example
of a degree two circuits so so your
language is recognized by a degree two
circuit and the prover is trying to
convince the verifiers again who hold
pieces of the input in distributed
fashion that some degree two circuit
recognizes this accepts this input so
what the prover can do is we show that
the prover can send each verifier a
short proof like a constant size proof
and this proof has the property that
checking the proof only requires the
verifiers to apply a random linear
mapping to the in their piece of the
input and the proof and then it evaluate
a degree two circuit on the result so
you'll have to believe me that this is
true actually proving this requires a
little bit of technical work but
essentially what the verifiers can do is
they can apply this randomized linear
map on their piece of the input in their
piece of the proof and then once they
have they just need to check that there
this kind of new squished input
satisfies this new degree two circuit
and rather than evaluating the circuit
themselves they can outsource the work
of evaluating this circuit to the prover
and recursively invoke our proof system
so the verifiers send the coins that
they use to sample this random mapping
to the prover and then the prover
convinces the verifiers that they would
have accepted had they actually computed
this circuit on their their inputs so in
this way when when your language has
structure like this you can use this
interactive trick to reduce the the size
of the proofs so after logarithmically
many rounds the verifiers will will
accept or reject okay so the last thing
i want to do is talk about an
application of zero knowledge proof on
distributed data
to multi-party computation or in
particular three party computation what
we show is that for any arithmetic
circuit you have over a field F there's
a secure three party protocol for
computing this circuit that tolerates
one malicious party is computationally
secure with abort and we make only
blackbox use of a PRG for this and it
has amortized communication cost one
field element per party per gate in the
circuit so this is interesting kind of
for two reasons so one reason is it
gives constant factor improvements over
the communication complexity of Prior
and PC protocols that satisfy these
properties but more interesting is that
with this work we essentially match the
cost of the best three party computation
protocols that only have semi honest
security so you get malicious security
for the cost of semi honest security
essentially using these this
transformation so I want to give you
some sense of how we actually use these
your knowledge groups on distributed
data to get malicious secure NPC so our
starting point is we take a semi honest
NPC protocol that I'll call Phi that has
two extra properties so this NPC
protocol should have the property that
the protocol reveals nothing is kind of
perfectly secure until the players send
their last messages and this should hold
this kind of perfect security property
should hold even if parties deviate from
the protocol while they're executing it
and furthermore that if the parties
misbehave at the very last message the
worst that can happen should be an abort
the second property is that it should be
a degree two protocol in the sense that
every one of each player's messages
should be a degree two function of their
inputs their randomness and the messages
that they've received so far these may
seem like kind of onerous restrictions
but it turns out that a number of the
NPC protocols that are already in the
literature satisfy these properties so
I've mentioned two here but I'm sure
that there's more so if we're given one
semi honest NPC protocol that satisfies
these properties I'm going to explain
how we use distributed proofs on
distributed data to sort of lift it into
a malicious secure one the way this
works is the players first run this
malicious secure NPC amongst these three
players but before they publish their
last message they halt so they run the
proto
all the way to the very end but then
stop before they publish their last
message at this point the players each
prove to each other that the messages
they send so far complied with the
protocol so in particular player one
proves the players two and three the
messages that I sent you observed the
the protocol five that I did the right
thing now notice this is a zero
knowledge proof on distributed data this
is what the tool that's called for
because the message is that player one
sent during this execution or were
received by players two and three and
player 2 doesn't know what player three
received and player three doesn't know
what to receive so these messages are
kind of held in distributed fashion and
because this protocol has the degree to
property that I mentioned this language
is actually recognized by a degree two
circuit so player one completes this
proof players two and three check the
proof then player two proves the same
thing two players one and three and
players player three proves the same
thing two players one and two so we do
three of these proofs and the
communication complexity of this step is
is logarithmic in the size of the
circuit so this is how many field
elements are required and the reason
that this is only a logarithmic cost is
because of these new zero knowledge
proof some distributed data for degree
two relations that I mentioned so
finally if all the proofs check out the
players can reveal their last message
from the underlying semi honest NPC and
they get the output so just to give you
a summary of what the cost is well there
is C plus little of C messages from the
underlying NPC protocol the proofs that
the step of proving things to each other
just required log C number of field
elements so on average per party per
gate we're looking at 1 plus little o of
1 field elements and in the paper we go
through a number of generalizations to
say a constant number of parties with
any honest majority or two arbitrary
rings so if you want to work over 32-bit
integers or 64-bit integers similar
ideas apply for those of you who know a
lot about MPC you know about the gmw
compiler which is another way to go from
a semi honest protocol to a malicious
secure protocol I wanted to mention just
a few of the the differences between
these two approaches the first is that
gmw use
is message by message zero knowledge
proof so with each step of the protocol
every party proves said the other is
that this next message I'm sending is
actually well-formed what we do is we
defer the proofs into the very end of
the protocol and do use one big
sublinear size proof for this one big
statement at the end the second
difference is the gmw requires
commitments and therefore assumptions
whereas the the compiler that i
mentioned just now is information
theoretically secure so you don't need
any assumptions and then finally gmw
requires that all players see all the
messages because to verify a proof i
kind of need to know what you sent to
everybody else so this compiler makes
the most sense in the setting in which
players communicate over a broadcast
channel whereas with these distributed
zero knowledge proof the this compiler
makes sense even when players only have
point-to-point channels and that's
because we're able to prove things about
data that's held in distributed
distributed fashion so this talk has
been about these new zero knowledge
proof saan distributed data and the
setting again is one prover and many
verifiers with each verify are having a
different input and the goal of the
protocol is really to hide each
verifiers input from the other the
others the proof systems we get out of
this approach are information theoretic
and lightweight and we construct them
using this new tool tool called fully
linear proof systems the applications I
mentioned to MPC also two other types of
privacy-preserving systems and we're
hoping to many other systems in the
future and I think there's still a bunch
of work to do and comparing these proof
systems and building them from other
types of ideas in the cryptographic
literature and also trying to understand
the connections to other models of
distributed proofs so with that happy to
take your questions Thanks
questions yes so can you extend this to
the case well so the prover is trying to
hide things from the verifies likely can
you extend this is the case where
there's also a witness yes yes
absolutely okay but then you need some
cryptographic of somebody's presumably
bit if you want a sublinear proof size
than you do but if you essentially what
the prover can do is it can send the
verifier shares of the witness and then
you're looking at the essentially the
same situation that we're looking at
here thanks for the presentation I was
wondering if you can comment on is there
some kind of natural barrier if you are
trying to apply this result to achieve
dishonest majority MPC I think you would
you would require a different set of
techniques yeah because these
information theoretic proof systems are
not gonna not going to apply in that
setting but yeah it's an interesting
question about what what would work and
what you could do along these lines
okay let's engage weekend
[Applause]
[Music]