[Music]
[Applause]
[Laughter]
hello everybody my name is wasim
al-sindi and i'm the janitor
an organization called the xerox salon
and uh today
uh eugenio and the um solar punk
rc3 crowd currently invited me to
talk a little bit about the latest state
of some
work in progress research around the new
topic for the salon
that we're calling the indifference
engine and uh the
um purpose of this is to work towards an
ecological characterization of bitcoin
so we will without any further ado
roll straight in and so uh this is what
we're going to talk about today
um and you know hopefully some of these
things will make a bit more sense as we
uh go on so to phrase a coin we all know
about
the difference engine right babbage
lovelace
um and so on but
why indifference and so uh to
exemplify this i've taken a quotation
from a recent
poem by a collective offshoot of the
xerox salon
called the cryptographic poetic
researchers union the cpru
and i'll read it to you now so fractals
don't care about your feelings
systems disregard their externalities
and formalisms cannot reason about
the real and so here's the kicker aside
from a single very course
a feedback mechanism that's called the
difficulty adjustment algorithm
bitcoin is essentially insensate it
cannot care about what happens outside
of its
borders outside of its environs
only that the piper is paid and played
in this way that we call them economics
which we'll get to a bit later
and so here's the tldr the bitcoin
pits capital ecology against each other
in a prisoner's dilemma
style paradox that could tip the balance
in favor of a hot house earth
and so this is very hard for me to say
because i was one of the people banging
the drum for bitcoin for
many years seven years or so um
and uh i will explain to you and
hopefully impress upon you that there is
a value and worth to bitcoin
and there isn't a need for uncensorable
ungoverned means of digital value
transfer but
the cost that we might have to pay to
keep bitcoin running
is arguably too great for this planet to
bear okay
so let's talk a bit about motivations
and so as i said i'm a janitor at this
loose collective organization called the
xerox salon we don't really know what it
is yet but we're thinking of it as this
uh tentacular um post-disciplinary
assemblage of entangled concepts and
methodologies
so we are an informal research
collective approaching unusual
topics um and trying to break down
epistemic boundaries bringing people
from all kinds of different
places and creating an informal space
for unstructured discussions
to explore unusual topics and we are
holding discourse events the salons
themselves we are writing we're
producing artistic outputs
and one of the uh interesting things so
being the sounds based
trust this multi-disciplinary workspace
in berlin and the interesting um
thing is that many of our salon and
trust colleagues have actually worked
very closely with bitcoin
cryptocurrencies and blockchain
technology for many years and uh there
are quite a few tells to tell and so
there's a magic
car there's some kind of art piece
behind me on the screen and let me
read you a little bit more from one of
these poems accumulationism as a mode of
being
the decentralized death drive is
indifferent to your plight nagasaki
sunrise for all eternity
now those are pretty strong words so
let's see if there's uh some
someone's got something to back them up
with so there's this thing called
bitcoin you might have heard of it
it's a cryptocurrency it's a network of
computers that speak the same language a
protocol
and through the implementation of this
protocol a series of
machinic and algorithmic processes take
place which lead to the creation and
redistribution of these
um cryptographic abstractions of value
that people call
tokens or coins excuse me and so the
graph that you see on the screen
is what's called the hash rate this is
an indirect proxy
of the measurement of the amount of
energy going into bitcoin to defend it
to keep the um the the sanctity of the
transaction history
um maintained so bitcoin's this
extremely defensive network
that requires this constant uh input of
energy uh for uh security reasons for
coin distribution reasons and also
uh because it has no way of generating
randomness uh internal to it
and so uh you know what do we what
should we make about all this bitcoin
stuff so like we all heard about bitcoin
uh you know a few years ago people were
stopped talking about it and it kind of
went away
now it seems to be back so we are
hitting all-time highs in terms of the
price
uh last time i checked the price is
around twenty seven thousand dollars
which gives bitcoin a
nominal value of the network as a
nominal value all the tokens put
together of approximately half a
trillion dollars so that is quite a lot
of money
okay and so here is uh the first of a
series of provocations
uh around the indifference engine and
i'll read you the quotation again from
the cryptographic poetics researchers
union on the card
the elephant in the room grows less
restless as the air fills with soot
some cheer it on as others choke and
weeds the temperature rises again
and so this graph is we're watching the
temperature rise
just as when you look at the price of
bitcoin that chart as
every time you see a green candle and
the price goes up the beast gets
thirstier wants more energy to defend it
because the honeypot
that this network is defending um it
grows larger this is actually the
biggest
computing honeypot and biggest monetary
honeypot on the planet
at half a trillion dollars if you could
hack this thing say with a quantum
computer on some
pre-quantum signature schemes then um
you know this thing would lose all of
this
um a perceived value
okay so uh here's a provocation that we
wrote over that we're
drafting we're in the middle of writing
for bitcoin and you can see that bitcoin
here is pictured as a black hole as a
naked singularity
uh something with a hard boundary uh
beyond which we cannot
uh a reason beyond and there's a reason
why we've uh used that analogy and we'll
come back to that bit later in fact even
bitcoin is quite proud of this analogy
for other reasons
so let me read to you what's on the
what's on the screen as bitcoin
surpasses previous
price records and re-enters mainstream
consciousness following several
wilderness years
the 12-year cryptocurrency appears to
have arrived in the eyes of the market
the value proposition of an ungoverned
unsensual digital means of value
transfer is clear for all to see
but can our planet afford the
thermodynamic price tag
to maintain the integrity of the
transaction record the bitcoin network
creates a hard boundary to the outside
through exacting validation requirements
there is no sensitivity to the
consequences of the thermoeconomic
challenges it issues
this inability of mined cryptocurrencies
to differentiate the energy sources used
to secure them has led to criticism as
to their indifference
to their ecological externalities
and so this is where the indifference
engine is coming from like
bitcoin can't care about what happens
outside it just like a black hole can't
care
it just wants to suck mata uh you know
um mata energy let's say in the
einsteinian sense
out of the external environment and
that's kind of what bitcoin is doing
so we'll take a little break and we'll
look at a meme on the screen
and so you may have heard about this
movement called decentralized finance or
defy
it's all the rage at the moment uh
particularly in some parts of the crypto
blockchain space and really what i see
here
is a great deal of the replication of
the systemic fragilities and problems of
the traditional financial system
being built atop some very experimental
and
untested foundations and so um
there's no uh surprise when i see these
projects failing and collapsing
on a daily basis so this is a house of
money cards territory if you ask me
in the middle we have the internet of
value which is a more kind of um
neutral um platitude that's quite
inclusive and welcoming of bitcoin and
all the other cryptocurrencies
uh thinking that we can make a kind of a
network society for these different
uh coins and that sounds great but the
problem is that all these things have
for humans around them like
tribes or or ideologies and you know
what humans are like when they have
ideologies
and so but the apotheosis of this meme
really is the black hole of money and i
think this is
like what bitcoin is bitcoin is quite
proud of calling it the black hole of
money because they see that
as a way of stripping away the impure
the central banking and the fear
uh from um humanity and from from earth
but as a card carrying uh a physicist
who started his scientific career
and the oldest research astronomical
research observatory in the world
i would caution people at hoping that
their thing is a black hole you may
not want what that entails in reality
and so um
we had this funny conversation at trust
and myself when a colleague joined a
pope where we were talking about
systems that barely work and we had the
joke that we would like to set up
the barely working systems working group
and so if anybody would like to join
that
then let us know and i guess we'll have
to start it and figure out what we do
but the point i want to make here is
that bitcoin is kind of this
clutchy solutions highly suboptimal
solution
if you look at the component level
almost every piece of it from the kind
of
the networking from the economics from
the cryptography
and from the distributed systems um
these are all very sub-optimizing even
the governance as well these are all
very sub-optimal individual solutions
so it's a paradise for mousetrap
designers like if you're
an academic a professor a protocol
designer you'll look at something in
bitcoin and think
that sucks i can do it better here's my
new mousetrap
and obviously with um everything outside
of bitcoin people can make their own
tokens and cryptocurrencies and networks
you can print your own money
and so if you can build a better
mousetrap and you can print your own
money
you can see that there might be some
incentives for you know
grifters and all the rest of it um but
one of the points i wanted to make here
that i i skipped over earlier is that
um bitcoin even though it looks highly
suboptimal it's very resilient
bitcoin is a cockroach it's the
cockroach of money just as emails the
cockroach of communication
and i think with quite a high degree of
certainty
if there was a nuclear fallout and a
kind of apocalyptic
um happening on this planet and bitcoin
would be one of the first um
global networks that would get back up
and running at first in localized areas
as
computers start to connect to each other
and then as the linkages are made by
whatever satellite
homing pigeon a smoke signal who knows
uh i i think things would carry on
anyway moving on and so some people
describe bitcoin as the impenetrable
fortress of validation
and they mean that in a good way that
means it's very hard to cheat the system
there are no rulers but there's a
great deal of very stringent rules and
so transactions are checked to be valid
before they enter the permanent record
in a block and then as a minor creates a
block
um and attempts to claim the reward the
incentive economics incentive
the lottery incentive uh that is checked
by all of the other
participants on the network to make sure
no rules have been broken no shortcuts
have been taken
and no improprietary impropriety
has been has been occurring now of
course when you have a set of rules
you can still do some finagling
underneath the surface whilst you
um pay heed and lip service to the rules
but one of the points i want to make
here is that this very hard boundary
creates a hard delineation between the
inside of bitcoin
and the outside in a cryptographic and
computing sense in a networking sense
system sense but i think i would posit
that this also
creates um like an economic penumbra
of this hard boundary and a
socio-political one as well
and we end up with these scorched earth
mindsets we have scorched earth
economics
this uh economic double jeopardy that
we'll talk to
talk about a bit later we have this
scorched earth discourse
log on to bitcoin twitter if you don't
know what i mean and we have this
scorched earth governance and we'll get
to all of these things in a moment
and they lead to this insularity of code
in mind which we're going to give a name
to in a moment
and you know so we all can see the value
of having a stateless currency with no
rulers
you know there's no um plutarch or
oligarch or overlord
and telling you what you can and can't
spend on like you know spending should
be a form of speech right
if you can say what you want you should
be able to spend how you want um
but even though there's no rulers we
still end up with
tolls and toll keepers trolls and grifts
a lot and a lot i mean there's no
permission to
start any of these things so that a lot
of people have ended up in this space
doing that kind of stuff
it's all quite unpalatable and so one of
the things i would like to posit
is that bitcoin is a form are possibly
the first form
of an algorithmic materialism so it's
using the
um algorithmics of the thermoeconomics
as the incentive
and the algorithmics of the um proof of
work of the cryptocurrency mining
and combining these things together and
the real and the virtual
to create this um synthetic
uh abstraction that straddles the real
and the virtual which is the currency
the cryptocurrency itself
so i really i would argue that it's um
algorithmic materialism
and uh we'll go even further with that
in a moment
so here's another poetic interlude and
i'll just take a water break before we
start
again from the cpiu a black hole greater
than the sum of its parts
the ultraviolet catastrophe of money
rugged individuality meets naked
singularity
thermoeconomic double jeopardy a game of
russian roulette
with alice bob sybil and sock puppets
and that's
also by the um alias satoshi webbed
and so thermoeconomics let's talk a bit
about that what does that word even mean
well here's a recent uh usage of it by a
couple of salon colleagues
in a recent explainer for um
cryptocurrency mining is quite relevant
today
cryptocurrency mining is a
thermoeconomic process employing proof
of work and a parameterizable feedback
mechanism the difficulty adjustment we
mentioned earlier with direct incentives
provided by block rewards
from an algorithmically regulated
network level issuance schedule
alongside transaction fees
and the picture here is from my politico
and these are
um engines uh
natural gas powered engines that are
fueling
um bitcoin miners and they sit above
um fracking wells in places like um
alberta saskatchewan alaska
so bitcoin doesn't care about where the
energy comes from it just wants energy
doesn't care
how dirty it is it doesn't care if it's
helping it doesn't care if it's harming
in these cases it might actually be
helping believe it or not because a lot
of the
um gas comes with this fractal oil and a
lot of it is just flared off it's
burning and let it into the sky
and your methane going into the
atmosphere that is not good from an
ecological perspective so maybe burning
some of it in this like you know
horrifically inefficient
diesel you know did carbon engines
combust combustion engines is a is a
net gain but because i wanted to try to
illustrate the point
that bitcoin doesn't care where the
energy comes from to bitcoin this could
be coming from solar
plant could be coming from nuclear power
could be coming from
space uh space harvesting a dyson sphere
it doesn't care and so
this is what we were promised by all
these cryptocurrencies we'll get rid of
the rulers
we'll be able to transact in freedom
we'll have this p2p egalitarian one cpu
one vote
utopia but i think we're actually a bit
closer to this where we started uh the
bosses of the senate the oligarchies and
the plutarchies
i think we're probably a bit closer to
that than we think and we have these
several kind of principal constituents
in the bitcoin network
and one of them is this developer
technocracy which we'll get to in a
moment
and one of them is this mining illegally
the thermoeconomic cartel
and um both of these things i don't
think they were necessarily anticipated
by the creators and progenitors of
bitcoin
but those are the reality that we have
to deal with now
and so here's a pyramid we've all seen
pyramids before
i think that most human uh uh
organizations
seem to play out in this way by accident
or by design so you could argue
that at the top of this thing are the um
people that found bitcoin very early
and then you know there's other people
that set up companies that do mining
they're the developers and so on
then there's kind of your media
personalities then you've got kind of
that people like me talking heads kind
of bro
whatever bitcoin bros x bitcoin bros and
then you've got the kind of
followers and the people that watch
bloomberg tell them which coin to buy
and um the people that casually log on
to twitter and have like you know five
followers and things like that
so there is some kind of hierarchy here
and i'm
you know speaking of it because i've
moved through this hierarchy over the
years
and i've also swept floors at some of
the very highest levels
and so when you sweep the floor you hear
interesting things
and so one of the most interesting
things about all this bitcoin and
blockchain stuff
is that some people see uh bitcoin and
blockchains and and so on as a new
instantiation a new exemplification of a
synthetic time or even a synthetic space
time
and uh for people that are interested in
the philosophical
work of emmanuel khan and everything
that came beyond that
and this is extremely interesting so
this is giving you a
some kind of like a um
a new yardstick a new kind of time that
is divorced from the outside time
and so this is many people think that
this proved
can't write and there's this very
beautiful picture of emoto from
alison's book mushroom at the end of the
world uh called conjuring time
so we will probably litigate the time
thing another another another time
but some of us have been in the
cryptocurrency space have been using
these
spatiotemporal thermodynamic and astral
lenses for a number of years here's some
old
tweets by this janitor uh talking about
blockchain's time machines
a couple of years ago all right
meme break so um here's a very
controversial philosopher
on the screen and somebody that is very
interested in bitcoin and
at the blockchain and spaceline
i suppose you could describe bitcoin as
a dark crystal if you were so inclined
and so unfortunately um the nice uh
animated image of cellular automatic
going around the screen here did not
translate but i will just leave you to
imagine
a conway's game of life unfolding in
front of us
and i will say that you know we are at
the salon we have spoken a little bit
about
moving beyond the natural and towards
the synthetic you know what does a
synthetic life form
look like what can it uh do what can it
be how can we tell if something is
alive or not and um the uh
research alexander daisy ginsberg has
done quite a lot of work on this
and this is an interesting speculative
um
epistemology of um how a new
you know taxonomic kingdom might exist
uh kind of like a meta state above and
across
transcending the boundaries of other
living
kingdoms and families some people are
starting to work on
uh trying to characterize the behavior
of machines in the similar sense that we
do with uh
human and non-human living things and so
this is like some of my colleagues and
yours
writing some machine behavior paper in
nature and um
i'm going too much into this we've
discussed it at salons before so this is
building on work by tim berg a couple of
generations ago
where we're looking from the individual
to the collective in terms of behavior
and then hybrids of individual
collective behavior and
also hybrids of machine or human and
non-human or
natural and non-natural forms of life
whatever they may be and so let's
now look at an interesting example of
somebody trying to
ascribe the agency of life to bitcoin
and so this is uh some work by a fellow
called ralph merkel and he's actually
immortalized
in the bitcoin protocol because every
block of the bitcoin blockchain contains
this thing called merkle tree
which is this hierarchical space-saving
cryptographic construction
which um proves in a quite an efficient
way
how transactions are related to each
other and we need to do that for
validation as i said the bitcoin is a
very strong
uh validation um
engine and this is one of the components
of that engine
so ralph merkel started off as a
cryptographer he's now a chemist and the
chemists are kind of
sitting at the limit of life between
physics and biology
and i say that with a little bit of
experience so having spent a number of
years as a chemist with phd chemistry
so let's read what ralph merkel says
here so bitcoin
is the first example of a new form of
life it lives and breathes on the
internet
it lives because it can pay people to
keep it alive it lives because it
performs a useful service that people
will pay it to perform
it lives because anyone anywhere can run
a copy of its code
it lives because all the running copies
are constantly talking to each other
it lives because if any one copy is
corrupted it is discarded
quickly and without any fuss or loss and
it lives because it's radically
transparent
anyone can see its code and see exactly
what it does
now i think there's plenty of food for
thought in there
but um one of the things i will say
going back to our point about
um bitcoin's uh uh a
very poor sensitivity this feedback
mechanism that it contains
um you could argue that this is kind of
an
adaptive mechanism but it with without a
more sophisticated sensing
it's um uh i don't i don't think it
would qualify meet the bar for
any kind of meaningful definition of
life and one of the other things to say
is that the point that was brought up in
salon by uh our colleague sarah friend
is that
bitcoin has already reproduced itself
through forks and some of us have
written papers about
uh the forks of bitcoin and and what we
might learn from those
but i would say that the this network
partitioning that creates these
blockchain forks there's no um
opportunity for mutation evolution not
naturally speaking
to improve the fitness you know in this
progeny
and so um this is what i would call a
degenerate reproduction
this is not the reproduction of life at
best
it is a kind of prokaryotic um
you know cell division kind of naive
asexual
reproduction at best okay
so there are some paradoxes within
bitcoin and with all of this stuff
and um i just um hope that we can spend
a little bit of time
unpacking some of those now and you know
hopefully they'll bring up some
questions that we can discuss
uh either at the end of this talk or at
a a
zero external event in the future and so
i'll read to you another
um stanza from one of the cpru poems
being at once dissented hyper capital
and subordinated machine socialism
where the abstract labor itself becomes
the means of production
mindlessly grinding as the commons burn
for what
to fortify a barren walled garden emote
without a castle
let alone a citadel and that's a
courtesy of satoshi wet
and so we've said the first part here
that this is like you know
hyper capital and transcendent machine
socialism so like how can those two
things
mesh together in some kind of meaningful
way and
others have written you know over the
years quite a lot about different um
philosophical angles within bitcoin so
you know for example colombia is written
on
politics of bitcoin as uh you know a
vector for right-wing extremism
and also more recently written about
crypto communism and the kind of mass
emancipatory potential
for um mostly other blockchains and uh
and revolutionary praxis and so on
so here's the kicker for me i think we
can leave
left and right politics out of this 99
of the planet hates bitcoin and for good
reason
bitcoin requires constant import of
export and export of randomness to find
blocks
this gigantic entropic generalization is
the output of
mining farms which soak up underutilized
resources
around earth the global consensus that
bitcoin desires
and strives for every 10 minutes on
average is the most expensive
luxury in the universe so
there's a mic drop and uh i will leave
this on the
screen while i take a walk to break
so necro primitivism it's time to go
back to school
and today's lesson is introduction to
necro primitivism so what the hell is
necro primitivism so
we've been talking about this resistance
to change inside the bitcoin network
through these validation requirements
the difficulty of getting consensus to
upgrade the networks
and this has given rise to what i call
an echo primitivist class inside bitcoin
and it informs some of the behaviors of
the social political
and economic aspects of the network so
let me read to you
a little provocation on this primitivist
priest card
on the screen for now there is only
thermotechnics
to centralize cosmic horror a zero-sum
machine of fire
sand and pressure synthesizing scorched
earth's realities
the heat death of the universe passes by
as we languish in plato's cave
so here's a psa is someone you know
a necroprimitivist somebody you know
hiding a dark secret
is does the person you know exhibit a
lack of imagination
some bitcoins believe it's easier to
imagine the in end of the world
than a new pro proving mechanism to
replace the mining
scorcher economics is another telltale
sign bitcoin has hate central banking
and fiat currencies so much
that the death of the universe is a
preferable outcome
scorched earth politics worshiping a
developer priesthood
and foretelling futures for minor
semiotics now this might require a
little bit of explanation
so when we talk about developer
priesthood we're talking about
the um the cathedral in the sense of
open source software and so these are
the
wizards of bitcoin uh which are mostly
white american males um who are trusted
with
the um janitorial
maintenance and assurance
of the code and the network that is
implemented from it
and i have some experience of speaking
with these
janitorial and primitivist types because
until quite recently part of my
days were spent uh raising money to pay
their salaries so i was sweeping floors
in the priesthood and so um when you
sweep floors you hear things and you
notice things
so we're going to move on now to the
discourse of how that is
scorched earth so as you said about
colombia's book there is this
ultra-libertarian bent
going through bitcoin and i suppose that
might be because the amount of coins
that were distributed at the start
before the first subsidy having the
first four years of bitcoin between 2010
when nobody knew about bitcoin uh 10.5
of the 21 million coins were issued
and so the people that found bitcoin
very early have this enormous incentive
to keep things the way they are to not
let things change too much
and so there's this hyper individualist
going through bitcoin and again i can
speak to this because i was
also there for many years and there's
this you know this these things result
to this kind of zero-sum
community dynamics and if you want to
know what i mean go take a trip to
bitcoin twitter and see what a
uh uncharitable inhospitable place with
quality discourse that is they've
literally been having the same
conversations
for the last seven years as long as i've
been paying attention
and so this all results in this
overall resistance to change so without
the will to change
on the social layer like to convince the
necro primitivist priesthood the
developers
the minor oligopolists um who control
the the resources the hashrate
um nothing is possible like you need the
the buy-in of these two
stakeholders to make anything happen and
the economic side
and the user side well apparently
they're involved somehow
but some that that signaling is very
coarse and very informal
i suppose just them restricted to who
shouts the loudest on twitter
and so this kind of so-called
inter-subjective consensus
between users and the uh developers and
the miners
is what's meant to reinforce the um
trajectory of bitcoin but i would argue
that this is a new form of theater that
has replaced decentralization theater
and the signaling ground of twitter has
become
a new uh theater for uh battlegrounds
in fact i think it's been like this for
years so
what's an extra primitivist i think you
might still be looking at one so here's
me
18 months ago moderating a panel at one
of the premier technical bitcoin
conferences
on economic and social risks and
standing sitting beside me
was the technical editor of bitcoin
magazine aaron fanfield and
we were both calling out the cultish
nature of the bitcoin community to their
faces you know not just only to the you
know the
community at large we're talking about
the kind of vip
community of bitcoin people who go to
all the conferences that speak all these
things that have
ten to a million ten thousand two
million followers on twitter
the thought leaders of bitcoin and they
were laughing it up
laughing and applauding you can find
this talk online if you so choose
and uh more recently you can see i'm uh
as a screenshot from another talk i gave
her not so long ago
where i was running uh and founded and
edited a journal
called the crypto economic systems which
was based at the massachusetts institute
of technology media laboratory
at the digital currency initiative so
i've been sweeping quite a few
interesting flaws
meeting a lot of these interesting uh
people that are very close to these
networks that have a great deal of
um social technical and economic
gravitas
within these networks of networks
so let's talk about swans so people
always like to talk about black swans
and you've i've heard people say that
bitcoin is a black swan generator a
black swan tractor
it's always spitting out these crazy uh
event
based externalities and i would argue
that you could think of bitcoin as a
black swan
but more like a thermodynamic one but
let's talk about this white sperm
hypothesis which a lot of people have
spoken about
myself included i had to go through some
very embarrassing older talks to
dredge out my arguments um as to the
incentives that bitcoin might provide
towards the development of
cleaner and greener energy and on the
screen is a another card and there's a
quotation there
about like whose skin is in the game so
obviously the black swan is a
is a talib aphorism and title of a book
and so skin in the game
so the idea of skin in the game being
like incentives are
correlated to disincentives so like you
know you have to have
something at stake in order to reliably
be signaling
your the truth of your intentions and so
we were talking a while ago in the trust
discord about conspiracy theories and
cults
and movements and what the differences
might be between these things and
uh this person was seen talib said the
difference between a movement and a cult
is whether the skin in the game is your
own and others and that's something i
want to impress upon you because
some of the people in the stakeholder
ecosystem of bitcoin do have some skill
in the game and some of them don't
um but that is not necessarily
correlated with who holds sway
whether explicit or implicit and that's
something that's very important to note
so we spoke about thermal economics and
this incentive mechanism for the lottery
and that this
feedback mechanism that regulates the
difficulty is the only sense8 connection
in bitcoin
and because the subsidy the amount of
coins that
a miner gets for finding the winning the
lottery every block
it's halving on this predetermined
schedule every four years
there is this incentive double jeopardy
that as the
number of coins becomes scarcer and
scarcer the amount of energy required to
defend the network becomes greater and
greater and greater
and this uh you know it's no this is
kind of like a game of chicken
and so we don't know who blinks first um
or you know
what happens when these two things crash
into each other and so
we used to talk about bitcoin as being a
way to make payments and
this was a a form of fast and cheap and
uh
facile value transfer and we had to walk
back on that one because the
transactions got expensive
turns out space in the blockchain to
confirm your transaction
is a precious resource and people were
willing to pay quite a lot for that
and so there became this rise of this
narrative shift as
long as schwartz and others have
discussed since 2013 of digital metalism
you could think of bitcoin's digital
gold you've probably heard about this
analogy and you could think of this as
an
ideology this is like a computational
ideology and we mentioned columbia
earlier we're going to read a little bit
from a quote of his from the cultural
logic of computation
on the card computationalism underwrites
and reinforces a surprisingly
traditionalist conception of human being
society and politics in other registers
we might imagine these views to have
long been abandoned
in large part because their faults as
part of the total account of human being
have long ago demonstrated bin long ago
demonstrated conclusively and so because
bitcoin has this inability to mitigate
or even have awareness of its
externalities and because there is no
alternative there is no other consensus
mechanism that has been proven
at scale computationally and
economically
is there no alternative at two margaret
we live in hope i've been waiting for
proof for ethereum to move away from
proof of work
since it was first announced in 2014
still waiting
so we often hear this and i've often
said these things myself
in times gone by solar energy and wind
will save bitcoin
the shuttered aluminium uh plants next
to three gorgeous dam
hydro uh outlets will save bitcoin
the green indexes say that most of the
energy in bitcoin is sustainable and
renewable
well you know i know the people that
wrote these reports
people like uh chris bendington and
michelle rouse
and a lot of these reports are relying
on self-reporting and self-reporting is
susceptible to
goodheart's law which means that you
know people may not report honestly
they may report for their interests
rather than to report
and then you know where do things like
uranium and biomass come into all of
this like we've been researching
chemical industry
externalities and trust not in recent
times and a lot of the time people talk
about
biomass as a renewable energy so one of
my colleagues
used to develop um power management
algorithms at
the drax family of power stations in the
uk and one of the things that they do is
they do lots of
renewable energy but one of their
renewable energies is um
wood biomass it's processed wood that
they chop
up then burn and they plant some more
trees does that sound
green do you i think they just do it so
they can burn they can use coal plants
to burn stuff
excuse me you also have to remember that
there are embodied costs
to all of these things like solar panels
the silicon has to come from somewhere
the exotic materials
the photovoltaics have to come from
somewhere i have a phd in photovoltaic
technology
i watched the solar panel industry and
technology develop
at that same time that i was doing my
research we are still not there yet
um there uh there is only a marginal
benefit of running
solar panels that we have today when we
do these life cycle analysis
analyses maybe one day we'll be making
solar panels out of graphene
or some other kind of cheaper um
reproducible material
that has minimal externalities but until
we get there this is still
um problematic and one of the worst
things about
bitcoin it's kind of like part of the
very foundation of the house of cards
that bitcoin is built on
in terms of centralization anyway is
that there are only a handful of places
you can actually fabricate
um semiconductors silicon wafers to make
computing
chips and so bitcoin requires
specialized computing chips there is
this enormous arms race due to these
incentives
to create a more efficient and uh
you know more performant more energy
efficient and more perform performance
efficient
mining chips for these application
specific integrated circuits
asics uh the bitcoin mining machines
that create these
gigantic farms next to these hydro
plants and whatever there's only a
handful of these plants in the world
making one is very hard you require a
great deal of capital and a great deal
of
um know-how i know people that used to
work on
uh silicon fabrication is extremely as
a business with extremely high barriers
to entry and so the problem here is
if you want to make bitcoin mining chip
you need to have a friend
at one of these places that will let you
get your
um your uh production batch
in the queue among the sony's and the
apples of this world
samsungs of this world it's very
difficult to do
so let's talk more about this white swan
so mining energy costs are mostly paid
in fiat
the piper that the miners have to pay to
win these bitcoin rewards
is mostly denominated in yuan or dollars
or pounds or euros
so the token price the price of the
price of bitcoin
matters every time the price of bitcoin
goes up
the price on bitcoin's head from this
kind of um
uh bounty that we discussed earlier and
also the um
incentives to defend the network against
um uh them
against a 51 attacks against uh honest
attacks
compliant in the protocol must increase
we must put more energy into this thing
to keep it safe
it becomes more valuable makes sense
right and so here's a
quote from an old paper which tries to
describe
um the value of a bitcoin
solely internal to the system
okay considering the functionality of
the bitcoin network
the current value of one bitcoin may be
understood implicitly as the value of
150 seconds
of the computational results directed at
defending the network from thermodynamic
attacks
and providing a high probability of
assurance that the integrity of the
canonical ledger will continue to be
maintained okay so
and let's wrap up now by taking this to
the kind of logical end point
so if bitcoin is this black hole and it
wants to suck all the energy out of
you know where as far as it can see to
its event horizon
where is that so uh there are these
things
in the universe that we call kind of
constants and natural laws
whether they're constant whether natural
laws is another matter in fact the most
interesting
uh scientific talk i ever saw during my
tenure as a
as a physicist and chemist was by john a
popple iii
nobel prize winner which was called his
chemistry branch of pure mathematics
where he took apart every single natural
law
and fundamental constant that um people
would uh shout out from the
from the lecture theater armed with only
a uh
a sharpie and a piece of transparent
plastic on an overhead projector
so um the light from the sun
takes eight and a half minutes to reach
earth at the yeah near enough
the speed of light that is an upper
limit or an asymptote at least in our
side of the veil and so that's kind of
like a
hard limit of how far bitcoin can go
back to the sun
basically like imagine a circular radius
from the earth the sun and
other side towards mars but
because of the way the lottery works um
every second you move away from the
economic
center of gravity of bitcoin you're
hamstringing yourself
and this race against the other miners
that are close to the center of gravity
think about how high frequency trading
works people built
computer exchanges next to the chicago
mercantile exchange so that they could
shave milliseconds off their trading
times
and jump in before other people and so
this is what would happen in this
thermodynamic lottery
if you even went just a few light
seconds away to the moon you would be at
this advantage compared to everybody
else
it's usually on a matter of seconds the
winning block versus another one
and so unless so much hash power is
deployed
off earth that the center of economic
gravity of bitcoin moves
also off earth i i don't see how um
the network is constrained by the
current parameters things like the
10-minute block time and so on
and so bitcoin mining in space maybe
nearby
um maybe we could make a death star like
maybe bitcoin could be the death star
and so we all talk about dyson few
thousand spheres and
you know cold fusion and all these kinds
of things sounds great
but like the planet is burning now and
bitcoin is trying to suck all the air
out of the room now
so even with all these things it will
still be a brute force thermodynamic
arms race bitcoin requires
a simple majority of all of the energy
that it can see
in order to know that it's in order to
be secure doesn't know that it's secure
but in order to be secure
and so it just wants to suck all the
energy out of the room and so
the tldr here is that bitcoin has this
you know
putative form of artificial life if you
believe or agree with ralph merkel
bitcoin is in competition with natural
life for the harvest of energy
this side of the sun and that means that
in effect
bitcoin it's not artificial life it's
artificial death
it's trying to suck all the oxygen out
of the room or the photons out of the
room or the energy out of the room
so that it may prosper and survive and
it doesn't care it
can't care about you you can't care
about me can't care about us
they can't care about our planet and so
um this is the
uh where i'm going to wrap up this
latest stage uh latest uh
interim state of uh xerox salon topic
number five indifference engine
uh research um i hope it hasn't been uh
too
scatty and disorganized i had very
little time to prepare this um
and i hope that so you can join me for q
a
after the talk now and so thanks very
much for listening
uh this is a a archived picture of me
sweeping some flaws and
i work at the xerox salon which is an
informal research collective
approaching unusual topics with
post-disciplinary activities
involving discourse art and writing if
you'd like to know more about
the xerox salon please visit xerox
s-a-l-o-n-dot
and thanks very much for your time there
was sim that was an amazing talk
and really really
heartwarming to see how things are
evolving uh for you
in the last couple of months how you
sure you've been there with me on this
journey
yeah yeah yeah like a year ago when
we had this discussion back at trust i
was
trying to to poke through uh some
ecological perspective um trying to
trying to address this relation between
the ecological and the economical
and and uh i really appreciate uh
the trajectory that you're taking i
think i let my thermodynamic defenses
down between
now and then it it's really and and it's
lovely that it comes right after
christine's talk
i mean eugenio my talk i changed the
topic
i adapted it so that it fits
ecologically
uh christine and wesson's talk but it's
like what i'm going to present is kind
of
a a very close resonance to what wasim
is discussing so maybe
we should uh get a few questions from
the audience before
i step in yeah i think the audience have
just a lot of comments
uh maybe now some of you some
are coming up i felt like quite a lot of
them were more
kind of polemic comments rather than
things that we can we can discuss in
detail but hey there are new stuff
recently still okay here's one that i
think might be interesting it says
actually making bitcoin co2 neutral
would be very cheap
half a percent of the value at a very
conservative uh estimation
and i mean that might be true actually
it might be quite cheap to uh
green bitcoin but the problem is because
bitcoin is not sensitive to the energy
that's going into it as we've discussed
how would you know and so like all it
takes is another kind of
a marginal step down of some other
non-green form of energy
and that would re-enter the mix just
because of this kind of um
rational energy market that we mostly
find ourselves with
bitcoin is seeking the cheapest energy
and it doesn't really care
what it is um
satoshi you are still polluting the
planet with heat you are still
responsible
now this is an interesting point that we
came to the salon when we talked about
algorithmic realism
which is like you're a developer you
write some code
you put it on the web or github or
whatever and then you
disappear you might die you um left the
planet
and somebody else implements your code
or puts your code in somewhere something
else
are you still responsible for what
people use it for like so satoshi wrote
some code
and then satoshi implemented a network
and then disappeared
are they still responsible it's an
interesting question
i think there's a danielle ass uh
sounds familiar thanks for the talk
crypto will hunting
do you see a possibility of decoupling
bitcoin's value
from its energy usage this is actually
really interesting question uh thanks
daniel
um and it actually seems to be a similar
question to the one that goes around
in the uh degrowth world which um you
know christine would be very familiar
with
on the decoupling of economic economic
uh
uh prosperity and energy consumption and
it's actually kind of
almost the same uh thing that we're
grappling with here
and the real question with bitcoin the
way it works now i don't think so i
don't think that's possible i think
the energy draining of the system will
be accompanied by a loss of confidence
in the security of the system
and unless there's some uh other way of
arranging or connecting the
uh cryptographic and the economic aspect
of bitcoin together
i just don't see how we're going to do
that
yeah christine what about decoupling
what's your
official or unofficial take on
decoupling
yeah i mean um
yeah i mean like i i touch upon the talk
like we
um we have achieved relative decoupling
ever obviously um energy has become
become more energy efficient um but the
thing is like
we're still aiming towards um like
absolute gdp growth
um so that like means material
throughput and often energy itself also
like well simply
consumption will continue to rise
regardless of how like efficient we're
being because we're demanding like ever
more energy
um so um yeah then people are arguing
that
like sufficient absolute company
decoupling is possible but
many people in the ecological sector
argue against that because simply
because we don't have enough
time and we need to act now on climate
change mitigation
um so the simplest way to do that would
be to lower
like energy usage itself um and because
we're quite wasteful with it anyways
so um i guess my personal opinion about
um
bitcoin or cryptocurrencies that use
energy
system or it's maybe just like a bit of
a
bit of a challenge is is like i don't
consider something innovative
unless it's ecological so i don't i
don't consider
um proof of work innovative at all um
like it through the lens through my
extremely biased lens
um but i think that's just like uh maybe
that's just a provocation
that's a good provocation christine what
i might encounter with is say that
um if proof of work may not be
ecologically valuable
uh as it is but it may um provide a way
forward to something that does have an
ecological value
innovative sense i just think it's like
it's pretty disappointing because
when it was developed it's like we were
you know we were well aware of these
environmental
issues so i just feel like at this
at this in this day and age like if
you're gonna call your
your work uh innovative like it has to
be
aligned with civilizational longevity um
you know and it's just and that's my
like very strong opinion about it
um but also like with bitcoin
i don't know too much about it but isn't
like the majority of the wealth
also held in very few hands like it kind
of is mirroring
the the well disparity in society as is
and i i
also like you know propose people think
on that metric
um and really really think about whether
or not this is
going the direction we want it to go if
it's the response to 2008 2009 recession
it shouldn't be containing external you
know ecological externalities
it's it's not radical then right like
yeah there's a big
there's a big difference between um
where we where
the network was intended to go and do
and achieve and the kind of grand vision
of that
and what it has achieved so it's
achieved more than its minimal promise
but it's fallen far short of its maximal
promise so this was meant to be
something very
egalitarian one cpu one vote like a
computer democracy a machine democracy
what we ended up with is a machine
oligopoly a machine cartel
the the um industrialization of the
mining wasn't foreseen
originally and so there weren't any
failsafes put in uh to mitigate against
uh
centralization and and the coalescence
of power in that way
um the developer priesthood which we
talked about i think that
um satoshi would have been blind to that
because satoshi was
one like so this is something that was
created in the person's image
to perpetuate uh you know small
cadre of expert wizard people
and in terms of gosh weber obi in terms
of the
ecology i mean uh
people always shift the boundaries shift
the
goal posts as the expectations and the
reality
diverge more from the bitcoin we wish we
had and the bitcoin we ended up with
and um at some point
um people have to kind of take stock of
the situation this is kind of what i'm
doing with this talk like i was one of
these people banging the drums saying
that
the cost was worth it all of this energy
was worth it
to have a stateless value transfer
system and but now i'm looking around
and thinking this is pretty high cost
and it's increasingly
very rapidly uh look outside and
the externalities seem to be piling up
and so at some point
you have to make that value judgment and
every person has to do that for
themselves
and just try to tell my story of how i
did that and how it tipped from one side
to the other
but i could totally see christine while
this was never
a contest for you um because you've
probably had like
some fairly rock solid values all the
way through whereas i was on the side of
the machines before so i'm coming over
to team human now
plus she she's canadian
[Laughter]
um yeah cool um do you have some
other question here that you want to
pick up um
there was one wasn't there where was it
um if over here we can do this one
if the whole bitcoin mine community was
listening to you right now
uh where was it yeah oh uh what would
you suggest to them to reduce the
ecological impact of bitcoin mining
well i mean uh like again like coming
back to christine's talk
discourse and discussion is the most
important thing so what happens now
is a lot of kind of green washing where
people in the bitcoin mining industry
are always saying
we use mostly green energy it's mostly
from dams and solar and blah blah blah
and so i really the first we have to
start with an honest debate about what's
going on here
that's kind of what we're trying to do
with the salon and with this provocation
and the problem is most of the time when
people bring this conversation to the
bitcoin community
they're coming from outside the
community so people are
um very skeptical of people coming from
outside the bitcoin community
telling people how to fix bitcoin
because that's been going on since the
start
and so maybe it's possible if people
from
that have some stature and some
familiarity and expertise with how
bitcoin works and
what it does and the people around it
might bring up these points
that we might be able to have a more
substantive discussion and that's the
starting point i think you know
unfortunately planet is burning while we
wait to start these conversations
[Music]
[Laughter]
wow
you