[Music]
[Applause]
[Laughter]
hello
[Music]
foreign
[Applause]
[Music]
oh
huh
this time
[Music]
thanks
that's right
[Music]
okay
is
[Music]
it's a form without
features
[Music]
it's a sleek form
that is so fluid
that can be tuned into the digital world
it's a digital thing um yeah
um are you a different fit i am
a living ipi
[Music]
no i'm a practice
how do you practice i
practice extradition
through ludwig
creation and interpretation
yeah i play
but i play without
rules is not a game
ah it's a game under construction
it's solidification it's a lyric thing
so then they are holy yeah
yeah it's a open practice
so it's like extreme and gesture so we
can experiment with our whole being
exactly what do you want to think today
what could i be you could be a horizon
alright so you could be a ginger
right let's be a horizon ginger
and you what are you me
mm-hmm i am i
am no i am i you are i
am i and i am you are you oh
i am
is like furniture
between
[Music]
and how they're interacting my
interaction defines
that state in that point of time so jump
is about
jamming okay
sure always
what are you
you i yeah
[Music]
is about not being anyone because
i'm trying to erase
my persona
amenti i don't want people
to refer to me as i
and so i just decided to be
yellow
hmm today i am yellow which i might be
pink
and the other day after hang on be white
you know
what is the result of
letting go of persona and identifying
with
only what you were that day it's not
about unaware it's about korean
and uh basically so if you want to go
deeper ahead to
why we love the center maybe that would
be like
something interesting um it's not about
um
who can you be given your identity
and uh when when you do not
when you're not a caller when you're a
person then you cannot be anyone you
wanna do it because
people see you for something that you're
not
just because you look in a particular
manner just because you're particular
gender just because you have a specific
ethnicity
and so you cannot really explore who you
really are because
every single one of your actions and
interactions
are shaped by the subjectivity of the
external world
so you're constrained by whatever people
think you are
and only when you can eradicate your
face
and your persona and your colors and
everything
your identity can you actually start
exploring your whole colors
so you shed the package in order to
expand capacity
exactly it's about like removing
removing from the outside in order to be
able to add more
in the inside
[Music]
what's wrong with institutions what is
wrong with the institution can you tell
us
who are you you're purple what's wrong
with institution
nothing is wrong with your institution
[Music]
have you heard of expectations
yes what is an execution
zentai is an execution
do you know why
[Music]
an institution
people to a whole because they match
a particular call description
perhaps executions are about colors
and relationships and it doesn't matter
what is your fault because you have no
identity and so it's
all about what you do and
how you do it and before you're doing it
and it's only the individual interaction
that comes everything to be honest
[Music]
right now what are we doing
and and how can we construct an
individual
relationship with this creature
but i'm an institution there are laws
you think you are an institution
everyone is also an exhibition
you just don't know about it yet maybe
maybe maybe if you have difficulty
and you start expressing yourself
instead of speaking as an institution
like an institution
but i'm locked in my role about the
institution
but you're wearing a zombie so no one
will know
that you are encouraging the lives so
i'm escaping
no it's not skipping it's about finding
discovery
discover you're experimenting you're
becoming
you're becoming blue
whatever
you need to be becoming
in order to find new meaning
for yourself
can you feel that
if you don't experiment you're always
gonna do what people expect you to do
because you're gonna be subject to the
fast objectivity
of the external world
people tell us what to think people tell
us the stories they want us to tell
ourselves
and now we are in a state where
we've lost we've lost ourselves we've
lost we've lost our true meanings we've
lost
we've lost the ability to play we've
lost the ability to think and
with zentai i feel like i'm finding this
magic and yet it is by losing yourself
it is by
losing precisely your identity
and self that you can finally found
find your real being that you can become
what you really are
since by amazing and science
you can
one thing with institutions is that
they'd like
people to know what they want
you to do the exception tells you what
your role is they tell you the story
they tell you what yourself is and you
tell me now
i can lose myself and find myself
because i lose the self that the
institutions gave me
and i can find myself through this
thing you call executions
maybe we should make a sunday collective
maybe maybe
it's funny when we there's what we know
what we know that we don't know and then
we
don't know that we don't know i didn't
know anything about
sentai until we put them on and we're
experimenting now
and it tweaks open the edges the
boundaries of our minds
first only by a little bit
but that exploration that play at the
edges you
know what might lay beyond
i think we forget how to play sometimes
we don't want to play how did you play
come on show us why should we play
you should fight
[Music]
oh
is creation the identification is how
families
love to live and to become yeah
without notification we will all be just
institutionalized
what is this life without play
all the life is play
life without play is order
but i think it's a little more catholic
but you can have a lot of objects in an
institutional
settings as well it's just a different
type of problem you should have this for
the viewers
and the horse
and forehead
[Music]
it
second point is about creating a system
in which
everyone is an eleventh name
it doesn't matter who you are you can
speak your voice
and you are just the same as anyone and
so they will just hear
you and i hear you and i hear you and
it's just like
a common collaborative discussion
without anyone trying to
reach more stages in order to love their
voice
so no biases towards
status yes it's about the liberation
as opposed to decision making
exactly we want to be able to experiment
with ideas
and show every stupid idea of smart idea
in the earth so that we can
brainstorm and build upon it without
fear of being
anyone or will we reach conflict
we don't need consensus but it's
important to
be able to speak of mind purity of ideas
yes without corruption
through reputation
yeah detection and stages is what we
reject
is that by collecting it's not like
stickers
it's not like money only crypto
that's not like money we don't like what
we take
because money is the same as pitch
we use money to purchase stitches we
don't like stitches hard to not like
money but we are
happy with crypto
i think zentai fun can be also about
many other things
and one main thing also is that they
have fun
is anti-censorship exactly entire
censorship
and it's about privacy sedanity
and uh basically all those values that
we are promoting on the digital world
about cryptography
actually apply through this
anti-aliasing
physical world it is a physical analog
cryptographic medium
hmm physical
analog crypto that's why we like the
classes
well this is kind of a message to the
ccc i think which is
um you know there's a lot of focus on
the digital
and we have all digital beings here you
know just bits of colors
um and this physically is oftentimes
about like
you know hardware and stuff but
it's not about social
social privacy and
privacy hygiene in the physical world
we don't often think about that
we don't have many tools to promote our
privacy
and of cedenity and our freedom of
expression
in the physical world what can we do
we can collectively create
do you know how to do that collectively
what
is i would like to create
not only uh with a status
of a creator for me
materiality colors
are also the creators
and zentais is
enabling us to see
beyond the persona of the creator
and listen to the materiality
and what the materiality has to
say about it we are like
paintbrushes yeah you can make
the hallways we got fun we can make
drawings with ourselves
but we can also perform yes
and there is no guy hector no
no they are just participants exactly
participants but an object can be a
participant
as well of course like
[Music]
a software can be a participant
together they make an assemblage yes
together they make an assemblage
tell me assemblages
are something more expensive than a
collective
in a collective more expensive yes
expensive
yeah so in a collective you have people
uh that are constituted a collective in
an assemblage
you can have people forms
matters software
artificial intelligence
gpt3
[Music]
and together
we form an assemblage that is somehow
working
in a becoming state
and while we are performing
within this assemblage and evolving
together
we might be able
to create where we
[Music]
of participants that just connect
with each other and explore the
capacities
just for simple interaction
and we don't need to think about why
and who and where and when
it's like doing it in the present
just for the simple interaction
of this object put together into an
assemblage
that activates the potentiality that we
didn't know
we had hmm can you tell
us can you tell me a story
about such an assemblage
such an assemblage well let's take this
example
of uh this bunch of creatures
living creatures like gingers
dead creatures like they're bad not dead
just non-living and then you know
a bunch of humanoids
so what are we really doing here um
we don't really know and yet one day we
met
and uh and then somehow it happened that
the postman amazon
found a bunch of outfits into a house
and we didn't really know what the funk
it was about
and we just worked them and all of cedar
magic
happens and all of steven
realized that we could do anything like
go to lidl
and purchase a can of coke with a beach
cart
who could have found they could ever do
that
oh organized a fantastic
uh a fantastic
um involving and uh
and involving each other with all those
capacities
and um and behaving in ways that we have
never before
behaved exactly maybe when we were
children i don't remember ever behaving
in that way
but embodying the
just owning
the absence of identity
not being able to see others reactions
properly so
not performing in a way that makes us
subject
to what these people around us hope for
us to behave like
but tumbling and laughing and just
gibbering in languages that don't exist
and
enjoying it riding around playing
jumping hopping in ways that we don't
normally do
why not perhaps we haven't been
inspiring others
maybe more people can understand the joy
of
faithlessness and
maybe one day they will try to
experiment themselves
and more and more people will be feared
on the institutional version
that is corrupting them become afraid
do you kill female yes hmm
[Music]
unknown in me
and in any
common that might come across
i feel not changed
by the roles of
the expectations
this is the way to getting public
in an anonymous way
yes
i mean it is exactly like we do on the
internet right like when we communicate
on the internet
we don't expect everyone to
know what we're talking about and yet
when we go out in the street to buy
coke at little we expect everyone to
know and we don't find it
concerning that that we have absolutely
no way
of finding the fact that we're
purchasing a can of coke
this is extremely strange that even
though we all have built
so much desire of actually
protecting ourselves from protecting our
communication and protecting our
identities in the digital world
we are not doing it in the physical
world and at the same time
just like we have seen in the digital
world
um where we can really play we can
incorporate and we can assimilate the
identity of anyone
yeah but why do we we can only do it
very shortly we can do it with like
mask and fingering like caravan and
stuff like that but
that is very strange you know in a
day-to-day basis
to wear a mask especially in times
so this is kind of like the possibility
of
really enjoying the same experience that
we
all have loved and discovered through
the internet
the possibility of but expanding
the reach of our persona and
communicating privately
and acting privately and not leaving
traces everywhere
especially today in which there are
cameras at every corner
so it is bots it is
it is privacy it is censorship
resistance
and it is expansion of self and
experimentation
is it a whale say with this sedonamity
to incarnate whatever you want
whenever you want and so
expand your imagination you don't have
any limit
with the pseudonymity am i right there's
no limit
you could be a dog i wouldn't know
i can be a dog
[Music]
[Laughter]
do you know the joy of unboxing
i know someone knows the joy of unboxing
unboxing the unboxing like the revealing
of what's inside
the zentai is the unboxing it just
looks very different instead of opening
we are putting on the zentai to reveal
what else is there
[Music]
yeah it is the we want to be
we we have to we have to hide in order
to reveal
this is also very expectational unboxing
because
i think institutions they
give us boxes to be in
and executions help us to remove the box
and as you said see what else
the joy of unboxing through zentai
mm-hmm
unboxing now yeah
you know the joy of unboxing
i love it
[Music]
and that's why i think zentai is an
enticing sushi
tool as well is that it doesn't allow
them wear or experimenter
to censor itself because of the usual
social norms that
rule our lives
[Music]
because of course if you're covering
your face the
only reason you will be covering your
face is because you have something to
hide
this is the institution
if you have a little sketch here and you
don't want to show it
or maybe you might be a cleaner
this is so sad that
everything is the worst is always
assumed
the worst is that first human father
because of the words
everyone else gets constrained
just because there might be ones
anti-criminal
or one somebody become illegal
just because one person uses
cryptography
for bad reasons then everyone who uses
is a bad person exactly that is very
institutional this is institutionality
because they boxes us
or not they don't actually understand
the world granularity
and the whole incentive and then the
whole
different needs and designs for
people doing it do you have anything to
hide
i don't have anything to hide but i like
the freedom that hiding brings exactly
so this is less about crime and more
about freedom
privacy
[Music]
privacy privacy hygiene in the physical
world
most people don't think about privacy
hygiene in any world
what do you think about privacy hygiene
now
well i think as this relates to
the way that privacy is seen as
something that
people don't necessarily need if they
have nothing to hide
and they think that this is a broken
assumption it is an assumption that
many many institutions many governments
many employers
many organizations that
are trying to see everything
they want everybody to believe this
they want to box everyone and i have a
zentai friend uh
and within his assemblage
there is another intelligence
and the art world doesn't want him
to be part of the art world because they
are constantly
asking for the artists
behind the artwork of this assemblage
the artwork is looking for
the persona behind the creation
in order to box and
to entitle the creation
as an artwork do you think we can
work on that and try a way
like try to find a way for my friend to
be finally recognized as an artist
even if there is no name
no persona behind it
[Music]
is
encouraging collaborative practices
because what i do is also what you do
and i do something great every that i
benefit from that because we are the
collective and as an artist
i want to create that i want more people
to create and now
this entire collection to be the most
amazing artist
and so i'm going to help you be an
excellent artist
and you're going to help your friend be
an excellent artist and we don't care
about the ego
because the notion of this single genius
that is creating an office is
completely ridiculous and by eliminating
our identities
we don't have this drive towards
acquiring
status and recognition and appreciation
for itself
we only want the artwork to exist and to
try
and so all these things around copyright
which is obviously
inevitably connected to the asylum
do you think so that my friends
the software can also be part
of the collective and can also be
recognized
as a creator by the end of not a
massager
[Music]
there is no membership to the collective
if you are hazardous
hmm so
how can we can you say
how we can plug our sentai collective to
the outward
because somehow i have the feeling that
we need to by
erasing all those boundaries we need to
create some ways to
talk to the afterwards and be
accepted by it you know
that i think i think we are art
do you think this is art yeah
is this out thank you sir yeah
so we are part of the outworld perhaps
the art world is not part of the art
world
you should ask our friends yes
i think the economy that they are from
is very institutional
and whatever question is do we as not
like thanks
do we want to become part of this
institutionalization
ah do we just foster
the execution of our world
yes how can we do this
by playing without trolls
is that nice and it's not about
behaviors
yeah really are still playing by the
wheels
yes recognizing the rules as well it's
about
playing and it's about ignoring those
rules i'm just
going to use organic and emergency
and vitification causes which is what
art should be in the first place
it's just like expressing yourself and
just
doing what feels the most fun and
creative at the moment
is the perfect performance
[Music]
this is my friend
what's your friend's name oh
i think he's she's getting screen
i think it is a software yeah
[Music]
of being an institution those
die slowly it's okay you don't need to
get scared of the institution
it's about letting your exhibition
express itself inside of the institution
inspiring maybe with practice
with wearing the zentai more often it
would be
unboxing layers what do you mean don't
you wear this anyway all the time
how is it dipping in and out of the
institutional and the execution
lenses that give both meaning but you
know it's um
it's like the institution is like a
master and
indeed like as as you wear the sunflower
and you can experience an experiment and
train
your extritional muscle and then
sometimes by mystic
you remove the suit but the muscle is
still there and you
keep yes and acting in an executional
manner
yes and you understand when to play
exactly and you can access that play
very very easily once you've practiced
once you've trained the muscle unbox the
layers and layers and layers
like past the parcel you go around and
you take off a layer each time
you discover what's inside and the good
is that
we should today now our default mode is
to be institutional and we need to put
effort and exercise in order to
move into the expeditionary being and
the objective
of the santa fe collective
is that extitional being comes fast and
only when we want to be exhibition and
we have to fight a mask
when we want to be institutional we put
on the mask
yes yes yes exactly
so the default state is the state of
accessibility to our capacity yes
being able to easily access capacity box
only when we need to
it's anti-punk funk
[Applause]
[Music]
huh
[Laughter]
[Music]
wow
you