okay hello everybody my name is Ricardo
consults and welcome to the road one a
Wi-Fi story so this talk is going to be
about a project that I developed during
my master thesis at the beginning it was
to detect rogue access points but then
it expanded to a way to detect also
Wi-Fi attacks so basically what we will
look over this talk its contextualize
the background that is needed to
understand the tool that was developed
and then we'll look to rogue access
points what they are and Wi-Fi attacks
that are sometimes needed and used
together with rogue access points and
the last part of this talk we will see
the tool in action actually I record
some demos
I don't trust doing some some live Wi-Fi
attacks here so we also see a guide
through over the detection process of
this tool so the things that that drove
me to embrace this project and to
develop this tool was basically this the
eye expansion and our our requirements
were always being connected and
everywhere so in order to this be
possible we need to have these access
points that will give us the internet
that we want and so these need to be
always connected and the easiness of
performance and Wi-Fi text kind of drove
me to try to create a tool that helps to
detect these scenarios it's not the
protection to its actual to detect this
has different things so sorry so the
thing here is among all of these access
points how can how can we trust that we
are connecting to a trusted source and
if you were for example a small company
oh you can in a cost-effective way try
to guarantee the wireless security and
yeah basically it was all this kind of
paranoia that made me create this
detection tool so in order to start and
understand the eristic used by this tool
and how it is
done the process of detection we need to
understand a few a few concepts
so basically when we talk about wireless
we are talking about $82 level which are
a set of rules on how to implement and
use the wireless networks inside this
802 dot 11 there's different operation
modes we have the a dock where it's like
peer-to-peer communication and we have
this infrastructure mode which basically
it's one that we care about it will be
our environment and it's where the
mobile units communicates through the
access points that serve as a bridge to
other networks and then we have these
the the basic service set which is our
environment which is the place where the
things will happen basically it's when
an access point is connect to the wire
network that will receive the actual
internet that will be send it to the to
the stations and this wireless stations
our laptops our smartphones and things
like that that are all together in this
environment which is the BSS so we have
the the environment ready so now you
need to know all these entities all
these environments communicate between
each other so they communicate by
sending some frame packets and these
packets we have three different types
the management ones the control and the
data and most important and the ones
that we will use in order to create the
tensions are the management frames that
are used to power management and
emission controls and they will allow
some devices to initiate and maintain
communications they will send
information like all of these subtypes
of frames which is like the associations
reassociation requests the broth the
beacons and other important subtypes
that are going to take place between all
these communication between these
entities and for us we go we need to go
deeper into the probe and the beacon
frames so the beacon frames we have the
the access points we have the clients
and they need to talk between each other
in order to understand them so the first
thing comes from the beacon frame that
needs to announce itself and
say hey I hear and I have all these
capabilities and this capabilities will
be something like the name of the access
point which is the service set
identifier will be the basic service set
identifier that it's like the the MAC
address of the of the access point which
is unique and I didn't if you identified
that access point and all the other
other all the other subframe types like
for example the time stamp that will be
used to synchronize all the stations
that are connected in that environment
the basic service set
so these beacon frames work in analysis
the the access points and you as a
client will listen to that beacon frame
so you will do the things in the passive
mode but if you want to be more
efficient you can probe for that
information so there's where the probe
Procrit appropriate quests the probe
frames will come into place so probe
request is basically asking for the
access point asking for the access point
information you do this probe request
and then you will receive the response
that will contain the other information
that we saw previously in the beacon
frame like the name the MAC address and
stuff like that so having all these
information together we can now see the
process of authentication to an open
access point so you will have the first
case where the Authenticator which is
the access point will announce itself by
sending the beacon frame and then you
can have in some places you asking for
that information
so basically sending the the probe
request and then you will have the
information back the probe responds and
then will take place the authentication
request the response and finally the
Association requests this is the
representation for an open
authentication if you will have an
encrypted authentication the next step
would be a four-way handshake so now we
came to a point where we know what is an
access point we know what the the
clients the
applicants are so basically your mobile
phone your laptop all these entities and
then comes to the point of what is a
rogue access point so basically a road
access point is an unauthorized or a
false access point which is created with
malicious intentions and sometimes it's
used to support some Wi-Fi attacks LED
strobe access points the most the most
known one it's the evil twin type but
there's different other types so for
example the unauthorized access point
it's very much the case where for
example a naive user or an attacker
deploy an actual physical access point
into a wireless network it will be there
it will be an unauthorized access point
and it is a rogue one
so the next one is the improperly
configure inside this type we can have
for example access points that are
configured with weak encryption like for
example the web and they are vulnerable
to some attacks and then they are again
also a type of probe access point in
space improperly inferior ones the
compromised is the case that affects pre
shared key WPA networks which in this
case it happens when your pre shared key
is disclosed Simo
so when attacker knows about this pre
shared key it means that your access
point is compromised and it is a type of
rogue access point so the last one the
evil twin which is the the most
mainstream one it's like a clone of the
exact believing at this point so in this
case the an attacker will pretty much
blown all the other identifiers that we
saw in the beacon frame and it will
create an exact clone which is the evil
twin this one can exist in two types
coexistence where pretty much exist
side-by-side the authorized one and the
replacement where pretty much you will
be off the we will close the connections
to the authorized one and only exist
your access point so these are the types
Robles points so what what what you can
do if you create an access point so
basically you can perform an individual
tax and to this you can say to me yeah I
use a VPN I'm safe okay that's fine
that's the way to go but there are other
people that don't use VPNs and there is
also the problem that if rogue access
point is deployed in your network they
can reach other nodes in the network and
they can target them and perform another
type of attacks like for example data
exfiltration or maybe flood the network
with some random data so at the next
point we have these Wi-Fi attacks this
Wi-Fi text for example the rogue access
point with strong a signal it's used in
case like I said for example to evil to
me where for example you have the real
access point and the rogue access point
and in this case by default be able to
got 11 networks they will give you the
connection to the access point that as a
strong signal so if you have to choose
between these two access points you'll
pick the one with a strong signal but by
default if you are connected to a rogue
access point you will not be
disconnected because you have a stable
connection so you will not switch
immediately to the strong signal so what
happens here basically the attackers use
the second point which is the V
authentication attacks they will send
some specific way frames that sense this
V of medication information and will
make you disconnect from the from the
real axis point and since you are now in
this condition of choosing the access
point you will switch to the one with
the stronger signal and you will be
inside the road one so the next one the
route next the Wi-Fi attack is the Karma
attacks
so before I explain the car attacks I
just want to give you a little context
that these are not all of the Wi-Fi
attacks that are available are the ones
that are in the scope of the detection
of these two so yeah you might know
about other types of Wi-Fi attacks like
for example the crack and attacks to web
network
but they are not mentioned here because
they are not in the scope of the
detection of this tool so keeping on
with the karma attacks so it is the case
where he targets devices that actively
probe for networks so my device for
example can start saying if there's
around the network or example a broom
and it will also again ask if the
network the Wi-Fi events for example is
around and what the karma attacks is is
basically responding yes I am headroom
yes I am Wi-Fi event yes I'm other
network so basically the same device
will say that it is different type of
devices and this will target is this
supplicant devices these these clients
that actively probe for Vogue before for
access points so then the fourth one the
rogue access point with radius server is
pretty much similar to do one describes
but targets aro 2.11 enterprise networks
and to these you can use for the tools
for example like post a PD BB he that
will create a fake radius server and you
can pretty much explore the the victims
targeting these networks and the last
one is the pmcid attack which is a
recent Wi-Fi attack was discovered I
think August this year and it targets
again delegate to pre shared key
networks and it will allow the attackers
to obtain the preciate key that are
using that in that particular SSID so
it's it kind of give you the same as the
the old Wi-Fi attacks where you would
target a network the authenticate the
client and try to crack the and shake
but in this case the thing is that you
don't need to actually have clients
inside that that network you will just
interact with the access point so the
attackers will target the reassociation
process in order to obtain a master key
ID which is free maitus the pmcid
and this is derivated from the access
point
to MAC address the clients like address
the PMT and the PMT name so these ones
are are easy known by an attacker the
one that it just needs and wants to know
is the PM key which is the right from
the pre shared key and if you do a
dictionary attack you could basically
crack the password of that access point
the thing here is that maybe some of you
already tried them you couldn't break
your neighbors Network is that it only
affects mostly affects wireless vendors
that using roaming technologies so
usually our home routers don't have this
capability so yeah we kind of safe from
this one so we now know about the Wi-Fi
attacks that are in the scope of this
tool we know about the types of rogue
access points we came to the point where
we all look at the tool that was
developed so basically this tool the
techs different types of rogue access
point and some Wi-Fi attacks it is a
modular framework it was divided in
different modules in order to make it
easy to extend it for different things
it is stationary one so basically yeah
it could be improved but if I started
this tool here it will just capture all
what's going around in this room so it
is limited to the scope and it can be
used in Linux systems systems and it can
fit all four different users if you are
a home consumer you will just figure
with what you know about your network if
you are a seasoned min straighter and
you have a different network you can
input some different some different
specifications so basically we have this
main tool which is the rogue access
point detector and it will load a
profile or not you up to you if you
place this profile by the way you are
saying informations about your network
and these informations are in the name
of your network your MAC address the
amount of access points that you have
the the channel where they are
configured the
the type of the encryption size that you
are using the signal the signal strength
of your access point all this
information will be stored in a profile
that then will be used for a part of the
detection process apart from this
profile which is an optional one we left
underneath a profile for free Wi-Fi
networks
it actually has just some free Wi-Fi
from the Portuguese ISPs the north
networks and and Mail networks and try
some evil news and eristic that I was
quite explained further on in order to
give you some some authenticity about
these free Wi-Fi so then once the
profile is loaded we'll go to the
modules where we have these scanners and
detectors which are passive ones and
we'll have the actuators which will do
active approaches so basically the
scanners do the scanning process it does
this scanning process with iawn lists
from linux systems or it can use this KP
framework and this will basically scan
what's going around in the in the air
and I'm doing this you will face a
problem which is the you need to filter
the access point because you just if you
just keep listening you will have a lot
of a lot of the same access point you
have a lot of times so we need to do
some threshold in order to to just keep
once the adult the res access point and
don't have a swath of that so basically
the scanners will they'll give you all
the information about what's going
around in the access point and then
we'll place the the detection process
detections at the to F the passive ones
are the authorized list techniques which
will depend from the profile that was
configured
if you don't configure profile it will
be the no knowledge network there's no
knowledge detection process that will
basically use what it's known in the air
and and try to do some no knowledge or
it tips over these access points are
announced so even if you don't configure
the right list you can still have some
results
but from that we have a black mist
technique which will make most of these
Wi-Fi attacks happen for some some
defaults brands like the pineapple a
piece of interfaces and if this is not
immediately saying that this is a rather
at this point but it will figure
something and say oh it something is
going wrong and we we have found an
access point that has a brand from alpha
cards that's not normal
so if I take a look so the next one is
the validate free Wi-Fi authenticity
like I said not going to explain later
the D authentication attacks detection
karma attacks detection it works both in
passive or active mode and the pmcid
attack detection next one we have the
actuators which will support the
detections that are described in the
previous section
so this detected these actuators will
pretty much do the the active active
process they will exert the access point
and will retrieve these amounts of
informations like the IP the the ISP
information will calculate a trace route
for example for a node in the network or
for and a website that you know the
amount of ops that you need to do to
reach it and will also calculate the
access point fingerprint actually this
uses the N map framework and will do a
scan over that node and will give you
information about that that access point
the last one is the countermeasure
mechanism what where you can basically
the authentic eight rogue access points
so now we'll throw a tune to the
heuristics in to detect the first one
they'll try to list attacking it's
composed of four detection mechanism the
white which one is the most easy one and
known by everybody we pretty much see if
the the announced SSID the announced
name of the network if we have to
announce main works with the same name
and we have the different bssid which is
unique or network we will alert the user
about that something
wrong of course that it's that this is
available but that's why we have on top
of that another heuristics the
encryption orig eristic will look if the
the encryption scheme used by the access
point is different forum for the one
that it's authorized so if it is
different it will alert the user we also
have the multi-channel detection which
will see if this slim access point it's
an ass in a different channel which is
also gives you another mystic about this
this thing and the last one is the
received signal strength indication
eristic which will pretty much else will
see if your access point the data point
lost is inside of a baseline of the RSSI
so in your profile you can figure this
baseline because you know about your
network and you know the the signal
strength that you are of course that
this is the air spectrum and we have
interference that's why you have this
baseline there that you need to
fine-tune correctly and if you do this
you will be it will not alert you but
will prompt you if you want to connect
to that access point so if it's your
authorized access point you will
successfully authenticate and will do
the wrist Xterra explained in the
activators and you will see that
information and Steve really match your
access point if if it really matches
that's ok
you are good otherwise something is
wrong maybe an attacker knows your
appreciate key and create an access
point similar to yours and you're kind
of in trouble or not so so this I have a
little video to show the process of
detecting of using the auto authorized
waste detection process so I hope this
can be seen with good quality so
basically in order to start the to
detection without right with we need to
load this this profile with the flag
waspy and this profile is basically what
I said you will put the information
about your access points and so we just
start
start the tool with bids and we will
start looking what's going on around
here it's just showing our access point
in lab network because we are using the
profile if we are not using a profile we
will see a bunch of access point well
I'll show you later on and now in this
second window I will create an access
point that will represent the first case
where it is the one that it is a a bssid
that is not authorized so I create this
access point using the tool it has a
method which is the last H flag which is
the ID mode where pretty much you can
you can can configure a profile called
road access points profile where you
have pretty much set the config for your
rogue access point this is mainly useful
for testing purpose nothing else trust
me
so I started the world access point and
you can see immediately that it's not
readable enough but I can I can tell you
that it says evil twin unauthorized DSS
ID and on top of that you can also see
that there's that information about
recently created access point so and
this is because of this tsf function
which is the time synchronization
function that like I said it's the way
that in inside the environment to be as
DSS they will they will define the they
will synchronize all the the entities
inside that VSS I so basically since
this access point is is created now by
an attacker of course that you can use
tools that can come you can have some
specific time for the tsf but by default
i am using the skeptic framework to
create the rogue access points it will
start by 0 and by 0 it's a recent access
point I don't have any other access
points in my my lab environment so it
will be strange so the next one will go
to the profile where we configure the
world at this point and we'll change it
to target next next case which
the encryption scheme so we changed to
the open access point and we will see
once we start the access point that will
get rigorous the alert in this case
these are two alerts the first one
saying about the multi-channel thing
because apart from you are deploying a
rogue access point that is similar to
the one that you have your network you
are deploying an incorrect Channel so it
says that it is a multi-channel access
point and also give you the information
that the authentic delta-t the
encryption is different so this one is
open and your is a double pa-choo so and
again it's recently created access point
so this gives you some some information
that something is going wrong so the the
next one will be the received signal
strength indication eristic so in this
case you will have for example a
scenario where the attacker will
increase the signal of the road access
point and in this case once you start
the tool you will be prompted about you
will be prompted you want to
authenticate to that access point you
can see here that yeah actually you can
see what I'm telling you that it is say
that strange receive signal strength
indicator do you want to associate if
you if you do okay it will ask you for
the informations about that network the
interface that you want to use to
authenticate the password of the access
point and yeah it will try to associate
after this association process if it
works correctly it will perform the
Mystics that I set internal IP
information external ISP evaluation the
traceroute actually is calculating it
and then it will do the fingerprint with
an map so with this since we were
connecting to the authorized access
point these informations are the correct
ones but if we were in the case where we
have an access point deployed for
example with without encryption you will
have different results or if it is one
that it's the similar to mine because my
my pressure
was leaked maybe it would be somehow
difficult or maybe the attack will not
be it is we think about it and something
here will not be right so about these
detections
we are clear so the next one is the
validate free Wi-Fi authenticity so in
this case we notice the pattern that is
that happens in in some networks
basically the thing is that in the north
and male free Wi-Fi is the the enough
free Wi-Fi follows a specific pattern in
the creation of the of the MAC address
so because the this network is a nas
from the same access point where you
actually have your authorized your own
network and since it's from the same
access point the MAC address is the
write from it and what happens in the
North free Wi-Fi is that the last byte
from the bssid will increment one unit
and if this happen we will give you some
some heuristic that probably this north
Wi-Fi it's an authorized one this is
just probably because an attacker can
think like we did and deploy this
authorized network and create the right
conditions to treat my tool so this is
this is okay but this is a different
different step and an extra layer that
can give you some confidence that this
access point is actually a trusted or
not so the same happen for male free
Wi-Fi the first byte is incremented to
units and the last five one unit this
also happens for for for example it is
also considered in the tool for for
Wi-Fi advantage and university of war to
access point because the the this VSS
are these are the right from the ever
new one and follow a similar pattern so
we use that also to identify it someone
is playing around
so the demo to see this working it's
pretty much we just you just need to run
the tool any scales you don't pass any
profile the thing that you pass is
basically the interface and the scanning
mode that you want here I'm using the I
double missed and you will see that it
will immediately say that are some
probably valid free white flies and if
we look at the pattern they are the ones
that I described before so yeah it is
trying to do the same from this male or
male this one failed but you can see
over there that it actually found some
problem well it's free Wi-Fi then I run
the tool with skeptic foot escape Lee
prema just to show that it also works
with skeptic but the thing here it is a
little slower with scape II because you
need to do the extra weight channel open
you need to code this channel open and
because of this the tool becomes a
little slower in this situation but you
can see that it already detected a
problem with free Wi-Fi network so as
for the sport the validate free Wi-Fi so
that's it we could do other eristic but
it's kind of a fair accurate to detect
rogue access point in such conditions so
the the karma attacks detections
can be done in in different modes the
active one or passive by default two
runs in passive mode where we just
listen for some probe responses that
will fall into the condition that this
progress pulses will will say that it is
different
SSIDs from the same access point so we
spot a common attack if you want to be
more active than you you have some some
some speed results you will activate the
active mode which will which will probe
from different SS IDs and since this
attack is running it will just be
spotted because it will answer to all
these requests so to two detectives
basically we just again run the tool in
the normal mode you don't pass any more
slugs except from the interface and the
and the scanning process and then in
this second window I will perform the
comet X using the air base and z2 and
once I started we will see that some
some karma rogue access points will
happen we have the first one which is
the default access point which is
created by the air base 2 and then you
will see in a while yeah that it
detected the karma attacks for this part
is not zero 157 Network so yeah
basically we detect the karma attacks ok
so the next one and I think yeah the
last one flock for the videos is the PM
k ID detection which in this case we
will need to run the tool in a different
way which is the we need to pass the
different interface in this case it's
the hi m interface which will need to
put your interface in a monitor mode and
then you'll pass the flag the white file
the attacks detection once you started
you will start looking for what's going
on in the in the year and in this in
this window I started the PM k ID attack
using the H hcx num2 which basically
will try to do this p.m. key ID and how
it works like i said it will use this
rate will target to reassociation
process and what it does it will try to
do a bunch of authentication requests
and association requests in order to see
if it can leverage that p.m. key ID from
the access point and so we will gather
all these effectively authentication
requests from a specific from a specific
access point targeted a specific actions
access point and you will alert the user
that something is going wrong and is
probably a pmcid attack so as long as we
run the tool we will see
this this buckets going around which is
not normal and they are told target all
the same network or if they were done in
broadcast they will talk different
networks and we also see here these the
authentication packets because the two
also identifies the authentication and
attacks but these ones are kind of
legitimate because if it's reason 15
code which you pretty much it's the four
way and shake timeout because once you
are trying to do these associations
request you will interact with the
access point and you will fail doing it
and the access point will send you the
information about the authentication
packet the forward four-way and shake
went wrong so in the next step we
configured this used every play to send
some the authentication attack to show
that it also detects the authentication
attacks like we already see it detects -
the authentication packets but yeah just
to be sure I change the channel of the
interface to be in the same one of the
target access point and we can see that
it's flooding many the authentication
packets and we can see that we rightly
identified to the authentication attack
so so basically these are the detections
of the tool they are covered some of the
of the detections process and in the
next slide I'll show you a small case
study that was done in the company where
I work and it's pretty much we were
doing a Wi-Fi assessment and the auditor
representing the attacker try to - - to
validate the the Wi-Fi security of our
networks and so basically he deployed a
bunch of Wi-Fi attacks that were unknown
to us and and we was running the - in
the background just to see how it
behaves and we can see that the we have
three different types of detections this
ones here are shortest to represent two
one
are not identified in the previous demo
but the first one will identify
Robeson's point with the same SSID and
different the SSID the second one will
identify rogue access points with
actually everything exactly like the
ones from our company but failing in a
different region our SSI and the last
one it's pretty much identifying karma
attacks and the one that I didn't show
the black.we statistics so in the first
case the auditor was just setting up the
tool and didn't pay much attention and
it just deployed the rogue access point
not caring about the SSID so this
diversity is not one of our authorized
ones and we will immediately spot that
rogue access point was going around so
the next one
challenge accepted from the from the
attacker and it really go deep and
configured an exact access point of our
owns and in this case what failed here
was that it configure it with a much
higher our SSI which are much higher
signal and it showed something strange
to us we try to authenticate to that and
since this an enterprise network the the
authentication process failed because
the attacker didn't our our our process
of authenticating to that network was
not one of the attackers so it failed
the Association process and basically in
this kind of attacks the attacker just
wants to steal your your credentials so
it will just target the first phase of
the authentication and will not actually
authenticate you to the radius server so
it failed so it spotted that there's a
rogue access point around so the last
one we look at this points from the
pineapple AP tool and the karma attacks
was spotted inside black base terrific
because pineapple also called the
pineapple access points are are
blacklisted by our two
karma attacks we already saw the the
auditor started a branch a bunch of
karma attacks and we saw that something
was going wrong and we successfully
identified this rogue access point is
Wi-Fi attacks a thing here is that apart
from this the tool also has a lock
mechanism where for example if you'd
integrated with CM system and you could
receive these alerts in real time and
monitor them in your in your
infrastructure but as the way it is
configured we just run it in the
terminal and that's great for us but see
that this lock system you can actually
connect it to to a to a cm so to
complete so we saw to that it's it's an
open source module or framework actually
if you are interesting you can you can
look at that gita and then pretty much
identify different types of rogue access
points like even twins and authorize
improperly configures ones that was
described previously and also detects
some Wi-Fi attacks like the karma the
authentications p.m. key ID and i added
here this limited crack detection
because the way the crack attack starts
basically one attack vector is to deploy
an access point in a different channel
so we have that nutritional detection
that I don't say that it is specifically
a comma attack that if something is
tried as you should look on so basically
that's it if you have any question
please go around and thank you all for
it
any question yeah
have you thought about implementing like
Auto learning feature for a profile
generation and stuff like that yeah that
would be great yeah for example I think
in a scenario for the free Wi-Fi that
could be interesting because it's really
hard to maintain all these profiles for
free Wi-Fi so we have a couple of of
detections but it will be interesting if
you have this also learning feature but
yeah it's something to think about in
the future yeah also expand the tool
from a stationary point to a way where
it's deployed in different nodes will be
great yeah
any more questions that's it all right
thank you