so hi I'm Rose Regina I am the digital
security coordinator at an NGO based in
Berlin where I provide internal digital
security support I create learning
resources for activists journalists
human rights defenders and members of
civil society as well as providing
advice and workshops to other
organizations this means I get to think
about fun things like a PT's organized
crime disorganized crime hate groups
abusive family members and intimate
partners and bad luck in the context of
no or minimal funding lack of dedicated
security or technical support low-end
old or second-hand equipment and
exceptional baseline levels of stress
all of which makes effectively targeting
security behaviors that much more
important okay so I'm going to talk a
bit about things to consider when trying
to get people around you to learn new
security practices my background on this
mate comes mainly from coursework in
public health
years of running trainings and then lots
and lots of time around much more
conventionally trained teachers then I'm
going to look at how some of the skills
and techniques commonly used in social
engineering can be helpful or how they
can be distinctly unhelpful my
background in that comes from my
activism my work and some other stuff so
when I think about teaching I I think
about it as creating this experience
that is both engaging emotional and
rational aspects and it moves people
from one point to another and there are
a lot of different things that can
affect a given learning experience like
the topic being covered the materials
being used to support the educational
intervention the skill of the teacher
how distracted the learner is how
distracted the teacher is the cultural
background and personalities of both the
teacher and the learner and then lots
and lots of other things and so this
applies when you're doing like more
formal trainings but it also matters
when you're just like sitting down with
a colleague one on one
hmm so when I start thinking about
getting ready to teach something I
generally start by asking myself to what
ends meaning what is my goal for the
learner and generally I find that tends
to fall into one of three categories so
I have teaching four facts which is
about specific pieces of information and
it's often referred to as rote learning
or memorization and there is teaching
for understanding which is much more
about learning a way of thinking or
framework of analysis and then third I
have actions and this is basically
behavior modification so this means not
only conveying information about how to
do something but creating a space that
builds the self-efficacy for people to
be able to put that information into
practice and this is my favorite because
when done correctly it's basically about
supporting people on fixing and
improving their own stuff so figuring
out which one of these three things I'm
aiming for it helps me figure out what
might be appropriate approaches but then
it also helps me figure out how I'm
going to evaluate how well things went
at the end so increasing a learner's
self-efficacy greatly reduces how much
effort I have to put in to get them to
actually change what they're doing and
what self-efficacy is is it's just the
belief that you can actually do a
specific thing and it features really
prominently in a lot of public health
interventions especially related to
addiction and the idea originally comes
from a psychologist named Alfred bendera
and it's it's basically the idea that
you're in a better starting point for
changing what you're doing if you
believe that you can change what you're
doing rather than if you believe that
it's impossible for you so bandura also
came up with this nifty idea called
social learning theory which is the
acknowledgement that you can learn
things through indirect social
observation which is sadly way more
applicable for bad habits than good
habits so I don't recommend relying on
that social learning theory is an idea
about how people learn but there are
also theories about how to teach to best
facilitate learning some approaches are
geared towards specific
populations and some towards specific
topics I've put a few examples up here
and I encourage you to look into them
deeper that we don't have time in this
talk but like almost all of that there
can be summarized as basically ask
questions borrow from other fields get
learners engaged and then like be aware
of social dynamics I'm gonna dive a
little bit deeper into Malcolm Knowles
and his work which is commonly known as
adult learning theory that there are a
lot of other theories about how adults
learn Adult Learning Theory has criteria
for who counts as an adult learner it
has guidance on general ideas to promote
learning by adults and it's tied to the
added content structure my major
critique of adult learning theory is
that it assumes that adults learn
differently than children and I think
it's really just that we have accepted
that we can't bully within learning
adults the way that we try to within
kids and so I I would hope that if
you're working with teenagers or or even
younger kids you might also think about
some of these ideas so I did stands for
activity discussions on activity
discussion input deepening and synthesis
and I use this structure pretty
extensively when I'm drafting curricula
and self learning interventions but I
tend not to follow it super super to the
T but it's just a good checklist for
myself to make sure that I'm putting
things together in an order that is
supportive to the learner so with the
activity it is something interactive
that draws on the learners lived
experience and Prime's them for
integrating what you want to teach them
into existing mental models and
frameworks the discussion is a chance to
get everyone on the same page and to add
in any key points that you want people
to start thinking about that didn't come
up organically in the activity the input
is the more conventional learning
teaching standing up there doing
something like this part and then the
deepening is a chance for the learner to
try to integrate an
with the new information from the input
and kind of deepen their understanding
synthesis at the end is just a chance to
wrap up any loose ends provide a summary
and just like catch any stray questions
so functionally what this means is I
start with something interactive I have
a chance to talk about what that
activity raised I move on to direct
instruction apply that learning hands-on
and then I give another chance for
questions and reflections this is
because just talking to people is not
necessarily that effective all at the
time though I'm really glad you're all
here so if I were doing this talk as a
workshop it might look something like
starting with a popcorn session where
you talk about good and bad learning
experiences that you've had and then we
might go on to talking in a group about
the different characteristics of the
things that you brought up as good or
bad at which point I would introduce
adult learning theory and it did and
then we could move into a small group
work which could be brainstorming or
trying to apply what you just learned to
the topics you generally teach people
about and then we would come back
together you could share what you
noticed ask some more questions and
maybe do like a little bit more of a
presentation of what you did in the
small groups if I had enough time I
might even include a second go around
that had more of a focus I'm planning an
implementation like making a full
curriculum and then troubleshooting
issues that might come up like if this
is a really new approach for you or if
this would be a really new approach for
where you're working we're trying to do
the educational intervention so notably
only one of these five steps is actually
someone standing up here talking and
that's because the activity and this
discussion get people ready and open to
the topic the input is the new
information and the deepening and
synthesis are about making sure that the
new information gets cemented in by
connecting it to what they argue now
this is basically about getting people
into the emotional and mental state that
they need to be in order to work with
and really integrate new information
another nice thing about it is is it
makes it a little bit harder for you to
move through info way more quickly than
people are likely to be able to absorb
so when when your goal is behavior
change addressing self-efficacy can
include troubleshooting real and
perceived barriers sometimes it can be
about helping set realistic expectations
and sometimes it's just about
encouragement so it's worth like
thinking about how you might be able to
do that in a way that's specifically
relevant to whoever you're working with
so if someone says something is hard
just just believe them they're
experiencing it as hard and insisting
that they're wrong isn't going to change
how they're currently experiencing it
but it may make them not want to bring
problems to you in the future
I also really like to frame things in a
way that kind of validates the
experience of challenge or difficulty
while setting future expectations at a
more reasonable level so this is things
like okay yes it's hard now but but it
gets easier it's going to be easier and
another good thing about this is as long
as it is something that will actually
get easier if it continues to be
incredibly hard you maybe want them to
come to you because it may mean that one
they're doing it wrong or two that they
just need a different solution so I DIDS
is a great guide for planning but it's
just a framework to help you create a
controlled emotional experience and
there are a lot of other skills that are
also needed like asking questions to
guide a discussion or prompt a learner
to try a different approach and using
active listening reading expressions
sensing how much you can get away with
pushing someone's impatience and the
ability to gauge them and then present
in a way that is comfortable to the
other person all of that is important
for shaping an effective learning
experience and there are also all skills
that are frequently used in social
engineering there's also a ton of acting
skills that is kind of about holding
people's attention or presenting to a
room or just like broadcasting your
voice that are really helpful with both
us so scaring people into better
security really doesn't work I prom
you but creating an addressing feel or
fear can be extremely powerful tools in
predisposing people to specific actions
so we know that creating fear and stress
can massively increase the effectiveness
of phishing attacks and other kinds of
social engineering an appealing solution
to manufactured fear can also be used
like when you have a pop-up that
simultaneously tells you there's a virus
and if you just click here and install
this thing it will fix it
but fear can also create paralysis and
the association of a topic with fear can
lead to avoidance most of us have
probably experienced this most likely
with a topic related to money or health
so in public health there's a lot that
goes into trying to figure out how to
both acknowledge the seriousness or
gravity of the situation while also
pushing as few emotional buttons as
possible and so this is stuff like
maintaining a calm demeanor and warning
before you're going to say something
scary instead of it being like and then
immediately providing context to help
people understand the risk as well as
talking about mitigation options so with
social engineering that paralysis is
often really useful but when you're
looking at education sometimes just
reaching that level of heightened
emotional state is enough to kind of
dissuade someone from ever wanting to
revisit the topic and just leads people
to avoid thinking about it instead of
having any kind of motivating effect for
them to take proactive action so
establishing trust is importantly
teaching and especially when you're
talking about a topic like security
where people are fairly unlikely to have
the internal knowledge already to be
able to tell if what you're saying
actually is true so while sometimes
similar rapport building is not the same
as establishing trust report is about
feeling connected but you can feel super
in sync with someone and know that they
will still let you down it's it's good
for getting favors but security should
not be a favor you can use a bunch of
techniques like mirroring and obligation
to get rapport fairly quickly but it
also breaks
Trust is better thought of as slow and
like hopefully persistent so with social
engineering the goal is generally
short-term with the expectation that you
don't need the glamour to last much past
the end of the interaction or the con
for lack of a better term but with
teaching our hope is that the lessons
and behaviors are going to be retained
indefinitely if social engineering is
about getting someone to do a thing then
teaching for behavior change is about
helping someone figure out how to
socially engineer themselves so like
it's one thing for me to get my
colleague to use a password manager to
generate super strong passwords when I'm
standing right there it's another thing
for me to get that colleague to a point
where they're going to do that even when
I am NOT looking over their shoulder
so rapport is sometimes more important
than trust especially for those of us
who are not people people and rapport
building techniques can be incredibly
useful I'm not I'm not against it
even with looking at the differences
between trust and rapport you can kind
of see how you could sort of substitute
one for the other sometimes however
potentially more important than all of
these kinds of mismatches attempting to
use certain social engineering
techniques with your colleagues causes
two kind of fatal problems that aren't
really just that it's the wrong tool for
the situation so problem one with some
of your colleagues you are normalizing
manipulative behaviors in connection to
digital security you are training them
to be vulnerable especially to the kinds
of attacks that are not going to be as
easily stopped with better visibility
employ solutions or a higher level of
lockdown when we tell people to ignore
scarily worded messages with explaining
them without explaining them or when we
ask people to share passwords especially
over the phone or over email it kind of
puts the idea that like that's okay
stuff plus if you're mean while doing it
you are doubly setting up your
co-workers for an attacker to be able to
come in and pretend to rescue them so
just because they're going to be so
happy to maybe get some help without
being made to feel awful about it like
all of us have bad days
we all have our mean days and I'm not
saying that if you're ever short with a
colleague
you are responsible for every phishing
attack that ever happens where you work
but do kind of think about the impact of
how you choose to engage with the people
around you and whether or not that's
actually what you want it to be so
problem two is that some of your
colleagues are bound to be a bit more
resistant to manipulation and with some
of them you're just gonna fall a little
bit short and you will fail and then
that's fine
if disappointing to you but with others
you're going to set off the same twinge
that an attacker would so they're gonna
consciously or unconsciously sort you
into the bad actor bucket and that's
that's not a good thing like sometimes
it means that they just will be a bit
wary of you but sometimes it means that
they're going to actively hate you for
insulting their intelligence and
thinking that you could pull a fast one
on them and it can also feel super
disrespectful so in that situation
you've not only made enemies of a
colleague by doing this but you've
specifically aligned against you the
people who should be most able to get to
to work with you and to like come to you
with problems that they're noticing
earlier because they're just a little
bit more aware of it and this can also
feed into shadow IT because if people
don't trust you especially when it's on
a gut level they're more likely to go
out of their way to avoid interacting
with you and that means that they would
rather go through the process of setting
up an alternative system than trying to
get support from someone they perceive
as unsupportive or worse so you can
affect habits through directly targeting
behaviors or indirectly through
affecting attitudes and understanding
habits are also seldom contained to just
one area of a person's life this is true
what the bad habits people bring in from
like an old job or from their personal
life and it shows up in the office and
then you have to deal with it but it's
also just as true going in the other
direction in terms of thinking about
like the impact that what you do in
terms of security education where you
work has on their personal lives
so what you do the impression you make
when you're doing security education
interventions that carries over into
people's future workplaces and and their
homes and that's actually a serious
responsibility but it's also a pretty
amazing opportunity so I hope this talk
was helpful or at least a little
interesting teaching whether formal or
informal is hard but there are tools to
make it a little bit easier and if
you're trying to get someone to do
something when you're not there just be
aware and like try to specifically aim
for the things that are going to
facilitate that you may already have a
bunch of the skills that you need to be
great at teaching but take some time to
reflect to make sure that like you're
doing things that are going to lead to a
better outcome and not things that are
going to get in your way of being
effective and when you teach about
digital security in your work that is a
responsibility and an opportunity and
the people you work with deserve good
security in all parts of their lives
because everyone does and this is both
about your responsibilities to other
people individually but also to like the
larger society so thanks
so I I I think there's time for
questions if anyone has them there that
that was the the 20 minutes I believe
all right come find me later if there's
anything you want to ask privately