okay I don't have a fax it's good to be
back I was actually here six years ago
security conference 2013 by camping or
what I have learned from doing bag
hunting for a long time and there's
really only two parts doesn't even talk
about bug hunting moving around a bit
about this brochure and we'll finish off
with a conclusion now about myself I'm a
former developer transition Minturn
pentester
full-time security researcher I'm in the
software labs of zenit labs which is
part of dark matter and we're hiring by
the way we're not on that spreadsheet
but if you go on a website there's about
70 roles including some here in Canada
on my own so with that out of the way
specifically when I say bike hunting I'm
really interested in bugs that results
in vulnerabilities so you know what is
it what I don't care for QA bugs
anything like that where do I look for
at least specifically for me it has to
be software but obviously
vulnerabilities can be found anywhere
ranging from security locks airport
security IOT software hardware you know
crypto bullets yes absolutely everywhere
and basically every system has an
opportunity to have its security posture
strengthened
that'll vary depending on who you are
some people look at it on a challenge
some people to improve their some people
look at it to improve the security
posture of the software industry
everywhere
and you can apply that in different ways
and as such there really isn't a cookie
cutter approach so you can use tool to
find some vulnerabilities but I think
uniquely what you do is you start with
what you know and then you look for
problems in that space if you try to
look for vulnerabilities in a completely
different space you'll often be hindered
by the fact that you're learning the new
technology more so than actually funding
vulnerabilities so let's say you just
learn okay I'm gonna go ahead I'm gonna
look for some vulnerabilities
I generally always recommend with
reading the documentation
or even just straight up or examples
when I was here six years ago I was
talking about security problems in
payment gateways and universally across
all the payment gateways I was looking
at and presenting at the time they all
had the same design flaw which I assumed
came from copying a previous
implementation and it sort of eventually
spread and became the standard but that
was something that identified simply by
reading the documentation and he said
the sign flaw that you can't easily
patch out of existence so that's that's
a very good place to start and very
valuable and then you gotta learn to
recognize weakness patterns or you know
critically think about what you're
reading whether or not it makes sense
whether or not there are corner cases
that they didn't think of and once
you're done with that you actually test
the authentication rather than
authorization so you get privilege
escalation vulnerabilities and the other
thing that's nothing very important is
once you find something or you've had an
idea you sort of you read the
documentation but but what if that
assertion and the assumption that this
function you know always returns true
it's wrong you know it's very often good
to challenge challenge the status quo
you know be be curious assume that the
documentation is right and assume that
the the framework you're using is with
that flawless on its own now once you
consuming a large volume
nation and then you might not be too
specifically experienced with with a
large number of under ability classes
and Sarah I generally said there's a
couple of things you did to simplify it
and the first one is to start off
learning specific bag classes so you
might say well this week I'm gonna learn
SQL injection and this week I'm gonna
learn learn buffer on the flow so this
week I'm going to learn some other
vulnerability and you can hop on exploit
maybe you can find software that is
vulnerable to the class you want to you
want to learn you can download the
export you can download the vulnerable
application and then you can see what
they actually did but better yet you can
try to discover it yourself
so from installing blank piece of
software finding the vulnerability
writing your own exploit it's a very
good learning curve and then I generally
say that once you once you have one you
then build on it so you learn one by
class two three four five and expense
that reviewing software generally it's
focusing on specific abilities at the
time until you get familiar with the
software and at that point you can start
looking for for more things and it
certainly I generally never look for
cross-site scripting because those
things just show up everywhere it's like
two or three years later you can still
come back to the same piece of software
and if you find something you you can
when you find one durability what you
want to do with it is you want to report
it so whether it's to the vendor or
whether or not you're going through some
like search that's kind of up to you but
I generally find that my my enthusiasm
for software vulnerability kind of
follows this curve here which is it's
kind of flat I've got an idea
I usually find that you can leverage up
specific report writing wasn't my
favorite part of the job right advice is
usually easier and they're very short
and sweet so some of my declines and
nonlinear time scale in this problem
because essentially the first three
panels and then portion typically drags
on from one month to multiple years so
it actually looks very different in
reality than what you see here
and and of course one of the other
problems with the fact that the score
she drags on for so long is that as you
find vulnerabilities this doesn't scale
so I had a friend in Melbourne it just
tweeted the other day that he so far in
2019 he has gotten over 100 CDs and if
each one of those is to a different
vendor and each one of those drags on
for four years it's got a lot of time
messing emailing vendors and trying to
follow up getting a batch piece that
email chain anyway so when you are
reporting one ability there's a couple
of things you should know the first one
is what do you report you gotta you know
write on the technical accurate
description section if your expert is
changing them altogether each problem
that needs to be addressed by the
developer needs to get us on specific so
you describe I generally don't try to
tell vendors how to fix the problems in
the software I might give you a
reference link but I generally leave it
up to them to choose how they're going
to mitigate the problem because a lot of
the time mitigations aren't just used
perimeters queries or whatever the
security industry tend tend to repeat us
an anthro very often security problems
in in other ways as well now where we
have to report it that's the hardest
part
I'm like established vendors and
particularly in the later years where
we've done many programs it's gotten a
lot easier to explain order to work out
and where you need to just send this
information they have no and yes a new
standard security security information a
lot of the big players they do have
notification pages they just not live
where you think that they would I gently
email support and they'll see see in
abuse cities cities you can just go to
my online web form you fill in the
details you click Submit and you should
Google details and if you don't want to
do that
open wall has a web form we just take
your button and you
any public which is where the researcher
will find a vulnerability and be more in
detail later whether they sell it on the
black market or sell it to a private
expert acquisition program doesn't
matter doesn't get notified it's
unlikely disclosure is what we usually
there's a reward no that's the one that
we see the most
it's when a vendor gets an email from
security researcher there's a bit of
back-and-forth
a patch gets produced public disclosure
bug track or released alongside the
software and then apply the patch which
is I guess the primary pin disclosure
full disclosure is typically when the
vendor gets notified when the research
makes public there's no
and then the last one which is pretty
new it's a notional see specific this I
think people they're unhappy with the
current status quo to make money
all right now so much say I didn't see
responsible disclosure on that slide
I really dislike used to say but the
industry as a whole
traditionally it was used by vendors to
make sure public smack responsible
public responsibility you know well hey
Chico gets produced in the first place
which were prevented so that's that's
the reason why I dislike responsible the
second reason why dislike responsible is
no matter how you some users will always
be and so yeah you know we spoke with
the vendor and
no superiority using now the industry
does I really think we should value to
the discussion to begin with there's a
mute button liberally engage the other
thing that I see is this installment I
think the truth is that what keeps you
secure is
so very valuable for defenders
and again you might argue that there's a
link between proof of concept once it's
a passion available the problem is or
even MOOC and so between
the time between
the disclosure local vendors think that
you should delay that on one two weeks
or whatever to patch adoption unless you
have very rapid automatic cashing we
have no way of knowing what the last the
Scotia policy compliance as a problem
being each if you find that the week I
think it's useful to wait for money days
again it's
but I think that we can we possibly need
to rethink the core the core problems
that we wanted
with the current disclosure so also
placed under this this is a OC guy I
know him I absolutely expected better
from him don't arrest security
researchers security researchers they're
trying to help the bad guys that I'm
going disclose that they exploited
saying you never get to yell at them
right so he's shelling any guy who's
trying to help and the other thing is
looting his he's not yelling in the
vendor so in this specific case it was a
vendor who had exposed all the customer
databases on the internet no credentials
cameras on the internet no credentials
this thing wasn't showdown and at this
point whether or not it's insured and
bad guys either months old and or they
they simply they scan for it themselves
the people who want to steal this data
and I've already stolen it and he's
yelling at the guy who's trying to help
the vendor teach the problem so yeah all
right some of my own personal stories
trying to speed this up a bit I'll
probably go over just you know all right
this is a non-scientific
75 most of the time going to deal with a
vendor they're very good
you know I send them an email all that
apply no hard feelings even if they're
never seen the vulnerability report
before
in the undefined section so I never got
to deal with we just
I've also done a number of different
disclosure methods I've gone through
search before
direct I've done full disclosure I've
done my man piece the one thing I'd say
about going through a search is usually
usually good as well they usually you
know help the one thing that I feel like
they do that is that they kind of just
shuffle e-mails back and forth and it
tends to add to your your volume of
email as opposed to dealing with the
vendor directly but if you are concerned
about you know I've been there turning
around and trying to sue you for finding
a vulnerability in the product which we
all know happens going through a search
can be a useful way of dealing with that
so in my experience disclosure tends to
pull in one other two streams one is I
contact the vendor si hey I got some
information how would you like to
receive it they respond
I send through the details we email back
and forth sometimes to patch but
sometimes they take forever or they
change them on say we're not going to
patch this whatever then the advisory
comes first and public pressure tends to
make them rethink and the patch becomes
second and the other the other one is
when you email the vendor email the
vendor email the vendor and you never
get a response just one of these two but
I will talk about some of the the banks
have been involved with that we're very
nonlinear or very non straightforward so
the cacti super link a place or a
network monitoring tool that a plugin
for dealing with links
in 2014 somebody published an exploit
that's SQL injection expert on Expo dB a
few months later I'm on a pen test I
come across the same software the same
plugin I independently find the SQL
injection and then when I get back to
the office next week and install the
software and I determine that it's
actually not just an SQL injection it's
a very trivial remote code execution so
I contact the vendor we can loss the
diets that deleted the website so I
wasn't able to recover it but the vendor
anyway they come back and they go yeah
it speaks to next week and I come back a
bit later to check and that's the end
it's not public and the download is
still serving the old vulnerable card
critics and then I give up an escalating
but I come back a bit later because the
way I see it they've already had the
initial exploit expect to be for six
months and anyone who actually looked at
the source code would have typically
draw the same conclusion it's a remote
code execution this is very likely to be
exploited in the world but this states I
mean it's been public for six months so
release my exploit and I include my
proposal patch so that you know nothing
else they still serve the vulnerable
code and then I've kind of just given up
on it and I went back and I look through
the timeline before we giving this
presentation as it turns out in 2016
basically two years later they added the
the plug-in functionality into the core
of the application in github and then
six months after that they released the
official version that not contained the
plug-in in the core but it's also its
it's not no longer vulnerable so that's
great that's almost three years after
the initial disclosure then I have a
patched version in the core but the
website has enough that it still shows
you know eventually a year or so after
this way they go on there after the
website indicate it's now in core blah
blah blah the old download link is still
there it's still vulnerable if you run
the old version of the software or you
try to install the plugin over the top
of this you might end up still being
vulnerable so and they never disclosed
anything to their users into himself in
this they just incorporated it into the
core functionality and she quietly
patched it so that was one experience I
have a lot of these same thing run later
two weeks later somebody opens an issue
on the developer saying hi he said Billy
could you please patch this I run
yourself through and then nothing
happens random person the expert called
system function in PHP see the problem
is that they chose to call system with
it they could call pass-through where
they can do any number of other things
you can't just go patching on the basis
that if you just you know do this one
content change you wouldn't be
vulnerable because that's not understand
the problem here is a bunch of other
people also joined in on that eventually
this is a problem now you know who wants
to patch this apparently he doesn't
intend to patch it so he's asking the
community for I guess that's fair enough
but no one comes forward to submit a
patch so one year later you know this
thing has now been in publicly
exploitable for for two years they
firmly submits a patch and he closes the
issue and I remember looking at their
past John this looks like the wrong
approach for solving this problem I'm
working on some material for for
training this would be I think a good
good use case to look at patching not
being done correctly so I come back to
look at it turns out the developer has
rebooted the code back to the original
vulnerable code presumably because he
made a mistake in the pattern of the
patching Brooke starting and it's still
there today he's still serving the
vulnerable code he still has no there's
no updates on its website there's
nothing you know he's closing issues on
the github I guess so this thing's been
yeah for for four years and anyone who
downloads this gets a free remote
understand to get a remote code
execution from the internet as soon as
they deploy that's great so those are my
stories I mean you know there's only
some of the story it's not every story
is bad but it also proves this notion
that vendors don't necessarily care to
fix the flaws in their product they
don't actually necessarily care about
the security of the users even though
they have a public statement about we
take security
that is not a very seriously blah blah
blah we repeat if I ever get breached
but deep down a lot of them they just
want to write their software or live
their life or you know do whatever so
let's look at some some of the very
famous cases hopefully you all know
these three that I'm going to go through
we get shell shock shell shock is it's a
very curious example this one followed
wouldn't you know people would have
called responsible disclosure for I call
coordinated disclosure in September the
initial
environment ability was reported and
then they decided on roughly a two week
patch cycle so 24th of September the
patch all the distributions
notifications that were already by the
patch released all very good but
unfortunately it was such a trivial
vulnerability to make a worm right next
work for that it would literally take
someone with skills five minutes to
write a function and exploit and then
you depend on the entire internet to go
and apply the patches from there they're
using and that's always going to fail
because certainly at any given time also
that the patch was initially flawed and
there was in fact six other hundred
bilities and it took about a week and
then over the next month or so patches
do get applied and
scaring some use all sort of dice off
this is something that follows the stock
standard recommended disclosure
practices and you know we don't actually
know how many people got exploded across
the internet but it was a non-trivial
amount we don't know much target stone
etc and it just goes to show that you
can do this motion with the best
intention and recommended practices but
if the time it takes to write next foot
or reverse the patch it's less than it
takes to apply the patch you're in
trouble
alright the other famous one heartbeat
so in April in 2014
within two days of each other both
Google and codon on the condom reported
the same vulnerability they scheduled a
patch release back for about a week
later and what actually happened was two
days before then somebody decided to
make it press release saying that oh you
know serve honorably in open SSL but we
are patched and they're broke the
embargo there's also a lot of other
potential concerns about the embargo and
handling of this pre-release information
there's a lot of argument but the thing
that I think we can focus on again it's
asana patching so at the time that this
bean burger broke in the seventh from CA
that are vulnerable oddly two days later
security did a scan of the internet they
found six hundred and fifteen thousand
servers they also found three hundred
thirty person that had happened enabled
but it didn't appear to be vulnerable
likely patched and on one hand I think
that's good within two days we have one
third of the the server codebase have
applied the patches I'd like to see that
heuerman
it's not a bad start however the CI son
of thing was significantly slower couple
of days later only thirty thousand of
the five hundred thousand certificates
have been reissued a week after the
initial embargo brach there were press
releases with official breach reports of
companies getting again a month after
net craft does another press release as
it turns out 43% of the sea-ice have
been replaced
furthermore 7% of the had not renewed
their key
so the key potentially been stolen it's
still in use so you renew the
certificate but the attacker has the key
can still just at will decrypt your your
traffic or perform and in the middle
attacks against your website so very
poor practices there as well we moved on
to June at this point errata that's
another skin 309,000 so this stage the
bulk of servers have been patched we
don't really have clarity as to how
quickly those patches were were applied
but there's still there's still one
third now in January 2017 showdown did
another and they found that three years
after the almost three years after
disclosed 200-person or roughly 20% of
the initial silver base we're still
vulnerable so yeah this is a very high
profile vulnerability you'd hope that
patch adoption and remediation would
have been faster would have been you
know more widespread but here we are
three years later 20% is still
vulnerable and they would probably still
be vulnerable even if the embargo hadn't
hadn't broken and the
the disclosure and follow the intended
in the intended path but its owner comes
back to this notion that you can't fix
vulnerabilities with discussion you have
to fix it with patch it similarly I'll
skip this one really quickly eternal
blue Busan / / 2016 Microsoft said
please turn off SMB version 1 following
bad luck then
in March in 2017 that you should have
okay blue month after that shun brokers
releases the export public a month after
that wanna cry 8 so at that stage you'd
had 2 months of the patch window sir
provides some air cap dates and you had
had six months of official advice and
turn off SMB version 1 you had if you'd
listened to the security industry you
would have been the ease of warning some
turning off SMB one and still what a
crock hits courses
billions of dollars in damage and at the
end of 2018 the estimate was still there
was millions of unpatched pieces yeah
he's a whole bunch of other stories with
vendors from promoters physically
attacking through dodgy patching through
things it's it's not it's not a problem
the conclusion it's not it's not hard to
find this you know funny things like
hard-coded credential and I devised this
failure to validate SSL Certificates
default credentials
you know week we password policies any
number of things like this it's pretty
easy to find you don't have to be that
is everyone durability every every
impact every vendor they're all
different you can sort of its this is
this is the wrong policy one policy
suits all right it's I really feel that
each one really should be evaluated and
disclosed in accordance to its own
criticality Albanese law that's that's a
pretty new thing but it pops up he gets
hassled by people and it's been proposed
that we should have something officially
called Albany slaw acid bender your
allocated time for the structure is
directly inversely through the amount of
time your staff spends harassing
security researchers on the internet I
don't think we need I think we should
all do better I don't think that people
will stop harassing security researchers
even though I wish they would but people
who are in this industry I don't think
will make good informed decisions on
behalf but I think bigger than the
squash of debate we really need to work
on you know secure code development
whether you think that's shifting left
whether you think it's better frameworks
what do you think it's better tooling it
doesn't matter we I understand that some
bugs will probably always still slip
through that's not a problem and that's
what we need to fix patching right
eventually you're gonna have to
for your product and you don't want to
leave you use this and risk yeah you
really want the patch to be reliable
patch to come in quickly and yeah so
that's it I know we're out of time
so questions I have a bunch of middle
koala thinks if you catch me afterwards
and you have a question I'll give you a
little koala from Australia