[Laughter]
it all boils trying to most of the time
not all the time but most of the time
we're trying to protect data and most of
us are probably familiar with the three
facets of data security that we call it
CIA confidentiality integrity and
availability this is pretty
straightforward this is nothing new but
it boils down to can you keep your data
safe can you protect it from being
altered and can you make sure that the
data is always available when it needs
to be available there's a few nuances to
that that have been added in our
technology world in our Internet
connected world but you can still argue
that if more or less falls down to those
three categories I may remember that
movie and it is what's the name of the
movie sneakers thank there's a scene in
the movie where the good guy and the bad
guy Robert Redford and Ben Kingsley
they're having a conversation and Ben
Kingsley is making a statement and I
want to read it to you because I think
it still holds true today in fact I
think it's always gonna hold true and he
says there's a war out there old friend
a world war and it's not about who's got
the most bullets it's about who controls
the information what we see in here how
we work what we think it's all about the
information now for me to have an
old-timer moment does anybody know what
they're sitting on right now in this in
this shot hey Craig I knew you would
know anybody else no it's a Cray
computer it's a mock-up of the Cray
computer if you want to see a real Cray
computer you can go to Maryland and go
to the Fort Meade National Cryptologic
Museum they have a Cray computer in the
museum that's one of the computers that
I literally used to work on when I was a
cryptologist I don't know say so stuff
that I used to do is now in a museum and
the last time I shared that her to talk
somebody shouted out when are you going
to the museum be in the museum but as
this is totally just a free
advertisement for the National
Cryptologic Museum I know it's a haul
for you guys from up here in the
Maritimes but definitely worth your
while if you do happen to ever MIT find
your way down to Maryland and want to go
to the museum get in touch with me if
I'm around I'd be happy to give you a
tour and show you lots of lots of really
cool stuff there anyway that's a sidebar
my point is and what I keep coming back
to is I don't think technology is ever
gonna solve our problems I think in fact
the technology is our problem
somewhere along the line in our
in our rush to throw information in data
on the internet and making extreme
streaming and freely available and all
the data at our fingertips at any time
at any place in any way in any form I
think we collectively have already
agreed to give up on the security of
that data just by the mere fact that
we're putting it out there just the
thought I had a couple weeks ago a
grittier disagree but one of my early
lessons that I was taught by a chief
scientist at NSA and this goes back to
when I was trying to design a software
system to be used as an encryption
system was whatever can be created by
man can be broken by man and you know
virtually all the cryptography that's
out there in our computer world today
even though it's billions and billions
of bytes and bits and you know super
long keys and and huge prime numbers and
so on and so forth and not even the
sidebar into quantum cryptography or
quantum computing but it's all solvable
it might take as new leaders to solve
brute force but there's a solution out
there and it's ultimately softball not
the one-time pad the one-time pad if you
use it right it can't be broken so as
far as I'm concerned we should still be
using one-time pads it's not pretty not
very practical though so this gets into
what I want to talk about in terms of
what I learned classically about
security and and pose a couple questions
to you I learned back at NSA what what
we knew then and what we call now the
risk equation if you google risk
equation
there's hundreds if not thousands of
them out there a lot of product vendors
a lot of security consultants advisers
auditors very often will try to use or
talk about the risk equation so there's
lots of formulas out there there's lots
of formulas that go to great lengths to
try to actually come up with real
working numbers I've never been into
that as much I like to try to simplify
these concepts so that more people can
understand in my experience
over the years of working with customers
organizations that were having to do
security particularly in the PCI world
these were companies that security
wasn't in there their DNA it wasn't
something that they had experience with
it wasn't part of their culture they
didn't have people that had long
backgrounds and insecurities they were
pretty much dragged kicking and
screaming into it it's not exactly true
for every organization there's certainly
organizations out there that that are
more proactive about security but I
think the majority of organizations out
there don't really understand security
don't really want to have to do it so
they you know just tell us what to do to
get by tell us what to do to get the Box
checked don't make us think just tell
them tell us what kind of boxes we need
how many where do we put them and what
color lights should the lights blinking
and that's that's been my experience
over many years and but what I've tried
to do is simplify and try to help them
understand what's going on
so I start with a very simplified
version of the basic risk equation now
I'm not a mathematician so I don't get
all the terminology right that I could
but risk at its most basic form is a
function of three different variables
vulnerabilities threats and what I was
taught is countermeasures but for the
sake of our discussion let's let's think
security maybe is what countermeasures
is but we'll talk more about that but
notice that the risk equation doesn't
technically have security in it at all
and these are terms that we've we hear
all the time we use all the time we
throw them around all the time
especially at industry conferences
vendor display booths I was walking
around there earlier today trying to see
which of these words were popping up and
didn't see too many of them out out
there actually today but there's a new
set of buzzwords that are out there and
I think part of the problem is we claim
to be security professionals or claimed
to be the ones that know just how bad
things are I don't think we always do a
good job of explaining things in a way
that people that are the decision-makers
can
understand and make well-informed
decisions so the way I learned this
equation and the and the definitions of
the components are simply this a
vulnerability in its most basic form is
a weakness and you know there's longer
definitions but the way I think of
vulnerabilities are it's a weakness
anywhere systems people processes
technology products hardware software
it's a weakness the threats and this is
the one that's a little bit tricky the
way I learned threats our threats are
the bad guys
threats are the ones that are your enemy
they're the ones that are out to get you
they're the ones that you're fighting
against again military turns Cold War I
was at NSA during the Cold War we used
to have a threat office that would
inform us if we were gonna be doing any
kind of international travel we had to
call the threat office to find out what
the threats were in the particular
geographic region that we were gonna be
traveling and of course I had to do that
one time I was going to West Germany and
I called the threat office I forget what
year it was exactly and they said oh
yeah the threats very high there's been
rumors of some sort of terrorist
activity that's brewing something's
going to happen it was kind of like
great so what am I gonna do with this
information
well the explanation I got from my
management was well you know you just
it's good to know that so that you can
be more careful
I did not tell my wife that the threat
level was high until many years later
and I still think she hasn't forgiven me
for that you know I saw a process
weakness the threat was high what do I
do about it and not travel no I still
needed to travel anyway threats are bad
guys threats are people the way I taught
it and then countermeasures the the
mitigation it's what you do to counter
all the things that are out there in
terms of vulnerabilities and threats so
if you look back at it risk then I think
everybody understands this intuitively
but just to explain it the goal is to
reduce risk to make it lower
at its most basic level make it low
enough that you can live with it make it
low enough that as an organization
you're you're comfortable with it it's
it's rich there's and there's different
kinds of risk financial risk risk of
data loss you know you can sum it all up
in different ways but at its most basic
component it's lowering risk and to do
that and this is where I have a problem
with our industry you do it by lowering
vulnerabilities or lowering threats or
doing more in terms of countermeasures
and it seems like this whole industry or
a good portion of this industry is
focused on that vulnerability variable
as if that's the only one that can
really change it's that that's the only
one that we really have any control over
so by the way you can find this in
various versions out on the internet and
it's kind of changed names over the
years but I originally knew it as the
national information system security
glossary the InfoSec glossary this is
where I got my classic definitions from
and I wanted to share these with you
just so you know I'm not making it up so
the definition from the glossary which
was produced by NSA many many years ago
and has been adapted over time risk is
the possibility that a particular threat
will adversely adversely impact an
information system by exploiting a
particular vulnerability sounds pretty
straightforward
the threats a little bit different and
the threats a little bit more what I
hear in terms of threats today in terms
of our conversation and dialogue is in
industry which only bugs me because I
think of threats as people but threats
have become the things that happen the
things that are done to our systems the
things that are introduced to our
systems either on purpose or
accidentally so any circumstance or
event with the potential to adversely
impact impact an information system and
so on and so forth this is actually a
slide from a deck that I used over 20
years ago when I was first out in the
private sector trying to teach what I
learned about security to my
it's my customers my prospects and we
listed the threats and you can see most
of them are really people they're their
actual beings there's a couple things in
there that are events so I think threats
I think what I've evolved to is threats
are either people or events and the
events are more often than not caused by
people or at least by the in actions or
the wrong actions of people and then we
also had to talk about and we learned
about at least classically why would the
bad guys the threats want to do the
things to you
my question for you is has I think this
slide kind of stands today
it hasn't changed a whole lot I don't
know if you agree or disagree but some
again something to think about the
definition of vulnerability out of the
wall street weaknesses and information
systems weaknesses and procedure its
weaknesses in internal controls and so
on and so forth it's not just the
systems the technology it's everything
around it and anything that could go
wrong might go wrong gets lumped in as a
vulnerability and again as somebody
that's been in the business a long time
and has learned to trust certain tools
and certain programs and things over
time I pulled out some of these and now
you know vulnerabilities aren't a
vulnerability today unless they have a
logo but some of these things are
affecting systems that have been around
for 20 years that we've discovered
vulnerabilities and things that we've
trusted for vulnerabilities so it got me
to the point where I kind of thought
maybe just maybe we shouldn't think of
vulnerabilities is something that we can
manipulate as much in that risk equation
but let's get through this and we'll
talk more about that countermeasures and
finally again these are the things that
you do to sort of negate the effect or
the impact of those other components of
the equation so and it can be anything
in our context it's very often
technology we think of security products
security solutions very often they're
monitoring solutions very often there
are things that are
to detect what we would call anomalies
things that aren't supposed to be
happening or happening at different
times or anything that's out of the
ordinary that might indicate that
something's going on but my question
then is in that whole equation if risk
is some sort of a product of
vulnerabilities and threats and
countermeasures and if so much of our
industry is focused on the vulnerability
component the thought I've had for a
while that I just submit to you for
thinking about and maybe we can talk
about is what if all the stuff that
we're doing to try to drive down the
vulnerability accounts in an
organization in our organization in our
private lives if if you follow my logic
that in this equation there's three
different variables and maybe one's
called security and one's called threats
and one called
and one is called vulnerability if
there's already a variable in the
equation that's called security and it's
not vulnerabilities then what is all the
stuff that we're doing about
vulnerabilities maybe that's not
security at all maybe that's just our
job
maybe our job is to produce secure
software and applications that don't
have vulnerabilities in them maybe it's
our job to to administer systems
applications servers devices that don't
have the vulnerabilities in them
obviously its security related but maybe
it's not fundamentally what security is
so I asked the question if security is
another variable in this equation and
it's not all the stuff that we do about
vulnerabilities and it's not all the
stuff that we do with threats then what
is it it's an open-ended question
somebody laughs cliff so let's go back
to the risk equation and this one's a
little bit different and this one I've
adapted more or less for what I would
call the private sector the commercial
world when I learned risk in the DoD
basically what was at risk in one way
shape or form at the DoD level with the
military level was human life so there
was sort of this concept of there was
money with object I worked at NSA at a
time where there was huge budgets and we
got to buy everything we had we had one
of everything at least I think we had a
couple Cray computers and they were not
cheap we had source code to UNIX
operating systems before Linux ever
existed so we had the opportunity to
purchase and have source codes so we
could get into the internals of how you
early versions of the UNIX operating
system work and so on and so forth so in
the military terms that all had to do
with human life you know whether we're
protecting our military on the
battlefield whether we're protecting our
citizens at home or abroad our state
department our ambassadors whatever it
is that all loosely related and revolved
around the protection of human life
American life u.s. life but human life
in the commercial context so it's
different in the commercial context most
companies aren't out there you know
worrying about the life of their
employees or management it really has to
do with the profitability of the company
the organization it has to do with money
so new to this equation is trying to
assign some value to the data that
you're ultimately trying to protect in
this risk based model but it really
boils down to
there's the as far as the risk is again
I'm simplifying but risk in a commercial
sense is the ability for an organization
to earn revenue on the one hand and the
other risk is how much it's gonna cost
them to conduct business and that cost
then gets spread out over all the
equation
it's why this industry exists because
there's so much money out there that's
spent and there's so much money out
there to be made because every step of
the process whether you call it security
or not every element that goes into this
whole thing that we're loosely calling
risk there's a dollar cost to it so the
equation at the end of the day has to do
with how much are you willing to spend
and where to get to some sort of level
of where you think you're safe in terms
of risk and then of course if something
bad still happens are you prepared from
the cost of associated with that it's a
little bit different way of thinking
about security I think and it's it's
again it's not new but it's out there
and probably most of this intuitive ly
understand this but it's certainly a
little bit different from the dynamic of
protecting human life you know
protecting the American Way protecting
our citizens it's protecting our
profitability it's protecting our bottom
line it's it's it's it's how much or how
little we're gonna spend of our of our
profits in order to keep this business
going and that it's not bad in and of
itself it's just a different way of
thinking of things and I think it puts
things in a different perspective and I
think it's why we so often get don't
explain security to me and just tell me
how much I have to spend because they
you know people understand intuitively
at some level it's a it's a money it's a
dollars game they don't necessarily
understand that there's more to it than
that and I guess what I'm suggesting is
that maybe rather than coming up with
something continuously new and shiny and
different that we can spend more money
on in hopes of solving this overall
problem maybe we need to think more
about doing more to teach and explain
exactly what it is you're trying to
accomplish in your organization whether
it's where you work or it's the customer
that you're working on behalf of to
explain
what's the big picture what's really a
play here explain that it's about data
help companies understand what it is
that they have that's worth protecting
that needs protecting
try to figure out some value to it the
money is gonna need to be spent
somewhere along the way I guess my
contention is I think where my customers
have felt like I have helped them over
the years it's when I've helped to make
a more informed decision about their
spending not that they weren't gonna
spend the money and in PCI especially in
the early days there was a lot of
companies spending a lot of money anyway
so I go back to this this main question
first of all agreeing on the terminology
or at least understanding that there's
differences to the terminology the
components of the risk equation I guess
my frustration very often has been I
hear people in conversations especially
at conversations especially at the
vendor booths not to pick on the vendors
but I hear people using these terms like
risk and vulnerability and threat almost
interchangeably like they're synonymous
not apparently understanding that there
are different components of this overall
equation and that there's differences
between them and again ultimately it
boils down to for me and it's it's a
question that I put to you guys to think
about is if the name of the game if what
we're really doing is more about risk
then you know where does security fit in
and what is security at the end of the
day I'll give a little bit of my opinion
but I really don't want to give too much
in my opinion because I think it's
something that we should all think about
and we should all ask ourselves well
what is it that we're talking about I
hear two things very commonly when I
hear people talking about security or if
I stop and ask them what is security
I think the predominant view is a
perception that secure security or being
secure as the state that you achieve you
you make your network your systems your
applications your databases impenetrable
impervious to attack the bad guys the
hackers the pen testers the red teamers
the malware is nothing can penetrate
nothing can get to you and so that's
there's this state of being secure I
think that's the prevailing attitude
about it again my view it's a little bit
different what I see is being secured or
what security is has more to do with all
the things that you have to do after
you've done all the stuff to reduce your
vulnerabilities or to identify at least
point out what your threats are it's
things like knowing your network knowing
your systems knowing your environment
knowing the habits of your people if
it's ongoing this is one of the hardest
lessons that a lot of the customers from
PCI days have had to learn is PCI is not
a once-a-year go through all this
rigmarole to get to the finish line
where you're compliant and you have that
report produced in that standard there's
all sorts of things that you're supposed
to be doing on an hourly daily weekly
monthly quarterly ongoing basis so
ultimately I think my view of what
security is is that it's a verb it's
something that you do it's not a noun
it's not an adjective it's not a state
that you achieve arguably it's both but
I think too often we're sort of locked
up on the we got to be secure we got to
secure all things the pragmatic part of
me says well no that's not practical
nobody is ever gonna drive the
vulnerability countdown to zero hasn't
happened yet and if you're honest with
yourselves I don't think it's gonna
happen so again I'm not a mathematician
but there's probably some term for when
a variable and equation is to be treated
more like a constant if you're
mathematician you can explain it to me
later what it is but you know if it's a
constant and threats are relatively
constant what's left to do it's that
thing that you do on an ongoing basis
that's security that has
more about knowing what's going on which
means observation which means knowing
the processes the data flows doing all
sorts of things to monitor and react
that to me is what security is
ultimately you can agree with me or
disagree with me hopefully I'm just
making you think a little bit and maybe
think differently maybe not in a new way
but maybe in a way you haven't thought
of for a while our time is running up if
you're at all intrigued with what I've
been talking about you want to hear more
I am part of a podcast called Paul
security weekly I'm one of the hosts you
can tune in where we usually broadcast
every week in fact we're broadcasting
tomorrow but I'll be here so I won't be
on it and here's the escort I had at
Atlantic security conference three years
ago they had a bunch of storm troopers
dressed up here and they walked me to
the stage I'm also in a book called
tribe of hackers if you haven't heard
about it yet tribe of hackers calm it's
it's a charitable thing if you buy the
book that all the proceeds are going to
charity there's 70 people in it that are
have been recognized as people that are
innovators influencers some young some
old new different it's it's a pretty
good cross crosscut of different people
in our industry all answering the same
questions there's a set of 14 questions
and we all responded to so it's a good
book to get a hold of I'm still working
through reading at all several of the
people speakers here today or in the
book I'll leave it to you to figure out
who they are I don't know if cliff
there's a group of people that get
together with Jean Stafford once a year
at RSA conference and I was allowed to
be into that group a couple years ago
and they call themselves from an
educational perspective there's an
organization called hack for kids to put
out this educational card game it's an
interactive fantasy type trading card
game I don't play it do that stuff that
there's face cards called in hacker
anism so I'm part of that if you go to
Freaker dot life
get yourself a couple decks and the
front of the cards are all about the
history of hacking and freaking from the
70s up through the 90s so it's kind of a
good educational thing my contact
information again if you still are
interested in getting in touch with me
and finally are there any questions