alright welcome to be kind you guys have
a good time
awesome thank you guys so much for
coming my talk it's always great when i
see so many people come it's always it's
it's it means a lot to me means that you
guys appreciate a lot of the stuff that
we do but understand that
hold on i'm going to be back there we go
that much better understand
ok so now I'm going to say this but I'm
standing on the shoulders of giants
which is just about everyone in my life
because I'm so short and you know but I
jeffrey stone over and leave holes can
you to stand up real quick because I see
you guys right there can you guys give
these guys a round of applause
ok so without their work
none of the stuff that I've been doing
you know the last couple years would
actually be you know worth anything so i
have to come up with you know different
attacks or whatever the case may be so
so I really appreciate everything that
they've done I'm son of a
I've got a bracelet i got a bracelet i'm
not doing
I got a bracelet ah
wait i'm not old enough to drink
yeah I got that okay love you too Dave
I quit I can't cope sep sep sep I hate
you sorta oh em I'm not getting through
that talk if i finish that who have a
nasty
yeah anyways a little bit about me i'm
ben ten been 0xa not been AXA 10 is not
my age it was funny because they gave a
talk here last year and then shortly
after Dave called me he's like hey we
want to bring on the trust sex so now
i'm a senior
excuse me
hey you sorta senior security consultant
I'm Way more professional and come on
site by the way i would try to sex so
doing a pen testing and stuff with them
so even though I look really young I've
been doing this for quite a while I
developer for over 20 years
I actually did start programming when I
was 12 it wasn't last year you know so i
actually started writing stuff I did IT
infrastructure for 13 years did you know
defense for in a vice president for
eight and then for the last couple years
I've been doing often side i've written
a few tools Patrick framework that's
actually more people more and more
people i'm seeing actually are starting
to use it
I'm it's a defensive tool kind of like a
poor man's IDs not powershell i'm gonna
show you guys a little about this super
fun and then invoke any creds I think
I've shown some people that towards the
end if we have a little bit of time i'll
show you guys that as well but before I
get any further
jeez it's so bad i do have a special
introduction would you guys get up for
my son Joe
yeah
so so I'm all about teaching right I
love teaching and so he gets really
excited about what we do he came last
year went to the hardware hacking
village completely torn up in there came
back and he's like yeah my hacker now
and I'm like no you're not
and then he's like well show me how to
do it so i use dave's unicorn and I
should have to do it and so this is his
first shell where he not only got the
shell he migrated to win login and then
got system with NT authority so that was
his first shop so a lot of people say we
look alike and we use we like same
technology we like same things but the
difference between me and dad that I'm
supposed to be this short
yeah
you're grounded so anyways that's my
little guy somehow about this I so every
year I up into this year I've been doing
a derby contest you guys anyone ever
participate one of those where you guys
have to photoshop me into something
crazy you know so like if you do ben10
meme you know I'm there's all sorts of
fun things out there on but i decided
not to do that this year for two reasons
1i you know super busy but to the
tickets went out so fast i would I felt
bad not being able to you know to take
one of those but that doesn't mean that
y'all haven't been messing around with
me so you know like you know here even
14 hours ago I just I spall couplets
from recon aren't you are you old enough
to do that here's Joe and me on our
first airplane ride how nice the
airplane supplied you with a guardian
for your plate
jerrika and here we come
the guy in the striped shirt is bringing
his son awesome and it's so nice that
today's you can fly without an adult
present safe travel kids so this next
one is an actual perspective shot and it
was for those who are not tall you can
understand like I go to the magazine
shop and I'm like I had actually asked
the guy to get air space from the top
shelf for me and this was the only
response i got so there was an issue in
my neighborhood where you know there was
some real sketchy things going on this
car was like driving around this kid was
middle school day the kids have been in
school like it just seemed off right and
so like there wasn't anything bad going
on but I just wanted a police officer
just come by see what was going on make
sure everything was okay because I mean
it just seems odd for this kid to not be
in school so I call the police and you
know I'm like hey cheese
can I get an officer to come by whatever
like yeah sure so the officer pulls up
and i'm in my running gear because i had
just gone for a run and I roll down so i
go to walk over to tell him like the
whole situation looks amigos
shouldn't you be in school
so of course i post that is like I would
have thought is can I speak to your
parents
I mean so I got made fun of all the time
in fact we're here it really they're
like they have it doesn't ever get old
might know it's fine I'm perfectly okay
with it a lot of times i do act like a
kid so so anyways I I'm perfectly okay
with you guys making fun of how older
how old they look how short I am but
that's perfectly okay I'm big on
interaction
ok so this is not just a keynote this is
not just for me to this talk to you and
all for asking questions and I've got a
few extra drink tokens for non inane
questions
alright so the past few years we've been
talking a lot about powershell right
in fact if you were just in here with
will by the way we'll have some awesome
stickers so I'm gonna give away will
stickers warm for partial umpire you
just heard about Empire you seen a lot
of the cool stuff that's come down the
track
Carlos Perez does a great a powershell
training there's been a lot of cool
things matt grevers doesn't matter his
team will in his team and I know there's
a lot more people they're doing awesome
powershell stuff and it's happening
everywhere and a lot of technologies are
actually being very cognizant of that if
you look at a lot of your detection
mechanisms there now flagging Empire
there who's there you go back me bro
the flagon Empire their flagging other
things are looking for all of this stuff
you guys should actually start to see
that a lot of the different scenarios
right so that's fine and that's great
but I'm gonna but part of what i'm going
to talk about in this talk is how over
the last year as vendors have gotten
smarter and people have come up with
defense methodologies to try and detect
it
I've come up with ways to get around it
and so that's part of what we're going
to talk about today so I'm gonna start
with the one thing and I think
unfortunately I was running security so
I didn't get to see Jefferson and leaves
keynote but I i saw that was tweeted out
that they would talk about this a little
bit about execution policy
ok ok it's not a security control at all
okay if that's what you're using to stop
powershell it's not gonna do you any
good
so let me show you
so just to give an example here we'll go
ahead and run this administrator I
always click yes no matter what the
execution policy default right
yay so now if i do import module lets do
invoke any cards
ok boo Oh execution running positive
just you know is disabled on the system
hi got you no more bag
oh yeah right okay whatever and I hit
tab that's right there and I can boom
there you go
obviously it's it's trying to do
something that I'm demonstrate later but
that was so let me show you the command
again just here using
string with file download string you
typically would put in HTTP or HTTPS
address but file works just fine
so if you are using execution policy as
a security control stop okay it's not
doing you any good
there's actually a shorter way of doing
this as well so there's other ways that
you can actually get this now detection
obviously you're looking for IX download
string with file colon forward slash
forward slash that's going to be a good
indicator that someone's trying to
bypass some of those things right so but
execution policy is not a security
control in fact
microsoft has never said that it was a
it was to see security control i'm in
fact they actually said that it wasn't
it wasn't designed to be that way so if
you go to this blog and i'm not sure if
you guys talked about this get this
morning or not but if you go to this
blog talks about it but that's the whole
idea here right
that's not a security control and a lot
of times what I see with a lot of with a
lot of your defenses is you guys are
welcome all security you see one thing
and you try and shut it down
you see another thing and try to shut it
down and you only focus on those initial
vectors instead of looking at the attack
from a bigger point of view because no
matter what my vector is i still have to
do the same things that from on your
system so relax a little bit like yes we
want to have those controls in place but
your focus should be on those initial
vectors because every time that you shut
something down I'm getting pissed off
and I'm gonna write something new so
then this is this is what yalls kind of
reaction is you know when we're trying
to do you know anything that comes to
security or whatever
that was how you stop powershell this is
that the new full disk encryption
yeah
dude i have tried to take that the
screen off the laptop is taking me hours
that woman just ripped it off this is
the best part it wasn't her laptop
so so this next one this next one is
actually really cool because a lot of
times like you guys think everything is
fine or I'll go to the post you know to
a post-mortem or whatever and be like
how in the world did you get that now
showing the attack path and this is
typically the reaction because they
think everything is good like I got you
everything's good
ok it's not a security control
ok so part of what i'm gonna show you
today is a lot of the things that you
guys have done or that I've seen
organizations do in the middle of a pen
test and it's it's pissed me off and
then I've had to write something new
right and that's exactly what an
attacker is going to do if you are so
focused on those initial vectors and you
whack them all your security they're
just going to move someplace else
yep you know that's a great question so
you get a token here so you're gonna
block powershell that exe huh
ok
uh-huh alright let's see how that works
out for you
alright okay sounds good let's go give
that when i try so let's come over here
i think this requires a reboot
unfortunately it i'm gonna show you guys
where to actually do this but I'm not
rebooted my system is under local
security policy and it's not this you
think AppLocker is it but it's not
unless you have Enterprise I found out
the hard way after doing a class that
when you have a block around here it's
just so you can write the rules they
don't enforce them so I'm like it's
there and there's even power show
Commandments to test your rules and it
says past and I'm like yeah and then a
powershell kept opening I'm it's
actually right here
software restriction policies under
additional rules here you can come in
and say new path rule go browse and will
point to you know obviously you put into
the power show but all that being said I
decided that I was going to write
something else so I wrote not powershell
understand you can whitelist that's fine
whitelisting is fine i'll get there just
get there I'll get there all right I no
good
so this is not powershell and basically
it runs the exact same way as powershell
does so if you're looking in your lot of
your logs and you're looking for
powershot exe for a lot of your stuff
yep this is what I got I was on an
engagement and I was in the middle of
doing something now as a penetration
tester we obviously ask that like we've
got a week right so we have a week to
get things done right so I'm i want your
incident response plan to kick into
place
cool fine just don't shut me down right
and I need to finish my test let me
finish and that way you can know
everywhere else that you have to go so
I'm in this test and all of a sudden I'm
I've got a command prompt open and I try
and get a new one it said this app has
been blocked by your administrator I'm
like all right
fuck you
so then I opened up our shell and
started doing some powershell powershell
stuff and then 20 minutes later this app
has been blocked by your administrator
I'm like all right it's on
so then I grab NPS and I download it hit
whatever come back the next day and look
how did you get access to the box there
like we found this binary called NPS it
was written by this guy named ben 10 and
like me bro
then work for you did it so then i got
access to their system they're like I
hate you and like I love you too
so NPS so if you're only looking for
power show that exe it's not gonna do
you any good
yep under 41 for GM mhm yeah 4104
eventid yep yep totally because it's
actually just hooking into the
powershell library so any any of those
types of things it will do now we're
going to go into some obfuscation things
here in a little bit but it does still
log
yep absolutely so you'll still catch it
but if that's what you're doing is
trying to block powershell exe he is not
gonna work right and here's the thing
don't go and grab NPS and you like i'm
going to write a navy signature for this
guy because I released the full source
code anyone can just add a few lines or
do whatever and you're back at square
zero that's whack Amole security stopped
if how many of you guys actually thought
about blocking n PSI DX see before you
got back
good don't because I don't want AV
signatures that right it that's NPS sexy
is it's it's benign it just runs
PowerShell commands and actually power
show that exe is just a host application
it doesn't actually do the powershell
heavy lifting
it's just an interface between you and
the powershell right the power cells in
the dll so blocking it doesn't quite
work so then you're like all right okay
what about my block the ps1 fox
right right I'm just gonna block all
those ps1 files if i see i'm going to
delete them
ok sounds good let's go back to my
previous example
hold i'll make the font bigger don't
yell at me alright that's good man
you did such an air I don't know what
the error message I just click ok ok so
let's let's do this i'm going to create
new program
ok and we will save this as a test at
ps1 right are loaded we'll just do this
as test that text
ok so if i try to import module invoke
that I say that the right spot
yeah but they named it out test X did I
really good step for me did alright so
if i do say go der here's my test text
right if I try and import a module test
text
oh it's not a valid file whatever okay
boom
let's think
ok so if you're looking at ps1 files if
that's the way you're trying to stop
things that's not gonna do you any good
either
ok I can make this a WTF file I can make
this whatever file it doesn't make any
difference
ok so if you're only yep good
what do you mean by the since what do
you mean can I do something else
IEX invoke is it's an alias for invoke
expression and so that's all i'm doing
is invoking the expression and creating
a new web client client object which is
built into that net as part of dotnet
that's the way it is so if you've got
that net basically you've got windows
seven or later or whatever like you've
got this on there whether you like it or
not and then I just called the download
string function and because i connect .
at a file it'll download whatever I want
and then run it the file extension at
this point makes no difference
you could have no file extension on this
and it'll run and it'll be just fine
answer a question can you block this
don't know Jeff can we can be black
invoke expression directly in powershell
yeah I didn't that
yeah yeah you can come and grab a token
here
ok you guys see that so blocking PS ones
doesn't really do any good
right so we've got that so so let's talk
about powershell in some weird places
come on I was good at it that's it
doesn't mean I don't know if I quite
understand what that means no we've
already signed up for counseling after
we get back right so I so a couple of
different things is you can actually put
some power shell in some cool little
spots uh on different systems so one of
them is in in asp file it's not really
the powershell it's calling powershell
that exe but let's look at something
else here so let's look at this so let's
look at some csharp code did you guys
know that you can puts that good good
you good
alright so did you guys are you can put
C sharp code directly in there so you
can grab some sort of library like I
don't know and not powershell grab the
code and put it right in here so this is
C sharp code so the way to do this is
any type of assemblies that you're gonna
call you going to call that right here
and then you're going to put your code
directly in here just like you would any
type of C sharp code and so here we can
see that i'm looking into the powershell
that create whatever command you're
getting i'm adding as a script i'm
invoking it grabbing the output and
showing it to the screen i also added
some base64 encode and decode function
and they're just for the fun of it then
what you do is you check to see if your
type has been added and then if not then
you go ahead and add it with ad type so
now if i ad type and I used basically
and coding and decoding here which I'm
actually not going to do i'm just going
to do this as because you guys made me
blow this up source
I'm gonna make this a little bit smaller
there
ok so once i do that then I can actually
call NPS c-sharp run and then get date
so I'm its power shall within your power
show within your power show just because
we can so i will import oh hold on my
execution policy set let's do it this
way invoke see sure
good vs 10 sorry i was messing around
with this yesterday
yes it does we talked about tonight
change the right 1i got it here let's
try this one
let's do the what let's do though WTF
module and see if that works
I have to close this out though so that
one key is if you use this ad type you
actually have to close powershell to
clean everything out and let it back up
again you can't read if you make a
change to the code it won't actually
work
oh there you have to run everything as
administrator
it's just better to set your users up
that way
let's try this again
alright so now if I import my jewel
scripts invoke c-sharp code
ok
ps1 there you go so you guys can see it
ran might get date right that's all I
did right there and to show that it
actually works i can do like right
output right and again i have to close
any open it because i can't we add the
same type
it's just not the way it works so if I
go like this
import a module C yes i have scripts
invoke c-sharp code and folksy charm
code there we go
oh my god the 110 I changed look I
change WTF is 10
let's try to get as administrator module
cpss scripts and poor invoke c-sharp
that cuz im doing the base64 encoding
that would be a good segue so we'll get
there be kind of show up here we go
hello Erica okay so no matter what's
going on we can we can run c-sharp good
so let's see what this looks like in the
event log boobs right so now we've got
two thousand events we look through here
these are 41 of fours if you haven't
done powershell logging you should
really look into that
let's see if we can find where r
injection . was it was too there's a ton
of logs in here
yeah see it's us if you're doing this
manually it's super awesome so kind of
difficult to find but there are things
that will actually pull that up and so
you can see all of that but so let's
talk about so we've got our C sharp code
and you can maybe see that and see what
everything goes on but what happens if I
do something a little bit crazier
what happens if i go
like this and what I do is I base64
encode my C sharp code view or grab
where are you
so now here's my stats my C sharp code
now everyone's going to say oh a
powershell decodes the encoded command
well this isn't an encoded command this
is the c-sharp code that's it's in there
so when you're looking at this and when
you're expecting files you actually have
nothing to hook into so when you go to
run this is still going to run because
it's going to base64 and decode that
code but the ps1 when you load it
it's only going to show this in the oven
4104 logs so the 4100 fallen logs have
no idea what you're seeing sharp code
looks like none none now you can
manually go through and decode that what
are you gonna do that in 40,000 assets
I don't think so so that means a lot of
your tools and everything you've got
going on right now that are inspecting
these things in the 4100 fours I load my
C sharp code you have no clue what my C
sharp code is going to do nun
this is another . understand at the base
level what I'm trying to communicate
with you guys stop whack-a-mole if your
job is to try and stop the initial
vector and you're not looking at the
bigger picture that's a problem
I'm not saying don't take means to stop
it but understand there's always gonna
be someone who's going to come up with
something else to bypass that you're not
going to have that insight you guys read
Casey's blog about ms build oh you guys
you need to google that so ms build is
actually pretty awesome its installed on
just about every windows box if not
every windows box and you can actually
take C sharp code time I said hi
you can actually take C sharp code and
actually run it and it'll adrian has
going
boy
so you can actually so you can I Adrian
so you can actually take C sharp code
and put in ms build so that's something
that you'll want to look at as well
I what I want to do next is you know
talk about antivirus right right yes no
it's just that once you close but
everything's gone
it's there's nothing there it's all
within this namespace that it's created
not the name sweet but the run space so
it's all within that self-contained
situation
yep so I haven't looked into that it's
the question was is there any other
opportunity for DLL injection I don't
know so i actually just wrote what I'm
about to show you guys here in a little
bit last night my hotel room so i'm
gonna show you guys something that I
think is actually really cool but let me
talk about a be as well
antivirus . it right that's awesome
Matt greater stuff even will show
there's a lot of their stuff we're
getting picked up Dave's stuff got
picked up and it was it was like
powershell that exe no profile and Cody
command right this right right you know
what he did to that bypass AV he did
this done he just changed DNC to encode
command right so and i'm not saying
don't have a baby i'm not saying that's
a great control but that's not the
control that you need to be focusing on
with these types of attacks
ok it's too easy to do the apps
obfuscation and look like you're not
going to inspect this there's no I mean
unless you're going to hire someone to
go through and monitor all the event
logs looking for base64 encoded stuff
and then reverse engineering and looking
through the c-sharp code of which will
probably be obvious cated anyways that's
going to be a problem right
so that's not gonna do you guys that's
not going to be the focus that you guys
need it need to need to go about because
we're gonna come up with different ways
to bypass that so let me show you
another cool little thing so a lot of
you guys are looking for this like this
system that reflection like if we call
these libraries right you guys have seen
these right these are some basic
indicators of PowerShell Empire power
supply and everything else like that so
if you look for you know system .
convert you know to base64 string you
know whatever you know it basically will
give you the binaries and that and so
what you're doing isn't a lot of your
searching you're looking for you get
okay you're looking for this right so
let me show you something cool you can
actually do something like this
so what you do is you build your string
system . text encoding and then you use
type with the type name then you can
call the library which is t1 so now
instead of me calling those libraries of
what you're looking for
I'm calling t1 and t2 so you guys are
checking it so let me show you what this
looks like
I know some people taking pictures so
waiting so if I import module invoke
type if I invoke type
there we go and if we look at the event
log
there's are invoked type if we look at
this this is what we're looking for so
we loaded our code it didn't change that
it didn't change it to the actual
library so even when you're looking at
your 10 fours it's not pulling up those
libraries you can do the same thing with
reflection you can do the same thing
with any . netlibrary you do the string
cast type you're not looking for those
libraries it's gone you don't have
inside any longer
right now I'm a defender at heart i love
being able to defend so what's my point
right
why am i doing all of this stuff to yet
you know further along you're weakening
our ability to detect things the problem
is you guys are still whack Amole you
focus out no matter what what way I get
into your system
I'll get you in just a second no matter
how I get on your system I still have to
do the same things I still have to pivot
i still have to get users i still have
to inspect the traffic that's not going
to change
you're still gonna be able to see all of
that there are other ways of blocking
all of the or detecting a lot of the
other stuff that I'm that I'm doing
after the effect but i see so many
people focusing on these individual
attack vectors that they're missing the
bigger picture
they're missing the bigger idea that the
debt if i use PowerShell to get on your
system
ok so what I might use outlook tomorrow
who knows
I'm sorry who had a question back there
yeah yet so it's just blanks getting
this
but i didn't use encoded oh you're
saying the a B and C nc2 encoded right
well right
but if you look at empire so i can I do
a lot of my Empire and I don't use the
uncoated i just use a straight function
and that's what I love about empires
that gives me that straight function
that I can copy and paste in there now
there are tools that are actually
picking that up and its really cool but
again it doesn't take much to just
obvious get that that the point is I'm
not trying to say don't try and detect
this stuff i'm trying to say change your
defensive methodology and i'm showing
you new techniques need ideas things
that I've been doing for the last year
that i haven't shared with anyone right
and there might be other people that are
already doing these types of things it's
just this is the way that I've done them
and I've got around a lot of different
systems and it's pissed a lot of people
off but i don't like to lose
so you can do that so I'm going to skip
ahead i just want to show you that
picture so what I did last night i was
really excited last night I know ya go
i'm sorry go ahead
yep yep yep yep so his point was if I go
in using easy attacks and you know just
start using like cut-and-paste like I'm
blasting and you're absolutely right and
that's a great indicator problem eyes
and I'm not saying don't use those tools
we have great vendors out there right
I've been on some systems where y'all
have pissed me off because you keep
shutting things down or you get detected
and I take it personally so I write new
tools right so if you want a new tool
just pissed me off and i'll write
something new and we'll talk about it
after become next year
right and that's great and you might but
here's the thing if my goal is to get in
there my goal is not to get detected
I'm not going to go the path that you're
expecting me to go right I'm gonna go
through and I'm gonna base64 encode my
base64 encoded stuff right and you're
not gonna catch that on the stream
because your watch list that you've got
four carbon black and all of your other
things you're not picking up on it
because it's not gonna match any of your
regex queries that you've got going on
there unless you're inspecting every
single PowerShell command that you're
running on your system
it's not gonna happen right and that's
the whole idea you can use the MS build
to run the powershell code itself as
well or I can just use ms builder do a
c-sharp code which does the next thing
i'm about to show you
so one of my problems was on an
engagement was you know getting access
to the machine and getting that
persistence and getting things to run so
i got not powershell but the the point
was i didn't want anyone to know that
not powershell was there I had to get it
to the system to run it but I didn't
want to touch disk so here's what I did
here's what i did last night and
literally i'm sitting in the hotel room
after I got here i'm sitting in the
hotel room and all the Sun was oh my
goodness and just like what Dad I'm like
oh my goodness he's like that are you
okay let me go oh my goodness it worked
he's like you're weird so i want to show
you something cool invoke memory not
powershell
I'm able to download NPS from my remote
resource and run it directly from memory
without a touching disk
so let me show you how this works so
this is again this is just using that C
sharp code that i showed you earlier
again I could base64 encode this as i
showed you earlier right so you guys are
gonna be able to see this code this is
my payload so this is from unicorn
okay now I'm gonna double-check my
shells I've got going on here and I will
be putting this out on my github later
so we look at options to make sure my IP
hasn't changed by the way that stinks
when you're trying to like doing exploit
and your IP changes in your be that's
really annoying
okay so I'm gonna exploit this hold on
one second okay cool so that's running
so if this works and i'm gonna run this
not from an administrator just normal
powershell ok and I'm going to open up
the task manager I'm gonna leave it
running on top we're going to look and
make sure that NPS isn't on here
ok so no NPS right you guys are with me
and PSD XD doesn't exist but i will show
you that it's sitting right here on my
web server
I've got Apache running so so there's my
apache server running right there
ok you guys are all with me right you
understand so if we look at my IP here
to 137 and in my code i'm pulling down
from hoops because it's on time sorry
hold on i'm pulling down from here you
guys with me so that I load the binary
oops
oh my goodness stop it
so I load the binary and then I inject
the payload so here's so you can look
here's my hyphen enc which is part of NP
SDXC and then I give it the payload so
if this works we should get a shell
let's just do it the fun way
ok so we're looking right here i'm gonna
put this down here you guys know you can
turn sounds on a medically you get much
voice on there especially when it fails
he goes dry hada let's see if this works
and our expert works and if we look no
NP SDXC it's all a memory
yes sir
yes he said he might even mr. robot
attack absolutely he got that for me you
guys see and you guys understand the
point I'm trying to tell you this is not
be coming around saying its fuel to do
defense that is not what I'm saying at
all in fact there's a lot of
organizations I've been to that I have
been so frustrated because they did
defense well because they didn't care
about my initial attack vector they
expected me to be there
they're like yeah we know you're on the
Box it's okay keep going I'm like I'm
not even my final form yet bro and then
they're like yeah we saw your pivot we
saw you log into 47 different boxes
understand the attacking with that
mentality when you understand the
attackers mentality you're not so
focused on that initial vector you're
more concerned about what to do after it
a lot of you guys are looking for the
right things
some of you guys aren't don't even know
for some of the basic stuff you guys
know about this one
do you know that this is this is like
awesome for me to get this to anyone
know what this does this download
everything from a system and tells me
every kb that you have then what I do is
I use a tool called windows exploit
suggest ER and it tells me which kb you
don't have and not only that it tells me
if there's a Metasploit module or
exploit code available so ms 15-0 51 a
lot of you guys haven't patched you know
what that is that's a privilege
escalation and a lot of you guys on a
lot of systems that that's that we have
it so when you're looking for things
understand i have to get around your
network
I need to know your users I need to know
what's going on so I shown us a couple
of times but I know I don't think I've
shown it here at Derby but i want to
show you guys real quick you got her a
responder right cool tool right I'm just
gonna exit here quick responders are
really neat tool
so for those who don't know responder is
basically a tool that if you do any type
of request and it doesn't have a dns
entry it will actually respond to those
hence the name responder it's just or
don't worry
here we go and so exploitation responder
oh I need to shut down patchy hold on
okay i don't care about the ssl port
ok so basically it's just going to sit
there and respond so if i come over here
and I type net use a snowbird at local
Lee homes
that's his actual login ID
let's see so you'll see that I get a
poison answer for snows in that local
and when it does that i'm actually going
to grab at ash so you'll see that here
in a second so you see that the command
completed successfully snowboard at
local doesn't exist at least I don't
know unless Jeff is hacking me at the
moment
okay right so it's not there so so the
thing about it is is that this shows up
and it basically shows the hash that
goes on and and obviously I have a
previously captured captured cash for it
for some reason so what I want to do is
I want to check to see if i have an
account here in fact let me do this
remove responder DB and let's do it
again and that way i can actually show
you that you can actually see here's a
hash it comes through
don't worry you guys try and crack that
it's just password it's all good
ok so i have to craft this I can't use
this in the past the hashtag attack i
have to actually crack this
so what I did is I wanted to know how i
can actually detect this because if I'm
on your network on one of the first
thing I'm gonna do is I'm gonna see if I
can get credentials from somebody else
so what I did is I wrote a tool called
invoke any creds and what honey creds
are is credentials that actually get
injected into the network and it's in a
completely different name space so what
I do import module invoke honey threads
so when you say invoke honey creds it
will ask you for a password
now this is actually hooked into the
windows 7 or the windows credentialing
system so it's not some I didn't just
pop up a box this is actually good to do
then what you do is you create valid
looking credentials not user-based
service-based so if i do this and if i
do lead at local SCCM updater service
and I gave it a decent-looking password
maybe something that actually random you
know something like a lot of our service
accounts look like
yes no
ok so as we can
see there's our SCCM service update and
then look so I do two things with any
creds the first thing i do is i send you
the hash but then i also sent in plain
text because if your attacker and you've
got a hash that you have to crack or you
get plain text which one you going to
use first plaintext and with the cool
thing about honey Craig's is this
account does not have to exist and the
moment that responder response you get a
200 ok on this side and you know you
have somebody using responder on your
network and the best way to check for it
is event ID log 4648 right down
4648 that is how you detect somebody
using the set of credentials on your
network
what do you think cool
alright so I know I'm running out of
time so you guys can get a lot of the
stuff
minot powershell and honey creds are on
github a full open source you guys can
do whatever you want with that Jerry
Jackson has done some great stuff on the
defense side i encourage you use his
stuff we also you have pot check with
matt johnson myself some really neat
tools a lot of people have contributed
to that i'll let you guys take some
pictures
it is also on my Twitter it's a it's
pinned up there so you guys can do that
so in conclusion that's it I'm done
questions yes can I use PowerShell
bypass net nanny I think that's a
conversation for us later
alright guys thank you very much
appreciate it and i have i have free
stuff up here so you guys want to come
talk to me going to be some way to