okay so um technical difficulties with
the slides in the resolution so everyone
just bear with me here but thankfully i
know the slides by heart so it shouldn't
be that much of a problem so hope you're
all having a good day become so far I'm
just do this so there was gonna be a
dope logo there as you can see there's
nothing now but we're gonna be talking
about active directory
we're going to be talking about a tool
that I wrote called crack map exact and
I've been maintaining for the past year
or so now and just two things before i
start out one this is my second time
talking to a fairly large audience so if
i do anything weird or just act
awkwardly just go with it
second the main theme we're going to
talk about active directory from a
fairly offensive side there is going to
be a fairly demo heavy talk hopefully
the demos won't fail them gods be with
me and um we are also with the theme
that I wonder that I want to convey here
is that is what you would be seeing
underneath the the title of the slide
here which is owning active directory
using Active Directory so if you've been
in the fantastic space for a little
while now you probably have heard the
term living off the land right so
basically using built-in Microsoft tools
feature sets protocols and using them
against them and using a minute against
themselves for testing purposes and post
exploitation purposes and this is really
the main theme that see amy was built
upon it
it's been built one completely about
around this main theme so everything
what I'm about to show you again if the
demos don't fail is doing exactly that
there is nothing that's going to be done
that's out of the ordinary in Active
Directory environment
and this is where i would show you who
the obligatory when my slide but I'm so
I work for coal fire labs and my hands
by pleader I'm if you seen some of the
projects that i've been working on i'm a
pretty open source guy i've been working
on a number of projects that hopefully
you can see that that is my github
profile that is my pgp on key base just
in case you want to send me something
and with all things so what is this
thing and up with this with the name
ok so this is a ad pen testing tool this
should be helping you during your
internal assessments it should be
helping you saving a lot of time it went
missing after directory environments
you're probably wondering okay why do we
need yet another one of these tools i'll
explain that in a second
the name is really awkward
this is awesome ok I'm so yeah so
basically see me was based off of these
three tools which again really hard to
see but anyway credit crack SMB map &
SMB exact so these three tools are is
what see me was based off of crack if
you're familiar with it at all
I basically automated executing Mimi
cats on huge environments there was some
implementation issues with that in some
configurations issues with that and
that's what inspired the mainly the
cme's main many cats functionality SMB
map is another tool that came out fairly
recently actually had the pleasure
meeting sean at black hat for the first
time and fun fact was that see any
actually started out as a pull request
to the SNP map project and I just
started hacking on the code and at the
end of a rage code session i just had
something that was completely different
than us in that project so i decided to
start my own little project and then SMB
exactly exactly is pretty much the up
that's much better actually
hope everyone was hearing me
SMB exact I was the is and still is
probably the go-to tool when it comes to
80 pentesting although it does stuff
that i like to call it the pre
powershell arrow way of doing things
such as uploading binary the biscuit
uses windows credentials letter which
i'm not even sure anyone uses that
anymore and it does a lot of stuff that
we don't need to do anymore because
powershell and it's black magic that
enables us to inject arbitrary p add
binary into memory and a whole other
sleuth of things that we don't we can do
a lot more stealthily and as pen testers
we should be striving to do that emulate
real attacks and to give more valuable
to custom value to customers so title
here says I have 99 problems not 99 or
eight problems just FYI
so these eight problems features that i
wanted in a ad tool was a large network
so how many times have you just been
dumped on a large network as a pen
tester and the client goes ok you can
you have to now test this hundred
thousand host network but you only have
a week to do it and good luck with that
like that's that's something that you
know it's going to be fun but it's gonna
take a lot more time than a week at
least at least for me right
and so I wanted something fast i need
something preferably with concurrency
which is not something that previous
tools have done well especially python
tools the built-in threading module and
Python isn't actually concurrency and
this is a point of confusion for a lot
of people that's more concurrent
multitasking which is it completely
different thing
concurrency is actually doing multiple
things at the same time while concurrent
well concurrent multitasking is doing
the same thing across multiple threats
so it's a very different aspect that
it's a point of confusion and see me
kind of solves that by using a
third-party library called G event in
Python which is probably the closest
thing that you'll ever get to
concurrency when it comes to python only
from what I understand and python 2.7
that is the second point of this kind of
useless showing slides at this point but
credential overload so if you've ever
been on a large network the amount of
credentials that you get once you
establish your initial foothold just
increases exponentially from one house
to another
I'm not a statistician or mathematician
and in fact i suck at both of those
things but if you actually did the graph
i bet it would be a quasi exponential
curve and I needed something that would
help me with that right so I need
something to easily correlate specific
credentials to specific resources and
vice versa so that i can easily and
quickly access now just figure out which
credentials I needed to access specific
resource third one is situational
awareness so powerview how many of you
have heard of Power View I bet every
they have pretty much everyone I guess I
so i need i wanted to integrate a lot of
the power of your functionality and I
actually done that by writing a module
system with the modular system which
will get into later and later i'm
actually break up with the fourth one is
but judging by the tion okay well we'll
skip that nature so and the fifth one is
stealth living off the land which is
basically the main theme that see me was
built upon and the 61 is external tools
if you're familiar with SMB exact in any
way you should be aware that it seems
actually uses the passing the hash
toolkit in the back end to perform all
of its tough and if you're using a
custom pentest OS which I know a lot of
you do i do in particular I don't use
cali it's such a pain in the ass to
compile those tools it's not even funny
and actually i have not gotten them to
compile from source even once
so I didn't want anything with external
tools i wanted something that was just
pure python and I wanted it to be the
glue between metasploit and empire so
with that what i mean by that is easily
lobbying shallows between both
frameworks and sharing credentials
between both frameworks bi in on
internal assessments i usually use a
combination of both frameworks just
because the pros of one the day both
have pros and cons and using both kind
of outweighs that those feature sets so
I wanted somebody to easily lob shells
between frameworks and share crackles
between frameworks and the 61 I forget
so we will just get that pic so
thankfully because a lot of people and a
lot of time was invested in other
libraries and projects i didn't have to
start from scratch so I'm just a guy
that just came along and sort of put the
pieces together
thankfully i did not have to start from
scratch at all and these these are the
projects that in theory help me anyway
ok so impact it impacted if you you
should be using impact on every internal
assessment if you're not you're doing it
wrong in my opinion
alberto sordi know which is the guy that
develops it is pretty much a God in my
eyes like I have no clue how keep does
it impact if you're not familiar with
its a library and it comes with a lot of
example scripts that just helps so much
during internal pet contest and kind of
abstracts a lot of the low level
protocols that acting director uses the
second one is a power supply which
proved sure that everyone's familiar
with powers . so i wanted a way of
integrating powersport framework inside
of this tool
and the third one is many cats which
again I don't need to explain we cats
it's pretty much should be used on every
internal assessment so this is a heavy
demo talk demo gods in the past have
been really bad to me so hopefully these
will work this time but we're going to
be simulating a mock contest and usually
getting an initial foothold on a Windows
Active Directory network is that isn't
that hard at all the way my preference
is using SMB relaying which is another
point of confusion ID credentials that
you get with responder those you don't
you don't need to actually crack those
hashes you can just rely them and this
is something i don't think a lot of
people know that ntlm v2 you are able to
realize those hatches without cracking
them and you can do this by really
quickly because this is could be a whole
nother talk on its own you can do this
by turning off the SNB HTTP and https
server that responder has in its
configuration file and then using a real
laying tool I my preferences ntlm relay
that X that the pie which is a example
script that comes with the impact
library and you can use that in
combination with responders just pop
shells from every credential that you
really like and it's awesome but um for
the live demo which we will get to now
for a live demo we're going to be we're
gonna just the company that we're going
to attack we're just gonna pretend that
it's got everything locked out like that
it hasn't be signing enabled so you
can't rely hashes it has every it
doesn't have any multi-gas burkhard
broadcast protocols enabled so you can't
use responder you've tried like
passwords spraying or whatnot doesn't
work and it has everything pache so they
got shit lockdown and you can get
initial foothold but let's pretend that
you did some emotions just like
certainly and you found
and a couple of Active Directory user
names on the web right so my first
approach in that case would be password
spraying so we're just gonna do that
so once you install see me which if you
go to project page there's the
installation guide right there you're
able to invoke it using the CMP command
visit everyone see that by the way is
that don't need to increase the font
yes it's good a bigger fun ok cool to do
that real quick go all the way to 25 ok
this that help is that better
ok everyone see cool ok so i invoke the
actual program either by using cme or
the full name crap exact which is
awkward as hell i know a kind of like
the awkwardness to be frank and the
first thing that I do is just scan the
the subject but I'm attacking right so
I'm book see Amy and I give it the
subnet of the network
ok so thought is big and the resolution
sucks so just go with it
so the output gives you the IP of the
host and the hostname and since you can
actually get OS domain and host name
information without any credentials
whatsoever
it shows you that on the rest of the
line so you can see here that we have
three machines in this domain domain is
called lab we have a windows 613 box
which is a witness to 2012 we have a
windows 6.1 box which windows 7 and
windows 10 box which is windows which is
Windows 10 and the host names are named
appropriately
so let's say that in this mock pentest
you found Bob right Bob is username and
we want to get initial fold so we will
try password spring so see me out of the
box supports that by just passing
multiple username and passwords as
command line arguments with the dash you
and HP flag you specify the username and
password respectively
you can also specify a file containing
those usernames and passwords but for
just for convenience sake specified on
the command line so Bob and we get it
password one and I don't know change me
and password 123
so again resolution Sox apologize for
that but you can see here that the cma
automatically brute forced the
credentials and we prefer to crimes with
which you provided so i tried logging in
with password one change my password 123
and we see we have a successful
authentication with password 123
so Bob really sucks at creating
passwords and were able to authenticate
to all the machines in this is a valid
domain accounts were able to
authenticate to domain
the problem is bob is in a is just a
regular old user doesn't have admin
access so
oh we can't really do much at this point
and one thing that I want to underline
is that seems very much a post
exploitation tool so you can't really do
much with it without a set of
credentials in the first place so we
know that Bob is password is password
123 and we're just going to target one
well actually just going to target the
whole subnet at this point and we're
going to pass it the dash dash shares
argument which is going to enumerate all
the available shares on all the hosts
that we can authenticate to and
and so so on the windows 10 box we have
available shares you have the sea admin
IPC usual and they all seem usual and
the thing that you'll notice here is
that he actually tells you the
permissions that you have on those
shares so it's a really quick and easy
way of identifying what you can access
this way so see that we have no access
to the admin share here we have read
access to ibc which will give us nothing
and everything is kind of standard
except for the windows seven box which
has a share called all the stuff and we
have read access to it so bob has read
access to the share on this machine so
let's take advantage of that right so
see me has built-in spidering support so
we can spider both the files on that
chair but we can also spider the content
of those files on that share and this is
really handy when you have like multiple
word docs on a share and you want to be
able to spider word docs are essentially
zip files with xml Adam and you see me
is able to actually parse those in and
like search for specific pattern or reg
reg ex so I'm just going to specify the
password and with the dash spider option
we tell it to start spotting sorry
Oh perfect and I was going to tell the
share and I think that was one lying to
think it was 12 so we're not gonna
spider every host on the subnet we just
want a spider one you can actually do
that by the way if you wanted the spider
every host a subnet you can do that the
cma because it's just truly it's almost
truly concurrent
I'm just about to share so and a pattern
so I'm just gonna look for pass here and
hopefully it doesn't look that bad from
what you're seeing but you can see that
we successfully authenticated to share
over here using those specified
credentials we started spidering and we
found one file on the share called
password that txt now we can pull down
that file but i can just for interest of
time because we have a lot of conduct to
go through that Pat that the text file
doesn't actually contain credentials
it's just a just a random text file
without credentials so this time I'm
going to actually spider the contents of
the files on that chair and see if we
have any hits you can see we have a
second hit this time and password that
txt always shows up because it does in
this case at the spider the filename it
is search for the pattern the filename
and in the contents so in the first hit
we have passed that THC which was before
and the second hit we have cooking the
txt which as you can see the file name
has makes no sense whatsoever if you
actually want to open that up
it does have credentials in it and
specifically you can see here that the
output shows you so I at offset 75 we
have the match for the pattern password
and in this case that file again in the
interest of time I would usually pull it
down but that file has credentials for
the user Tom so we have another set of
credentials at this point that we can
use and test against the Active
Directory network that we are investing
so Tom and just going forward I just
want to put this in here because it's
just I find that I have a very weird
sense of humor so these are actually
password that i found on gigs just
during internal assessments so Tom here
as the password that 69 pickles and
we're gonna try that we're going to
authenticate to the whole subnet using
those credentials so it's a valid
credentials set you can see here that we
authenticated successfully to all three
machines but if you notice here on the
windows 10 machine we have this little
pwned flag that gets appended to the
authentication and what that means is
that this credential set has admin
access over that host so this is a
really quick way of determining which
credential set which could be granted
that you just pillage from anyone from
whichever method you want a hat which
has admin access over that hosts and
this is where the real fun begins with c
me because once you have admin access
over that hosts you can use the modular
system you can execute commands so we
have admin access over the windows 10
box which is at eleven of oracle
correctly yes said 11 so before we do
anything really noisy let's just do some
really quick recon and see what we can
we get from the box at eleven so what I
like doing is first we had already
eliminated the shares so we can try in
rating logon users and you can see that
there aren't any log on users which is
normal because my pm's correct
let's just open that up real quick
you're performing an interactive logon
here so you actually see that it's
integrating logon users and again all of
this is using built-in all this is being
performed using win32 api calls so if
you actually want to analyze all this
traffic you wouldn't see anything out of
the ordinary but the main traffic so tom
is now logged on and we knew Mary logon
users and you can see that this time tom
was over there hopefully that's not that
bad but tom is log on to that machine we
can also see if there any sessions there
aren't any sections so no active
sessions on that machine but what we can
do is we can use a payload module so see
me influence a concept called peeler
models which are basically just
powershell payloads that are custom made
to do certain things on host that you
have admin access to so in this case I'm
going to use the power view hill module
and I apologize again but power
repealing module which is basically just
a wrapper for all of the Power View
functions and what this does is but so
first of all let's execute the module so
i'm specifying with the dash and the
capital FM flag the module I want to run
and what this does really quickly
is it hosts the power view that ps1
powershell script locally over https I
then execute a powershell i x-rayed on
locust brush and cradle to download that
powershell script in memory and then
execute without whichever command that
we specify so in this case I we're going
to specify get net
group member i recall correctly that's
the correct part of your function
oh yes that's correct thank you
so I can specify that so what is going
to do it's going to go out its gonna
execute a powershell one-liner over wmi
and then it's going to pull down the
powershell script over HTTPS and it's
going to execute that command that we
specified so you can see here that we
got a call back so the host successfully
pull down the powershell script and it
posted back again over https so this is
a completely encrypted channel it posted
back the result of that our view man and
you can see here that the group name is
domain admins so we enumerate
successfully all of the domain admins in
the environment using power view and we
have two members of the domain admins
group we have palace
it's a year and the edges standard
administrative domain admin account so
we have some situational awareness
already we can also just directly
execute without using the payload module
system we can just directly execute
commands since we are we have admin
access to this host so say we wanted to
execute ipconfig using the dash X flag
we can just execute standard commands
and all of this is being performed
completely filus so the standard the
default method of execution for cme it
supports is w my it does support other
mixes methods of execution which are
similar to PS exact
and eighty exact which BTW exact is
basically way of executing commands
through windows task scheduler but the
standard method of execution of simi is
a wmi so you can see here that we
successfully executed the ipconfig bang
and this is the output for that host so
let's say we wanted to do something now
a little bit more noisy I see me comes
with a meanie cats module and it does
exactly what it sounds like
so it's just basically downloads me cats
in memory and execute it and post back
the output via a PhDs you can see here
that it's kind of the way the https
servers implemented its kind of smart it
won't exit out until all of the host
that executed a command on will post
back their output so we've successfully
executed me cats on this host and we
have three hits and i have no clear no
really confused why it gave us
credentials here because it's a Windows
10 box and shouldn't have either clear
check with Exponential's but ok I'll
just go with it and so we have a hash
for user Tom and we have the password
for user Tom as expected you can i'm
just gonna skip ahead here but just to
show you how fast this is
I've it's not recommended but I have
once or twice
meerkats the / 24 and it's it's not it's
noisy but it's actually pretty fast so
if i wanted to execute me Kat I'm just
gonna use the domain admin password here
and again this is another real password
that i found so pound of kicks ass
and licks but yep and may use different
this creatively password is create a
password on the / 24 I'm going to excuse
me cats on all three boxes at the same
time and I mess something up on the room
so let's try it again and kicks
oh yes there you go thank you sir
yes that worked thanks um ok well it
worked on
yeah it worked so we've executed a
Democrats on all three hosts so we got
two and two call back so far and this is
the credentials for the Windows Windows
10 box and this is the crunches for the
windows seven blocks and we should also
be getting transferred from the domain
controller yes there they are so we've
executed many cats on three hosts at the
same time and under what that was like
10 5 10 seconds so we have had not going
back to the pen test mark pentas we have
admin access to in the sandbox we want
to try to move laterally now at this
point so the most common configuration
that I find on domain networks are local
administrator passwords that are the
same between multiple computers and
either those were pushed out be a new
policy or whatever that is the most
common configuration that I find and i'm
going to use Tom again and I'm going to
specify the dash Sam flag and this guy's
what you think it does it just dumps the
local Sam database from the machine
the note is that one okay so you can see
here that we've successfully dumpy Sam
hashes from the windows 10 machine and
this is the administrator the local
administrators password hash right let's
see if I again
yeah okay that should work so now since
I've dumped the Sam hashes from the
windows 10 machine i'm going to try and
authenticate locally with that
administrator password hash the rest of
the machines to see if thats that
mosquito ms configuration in that
environment is actually the case so user
name administrator and we're gonna with
the dash a capital H flag we specify the
local administrator hash theory yes
there it is that's d just a ntlm hash of
that account and i'm going to pass the
bash Dash local flag which will tell it
to authenticate locally to every machine
instead of domain wide and see what
happens and we have oh yes that's
correct that's oh yeah and this we don't
need which is why aired out
ok so that again so you can see with
this account we have now admin access to
another host before we had an axis only
windows 10 windows 10 machine now we
have admin access to windows 7 machine
because they configured the local
minister accounts with the same password
between multiple machines so now we can
execute payload modules on that machine
too so if i wanted the execute me cats
on the windows 7 machine let me just log
into that real quick because this
stop working ok cool so I'm logged in
now and I can now use the admit this
local administrator password hash to
execute against again and work because
specify cash local ok so let's see we
successfully pass the hash authenticated
locally to both of those machines and we
have credentials now I'm both of those
machines so here the password for Alice
now again I'm just showing up i'm
showing you this on three vm because i
have a laptop and for demo purposes this
is fine but you got to do something / 24
12 / 16 although not recommended and it
would probably be pretty fast
by default see any spins up a hundred
concurrent threads you can specify more
threads if you're if you want to do a /
16 with the dash T option so you can
specify maybe like him in like 2 or 500
concurrent threads if you want to but
yeah it is pretty fast and this is now i
want to tell you a little bit about the
database so everything that we've done
so far now has been passively log to the
database and see any ships with a
command line program called see me TV
and i'm running extremely late so cmed
is just a client interface to the
backend database of cma and if you're
all familiar with Empire or metasploit
you should feel at home here with
credentials with the credits command it
just shows you all the credentials that
you used so far and going back to the
three
like the eighth features that that I've
always wanted to see in one of these
tools I this pretty much does it so you
can see here that it automatically logs
all the credentials that used so Alice
the domain administrator password at the
main administrator account that we used
before I has admin access on three hosts
so it automatically tells you it
automatically logs the admin access of
each account so Tom here's at Max's over
one host and so on and so forth and if
you specify the actual account with the
credits command it shows you which host
is that it has admin access on so Alice
here no wrong one
so Alice here has admin access to these
three machines so this is if you're if
you've done a deep investing in the past
this should be a hell of a time saver
just because it allows you to quickly
correlate the credential set to specific
resource that as admin access to and
vice versa and every host that CMV
touches is also logged as well perform
this correlation so if we specify if we
ran the host command these are all the
machines that we've touched so far so
the domain controller windows 10 box in
the sandbox and it shows you that ok
the domain controller has one
credentials with admin access to it and
so on and so forth and with this is a
new feature actually which I've just
implemented so if you rent run the
meerkats a pillow module on machines it
actually shows you from what machine you
pillage that credential from so here
politics with a resolution again you can
see that the host ID from which the this
credential was taken from his number
three so if i want to find out which
host is number three edges to host three
and you can see that that was taken from
the windows seven box so again for
reporting purposes and just for
long-term engagements this should be a
time-saver so I'm see me comes with a
bunch of modules which because what I'm
running so late on time i will show you
just really quickly and this font is
really small but we're going to go with
it really quickly that you can actually
get shells on a / 24 either using Empire
or metasploit using see me
so if we use the domain add admin
password again want to do that
oh nice try . and because if i can just
see if I have this in my yes
cool ok so the Met inject module and
this does what it sounds like
so it directly inject meterpreter into
memory using powershell and specify the
module using the dash and flag and we
specify the host using a dash of black
so it accepts our intimate a child
module can accept arguments and you can
specify them using the key value style
like msf venomous you're familiar with
it so ls VL host would be 192 168 that
wants you to that one and the old port
would be 8443 ok that should all work I
over here
I don't want to restart the metasploit
instance but we have a reverse https
handler setup and we have no sessions
currently active
and I don't want it around three
ok so we successfully executed the
initial payload launcher on all three
machines and this is going to call back
and download invoke shellcode at ps1
script which is part of the power supply
framework and if we go back here we have
received we already are getting shells
Amy's the second shelf from the domain
controller in the first shell from the
windows 7 machine just to show you that
I'm not lying i think yes and that's the
third shell coming in right now so she
wanted to you could just pop shelves on
$MONTH / 24 how cool is that
and you can do the same thing with
Empire so this is I have three or four
minutes so really quickly
this is if you're familiar if you've
ever used to in the past this is just a
bog-standard functionality that comes
with the new feature that I will be
releasing after this talk is module
training so really quickly
this allows you to chain as the name
implies multiple modules together and we
can do crazy stuff using this technique
like using a blocker bypasses so if
you're familiar with sub t know if he's
in the audience or not but if you are i
owe you a drink but he's come out with a
gazillion a pocket bypasses and you
should definitely follow on twitter and
I've implemented a lot of his bypasses
ncme so with the new flag dash MC we can
actually change modules together using a
specific syntax that i will be
documenting after this
yes yes it it will be after this so I'm
there's another modern see me called com
exact and what this does is it uses a
calm scriptlet to bypass AppLocker and
you can run commands using this method
on a fully on a windows machine using a
blocker so i'm going to use this bypass
to execute many cats so the syntax i
would show you the slides but as you
previously saw it's probably not a good
idea so it's this this is probably this
is the best way I could figure out how
to implement this I'm totally open the
suggestion so if anyone else has a
better way of doing this please let me
know but currently we do you specify the
module name and if you two to indicate
that you want to change the module you
just do a little ass quiero
representations of the equals greater
than sign and then specify the second
module that you want chain into so we're
going to be executing an app Locker
bypass which will then execute many cats
on the host and yes you're absolutely
correct glad you are all paying
attention so we have now for callbacks
because again this chain the modules
together so I'm you can see we have
already occurred just kidding and so the
first callback that we have is that SCT
file which is the conscript that
actually execute many cats then we
actually get a callback for the invoke
me cat script so we successfully
bypassed AppLocker and we've executed
many cats on the host and currently this
system only support so in theory this
should work just indefinitely with a
complete undefined amount of modules so
if i wanted to for example from this app
Locker bypass change into another module
that supports chaining so rundll32 exact
and Mimi cats i could do that as well
me for a reason unknown to me yet
there's a bug which only allows you to
have to chain two modules together but
i'll be working on that and the idea is
that you'll be able to change a infinite
number and chain and infant infinite
number of modules together so that you
can really quickly and easily automate
these bypasses and back post
exploitation techniques
there's also for example a UAC filus you
AC bypass which was released i think a
month ago at this point using the event
viewer matin event your work program
which is standard in CA me and I don't
think I'm people to show you that just
because of because I'm already over but
that is the new feature that I will be
releasing of this talk and hopefully
you'll see the value of this that you'll
be able to quickly in automatically
utilize all these bypasses and all of
these techniques UAC bypasses to execute
payloads on the host and saving a lot of
time
yeah
appreciate that you have any questions
please let me know but we are out of
time so thank you for coming