some kind of password changing service
we want to dig a little bit deeper so
using some w my numeration through
powershell an empire again we're going
to numerate all the services that are
currently installed in the system that
have the name past somewhere within the
name where they match that we're going
to pull out the name of the service and
then the full binary path where the
binary is so you see this password
changing our this password changer with
a this kind of a you know whatever the
exe path is right we're going to go
ahead and download this and we're again
going to take this off to like kind of
an offline analyst machine to pull it
down and we're going to fade out and go
into our animals machine so we're gonna
skip you would do kind of basic exe
triage figure out what it's written in
those types of things will say we
determine that it was written in $YEAR .
net in this case our C sharp which is
also for us because we don't actually
have the reversing with.net and clr type
applications and assemblies you can
throw them into a like a decompiler and
take you can go from the common
intermediate language like kind of run
time are the the opcodes and go straight
back to what the actual source code is
so our favorite tool for this is DN spy
is free and open source we can just
throw our binder in here and start
racing through you know we see also men
here in a second we see kind of the
entry points you know this
ok the services starting on you know see
this like create user function that
looks like a screen and helpdesk admin
all right that's kinda weird there's a
generate our you know this password
function okay this looks like it's some
type of algorithm that's being used to
set whatever the local admin password is
we see there's a date there's the
hostname there's some kind of seed that
looks like they're combining everything
md5 being it doing some kind of string
transformation and then you know
depending some kind of character at the
end so this is an algorithm similar to
things we've seen in the field that the
only secret information is the hostname
essentially and then whatever the date
is so this is nice for us because if we
can enumerate the host
they remotely from a machine we can
generate the local admin password and
remotely compromise it so because
sharpen powershell are so similar is
really really easy to take that
algorithm and pour it into powershell
what you see here now from here we're
going to go one step further and we are
actually going to build a custom Empire
module to execute this so right here you
see is the similar type of algorithm
right there in that this kind of custom
Empire module so I took just the basic
template but the powershell snippets and
in that basic function and we're going
to pair that with w my some folk w my
method so this will let us do remote
lateral spread through w my with the
password being pre-generated executed
based on whatever the host name is so we
can just give it a hostname it will go
and essentially install an agent be
pretty cool again very similar to
something we've actually done in the
field so now we need some target so now
it's going to scroll off here in a
second but we're going to use a module a
Power View module with an empire and
we're going to do right all the
computers that have the Windows 7
operating system so we're assuming this
password change your binary is done for
clients and we just kind of in the
little network segment where we're going
to see what other machines they are so
we landed on sirius say and we see a sea
critter for Freddy Kruger and jigsaw or
some of the other some of the other host
so now I talked about pathfinding with
bloodhound you can find a path from any
node in the graph to any other node in
the graph so instead of just spraying
agents to every single machine that we
might have access to we wanted to do
like kind of targeted attack path
execution so we'll gather a lot of
information trace out exactly what we
want to do and then do targeted
compromise on on those sections so we're
going to see is there a path from uh I
think like jigsaw tata to the domain
controller Vader no there's not
but there is for this of the screw
machine
so we see it has a has a session
whatever no I'm just got a particular
user logged in as a member of plans and
but you see like this kind of nessa
group memberships that might have admin
access specific machines that have
different users logged in so with the
information that we gather in the first
numeration phase we can actually start
tracing out a multi-step attack PAP now
we're going to flip back
cool we're going to verify that the next
step in this mission next step in this
attack path is actually true
so we're gonna use one my favorite its
functionality power of you getting at
local group it's rolled into the get
local group module Empire this will use
the windy service provider or some API
calls in the back end to enumerate the
members of a local group on a remote
machine so i can figure out who is a
member of administrators and remote
machine without having elevated access
to that machine so this really is kind
of crazy to me that you're allowed to do
this
Windows 10 inner Bruce tradition yeah
when Dustin anniversary edition Server
2016 finally lock this down by default
so they're paying attention and realized
maybe it's not the best idea to let any
user in your domain know all the local
admin memberships of every other machine
in the domain as you'll see how this
kind of comes into play and how we can
build these attack graphs so we verify
ok this helpdesk admin is a local admin
on on this machine so now we're going to
start executing our attack path we know
we can use this algorithmic like kind of
w my module to jump to the next quarter
machine so we can set it executed in the
back end is going to task down to
powershell to the pivot host and then
you see it generated whatever the seed
and the password and then it executed w
my with an empire stage on the road
system and got it back so this when we
did something kind of like this in the
field it only took less than a day or a
few hours to go up
well yeah about like less than one
assessment day to go from holding down a
binary pulling out the algorithm
building an empire module and then
having essentially like you know an
internal kind of oday whatever not okay
but whatever is an exploit on any
workstation the entire environment that
made it really really awesome so the
advantage of something like empire in
this situation is the ability to
customize these things in the field and
kind of roll roll with this new
functionality so okay we compromise the
helpdesk admin on this crew machine we
know that I think you lose the person is
login here
oh wait okay yeah so we knew that the
wave had a session here based on the
Bloodhound data so we could steal tokens
weekend me cats or we could just
essentially migrate into the process so
we're going to PS inject into their
process space and assume all their token
privileges so was nice of empire it does
a whole bunch of kind of black magic in
the back end that one my workmates
worked up of taking ways to load up the
dotnet common language runtime into an
unmanaged see your C++ process space
that then loads up an assembly that then
does a powershell runner and does much
other stuff so end result what you guys
should care about is you can run your
powershell Empire agents and processes
that are not powerful vxc so we're going
to migrate into her process basic
consumer privileges and then then we're
just going to use a regular w my module
for lateral spread to move to the next .
so we're going to move to the Baltimore
server arm because that we saw that
bloodhound attack graph that the wave
did have access to this based on her
unrolled like multi nested group
membership so if you adjust the
numerator that server directly you would
have known you know does this person
have access there because these things
to start to spider and this even though
this is a relatively simple example if
you can think about these things that
scale if you're thinking about thousands
of groups or thousands of users and
systems there is no way that you're
going to be able like by hand to find
every single attack path you might get
lucky and find one but you're not going
to find all
ok so now from here we know that the
wave has access
I wait with it yet
ok yeah so Eric Cartman is a domain
admin respect authority that the this is
the research and development group they
have their own domain because of this
reason they kind of do their own thing
so we have our production environment
another demand the same for so we're
fine like going yeah yeah we'll see
oh ok now the last kind of lateral
spread them to go over is something
called subversive profiles has anyone
heard of PowerShell profiles or a little
bit a few people's ok whenever
powershell txt starts up whether it's
the ISE or regular powershell dxc it
looks through a series of locations
which i'll highlight here in a second
for your profile your profile . ps1 the
set of PowerShell code that's normally
used for like she'll customizations and
things like that
now whenever so whenever powershell that
exe starts it's going to execute
whatever code is in that profile so
there's a blog post which I'll show in a
second where Mack graber my boss in the
next room talked about attackers
potentially using the subversively for
persistence we're going to use it for
lateral spread to get around script
block logging so essentially what's
going to happen is we're going to
generate the zoom in a second we're
going to generate your empire launcher
your empire launcher code and then using
Wi-Fi remote registry we're going to
push it over to a value on the remote
system execute command that pulls it
down and saves that malicious logic to a
profile that ps1 and like the the
powershell program files are the see you
know system32 windows powershell profile
be one thing then we're going to execute
powershell txt on the host its going to
start load the profile executor actual
logic is going to kill itself and then
we're going to restore with the original
profile ps1 is so all the client will
see or if you're doing command-line
login or carbon black or anything like
that is really awesome solutions you're
just going to see powershell BAC
starting no command
no command line flags no command line
whatever else is not doing Dash f4 file
or anything like that
then if they did have an original
profile like this system will be
completely cleaned up so this modules
and public yet we just need to clean up
a couple of things and we're going to
release it in the next month or so
so this is the blog post that Matt put
out so investigating subversive power
show profiles highly recommend everybody
ingredients so pretty cool so again he
kind of talked about this from dfi our
perspective of you want to ensure that
you know you pull all profile . ps1 when
you're doing ironing machine for us it
doesn't really matter because we're
using it for lateral spreading out
persistence and we repair and clean
everything up so there's you know we're
not really leaving any traces so again
nothing super super crazy but we thought
a kind of a cool new little lateral
spread method but uh no command line
logging has become a more and more of a
pain over the last year
ok so because of the local admin
password changing executable you took
advantage of the fact that the algorithm
wasn't secure as possible etc figured
out what that password was on a
different machine and then leverage that
information to jump 21 with the domain
admin and then using powershell family
to then run your code on our domain
controller
yeah so you know you see up there are
creating the profile pushing it over
executing powershell THC we get an agent
back and repairing the profile so okay
let's say we take care of that then
we're good right oh yeah sure
alright so that was attacking client to
client how many you guys Proust on a
regular basis anybody all right if
you're not you absolutely should be so
kerberos team kerberos ting involves the
abuse of user accounts that have SPN set
so ESPN's or service principal names are
configured for service accounts to kind
of enable the authentication flow for
kerberos and the normal Active Directory
domains so when a user request a service
ticket at TGS on it its ends
I he I keep forgetting exactly how like
this
kerberos is extremely complicated but
when a user request the TGS it will send
the request for the exact spin with the
user account to the domain controller
which will actually go through the
kerberos negotiation process and the end
result is you get a TGS that sit back
down to the user curve roasting you can
request these tickets as a regular user
non non admin on and those tickets are
going to be saved in your current
process space you can extract these
because you own your current process
space extracting and transform them into
such a way that you can then export the
McCracken with hash kapoor John so it's
a way to depending on the service
accounts are configured be able to
brute-force offline service account
passwords and service account passwords
usually don't change very often write
like they're they're usually around for
a long long time
so previously when you wanted to
kerberos you would do a bunch of
one-liners no mom it's intimidating a
year year-and-a-half ago I think he
talked to derby last year had you know
kinda came up with a lot of this
research and then had all these
one-liners request request the tickets
and you could use mimic cats to extract
the tickets out of memory either to
discard like kind of a 64 encoding blobs
now thanks to a poor request by
i think is macho sec from on the power
view the power of you prod the power of
you code in PowerPoint there's a much
much easier way to do this without
needing mccants so first we're going to
check whether our targets we're gonna
use the the get user module in Empire
which wraps get net user in a Power View
and there's a spin flag which will
return all users on Noel's ESPN set in
the entire domain so again these are the
targeted accounts that we may be able to
kerberos so it's going to task
everything in the back end is going to
execute it and we should get the results
back for i think in this kind of sample
there's three let's see we have a we
have the ring we have Death Star and we
have a white Walker somewhere up there i
think yeah okay so we have three
different service accounts that we may
be able to prost now we're going to go
back to our blood analysis platform and
again instead of purchase kerberos seen
everything and trying to exploit
everything we're gonna do targeted
compromise so we're going to see is that
our paths from any of these three
service accounts to the domain admins
group a bloodhound like the first one no
let's see does her know it doesn't look
like there's a path but for white Walker
there is a bath a white Walker which is
a member of house Bolton and then member
of the guild the clams 10 which has
access to that same Baltimore server
that we used in the previous attack
chain so we know that if we cover the
plaintext credentials for the white
Walker service account through nessa
group membership we should be able to
compromise that same server migrated to
Eric Cartman's process again and then
kind of go about the similar parts of
the attaching so now let's kerberos the
get yeah it's been tickets model this is
it's so nice this is a nam Empire too .
oh that was released yesterday so you
can either if you don't set any user
account request all tickets if you like
in this particular case we know we just
want one with white Walker and instead
of doing all that stuff and running
mechanics and doing multiple stages is
just one file its going to execute it
down it's only like a dozen or so lines
powershell and you can pull the
encrypted component of the ticket out of
memory so
oh and it will preform at it ready for
cracking for John so like way way easier
it's just like one single step you could
run this essentially and through
whatever age you want you could run this
through interpreter you can run this
through couple strike or whatever with
the ps1 or we're going to switch over to
the tickets saved off for John we're
going to go ahead and see if we can
crack it
so again just literally copied that text
straight over already pretty kind of
formatted for the cracking format for
you guys and we see White Walkers
password is jon snow sucks okay like I
said these are already folks they like
it with arms i'm gonna have some
conversations with them so now we know
the plaintext credentials for the
service account that lets start to
execute that attack path so with the
invoke w my module and Empire you can
you don't have to use the current users
credential set you can specify plaintext
credentials if you like
so we're going to set the credentials
for this white Walker service account we
are going to set the target to be that
that kind of Baltimore server that we
were able to spread to with an
additional hop from you know the client
side with the password change your
binary executed get our agent back we're
going to do the similar you know the
same couple of steps that we did in the
previous demo to where we do our
numeration of what what processes are
running because we know from the graph
that a user has to be logged on and
logged on we're going to PS inject into
this process is injected into this
process again it's going to do all that
kind of crazy you know . net stuff
loading up on the backend which i think
is like one of the coolest coolest
features of the project we should get
our new agent back here in a second and
now instead of spreading an agent to a
domain controller general we want to
probably try to stay FDCs as much as we
can
we're going to be a bit healthier and
use DC sink has anyone used e sink
hopefully a good chunk of people yet so
DC sink was a module for many cats
written by pimentel be gentle kiwi and
Vincent towed it allows you to simulate
DC replication traffic so the normal
kind of traffic protocol that's used to
replicate like password and let user
information data between domain
controllers with mimic as you can now
say on a client and Jaime Katz and i'll
say hey domain controller i'm also the
main controller please give me this
password assuming you have domain admin
rights so we do have da rates now but
this is a way to replicate that hash and
historical password information for
whatever account we want without running
an agent or any type of actual code on
the DC so we're going to set the user
account for where the really . ppl Corp
domain we have the care BTW that's going
to execute this and will inject me cats
down do that d sync functionality and
Empire also has a really nice credential
store in the back and they can almost
act as a golden ticket catalog so it
will automatically screaming cats output
and save all the information for you in
the back end so we see let's see a fader
fader . really evil corporate domain
controller so saved everything out if
you type Reds you see that everything is
saved is going to say about the domain
sit and everything else will show in the
next part of the demo how easy it is
after EDC sink or ash dump to use the
credential stores a golden ticket
counter
ok so alright lot of stuff going on here
um so you were able to get a service
ticket for this kerberos service account
and basically take that ticket crack it
offline because of how progress works
and then use that password because a
horrible password
pretty easily obviously in order to gain
access to get domain admin access on
this argument so when you do this blood
and stuff and pull the information from
the environment is not a traffic note so
I mean we do the numeration once and the
collection component can either be as
noisy years by kind of is we want you
know / situation and after that all the
queries have been offline so we're not
doing additional l decorators every time
in the the traffic itself is just ldap
enumeration for the most part for any
any type of the user group on rolling
and then it's a handful of like kind of
typical API calls with a remote nets
session and nam type things like in the
back end that are going up against a
couple of your servers at this point the
only thing that i know of there's
probably some commercial products that
can detect some of these components the
main one that i know of his microsoft
ATA for i think is an adaptive or
advanced threat analytics it can detect
the remote session enumeration against a
domain controller if its installed but
it won't detect against all these are
the servers at this point they don't
detect kind of anomalous ldap
enumeration traffic they say that that's
coming which kind of terrifies me but
we'll see because there's so many
devices are so many things that you know
all networked printers and address books
and all this kind of crap that needs
ldap and plugs in the ldap so there's a
reason that people haven't you know walk
down people running internet the next
group domain admins on domains because
lots of things plug into this
functionality active directory is meant
to be a directory for things look up
information i was Server 2016 there is
the ability to they've introduced ackles
that will let you lock down who can
enumerate what information the domain is
also kind of scary but that's not
enabled by default and we all know I
mean we all know that all clients will
enable and configure perfectly as soon
as it comes out so I'm sure that will
happen
so now we saw you know there is we're in
a really evil Corps domain we were in a
child domain and a forest so you guys
have some kind of like Boris trust
relationship so here we go
ok so we're going to go back to our
initial pivots or unprivileged user on
of Ramsay Bolton cirse with without any
kind of privileges and because we d/c
synced what we're going to do is kind of
the sid sid trust hopping attack to
elevate from the child domain all the
way up to the parenting normally trust
will flow down from the force route down
to everything else if your enterprise
admin great about a year ago on this
researcher named John Metcalf and
Benjamin delpy worked out a way to
really weaponize ati an attack that's
been theoretical for about ten years
which if you have domains within a
forest and you compromise any domain
admin rights are any if you compromise a
domain controller the kar bt or whatever
within anywhere within the forest if you
can modify the CID history for a
particular user and set the city history
to be enterprise admin is you can
instantly compromise the root of the
entire forest so you can hop up i know
this is like this blew my mind when I
first kind of learned about it and I
didn't really believe it but we've done
in the field and it works so Sid history
is a migration function arts function to
facilitate migration between domain so
if you had like going from domain be a
domain a the idea would be when you take
those users and migrate the menu set the
CID history to be that Sid security
identifier of their old groups so this
would preserve their access to the old
groups on again the idea was meant for
migration but people realize 10 years
ago that a theoretical attack was
possible to earth you could modify the
city history for user to be enterprise
admins then you became an enterprise
admin within the forest but in order to
do this previously you had to like hard
modify stuff in the NTS dat it's a super
super super protective attribute as john
Payne he asked modified but with the
golden ticket component
that figured out you can set this
history the golden ticket inject it and
then just instantly hop-up so is finally
fully weaponized so the one bit of
information we need last bit of
information we need is the the city of
the root domain so we know the city of
our child domain but we want the city of
ppl Corp an easy way to do this is with
the this user to sit functionality from
power of your empire just take that
username and i'll translate it to the
full security identifier so we know care
BTW always has to be there so that's the
one i tend to use going to copy off the
domain said we need that to create thats
it dash 519 is the city for enterprise
atoms for the forest now we're gonna
create a golden ticket
I mention that I credit the credit or so
you what's really nice is if any Empire
modules have credit ID it all except
just a number of the credit or that will
automatically auto-populate and fill in
the care of ETFs the domain of the
domains original sin all those company
components so you can again use it kinda
like a golden ticket catalog and i'll
scroll up the screen i'll do an info to
kind of show you all the stuff over
setting the SIDS so the extra SIDS to be
the fourth roots it dash 5 194
enterprise admins and also does anyone
know about the 20 minute rule with
golden tickets a little bit it's a
little bit on the more familiar for
people if you create a golden ticket
you have 20 minutes to run around with
it before the domain controller verifies
that account exists or not that's the
only validation that they do they don't
verify like is this user in the right
groups or whatever they verify the
account exists so if you create a golden
ticket for user that does not exist in
the domain you have 20 minutes to run
around and then really have fun with
event logs for with defenders so I've
known people that may or may not have a
cross-site scripting defender sim
solutions by stuffing JavaScript into
the user account names but on that's
another story
so I root said Dash 5 19 right as soon
as we inject this we should essentially
be common enterprise admin instantly
again showing that just kind of that
trust graph this is a simple one
if you have a really complex environment
you know it becomes a little easier to
to navigate a bloodhound
so we're going to execute it and it will
also do pass the ticket so it won't save
anything out to disconnect the ticket
straight into memory which we can purge
later if we need to come on
alright and this in the back end this is
all using invoke mimic cats which was
based off of work by Joby ellicott at
Microsoft so he was one of the guys are
really introduced a lot of awesome
functionality into the power supply
project so we see here we have that high
that user doesn't exist that followed
the blue team and then we have extra
cities to be that dumb the forest route
Sid dash 509 for enterprise advents so
now the last part we're going to do is
we're just going to go ahead d sink the
forest group I know arm i don't know if
you've had the advice to change your
care BTW account
yes actually we rotate that
automatically every couple hours okay
you just told me that would fix .
tickets you just do that in the forest
route
yes that's for production of our yet so
the really fun thing with the CID
hopping kind of attack is in order to
ensure that you're not compromise
forever
you would have to rotate the kar bt
account on every domain and every domain
in your entire forest all at the same
time because essentially any care BTW
account in any child domain controller
in the forest can be used to compromise
the forest route and anything else so
and this is hopping attack it doesn't
matter of the Caribbean TGT rotates we
just got it within a minute we get you
know hop up in DC but yet you have to
rotate it for every single domain in
your entire force at the same time
repeatedly on a regular basis if you
want to ensure that you're not gonna
completely compromise because it
comprises a child domain
and then you rotate up few other things
they forgot one of the children domains
then you can just hop back in not get
your exs again and go down ok so from my
rd domain in my active directory forest
you compromise that the then jump to my
production environment and now have full
domain admin rights of my to name my
forest you okay that's pretty awful
I so the thing I don't get is I spend
millions of dollars every year and
security tools i mean i have vendors
coming in all the time and they say that
they have the best security and i've got
i showed you got trucks are wolves and I
mean the web content filtering didn't
matter an email didn't matter none of
these things seem to matter in and like
we we detect many cats like we have
antivirus but you said use PowerShell a
lot so it's it seems like you're a very
smart guy and I've got great security
people
what am I supposed to do I mean you know
obviously come like these fine people
come to conferences come to things like
the Recon you know go have conversations
with people in hallway con you go to
trainings there's a lot of you know
really good kind of 80 type stuff out
there so people are starting to pay more
attention zat Active Directory
exploitation in the last couple years so
we're we're happy about this and there's
a lot of information out there for
people 14 ok so it sounds like maybe I
need to invest more in my people instead
of the products and focus one give me
all the money
so I learned a lot today and and I
appreciate your help with as well and
and if I I i guess i need to send my
people the more conferences they keep
asking me and I'm like yeah you're just
going to party and drink and and it
seems like that's part of the experience
but apparently there's a lot of good
things to be learned conferences and in
going to training and this is the real
thing that's going to help security as I
thought we had some pretty good security
place it and seen
yeah
so let's talk some mitigations arm the
initial foothold was pretty intense
right there's a lot of different things
you can do to mitigate these sort of
attacks not specifically this kind of
oily functionality within an email that
comes to the user but deploy Emmett
because that will help prevent and
mitigate those memory attacks that they
can use AppLocker can block executable
content from running and user locations
like home directory profile path and
often ransomware takes advantage of this
user runs download something and they
executed and runs so you can use
whitelisting this is more like
blacklisting you block certain locations
so they can't actually execute the
content you can manage car show
execution using a blocker or constrain
language mode
Matt next door's probably has some ways
around that but again these are all
layers and your security just because
one layer can be defeated doesn't mean
you shouldn't put in flakes as engineers
we often want a hundred percent solution
you do not need a hundred percent
solution forty fifty sixty percent is
better than nothing and it forces the
attacker to change their methodology and
makes it more expensive so you want to
enable logging like PowerShell command
process obviously block office macros
were possible
microsoft is back for it functionality
from 2016 and 2013 so any macros that
come from the internet or automatically
blocking the user can actually execute
and then you want to deploy some sort of
security tooling that looks for
suspicion this is behavior if the user
has word that's calling powershell or
some other executable or doing something
else back it's probably back we can also
limit this capability as far as
executables that get onto the system
executable tight content blocking email
and download capability for certain
types of files you can also change the
default program for scripting languages
javascript can actually be double click
on and executed by a user we don't want
that change that to notepad please test
first recon is a tough solution tough
problem the saw 80 recon active
directory is an LDAP directory so that
means you can pull pretty much
everything from at any given time
but there are ways to kind of limit this
if you increase the security on
sensitive gpo's like security group to
group policies than the attacker doesn't
have an advantage of just pulling
everything that's in those group
policies opening them up and knowing how
your security tools like AppLocker amat
and others are configured as well as
what you have out there and certainly
evaluate some sort of behavior analytics
tool like a TA we're talking about
lateral movement attackers moving from
place to place within your environment
we want to make sure that the attacker
isn't able to just run free if they drop
on a workstation if you block
workstation workstation communication or
just allow specific ports then they are
constrained into a specific computer or
environment and it's very difficult to
jump out of that look at laughs look at
trusted second ships ways to change your
local admin passwords that are out there
do not try to roll your own there are
some good solutions out there that work
very well privilege escalation i still
find some passwords insist ball please
make sure that you don't have a suite
consists all and we're talking about
kerberos ting the simple solution of
this is make sure your service account
passwords or at least 25 characters
preferably 30 or use managed service
accounts or get a password tool that
will automatically change those
passwords for you make them super long
and complex the longer they are the more
difficult it is to be craft and if we
make sure our computers running ntlm v2
or kerberos it's a lot more difficult
for passive credential theft like
responder to actually work which brings
me to admin creds if we make sure that
all of our admins only log onto specific
authorized admin systems we can raise
the bar and make it more difficult for
those credentials to be stolen if you
add your admin accounts protected users
which comes available in 2012
then they are not able to be delegated
and they don't support insecure ntlm
authentication you also want to reduce
the surface the attack surface of your
workstations and servers that are used
for admin accounts so control access
remove netbios probably doesn't need it
get rid of LM and r get rid of double
pad and this rolls over into legacy
audit and restrict your ntlm
authentication environment you don't
know what's being used
there's no way that you can control it
enforce ldap signing use ldap as for any
non microsoft windows type applications
in its unique see it's going to bind if
it's finding / l doubt that's clear text
that is that enable ldap signing and
encryption where possible we want to
disable these older protocols
I mean who has seen w pad use
legitimately environment right a couple
of times but it's enabled everywhere in
responder takes advantage of it and pen
testers and attackers can just drop on a
system and ask for credit effectively in
windows 10 pls uncheck smb1 and
powershell version too if you don't do
this arm certain tools like PS attack
and leverage the power shell version 2
and bypass all your fancy powershell
version 5 logging
so in summary once an attacker gets a
foothold in your network admin access is
often quickly obtain you showed a couple
of examples
this is all fictional but these are
things that are being done in real life
and you want to make sure that you
identify and Molly's defenses based on
typical attacker activity if you read
about what's being done
look to see what the mitigations and
defenses are focusing on detection first
and then moving into mitigation and
prevention and then you can model those
defenses and then questioned how good
your current defenses are do we have
visibility into the right places are we
seeing lots of our workstations can we
see when some of these things that will
showed are actually happening in our
environment but if we measure our
environment like Carlos was talking
about measure the environment document
the environment understand what you have
so that way you can figure out how its
tighten it up and lock it down because
ultimately effective defense limits the
attacker capability and their options
increases their costs
thank you very much
yeah
so go because I was there it was awesome
wasn't it was really high it was like
one of the highlights of my trip so far
his method man here haha
because I tweeted him last night so good
morning derby con yeah that's that's a
good response for having been up so late
this is attacking evil Corp anatomy of a
corporate hat i'm sean and I'm we'll
just a little bit about us i get my more
straighter my handle on Twitter's arm
joy I'm a security researcher and
contesta red team her for various groups
adapted threat division
I've written a lot of code developed a
lot of our tool set some kind of a
co-founder was one of the big developers
on the veil framework powershell Empire
python Empire hydropower up our view
helped with bloodhound which are going
to cover a bit during this presentation
along with a few other for the work
needs to work on that with me
Microsoft power shown DP on spoken a few
conferences spoke yesterday at a derby
khan had a great time I spoke a couple
years ago so one of my favorite
conferences for sure but show of hands
who uses either Empire veil framework
power of your power up on a regular
basis all that's what makes me happy so
awesome lots of pwnage so I'm Sean
metcalf founder Trimark a security
company Microsoft Certified Master in
Active Directory what about a hundred
the world
microsoft MVP like my good friend will
hear focus black hat defcon b-sides and
Derby con really happy to be here and we
can love derby con I'm a security
consultant researcher and I own and
operate 80 security toward who's heard
of are used 80 security at work
awesome so I the setup for this is gonna
be a little different than your standard
conference talk I we're gonna put on a
skit for the next 30 minutes so we're
actually going to shift from being Sean
and will the nice guys
that you like to hang out with and I'm
gonna turn into convert myself into the
CIO of ecor evil court right and i'm
going to talk about how perfect our
security is how we have great security
it's huge right and then we'll is going
to come up and he's gonna go
no no not actually kind of sucks and I'm
gonna show you why
so then after the skit we're going to
switch back to a standard slide
presentation and we're going to show you
the mitigations that should have been in
place for could have been a place to
resolve those issues that were about
show so this is where we switch
hello gone how are you today i am the
CEO of igor the most secure Network ever
we have a very large global Active
Directory environment with lots of
domains we do lots of security with
active directory to make sure everything
is in good shape got hundreds of domain
controllers we've got hundreds of
thousands of endpoints thousands of
servers all over the world we have data
centers to make sure things are
physically secure and we have offices
all over and these are well connected
but we also have executives and other
people at work from home and have mobile
devices so we have challenges with that
so we make sure we have really great
security and of course we have a
perimeter network for our customers and
our suppliers much like any other
network and we ever internal corporate
network protected by firewalls not just
any firewalls these are next-gen
firewalls
we have web content filters that filter
out all of the bad code in fact it looks
for the evil bit goes know we've got
email security appliances that say
viruses not today we have VPN security
using two-factor authentication so
there's no way that anyone who's not
authorized that I haven't signed a form
for can get on our network we have
endpoint security antivirus kids hip
sees we've got all those things
ultimately a corp security is the best
and we're unhackable
I'm sorry gentlemen up here you are you
saying that you don't think were awesome
and ok when you come up here let's see
what you can do on what's your name sir
hey well come on up yeah I going to do
you part so here's my here's my computer
let's let's see what we're talking about
here
alright so we're going to have kind of
five different sections with this so the
first one of the first things you
mentioned was kind of like
categorization web filter any kind of
next-gen expo yeah absolutely we have
web categorization with our web content
filtering and so that way users can't go
to any bad sites sure so this is
essentially a solved problem by the
search engine optimization community so
we have a kind of a proof-of-concept
tool that will be releasing later in the
year after its cleaned up called eminent
domain it will search a number of
different sites like one of the our
favorites are down calm so it will look
for domains that have just expired
within the last couple of days that are
already aged out and categorized so
beyond just the categorization issue we
see domain age is normally like a pretty
big pretty big problem sometimes for
forgetting exhale out but in general for
the last year-and-a-half first Oh giving
characterization exhale hasn't been an
issue for us
I'm you see down here the eminent domain
will actually search for wild card type
terms that are similar to whatever your
targeted so you're evil corporation com
we actually purchased that
oh wait a second you you purchase one of
my domain names can you do that
sorry you purchase one of my domain
names oh no it's just a similar kind of
Snarf's domain but it was a child but it
wasn't categorized so this is a
theoretical categorization page that we
absolutely did not actually submit to
arm and this is actually a response
email that totally doesn't have the site
categorize for your evil corporation com
so you know this came in about two days
ago so normally turnaround time is only
about a day or so for these types of
things if you set up legitimate looking
content or if you want to be really
sneaky after you buy a domain that had
just expired go to archive.org slow down
the old content and set it up on what
whatever the existing thing is so
doesn't skip a beat you know you have
the site went down for one day at
transfer donors and then you just
resubmit to whatever categorization you
want saying like oh my gosh what i don't
understand I've been around for 10 years
on goal so that's pretty much the
categorization so hold on a second
you're saying that you can get around my
web content filtering and get the
categorization that we do all the time
by either buying a domain that's already
categorized or setting one up and then
just yet getting knocked off the next
one of the next things you mentioned as
far as a next-gen kind of next-gen email
filtering you have oh right
absolutely yeah that's great you have to
have a on or externally are not yet but
it's in the works
so it's it's one of our favorite things
that hit to wear if we see any kind of
external interface if you guys aren't
doing this you absolutely should is just
do a cyclone or just do a press stealer
social engineering tool can do this we
tend to do it manually so just having
like really simple PHP snippet that will
clone you know save off whatever the
creds are when people go through to the
kinda spoofed login page and then we
actually redirected with legitimate
login information so really really easy
and efficient email out if you if you
get through with the with a couple of
people with the domain you don't
actually have to get your payloads by
just have to get your creds login 20 and
then we spear fish internally can
actually craft a lot of your messages
much more kind of targeted because you
can read through these in the email
correspondence so you don't kind of hit
that security uncanny valley to or maybe
the signature is just a bit off or you
know if you address somebody a little
bit differently and people kind of
freaked out so effectively you purchased
this domain
you gotta categorize one of my domains i
started and then you send an email to my
one of my users are a bunch of my users
and say go to this o.o page and they go
there they log in and then they don't
get in they get refreshed to our actual
lepage it and then you steal their
credentials
that's the same thing as far as as far
as payloads go are kind of standard
right now that we like to use are
malicious shortcut on k files embedded
within all a's in kind of office
documents so shortcuts you can create
these maliciously pretty easily with a
few paths embarrass my friends that's a
really cool project that applies graph
theory to active directory attack pass
if you guys haven't checked it out like
so is his name is Waldo yeah his novel
always right there I found you
yeah so basically we can take three
pieces of information of whose login
where who has admin rights where what
users and groups along to what groups
and that's it we can collect all this
information as a non-privileged user we
just need domain authentication or we
need a domain authenticated user but we
need no elevated privileges in the
domain with this we can run a powershell
and gesture which is essentially a
customized version of power of you that
will numerate all this information as
fast as they can and then spit it out
either to a RESTful API interface or a
bunch of CSVs that then we can adjust
down then it's I've got a really really
nice dashboard for pathfinding and all
this so i have a question about this so
you go through this email convoluted
thing and somehow I code running on one
of my workstation sigh i don't quite get
but ok fine and then is a regular user
you can get all this information from
the environment with without any admin
rights whatsoever you and then pull this
into some snipping tool knapper dog so
the from the pivot we're going to show
this user does not have local
administrative access in the Machine and
there Justin domain users they have no
elevated domain access so for the two
different attack past we're going to
show kind of starting with recon and
we'll move into the to pass keep in mind
that this is a completely on privileged
user so i don't know how ordinary this
is re the can actually see all right
just tell me what state Kennedy had seen
it all right okay i'm gonna try to click
this video and then move right here and
she was one alright so we're gonna start
up in part we have our fish user on this
is the really . evil . for domain and
all the Machine names and users are
named after evil characters so we have
we fished Ramsay Bolton on the co-state
machine
absolutely is a good guy or bad
ok and we're going to run the Bloodhound
adjuster so we're going to kick this off
and that there's a couple different
collection methods by default it's going
to rain all the groups are all the group
group memberships and like using
memberships and everything is also going
to enumerate all the systems that can
find on the domain and then running
numeration threads to figure out the
local administrators in session
information for each it that now that
touches every single machine is kind of
normal a t-type traffic but it's you
know one workstation conspiring out and
touching a lot of stuff if you want to
be a bit more stealthy you can use the
stealth collection which will do just
held up in numeration to domain
controller and then try to numerate
commonly traffic servers by checking
your home directory path and stuff
through user objects and then i'll do
the remote session and local admin
enumeration against just that has those
handfuls of commonly traffic servers and
then it doesn't gpo correlation tricks
for local admin so stealth collection
not as accurate but a lot faster and a
lot quieter
oh ok we're gonna kick off the new
bloodhound module that's an empire to do
beta was released yesterday this is
going to send in jester down and it's
going to be a going to start kicking all
the enumeration threads and everything
off in the back end and the videos
ok cool so you can see there it did all
the enumeration is saved all the CSVs
off so now we are going to actually just
download the CSV names and we're going
to switch over to our bloodhound analyst
machine
cool so all these pulled down
alright so we're going to start a
bloodhound it is cross-platform it's
written the front end