so uh how's everybody's confidence so
far been good deal
my name is Bill sem and I cannot see my
keyboard clacking okay that light really
right arm you can find me on Twitter I
hang on twitter i was an IRC guy before
there was a web arm i'm old like older
than snot anybody here know go for
script like the language you do not
you've never seen before in your life
you liar
yeah you maybe um I uh I had an email
address in the eighties so think back
and realize when you have an email
address and so I'm older than the hills
but i really like Twitter even though
apparently they're going to get bought
by somebody and probably go to hell
arm the UH it's a global conversation
very much like IRC but a much much lower
barrier to entry so you can chat with
people in it people who are searching
for keywords can jump in on the
conversation and do things and I think
that's really awesome so even though
twitter has got a lot of problems
there's a lot of heat on there it's true
and there's a bunch of stupid
celebrities doing their thing
really i mean i have a tremendous
collection of people are both on the
security in the development side that I
follow so feel free if you use twitter
to hook up if you hate Twitter on
reconsider our and from there so a
little bit about myself I'm a programmer
i have been since the lady's arm i'm
primarily a microsoft program I I was
early on a unix guy and moved to
microsoft windows 95 any active server
pages stack and then went on the aspx
and.net I've written several books about
it
r you can you can find me if you if you
choose to look on on Wiley rocks
originally the red and black books with
yellow lettering and then what wiley
about rocks i moved over to them
arm and I've been developing in that
that middle business space for a long
time that Dom like department-level
internet sort of line-of-business
applications stuff for a long time but
what happens i ended up becoming the
security guy on the dev team for some
reason I always ended up being the guy
was in charge of interactivity of
performance and security on the dev team
and probably because that's where the
really really hard problems are and
everybody hated it because you can grind
on it for weeks and not get anywhere and
maybe just have to give up and I've
never mind that offer some some weird
reason so i always end up being that guy
and eventually well wasn't eventually so
I am I i spend some time writing Windows
8 apps and JavaScript which was probably
the worst decision of my life and I burn
me out so bad on dev I i went to mentor
mind romantico and said dude is there
anything on the security space that I
can do and he says well why don't you
try vulnerability analysis he'd probably
be good at it and of course had done it
all along I know how to use all the
tools and stuff as a dev team member
so what I've never done this a security
person before so i started doing a
security person was doing web analysis
for a long time and as a dead-on I
actually turned out to be pretty good at
it because I know where all the mistakes
are because I made them all like in the
last week or so so I know I know where
the problems are going to be and so I
can go find them quite easily will know
next 18 months
um well actually about two years ago I
guess company was doing business with
ask me to do arm asked me if I could do
an analysis on android app and I was
like ah I guess I mean I did around the
android know java arm and I know how
they entered stack works and is like
wallets I mean how different is it
really then like testing a flash app
it's basically a rich client application
with services in the back end right
that's really all it is armed
so I said sure why not so i did a ton of
research and um got a pretty good tool
set together and wrote a pretty decent
report and the
the worker got around the stuff started
piling in
so now i do about half mobile and have
actually since even though i haven't
been an Apple user since 92 arm
literally I have a full mac lab now to
iOS testing so maybe if the derby car
gods are permissive allah i'll come back
next year do the same talk on on iOS but
this is an Android talk so we're going
to we're going to hack android apps for
fun and problem because there is profit
to be made on bug bounties are a thing
now
oh these companies will pay you if you
find flaws so you guys going to see my
screen right is is that working ok good
so here's what happens in this talk so
you can decide if you want to stay or
not this is the list of stuff I'm gonna
talk about we're gonna get as far as we
can you'll notice there's no power .
there are no slides I am literally going
to show you my process of how I figured
out how to test android apps a lot of
this is from other people's research but
it's all gathered in one nice cohesive
place arm and in and I'm i can i'm going
to show you the the you can watch the
sausage basically being made I mean
obviously this is a list of what i'm
going to talk about right so we're gonna
we're gonna go from there and I have a
lot of stuff up and running on my
machine and first I'd like to talk about
our what it is we're looking for okay so
this is the mobile top 10 as anybody
here ever heard of wasp you open well my
goodness I love you so much
the open web application security
project ok so i am the dotnet Pro
project manager for your loss and also i
run the Columbus chapter one of the
three run the Columbus chapter arm so
all those three things they have
chapters where people get together like
a like a normal meetup meeting and and
talk about application security we have
conferences like this one the next one
is absent USA next month
in in DC and then the wheels of projects
in the project some of them are code
projects like that attack proxy which
some of you may have used or dependency
check with some of you may have used
some more documentation projects the
documentation project sometimes are very
rich and sometimes are very thin very
simple
they're almost marketing tools the OWASP
top 10 is probably the most famous of
those it is the top ten vulnerabilities
discovered over the past three years and
web applications arm and it is um one of
the most cited documents at all of
application security in fact it's almost
too much
cited where people will call me and ask
can you give us a wasp top 10 training
to it i'll say new but i will give you
application security training and we
might cover the things that are in the
top ten but the top 10 is not
application security program so now
you'll know this
that said the mobile top 10 brings us
the same thing that the UH the the main
web top-10 does it describes something
for for people who do not have the that
the technical skills in an arena to
really know where the problems might lie
probably most of the people in this
crowd know what can go wrong in a web
application at least have a good idea
even if you're not an application
security specialist but mobile is
different a lot of it is black magic
so this goes back to where like the web
was 10 years ago or 15 years ago when
they started the top ten ten years ago I
guess arm 13 years ago and they said um
nobody really knows where the flaws are
we need something simple
well that's where we are with mobile
today no one knows where the flaws are
we need something simple so they wrote a
top-10 list and its really pretty good
this does cover a lot of the stuff that
you see so I'll walk through it very
quickly
I'm the number one very interestingly
has nothing to do with the mobile
application at all it is weak server
side controls so for those of you who
don't know a nap an application that's
loaded on an android phone has very
little business logic in it it is
calling back to
mrs. at some server that hosts just like
a web page and it speaks back and forth
using Jason or XML sometimes on which is
the data configuration format um those
services are just web pages that return
data instead of HTML
ok that you test them exactly the same
way they have all the same flaws
there-there there-there susceptible to
to cross-site request forgery they're
susceptible to sequel injection they're
susceptible to command injection they're
susceptible to all kinds of our
authentication and authorization lost
just like a website would be so it's
very interesting that really the website
that's backing a mobile application is
the most vulnerable part of a mobile
application and I have finally found in
my experience this is true i'm insecure
data storage is number two this is where
you do things your developers do things
like store your private keys to do
communicate authenticated communication
back to the server on the device
thinking well we've hit on the device
nobody can find it
that is not the case just like with a pc
a human can access every byte of data on
here so you cannot hide anything on here
unfortunately this means the developers
will have to learn how to do very
sophisticated authentication like H Mac
this is not a blue team top so i'm not
going to go over how to do that but i'll
be a bark on a few if anybody wants to
talk about it like seriously has this
problem
come find me I'll help you incidence of
transport layer protection basically
means they did not put in s and their
URL that happens almost every app at
least once I've intended data leak with
leakage this is where there is data
being passed back to the application
that the application doesn't actually
need and just the fact that it's on the
wire is often a privacy or arm other
risk violation for authorization
authentication is m5 that is exactly
what it sounds like the its application
where that they're not appropriately
checking for username password one of
the most common ones i find is where
they aren't checking for username and
password are you just press submit or
cancel and
the application broken cryptography is
m6 this is where people are too lazy to
download something that works on android
to do there are hashing or their
photography and they write their own
stack and broken which is happens almost
every time that somebody tries to write
their own client-side injection exactly
what it sounds where we can perhaps save
something onto database that then would
show in somebody else's machine and
cause some kind of cross-site attack
security decisions via untrusted inputs
where you're taking things like the host
header and stuff like that making
decisions as to whether or not this is
actually the app you think it is
improper section handling once again
exactly what it sounds like not actually
using the token properly the token isn't
random enough you're not changing the
session token on login the session
fixation those kinds of things and lack
of binary protections this release
directed there's nothing in place to
prevent me from disassembling the app
and figure out how it works
this is true of almost every application
out there so these are the things that
we look for that's super easy right
actually if we've been sitting around a
table having a beer you all probably
could have come up with these 10 on your
own that we even prompting you just as a
as a group to exercise the problem is
finding because it's kind of like
literally a black box and it's a flat
piece of black glass how that propaganda
against so let's talk about how we're
going to do this and the first thing
you're going to need is some kind of a
test environment
fortunately in Android you can
virtualize machine this is not true of
iOS are you can emulate an iOS device
you cannot simulate one know you can
simulate what not emulate one it doesn't
matter you can't actually make a real
iOS device on a pc or mac but you can
make a real android device so there is a
toolset that i'll show you later called
the Android developers tools are that
has an emulator in it but what I
recommend is this one on the screen is
called genymotion genymotion is
a rapper overtop of virtualbox which is
a son open open source but it's free
corazon source but it's three certainly
product genymotion is free to use for
personal use but it does have a license
which I only because i use it for
professional work arm and Jenny motion
is virtual box for android and you just
simply can pick any one of dozens of
phones and it will generate a new vm for
you
it's very simple to use click to start
and here is my vm oops gotta even in
here we are
so we have a virtual virtual machine
this is by far the easiest way to test
applications you can take the APK file
that you were given by the client drag
it from your desktop to this desktop and
it will install it done and then you
just test
it's that simple all of the emulated
roms are already rooted so you have at
out you have a you have a root access to
FSU is running you have root access into
them and you can do things like access
the file system and underlying pieces to
make the phone do as you wish
it is a fully functioning phone and if
you're lucky enough to have touchscreen
it actually makes it super easy to use
with a touchscreen ok arm my in my main
workstation at home i have a Windows 10
dell XPS tower with three monitors the
center one's a TV screen actually on the
right-hand and left-hand side I'm
left-handed is actually a 28 inch
touchscreen monitor that i can then have
it running like this big and touch and
it's very easy to use it makes testing
very simple you don't have to hope over
some it's it's much better
so this is definitely the way to do it
but this isn't enough we can run our
application that we're going to test
right but we can't do anything and what
do you do
right it's that that really going to do
anything so let's go back and check our
thing
yes oh if you're running in windows oh I
should talk about windows if you're
running windows
remember you will need to turn off
hyper-v to make virtualbox work anybody
who is taking notes write that down
arm it is hyper view will break
virtualbox and it's extremely difficult
to google the error message so that's
that's a that's a definite gotcha
but let me talk about windows um
probably most of the people in this room
either have a diminished outlook on
windows or are frankly dismissive of it
as an operating system because of its
past failures and i understand that very
well i truly do that said the android
development and modeling scene is almost
entirely consisting of 14 year old boys
and they're all running their moms
windows 7 laptop that she replaced this
year with something newer ipad or
something and um all of the tools that
are written to do this with almost no
exceptions run either only on windows or
better on Windows than anywhere else and
I you can ask my wife
quite literally have a laptop in each
platform that I use every single day and
I tried to write this talk on my linux
box because I thought it would by far be
the best and nothing worked
nothing which is amazing because and
during is linux under the couple's yet
when it's under the covers but none of
the tools were even a DB which is the
connection tool that will go over a few
minutes doesn't really run great on
linux all of these tools are designed to
run on windows
what's worse most of them like
genymotion only run on the metal of
windows so you have to have a machine
with windows install arm if you don't
have one I would advise finding 1i have
done this under windows 7 i've been
under eight have been under 10 and it
works just fine and all of them of
course all the standard protections
apply make sure your laptop is locked
down
I mean just because you're using it for
testing doesn't mean you shouldn't take
basic precautions and windows is like a
wire sit I will admit you've got to do
all the normal stuff but having if
you're going to do this having a windows
machine is highly recommended
in my opinion so there's that so now we
have our phone or virtual phone we need
the first thing we need to do is that
one right we need to watch the traffic
between the phone and the server we're
going to do that the same way as if we
had our a web browser
ok if we have a web browser we go in we
install some proxy and we proxy it
through Pearl and that is exactly what
we're going to do in order to do that
we're going to set a new listener on
port 80 90 alright
it has it uses the all interfaces not
look back because we're not on our
machine i'm on a different machine so i
have to i can I could do it specific
that's a pain in the butt
so I'm doing with all interfaces yes
that man means that if you're on the
same network as me you your tracking
would go through my birth as well that's
true you are not on the same network as
me don't worry about it
um so um that is what we're going to do
then i have a mouse then we're going to
go into our phone okay and we're going
to go here to here and open up here and
we're going to modify network and we're
going to add the proxy just like we
would if we were using a web browser
that's all this is now 2 caveat to this
one
not all traffic goes through port 80 and
443 some apps do write their own binary
channels to call home then it gets day
and get freaky then we got to get
wireshark out and do some nasty stuff
i'm not going to demonstrate that
because frankly much of that is above my
level of skill i'm working on it but i
have not gotten there yet to burp will
not always show you the traffic even if
it's over for 80 and 443 ok so you
sometimes we'll have to fiddle with
groups have to fiddle with verb
so what you end up doing is you'll
notice on both the target tab and proxy
tab of verb there is a filter bar
how many people here have used burp in
the past
ok that's a vast majority of those of
you who don't have and I'm sorry I'm it
so purpose in it
those of you don't know represent attack
proxy it sits between some clients some
server and record traffic on port 80 and
443 up and then it provides a load of
tools to allow you to do nasty things
that traffic record the traffic and
replay it with your own values and
things like that
um so if you look at this filter if
you're not seeing your traffic come down
and click the show all button because
sometimes burp gets confused with these
data traffic and it thinks it's by an
area i think that's something else
not always but sometimes so give that a
try if that doesn't work
fire up wire sharp because it's probably
communicating on a non I HTTP port which
is not great for you but we're not gonna
worry about that right now
so once so once we have this configured
arm and we haven't configured over here
we are we now can proceed exercise an
application and watch traffic
alright so we go here and we refresh
hacker news and absolutely nothing
happens
they're seeing and here's the here's the
requests and here's the response from
acronyms and now we can start to attack
these requests just like we would with
any other web application but you'll
notice it's coming back in Jason right
so i would recommend i don't have them
installed and think about this right now
but the pretty print options for burp
you can install plugins to do pretty
print with Jason um i would recommend
that so the Jason's easier to read our
major deal with xml as soap app you know
one for xml so you're actually in a
block of text those things which makes
it significantly easier
how we doing on who
wow I got going on oh yes
you do have to install the birth
certificates I when I last gave this
talk to give an extended demonstration
of that I no longer need to because I
pink david the guy who does burp and he
put a page up on the Burke website on
how to do it and it's super duper easy
and there's a video so if you don't
already have a birth certificate on your
test device install it
it's on the Burke website
ok so sometimes even if it's on port 80
burp gets confused there's other tools
you can try that attack proxy is an loss
product that's one of our projects and
it's a java app just like burp and
that's an attack box just like burp the
only difference is 100-percent open
source and free like beer are so you can
you can download it
r you can you know a plot oh yeah sorry
about that
interpreting of course arm but it's it's
exactly the same tool as burp it just
things are in a different place and
sometimes it picked up on traffic Burke
doesn't so you might want to give that a
try
worst-case filler filler filler is a
developer tool
ok it is a debugging proxy that's
designed to fix problems whereas
Bourbons after designed to cause
problems but ver pacific air filter is
exceptionally good at finding traffic so
on.if you proxy through it you might
find you might see things you wouldn't
normally seen arm so one of the things
you'll probably want to do at some point
is set up your machine as a developer
studio it is an actual your requirement
but it's highly recommended because
there's a lot of tools that come with
the developer kits that that just make
this a whole lot easier
the first one is android studio and
android studio isn't technically a
requirement to do this work in fact the
main benefit to having an android studio
installed is that it has an emulator but
we're never going to use their emulator
because it is not figuratively literally
10 times slower than genymotion I'm
sorry
it's horrible yes it is horrible but
understanding how he doesn't exist
well fine on understanding how Android
applications are developed will make you
a much better tester let's put it that
way so having absolutely installed is is
very good that said you can get my with
just installing the command line tools
and they are very small so adb is the
android I think android debugger is what
it stands for is that it and did you
guys do well that's where you want to
talk cheeks my dulcet tones I'm working
on it
ah freaking windows he had and linux i
can just press ctrl+ just ok so a BB is
other people in the room who don't know
what a DB is please tell me there are so
a.d.d is allows you to send commands to
a connected android device genymotion
automatically connects the device so
it's as if it's plugged in with the USB
cable so if i run adb I have to do
nothing else
well list right ed adb clients to be
devices right so what
on my one device right in the moment the
best thing you can do here is you can
login now I'm route on that machine just
like it's linux box and any not anything
most of what you can do in Linux you can
now do standing here i can look at the
directories and process wise the in all
honesty there's a lot of things you can
do the most important thing you can do
is install the app exercise it and then
get it settings
okay all the stuff saved on the device
you're gonna have to look around and I'm
i'm working on a tool that looks for
changes a lot of different places but
that's going to be a ways out arm and
there are very expensive tools you can
use that will tell you all all the
changes that have occurred because of a
given application are but for our
purposes and for the the vast majority
of applications arm
you just need to look in our data data
and all of the settings for each chapter
in there you can then log out and you
can do a pull
so it's a TB pull the Nets . . web that
arm
oh no i'm sorry but you got to the
directory arm and they are very
throughout the save the file oh no did
one but you get the general i for i
deleted the pole that's good
oh my god they're now there's nothing in
it so it was very exciting but that's ok
you get the idea
I thought there'd be something that I
anyway it but you get to do you you will
pull down everything that not everything
ok
it is possible to save things in other
places but ninety-seven percent of all
applications just saved to the default
android locations which is going to be
in data arm if the developer will have
had gone to extreme lengths to save
elsewhere so tremendously much the the
application that the most developed
applications are going to save that
location then you can go and look for
inappropriately safe values like the
private keys or passwords URLs that our
internal any of the normal stuff you
look for in a web assessments arm and
benefit of linux box you probably know
where things are better than me are you
download oh so getting the APK ok so
there's two ways to get the APK by far
the easiest way is to ask if you're
doing a legal assessment which please
hopefully you don't have to say that
here um ask the developer for the APK it
is by far the easiest thing to do if
you're doing the assessment for like one
of your company's android applications
go to the dev team say add media hockey
I want to be able to download the apk
and then download the apk and there are
a lot of reasons why that makes things a
lot easier
that said there is now a chrome
extension i kid you not I did what I
when I first wrote this talk there was a
lot of different things you use there's
literally a chrome extension or you can
go to the store on in chrome and it will
get the APK for you when you save your
machine it on a pc or mac or anything on
anything on problem
um so it's called apt downloader and
just you can probably just search chrome
for APK and find the latest one
it's super easy to get a BP now so
that's that's that's very that's a very
easy very easy piece of this
ok so
so we've gone over arm how to set up a
virtual machine
we've gone over how to setup our our
proxy we have gone over how to access
the settings and get into the internals
of the android application from RPC are
so there's a couple other things that
you can do
oh the first one is not there
ok so oh ok so LinkedIn who was recently
purchased by Microsoft are built a tool
called harp that is an Android scanner
and it's actually kinda cool arm it is
on can help and i recommend you download
it and run against your apk file it's
super easy to use so it's just thrown
right and we say we have anything and it
does provide a path and we say that a
man
oh now my linux skills going to get
pressed here so it's you know I just do
home roots or tour would trying out wow
see this is why we don't do live demos
people but this one boring besides yeah
i mean with by Scripps and then it's a
see anyway yeah can you / route there's
not all after /i happen
oh my gosh
its expertise alright you can call up to
be with my nazi not working
wow this thing's not liking that ok so
do / right here exploit pk's slide
well let me that welcome
oh that's it doesn't have them always
alright nothing in there that's actually
tested that your arm
what it will do is it will use apktool
to decompile the application and then it
will do a static analysis the
application and find all that low
hanging fruit so if they have all the
stuff that you presume you're an Android
developer probably don't even know
exists like unprotected activities so
Android application can can leave an
activity open so other applications can
open it and that is very dangerous
because you can then build a vulnerable
area and malicious application that will
spin up your application and do nasty
things with it it will also find like
buttons that don't have a tap through
protection on them all these things you
have to look for manually it's a very
simple tool and it prints out a
super-nice HTML report me and so i
highly recommend you use it even though
it's really tough to do on a really big
screen like this arm but it's it's a
it's python it probably would run in
windows I just don't usually run python
absolute windows so i have been running
on my cali instance are definitely
something you should look at but even
better is armed
oh no I'm sorry it says linux only here
in my notes apparently it doesn't run
linux for some reason I don't know why
I'm so that's one of the few write that
did it is that is run on linux so we can
also use a wonderful modders tool called
virtuous ten this is another app that's
so good i paid for it
arm it is a tool that is designed to
allow people to skin applications for
platforms where that's allowed like
cyanogen arm and it's literally I mean
the guys the road that the guy that
wrote initially in Sweden where high
school
kits and and so it's a windows app our
mitts off and obviously has the dotnet
look about it
arm but it is extraordinarily powerful
it will allow us to go in and modify the
Smalley code which is like the runtime
arm pieces of this arm with modifying
and then recompile the app and reinstall
it
so if you have an application where
potentially a user could do was on the
privilege escalation by modifying the
application use somebody else's data
this is the tool that the attacker would
use to do it and what's more this is
tool you can use to find fall flaws in
the underlying Smalley code and there
are a lot of guides out there to help
you do that
not least of which being the arm
uh oh awesome android pentesting a cheat
sheet which is out there somewhere i
should have pulled that up there too but
it's super easy to find you can just
search for it and I'm church structure
also be Android it'll be one of the top
couple couple results so we can go in
and look at the this small code this is
the like . Net Applications compiled on
the IL first before they go into DLLs
and then you can use I'll dazzle to look
at the IL code that's what small yes
ok it is the idea is interpreted
language code you can go in and look at
this underlying code for potential flaws
like for instance if you want to know
how they're calling the services
what kind of authentication method
they're using you can see it in the URLs
but if you want to see how they're
constructing the URLs and if they're
getting a value from somewhere else in
the device that maybe will be used to
you as an attacker then you can find it
using virtuous 10 is extraordinarily
powerful tool for the pen tester on
however I warned you it is incredibly
fragile and in fact I am when I the
first time you gave the talk it work
oh and i had to just describe it like
very similar to the car park this time
um I i had some
I had some difficulties with it and so I
haven't subscribed i'm very glad that I
got to work out I literally got a java
update the night before and it
completely broke completely broke the
application even though it's written in
dotnet because the android apps for java
apktool requires a certain Java
framework to run so there are tons and
settings you have to get extremely thin
layer whoa those do not fit in this
monitor nevermind a very familiar with
as far as your apk version and you have
to make sure that like your framework is
tied into the vm the apps running on its
super picky
fortunately there is extraordinarily
good documentation so if you're serious
about this getting good with this tool
make your life a lot easier
um so you want to look at the at the the
arm you want to look at smaller for the
underlying source code you want to look
at the manifests arm for flaws in there
as well so the manifest is the config
file for an application and what
developers like to put a big files
everything especially if their web
developers will primarily like the think
of the config file is something that a
user can get access to well obviously
that's not the case here right so that
is something that we want to look at
um there's there's all kinds of the
other original up starts right here you
can check and see what search are loaded
into it you can look for vulnerable
libraries right which there are a ton of
Android by looking to the lib folder
very very powerful tool
ok oh so I'm not gonna actually pull up
a spreadsheet action internet access
no yeah all going
so literally it's just this is it folks
and said this is here's your test plan
right there on the loss webpage frankly
like all your other test plans if you
take a minute to look ok the test guys
out there
SVS is out there the cheat sheets are
don't tell me you don't know how to test
for things once you have the tool set
which is what I'm giving you hear the
test plan is right there
copy the stuff over to a spreadsheet
making duplicate of it for your test
check each one if you don't have to do
it look it up if it's still know how to
do it send me a tweet I'll help
so there's there's your test plan it's
you know it's it's as simple as that arm
there are a lot of other guidelines out
there for test plans but a ton of it is
just you know use your head
user had think through what it is you're
looking for and go and look for it so
that's the so that's basically might my
core process but sometimes you have to
run on metal so when you do that you end
up setting up a device level test
environment and that is what i have here
this is my test physical phone where is
this useful
this is useful if you are doing anything
device-specific with the application so
if you're using the candy app uses the
camera though admittedly genymotion is
that pretty well the app uses Bluetooth
the app uses gps anything of that nature
arm then you but I'm not done
gosh hacking D'Arnot then you'd be able
to go into things that we're going to
try this and see how this works yeah I
know you can do better
that's not how steelmaking people leave
you scared them all
so this is this is a one plus one case a
mobile phone manufacturer out of of
China that makes arm it makes seven
hundred dollar phones for 300 dollars
arm and the oneplus one has a benefit of
being one of the only seven devices that
will run cali net hunter so cali not
hunter is a pen test suite for android
now it is not actually for testing
android apps for doing regular pen
testing there are network tools on here
and are the all kinds of little stuff
Wi-Fi tests and that's a plant
I shouldn't have that on there to do
just ignore that piece okay arm there is
a fun food right fine are all kinds of
great all kinds of great tools to help
you test a wireless network using a
mobile device super awesome but it also
has the benefit of being well hardened
and are rooted and it will work really
well for application testing as well as
for your arm is for your regular dentist
needs so i strongly recommend you track
down one of the phones that that her
runs on and use that for your regular
testing regular application testing
situation
yeah there's no better yet so there's
here's net hundreds of all kinds of cool
tools in here you can see VNC manager
Mac changer duck hunters on your end map
all these various and sundry digital pen
test tools but we can also do exactly
the same thing we did before right where
we go in and add in that proxy
so that we can watch the traffic from
here through burp suite visually
AirDroid pushes to this device that's
the only thing i've done with it I can
go run chrome or something do you guys
know it's because it's connected so once
again separate device running through
burb works great see what else was going
to say about this
so yeah if you don't have a richer own
rooted android phone look it up it's
easy are other than that it's runs it
with this works exactly like using a the
vm exactly the same detail so that's
about it
good there's one thing i want to talk
about so i'm working on a tool i the the
so anybody familiar with retired IAS yes
it is the library that is being
maintained by the community of of known
vulnerable javascript libraries which if
any of you are doing any vulnerability
assessment you know that javascript
libraries are big deal these days most
applications use some some applications
use nothing but um it is absolutely
essential to be running that as a butt
plug in if you're doing web assessments
there's no way you're going to remember
that some obscure toolkit is um is
vulnerable and looking up each one takes
forever so please run if you're doing
what assessments but there isn't
anything for android assessments so I'm
building one arm and it uses the same
pattern as retirement jazakallah khairan
IDK i've got the repository set up in
the same configuration obviously don't
have much in here now just got started
on this a couple weeks ago arm so if
anyone is interested in it doesn't so
this isn't for the this isn't for
everyone necessarily if you're involved
in the android security scene and you
know the vulnerable libraries and you
would like to participate or if you want
to get into it then this is a great way
to kick in
um I haven't yet actually written
my my core code yeah I got it figured
out like a android APK files just a zip
file you can actually if you want to do
super basic analysis you can change .
zip and just open it in 7-zip something
if you want arm so on and then we're
gonna do you know we're going to regex
and pick up those projects commands and
running from there so I i just got
started on this so it doesn't do
anything yet it's not ready for anything
it doesn't actually work at all but arm
it will sue and I think that will be a
good addition to the scanning tools that
are out in place so that pretty much
covers that I think he's gonna go give
me a hand and just a minute here so arm
oh really it's it's so i will take any
questions anyone has but frankly i'll
also be hanging around the con all
evening and into that tomorrow be here
all day of my wife's Gabrielle is in the
back she's the pretty blonde
yeah very good yeah that's good um and
uh and she's really easy to find because
she's a pretty blonde and not a dumpy
white guy like most of the rest of us
are so if you see here i'll be near want
your body but I'll take any questions
you've got right now to go
sure are so the question is strategies
for absolute install a rooted device
um I hate to be this way but google it
there are there are a lot of tools out
there that hide that from you
nope no it works just fine hey if you're
leaving her shop so that the people who
want to ask questions can question or
good
ok question over here
think about all the way back to java
virtual stendhal do that
um there's the the standard Java hell is
it the standard tool will will roll back
I just don't have it configured for auto
care arm but yeah it's it's it's just
it's built right into the 280 apktool so
apktool is the underlying technology for
all of this right for all that
decompiling arm and it's it's it's a
queer actively maintained on github and
you can go there and find things for it
and there are settings for apktool that
the roll all the way back to the job if
you want and and virtuous 10 will will
handle those settings
yes absolutely absolutely
yeah that's that's absolutely and
unfortunately there's no good automated
way to do that arm but but what you can
but you can definitely do is arm I'll
review the manifest that's that's really
where it's all at are all of the
permissions required are in the
manifests and you can analyze them and
balance them against what has been asked
for and makeup make a decision for your
route 44 whether or not they're asking
for something they don't need now with
android 4 and up they can't use
something they haven't explicitly ask
the user for by rule arm there's no way
around that even on a auto rooted
machine there's no way around it
you have to have it in the manifest to
use it if you don't ask for right
external storage your app simply does
not see the SD card it's just not there
are so it'sit's very solid arm but that
doesn't mean that users won't look
because users well
look he just say okay they want to
install the app you just say okay so if
you're reviewing apps for your own
company going through and looking at
that and calling them and saying do you
actually need the microphone because if
not I would like that not be in your
manifest that's a very reasonable thing
to do
yes so the question was how hard is it
to cut a UH activity out of the manifest
earn operational manifest so you mean
from the developer's perspective or do
you mean afterwards you know I've never
tried that arm it should technically be
possible using using rituals 10 i'll
have to try it and if you use twitter
find me on Twitter or find me any one of
the hundreds super easy to find and end
and remind me and I'll try it and let
you know probably long you down okay i'm
done i'll be a mark on i'll be around
i'm easy to find it super easy to find
me on Twitter look me up love to talk
android ok