that we're going to get started alright
so welcome everybody to beyond the Crypt
practical iOS reverse-engineering my
name is michael allen and I I'm a
security consultant with Iowa obviously
i'm interested in mobile assessing
mobile applications but I also do
penetration test code reviews
vulnerability assessments and so on
incidentally I walked we are hiring and
so if you are interested in joining the
fire chip then just hit me up outside
and other more than happy to field your
questions so why the start
partially you know based on my own
personal experience when i started
protesting for example mobile
applications
I couldn't hear our didn't pay attention
to what was happening Underwood right I
pretty much just run the common to that
were often recommended got some results
and that was pretty much it
and I work for a while but then you know
I . I get a snug and so I had to change
my approach and so there might the
persons who are here know who are
currently at that point and would like
to move beyond it or it could be that
you have been you have been testing
third-party applications and you kind of
want to move beyond that and get more
into iOS the iOS system itself and also
the fact is that a lot of the common
books that you would usually find using
the approach that you'd normally see be
recommended on blood and so on are
pretty much clothes and so you know at
some point you're going to have to
change your approach so
I the outline interpretations we're
going to start with the current state of
the union right so we're gonna look on
the common tools that are currently
available know the results they are
produced and it's going to bring us up
to the point where we realize that you
know a lot of common bugs are no clothes
and so we're gonna have to change our
program and that new approach is going
to involve a deeper understanding of
what's happening under the hood so we
look at what a muckle binder is one of
my task is look at objectives en suite
from a reverse engineers perspective and
then we'll wrap up with identifying you
know simple Jeffrey detection routines
and how they can be bypassed all right
so the first thing is you're gonna you
know need to build your to attend so
we're going to look at they the common
to get started you know kind of general
to get that you'd see often being
recommended know so we just go through
this so the first thing is of course
you're going to need a jailbroken device
and jailbroken is jailbreaking the
process of jailbreaking is just removing
the restrictions that have been informed
by iOS right you are weakening the
security posture of the device because
you are exploiting vulnerabilities and
so the recommendation is to have a
dedicated testing device the latest
jailbreak public rubric no ice Pangu 92
93 on the supported on 64 bit devices on
their private jailbreaks I understand
for example Lucas test for just you know
published it and then briefing
what's a jobro the types of jailbreak
head on over requires a computer to
start advice on Ted it's the opposite
and semi is a mixture of of the two so
late as fungal jailbreak is semi 10 as
each time the device gets restarted you
have to run the application again to
read your brief advice just some tips
here change the Department password from
alpine I would you know also encourage
you to access the device over USB
instead of using Wi-Fi and Soyuz you
know USB box d you're pretty much on tcp
really specify your port would also
recommend that you generate your use ssh
keys generate your keys
copy your public key over and also add
an area for your device so that you
don't have to be typing in the password
every single time you want to access the
device
alright moving five you're going to want
to move well during an assessment you're
going to want to move fire between your
horse and the device itself recommended
to use ifunbox I explorer but really you
don't necessarily need those schools
you're going to be accessing the device
over ssh anyway so you can always use
SFTP I've also had problems with a
particular tweet for iphone box on the
AFC to has given you some trouble so you
could just use SFTP intercepting network
traffic most applications are going to
need well speak to a back-end server
usually over HTTP HTTPS the defect or
two for intercepting traffic is bourke
street you could of course use a party
that attack proxy but they they the main
tool Pittsburgh sweet and so you have
burb running on your host machine
assigned to an IP listen a particular
port and then from your device you
configure your device to connect to that
machine on that particular port as well
right now the problem you run into that
most of the application these days use
ssl painting which means the certificate
is no in the binary itself unsorted
bypass that you use ssl to switch is
eric you switch over is no longer be
maintained and so the new thing with ssl
kill switch to and pretty much it's just
that we
it wouldn't start and you enable and
disable as required keep in mind that
when you do enabling you are disabling
SS certification across the entire by
which again goes back to the
recommendation of having a dedicated
test device right so instrumentation the
usual 20 again is script so you
basically injections or process you get
a interactive console and the sin that
is you know mixture of objective-c
javascript only supported right now on
iOS and OS X and just recently the folks
over at no secure 24 so they replaced
the run time the script runtime is no
power by freedom and incidentally the
talking and Michael beyond the script no
this is not a knock against scripts up
powerful tool but you do in fact one of
more beyond that then the target just
aimed at laying that foundation so how
do you script pretty much specify the
specific the process ID that you are
interested in instrumenting and then
just run script minus P provide the ID
and that's it you're in the interactive
monsoon whereas we said the synthesis
objective-c javascript the new hotness
however is Frieda this thing is pretty
much on steroids crack cocaine heroin
you name all right so it allows you to
inject the google v8 engine into the
target process and so that JavaScript
know has full access to the process
memory support function cooking access
to native methods but more importantly
you can inject into a starting process
right i mean it also supports up a whole
lot more architectures than those
stripped and so with the combination of
the freedom runtime engine and the
script interactive console you know how
the best of all worlds
I'm so this is just a very simple
example of using freedom and in this
example we were just you know highlight
specifying a particular application that
would like to instrument and we want to
see every time in particular method is
called and so the minus U is over USB
receiver is for functions that start
like that and we're just racing each
time one is God but this is merely
stretching that not even scratching the
surface like i said i'm a lot of tools
these are no powered by freedom during
an assessment there are some common
tasks that you know I'm gonna go through
right and so on these include things
like you know checking the keychain
looking at the logs and you know just
some one day and asked and so there are
tools that automate all of these common
task and some are listed here are they
however have varying levels of support
so for example stupid no longer
supported on so the exam and the one
that's interesting is leaving this was
really just reset the at our black until
the example here is shown up
you know I Demi tune logging teaching
dumping provides just general up info
I'm and pretty much looks like this
right and then the fact that most of
your work is going to be done in the
from a command line and so you're gonna
need some essential tools and so the
recommendation again his usual to use
big boss or Erica youtube but I'd also
like to recommend using the iOS been
packed which is a number of tools that
have been compiled for iOS platform by
jonathan levin
I'm some examples of the bynars that are
included in that is being but are listed
here
keep in mind and my recommendation would
be so you get a tire fire that you
pretty much switch over to your root
directory and Justin tired and all the
five get copied to where they're
supposed to go i have lost jailbreaks
because of that because some binary
didn't play well with some of the
install the tweaks that i had so if
you're going to go this room may I
suggest you choose the binder that
you're interested in capital what's your
device rather than just using them all
I'm spoken to him about this and you
know he has said that he has used it on
several devices with no issues so it it
may have been that in a couple of weeks
that i had installed a cosmetician so
keep that in mind
alright so that's the you know basic to
get that you usually see and so now
we're going to get into what usually
happens during a an assessment right so
again let's go back to look into setting
traffic the application is going to
communicate to a back-end server you can
use birth or you could set up a remote
virtual interface so you plug the device
in to itunes get the udid grab that ID
and then just run RBI CTL minus s device
ID that brings up an interface and then
you can just move on that interface you
can write to a peach up five and then
you can use your you know network to
your favorite network tool then parts at
five right in secure storage most of the
attacks are based on insecure storage so
properties files stores she realized
objects that appears sometimes they are
in binary format but you can use the .
you tool to convert that in this example
this is photowall storing the access pin
my super secure access pin in the
feeling by in plain text right so you
have information leakage here transit
data stores sequel databases most often
are used for planetside storage just a
lightweight France I database when you
you know Korean using SQL again you
might find sensitive information being
stored and in this example we're seeing
the administrator username and password
again means toward implanted fun talk
about sequin about sequel I believe
doesn't actually do what you think so
when you delete data it gets added to
freely right and those three records are
not overwritten two more space is
required
the end result of that is that the data
might not be for working for wire and it
can therefore be recovered something to
keep in mind and there are of course
tools that will allow you to recover the
data dump in the keychain another good
it's just a sequel database stored in
bar keychains you can courage again
using the secret three command to force
people like three people like three
command-line tool would be in the
repositories that we spoke about earlier
or just use teaching dumper and don't
the entire contents of the key chain
itself right snapshots launched an iOS
application iOS application goes into
the background takes a snapshot and you
know exactly where to find that snapshot
might store sensitive information again
and so it's you know one of those places
that people usually check for $MONEY
Josh's so the application directory is
going to have a ashes directory and that
caches directory functions almost
similar to your web browsers cache
pretty much in that improving
performance and again it may store web
cache content and mr. sensitive
information again and so it's just a
bunch of tables and you interact with it
through the sequel I'd three command
again
come online tool again something by
newark is wonderful is created by the
euro loading system stored on the file
system in binary format of course the
assumption made by the developers is
that fits it if it's a binder if it's in
binary format nobody will be able to get
to it
of course there are tools that allow you
to parse that and pretty much free
tonight
ibc inter-process communication
I'm so the application registers a
custom URL scheme under the application
is involved in the urine scheme that's
called and so usually you would don't
the application binary and then you
would probably run streams on the
application binary or you could created
peerless I'm and then you would grip for
a particular string right well and this
was abused back in the day by how about
where you could pretty much in vogue sky
through Europe scheme will be used as
content make premium cards right and so
the recommendation here are the tools
that i would recommend you using is LSD
trip and to use the public or private
URLs option i pretty much gives you the
same thing and then some problem though
is as we mentioned when we started out a
lot of these bugs are not being cold and
so the URL attack your team attack is
pretty much dead in iOS 9 because know
they have introduced universal links
right and so the developer can now
specify the high
that will be open for process by the
application communication is done over
HTTPS and also print is nine you could
enumerate what apps are installed and
advise using the chance openurl method
that's no longer the case
so just an example of you know common
bug that you'll find that are no code
injection attacks were abused injecting
into webviews 500 routines xml attacks
and so on
I'm so the point of this is keep in mind
that the issues that you identify with
local storage are only valid are on the
work when the device is unlocked right
some other common results that you might
find have to do with on security is
which you would find you know using burp
suite or some hard-coded secrets but the
fact is that with each other version of
iOS more and more of the common bugs are
being closed that so pretty much binary
protections are are no standard at least
in most of the third party app that you
see and then you know if the developer
makes good use of the data protection
ap is that's another thing that we just
mentioned that Universal links were
introduced in iOS 9 that killed the IPC
Lupul so question we have to ask
ourselves then in what happens when you
are in the common to steal or what
happens when Google your google fool
doesn't return anything right or there
might be custom security protection
protections in place or you might want
to extend an existing tool . is at this
point we're going to need to change our
approach right and so
moving towards this new approach and I
put new in quotes because i know that
some people will argue that there's
nothing about this are there's no such
thing as new in in closet so I just put
this interview write in codes you're
changing your prunes and it's going to
start with a better understanding up iOS
internal right and so we're going to
look at what happens on the hood get
into arm 32 64 just a little bit of a
deep dive into objective-c and sweet you
know like what happens under word from a
reverse engineering perspective so the
first thing we need to do is kind of
improve our toolkit
so what does the reverse engineers to
look like disassemblers a pro shopper
and we'll go through this no idea pro
kind of the photo tool that it comes to
reverse engineering chances are you
happy if you're buying individually you
will have to sell a body part or two it
is extremely expensive but I in my
opinion
Ida is to reversing what burp suite is
to web fantastic right and it's very you
know extended you can extend it writer
on plugins strips
I mean an entire top could be given on
just I'd alone and the i think the most
recent version 695 also supports iOS
remote debugging right hopper scaling
down a whole lot more
just a couple hundred bucks doesn't
support as many architectures as I de
but it's enough to at least get you
going right and i think--not just
support
on OSX i think but don't quote me on
that
leb so Ellie be replaced gb just an
example here I'm so it's a plan server
setup so you copy the debug server onto
your testing device and then on the
client you simply connect to it right so
on the mobile device you're on the debug
server it's gonna listen on a particular
port connection comes in launches the
application during business and you know
an example is shown here you can just
some tips so pretty much what would
happen is you launch the application or
you would have the application binary
you would have the binary opened in your
favorite disassembler my nephew and then
you would be interested in setting up
great points at the particular offset so
you drop that offset and then you would
from the ellen vtune you would first of
all launch the application on the device
itself and then you would connect and
then you would run for example image-
list to list the images grab the slide
the SLR offset and then at that slide to
the offset that you are interested in
setting the bird . on of course you
don't need to go through all of this if
the application has symbology but always
get the bird . on the symbols but mom
it's just up and i'll step multiple ways
of doing the same thing
j 2 j tool is the new hotness
so usually you would co2 will be
recommending right but an O'Toole is the
Michael binary Swiss carbonite but Jay
tool offers prototype functionality with
a lot more options right so you can do
Michael analysis you know each other on
strings & M supported on multiple
platforms OSX iOS and it's a arm support
assembly and so an example is shown here
of dumping
the text section of a simple binary
using the gentle- the option on the
bonus though is that Jada will also
operates on the chair catch and for
those who may not be familiar shared
cache is a single file with sealing
system libraries gets loaded once and
then is shared by all other processes
alright i'm using a tool you can list
the libraries that are in the sharecash
one and if you are interested in you
know extracting that library to go and
do like further research it will also
facilitate that and if you're interested
in him the shirt ash can be abused
i would recommend checking out angles
talk at black hat heard of this year
Frank exp getting no task related info
so you can display threads my ports dunk
or image and a whole lot more and then
of course there's gb no longer
well when I was putting this together it
was not supported on you no harm 624
architectures and so you're left with
using LED be a five-month are useful
tool if you want to see the haha one
application interact with the file
system very useful but of course it so
it traces the file system activity using
a press event right very useful and then
there is the Apple CC tools so you have
a tool which we mentioned earlier on
Marcos spider-knight you have NM for
dumping symbols lipo or thin and binary
the binder may-maybe a fat binder which
means that it supports multiple
architectures you might just be
interested in a particular architecture
so you use my photo in the binary under
school sign for binary signing truth is
you need none of this jay tool pretty
much does all of this and denser right
so we look at the common to come on
tests realize or limitation realize that
we need to change our approach and so we
improve our toolkit and we're going to
get into the fun part of the top which
is you know reverse-engineering iOS
applications and what happens on the
hood so we're going to look at the we're
going to start with the buckle binder
former then move into ma simply i'm
going to introduce arm 32 64 and have
very high level and then look at what
happens under hood with Objective C and
should write know every away as its own
binary former windows as PE linux has
dealt Marco OS X and iOS have model
right and this is because that a brief
history lesson at the heart of iOS or
sex with the ex a new current and at the
heart and ex- that the colonel is has
like three major layers of the vsd I ok
and Marco right and so at the heart of X
and nupur note in the mock my program
alright so of course if you're going to
do any assessments on the finer the
application binary you need to know
where it is right
so in part is it formal application and
then iOS 8 and beyond a spirited so no
the application binary is that one
location and the data that the applicant
that binder uses that are not a location
and then in iOS 9.3 x I realized that no
the applicant the pop binary is in
Argentina bundle application but
lighting just something to know so what
is this michael binary quite simply has
a header followed by a number Lord
commands followed by data right the
header to pretty much indicates whether
or not the binary is a
32-bit or 64-bit binary also indicates
the architecture that it supports the
file type also indicates whether or not
it is a dynamic library 45 executable
and so on and then there are a number of
lugs and incidentally some of these
flags are what you would check for
during an assessment so you would
usually check to see if the binder was
compiled using you know SLR and so you
check for the pipeline so using j tool
minus h2 doctor had a minor v4 to
increase for verbal stresses there such
a word and you dumb the head right
no the binary is going to have a number
of instructions and these instructions
are going to be essentially determine
how the binary gets mapped into memory
right and these instructions
some are gonna be processed by the
colonel and some are going to be
processed by the dynamic linker alright
we refer to these instructions as Lord
commands know the one of the most
important or commands is Elsie segment
on a segment is pretty much remember
regions that have the same read/write
executable protection right so the as
you said some of them are going to be
some of these commands are going to be
hunted by the corner
some are going to be hunted by the
dynamic linking all right so things that
the current will handle are like LC
encryption input that deals with
encryption dlc code signature that deals
with code signing and code-signing is
heavily you on iOS ilc made the miners
main entry point right well and so what
are these segments um you usually see
page 0 for no point of traps and that
segment usually has all its access
permissions revolt
so for gamblin
64-bit architectures the entirety of its
base will be dedicated to bid or the
first four games and then you have the
text segment music program coord data
segment rewritable program data think it
symbols ever used by the dynamic linker
and then you have the restrict and
restrict segment prevents you from force
loading your own dynamic libraries using
the UIR the insert libraries environment
variable option and then each segment is
going to have an optional section
what does this look like just an example
here but the doctor segment you just use
j 2 minus F mr. segment example shown
here or if you prefer to use a GUI
option you could always use the
ever-popular Michael you to write so
after the colonel is done doing what it
does it has over processing to the
dynamic linker and the linker pretty
much is going to resolve among other
things symbols and it's going to load
each l-look it's going to load each LC
Lord dial in command so if you go back
to the for the bye run around where
right so if you go back to the battery
you see a bunch of LC LC Lord dilated at
the bottom it
dialing is going to load those commands
and also the LC Lord dialing can specify
specifies which value will be used in
this case / user live valid also very
important
the dynamic linker support in supposing
or method touching and so all you need
to do is at the interposed section to
the data segments and you could force
load your library's again using
the URL the insert libraries environment
variable I'm just a note that code that
has the attribute constructor will alter
on
so in your dynamic library code that has
they attribute the constructor once at
the dynamical ever gets loaded it will
order on and so most people might be
familiar with dynamic libraries music if
you use dump the cryptid for injecting
into a process and dumping the binary
itself because miners from the app store
are encrypted and so but once they get
executed unloaded into memory they are
unencrypted don't the cryptid inserts
the a dynamic library is the binder Oh
plaintext food so what are not map tasks
so at this point the barn is loaded into
memory right on other systems you would
call this a process in the world--love
mark this is a task as with other
systems processes need to talk to each
other and so you have inter-process
communication to facilitate
inter-process communication each task as
a port to port is simply an IPC end .
the point here very important point here
is if you are able to put on that Court
you own that process and by own I mean
you have full control of that process
the logical question is how do you own
that for two options you can use the
mark trap task for . where you party in
the process ID of the process that you
are interested in get a hand
done depending on the jailbreak if it is
passed for top 40
that means that you could read current
remember right the other option is
processor set talks which will be no
return a sport in the system so as we
said owning the passport means you own
the process and so you to interact with
the task the task support once you have
it it's pretty much up it's pretty much
left up to your imagination as to what
you wanted to you could rewrite member
with using the portal mark vapi you
could inject her own show cord pretty
much left of what you want to do an
example is shown here tasks Finn grab
support and then you passed that hand of
into in this example my vm region that's
an example dumping memory you can write
your own code again
so you're pretty much grab they get the
passport use them up vm api's read
member are quite simple you could use
rocket speed using the region's option
which so you from exp process ID regions
options and then you take the reason
that you are interested in facet to leb
don't fit right into a five popular file
off the device and you're good
so arm assembly course we're targeting
our devices here i'm so very quickly 32
I'm 32 bunch of registers are 0-2 r12
you know general purpose we have our
start point that we have our link
register which stores the return address
top on car and we have the ar-15 in the
program counter what is important though
is to understand how functions are
invoked and hope parameters are passed
the functions so are 0-2 archery first
four function parameters return is
usually stored in the stock from concern
book using a weekend brunch brunch and
Exchange where branch and exchange means
you're going to be an arm and thumb mode
branch and link
return address is stored in the link
register grunting can exchange
combination of officer basic coding
instructions it's a arm is a load store
and so before you can use data must be
loaded into a register right and Hawaii
remember this is loading goes from
right-to-left story goes from left to
right that's it
arms support lot more registers so no
you have x0 268 you know general-purpose
64-bit registers the busier 2w 30 32 bit
of course you have your usual suspects
again 3-pointers and so on
I'm but the and again how no arguments
get past the functions and so on an
entire talk could be just under section
alone
alright so this is just to introduce you
to just enough to at least get you
started
objective-c iOS
Andy care of
fortunately you have a video problem
with the other media's and you don't
have the audio to about the 38-minute
mark but we get that back up shortly
sorry
and all this topic
does is you click on a button check to
see if a certain file exists and if it
does Prince the device is jailbroken if
not it's not jailbroken food that's in
function gets translated to this Alaskan
thing that you're seeing here
alright so first thing on the sporty
symbol F indicates that it's a function
then you have to see that indicates it's
a function that belongs to a class then
you have the module name prefix then you
you have the class name prefixed with
Len function name prefix then this is 0
PS i have no clue what that it so if
somebody is here who knows what that
means
please tell me when the talk is done and
then you have function attribute
followed by your parameter on your
return type you don't have to do this by
handle you could use the Swift the
Mongol tool to assist or if you're using
proper there are plugins that automate
this process for you
alright so we're going to get into your
protection routines simple their break
detection routines we can identify them
and how we can bypass so we're going to
know you know trying to apply some of
the things that we discussed earlier on
and see how we general bypass simple
divert attention routine before so we're
going to discuss minor budget estimate
that we're going to use before we
proceed
yes you could do this with several other
tools you could use ex-con she has
protect up officer in fact some of the
virtue that we discussed earlier on
freedom for example you could use to
accomplish some of the things that we're
going to discuss know right now but the
question again is what happens when you
can and so the idea behind this section
is really to introduce you to assembly
right
like I said when I started out I just
run the common tools didn't care much
for the essence and so this section is
just fine in that introducing you
to assembly right with some of the best
way to do that i thought was to use like
some simple examples as a binary
touching 11 you can replace an
instruction we are not know operation
could change up you know conditional
instructions to unconditional one so
branch not equal just a branch of the
register its own and going back to that
restrict segment as I said sometimes
you're going to encounter biner that
prevents you from force loading your own
dynamic library because of the district
segment we're going to have to add or
remove the article on jabber detection
routines jailbroken idevice usually
results in some artifact to be left
behind the one that we're going to look
at quickly lon five parts inline
functions checking to see the sandbox is
still intact and some methods that
developers might use to deny the body
simple routine here so we have our is
your broken function and it just checks
to see whether are not certain files
exist city up store at the stage but
what does it look like from a reverse
engineers perspective simple we should
call it too or is jailbroken function
return value get stored in register w8
we see a comparison against 0 with
registered late and then a branch so all
we need to do is about this check is
such that comparison don't like I said
pretty straightforward and simple
some might say okay but this is a
contrived example nobody does this enter
in ticketmaster you install the app on
the device pretty much always you to
purchase tickets from for a number of
events right installed on a jailbroken
device from to that you know jailbreak
is detected open it up in a disassembled
and you see again checks for known five
parts some common five parts and then
reading through you realize that there's
a comparison between register that
there's a move instruction that moves r1
into register w 9 and then w9
is stored on it later use that later on
in the application to determine the
state up to determine whether or not the
device and jailbroken all you need to do
is write a 0 to register the nine and
it's done well
inline functions basically change the
declaration of function know instead of
seeing a clear branch to our jailbroken
function we're now looking at the body
of the function itself and all this does
it just increases our time that would
normally spend reverse engineer because
know you're gonna have to read through
the entire assembly right but again
usually there's some comparison and so
if you could find a comparison and
update register and again here we're
seeing compares not tolerate again some
value and based on the results a
particular branch is taken all we need
to do is update this command for in a
properly function in sandbox the call 24
should fear from a reverse engineers
perspective again you see the car park
reading through the assembly again we
see a comparison up
what is that double it again and based
on the results that I checked we see a
branch again all we need to do is update
this particular from person to take the
branch that we want pretty
straightforward but to get to this point
it just means that you have to not be
afraid of the SMN just read you the
instructions right features prevents you
from chasing the application and so
here's a kiss control car the results it
is then returned in a strop where the
PFLAG is going to have the status as to
whether or not the device has been as to
whether or not the application is being
treated and then we see an and operation
against the PE underscore trees variable
right but this petrus variable is
defined in this product that h is that
body and so if we look in or disassembly
then we
and see the under-construction of w10
against the patriots value and so we
need to do is read the register using
register read we see the value there and
so the bypass check all we need to do is
updated to any aperture about you and in
this instance I just wrote a zero right
so that the under-construction that
check would feel and pretty much done in
i attached you know prevents you from
attaching to process an itouch of course
is defined in sister Beatrice . h as
third one and so I in this instance
again using j tool put the actual
function and the disassembly and so we
see our call to deal open we see the
call to so what is that year
shim so basically we kind of have a kind
of like a one-to-one mapping of what's
going on and then we see and/or
operation against w9 with the value
wanna converting one of the decimal
third one PT denied that value and so
all we need to do this patch that and
you're done
mom I had a simple application
development fit and so I have a in this
instance is jailbroken function that is
implemented in c and in this case it's
just checking to see whether or not
certain files exist similar to what we
did before calling this
sweet call the function check the return
value based on the ballot return printer
particular message from disassembles
perspective or reverse engineering
perspective we again see the mangled
names and in this instance i'm using j
tool again to December that particular
function and of course we see or call
the or jailbroken function value gets
returned in w 0r comparison of 20
against one
so all we need to do is just that
compartment right so wrapping up the
fact is that the common bugs are pretty
much are getting close
alright most miners bdays have the
environment where from the app store how
most of protections that are you know
pretty much standard SLR stop cooking
that kind of thing and so you know we
kind of need to change our approach and
changing that approach involves not
being afraid to look at and read and
make modifications to assemble all right
also if you want to move into iOS into
looking at the Iowa system it show then
you're going to have to you know get
into reversing and so on and you know
this offenders are really your friends
and I would encourage you to add the
reverse engineering skill set to your
arsenal my you know you will i went
discuss some simple algebra detection
routines but there are some commercial
tools that you know our custom and it's
not as straightforward as it and you
know it's going to require you to get
really deep zone both dress similar code
identify what's happening and made the
passion so again mean take away at the
reverse engineering skill set
you're a sinner opens up our whole new
world of testing and that's pretty much
it
and supplement to attack by the way by
the way on so these are they you know if
you are interested in getting more
information on the tools that we
discussed these are the books blog posts
and so on if you are interested for
example in arm exploitation in learning
more about arm expectation zipper SEC
has a very cool course if you're
interested again in iOS OSX
reverse-engineering Jonathan 11 again
also has a very cool course so at least
those two courses will get you started
and on the right track thanks for comin
appreciated