okay so we're gonna start and I'm going
to keep an eye on this whole piece of
trying our level technical difficulties
and because of this because of this
awful piece of technology we do not have
soundtrack which we work very hard
it happens I'll keep an eye on ya serve
them
ok anyway thanks for comin out despite
our our difficulties i'm adam Hogan and
I am rocky Brock word our files are in
the book but what we want to talk about
is how to change a subculture some the
difficulties that come with it and what
we might learn from punk rock so from an
agenda perspective we're going to kind
of outline some goals right at the end
of the day everybody here at this
conference and those of you who have a
tendency to migrate to other cities and
and hang out with other people of
similar mindsets in this community we
are a subculture ok and as a subculture
we have the ability to influence culture
mainstream culture so there's a number
of challenges around that but the goal
really you know new so we're going to be
talking about what our goals are from a
high-level what these challenges happen
actually be we're going to walk through
some group theory is this guy home you
guys on let's turn it on
we're going to walk through some some
group theory and look at some case
studies and talk about complexity theory
look at some case studies
we're going to talk about adaptation and
how systems and organizations even
organisms and therefore organizations
adapt and try to wrap it all together
with some interesting kind of take
ways from our recommendations
perspective alright
explore the back so why care i do the
stable talk here the background of this
talk was basically i'm probably getting
closer that I should start walking
around so the background of that talk
was in the nineties in the eighties and
nineties i was in this indie rock math
rock band and the we released or records
three of which were recorded by steve
albini of anybody has an idea who that
guy is
and so those first three records that we
released in the early nineties just kind
of missed the whole internet streaming
you know technology subset so a bunch of
lunatic fans about two years ago decided
to put together a kickstarter and they
raise twenty six thousand dollars to
basically take the old tapes we release
them into digital format get them back
in to get them into itunes spotify and
all that stuff which it didn't exist in
at the time because all those records
were out of print being from an indie
label that a bunch of indie labels that
had you know basically blown their wad
over a couple years and then disappear
right and as part of this kickstarter
that they put together they also
released the collective recordings of
the band in a 6lp box set with a
200-page history of the bands so this is
really kind of cool
from my perspective since you know that
was really kind of a hobby of mine as i
was building my info SEC career so the
talk that I did last year which is kind
of hey you know you know what I've
noticed being in both of these kind of
subcultures here are some similarities
and here's some things that we can kind
of like shared wall this guy happen to
be watching that talk and within an hour
or so I think
email me this long list like hey that
was really interesting you can really do
much more than you know we can really
extrapolate you know from your original
topic into some really cool things like
group theory involving so there's kind
of part of it it was a really long email
and I'm provo yeah he's very remote and
so my response was that's really cool
put your money where your mouth is let's
let's do a talk with now we got here if
you're looking for a way to talk at your
next conference maybe just her at the
speaker look at the pretty much world
only work
ok so let's talk about some goals right
we all here throughout this industry
that we need to change security culture
there's an inherent problem with that
right because what ends up being the the
reality is that there's these underlying
subcultures within the overarching
corporate mainstream and so as well
we'll kind of talk about as we move
forward here there are very very
patterned and historical difficulties in
changing a culture so we're going to
help you understand how you can try and
influence the wider culture right so
let's I understand what is how it
changes high input the change and we can
try to about right
good now we all accept that difficult
right getting ready to change the
culture and handling it so that's not
new we're not breaking any ground there
but we want to get into how we blend the
ideas we have back into the mainstream
right we're gonna spend an entire
weekend agreeing with each other and
cornerback we know how to do it
user awful day we told him in a
wonderful right well how right when i
learned how to get those ideas back into
the rescue organization right so when we
were moving to challenge right one of
the challenges that we face today
basically security culture change is
attempting to change user assumptions
beliefs etc are changing
check changing beliefs is you know
two-degree almost like that's a popular
belief system if you believe that you
don't need to reuse that if you don't
need to change your password for every
different website that you attend that
you are you have a log into well that's
your own personal belief system is very
difficult to change it is akin to you
know religious beliefs and political
beliefs right and and because we try to
you know corporations try to change
these belief systems from a top-down
perspective right here's a mandated
policy that you need to read you know
have a different password for every
whatever every website that's where all
of this really kind of fall apart right
the mandated top-down policy is not
going to change the end-users belief
system we want to the point where we can
encourage creativity but there's going
to be obvious limit right it's an
awfully creative paying it had to on
your faith but it might be too far i can
really go to the experimentation night
when we created whether certain limit
there and we know that there's an
outlier subculture that's why we like
that on it's great to be around till the
rest of the Nerds our entire weekend
right that an amazing experience
why we come here and what a great extent
of contract to meeting our heads and our
death and trying to convince him around
listen to us to rent the year right ah
and we know we're going to be a little
isolated we're all here because you
loved it right either
I handled stumble into security with the
most part were here in a bad way
spending our weekend to come at the
conference because the absolutely love
with stop going to make it a little
isolated yeah inherently and and you
know again this the people that go on
other way to come to something like a
derby con or any you know intersect /
hacker type conference were all really
kind of the same mindset we like to
break things and and and you know figure
out how they work and potentially fix
them right potentially not all of us you
know
we have the red vs blue and all that
stuff but so along those same lines
right Patrick gray who runs who has his
risky business podcast he always talks
about you you can't teach someone to
love punk rock they just do right and
the same thing really kind of applies
for information security alright but you
know is it is it feasible right can we
mentor and train someone who's not wild
about the 24th that right that's where
we are to its scaling problem first one
higher than willing to live and breathe
this stuff are our passion for this
industry is what drives a lot of our
productivity why we're in the top brand
but no one's got enough people right now
we're . working we've got two without
hiring more people and that you probably
hiring people who come five o'clock one
stop thinking about information theory
and maybe that's a little weird for
someone with it the only way to tell but
we have to be able to reach out across
are very isolated subcultures you are
reach out of the fridge and get you do
to people who are willing to learn if
not from a wildly borderline of death
example right right all of us in here
for the most part are probably following
in their category of this is what we do
and we really like what we do we can be
very frustrated about the lack of
results and really this entire talk is
about how we can fix those like a result
because most of us are probably really
good at what we do but you know we're
not seeing the culture change and and
this really like you know it from my
perspective it's really really important
to try to find some of those fringe
really you know talented outliers who
can communicate with the business can
communicate with the people and
potentially find others within the
organization that they might not have
the same passion about what we do but
they kind of get it and kinda like it
this could be a nine-to-five job right
contributing to the entire system
so recognizing those challenges that
we're going to have to make it happen to
get a culture change let's try and dive
into the music right so let's start with
the definition that is suitably standard
a little dull place to start right but
they didn't you know from Webster right
didn't definition i think actually is
going to help understand because the
standard very lazy definition of
corporate culture it it's the way we do
think okay look a little bit deeper than
that
this one is different from major shine
is a culture of the pattern of shared
tacit assumption that was learned by the
group as it's all problems right because
they worked well and we could and were
considered valid to get that those
illusions are talking to members and
that what team roles become the culture
right so it's not an accident
it's not you know we just happen to have
this culture that would learn all those
behaviors are learned and ultimately
because someone decides this is the way
that works right someone's right it's
all the problem they came up with a way
that work and that where the culture
grew out right now that also tells a bit
why it difficult to change culture right
culture and written up on the whiteboard
you can't erase it one day right up the
new corporate culture because that all
learned behavior and you don't want only
unlearn the way we've been doing things
right you have to actually now show
different solution you have to leave and
get people to learn a new way of doing
things that will roll into being I'll
wider corporate culture right now it
also can show us why sometimes corporate
culture goals in the wrong direction
right because learned behavior doesn't
mean you're right you can learn the
wrong way to do things right
I'm always reminded of Skinner's pigeon
right this charisma first behavioral
psychology experiment where he had like
them half star pigeon any drop some food
in there
well the pigeon develop superstition if
they were turning clockwise in a circle
and the food came out next time they get
hungry during clockwise in the circle
they were convinced they had some active
control right and now that's becoming
part of their culture their learning
this behavior is not right but they
think it and that the know right i'm
making fun of these pigeons for their
ridiculous superstitions i'm wearing my
lucky conscience so it's not
totally related to these ridiculous
visions right now is wet weather whether
there's any logic to it or not if we
have to learn illusion that part of the
culture so here here's what I would like
you to ask yourself right
do you think that your security
organization should be able to change
and adapt
alright so we're kind of at a high level
touched upon culture and subcultures but
at the end of the day the organization
needs to figure out whether this is
possible
alright so once you ask yourself that
now ask do you think your organization
is capable of changing and adapting and
that's the much bigger question that you
know hopefully as we kind of walk
through this set of checkup positive
hypotheses you know that hopefully we
can help your organization's begin to
really kind of change and adapt by
thinking about things a little more in
terms of subculture and how that can
affect culture so let's talk about group
theory how one of the way that
inherently affect our behavior how we
work with a team is whether we hear that
part of the team and this is actually
like a fundamental part of our
psychology the way that actually studied
in the lab and we offer station topic is
my my graduate work within behavior like
now always studying the lab start to
look at studying you know altruism or
cooperative he'd really done is
experiments around game where the rule
are very strictly defined every probably
heard of the prisoner's dilemma is
certainly the most popular experiment
second is the ultimatum game and I throw
how we decide work on the design ideas
all true
the game goes like that there's two
people playing the game I don't know
each other completely anonymous you
never get to each other get player a
gets a hundred-dollar and get to decide
how much of it to give the player DVD
player B decide whether to accept or
reject the offer if you accept they both
get the money if you
Jack nobody get any of the money so if
people are perfectly rational why would
they ever turn down free money free
money free money
great hit better than no money but even
if it's like one percent right now
that's not what happened to run the
experiment in the lab and people
routinely reject offered that are no
less than forty thirty percent right
there have been found routinely and not
just four hundred dollars they went and
did these experiments off on new guinea
with the equivalent of three months
salary they were offering these people
three months salary at that wall but you
get more will screw both of us right and
reject the offer they both got nothing
so we have inherent ideas baby way into
our firm we're not going anywhere of
walk to fair and with not defend right
so i mentioned that the things you don't
take to get to this that that framework
is it done it with a lot of different
variable to explore that and one of the
interesting experiment is my group
membership a lot of experience look at
okay well what's the difference then in
what offered and was accepted based on
whether they're the you know from the
same country whether they're the same
religion the same race if they're part
of the same group and they do in fact
find that people are more likely to
cooperate of people who are part of the
same group is now they went on to see
just how deep that ran and found wasn't
that important right
you think okay yeah I for the team Kanye
for the same religion yeah you're pretty
close right now
nothing beats family tie that's way up
there forcing you cooperate your family
more than anybody else after that it
kind of called part they found that the
groups were actually completely
arbitrary point where they ran the
experiment what is that ok we're going
to buy group your team read your team
green and they found the exact same
result so I want to read
nobody bring that he's been in red for
all five minute so don't know what it
mean like in green
nobody's got all right so this
inherently part of our psychology if we
if we start carving people often failure
and the team here on this
name we are literally fixing and people
brain how well they're going to work
each other and how they're going to
cooperate with each other
Red Team Blue team and I are so familiar
so PBS Frontline had a really
interesting piece called a class divided
in I believe 6800 my way right after
Martin so Martin Luther King jr. was
just been assassinated i believe that
was 68 and this third grade teacher
basically in order to try to explain to
her students in her third-grade class
about why this man was assassinated put
together basically what was a
discrimination exercise a little bit
controversial right but she basically
took the class and said okay now it's
well known that all blue eyed people are
smarter than brown eyed people
ok and so you brown eyed people you're
probably going to have a little bit more
difficulty in life because the blue-eyed
people inherently are smart and the kids
all absorb that and you know they
started kind of like dividing within the
class and all that the next day she
basically said Oh to the class I i'm
wrong i misspoke right
brown eyed people are smarter than blue
eyed people completely reversed the next
day completely reversed it and they ate
it up right now and to the point where
you
yeah hey that person do that person
failed this map quiz part typical
brown-eyed behavior
yeah alright yeah the kids bought into
it right away it's a little creepy lot
yeah and yeah it's not entirely sure if
you're supposed to remind your students
right that's a little yeah I kind of
have a little bit of respect for that
aspect and level of experimentation
normal but there is this 60 they didn't
have informed consent so we're looking
at a real double-edged sword here we
know there are great things that coupled
with being a part of a strong team right
everybody thinks be treated in the great
idea right we're all proud of the
country come from but I think about you
can all name a few different times or
strong for each of them led people to
war
alright the double-edge part right so we
we all really kind of inherent value the
concept of being on a strong team but
there are also dangers to that will kind
of get into that as we get into like
complexity . and whatnot but you know
and at the end of the day a very strong
team has a really into a really a decent
probability of alienating itself
ok but we start talking about clicks and
things of that nature right this info
SEC culture subculture here right we
have a tendency to have a hard time with
the end users and the challenges that we
face trying to communicate security up
into the business right so there comes a
time when these strong subcultures end
up alienating themselves and just kind
of building wall and when that happens
they become ineffective right really
need a way to bridge the culture right
because i did not a template knocking
down the wall i'm not going to work
right we're here because we're on
well that's not going to go away and we
don't want to get rid of the passion
that drive them all right now we're
going away to bridge the culture I think
some of them pretty example about that
right it's not that we have to break
apart that but maybe we need an
ambassador
alright maybe he'll have to work as you
breathe well that's one way to do it but
we do need to figure out you
people to work together and make sure
they're not gonna completely silent all
right and and within our industry we've
heard you know you've heard so many
years of talks about we need to bust out
of our own echo chamber
alright we are a subculture that comes
together with like-minded people who
like to break things and Bob Loblaw and
were conveying the same messages over
and over to ourselves right I'm this is
not the first time you heard it right so
the problems with these strong
subcultures and building walls around
themselves that you end up the outcome
becomes this echo chamber and we're not
really doing anything without making any
progress
so the dangers of being too intrenched
in a subculture besides my wife does
anybody have any idea who this guy is
ggl thank you one person will buy a
drink after this yet
did they yeah we didn't we did not think
we yell and it is a very extreme example
of the punk-rock subculture right right
I'm not going to get into any of the
details you can google it
supergroup it's really gross ah but you
have to kind of way because we're doing
this analysis between information
security subculture and punk rock
subculture you have to kind of also
analyze this whole thing you know
there's going to be a subset of our
subculture that are the super geeks that
are super hardcore felt about what they
do
ok and and there are dangers about right
i first started thinking about this that
I'm afraid I'm guilty of it and i was
interviewing people and third expect
like okay well tell me about the first
you know PDF file into maybe that should
be the standard we've got to reach out
to more people than you know just keep
that came up the way I did that
obviously not gonna scale that's kind of
where I started right and certainly a
lot of you like to brag about their
their get going pd
ok let's do you know how I got into it
with this isn't how I learned it that's
how it felt hot right
good thing we got a branch back then
okay look at yeah I mean it's great for
me I'm certainly glad the way I got
another industry but for everybody all
right that question we really want to
add the necessary to be obsessed with it
about to be a good degree is it
necessary to be that hardcore about
something to be successful at what
you're trying to accomplish with the end
of music genres is arguing over who's
more hardcore now what the actual what
actual computer now I don't think like
you know I think right now during this
dumb computers version of this talk
we're listening to the bad rings okay so
many of the people who are familiar with
fans of that genre that original kind of
punk genre will take a look at a green
day and be like that is not punk rock
ok but at some point Bad Brains Black
Flag Sex Pistols clash at some point
those ideals influenced others that may
not have had that really hardcore
subculture focus and that influence got
into the mainstream culture common sense
and yeah and if you and if you end up
just hanging on to that just pure
hardcore portion of of you know of your
subculture sure you will likely end up
with some level of a crazy cult
following like GG Allin did but your
spirit of influence becomes close to
zero
it's approaching null diving example
here
mergers and acquisitions are a
particularly interesting case to look at
how culture change right we take your
invasion plan together and we're doing
one call to the other are we gonna leave
you stop
it at one culture going to dominate the
other we try and blend them together are
we end up with some type of counter
culture or one side pissed off at the
other one right now in every single
murder that happens they always say oh
we're going to take the best of all
right
and obviously doesn't happen to the
point where am I to go to business
school and learn about merging
accusation the first thing they teach
you is a back majority of them fail
completely to the point where it's aight
the research topic in business school
like lying to people keep doing actually
why do they keep trying it's like they
feel so often what's going on at the
point where the leading theory for why
murders happened in the first place is
managerial hubris you must be so wildly
over confident in your own capability to
tell ya sure most of them fail i got it
right like that how unusual it is the
one meets so go back go back and read
that
oh I love the motivator poster right for
acquisition in case you guys can't read
this
yeah that was the text mari the
discovery that you are no longer a big
fish in a small pond or even a small
fish in a big pond but a small fish in a
big fish
ok so as an example I one kind of close
to home just got fired for fire and i'm
working at Sourcefire for a few years
when Alice there's good and bad to come
out with it and take a moment to good uh
it was wildly example with their
research team and we take a look at that
arm at the coat coat started that's
wrong with sio team and your smartphone
ability research team they came together
and it's been awhile that the guide love
it
alright guys are writing snort rules and
in doing that kind of research arm it
naturally great for people i know around
the whole team we're still there and
they really enjoy right when the
absolute first thing they did was likely
we've got you two teams right everyone
brt we're going to do they dropped both
the name and there's a new organization
out all towel and I think that got to
play a big role we just went over how
much it matter if I literally make up a
team that your green your rep we
actually working together
I think i'm a tremendous amount about
how they were able to immediately start
working together oh we're a new team now
we're towel not the old now we're
working together now I don't think that
the only effect and it was kind of
compare with him it was a left then
picks up all built those did not first
together quite tho happens and you're
like I very few people on a field side
are actually still there right and I
laughed so he it literally most people I
know and work with I don't think if they
give us a shiny new name it would have
had any effect on right i really do
think it helped with the researching but
they don't look very similar background
people in researching for coming from
the same place but locate we're going to
your research now where we're going to
find a way to stop a bad guy and get
that out there
so a lot of the same background right a
lot of the same ol a lot less that would
kill a wildly different ways of doing
the court is going to be like oh we're
going to dominate your culture they find
out that we want to bring in the way you
guys are doing right you guys are able
to build the company out of nothing
you're selling you know security value
but the way you sell one product to a
customer and the way you try and sell
any product in a bundle is so wildly
different a complete waste of different
ways of going about it the people who
were in the jobs are for different
reasons a totally different background
and I suppose people who were just again
rabbit security people at what people
may be came off their networking and
routers like let me get dirty shot right
so two wildly different processes really
blend well together all a little bit of
a little bit so why didn't it work for
the deal right i don't think it just
template hey they needed a new name
right
the more we look into and think ok well
have changed well there's way too many
variable and that's ultimately the
problem how are we going to tell you how
to picture culture
oh we're not there are so many very
involved we actually come back to this
is insanely complex
and i don't mean that and then it
complicated right complexity is a whole
branch of client now I complex system is
a completely different ways of looking
at a problem and there's a given that
complexity is sort of fitting that
there's no good definition for but the
basic idea is that I complex it is not
just the sum of it part is actually more
than the sum of its parts because the
interaction between the part matter and
when they and interact actually come so
unpredictable
that's really talk to manage right so we
see that with emergency we see that with
the organizations that you organize
themselves in the pattern or change
their strategy based on adaptation
actually come back to the complex
systems go back real quick that that
imagery yeah that image right there is
you know it is the representation of the
relationships within the e.coli box
right so the simplest ordered a doubt
one of the SIP was organisms that right
the researchers are looking at and
that's about how companies we start
breaking apart right now let's take that
do that with all the different
motivations and all the different people
on the teams and who they work with and
we are going up with an insanely complex
system and we're not going to be able to
predict the result was going on
everything we going in a different
direction so we want to be able to treat
it the way we're learning about other
complexes right and so you know when we
talk about obviously within business we
all understand conceptually the top down
Vs bottom-up kind of managerial style or
how to run a business right but within
complex system that for lack of a better
word intelligent design aspect of it
doesn't pan right you want to enforce
natively you want to enforce policy from
a top-down perspective that's just kind
of the nature yeah I've got an idea
now i need to push it out here's the new
password policy push it out right but
the reality is that that ends up being
because of those belief systems that
kind of attached to the whole equation
that becomes a culture religion and the
only way to really change cultural
issues is from the bottom up and taking
advantage of the subcultures right and
and you know they're there
therein lies one of the biggest problems
with information security in terms of
you know us trying to change the
security culture for the most part were
trying to force this top-down approach
you can let's take a look at an example
right I'll take your typical security
awareness program we want to tell the
user don't click that link make your
password strong and only thing and a
typical way to set that policy and say
follow the politics that's a top-down
approach now why would the user hear
that and think anything other than than
that right what's the different but
we're fundamentally thank ya you got
your way to doing things but I need you
to care more about the right that's the
way any further with anything that isn't
going to see it . awareness program
right right and and so let's take a look
at some awareness big success examples
right of the of the security awareness
programs that I've seen actually succeed
it's really targeting more of a personal
family side of the end-user right here's
how you can protect your children on the
internals here's how you know that the
whole you have to personalize it right
this isn't the top-down kind of you must
do this or whatever right this is a no
here's the best practice and this is how
it relates to you and your your family
alright everything so
what we really have is this clash of you
know within an organization the top down
versus the bottom all and I stole this
slide from the deck that I that I that I
did last year right
if on the one side of the house you have
the manager who is you know hovering
over the people that report to him
hovering over their shoulder making sure
that they are doing their job even if it
it's a detriment to like your job as X
but even this security awareness
training that is going to be an hour out
of your day
you know that even like it pushed off
because top-down management like we have
we have to have results right and and
you have a job to do the clash of that
versus a bottom-up natural kind of
society not society but a subculture
write it if you find me out so the slot
right if you are involved meaningfully
you know in the design of your work if
you find joy in your work if you have
the passion and ability to speak
honestly about right so collaboration
and the whole wisdom of crowds concept
really is much more effective in terms
of being able to change at a top and a
bottom up subculture level changing the
culture itself and direct parallels
direct parallels with you know the indie
rock and punk rock subculture will go
over another example quite a while ago
art already tried to bring in a new
video he had a very strong background in
marketing
I any had tremendous success going to
company and improving them back Lee by
implementing individual invented right
to reward people for their hard work and
a career system right here's your career
path here is the promotion you should be
going for let's look map that out for
you to understand you know what rewards
down the line right so he had used this
isn't a couple different places in order
to build that organization get people
motivated and work it failed miserably
at heart
those guys are building games in such a
collaborative format
they're just sitting around football
with each other they were always working
together bouncing ideas off of each
other to the point where they came
around
oh hey this is a great idea we've got a
reward for your whose idea was it a
straw
I you don't know we work together and
everything that is a little bit so they
start naming you know engineer the model
the rest of the team with Connor example
like we did that together upon so this
is textbook business going and make a
company better you know give you get
people the incentives they deserve and
it didn't work that he didn't understand
the culture here
alright if you don't understand that the
changes you make are and can I think
that big enough to just throw the entire
thing off off and unfortunately it's it
wasn't even understanding the culture it
was understanding the subculture right
yeah that guy worked with marketing and
working visit he never worked with
engineers who would you work with each
other in the play he didn't understand
at all he was completely baffled when
they came back frustrated and and
frankly start leaving comments so yeah
we come back and saying it complex
systems are too complex to predict what
happened
so do we give up oh well no will come
the theory of complex systems it
ingrained in a lot of their science now
in physical chemistry and economic the
point where we can serve take a look at
what's working now and right so how can
we actually then take these complex
systems and improve right and that
really then comes back to you know
adaptation here right
adaptation theory really kind of comes
down to a subset of variables including
variation in systems and then the whole
selection process right trying to do
something and if it doesn't work
okay well I'm going to learn from my
mistakes you know and or some type of
mutation doesn't work why law and in
nature that species or that variation of
that species doesn't actually that
flourish in
environment right and right so this
again kind of ties back to a bit of talk
that I did I think three years ago now
right but what then does make an actual
system evolve when we talk about natural
security systems the whole concept is
all about right presenting the end but
you know the end contributor of the
organizational organism presenting them
with a challenge that challenge could be
finding food that challenge could be in
a group setting
finding the whereabouts of a sunken
nuclear self if anybody knows the USS
scorpion soy alright but the bottom line
though is that in and organizational
setting presenting challenges then
starts to instill competition within the
individual elements of that organism or
organization it's the same concept right
and then that competition once the
individual elements of the organization
realize that we're all kind of trying to
accomplish the same goal that
competition leads the cooperation right
and then it's a repeating cycle that
gets bigger and bigger and bigger from a
top-down I'm sorry from the bottom up
right within the organization
this is how adaptation theory can help
organizations really from again the
bottom-up right change the culture
because this at the subculture level
were you know working with challenges
were identifying competition and through
that competition were figuring out how
to cooperate with each other and that
how adaptation occurred right and at the
end of the day the simple statement is
that adaptation is going to accord when
it occurs it occurs when the end user or
variable of the system either moves out
of or gets forced out of their comfort
zone and that's a huge huge part of this
whole equation because most
organizations today live within its own
comforts of right the stock price is
good our revenues are good
blah blah but the next week we just got
have well that's right because you
didn't get out of your comfort zone you
know instill this kind of bottom-up
change when he's not got anything to
talk about evolution evolution doesn't
mean you're going to get better doesn't
mean you always stronger you always
faster i actually means the population
of the whole adapt to its environment
better and that doesn't mean it's good
for everyone
I in fact that this up here the subject
that it could be the purpose of your
life is to only serve as a warning to
others and extinction is actually an
important part of an evolutionary system
what doesn't work is out right
oh it's not the devil exactly make it
better we might actually want to target
the ways that don't work
I and help them die pad all the way to
make the population improve right so if
you want to get the system where it's
going to evolve again you need those two
things in variation and you need
selection got that right so we need to
figure out how to do that now we can
look at nature and to come back that
like what you don't mutate a random
necessarily in fact nature tends to vary
mutation rate by gender right if you try
it a mutation on a female and something
goes horribly wrong then she's not going
to have any baby if you screw up a male
that other fuels probably still going to
have a baby right because of the the
inequality in and reproduction that the
key and because of that there tends to
be a whole lot more mutation email and
serial killers
yeah take any given prison it's full of
men right right and and the the problem
though years that we if we're trying to
change the security culture we don't
have the luxury of waiting thousands and
or millions of years for nature's
mutation variations so then potentially
have a positive impact on our business
right so the lesson is ultimately we
need a safe environment where we can
experiment right we need that male we
can screw up and no one will know right
we sort of figured need to figure out
when is it okay to expand
and how can we start doing that in order
to start discovering new ways of doing
things better ways of doing things
of course we can learn from previous
experimentation that a huge difference
if you learn about evolution entirely
through biology you always thinking the
terms of jeans and it's wildly different
we talk about evolutionary system is
human being and involved because we can
talk to each other and we can learn from
each other right jeans don't just passed
on exactly i can literally tell you the
good idea then we can learn that way
right
and speaking of jeans a moment of
silence mr. gene wilder by that
extension right we want to know when not
to mutate some problems are eating
that's all you got a physics or
chemistry problem you literally solver
act they don't need to you cater
experiment I know it's usual and also
when the cost of failure is significant
you run a nuclear power plant
you're probably not going to start
flipping button that Wild play we should
experiment right that's not a good
option for you so we need again to find
that sort of optional for optimal
mutation way when it's safe to
experiment when it's not and the mommy I
think we can learn from it what calls
don't work which is actually what
lockheed martin call this organization
they like took the engineer's send them
up in a different building they pulled
him out of all the bureaucratic nonsense
that usually to deal with that
here here's your own little playground
figure stuff i'll go play and out of
that came like the u-2 spy plane and
frankly a lot of other advancements that
lock isn't very profitable to the point
where we can't if you want to take this
model can't call it a comfort thoughtful
example Phil going on this organization
is still running they're still doing
research and drone and I thought this
was insane
they're actually working on tiny robot
fighters that will call around inside of
airship envelope to find hold and repair
them airships that's a thing so i don't
know if it's like some weird fantasy and
they're actually docked on orders
legitimately people are or head back
towards the airship I want to learn more
but yeah this is really what they're
working on it was a headline from a
month ago or so right whose organization
will set up as a way to experiment and
try new things and and and you see the
exact same thing in pump generation
right so Punk when you really going to
look at the roots
was a response to the seventies giant
like you know long-winded a big
complicated songs you think of your pink
floyd's your king crimson's and things
of that nature even Zeppelin to agree
right and and as from from a subculture
that took a look at that and and and saw
well you know really thought how
arrogant all that is and then coming to
say hey you know here's what we're gonna
do we're basically going to break this
down in our own experimental environment
we're gonna break this into a very
simple songs we're going to do stuff
we're going to create art that you know
is outside of the mainstream and to
basically get our own subculture but
again you still need the isolated
fringes for you can't be so it doesn't
isolate the mainstream you still need
some of those fringes for the innovation
right and so you have people like this
guy on stage and Iran and Iran you know
legendary icon and you know today is
this you know amazing world traveler are
but at you know when all of this was
going down his whole subculture ideal
was this stuff over here that is
accepted today don't like it I'm going
to do something else
alright so let's let's wrap it up and
bring everything back together right arm
what we want to get across more than
anything else that beat them if you
accept our private that the systems were
working in our complex that the way to
get them improve and make sure that they
can evolve and to get to that point I
want they don't be afraid to fail that
the culture we want to build a point
where people can try something different
they can try something new in a
corporate organization i don't think
people try and maximize success as much
as i'll try to minimize failure on a
plane thing we want to get to the point
where we can actually celebrate your
failure right Thomas Edison said I i
didn't i didn't fail these experiments i
found 10,000 ways that didn't work and
we should try to do that you know the
same way in fact we're talking earlier I
if you can think of a good
way you failed and learn the lesson from
it um let us know or send that
information frankly we'd like to put
together a panel for next year's webicon
if you want to come off take five
minutes say this is a project we're
doing I screwed up here's what I learned
that be great because in the scientific
community we can only talk about the
trial yeah but we're all in the same
road and if you can leave some warning
signs for the people behind you that
just as valuable we should literally
stand up and applaud your failure if
you're willing to share it with all
right so we want to do that conferences
you've got away you failed spectacularly
a lesson you learn to let us know if we
can put together a panel will see if it
turns out interesting maybe that'll work
out connected but we do want to say that
you know in your organization let people
try it up and if it doesn't work out say
that was a great idea where can we go
from here
yeah okay so if anybody's unfamiliar
with this book
get familiar with ok that is Russell
wrote a book couple years ago called a
renegade history the United States in it
he talks about our bait and and this
quote from him on on the slide is taken
from an interview that he did on the Joe
Rogan experience but basically this book
is all about how the fringe subcultures
really set the set the course and
steered overarching American culture as
a whole right and a great a great little
example here is in 1968 at the time they
were very you know very stringent laws
against gay and homosexuals and at the
time the Mafia a subculture owned a
majority of these in new york city of
Moore majority of these bars & inns and
things of that nature and they were like
you know something i don't really care
about though the rules like prohibition
against I don't really care about the
laws you know anybody wants to come in
and drink and we
make profit and all that stuff yeah come
on in that led to the stonewall riots
rightmost alright it's really kind of a
keystone for you know that the gay
rights movement in that I don't you know
on the one side you know and once all
this happen to really like the police
were kind of like breaking and and and
you know get whatever I cannot permit it
they were disrupting these you know
these bars in these speakeasy and all
that stuff and so on one side of the
street you have all the police with
batons ready to cross skulls and on the
other side street you have all these
drag queens like doing like full-on like
Rockhead type you know movement and over
five days that then you that this but
but after those five days the results of
this really kind of kind of steered
American culture and and viewpoints to
the to the extreme fact that like not
not even three years later a book was
published a book was published that the
author had that not happened as well you
know that was a variable of this culture
change but had not happened the author
who wrote this book would have been
imprisoned in that book was the joy of
sex and I'm guessing that a lot of you
probably have seen that from your
parents because i know i found my
parents copy right but but that book
instead of that author going to jail or
prison not even three years after this
big shift of American culture and the
gay rights movement that book was on the
New York Times top five list for 70 that
70 70 weeks
all right through all the old history is
driven by our leaders and you dig in if
I know I might have been a pack of
weirdo going to push the lobby so maybe
you want to be able to experiment right
expert can't necessarily tell you how to
do what you need to do right now you
gotta start somewhere
again we don't have a million years to
try things that random involved that way
we got a third so let's start with other
ideas that people have good way to do
that so every talk to go to today I'm
you get a look at the great talk
that's how i should be doing it but i
would suggest another way of looking at
it would be okay that's really good talk
that's a good place to start experiment
it might work brought but we have to
give it a try and find out
yeah and also we can learn from other
sub-cultures we talked about punk rock
that's rocket background we had all the
data on it right so that's where we
started talking about it any subculture
do you gonna be able to pull the same
laughing and if you don't know any
people in from tight subculture go to
the after party tonight
well I'm we start me now there's gonna
be a whole chance to learn about how you
know these kind of cultures of all
reward innovation right we've got a few
more minutes here you know rewarding
innovation and incentive izing change
through challenges is really again one
of the most important one of the most
important takeaways here I don't have my
reading glasses on but the quote here
i'm not a huge brands and follower but
this is a great quote right innovation
happens when people are given the
freedom to ask questions and the
resources and power to find the answers
that's fantastic alright we're on it
yeah that'll at all right last slide
alright and so again let's go back to
the original definition of culture is
right that culture comes from learned
behavior what works in the path we learn
and that team rolls into our culture so
keep that in mind because if you're a
problem solver you are contributing the
culture right whether you like it or not
you're developing solution and people
can learn about the solutions from you
that is where your organization culture
and at the end of the day also this
version of this talk did have a fight
the power playing it was gonna be great
really I it wasn't but yeah you look
listen forget you forget the bosses i
know that you know that to a degree
that's well fuck it that's punk right
forget the bosses your subculture
solutions contribute to culture right
and and that's really where all of this
and when we as a collective subculture
here talk about the frustrations of
being able to enact
change within an organization this is
how we can do it it's it can't be
top-down it has to be bottom up from a
subculture alright thanks everyone for
coming we should probably update with
the next person God record that you have
any question up we let know after that
the talker in the bar later tonight I
don't be happy to talk to you guys again
if you want to celebrate your own
failures let us know and maybe we can
scrape together not to put together
another pop right thanks