appreciate y'all coming on 90 and after
party on friday i want a beer because
there's more than 20 people in here so
that's a so my first one today
my name is Bill books and we'll be
talking about privileged access
workstations and some other ways women
potential that in lateral movement out
of your networks a little bit about me
I'm blue team on twitter i work in the
financial sector for a small company 400
employees and ten locations
I you know working for a small company
usually means we're a lot of hats and
you know i do everything from
configuring network equipment to vendor
management to daily sysadmin stuff and a
little bit of physical security and just
a wide range of different things and you
know I'm truly blessed i'm one of those
people that i truly love what I do for a
living like a lot of you guys probably
pretty passionate about it and my
favorite things to do is to learn
offensive techniques bringing back to my
network and taking apart the girl
countermeasures moron and protection
mechanisms and things like that so in my
free time I like to build up my hands
you know as I keep people we don't
always get to see the tangible thing
that we built and I just think there's
something really cool about you know
stepping back after a long day at work
and you
you see that cool thing that you built
the summer i built a pirate ship with my
kids in my backyard which was a lot of
fun i also like grow my beard and cook
yeah homebrew and also look but also
cooking and stuff on the grill
ok so let's start here by talking about
a typical attack scenario on windows
network in this first case let's say
that the organization might not be very
security-conscious most users are going
to be running as local admin and one
gets popped with a phishing email
I'll attackers can be running as local
admin they can migrate to system .
credentials and you know it's probably
not all around possibility that I the IT
admins set the local admin password the
same for all of workstations just to
make the license you huh
and if they did that the attack and
obviously you can use that local
conventional walking have literally
throwing almost workstations and have a
password
I tell you find another workstation
where maybe a domain domain admin login
we can steal those credentials the
various ways so it's pretty quick path
to game over
ok the next scenario let's say that
their little more security conscious
most users are running a standard users
and same situation either get popped by
phishing email and now this time the
attackers running as standard user so
you're going to need to be able to
escalate privileges so that they can get
the local admin and then system so they
can you know . credentials still tokens
and things like that
oh and one way to do that they may use
something like our boys powerup tool
look for common misconfigurations on the
system along escalate privileges are you
know it if they don't see an easy way to
do that they might move laterally with
the standard grids and look for more
configurations just trying to find one
that works for you only doing that you
know that probably will be looking for
credentials that are just on the network
so maybe they have been team left
unattended xml file they're using .
images for pcs or maybe they deploy
password policy preferences attacker
could get password that way but one way
or another you're going to you're going
to keep moving around laterally I'm
stealing credentials until they either
get domain admin or some kind of
privilege potential until I get what
they're looking for
oh so you know these scenarios are
certainly not almost all accompanying
but i think that you follow pretty
common path
on windows network that attack on my
cake and like I said domain may not be
the end goal and if they find what
they're looking for an open share from a
standard the first box the population
standard user may not care about domain
admin but the point here is that the
attacker tactics tend to revolve around
finding and using existing credentials
on over and if you want to see really
good demo how attackers do that
Holly Holly move laterally and
potentials checkout illustrator and Amy
Robbins top and besides las vegas on one
hand some really cool stuff there but
the main goal of these privileged access
workstations that is to limit exposure
right I in order to do that you need to
understand where potentials are stored
in what form they are stored and then
you gonna do some other issues with
windows authentication and credentials
so to start off your little background
like for windows logon types different
login times within windows you know when
you when you log into the system are
interactive would be like when you
actually type your password into like
console or any type your password in the
computer is going to be interactive and
there's a bunch of other logotypes but
the the key thing to take away here is
that all of them except for the network
logon time are going to leave some form
of reusable potential when you use it so
that's a pretty key thing takeaway here
as we move along and network logon types
are going to be things like that use
from the command prompt PowerShell
remoting registry using a tendency
snap-in to connect to remote machines
although there are not to leave any
reasonable grandchildren the system you
connect
ok so let's talk a little bit of all
your credentials are stored and windows
of the one more commonly known ones is a
book like local San database which is a
file on a local computers that has you
know all local user accounts and their
hashes that are associated with them
you mean don't with system rights and
you know it's just pretty trivial to get
once you have a local admin once you
once they're done they can be reinforced
offliner or past other systems are going
to do a little bit you know Active
Directory database pretty pretty basic
stuff here i think most people know but
just kind of cover and we're all the
credentials are stored
ah Active Directory database same thing
only its potentials for all users in the
domain now read only domain controllers
by default aren't going to store for
those credentials but don't have a
subset of of of the of the database in
there but i'm not going to get too deep
into diving the Active Directory domain
controller security but it is good it is
going to remember that another crucial
concept considered potential story
elsass were made famous bike tools like
me cast and windows financial editor and
only those tools pull pull the
credentials from memory of that process
when a user logs into a system also has
will catch your credentials so when when
when
after you log on when you go to access
the network resource you don't have to
type your password every time and these
can be stored as hashes grows tickets or
just the actual plaintext password so
prior to Windows 8.1 server 2012 lsat
store a lot of potential remembering as
you can see here they mean a lot of
progress in that department
you know this chart actually comes from
the second past half white paper from
microsoft it was originally adapted from
a Twitter post by Benjamin del P is the
creator me gets and i find that kind of
fitting because you know it's because of
people like like Ben and I other people
in the community you know like chris
campbell and skip the wall another and
lots of other people that have really
brought these issues in the spotlight
and kind of course Microsoft it it's
more tools to mitigate these issues so
just want to kinda . that on state you
too
everybody was involved in that but this
kb 287 1997 also known as we cats
maybe my son was released in 2014 and it
gave us a lot of the controls that we're
going to talk about today
yeah for example as long as that updates
installed on Windows 7 computer only
plant exponential is going to be the w
digest provider in LCS s4 windows 8.1
above is going to be no point
exponential store small but there are
some caveats this
ah it's good video is going to store any
hash and thrust to get for doing the
main accounts for what for windows 7 or
windows 8.1 involved and also the third
party SSB my store some third-party
software my storage potential is it
announced as well this this this is
reach out here from the meerkats github
page has a bunch of really good stuff on
it so caveat to the win kick
Exponential's if you're off its domain
computer and that you can't access the
domain controller the kerberos provider
my score some credentials memory
although windows 8.1 evolved does not
store . Exponential's and everybody all
it can be reasonable with the average
tricky registry edit reboot similarly
windows 7 w digest can be disabled by
educated reboot to and these are
highlighted registry keys here at these
have certain value them and also my
store some point exponential significant
memory for example if the organization
has a group policy that sets our
delegating people potentials for for
auto logon and select remote
applications terminal server that will
also store that will put some keys into
those registries that highlighted last
slide that will store . Exponential's in
the TSP Katie provider or else ass so
good thing to keep in mind
ah LLC secrets are going to be dat only
accessible to the system process some of
these are going to be potentials and
encrypted and stored on this is going to
be things like to get scheduled task
passwords computer account passwords
service account passwords and also cash
will be typically call cash potentials
that Microsoft calls password their
fires are stored in LSA secrets
these are stored as soft and hashes and
these can be passed in a fast cash tag
but they can be dumped into of course
and you know the cash potentials being
that when you bring your computer home
into can talk about making troller if
you're able to walk in with that
confidence cash on the system is also
crucial manager where passengers can be
entered manually in the control panel
off or when you tell windows to remember
your DP password i'm going to start
there
these are encrypted with a key that
comes from your that users password and
any user that's any program is running
as that user can access those and if
there's actually a nice white post
module we don't go i believe
ok so that's kind of where is restored
some of the common issues with windows
credentials you know I think we're all
pretty familiar with hash if you're not
there's a ton of documentation on
internet with building my references
I you know it until I'm passionate can
be acquired from various various ways
whether it be pulling up from memory
with someone gave me cancer windows
translator or dumping him from the local
samer the active duties and once you
have a hash you can authenticate just as
windows does no legitimate walking on
the background bypassing each other
systems of network when you log on to be
until $TIME a.m. until out there's
different people different flavors with
protocol that uses and it doesn't
challenge response mechanism that I
proves that the user knows their
password hash basically this couple of
flavors that is until everyone is
completely broken if the attacker can
capture the traffic on the wire we can
we can recover the hash and you went to
a little bit better but
as has issues can be grouped forest and
both these vulnerable to relay attacks
which I believe can be partially
mitigated by S&B signing but not totally
similar issues with kerberos you know
you can dump the ticket from one
computer loaded onto another computer
also known as past ticket ticket ticket
technically expired but they can be
there
it expired to get presented they can be
repeated be extended and others other
issues with kerberos you know I golden
ticket silver ticket which kind of
hospital for today but still no ball so
you know the things we talked about so
far branches in memory pass the hash
pass ticket i think you're already one
blue team about Windows good i think
it's the same can be true said about
Windows access tokens i remember i did a
class a few years ago when did Kennedy
and you know we showed us how to use
incognito still tokens and print
privileged users but I really didn't
grasp really what I was really doing
oh and to be honest with you didn't we
know windows access tokens existed until
fairly recently but to kind of quickly
explain our go over what windows access
tokens are when you log into a system
verifies your password
check your passwords ok if the past your
password is ok that soaking gets created
and every process that gets executed on
behalf of that user is going to have a
copy that token and talking talking to
be stored in memory and they basically
enable six single sign-on functionality
within windows so there's a couple
different types of these tokens there's
a person nation tokens if you saw the
red potato talk yesterday you're talking
about personation tokens there is
generated by non-interactive logons
these can be used escalate privileges
but they can only be used locally then
there's delegation tokens which are used
generated by interactive logon and these
are really the ones that attacker wants
to get because the attacker can steal a
delegation talking the have a privileged
user they can use that to your advantage
just walked onto any network accessible
system so is everybody pretty familiar
with incognito and help and homework
still tokens are you guys use that for
ya
I don't it doesn't seem to be super
well-known model defenders I just want
to go over real quick little demo on
what looks like to go from the local
admin to have been by stuart tokens so
you can see here we've got a interpreter
shell running as local admin you know we
got this multiple ways let's just say
it's a phishing email and now in order
to steal or list opens we need to be
running a system and so you know you
want me to do that you migrate to a
process that's currently running a
system and then you become you been
running a system to this prophecy this
example i migrate the winlogon process
and offered on the victims computer i
opened up a computer management box and
in the USC probably typed in my domain
admin credentials and then close the
computer management loss now that that
left that talking about user on the
system so now i'm going to really attack
her list all the tokens he sees the dog
is uh accountants in the blue team
domain domain admin account and it's is
it was you know a person a token and you
steal that token you are able to use it
on the network to access any any system
or network with those credentials
well one thing I didn't know until it's
kind of preparing for this talk is that
this company has been around for a
really long time it was presented it was
written by the presented by a guy named
Luke Jennings in death on 15 and I know
kind of late to the party on this but uh
his white paper that you wrote for
public nine years ago it still rings
true today and if you go
he's advocating for a lot of same things
that i'm talking about today so if you
haven't checked it off it's still worth
three even though it's a 90
the whole oh so you know eventually
after Zack has been a major issues for a
long time even in that white paper he's
talking about how is nothing news and
happiness has been an issue for a long
time
ah but there's a couple major roadblocks
we need to overcome to to combat these
issues i'll remember one thing IT admins
and other people that may not consider
themselves you know security people they
don't think might not really understand
the preschool talking about
also you know change is hard and
usability tends to trump security you
know as Luke Jennings said in that white
paper and chris campbell and skip the
wall echoed in their black paper a
couple years ago
there's there's no patch from these it
for these issues you know it's an
unexpected consequence of a single
sign-on implementation and without a
single sign-on you have to type your
password and you know ten times just
when your system . right so you know but
there is panda life in the tunnel here
and we're getting we have more controls
that than ever before to mitigate some
of this stuff and it's going to provide
so much more value by using some of
these controls than any next-gen blinky
blocks but you can go by and one of the
wireless controllers using privileged
access workstations so privileged access
workstations or pause you know that the
concept as far as I'm aware I'm was kind
of outlined in the first pass the hash
white paper from what Microsoft and it
was kind of expand upon a technological
for really this year and it could be a
much older concept that it probably is
but the first i have heard about it was
that second article but at the most
basic level their hard-won admin work
stations that are designed to limit your
exposure to the types of threats we
think we're just talking about
so if your goal is to limit how often
privilege credentials you have left on
systems for attackers to steal how do
you go about how do you go about doing
that
oh I like to think of it and compared to
network segmentation where you want to
isolate those privileged credentials and
keep them off and away from riskier
systems and risk your users and to do
that you need to group the systems and
users my privilege level so the second
article references this administrated
active directory administrative to your
model basically what this is it just
splits up users and computers and you
computers into different levels of
different tiers of access so you've got
20 which is going to be your domain
admins domain controllers if you don't
make controllers are virtualized it's
going to be any admin administer the
virtualized infrastructure this tier 1
which is going to be your anything that
has control over mission-critical
applications that's going to be a member
server admins never servers enterprise
application admins and then this tier 2
which is going to be your your user
devices in any accounts that have
control over the user devices so the
idea here is that you have your domain
admin account you never log into
anything other than domain controller
stay in that same here
you're a member server admin should
should never log into a standard user
workstation and a similar thought here
you never log in to a domain controller
from the same computer that you're
looking at kathleen's and i'm checking
your email and things like that because
once your admin state workstation is
compromised so does anything else that
you've administer from the right and
that's the best that's a really key
thing to understand so you know
traditional solutions this problem are
can be inherently Flying Squad depending
on Halloween implemented if you're
accessing admin jump server from a user
workstation that you browse the internet
and check email from got the same
problem we just talk
well I know you can use any more jump
servers I pot appointment but you're
gonna want to make sure anyway that's
asset accessing them is doing it from a
hard work station now before you go
start configuring hard work stations
there's some prerequisites you're gonna
want to consider before you do that
first of all here in Austin users are
running as local admin you're gonna want
to tackle that problem first grade that
could be a difficult thing to accomplish
depending on how much you know
management wise and just security types
of legacy application long run and
things like that but you know don't give
up if you have a subset of users that
you just can't figure out how to get
running a standard users don't give up
because there's so much there's a ton of
value and getting a few people running
as local admin as you possibly can you
know you want to you want to make it
harder for the attacker to go from
staining you want to make a call from
standard user to local admin and system
and if you have legacy applications that
maybe not don't play well as user
account control
oh you cannot you think was a workaround
you can do maybe you can run it from the
application in terminal server you know
if you need to put some pressure on that
vendor if you need more full of the
vendor maybe team up with other
customers and vendors to try to get them
to fix their software
ah and you can also split up their
college give them a standard user gonna
get a local admin account and try to
force them to use the standard user
account only the what will happen when
they need escalate you can put the local
admin account to protect users group
will have a little bit more in a minute
um so you know you're happy here
your IT help us people are going to be
running a standard users to and what
they only use the local admin we need to
and if you do have some of the group
users that are 90 in a separate house
for standard and local admin make sure
they're only love living on their their
box and not
every box and the next thing you want to
do is uh you know some small companies
they just use domain admin and mr.
everything is a big no-no so break out
your break out your admins into like
never server admins and also you're
gonna want to limit your domain admins
to view is he possibly can get you know
delegate villages and easy as as you
need to and it's also a good idea if you
can two segments each group admin so if
you've got a you've got a couple of
admins that we need access to operations
cooperation servers you make them their
own you make them their own group so
that the technical is so a couple of
phases of deployment here on these was
going to be immediate deployment Active
Directory admins this is going to be
getting up and running using positives
quickly as you can to help your most
privileged accounts phase two is going
to be extending pasta all users with the
fish better admins over mission-critical
applications to me things like never
happens cause services admins energy
phase three is going to be advanced pasa
curity it's going to be adding some
additional controls which all . so for
the deployment models that is a couple
recommended . models on the first one
being dedicated hardware which is going
to be where you give admins a dedicated
workstation will it be a laptop or
desktop and they have one that's your
standard user system they only use their
standard user account login to that they
that's where they check email browse the
internet things like that they have a
totally separate system the user
administration they log in with their
privilege potential and then they're not
local admins on that box they can browse
the internet and so isn't there some
pros with the dedicated Hardware model
it's probably got the strongest security
separation because they're two separate
systems the job apps takes up more desk
space it's more week to haul around
if especially this laptop and it's
double hardware cost model is
simultaneous use this will be a hardon
host machine will be your paw and you
have a local your local p.m. that is
your standard user system or you'll
access of a vm on like up with me dir
dep or something like that but in a
centralized place and so the conflict
arose they're obviously a little
hardware costs better user experience
and the drawback is you know when you
have a single keyboard mouse you can
tend to type the password into the wrong
system may be no it's just easier to
make those years and also you don't have
that separation as you would with the
dedicated hard work
so for the simultaneous use all you know
you either have that local of a vm
locally on the harder haha that's your
standard user system or you can have
access to your beady eye on him and
essentially the drop back up the vdi
that it is that if you're offline or you
can access that data center if you can't
do your standard user activities so you
can access that so you have to be always
kept that I'm gonna start talking about
this model other IT people attend this
table i can I just have a know my
regular user workstation and have an
admin vm on it just seems like that
makes more sense it's more convenient
but that brings us back to the same
issue we're just talking about where you
use your workstation gets compromised
and anything that you administered from
there is because also could be
compromised as well as if you flip that
around and your your user p.m. gets
compromised
I'm going to get back the host you need
you know a vm escape exploit or
something like that which I'm sure is
beautiful but going to be a lot harder
to do so once you've chosen your . model
and you can mix and match that obviously
de to your environment what your admin
group you can use a couple of PowerShell
scripts that the
they actually microsoft has a non-tech
and so one will create the new all you
structure one will create the new
security groups put them in the right
only use and one will assign permissions
to do you put the right groups
oh it's so when it when you get to know
you always created the meat potatoes
we're gonna be working in the admin
top-level newly-created admin top-level
ah oh you and it creates mother used to
but mostly what you're going to be
working is that you and that underneath
that is going to be 20 to 1 tier two and
then a column underneath each one of
those there's a palace devices groups
and services counselor I'm just going to
quickly go over the tier 10 you so
enough in the account so you want to
tier1 this is going to be going to put
users that are members of domain admins
enterprise that means our club global
Internet know you and the devices though
you're going to put your your pocket
computer accounts that's going to be the
computer comments that are in our paws
and here's your old and then under
groups are going to have some new groups
that were created in there and the pot
users group is going to be the actual
users the logon hopefully to the the
workstations now these are not going to
be local admins on those systems there
are the palm maintenance group is going
to be localizing if you need to login to
troubleshoot it or whatever you know
you're going to really use that but
that's that that that group is going to
be the local admin on the system and
it's important to note to users should
never be a member of both parties and
comments so keep that line so i want you
have the whole you framework laid out
you can start working for policies that
are going to harden the heart of the
devices is some of the ones listed on
the technical and you could obviously
expand on this and do more but i'm
personally that you'll do is it empty
using group policy to empty on google
groups and just put in the Armenians and
local administrator account
do it localizes group if you can grant
all users group local walk-in access to
the top and then you can use windows
firewall rules to block all unsolicited
involve traffic you can use you can't
wait list for certain ideas that you may
be used for cash management security
handing things like that and then you
can get your w says to automatically
install windows updates for the user
gpo's you're gonna want to block
internet access for all Paul users group
that was created
ah you can do that through you know
RuPaul see you through internet explorer
approximate sittings or you can use
whatever you already have in place you
know if you have processor windows
security when let's carry whatever you
do that
oh you're also going to want to restrict
administrators from walking onto
volunteering post and you can do that
with the dialogue on rights so basically
you know you have your tr0 college they
should not be allowed to log onto your
tier 1 systems or two systems and then
you have your tier 1 college but should
be allowed want to use your workstations
you can use those login login right bebe
eau de do that
so what you have all the policies know
you all also pretty much been ready to
go you can start working on your
hospital hardware and when you do that
you can might want to consider your
supply chain and how much you trust your
you-know-what manufacturer and supplier
their security practices of a few actual
hardware that you're getting you don't
want to acquire your installation media
I'm so if you can use Windows 10
enterprise that the ideal so you can
take advantage of things like potential
guard place card you can use Windows 10
pro to you just walk you're going to use
those things so keep that in mind you
can set any complex password of the
local admin account
look look at this guide you can catch up
on the network join the domain go to the
right all you install windows updates
any necessary admin tools and when you
for the admin tools and installation
media you're gonna wanna obviously
verify your integrity on that and you
know check the hashes make sure that
match and for any admin tools that you
install the box
you're gonna want to really carefully
consider the risk exposure that you're
adding that system he only wanted
install stuff that is absolutely need
that in then you can forward your lost
any sim that you have a centralized
water repository and validate your
parking policies and once you have these
deployed to all active directory admins
that will be that you'll be doing phase
1 phase 2 is going to be extending this
out to all admins of mission-critical
applications and this is going to be
things you know like member server
admins hot services admins network
admins things like that and in face to
microsoft recommends enabling enforcing
restricted admin mode for desktop
connections and you know this is kind of
controversial thing I think you know the
the because ironically when you enable
restricted mode you are allowing hear
your long past the half Ashby rdp the
system and you know the benefit of
restricted have been mode is that it
leaves no reasonable credentials on the
other systems that you have anything to
wear as typical remote desktop
connection will leave it empty fashion
girls to get but you know you don't want
to weigh the risk versus reward here and
you know
you know that in my mind if you lock
down rdp so you can only you can only
rdp from trusted host enabling
researchers have been mowed the benefit
in not leaving reasonable credentials
when you have medicate are always any
additional additional recipe gets
created by enabling restricted am
anymore so you decide to use your admin
mode is off by default you need to
enable a lot of destination systems the
restricted to use it you just use the
restrictive in flag all with rdp and to
enforce that you do the restricted
restricted allegation of potentials to
remote servers are awesome and you make
that to any admin computer will use the
limitations of using restricted mode is
that when you connect to a system with
the shutdown mode and then you connect
to another system from that problem
there you're gonna be up any getting
with the computer account of that system
that you first walk into so you know
what you have like a network share
something like that it's going to be
using the computer account logging that
so that's just want to keep that in mind
then face to you're also going to want
me
move move objects to appropriately use
so 21 users herbs
thank you computer console and then any
Oscars want to also add users to the
tier 1 admins group so that's going to
allow you to use your policy to restrict
water or two places an optional step
here is you can while you can allow
whitelisted in a destination so like if
you have a cloud services that you need
to administer if you have a vendor that
means to be able to remote into provide
support for their application you can
West their their investigation on the
pause you know tr1 admins might need
different tools and 20 admin so you
don't want to carefully consider the way
to risk the beach in the tool you're
going to install
all you can also enable crystal guard at
this point guard is a fairly new
technology that the idea is to
virtualize windows services that manage
credentials
the idea is that you you're isolating
soul of an attacker is running as local
admin admin rights they're not the idea
would be not allow them to access those
credentials but there are some
requirements for that you need Windows
10 enterprising forbid i even have
secure boot enable and if they're good
the machine is at $TIME p.m. and he's
being hyper V and there's also a couple
of the record apartments with that so
keep that in mind
so face three builds on phase one is
really not depending on face to it all
and as things like multi-factor
authentication using smart cards and
white listing but things like device
garden at Walker which are really
awesome controls I don't have time to
dive into that you're fairly complex but
I brought them in for device card if you
can if you're interested in looking at
that check out matt grevers uh Bobby's
gonna get stuff on there also will talk
about protecting issues and dedication
policies styles so when those two factor
authentication solutions great control
but you gotta remember they're not a
magic bullet for this issue these issues
no they do have some limitations there
only enforce our interactive logons and
if you force my heart logons the hash
won't change that count
so if the attacker gets a passion for
those accounts they could use it to log
on the network wat ons and now you can
mitigate that by toggling the smart card
required setting and you can you script
that obviously but i believe that will
invalidate any sessions of those users
deadline
so protected users group this is one of
my favorite controls i think most think
that's the most painless to implement
basically just put users in the affected
users group and you get a whole bunch of
good benefits from that most of your
benefits that you're going to be you're
going to be given when she's running
2012 r2 functional level but you can you
still get some little bit if you're not
quite there yet and what this basically
does is it'll it'll force kerberos
authentication so you won't use it to
him at all and it'll force using AES
partner Bruce it all take your ticket
hours from 10-2 for your ticket you take
it only lasts for four hours instead of
10 and if you want to take it expires
and forces the user to relog on really
indicate now and also in in a little
graphic down there
the only thing stored in memory or else
ass is gonna be girls to get and don't
feature limitation depending on how you
look at it I wouldn't the user is a
member of protecting users group it was
the system any system log onto will not
store any local cache credentials so if
you put your user into the pop into my
user into the protective user group then
you go home and you're not able to hit
the domain controller you will be a lot
on that account so good thing to keep in
mind they're so education policies in
silos these pair well with protecting
users group and they do require 2012 r2
functional level now this'll do things
like you can control warehouse log on
what services they can authenticate to
you can set kind of granular Kerberos
ticket settings and is a great control
as well and also lessons learned from my
deployment
oh i know not everyone shares this but
Windows 10 enterprise has been great for
me
oh really good really good experience
with that you know using local p.m. we
don't have a dual monitors in a dock and
the audio microphone and copy space
between hosting bm's
ingrate also hyper-v networking has been
great you can easily put the answer in
two different view and you can change
from the private network to the wired
network wireless network
I had really good luck with all that but
i'm not going to say that deploying
pause going to make anything easier for
you
you know it really is a dramatic shift
in the date of most IT admins and you
know even for a small company you don't
have a handful or couple of IT people
the number of privileged accounts you
have to manage is can be seen kind of
daunting and I haven't found myself kind
of swearing at myself for making me
making myself do this but you know just
you get used to it after a while and the
benefits are definitely worth it if you
care about security environment so even
if you you know if you need just have to
figure out what works for you so if you
need you can't remember all those
passwords yourself you might want to
think about enterprise password project
something you're obviously going to put
away the risk of that as well but you
just need to figure out what works for
you and your your decision also you're
gonna probably want enabling internal
web browsing is it probably managing no
weapons of systems on your network and
if you do that if you walk in and
browsing with proxy settings policy one
way to do that is the proxy override the
policy-setting and also i found it
useful to script virtual switch config
changes in title using powershell like
switching locations shape scripting
those things making a password
ok so that's kind of the pot appointment
i'm gonna switch gears here a little bit
and talk about other things you can do
to women exposed to potential that and I
don't move and first one here being
network segmentation and you know I i
kinda compared college access
workstations 22 network segmentation at
you know it's a theory they're similar
but they're also have also found to my
appointment that they also pair well
with network segmentation so you know if
in this in this
Campbell here we have three offices in
each office has a different subnet four
different user groups you've got legal
accounting HR and IT and you know if you
start talking about network security
segmentation you start thinking about
things like okay like counting users
inside wanna do those pcs need to talk
to other users in accounting inside one
you know I don't know depends on the
business that could be a reason but
probably not another situation would be
like my users in legal and like three
they need to walk any of those computers
be to be able to talk to any other
computers in any of that coming subnets
you know maybe but if they do why do
they
and can we figure out a workaround so
they don't have to they don't have to
talk directly to each other it now
example that would be like if your legal
users inside 3i like to share screens
and help each other out with the legal
users inside one maybe you can use some
kind of cloud remote support service so
that they can still be each other's
screens but they don't have to talk
directly back and forth to each other
that would be a workaround so that you
can still segment those networks now one
way to do that never segmentation is to
use layer-3 ACL of the router level 2 to
block access from each subnet from each
other and then use do anything else
switch sides switch little hole so that
users within the same VLAN can't talk to
each other and save you in so in an
ideal an ideal situation here your your
legal users inside one would be able to
talk to any computers in any of the
counting subnets any computers in any of
the HR subnets or even any other
computers in any of the legal subnets
and what they know and obviously still
be able to get the servers so that they
need to hit
and and you know obviously need to hit
the IT subjects to be managed my key so
I was just thinking about those things
you know if you drop an attacker into an
environment where they can talk to any
other user workstations I think you're
going to make my job harder and it's on
top of that you're doing some of these
control so many potential left you're
gonna you're gonna make the job even
harder so does invest that kind of logic
there some other things you can do to
limit the potential left or specifically
lateral movement in this case I'll
randomized you look like a glance you
something like Microsoft lapses in where
I in that would that mean kaskapi they
give you a couple new SIDS user sits so
you can use the local account therefore
it says s 1s 5s 13 locale that's going
to be you can use that to deny logon
network logon to other systems so that
in a first example where you don't
potentials and you move laterally with
local accounts that will know how that
as a huge quickly and you're not doing
that I make sure you go home and do that
right away
also you can disable on the lnternet
vials if you familiar with like
responder and how it works you can see
obviously going to want to limit your
service top villages so as to as little
as possible and use manuscripts account
whenever you can and you can you don't
want to force into mb2 and if you can
disable some people say disabled in
Thailand altogether
I think that's great if you can not
everybody can probably do that so you
want at least for porcelain v2 and so it
comes to kind of wrap up here you hear
people talking all the time of all the
next-gen clients your sophomore that
stops every threat on demand and has
machine learning
Union apt detection and probably why
you're asking stuff ready to oh you know
it's so those are sales and marketing
people those companies are really good
at what they do that got really sexy
graphics and everything is so much
easier to go find one of those things
wrapped in your network and then say
alright we're good we're protected let's
go to lunch guys you know when to really
sit down and truly understand the risk
that you're dealing with and you know
learning from some offensive guys taking
their tools and trying to let Holly were
thinking you know things like power
company don't you know when most things
on your own mini-me cats rentals on your
network and use them to try to figure
out how they were not necessarily
blocking those tools to figure out how
those tools work you know finding your
weak points building walls said trips as
many trip wires as you can and plug the
point of all the best you can so
oh just want to say thank you to watch
people on Twitter that stuff with me
asking dumb questions after blue team
and these are definitely people with
people ball also well did mention Carlos
Perez but also fought him a lot of good
stuff there and uh i also want to
mention breaks that podcast and
offensive security podcast really good
start with your booty work so it all the
time we've got three minutes for
questions
yes the believe in you
organization i'm not doing much as these
switches and I mostly work with this
gold hardware switches and actually on
the slide back there's a config you an
ACL and that's what i use and all that
sounds like a kind of a more specific
question for any organization I i can I
don't have an answer for that
alright alright well thanks everybody
for coming