alright so as I stated earlier the talk
that was originally supposed to be in
this slot was me talking about medical
device security-related insulin pumps we
found some zero-day vulnerabilities in
the pump and we're working pretty
closely with the vendor and they need
some more time for the disclosure so we
pushed back by two weeks to help them
with that and so you'll find out about a
lot of the details related to that in in
two weeks but some of the technology
that I used and some of the techniques I
use came directly from my experience and
radios so when they asked me well do you
have another talk that you could give
even though it's only five days away
I said well I guess I could give a talk
on some of this ham radio stuff I want
to do and I said yeah that'd be great
so this is something I went together in
the last five days i have no idea if
it's going to take the entire hour or if
it's gonna take three hours with
material here but it's kind of an idea
that I've had for awhile to give at a
conference which is about license camera
operator since I was a kid and a lot of
the techniques and things that I've
learned in that hobby are things that i
use in my information security career
all the time so I wanted to kind of
compile them and show what things in
that hobby and the ideas that you learn
that hobby can be used
uh you know in practical application in
the security world this is me i asked my
dad for a picture of me taking apart
stuff and this is what he sent and I've
always been that kid I've always been
the kid taking things apart and trying
to figure out how they worked and from
an early age
ham radio has been kind of a rounded
part of my life
my dad's a ham radio operator his
brother is a ham radio operator and the
idea of ham radio operating to me is
kind of second nature and there's a lot
of controversy over like how the name
ham radio came to be about but basically
ham radio operators are hobbyists that
play in the radio community and you get
an FCC license and you're allowed to use
radios at certain powers at certain
frequencies
and there's been a lot of great talks
about what things you can do in ham
radio and what it is to get license that
i'm not going to cover because I want to
talk to you about some of the things
that goes on after you get a license
which i haven't seen covered too much in
a lot of these talks so where does my
story start well this is my dad .
embarrassingly probably drinking at the
kitchen table with a soldering iron
putting together or fixing something and
he ever since I was little has been
exposing me to the world of hardware
electronics he's big he's done computer
programming he does hardware programming
and overall has been a great dad and a
great mentor to me even to this day when
i run into problems when I'm
reverse-engineering a protocol for doing
RF stuff or even code
I'll call my dad and to get advice and
get a different I look at things and how
things work but in the summer 1988 we're
at the very peak of the solar spot cycle
and we're at the peak of the solar spot
cycle it's probably the most exciting
time for amateur radio operators because
it means that you don't eat very much to
talk all the way around the world and I
vividly remember that my dad had this
exact radio in this car it's a 10-meter
radio that you can be you can use it for
Syd CB radio as well but it puts out
only 10 watts and he had a little magma
antenna that you stuck on the top of his
car and I would remember going out and
sitting in the car listening these
stations that were all over the world
they were in South America they were in
Cuba there in Europe Australia and there
was nothing between me sitting in this
car and that other person either side of
the world and i think that that's
something that's lost in today that
magic we just kind of take it for
granted that we can spin up an email
send it off and gets where it's supposed
to go in half a second in 88 this was
crazy like it's crazy that I could do
this with a radio and a piece of wire
off the top of my dad's car and here and
talk to these people and instantly that
magic is what really had me hooked
so first to play in the game you gotta
get a license and back in eighty-eight
the licensing requirements still meant
that you had to learn morse code and
this was a really controversial thing
right
so for the very first test you had to
pass five words minute
whoo-hoo so this is what five words in
it sounds like
all now at the speed you could think of
it and you could probably look it up in
your head all right dash . all right
that's the you know and and something
like that so it's pretty easy the bars
pretty low to pass that as you advance
through the licenses they get harder so
13 words per minute is the next one
that's what it starts to speed up it
becomes not as easy to look up in your
head at 20 words per minute is the most
advanced license you can get and that's
what this sounds like
so those are the three classes now since
then they've removed all of the Morse
code requirements for the lace injure
the back back in my day and this is
something that ham radio has in common
with the security community is there's a
lot of people that are back in my day
people real hand did CW real hands did
Morse code you know real hand real
security people use the command line
very similar methodology is between
those two along with this code test you
took a multiple choice test that's very
technical just kind of study for it
memorized the questions
it really wasn't too bad at 12 years old
I pass license you get a call sign and
that call sign is unique to you and how
you identify yourself on the air and my
first call sign was na RHP and that
first part there the end part signifies
what country you're in and the eighth is
what section of the country you're in
so you can tell by a person's callsign
where they got license from originally
this is the very first radio I had it
was given to me as a gift by my uncle
it's a nineteen seventies handheld radio
it only covered for megahertz for the
bandwidth it was heavy use nicad
batteries i could probably knock
somebody out with it it was a great
little radio back in those days there
were several several hundred dollars and
that was that was really cool was a
great gift to have it was a
I very bond memories of it now the first
passion that I had with radio and ham
radio stuff is actually in packet radio
a packet radio was this concept and let
me but hopefully it sounds familiar is
you take two computers and you make them
communicate with each other
digitally and they can exchange
information so through a combination of
things through the HT in the computer I
i was able to load a program called NOS
network operating system and this nice
thing had a full list of this tcp i--
something tcp/ip thing and with tcp/ip I
could communicate and get my own IP
address because there's an entire class
a set aside for amateur radio
communication 244 net so you can see up
there that was the IP address that i got
back in 1989 and i was able to set up a
station with that IP address that was
able to do male that was able to use
ping finger was another command that we
used quite a bit if you remember this is
way before HTTP way before web browsers
and was also slow it was 1200 baud
half-duplex so i could only talk or
listen I couldn't do both at the same
time so to give you an idea who silly
thing give you an idea of what that
sounds like
that is this that is the first part of a
TCP handshake what it sounds like
also with this program was kind of neat
if you hit f9 you could see all of the
packets that could be heard on that
frequency that sounds kind of familiar
it was exactly like wireshark is for TCP
dump i can see the headers I could see
the tcp all the tcp fields and at 12 and
13 years old I was kind of figuring out
okay this is how the packets are
structured this is how they were talking
and it was really fascinating to play
with this type of technology and one of
the things that was kind of neat i lived
way up here my callsign now is n 80 s i
lived in the Detroit area and there's a
gateway down at Wayne State University
21.1 miles away and that gateway would
from Radio to the internet because Wayne
State back in the late eighties was you
know colleges had internet connection so
i couldn't quite get my signal all the
way to wayne state so what I ended up
having to do was I had to talk to a
friend of mine and I would route all of
my traffic that needed to go to the
internet to their also sounds very
familiar to what
maybe we do these days with routing and
i set my default route to that so i
couldn't communicate with something
directly i would go through that person
or maybe if i was going north of me
there would be another route that I
would take different thing in these
programs you had to set all of these
routes by hand so you were manually
making routing tables to figure out how
to route packets all over the place and
collectively back in the late eighties
early nineties you get all over the
United States purely on wireless with
the wireless connection connectivity
that goes around now since then
that's kind of a little bit falling off
the wayside because everybody's got high
speed internet at home but it's starting
to make a comeback that we'll talk about
a little later but the skills I learned
in in packet radio where I went to read
my
packets everything was going so slow
that i could actually I remember laying
in my bed and listening and saying all
that's a handshake
that's a piece email coming in just by
how long my transmitter was on and how I
could hear it because of how slow the
data it was being transmitted
so if you were to slow down a TCP
handshake and listen to it you could do
that at that speed and building routing
tables is something that a that became
second nature but you know what
and really didn't want to depend on
somebody else to get down to that hand
gate
I wanted to have a direct internet
connection so how do I do that I'm 12
years old I need to build an antenna is
what i need to do now I don't have any
money because their child labor laws and
my dad's gonna buy the antenna and hams
have a long history of building stuff
out of garbage of taking things apart
taking junk and building something else
so i built what you see up there on the
screen i got a broken hockey stick
I some dollars from the hardware store
the leftover wire from a construction
site and a 20-ounce pop bottle and with
the knowledge that I had from passing
the tests i was able to build a cubicle
clot and with that i was able to easily
talk down to that hand gate and
directionally move the antenna to talk
to other people and this was pretty cool
I was so bummed when I would start
looking for pictures this week because i
was like dad why do we take pictures any
of this stuff he was like you mean that
junkie antenna that you built that you
stuck at top your bedroom like yeah he
was like I'd never thought you would
need a picture of it
and i was like i really wish i had a
picture of it so this is close as I
could get
but it's really kind of cool and like I
said there's a history of this and hams
love doing this kind of stuff
how about an old beat-up launch it
doesn't work anymore right
very easily this guy took this aluminum
frame lawn chair and built-in antenna
out of it
how about a broken tape measure broken
tape measure in a couple pieces of
leftover plumbing material PVC and you
have a very accurate a high powered
antenna the thing that I learned here is
that knowledge is more important than
commercial tools right you can go out
and buy any kind of commercial tool you
want but having the knowledge on how to
build things on your own whether that is
an antenna or shell script or whatever
it maybe sometimes it's better because
you actually have the knowledge on what
it is and how it's working as opposed to
just quit taking it out of the box and
sticking it and hoping it works you can
build things that you need to be
creative i mean i think that's that's
part of having fun
um you know I've always think thought of
hacking as taking something that has a
function and making you do something
that was never intended to do like this
slinky this is one of the more popular
intends to build as you get to
old-school slinkies and you can make an
antenna out of them and taking things
and making them do something else
whether it's a program whether it's a
website whether it's a toy and making it
do something else is a lot of what our
security field is and about how we think
about it so on the next thing of
building things I got into kit building
and this is something that has become a
lot more prominent and a lot more useful
as we have gotten into hardware hacking
and that's become an Internet of Things
take things apart look at the circuitry
well I would be I would build kits
here's an example of a kit that I built
it's just a bag of parts you've got to
get a soldering iron and learn how to
read a schematic and nowhere to put the
parts in so I could remember as a kid
sitting with my dad at the kitchen table
building things like this learning how
to solder how to troubleshoot things
when it didn't work and never did the
first time you tried to build it it's
really the foundation of hardware
hacking the history of kids for ham
radio operators goes a long way back you
know this right here is probably one of
the most famous kid companies that there
was which is he KITT and heat it was
based on a Benton Harbor Michigan and
they made tons of radio kits this one
right here being the one of the most
popular which is a 2000 watt amplifier
you could buy this for a couple hundred
box back in the sixties and they are
still in use and quite popular because
they don't die and they're easy to
repair and they're worth quite a bit so
these kits have so much documentation
and you learn so much by building them
that it really produced a great
foundation for learning electrical
theory and learning how to build and
take apart things now today they're a
lot more advanced but they still exist
this is the most popular kit company
right now it's l craft and they're based
out of the Pacific Northwest and they
built this is kind of their flagship not
there
this used to be the flagship radio but
this is a kit that you can build and the
kit looks like this that circuit board I
you have to put all the parts on it so
you have to solder it together and you
have to align it and it's a process that
takes about a month to build that radio
but at the end of that month you will
have built a radio and you will have no
you will know how to tune that radio and
you will know all the pieces where the
amplification section is where the
oscillators are and that's kinda neat
you know that's kind of an exciting
prospect
you know we don't get a chance to do
something like that where we build
something from scratch and it's it's
been it
it's always a fascinating process and
because of that these kids are extremely
popular
the skills I learned there are i mean
this is the foundation of all the
hardware hacking that i do when i take
apart an insulin pump or medical device
or an Internet of thing or whatever it's
just like being a kid again it's
soldering it son soldering things it's
trying to make it work
it's trying to make it do something it
wasn't supposed to do in the first place
also being able to diagnose and
troubleshoot hardware
oh well i know that if i don't have the
ground setup right this isn't gonna work
or it's going to act like in this way
also gets need to build things you know
that the hacking community as a whole
has really gotten into a making
community with 3d printers and arenas
and raspberry PI's and this these two
areas really mesh well together and
learning how to read a schematic and
build those type of electrical circuits
going to talk a little bit about some of
the radio sports and these are
competitive features of radio so one of
the first that I participated in as a
teenager was something called fox
hunting and fox hunting is the sport of
finding the physical location of a
transmitter you got a picture up here of
some kids with a directional antenna
very similar to the one built out of the
tape measure i showed you earlier and
they're working on trying to find this
transmitter the transmitter could be
really small like it could be hidden in
a tree
it's usually battery-powered it's
usually maybe the size it would fit in
your hand so you use directional
antennas to determine the source of the
signal and then you try and track it
down and they have competitions for how
quickly people can can find it on foot
or to find it in a car and this is a
really kind of a practical thing because
if you have something interfering with
the radio signal or maybe interfering
with a wireless network you need to be
able to track down the physical location
of that transmitter so you can do
something about it also
back into this creativity element this
is something that my dad and I had built
one of these this isn't the exact one
because again we didn't take pictures of
the junk that we made because why would
we need pictures of it but this is a
Doppler unit and what this is is a small
microprocessor would switch between four
antennas and the Doppler shift in the
signal between the four antennas was
able to calculate the direction in the
heading of the signal so we could have
this strapped to the top of the car and
drive and the LED would point to the
direction of where the transmitter was
located and that's something that we
built from scratch on our own which was
kinda cool
the skills I learned here I learned a
lot about wireless signals and wireless
networking housing signals get
manipulated it by physical structures as
you get more advanced into fox hunting
they put which the transmitter in
sneakier places like up against metal
buildings or near power lines and it
becomes really confusing when the signal
gets picked up by those power lines or
bounces off of buildings not all that
much different than wireless networks
and how we map a wireless network but
also it was fun like it was the way that
they set these up were really tiny
things and you were going and hunting
around for him it felt very spy-like so
as a teenager I thought it was a blast
it was like treasure hunting one of my
passions really became a contest as a
radio sport con testing is a sport where
you try and make the most amount of
context in a set amount of time and you
exchange the information accurately this
and information could be very simple
like what state you're in and how much
power you're running or it could be
complex it could be your name a unique
serial number the first year licensed
the county or in things like that
so there's a 24 there's a 12-hour 24
hour and 48 hour period that they might
have these contests where you try and
contact as many people as possible the
most popular methods of contests are
voice and surprisingly to some Morse
code which is referred to as CW
continuous-wave the rates for how
quickly you can make contacts at a big
station can exceed 200 contacts an hour
which is a lot of information and the
reason that these contests became
popular and have been kind of used
throughout the years is this is how you
prepared for an emergency if you needed
to pass a lot of information to let's
say the entire phone system went out for
all the power in the United States went
out how would we exchanged messages
well we could use radios to do that and
we could use radios to exchange this
information accurately and effectively
all over the place
I had a wonderful opportunity to work at
what I would refer to as a superstation
which is a station that has a lot of
antennas and a lot of investment
equipment in order to compete at a very
high level so this is one of the super
stations that I I I didn't operate this
one but I operated one very similar so
each of those towers are probably a
hundred and sixty feet tall on each of
those antennas are at least 40 feet long
so right there you have enough antenna
you you probably have half a million
dollars just an antenna equipment there
and then each of those antennas are
hooked up the radios usually in some
kind of a bunker or house nearby there
it's pretty cool to see that kind of a
setup
this is actually the setup that I that I
worked at in ypsilanti michigan at the
guys call signs KCC and he has four
different and 10 are raised and his
entire basement is radio equipment and
he's invested a lot of time in competing
at that and he has records for the most
amount of contacts in some of these
contests
give you an idea of the scale of some of
this stuff i mean there those are the
two people up there working on the
antenna arrays those are big and tennis
a giant this is the rack of amplifiers
and all of those amplifiers put out
2,000 watts of peace and they're all
hand-built so the creativity and the
amount of knowledge that you need to
build this type of equipment is pretty
excessive and also to not interfere with
the other stations that are right there
two feet away give you an idea what a
contest sounds like I've got two
examples here voice example and icw
example so there's only 30 seconds each
of them so hopefully you can hear it
ya know president killing 15 tengo radio
your heart for cargo box 16 go find 176
/ trihard thank you killed my 510 go
radio power your little 9000 radio find
out 177 your kind of primary role thank
you for 15 tengo radio for BTW find 178
so you can see he's working those
stations he's exchanging information you
know and a unique serial number and
getting it back from them but you can
also it's a little hard to hear those
radio stations are calling three or four
at a time and he's able to sort those
out in his head by just by listening and
a very quick rate which is impressive he
did over 21 contacts here in three
minutes in CW you can go even faster
most of the contests most of the really
good high-end contest operators prefer
to do CW where
so it's kind of on its kind of a unique
way I've always been amazed at the
people that can sit with headphones on
listening that and be like have a
conversation with me and decode that in
our head and type in the station so
remember and just work people and I'm
like that's never been anything I could
do
I've never been a master at the Morse
code proportion of us so it's need now
just about everybody has their first
contest experience with the same contest
it's a special contest referred to his
field day and field day is special
because the object is to start with an
empty field with nothing and in 24 hours
set up a station and that station needs
to operate for 24 hours and you make as
many contexts as possible and you get
extra points for using alternative power
and doing it in public locations and the
object here is to simulate a very
realistic scenario whether it be a
hurricane or tornado a terrorist attack
where you lose all communication and
then you set up a station to communicate
all over the United States and exchange
that information and it's
really popular because everybody can
participate in it because everybody's
kind of starting from scratch in an
empty field or in a park or at their
house but you're not allowed to use any
existing antenna structures so this is
an example of like a field day setup
they went out into the woods and they
put these antennas up in the in a couple
hours and they're gonna operate for 24
hours exchange information all over the
United States you know what talk a
little bit about CW and morse code to
give you an example to give you an idea
of why it's still really popular is that
it's the original digital mode this is
how we were sending what this is how we
send ones and zeros it's on and off key
which is used in a lot of Internet of
Things transmitters right now and it's
exceptionally efficient you can see on
this slide there's a lot of signals
there's a lot of people transmitting
Morse code here but the amount of
bandwidth that this is using is
minuscule it's . 007 megahertz worth of
bandwidth to give you an idea of your
wireless 802 11 signal is usually 20
megahertz wider 40 megahertz wide so
that's this is not even a dot on the
stat spectrum relative and we've got at
least 20 stations communicating to each
other effectively here so it's really
efficient way of communicating in a
pretty good amount of information
one of the big things that amateur radio
has gotten into in the past that it's
always been a big part of amateur radio
but especially in the past ten years is
emergency communication and when they
had a slip they have a slogan that when
all else fails that amateur radio is
there we have become totally and
completely dependent on cell phones on
the internet and on that technology and
what happens when it stops working
we've had situations where it has in
hurricanes in third world countries
where amateur radio operators were able
to stand up and start communicating
statuses and coordinate rescue efforts
within hours and sometimes less
so a lot of amateur radio operators are
very proud of their commitment to
emergency communications and being able
to respond to disaster situations like
that the skills I learned here I learned
a lot about disaster recovery when we
advise customers on you know when I
advise customers on disaster recovery I
talk about testing and I talk about
what's going to happen when your phone
stopped working and they go oh what's
the chances of my phone's not working
um and I realistically know that that's
a possibility
do you do disaster recovery planning
have you tested this equipment out so
that it works
one of the reasons that field day is
popular is because it's every year in
June it gives you a chance to test out
that all your kit that you could take
into the woods and set up a station if
you had to and that testing only get
this only stuff only works when it's
tested completely and it's done often
passing traffic and messages and all
forms of communication or down is
something that's really important
how do you do that at your company you
know if something were to happen we know
we saw something that happened with
hurricane sandy when it came through on
the east coast is your debt disaster
recovery plan have the ability to
communicate with other forms of other
forms of communication are down that you
can't text how do you find those people
that are in your disaster recovery plan
it's important i also learned about
building incredibly complex radio
systems with lots of transmitters at
high power and that's been very handy
for things like devices that communicate
with wireless signals that maybe your
exchange data with cell phones or
medical devices i'm gonna go over a
couple of other areas that I don't have
a ton of experience with but are
definitely big in the community
the first is there's a lot of space
stuff that goes on there's a whole
section of the hobby that build
satellites
the thing that you see on the far
right-hand side is ham sath five it's a
satellite that hobbyist built that nasa
put in space that orbits that orbits
outer space and the picture on the left
there is a little girl in a guy working
that satellite with that intent that
he's holding and a small handheld radio
and just imagine that that's that's a
radio that puts out five watts of power
that's no bigger than your cell phone
and it's talking to a satellite space
that's pretty cool
a lot of the astronauts on the ISS space
station are amateur radio operators and
they do a lot of operating from the
space station so there's often
classrooms that get to talk to them
through amateur radio and through ham
radio connections so there's a lot going
on and that in the space world with
amateur radio a hobbyist level now we
can talk about some even crazier stuff
right
this is called a moonbounce array and
what this is is if you get enough
antennas and enough power and you can
see the moon you about signal off it so
maybe I can only talk 10 miles with my
little handheld radio on the same
frequency with this antenna array and a
whole bunch of power i could talk from
here to Europe if the moons in the right
spot
wow that's got crazy that's hacking
right let's bounce some stuff off the
moon and we can get much further signals
about meteors meteor standard is
something that we we can use quite a lot
on different things so if we know
there's a meteor shower we can we can go
thousands of kilometers between two
stations where normally we wouldn't be
able to do that by aiming our signal at
the trail of the meteors or the where
the meteor shower is happening and
bouncing the signal off of that these
are some of the crazy things that you
can do in the hobby in the hobby of
radio and to me this is like classic
hacking right like that's crazy you
can't do that that there's no
possibility that work well I want to try
it anyway
there's a huge group of enthusiasts that
really love the low-power aspect they
want to see how far they can go on a
little power as possible
qrp is it is kind of a slang term for
very low power usually under 5 watts the
record as it sits right now from what I
was able to find is two stations between
Alaska and oregon in 1970 were able to
go
sixteen hundred and fifty miles using
one micro watt and so that is the
equivalent of 1.6 billion miles per watt
that's crazy like and that's the truth
that's very similar to the transmitter
that they were using is what you see
there they build it in an Altoids tin
it's pretty creative stuff
Morse code has been actually increasing
in popularity since since they got rid
of that requirement in the license test
I don't really know how to explain it
people are very competitive with it the
speeds can get an excess of 200 words
per minute
I mean you saw how quickly that was and
that was roughly around 30 is about how
fast you heard some of that stuff 200
doesn't really sound like any human
sounds more like aliens are contrasting
people often 30 50 words a minute is
usually where they kind of hang out at
speed-wise again they do it all in their
head conversational going back to like
community stuff
public service is another big piece that
ham radio operators do they have clubs
and these clubs will get together and
they will provide communication for
parades will provide communication for
athletic events like marathons
triathlons here you see one at that my
dad was participating in in the state of
Michigan where they were doing
communications like for a bike ride and
this gives the ability for them to be
able to communicate if somebody got hurt
if somebody needs to get somebody needs
to get picked up those types of things
we think that cell phones would be great
for that but when you get out
we know how we know how great cell phone
communication works when you're out the
middle of nowhere this is a much more
reliable method another area that's
always been popular is collecting what
are called qsl cards in qsl is ham radio
slang for a verified communication so a
lot of ham radio operators will have a
card a little postcard and they'll say
yes I'm confirming that i talked to you
at this day at this time with this
information you collect these cards and
you can get awards for these cards so
there's a work call State's award
there's a work call countenance award
there's a work call countries award or
worked a hundred countries award so you
collect these cards and you can put them
on your wall you can see all these are
all the places that I've talked to
through my radio station and it's been a
very popular way to collect them as
we've got into the digital age
this has turned into eqs l cards and
there's several sites that specialize in
matching this information up and
automatically instead of mailing a
postcard now we do that digitally
verifying that we heard and it and
communicated with this other person
we're also seeing some recycling here so
this is an older linksys router and ham
radio operators are starting to you by
up some of this equipment and modifying
the firmware and building entirely
independent off the off the internet
networks that are high-speed multimedia
mesh networks so because amateur radio
operators can use more frequency and
more power and larger antennas they're
buying this equipment modifying the
firmware and then building their own ISP
they're building their own wireless
infrastructure to communicate almost
exactly like we were doing in the
eighties except for not at 1200 baud
have to place which is pretty cool
it's a great way of repurposing going
back to that original kind of
methodology and concept of hack
is taking things that are other people's
garbage repurposing them and making them
into something that's extremely useful
so we're by using all these ham radio
skills now
well at 900 megahertz is there's an eye
is what we call the is M band or the
mics band and this is used quite a bit
in the medical world a lot of medical
devices communicate on this band they're
designed to be very short distance so
maybe only 10 feet is how they're
supposed to communicate like if you had
a pacemaker or an insulin pump that's
what they design that effective range to
do but as we've talked about we could
build antennas and get much further we
can use higher power and we can get much
further and communicate with them we
also have a lot of equipment in in the
world especially in the power grid world
that runs at 400 megahertz which is also
right near a hand ham radios spectrum
this goes back again to we can build
antennas we can do things to communicate
with them in ways they were intended to
be communicated with about RFID chips
those run at 13 megahertz a lot of those
contests super stations the pictures
that you saw in there those amplifiers
and that equipment would work on the
rfid of 13 megahertz
hmm what can i do with giant hundred and
sixty foot towers and two kilowatts of
power with an RFID how far can I talk to
it I know and obviously software radio
has become really huge now that we have
so much horsepower in our computers we
can do a lot more with software than we
could in building and we can hear
farther and we can process more in that
time hack RF one is a great example of
that in the last several years these
come to be two hundred dollars and are
heavily used now in the hacking
community in the internet of things in
in the hardware hacking world
so here's an example of some work so
this is a yardstick one another tool
that's similar to hack RF and it puts
out 0.01 wants but at a ham radio
convention i bought an amplifier an
amplifier will make that into a hundred
watts
that's a pretty substantial increase in
power I'm license with my FCC license to
go up to 1500 watts if i want to but 100
watts will be enough for now
now for every 3 DB of increase that's
like doubling your power so i put some
and i bought some antennas that you can
see here in the pictures that double and
triple and quadruple the amount of power
but not only that they quadruple the
amount of listening that I can do so I
can listen further with these types of
antennas and in a single direction so
what's possible
that's a great question what could you
talk to with 10,000 times more power and
eight times more listening capability
that would be in the medical world how
far could you get or the smart grid
world or in the Internet of Things world
these are the kind of cool things that I
like to work we work on a new research
on because i don't know i don't have a
lot of the answers those questions I
have a lot of fun doing this type of
stuff and using my hobby and using the
25 years I've been doing ham radio stuff
to play around medical devices and to
say when people come up to me and say
well you can't talk to that medical
device it's more than 10 feet away and I
kind of smile and I think we can bounce
a signal off the moon at almost the same
at the same frequency range and I could
talk to somebody in europe i think i can
get a quarter mile away i think i can
get a half a mile away
I don't think that's going to be a
problem
and that's surprising to people but hams
have been doing this for decades have
been pushing the boundaries on what's
possible and that's something that's
really exciting and they still continue
to do that today I'm taking things
taking other people's garbage things
that are disposable and reusing them
very much like a hacking culture would
so that is what I have to thank you guys
for coming and I hope you enjoyed it
oh yeah sorry