all right where did the camera give me
does it start to state i want to move
around too much then but i do like to
move my good i need tape on the floor
pan allowed
alright so it's ten o'clock so i don't
you tell one sorry for the little
technical issues that we had but now
we've got that worked out thanks for
getting up early on a Sunday to come in
here I know that can be tough especially
after the big party that they have on
sunday or saturday night as we're going
to talk about recharging penetration
testing to maximize value and so pen
testing something to do for a long time
I focus on App sec side of the house and
I used to do all of it but now I really
just focus on the app's exide so that's
what we're going to kind of look but a
lot of this stuff that we're gonna talk
about can be pulled over into the
network side as well or Wi-Fi whatever
you testing so just a little bit about
me
my name is James starting if you haven't
met me before if you have great if not
feel free to come up I love meeting new
people
i'm the CEO of charting software don't
let the software confuse you have had
the company for a long time or I used to
do software and now I focus on the
application security services for my
clients
I'm doing things like program reviews
penetration testing and security
education do a lot of instructing a lot
of presenting presenting a few years ago
and most notably more is I do a lot of
blogging and podcasting so a lot of the
stuff that I talked about I also write
about i talked about on a podcast I'm so
you can check those out i got listed at
the bottom there so why we want to talk
about this for me and I just came up
with this morning so bear with me
630 I woke up and I was like you know
what this is perfect so I like to do
woodworking and such on the side when
I'm when I'm not working on security
stuff and so recently this is a bench
that we had that is very old
you know you should be a park bench in
the city and then it got kind of moved
over and they replaced them so we got
our hands on top but it's pretty quickly
right its functional we can sit on it
works it's good i but it is pretty
rundown absolutely actually took some
time and we redid it a little bit
this is the greatest picture i get a
better one that I did I felt bad saying
this is the same French this is the same
bench but I read it right and i said
look this is gonna be something is going
to be more enticing people going to be
interested in looking at it they want to
deal with it they may want to sit in it
may actually start conversations so we
redid it original wood new hardware but
the rails and everything are all the
same right
it's much better this one the pictures
just a little bit better but it's not
the same thing you just look the same
but just to show right i mean the
functionality didn't change but we get
out of it might actually be more because
we might start more conversation about
it so that's why i thought you know what
this kind of an interesting lead into
when we talk about pentesting as it is
versus where I think there's some places
we can make some enhancements to make
pentesting better and more valuable to
our clients we know we're doing when we
pen tap so how can we get more out of
the clients so the first question we
have what is pentesting alright
everybody this is different
I mean depending on who you talk to it's
actually going in and trying to get
doesn't matter whether its network
whether its web whether it's Wi-Fi right
now you're trying to penetrate in as far
as you can you get specific goals i want
to get domain credentials I want to get
all this data but you talk to other
people and a lot of times especially
when we talk about a pen testing it's
more about really the vulnerability
doesn't kind of steroids right here i
want to go find as much as I can about
this application find all the security
risks and then bring those over report
them and bring them back to the client
so they can get better at developing
software right rarely are we seeing
we're getting in there through an
application like this and getting domain
cred right a lot of our appt set out on
different servers are not even on our
infrastructure so we're not get this
right so a lot of the testing that we
see actually turns into really a
vulnerability assessment with some
exploitation involved right we're
identifying cross-site scripting and
sequel injection and logic blog and all
these different things right with to
understand what are we doing women and
how the different from things like bug
bounties right i mean how different away
from that and there's a big difference
there won't get into this but there's a
big difference
and then from what we're doing I you
know we do stuff on a contractual basis
we're doing things specifically for the
clients not its own silo will talk about
so anybody tender become last year mr.
pretty regular event people like coming
to this right
anybody hit the panel that they had on
the future of infosec I wasn't your last
year but i did watch the video as exotic
screenshot of it I it was good right
talking about where we going with this
and they talked a lot about penetration
testing and we're getting more into the
need of saying hey I can't just provide
a simple report of haiti across it
scripting we have to start mapping this
stuff and you know what let's go to
refer to as adversarial mapping right
getting further into and saying okay yes
you have cross-site scripting but what
does that mean what does that mean to
you in your organization because if it's
just a generic i have cross-site
scripting well then what does that
really mean for me as far as when i
would bet on my priority list right a
healthcare system may be different than
the financial system which is different
than your marketing site that's out
there
writes all still risk but i have to
understand how does it really affect me
and that's our goal was pentesting
writers were coming in saying i'm going
to put value behind these things that
we're going to identify not just
identifiable right we talk about David
Kennedy mentioned how the red team
learned from the blue team you know one
thing going to say is even though we
like to separate red and blue red is
really part of blue right we are a
defensive mechanism to be able to help
the defensive side if we weren't part of
blue that we'd actually destroy things
really actually still the data user
prevent we're here to help build up the
blue side and they hate your we're
testing your weaknesses were identifying
and we're gonna help you get past that
you know quantifying how while that
defense is detecting you that's
typically more unfortunately on the
network side applications still do a
really horrible job but doing good
logging so that people know what's going
on in them anyway but it's still
something that we're trying to detect
right when we do a nap past you know
there should be somebody looking to see
if we're gonna do this now the question
is who's looking probably not our
developers right i mean they're not
looking at the logs they look at
troubleshooting log they don't look at
traffic
logs and attack logs and those side
effects understanding our failure points
right Don strand talk about that and
nickerson who you know near to my heart
the idea that we are a quality assurance
industry right now we're pentesting when
we're doing any type of testing whether
bug bounty pentesting however it is
right it's QA I mean it is a form of you
a we're helping them understand the
quality of their application the quality
of their network against security not
just the we spelled stuff wrong or
functionally doesn't work and we expect
right so we're value at to them but one
of the concerns I often see I don't know
how many people saw this floating around
Twitter not long after it came out a
bunch of people were two hashtagging pen
testers on it you know as if this is how
we're proceed right we come in with
break stuff and relieve sorry about your
bad luck I'm not cleaning this up right
and that's a problem
I mean if this is really how we're
perceived then why do people want to
work with us right i don't want somebody
just come in and break a whole bunch of
my stuff and leave
I want somebody's gonna be a partner in
what I'm doing I want somebody to help
me out so I thought that was interesting
actually got me all riled up and if you
don't hear me talk offline i'll rant
about this stuff all day long but
working on changing that perception
right we don't want to be that we want
to be more than just a tester want to be
more than just a red team of coming in
and said hey I'll find some
vulnerabilities and i'll send him your
way to be more than a breaker right we
always say well we're breakers were not
fixed I'm not saying we have to be
pictures right that is a specialized
skill and quite honestly most of us
probably do not have that skill we're
good at breaking and it's nothing wrong
with that right with to embrace that but
we're here to be the experts right I'm
hiring a pen test company to come in and
test my apps i'm assuming you are a
network export you are an application
security expert right you know how this
stuff work and much deeper than just
being able to break it right and when we
look on the network site we have to know
this stuff how many people that do
network testing really understand
networks and they understand server
admin
you know you can go into a linux box and
walk your way around a command line and
do all this stuff but then you start
getting out start a web app testing
mobile app testing and it's like yeah I
can run a proxy and I can run some of
these tools but maybe I don't know
exactly how development works i write
some script that's not really
development you know I work together
some tools but enterprise development
very different
so we don't understand that I'm so it's
kind of a detriment to us but we're here
to help right if we understand that I'm
not here to be in a silo right i would
like to say breaking down the silos we
should help
we're here to test for a reason it's not
just adversarial testing that we're
doing we actually want to be providing
value back to the client and
unfortunately to do that we have to pack
that whole process use social
engineering to get them to understand
what we're saying matters everything
that we put out there doesn't mean it's
going to be something on the top of
everybody's less and I saw somebody not
too long ago they were ranting on
twitter about you know username
harvesting flaw and how it wasn't part
of a lot of bug bounties you know and as
we talked about it through the Twitter
hundred forty character limit which is
ridiculous by the way to have a
conversation as we talked about that I
started asking the question right but
why does it matter
i mean you're talking username
harvesting what are you trying to do
with it because everything you're trying
to do you've got a million user names in
your list that you've downloaded from
some breach and you want to go and
attack the site with that ok well what
username harvesting going to get you
going to help reduce your list right
great it'll be less queries going again
but quite honestly nobody logging so if
i send a million requests rights and a
hundred thousand requests if they're not
logging it doesn't matter if they are
logging that's 100,000 requested privacy
anyway so it didn't help me write so yes
it's a flaw but we have to understand
what is that plot mean and is it
important to the company because I can
do all that stuff with using harvesting
do without it you know until you want to
get down into really specific hey I want
to Spearfish people and I know your user
of this system so now i can send out
just to users and cut down
traffic but as far as attacking as I
directly write that not a necessary
means we can get around them so i always
like to say application and network
right there different anybody that
thinks the otherwise i'm willing to say
you're wrong there are different right
like i said before I mean application
people they know applications they know
development that it's a different set of
vulnerabilities that we're looking at
verses we're looking at the network
right we use different tools we use
different knowledge look at the tools
right what I'm doing a network
assessment we're looking at things like
cali and we use the metasploit right
Nessus an nmap and we've got this whole
list of tools that we could use to
attack a network right we've got
responder out there we got these
different techniques that we use that if
we get on your network this is what
we're going to attack with and this is
just a short list don't feel like a
gypsy anybody but then we look on the
applications i read these different
tools rarely am i using metasploit on an
application tasks except for if I
actually find a vulnerability through
some other means and then i'm going to
try to exploit it right like I'm
actually going to put a remote shell on
a machine but i'm not using metasploit
to find vulnerabilities in the webapp
anybody do that doesn't work very well
far as i know right typically we're
using verbal using a proxy of some sort
to find those animals would find them we
switch into tools i use my sequel map i
use these other things get around but
I'm not relying on the same types of
tools you know you might even run Nessus
but it's not going to give you a whole
lot with your web app it's more
infrastructure related so we have to
understand that these tools of
difference that we're using out there
the knowledge that we're using a
different right so that works odd it's
very heavy on the networking knowledge
your server admin pipe knowledge
understanding OS is all the stuff that's
going on in your dhcp dns and all that
stuff while you go into a knapsack
interview and they'll ask you those
questions but not nearly as relevant
right because i'm attacking an
application a true application
credentialed much do i need to know
about the NS a whole lot already know
about the ECP I don't need to know about
a lot of
packet traffic going back and forth
because I pack it differently and so
there's a different knowledge there an
application i say look we have to
understand development we have to
understand how applications are built
the same way we need to understand how
networks are Bill and of course
networking and server that all comes
into play with an application security
deal because what we actually pop the
box we find a way in
now we have to know all this stuff but
it's a very different context because
how often are you getting that far with
applications and then once you do i know
you have to have that so i always say we
need to have a solid understanding of
development
I just like I've said before we have to
have a good solid understanding of
networking when I go in and test Network
I have to have an understanding network
have to understand the protocol that
have to understand all that stuff you're
gonna go to Wi-Fi right you have to
understand those tools you have to
understand that same thing with
development we have to understand how
these after built there's so much change
going on and development right now we've
got angular like so much client-side
stuff now that's going on so not even
half of its server side anymore
now you're attacking things like angular
and react now they've got electron out
which we can actually make like desktop
apps that are all filled with javascript
then call out to api's you know if you
slack anybody slack that's written an
electron I'm so it's a JavaScript
application write javascript HTML and
CSS all put on there we can put a
cross-platform it's loading items from
outside down in right this is a
potential security concern but if we
don't understand how this stuff works we
can help go in and attack it right so we
have to do that side the way I say going
about this is no biltmore stop you know
if you're actually interested in
application development just like if
you're interested in network you know
you're gonna go out you're going to
build networks right you're going to set
them up you're gonna feel cool domains
you can do all this stuff from build
some apps you know understand what
developers go through as their building
applications because it'll help you out
a lot i just recently did a presentation
back in jacksonville code on the beach
i did a presentation for developers I
mean that's a developer conference and
talking to them about but this is how i
look at applications because we always
say write developers look at
applications differently than we look at
application are going to say this is how
i look at application and up the
applications i looked at over the years
here's the things that I see this you
see that right so you come in and you
see a nice little ecommerce site where i
can add items to my cards right I see
the ability to put negative values in
there and take money from you and put in
my cal right or I see ways to on your
simple contact us form because you
decided to put the to address in the
form and a hidden field
IC away where I use as a span mailing
system but you're seeing it this when we
start talking to about that they start
to understand it you know we do a lot of
talking about developers don't know what
they're doing with security and these
apps are crap and all that but if you
really look at the apps aren't junk
right there not just falling apart
they're working they're getting what
they expected to have it done
are they missing a security said yes
right and so that's what we're here to
help with help get that across to
everybody that there is a security peace
what we're trying to do how can we help
do that and so as we start to understand
it i think we understand it more in the
network time because a lot of us come
from a network background so you under
the that's just part of what you did
so you already understand that we're
going to try to understand network
concepts and all that but going in and
understanding how apps are built within
an enterprise and going through you know
whether doing continuous integration you
know how it goes through QA I mean
there's this whole process we got DevOps
we get the exact opposite respective ops
or I don't know what the colonies did I
don't know i have often that security at
the beginning because it's fairly new
but we've got all these things but we
don't understand the processes so when
we say oh you've got cross-site
scripting I don't know why that's not
fixed today but you don't know their
process for getting that from
development up into production and some
companies it could be a nightmare right
mean it could be an extra a really long
process to try to push a patch into
production
so that's why it's not happening so
quickly but we start to understand that
we start to understand how the tools
work that they develop with but we know
that we're packing people that it's a
dotnet application so they use visual
studio as their ide you know we start
making assumptions about how do they
work
what are you doing what is their ID
provide them what is their language
provides that I come from a dotnet
background I've been doing . net since
the beta release in $MONTH 2001 so when
I look at an aspx app I mean anything
that asp.net we talk about web forms we
talk about MVC right I understand what
they're doing to build that I understand
what it builds out-of-the-box I
understand what they have to do on top
of it and so when I go attack an
application and I know where I want to
look because the typical fit pitfalls of
we're gonna miss that just like most
common network people when they come in
they know the pit bal they know you got
corners over here because as a network
guy i cut corners over there you know
and so as you start to understand this
you start to be quicker and more
efficient at doing that attending
developer specific conferences anybody
any development work around here one RBI
means a couple I mean not common right I
don't want to put the name out there
because the project beat up in the
parking lot the guy comes developer you
don't see a lot and vice versa you go to
developer conferences you don't see a
lot of security people there so you know
the more we can get out now we're
starting to see more like job of one and
and some of those you know big
conferences are some some people start
actually getting pushing out right but
you're not seeing a lot of security
people going out the whole hua ab sec or
app conferences right and you see some
but it's not like we normally see
so if we start getting out attending
some of those and start talking with
people and saying hey I'm not here to
say your baby's ugly
good luck right it's not we could work
with you I don't know everything right
it's okay proud to say that but at the
same time we won't let them know we're
here to help not to be an adversary i'm
going to local meetup actually just
started recently doing this we're going
to like you know go to meetup.com or
whatever it
find local groups that part 2 i'm more
like the local dev conference i went to
i made a difference you know going in
and talking about security because as
you talk to developers about security
you'll actually find their interests
know about it they want to know they
want to write security because they want
to write the best app just like we take
pride in our work they take pride in
there so they want to do this but again
we separate ourselves so we're over here
talking they're over here talking I i
gave the concept a few years ago you
know but it's like high school dance and
nobody wants to cross into the middle
and actually start talking to each other
and we find that once we start doing
that when we can get it across but we do
in a positive way of doing things like
webinar I'm getting out there watching
some devil webinars you know what is it
keeping up with what they're doing
I've never even heard of electron until
I went to that conference and I watched
through and open this is cool and the
first thing I thought up with and it's
got to be some cool way to hack this
there's gotta be something going on
right one of the security deal with
electron around it and lo and behold if
you actually go out to the electron
website he goes to a search for google
work electron you have to the website
they actually have a link for security
and they've got a small little lift that
sense you shouldn't do that you
shouldn't do this shouldn't give you do
this you're on your own right we're
actually starting to see them put some
stuff out there
the question is how do we get more that
Ruby does it go out and look at ruby on
rails they have a guide out there that
talks about security for their systems
but we're still not doing a very good
job getting that information out
different names actually see it but even
so it's still just important for us how
many people that have tested Ruby app
from an applique made you a second here
and hopefully something to do you go out
and test this right and then I i come
from a company that we tested everything
I didn't matter what it was somebody
want a pen test you test it
ah but you're gonna go out and test a
ruby side you got look these guys that
part of your information gathering to
say let me go see what's common about
Ruby or you just go in there fire every
verb roxy is just hard hammer away at
the side you're going on this and that's
common stuff and how to go
it actually makes a difference if we
start understanding what
languages are using with frameworks
they're using and if we start building
into that now we get inside we can
actually give them a better result
because now I'm saying I understand what
you're going to be like me going out
there and saying look at the linux box
on a windows box but i only know one of
them and I'm not gonna look up the other
so i'll just run by same scams and all
around the same stop and we'll get the
same results and i missed the whole
bunch of stuff clinic or differently the
windows right and that's what we're
looking at here so as we start to
understand what development doing we
start to get better at how we're testing
and not only better we get faster right
you build up the templates we get much
more efficient
I'm gonna stop i can find very quickly
going through an application compared to
people that arms as good at development
or understanding the background of it
I mean it's crazy the difference you can
see some time it was interesting i was
at a company watching and another guy
doing network penthouse guy was amazing
i mean this guy had command line he knew
what he was running and i'll tell you if
i'm doing a network pen test because I
focus mostly on app you know i'm looking
up commands it but I do with this yeah
ok you know we can get through with
bumblefoot I mean that he's pounding out
commands like it's nobody's business and
you know I'm like that's awesome that's
exactly how I feel when I do web stuff
you know I know exactly what I'm doing
I'm not doing as much searching right
because that's my knowledge of eight but
then you go look at the same person that
goes into the webcast and you look at
the results you're like obviously this
doesn't work out because he has a lot of
stuff that went up right and so as we
start to learn more about it we get
better than applying these things
the other thing we need to look at is
scoping you know we talked about scope
all the time I know red team and
penetration testers you know we want to
say we're just like the attacker we
don't want any rules want to build
whatever we can I want to build test
whenever I can I want to build a dude
boss I want to do anything I can to get
into the site but as we know this is not
the reality right we don't get to do
that I've got an engagement coming up
they told me get tested night whatever
i'll test it i don't care
doesn't really matter to me it opens up
my day but it doesn't matter i told him
look my testing you're not going to feel
like I don't run a lot of automated
canna so i'm not going to bring down my
very manual testing but I'm not gonna
argue about you want to tonight
purple doin alright but understanding
more than understanding what's in scope
what applications are you testing what
applications that they have how many
times have you gone and everybody got
mobile app now that you know relate to
their web apps are you testing them both
at the same time I find most places
they'll do a mobile application pen tap
and then they'll do a web application
and then I do anything the ipad right
but they do with different times but
I've seen it i use work i mean like I'm
willing to admit the failures i have as
a developer and they were planning
especially when it comes to security the
head road some very insecure at that we
didn't know that at the time just a
disclaimer i didn't know what they were
insecure i actually wrote a nap it's
probably still live today where the
price and the cart is a hidden field and
you can change it if you'd like and get
the item for that price
so just didn't I don't run that fight
still so I don't have any obligation to
fix it
look at me like that alright but it's
out there but I work for another company
where we have webforms winforms mobile
device right we had a whole bunch of
stuff around it and what we found was
the web guy did a great job of input
validation you couldn't get cross-site
scripting past him productive right me
he locked it down a perfect didn't show
up when encoding we learned that real
quick because the mobile guys did not
care about what they took him they
didn't care about cross-site scripting
input because it wasn't a problem for
that you know this is back on the wind
ze days so there was no web browsing
through it it was a windy form can cross
that script app so it was nothing to put
malicious code into the mobile app and
cause cross-site scripting in the web
app but how many times like I said that
we actually go tasking like yeah we'll
do a mobile test this week will do the
website this week what we have done
those at different times
I'm not gonna see that not going to see
the correlation because I'm not going
back into the website that fit or I'm
not doing something in the website to
see if the mobile site there
I'm not testing the API that everything
is hitting to see how it worked right so
this becomes a concern
so we have to try to push it this is an
education part on our side that we go on
the clients and they say we want that
pent-up ok but tell us the component of
your half when you actually have because
we want to test this all at once I don't
want to do a separate here's the reason
why and often they don't know whether
the biggest don't think about it that
way so as we start thinking about that
then we start to understand
oh yeah we should really test these at
Sam and i'll fight with people you test
these at think you're really losing out
of value if we don't test these at the
same time what is our timeline for
testing center will talk about and being
descriptive i'm in that because we
really want to think about how long do
we test for that's a concern of time to
test for like a week
couple days maybe and then our reports
often times are not descriptive both
those we'll talk a little bit more about
something I often get asked should we
have stores Kodar pentest you see a lot
of people out there now talking about
source code assisted pen testing and I
seen that i'm seeing some people talk
about on twitter another few companies
that really pushed for it as a matter of
fact we'll go far enough that if they
find stuff they let you create patches
and give them to you
I don't know about that look a little
over-the-top and little risky but should
you have it to me that the question it's
kind of difficult to answer because i
don't think a lot of people can actually
look at the source code understand it
enough to be able to make it useful
right and so we want to make sure that
our cats are useful so if you're doing
app testing if you're not a developer
use a nap tester looking at source
that's gonna help but maybe you don't
pick up some simple stuff but it can
also be a sink of your time because I
calm and i'm really not find anything on
the web
we're going to look at the source if i
can find something to trying to scrape
through and find stop and maybe you
don't understand how to pray more to
work out if you can even get your hands
on the source code a lot of places won't
share it but it could take you away
right we always talk about the
methodology for pen testing and you know
that kind of five-minute five try rule
I don't want to get caught over here and
then miss testing the whole site same
thing if you actually have source code
brought into it is what am I going to
dance because inevitably if I got source
code
hopefully you're thinking and let me go
look at the log in as the other store in
the passwords because i can't tell them
outside you let me go see how they're
doing this if it's easy ways to bypass
anyone finding out that you didn't spend
enough time naturally testing the
application did this kind of have sided
code review you know it's always
interesting to me I wrote up some
recruiters you always say hey we need
abstract people and I want a knapsack
person that can do
pentesting and secure code review and
you know all these bangs and I'm like
does your kind of two different things
and a lot of us a really good pentesting
secure code reviews hard it's not easy i
did your code review for a company for a
year
we're always did and there's a lot you
have to tell even today
still I'll do code review but only for
dotnet because I know . that I don't
know java i can write a little tough job
but I don't know all the ins and outs I
know the ins and outs . bet that if i
change this configuration file it will
affect this over here this way right so
we talk about it i look at those and I'm
like so what you're really saying is you
want somebody to run the static analysis
tool and and give us a report but they
don't want to come out actually say that
but we got to be cautious
yes sir . at stake
no I have not I'll check that out
I so if you're going to do the source
code stuff just make sure that you're
aware there's some pitfalls around that
you don't want to get caught in to
increase timeline
this is something to talk about a lot
you know I got kind of fed up with the
whole week testing time frame you know
I'm trying to slam through it only got a
week to do stop you know i miss out on
so much think about how much you learn
in 30 days or think about how much you
learned in 60 day so a lot of what I do
now is I push for people and say hey
look you know what left onto a week
tablets your 30-day town and i'm not
saying i'm testing for eight hours a day
/ 30 day
what I'm saying is we're going to test
over 30 days and that gives us a lot of
flexibility in what we're doing
it helps build our collaboration about
what we're doing right and it helps
improve that knowledge transfer I've got
one client that when we test will do a
30 day tasks
every week we get onto our call a
webinar or a gotomeeting or whatever
right and will actually sit there and go
through
hey here's what we're currently seeing
they actually helped a little bit too
they work with me on it but we go
through what are we seeing and we
actually had where he had identified
something because we have two more
testing mobile but he was on the side
but he found the mobile he's had a code
in it that was important to us and so
he's like a check this out
and so we look at it Trina we're going
back and forth and he's a guy can do
this with this code but i'm not really
sure where to go and have a great idea
how we try this and we start working
through it and probably 30 minutes in we
were able to go from a self registered
user to a full admin user on that web
account based on the information found
right it was through i'm walking through
and it was great because you know we're
looking at a lot of stuff he found
something we get to go through it but
he's also learning as well but he seemed
different ways we look at it as he
wouldn't have put together over here to
over there right and so as we look
through it we talk about it right we
worked together so the collaboration is
great there's lots of ways we could do
it right mean one allows us to do more
but we can use things like black
anybody's black seems like it's coming
pretty popular now depending on your
fear of security levels and all that
stuff you know how much you want to put
through slack or something that's up to
you and your client but you slack to
stay in touch using something like skype
or other microsoft technologies i put
microsoft on there for things like
onedrive and I share a lot of documents
through office 365 a look at the report
as we're building it you go in and see
see what we're doing now if there's
things you have concerns about we can
address them right away you know but it
allows us to be interactive using things
that go to meeting or webex some of
those things we get on together and talk
about things and these things really
help kind of build that bond that I'm
not
here test real i'm here to work with you
and help you get through this
transparency you know getting more out
there
one of the things I was always
frustrated with when I was on the
receiving end of reports don't know
really what you're doing yes I see what
you found and I see some screenshots
that you burp to do it or if the network
test I see screenshots that use this
tool but you're not really giving me a
whole lot of detail about what are you
really doing to get this stuff so
helping them understand more of hey I
use this and this is the reason why i
use this tool right share ideas that
failed
hey you know when i tried this it didn't
work it's okay to not get something to
work let me know the stuff you're trying
because the more than we tell them about
how we tasked the more they start to
understand how they can look at their
house internally or how they can share
that with the developers or how our
thought process works that they can
share that out with the developers and
people start understanding a business
how they're looking at your house
these are the things they're trying and
a great job you didn't fall for this one
but you fell for this right and then
understanding why is it that you felt
for one and not the other is because
your framework protects against that
automatically write a lot of these view
engines now do a great job across
scripting lot of them you know they have
a lot of stuff is great for protecting
its sequel injection but that doesn't
mean developers to that on purpose that
was just luck of the draw right let me
know it like that you know hey look is
this is what we're saving you here
keep in mind that book working you know
understanding your frameworks to do that
are in creating these learning
opportunities and why did you use that
tool
I mean this is again is a relationship
you're forming it shouldn't just be a
black box test that we bring it through
here i mentioned the flexibility
how many times have you had when you got
to the site and they're like all right
we're going to start on monday and you
don't start till wednesday because they
didn't have credentials or the site
wasn't up there was some problem there
was a family emergency or what
whatever it may be but what happens when
you don't start till wednesday you still
finish on friday rapid
I've got other clients lined up I'm not
waiting I don't get to move you over so
you just now got yourself a three-day
test right and that's not good for
anybody
wow I guess it's good for our pocket
right but it's really not good for
anybody so extending that out saying hey
look you know what let's put more time
behind this
let's build this up with have some
flexibility that something happened i
lock out my credentials I typically
don't do help block out that stuff until
the end but not everybody works the same
lock out your credentials
how long's that take them to get that
you don't even care you know it's gonna
take a couple hours to unlock my upline
we got 30 days we got think that
whatever we got time
you don't have the diagrams ready on the
first day
no worry I've got questions about how
the site working because I found
something and maybe I want a piece of
source code you know that i do that
laughter hey can you send me the source
code for this because it seemed to be
acting weird
it takes you two days to get it to me
network network right I'm not eating in
and think you have to stop every time I
say something
stop what you're doing and go visit to
help us all out any type of emergency
changes they're pushing waiting on the
document and they all create kind of a
whole they can't get out of improving
our knowledge transfer this is something
where we start doing some videos and i
know some other companies that do videos
as well that when you find a good
exploit you video it so that example I
talked about where we went from the
mobile app to full admin on the web we
did video for that it was a four-minute
video we also did a story about the
story also click all right of a story
alright of them are you able to record a
video and it will make sure that people
understand the true cause behind this
and what it does is it showed that
impact right when i did the video that
showed grabbing that value and go into
full admin self registering account all
within four minutes in a video real time
I made a huge impact from what they look
at that versus be writing it up as a
story which i did I didn't get any grace
for that right my god whatever great
story to read all that anyway they
watched the video I watched a lot right
and they understood it and they said I'd
now I see it really only take this
much effort to go from here to here
we're going to fix this ASAP to give
that real-time feel to it because
otherwise i can read the stories like oh
yeah sure you know you grab that you did
but it probably took you hours to do
that piece and then you have to go do
that as a no
really these five steps and they happen
like that that's getting people to
understand that that's how really works
that we can get through this pretty
quickly online meetings like i said i
like to use them just to check in go
over what we're seeing because it helps
me learn about the application or too
many people when they do a nap test or
any type of test like that right sit
down and actually do a walk through the
application with the company so they can
tell you this is how it works right with
it anyway I'll get interesting . i'll
let you know right so you can do some of
these meetings you can build that up a
little bit one I actually find that as i
do these meetings are out have my report
becomes more of a deliverable then it
does the really the gold of the whole
thing write my report is more of a
document what we've already talked about
you already know about it there's
chances you could have fixed it already
if you wanted to before we even finished
testing
I'm kidding i like the 30 day test
myself but there are other companies
that are pushing for longer testing .
right you can still do multiple tasks
and how many ppl double-booked anyway
right this way I don't feel so bad about
it i actually don't like double booked
but with a 30 day because it is a
spread-out thing I blood to do 32 time
if we have to getting our reporting this
kind of where that whole bench thing
came up right are reporting works it
gets it out there but how many times you
think of going in to test a network you
tested application this year and you
know next year when you go back it's
going to be the same findings same stop
right nothing really happened with it
because what we do we go out with
findings in their we put an executive
summary
here's what we found its great record it
might make it to the dev team it might
make it to this is admin team it might
make it in a different form we don't
know why but I mean I get frustrated
when i go back and see the same
vulnerability if they're high-low
vulnerability whatever their well that
but the high ones make a difference
so getting better reporting out of it I
know nobody like the reporting phase .
the second part of pen testing but this
is where we give a lot of information
over so enhancing our methodology and
talk about ok instances vs findings
something that I find a lot of people
don't understand how many times does
matter what it is right i mean even
network like I said a lot of stuff
transpose it back and forth i give you a
report and I say you've got cross-site
scripting right that's a finding across
the cooking
well then I break it down to give you a
few instances here's some examples of
process gripping your site and so what
do they do they get the report to go
back to fix the instances but they
didn't really understand why they had
cross-site scripting right they went in
and fix those ones that you pointed out
and what do we do we come back and say
oh you pick some cross-site scripting is
gone man i'll find more next year
because we didn't actually identify the
rooftop
but if we start helping them identify
this and say and instead of just saying
hey this is rampant across the whole
site
hey you've got cross-site scripting and
you know i'm noticing a common thing
right using labels in your application
and you're not including those out go
out and look for those things right and
then updating our findings and getting
those squared away something I was here
they can't reproduce laws right that's a
common concern and it's frustrating
I have clients that tell me the reason
I'm calling is because their last
company they can't reproduce cloth
I'm so where the reproducibility i say
i'm a consumable steps make a detailed
don't assume they know what you're doing
it's very difficult like me talking to
my wife had no idea what that i'm
talking about makes perfect sense to me
doesn't work well as far as the details
right instead of being generic well okay
here's cross-site scripting and you
could steal cookies and you could do
this and here's a general abstract about
cross-site scripting that's great and
all but what if we actually start
getting into it was a halo coming to
talk about the details right I've got
cross-site scripting and your session
cookie doesn't have HTTP only enable and
so now my narrative cross-site scripting
and I can steal your session ID
and send it off to my server and login
as your user it kind of goes back to
that adversarial mapping p for things
like it's not just the cross-site
scripting I've heard your box the show
it works it's just a proof of concept
that so i can steal your session cookie
and this is why it really bad this is
why you're fixing this not just because
I come across because to be honest with
you if you tell somebody that process
available
it's a flaw but if i can show you this
is how i would use cross-site scripting
now it starts to make sense
good thing i like to talk about is
conversation starters so instead of just
doing our general recommendations and
this is kind of in addition to
recommendations
this is a way for us to say you know
what security rarely involved during the
design phase of our application we
always say we want to do it we hire apps
that people so they get into the fplc
know they live in security connectivity
right but here's our chances hey here's
hoping to get back involved with it here
is that we get the design discussion
going and look back and maybe do threat
modeling what if you want to call it
that you're doing to do this but allows
us to circle back around so I had this
example this was one of my clients that
they had using harvesting and they have
a status code that come back now the
error message was the same there's no
issue with the error message but they
have the status could come back and that
was a problem so i could easily say hey
we've got using harvesting it so
typically what we'll do is we'll say hey
don't return you know return a generic
error message that simple and even in
this case we could get rid of sadness
but is that really good recommendation
you don't even know how that application
work I don't know what that buses or
they probably don't know what's right
but I can't just say don't do this as a
poor way to do it and he's end up they
turn into like more coaching just it's
kind of fun actually but what if you
actually go in there and say hey I
recommend that you review the sign of
your login functionality and talk with
the developers of what are you trying to
do here what the status code for how do
you use that pepco do you need the
static scope if you don't need the
status code can we get rid of it if you
do need the status code what are the
other mitigations we can look at
to help us reduce the username
harvesting floor we have but we're
coming out as a positive hey I want to
work with you
we found that there's a blah let's talk
about it but let's not just talk about
the flaw
let's look at the log in right you find
an issue with forgot password
let's look at your forgot password let's
talk about what you're doing here and
say here's how we look at this right now
you're doing your tact reason your trade
model with them and now has a pen tester
of your external you're not actually
doing it right but you're pushing the
idea and the notion of doing it into the
reports and say hey this is what you
guys should be doing and then now that's
getting spread out through management of
their whoever sees that report now in
their base
hey I should be thinking about that
let's not just look at the cross-site
scripting incidents and go put encoding
out there let's think about why we have
cross-site scripting why do we have been
harvested let's talk about these feature
let's see if there's any other things
that maybe didn't come up in the report
I mean there might be other login issues
that they have made it wouldn't find but
when you go and actually hey let's start
talking about your thing are you coming
out and saying I'm here to help
I'm not here to tell you how you get
laws in your app and I'll see you later
let me know when you figure those out
that that's not going to work as we go
forward so you know really kind of wrap
things up you know it's more than
testing we've got to be more than
testing
I mean if we actually want to make
changes security we actually have to
think about how can we do that we have
to make it happen
we talked about we want better secure
apps a lot better secure network who
stopped to a default password the
hard-coded password and all these
different things we want this change but
what I'm seeing as our reports that
we're currently doing the way we're
going about it doesn't do it I say the
same thing among how we say developers
need training you know home and
developers think they need more training
but the people that are doing the
training around the red teamers don't
know anything about development but we
know about attacking and we teach them
this how you attack and then generically
wow this is how you could hypothetically
protect against them
that's not working right so if we want
to actually get changed out there how
can we do it we can start by looking at
how we do our fantastic agents and say
look we're here to help were here to
fight through the we want to get you
moving and these are some ways that I
think we can take to do that and as I
said it worked really well with the
clients that I've had they really like
the concept that we're putting here
getting more involved if you're
concerned about the idea that well
pentesting should be kind of a nobody
knows about it right in network it makes
more sense i don't want to sock to know
because i want to see if they pick this
stuff up but at the same time we do kind
of want them to work with us because hey
i just sent this stuff did you see it
you know if there's a fine line there
but keep in mind when we talk about
applications here the developers not
watching that
so it's okay to help development and say
hey look we want to involve with this
want to make you aware they want to
learn they want to do it they like
figuring stuff out like we do so if we
can identify who the right people to get
involved we can actually maybe start
getting more understanding out there and
hopefully we'll start getting more
security and we won't start seeing the
same low-hanging nonsense stop that
we're seeing every day so that's it for
me
I so the question is you have done stuff
with fusion team we're going to
dedicated people from certain areas i
haven't done a lot with that but that's
what I'm trying to get the goal here is
to identify the right resources are
going to make a difference if we do the
testing
yeah certain any other questions yet so
the question is you know do for app
reviews or desktop indicator on
authenticated I test authenticated I
know there's a question about that right
you know well you know it's beer true
attacker quite honestly a lot of two
attackers have accounts most of these
accounts are open but you're missing out
on so much you don't have a count if I
unauthenticated most likely I'm gonna
spend the time trying to just pack your
login screen and that's a waste of money
most of applause that was here not the
login alright the flaws that we're
seeing are these logic blog where I can
go and manipulate hidden field or you
know you're missing authorization that
I'm a regular user and I can access
admin features that type of stuff and
without authenticated testing you're not
going to get that type of testing you
know so I I like authenticated I won't
do not authenticated testing that it
seems that way yeah so I don't fix my
keep that separate because i don't want
it to be a conflict so the question you
know did I ever have anybody that asks
me to fix the flaws that i find i try to
stay out of that space i will certainly
I yeah I mean people will ask you know
you seen some companies will start doing
it but a lot of people they want to stay
separate right I'm on this side because
if i start centers and hey look I charge
you to help fix these well then I'm
gonna start a whole bunch of with it
yeah right you know I'm indeed it's a
sticky situation to get into but I've
got no problem working with them and
saying this is what will work i had a
cross-site scripting father came through
that was not going through angular for
template injection you know we're using
square brackets instead of your typical
less than greater than and I actually
did a write-up saying this is exactly
what the problem is you need to remove
the bracket right i mean it was very
clear what they should do but I'm not
getting into your cut like that's a
whole different insurance issue that I
don't want with your part up but i have
no problem you know i mean i will share
my opinions I'm not afraid to say
something in the fact that what you said
I should do this yeah i mean i said you
should do it but I'm not responsible at
the crack tip that so anything up now
perfect but I think everybody for coming
early in the morning for notes it
releases later than usual
ten o'clock not too bad