alright cool i think it's about noon
this is anti forensics AF if you're here
for a different talk or something cooler
than anti-french 6af you can go to one
of the other color talks or stay here
choose-your-own-adventure that's cool
my name isn't a TI the rapper in dual
core I've done a number of anti
forensics talks here at Derby condom
very happy to be back
I this is just like a bunch of truly
stuff like I get on the computer and I'm
like what happens if I do this so um so
first we're going to talk about some
memory forensic stuff and basically from
the point of being a malware author or
like an attacker on a system and you've
got your malware running you want to
maintain on the system without being
acquired or analyzed it so to do that
we're gonna use some self-modifying code
and we'll look at an example with the
windows and linux and then i will talk
about some android stuff
Oh which reminds me I might need my
android phone I should have kept that um
and then I got some really cool stuff
we're gonna play CTF CTF with the SD
cards and it's super fun it's like a
really cool trick I found that I don't
think many people have seen oh thank you
shall take you to make noise for you to
please
alright cool so I'm just lots of fun
random stuff so this is my like Who am I
page or whatever I don't do forensics
for a living i'm on a red team i come
from a reverse engineering and malware
background i love to just mess around
and see what happens so it's a troll
part I've had some really interesting
troll experiences with some three-letter
agencies like the FBI and most recently
the NSA if you want to talk to me about
that some other time I'd be happy to
talk about it i'm not an expert at all i
like I said just mess around so your
mileage may vary and pretty much like
all the cool things I've learned to do
with computers are illegal
so do illegal things
ok so are our focus on the memory
friends excited things is that we are an
operator or an attacker on a victim
system we've got our own malware that
we've built so we've invested a lot of
time in our own toolchain customizing
making stuff that's never been seen
before we are potentially apt and we
want to persist in for detection so we
don't want him out where to get picked
up
we don't want to get acquired we don't
want it to get analized so we're going
to work against that and so we all know
like last 10 years or so like the
hottest has been memory forensics write
like this basic forensics is dead so
we're gonna leverage that to our
advantage
alright we're going to take advantage of
the fact that we can do some cool things
in memory on that help us as an attacker
so in the example of malware on disk you
have a bunch of sections in your
executable file and to get from disk
into memory you need all those sections
all the analysis tools also need those
sections but once we're in memory we may
not necessarily need them so we're gonna
we're gonna take advantage of that so
it's pretty cool like by manipulating
our executables in memory we can totally
troll the analysis tools and have a good
time
wha so I this is a program that i made
called the keys are like right next to
each other now it's taken from vascular
quote and actually this is pretty much i
think the last demo that i left off
within my last Derby con talk but I ran
it under XP is a few years ago so i was
just curious to see like does this work
in windows 10 so in this case we're
going to use recall which is a free
framework from google for doing memory
forensics pretty dope if you haven't
checked it out a plus plus plus would
recommend would clone get repository so
let's see we've got on there's our
malware is just running just doing evil
stuff as it does now
oh ok
in a separate tab let's let's run recall
or less
sorry please win p.m. first and this is
gonna do our acquisition of ram and now
this this takes a while so I thought I'd
play video for you guys
while we wait I found this series
recently called you suck at cooking and
it's kinda cool
it's almost like the like howtobasic
videos but like put some dry humor so
without further further ado this is how
to cook corn on the cob chucking it's a
fancy word for peeling and how you suck
as a personal choice the traditional
method is to grab the husk and shutdown
word repeat this motion until the call
this husk free you can also up check it
these methods are hard work and you end
up checking yourself silly so consider
trying the Gulf shock cord or you can
try playing Chuck Benton or you can use
a comprehensive spinning wheel dual
momentum shock system where you can back
a check it you can throw it against a
rock groups don't throw it against a
rock or if you're quick enough you could
do the Falcon Chuck
the Shopatron six is new technology
that's based on particle theory and
magic you just slide it through there
and just make sure to wash the particles
off of your core and after his particles
aren't good for you and if you don't
like corn on the cob you can take a
hammer and get corn off the cob where
you can buy this corn had been
developing with Monsanto it's a complex
corn in the way we make it is through
genetic engineering
it's perfectly healthy and safe we're
pretty sure where you can start scoring
sausage wasn't making it looks and
tastes like real turkey sausage and the
way we make that is by having a turkey
for cob of corn to cook for a lot of
people think you just feel the polit
water boil the water throw in the corn
add some salt let it cook for a few
minutes and then it's done in those
people are correct . buttered corn is
also a personal rookies will use a knife
which is a sloppy way to go about it and
it leaves your corn tasting like butter
and metal this is the classic way just
gently roll your copy the butter until
it's coded more advanced way is to take
a slab of butter and caramel corn hole
and decide
slide your comment to the cornhole and
twist it while moving in
no to your car is completely coated with
butter if your corn hole isn't big
enough
gently twist it with perseverance until
it slides through easily you can also
stick butter on some tongs take those to
a broom handle and butter your corn from
a distance
this is a great technique if you suffer
from a strong fear of corn butter corn
can be slippery so be sure to attach a
handle like this 2.71 a Phillips
screwdriver i just made up the 2.71 a
pursed but yeah that's corn on the cob
and it's more delicious and corn on the
log or corn in the bog or corn on the
saw for corn on the dog or corn in the
fog or corn on the job or corn in the
clog or corn on Bob for corn on the slob
which is the same thing get your shit
together but seriously and it's
obviously best eaten as corn on the cob
and if you're sick a corn consider all
right so that's you suck at cooking
oh good in our acquisitions . in re
alright so let's run recall and let's
pass it is our acquisition file . AFF
for it's like its own format but recall
understands it so it's good
basically what you get is this ipython
notebook workspace right it's pretty
dope like I don't have to anybody's
ipython but it totally changed my life
before it was just me python so what
we're going to do is use a product .
module inside of recall and like if
you've ever used volatility for memory
forensics to extract a process you need
to find them the pit first right
in this case we can just say oh yeah the
process looks something like this
the keys and then we can just specify
the dump directory and all of this is
like to have completed just like ipython
stuff is which is super nice
alright
looks like our directory dumped all
right hope or no did not didn't like
that maybe i should are using tab
completion
I'll come on out totally right did
oh I forgot a comma Shh your shit
together and katie alright cool so I was
doing that let's let's look at what the
original program looks like alright so
hey I'm i found something weird on this
on the system like what you know what's
echo 22 and see what's up
so you know what
so this is you know
normal normal idea pro load the program
in looks legit right you get a cool call
function graph function names are all
all good everything good
alright cool so now let's take a look at
our dumped executable so here's our
dumped executable doesn't doesn't really
like recognize it this let's just go
with the default see what happens at
that doesn't look right
notice we've got like a lot fewer sub
functions on the side these instructions
don't look right there like 16 bit
strange right if you're in our analyst
and this is what you get to to work with
is your starting point you're gonna be
like WTF mate
like what is this i and III don't know
about you guys I don't know any i
personally don't know any forensics
examiner's that no idea well enough to
go through and start marking things code
and put the time in but if we go back to
our original
tab are now we're still running right so
we're so doing evil stuff so we thought
analysis and that's you know it's pretty
cool so yay attackers win and uh let's
let's take a look at the source because
pretty easy so uh this is very like
basic proof-of-concept we get a handle
to the process make sure that we're
dealing with the windows executable here
so here's our checks for 45 AMS . stub
and then 15 all the P header part
process the the sections means virtual
protect to add write permissions on to
the the header of the executable file in
memory and we're going to call Artie l0
memory this is like the thing that does
the special sauce and what it does is it
just writes zeros into the header in
memory so that makes it so that when you
grab the executable out you just get
like no information about what your
rights are we restored the page
permissions with virtual protect and
then here we just loop for
proof-of-concept demo purposes any
questions at all about the keys are like
right next to each other
yes in the back I
I about the question is about volatility
plugins and there is a practical plugin
in volatility when I did it in XP it
also failed and so I recall with the new
hotness and so I just built the demo for
recall in this particular case I haven't
tested it for the if like against New
volatility in windows so it it might
have better success i just tested
against recalls like a google smart pros
like should probably work and then it
didn't sound like a good job me
mhm yeah when I did in in windows in my
last demo like an XP it i won against
volatility and will actually do a demo
against volatility and linux and spoiler
alert when again so yeah so again this
is a we don't need the PE header after
we've loaded we can do whatever we want
if you really want to have some fun try
writing weird values into the PE header
and then loading your dumped executable
into analysis tools you might get some
crashes with some interesting values and
some registers just if you're into that
kind of stuff so pretty neat we win in
this is worked all the way from Windows
XP up into windows 10 for completeness
this is these are the commands that I
that Iran if anybody wants to like take
a picture of the screen but it's pretty
straightforward it's just when p.m. to
acquire the ram and then recall against
the acquisition and then run the
practice module inside of recall
alright so let's write in linux and will
go against volatility and we'll use line
for the acquisition which is an
open-source Colonel Colonel driver
password is my log luggage combination
alright so here's our inexperience so we
found RL fetter this is just debugging
output you could do whatever you want
here so now we're doing evil stuff as we
do
alright so cool
let's go yeah let's get line first
cool we have a build if you want to
build line for your kernel version you
just run make should build straightaway
so I we need to load my lime into memory
so we can do an acquisition and there's
a couple argument specifies so first you
tell it where your path is to store the
acquisition so let's just tell it like a
little outline and under temp and then
you can specify format i think the
options are like climbin draw the
volatility understands the line format
so we'll just do that
5500 from the password is getting ok
cool so we should have our our Ram
acquisition cool and again now we're
still running so now we're should be in
there somewhere we can grab it
so let's see
I'm not gonna go in-depth on showing
slides another there's a caveat with
volatility on linux it doesn't come with
a profile for your build of linux so you
have to build your own profile for any
system that you're going to be doing
memory analysis on a pretty
straightforward process and will cover
it in the slides rather than walking
through here in the demo you just get to
the cool stuff so you can test it if you
got it by doing something like this
use the cash inflow inflow flags and
then just grab for linux and then I'll
tell you gotta show your profile once
you've installed it
alright so let's let's get our malware
program because we know that attackers
are on the system we have to specifier
profile volatility so it knows how to do
the thing and first let's like i said
earlier we have to get the process
listening or the the pit for your target
process that you want to dump so here's
our pick of 22 21 when we use the
product module and specifier pit 21 then
ignore the storm stuff it's just I don't
have those modules installed
ok cool looks like we gotta dump all
right blue team is winning
here we go text dump it
oh we didn't get anything or how big is
that the process that we don't all its 0
bytes want long
empty a and are now we're still doing
evil stuff
good job red team whoo
so basically the same same setup going
on here we basically find our header in
memory the way i do this is really bad
and I should feel bad but it's easy and
it works so i'm just using proc self
maps and you might be on a system that
you don't have access to proc
potentially so don't rely on this but
i'm lazy so using a scan up to find the
entry for my header and uh here we use
and protected whereas in windows we use
virtual protect we set our page right
permissions so we can modify the header
here we use memset instead of RTL zero
memory and then reset the page
permissions using and protect again and
then here's this are debugging stuff
whereas in real life would be catching
shells and exhaling data and getting
bitcoins cool
alright so it was the next one
oh no sorry
ok now we're good forgot about the goats
for a minute okay so I'm say pretty much
same thing that we walk through here we
don't need the elf hunter just like we
didn't need the PE header so we can zero
it out or if you want to you could
tamper it and add in weird values and
get really interesting
register value sometimes and then uh
this is like the full process i can send
you guys slides if you want tho will
come as a PDF no malware I promise
get-get clone a line from github build
it
insert in smart it so you get it running
in the colonel get volatility install it
and then this is the the profile build
stuff so you'll see d into this like to
linux subdirectory and just run make and
that will produce this module . door
file if your own head on that you should
see . debug info the top let you know
that you've got to build correctly
laughs then once you've got your module
. or file you'll need to package it with
your current system . map and place that
zip in the in the directory under
plugins overlays for for volatility and
then at that point you can check that is
installed correctly with that Python .
Popeye info great linux that showed
earlier and then we just did
PS list and practicum and it didn't save
us in this case but that's that's the
completeness
alright uh so Android South any
questions about either the windows or
linux perience for the people like right
next to each other
cool alright and stuff so my girlfriend
were interested about android stuff of a
little while back and we didn't know
anything about forensics for android so
we're like let's figure it out as well
these are some things that we figured
out so all of this is based on the
premise of using encryption encrypting
your device also to quote the group use
tor you signal i'll know this one shows
up as well I want to eat a pint of jerry
garcia ice cream should i use a bowl or
not used to ru signal and then selling
social security numbers for bitcoins
contact me on my xmpp
I i guess i don't know if i should admit
or not but pretty much the reason that i
made this talk was because i had the
idea to use screaming goats for the
slide transitions and I was like what
can I put around that
alright so let's talk about forensics
real quick i'm gonna try to push through
this part pretty quickly and I can talk
more in depth about it afterwards but
really I want to play the ck up with
y'all for the SD card stuff is really
fun so I first android forensics
ok so I android forensics not the
easiest was like a bunch of stuff you
have to have in place also it's like a
weird setup you have to cross-compile
netcat forearm and then load it onto the
device that you're doing an acquisition
from so like if anybody's done like
hardware forensics like hard drive
forensics you're usually use a write
blocker and you don't write anything
onto the device you're firing from in
this case you're pushing a program that
you built onto a target device that
you're about to acquire from really
weird but it works
I you need the device to be powered on
decrypted unlocked rooted and have USB
debugging enabled us quite a lofty kill
chain right stop any one of those things
in forensics fails and then if you want
to do memory forensics you need loadable
kernel modules loadable kernel modules
enabled which on all of the android
devices that I've seen do not have that
enable so good luck
yeah
I guess I could live on a farm as long
as they have internet in goats
ok so basically what you do in an
android forensic acquisition off of the
nan storage is you push your compiled
netcat binary onto your target device
and you set up a port forward and then
you invoke she'll get root and situate
your neck at binary give it executable
permissions you could do you probably
like 75 if you wanted but yellow then UD
d this is all familiar to us right
DeeDee off of the man storage blocksize
64k no big deal and then type that to
netcat and send it across the u.s. be
using netcat on the receiving end on
your on your laptop you'll have a net
kak client that will connect into the
listener on the phone and then you'll
just grab all that data and store it off
into whatever you want to call your file
in this case i call it image . man then
standard forensics stuff checksum it
make a copy checks on the copy etc
I another weird thing i found with the
android stuff is that you'll find the
answer is exposed by a different
interfaces it just varies per device it
seems so I got these are some that i've
seen it under just look at the product
partitions on the system and that will
tell you like where the storage is so it
might be unheard of blocker mt/year vmmc
and then I was just trying to be clever
with that
c++ line at the end haha so ended up in
the situations where you can't like get
rude and you like a full DVD acquisition
of the nand you can get some other
logical acquisitions right atb pole is
basically like trying to do like a cpu /
onto like your local storage so it will
grab whatever it can for you and in this
case we have like a local directory
called dump that we're going to jump
onto on our target on our laptop
there's also just like dumpsters program
there's 80 backup which you have to add
a pin for you have to have the pin for
the phone or the device in order to use
adb backup which then puts it in the
back history so if you're targeting the
forensic investigator can find the pin
at the phone
there's also dumped state bug report
these things get you like logs of like
various radios that are on the device
there's an open source tool called a
logical osc there's a law enforcement
edition of it as well I don't know the
differences between the two but uh there
the open-source edition is out there if
you want to mess around with it so
tldr it sucks like android forensic
sucks would not do again forever and
it's weird that it violates the
traditional forensic methodologies to be
right like your writing onto the device
you're about to acquire from mine equals
blown and then that kill chain we had
things being like powered on decrypted
all that stuff it's super easy to
disrupt
not even a goat
alright so here's our setup is we have
our android device and we're using full
disk encryption and maybe we're out like
in the rated by law enforcement scenario
maybe we're out freedom fighting is a
great cause that route operating
somewhere you always of course
leave your phone at home when you do
that as as my girlfriend has pointed out
to me multiple times and so let's say
you're out operating and you come home
and there's a bunch of police at my
house like what's going on
you don't want the police to acquire
your device at home and then get
evidence off of it so or like is a
separate situation say maybe you're
deploying a hardware implant on an
operation and if blue team or law
enforcement or somebody else it's not
ever supposed to find the device finds
the hardware implant you don't want them
to get any evidence off of it so and
then this last one I was like shrug is
like you know there are other scenarios
but I can't think of any and then I
looked at it and it looks like cause
throwing a phone to me so you know you
want to encrypt your device if it causes
ever touching it don't go never let him
touch your phone
ok so i'm thinking like we're using
solution are using encryption right the
easiest solution is just power down the
devices but if you think you're in
danger
I mean it's not destructive you're using
your data is still intact in the event
that you're not actually being rated by
law enforcement or something and then
you've got everything your evidence is
all encrypted and then of course lawyer
up you know don't don't ever talk to the
police
um so what can we do to leverage their
to see like whether we're being tempered
with we have all these sensors at at our
disposal right but you hear my device
with another device in my house if it
becomes unpaired turn it off
it's encrypted it's on the cell network
if law enforcement comes in and acquires
a device they're probably gonna put it
in a Faraday bag and that's going to
stop any transmission and receiving
right so if it goes off the cell network
power it off its encrypted gps goes
outside the geofence of my property
power it off all this stuff so we can
use all of these two like leverage or
figure out whether we're being tampered
with and
consequently turn the device off to
protect ourselves so i wrote this app
called duck the police and I'd like to
do what I hope will be the worst hacker
con demo ever for you guys so i have
this android device here running duck
the police and we're going to set it for
movement and we're gonna say . the
police and I'm just gonna sit down and
going to pick it up and the phone is off
its encrypted so . the police and i will
accept Tony nominations for worse hacker
conference demo ever
I'll up with the pony award right next
to my other two it'll be in good company
no I was surprised at the lack of duck
the police means that were on the
internet that one I especially like
because i used to work with a guy who's
really good at lock-picking and he was
like oh yeah i can pick the boots on
cars like no problem and he's like the
police charged like a hundred
twenty-five dollars to take those things
off a charge 75 the fifth bubble tape
one just killed me LOL alright so so
yeah we were using encryption and you
know if we leverage like motion sensors
in the air like accelerometers in the
device it it moves if it's like require
recovered by somebody we don't want to
be recovered by powers down we went good
to go
alright SD cards right so if you've seen
this talk previously you're not allowed
to play CTF sorry
let's do SD cards
I'm just I'm just gonna go back and
forth i love that song
okay so have an SD card here and i'm
going to plug it in and we'll take a
look at it goes
alright the rules of the CTF something
something something can read from this
angle because privacy filter on my
screen I enter your name below so
basically the TLDR is we need to add
your name to this txt file we need to
save it we need to unmount the
filesystem remove the SD card at the SD
card back in and make sure that our name
is still in the file seems pretty easy
ok there's my name right everything cool
and dating yeah alright let's mount it
SD cards out SE car going back in there
oh no my name is not there but the file
is ok what we try to what the filesystem
this place look extended to I'm sorry
immutable bit ok so like your name and
then do not change after plus I on it
okay I like that
ok
ok and eighties there are good little
bit is set right there it is
hi mount it SD cards out as he cars back
in challenge that text
oh no my name is not there alright what
else can we try i like like with a
hardware switch or um ok so that the
premises that the hardware switch is off
i guess i should've specified that is
it's not hardware locked
ok sorry I and I heard something over
here yes I which you mount ok so then
you mounted I'm not charging you mount
so its standard email on linux yes I'm
sorry reading the file
yeah let's do that
so adding in a cool guy going to move it
call it pancakes okay pancakes is there
and he's still there
lets you mount it SD card coming out SD
card going back in
oh shit is challenged our texts and my
name is not there still
what else in the back
oh yeah we did which mounts a mount and
it's a standard mountains including the
distro yeah now
didn't-didn't amber that in the back
I yes and now we can we can double check
them out flags so here's rrw so we write
yes we can
I'll go ahead and spoiler alert for you
because it will take longer than is left
in the talk if that doesn't work either
but good good good is another thing that
I tried
yes
no i'm not using any you have gnarliness
or anything like that
sure we cool like that
lost-and-found is a standard directory
on extended Senate file systems
yes yet let's check partitions so this
is our device MMC block 0
nope just the 1v1 yes in the back
i'm not using an overlay on the file
system but good that's a good one
yes in the back ah yes there is
something on the SD card itself
way to go we work our way down the stack
so
there's a program called SD tool which
will allow us to interface with the
firmware on the SD card and we can
change the right state as to whether or
not we can write to the card so what's
awesome is the way that this gets
displayed to the operating system above
is that everything's fine
no errors no permission issues you know
everything looks good we mountain mount
no worries at all and on but under the
hood
we're preventing the rights and this
this tools open-source I don't know if I
mentioned the slides or not we'll see
but basically all I didn't change to
make file to use playing instead of GCC
but yes but it's but the locks which is
set up to like allow rights
yeah I don't know whoever figured this
out just figured out the interface to
make it make it do the thing
so there's a there's a few commands tata
like i said i'm not an expert I just
mess around on computer history so I so
here with the status we can see that the
right state is on temporarily so we can
update the right protection see so now
now the right protections off
so we'll mount it cards out cars going
back in is that boy
oh shit what up
Peppa so I shot the craig smith from
open garages he's kind of the one that
got me on this track and figuring this
stuff out so is really cool trick and
it's pretty thing that I hadn't seen
anywhere else
sagat alright that was just in case I
wasn't paying attention
whoa
oh that was in case you weren't paying
attention
alright so using this open-source LSD
tool were able to lock and unlock the
device and also check its status as well
again the physical lock is disengaged so
to anybody recovering the SD card you
know they're gonna be like yeah you know
it looks fine
I all the stuff happens in memory so
we're good to go
nothing gets right into the device AKA
no logs no crime which is awesome caveat
so USB hub does not present itself in
the same way all the time is an MMC
device so you might need an actual like
SD card reader that's not connected by
USB bridge i think some of them might
work
also I'd like run into just like hit or
miss with certain cards like this micro
SD card inside of the SD adapter works
fine other micro SD cards i tested did
not work so just ask your friends for
some totally safe microsd cards and then
give them back
so my ideas for like the example
scenarios are like you've got like a
hardware implant right you're using on
an active operation I've actually gone
against the Red Team engagement where
they use an android device implanted in
the facility and we recovered the
android device and rhythm our off of it
and I already the malware and then we
were able to pivot off of that and go
find more infected nodes on the network
but how they used a mechanism like the
android stuff or whatever they could
have potentially killed that or like use
that with the sdcard excuse me and I
would have been able to get any anything
good off the SD card also if you guys
like raspberry PI's right like those
runoff of SD cards so totally do this
year SD card put in your Raspberry Pi I
build a portal of pie or whatever you
want and if it ever gets acquired your
good nothing that we got into the device
and then I if you have if you want to
try like running your attack p.m. for
your attack platform off of an SD card
get off of it like nothing gets written
right on a laptop no hard drive no other
persistent storage just an SD card that
also does not do persistent storage kind
of meat is didn't know what this is nice
that what gentleman animalist