the buttons so hi my name's Steven hilt
and that's and that's fine I don't care
go ahead and go get whatever you want
when it comes in it'll be in the back to
just go get some time I think I know
about ninety percent of the room so it's
fine
today I'm going to talk about some some
legacy things that are still in use and
titled the nineties called they want
their technology back project started
with a healthcare related research
specifically to just discover potential
leaks of PII we looked at unique aspects
that are really talked about when we
looked at new hardware to look at new
protocols to reverse and things like
that and it came fairly prevalent that
was gonna cost a lot and I didn't have a
lot of budget at that point in time and
I knew that doctors still carry these
wonderful things around called pagers
and so that's one thing we looked at as
well as other communication paths is
anybody out here been at the doctor's
office and saw him carrying a pager you
ever wondered why they use them still
and potentially what's being sent on
those for them
yeah you have good good good good so we
started digging into that history of the
pages themselves they're launched around
the nineteen fifties specifically in use
in hospitals in in New York at that time
it was twelve dollars a month for about
25 mile coverage of systems in 1962 Bell
systems presented a radio paging system
at the World's Fair in seattle and
officially in 2001 motor all actually
stopped making new pagers despite that
there are still multiple
protocols in use still today and we're
going to dive into some of that here in
a little bit i grew up in the mainly as
a kid in the nineties i was born in the
eighties but in the nineties we all
remember that pages were used to be a
stable some bits doubt status symbol of
coolness
I remember when my school actually
banned pagers mostly because drug
dealers drug dealers were using them
some of us really wanted to be cool and
you can actually win a free pager
apparently this is probably the best
image i found and we all know one of the
greatest pager examples ever in pop
culture but honestly who uses pagers now
if you remember this movie and the
hangover
he specifically asked if the caesars
palace was pager friendly if you haven't
that's a good chance chuckle we're going
to specifically look into the doctors
using pagers in this talk and then give
a little bit information at the end is
actually ended up being a larger project
that i had planned because of some other
information that we had seen during the
analysis phase and watching of these
protocols so the protocols are going to
talk about which is pox AG toxic stands
for the post office code standardization
advisory group talks AG pagers operate
at the 512 1200 2400 baud rates the
standard operates at 512 think i have a
1200 a 2400 pager and later I'll show
them and if anyone has an SDR and feels
adventurous and has a hand license to be
able to actually transmit which is what
I'd recommend you do not send page you
can try to see if you can make these
beep
disclaimer disclaimer right we're gonna
go in a little bit about the protocol
itself the pox AG actually starts with
oxide particle starts with the preamble
this is something that is constantly
looking for is this preamble this is a
standardization across the world as we
found out in the research so it is
alternating ones and zeros 44 576 bits
then actual batches start with the frame
sinkers in synchronization code or FSC
the FSC is reserved word 32-bit string
it always is what you see right there
gotta drink to this
thank you
following the asset following the FSC
there is specifically eight frames of
the pox AG message each frame is
comprised comprised of two code words
separated by a synchronization code word
the secret is and that's just to make
sure everything's on time and everything
was received and how to piece things
back together frames are broadcasted in
batches and each batch contains eight
frames mother messages can span multiple
batches kind of what the protocol looks
like itself said the preamble the FSC
and then the eight frames with 16 code
words the code words are the actual
message themselves will actually go look
into some messages here in a little bit
kind of some of the examples we've seen
and I'll actually do a live demo and
during the live demo please put your
phones down don't record no pictures
please
flex as the next protocol heavily used
that's actually what will be watching
today's flex flex a high-speed paging
protocol that was developed by motorola
and is designed to operate the same
frequencies as pox AG
flex use a lot utilizes time sinks
instead of listening for a preamble they
were designed specifically to extend the
life of the battery of the pager have to
change these out really like month you
could go longer with Plex course I'm not
forgetting pages on these so it would be
shorter if you actually got pages um I
did get pages we'll go into that later
because i sent them to myself I had to
feel cool when you know I always wanted
a pager so I walked around the house and
you know or actually at that time I was
in the hotel room in another country
where it's okay for me not to have a
hanging license and send messages flex
utilize is that said that hundred and
twenty eight frames and a four minute
cycle which makes 15 cycles per hour so
you'll see a lot of messages for the
entire time sprint time span that you're
you're listening
most of these are going to be sensitive
nature some are still still the American
tone only pages all right bye guys
increase the number of cap codes so what
happened when flex with the design oxide
has a limited number of patents cap
codes just because then the length of
the cap codes and what happened when the
maid fucks they just made a longer
variable so you can use have more pagers
for the primary focus of this research
the majority of our pages came from US
Canada and Japan
however as you can see here there is
more pages then our go back first
you can see all the white variety and
the u.s. of observed frequencies that we
saw the pic pages on canada was limited
to two and Japan had
four different ones and you can see
they're not all in the 900 megahertz
range like they're in the US Japan and
we did observe some one or two messages
and Germany several in London as well
but the ones in London use the same
protesting frequencies as they didn't us
this kind of map shows kind of where we
tried to observe pages what we did in
this case was work on a globally
dispersed team after a meeting we had we
sent software-defined radios home with
everyone and said hey just see if you
can see things work your way through the
waterfall identify with the message
looks like and i'll show you what they
look like here in a little bit and start
telling just tell me if you see them and
then what we'll do is we'll work out
something where you can watch it for a
little bit and then tell me the types of
messages that you saying so that
includes Philippines Taiwan Japan Spain
France Italy Germany United Kingdom US
and canada and Sweden as well myself a
trip I took box AG and flex both can be
sniffed because they stay underneath one
gigahertz range for the most for
everything I've observed so far under
twenty dollars you can get these at
hacks hacks shop
amazon and as well hear they're selling
them in the vendor area had hacker
hardware has them I know for sure I
don't know if Jack 5 has them with them
or not go pick one up if you don't have
one
yes I'm gonna go through this in the
second yeah it does any software defined
radio does but this one obviously is the
cheapest yard sticks work my specific
setup included a hack RF one
thanks Ronnie and a log . I'll that's a
log periodic it's an LP 410 it's the 400
megahertz 2 1 gigahertz at this research
antenna that cost more than most the
software-defined radios do I think
that's a fifty-dollar antenna with that
i was able to capture longer messages
from further away get better clarity of
the messages as you'll see when we do
the demo there will be able to some
decoding issues just because the signal
is not very strong in here so it helped
me specifically trying to get good
quality messages that we could observe
and see what the true content of them
possibly work or so we weren't being
misled or anything like that this one or
the one before
that's a hack RF 10 the antenna it is a
LP 410 and actually i use these on the
other antenna as well you can get a
converter to fit that SDR it's another
cable costs about five dollars to get
and I can't remember the exact connector
types that you can research it i think
one knows to shut out what types those
are so then what you start doing once
you have all the software defined radio
setup and all of this is kind of been
discussed before but I'm going to go
through it so those people in the room
that kind of want to learn how to do
this and look at it it's fun and then
we'll get into some of the more
interesting newer stuff that we did in a
little bit so what you're going to look
for is specifically that's this this is
a flux message that you're seeing there
ng qrx but you can also use us SDR sharp
for those windows users out there you
can do both Windows and Linux
it's not as everyone who's done
software-defined radio as getting had
any radio up and running on a max not
the easiest task in the world so it's if
you can do it you can but I've always
had nothing but problems trying to get
it all and it's not worth my time so i
usually just get a linux box set up and
build it
there's a really handy tool has said
everyone's this is not new stuff
this has been discussed before and
there's a lot of examples out there and
so we utilize the examples out there
instead of trying to reinvent the wheel
or anything like that so under that
github page down there at the bottom
you'll see that there is a script called
pager RX pie it's getting radio python
script that sniffs specifically only
flex if you're looking for parks AG will
go through that minute
you can sniff multiple frequencies at
the same time if you use the 1i have to
go and look for the specific frequencies
then haha
hardcode them in another script and then
you can run that script and it'll it'll
correlate and pull them all into the
bottom waterfall and then decode them
from there on windows there's a handy
tool called a pw PDW a supports both box
AG and flex it's a Easy's the downside
of it was only will only allow you to do
one frequency at the time
that's an example of SD are sharp and a
flex messages as well and then what you
do is then you feed it into pwv a
virtual audio cable and you start
decoding messages maybe I see that is it
is fine too blurry
sorry about that the brothers blurred
messages in there because i can't show
personal information it
so there's yeah there's names in there
and things like that so what you're
going to see once you start decoding the
messages are a bunch of different types
of messages and this is a breakdown of
the data we saw we kind of looked at
some of the metadata around amazing
messages that themselves so you don't
actually store the information or
anything like that and over the span of
the project which lasted three months we
saw 18 million 291,000 alphanumeric
pages 8 million five hundred thousand
tone seven million seven hundred numeric
and those are the other types secured an
interesting one and binaries and
interesting that one as well we didn't
really dive into those too much secured
obviously as the encrypted pages so we
tried to we didn't look into those
because i wasn't the purpose of this to
determine the encryption schemes that
they're using if they're weaker strong
why because it's all everything else was
still in clear text based off of some of
the observations we had we learned how
pages were being used in healthcare one
would be the nurse workflow management
systems this is things that tell nurses
where to go who needs what this also
includes the buttons on the side of your
hospital bed if you push that holes
little page automatically to the nurse
asking saying you need assistance the
pharmacy and general communications and
general communications can conclude
anything like incoming EMS to the
hospital and what to prepare for
condition-wise what's the patient names
you can get them all set in and other
things like that and even hospital
transfers and patients are transferring
hospitals there will be a message sent
out to
that this met this hot this patients now
being transferred to a different
Hospital inside of the nurse Flo were a
nurse and workflow management herself
scheduling and and schedule discharge
kind of so schedule a discharge would
mean that the the patient is being
discharged and the schedule around their
discharge the better it's better for it
helps with and the reasons why they're
doing it is it's better for president
pet better preparation before the
patient's arrival it helps with reduced
wait times it improves efficiency in the
mission discharge transfer and
housekeeping by housekeeping you'll see
that just do this will seem a little bit
about this dispatching somebody to clean
the room after somebody leaves alright
pizza's here everyone go grab go ahead
and grab a pizza you can just pass them
around and about
yeah you can bring them up here it's
fine beers in the backbeats in the front
I i know it's six o'clock and people are
hungry and I appreciate you coming out
for my my talk so just sit over here on
the stage you can come grab a piece to
video get my god Lucy no no message it's
just being random one thanks though I
was it was a good try
personalized target information so
hospital workers only receive relevant
messages this helps with the workflow
management so they're not bombarded by
other things
I'm and it also reduce crop reduce costs
that's all the benefits of it i'm not
going to say workflow management is a
bad thing it's really good
however some of the information that
we've seen over the workflow management
is kind of alarming and scary i'm going
to show two examples these are mock-up
pages of what we've seen of a couple of
the vendors and specific one of which is
navy care Navy care is a clinical
workflow solution and it's provided by a
company called hill-rom and hill rom is
not at fault for any of this
they actually sell an encrypted version
of this system that sends to encrypted
pagers so it'sit's it comes down to a
lot of its budget and what people
actually are are doing as you can see
here you'll see that there is a patient
with medical record number the medical
record number is the end of unique
identifier that they moved to after your
social security numbers they used to
keep in track those
for those who just came in there's beer
in the back to go with that Pizza just
go get yourself a cup and everything
will go good
so this one's a stretcher Allart the
other one we've seen is a cura span for
span is a company that also automates
the patient transition process there's a
product at something called in quicker
and quicker is used to help as it says
in its name check in patients in quicker
a lot of its use for transferring it
actually also sends out the URL so if
you actually have a username and
password somehow obtained you can log in
and start changing some of the things
for them
another one is from epic system is a
piece of software by epic calm which
works on coordinating healthcare
organizations stories up and stores
patient electronic records a lot of what
we've observed were email page or
gateways bed status and medical orders
with this system that's kind of a
breakdown of the companies that we saw
in the total volume we saw again this is
based off some of the store metadata
once we figured out what we were looking
at we could flag and count the numbers
without actually storing all the
information when it comes to protected
health information for ph I breakdown at
some of the medical things that we saw
where ph i was being distributed again
based off of recognizing names and most
of those are based on english names so
this could be misleading it could be
lower than what the actual number is the
email they were stored within a
forwarded email that is put into a pager
medical term
that's just general medical terms were
included inside of the messages well
English names there was no 510,000
specific english names there was sending
syndromes and diagnostics medicine on
the actual FDA drug list will go through
some of that here in a minute as well i
can show you some of that would be again
named male 29 years old being admitted
with the diagnosis of X you sell a lot
of those messages are being seen you
start learning it's kind of scary and
thought like the minute I start seeing
this and I look through it I go when I
go to the hospital which i hope i don't
i will i be conscious enough to say
please don't page my information out and
if they what would they do if I told him
I didn't want the information out on the
paid pager systems so based off some of
the Diagnostics terms we started
flagging some information kind of what
we look at fled the EKG sepsis x-ray
ortho kidney know all those terms and
accounts that we saw within the time
span that we were actually looking for
these it's fairly high given that the
number of very genes and things like
that that we're doing short time
listening in just to verify pages
because there were several places across
the country and specific it's not just
one region inside the u.s. that we're
looking at when we traveled around we
look at things as well and see what we
saw to see if it's a systemic problem or
just a region in which I lived it was
visiting that one time or things like
that and i can tell you based off of
what I saw it may not be every hospital
in every town but high probability in a
major city you're actually going to see
a lot of this information
top prescriptions beer all tylenol and
so friend insulin
yeah that doesn't strike by a girl come
on guys chase
yo I don't think you get prescribed that
friend in the hospital just going to say
that that's a little too much
information there Ronnie yeah i know i
don't know his nursing homes necessarily
need pagers that like yeah thanks Eric
and so this was all seen was it within
departments within the pharmacy pages in
specific so we're going to go through a
couple of those pharmacy pages i
actually like this sign is refunding
found that was searching pharmacy signs
for the slides so one example would be a
morphine for the emergency department
medical record number room number so the
thought on this that we had would be in
a potential attack scenario or misuse of
this page in specific is if you are able
to send a page and you a medical record
number to a specific room number you
could potentially cause some damage and
issues to the person I don't know the
backend processes other than what i've
seen via the airwaves
is that what I've seen is that I believe
this is in theory possible that you
would sit in this they would possibly
dispatch medicine to that room and
probably charge him
I don't know about that piece either it
kind of same one with the next one next
to as well
hey Jason there's pizza here if you want
some pizza
cool
the next one is as I said in somewhere
in the country i won't say exactly where
it or not in the country in the world
organ donors was the highest thing that
we saw so once the morgue had the
cadaver what organs were up for donation
came around
so this is donor number at the donor
hospital
this one would be a female age 49 again
this is a mocked message not a copy
message so just kind of put those
numbers in there but it's like what you
what we have seen the offer then this is
for patients the donor for the patient
and the data burst of the next patient
and we talked about eric mentioned
earlier nursing homes however there is
home help homecare we did see some pages
that alluded to a home home care
solution system this one would be
Goldschmidt patient name date of birth
and the actual phone number for a
pharmacist for medicine at CVS or
Walgreens or anything please call the
patient has horrendous cough needs a
steroid not predators out there saying
that this this patient needs different
medicine
one of the surprising things that we saw
was the things when people actually die
in hospitals it's a page called def
notify I'll show an example here in a
second i want you to take this in and
and see all the glory of this mean that
i found is anybody know where Justin
else's so this is an example of a death
at two different notice notices this is
an example of what we saw in which they
were actually a manual message went
through about the family for a guy is
waiting in the waiting area their name
and phone number and then the death
notification as well for another person
that comes through we witness that there
are multiple types of messages notifying
of death
oh and also dispatching to send somebody
to speak with the family about somebody
who just got anybody have any questions
or anything like this at this point in
time I'm gonna go into some pretty crazy
real quick and it's gonna be blurry as
the screen sucks or whatever but having
my image is blurry
yeah I can't you can't
so the way pagers work their broadcast
based system so once one sent out you
can't I can intercept it and make it not
go but what you could do is send one
that said something else right after it
or keep upping how much prednisone they
need just keep dispatching it to him or
change it all up our say it's you and
you want more morphine because you're in
pain and no one's giving it to you know
it's this
pic to the cap codes and I'll go through
that in a second I should have done it
back in the beginning but the cap codes
are a thing that is uniquely identifies
each pager these run on the same
frequency different moderate but if they
even or the same body this these two
pages would never get the same messages
unless you send it to each one
separately so outside of the us some of
the messages we saw were fairly cryptic
and luckily I was nice enough to put the
string whites there are the this would
come through and in a numeric page and
it's 40 1049 4069 163 7010 4840 what
that actually translates to as we
figured out vs and some research and a
lot of help from some of the Japanese
co-workers who can actually read
Japanese and I can't so that actually
translates to english its test alert and
it uses a grid chart so 40 is 40 would
be a tea so and 10 e and so on and so
forth and there's actually kanji in
there so if you start looking into and
started kit ecology this is just an
example of test alert sell lots of these
in japan it turns out Japan uses a lot
of it for emergency issues for public
notification things like that the
broadcast out messages at this point I'm
going to switch over to doing a demo so
you can go ahead and stop the the the
recording for just a minute please
which is there you see things not in the
region because they're still utilizing
nationwide pager systems nationwide
pager systems again it's a broadcast
based system so it never knows where
that pager is like a cell phone so it
goes to every tower and gets sent out
so it's a fully broadcast good pickle
what we're gonna do now is we're going
to talk about actually spoofing the
pages there's again is the to cap codes
at the baud rates and the frequencies
there's a tool out there called gr
mix-a-lot it again
links at the bottom I really simple
gonna radio flow there she can see it's
pretty much just a box AG is built into
the new radio so it's fairly easy it's
really easy to go ahead and just send
messages Tupac sag flex a little more
difficult but you can do it but for the
sake of this just kind of showing that
we can send pages and this is being the
easiest manner so what we're going to do
here is this is my to pagers i'm going
to go ahead and play and watch it so
they're going to shut off my show you
that where I'm sending these pages in
dead space here in one second
so you see there's no messages or
anything like that
nothing around that that those
frequencies which is 931 4875 there was
the first message will scroll back walls
swing back over here in one second and
show you that that first page Seattle
the pager on the right lit up and then
the pay that's the second page different
baud rate as you can tell us a little
Wyatt and then it we're going to go
ahead and show show the messages
yeah those are my hands my chubby
fingers thanks and it's just that simple
i sent my pagers messages to the page
that could say anything on my original
test said hack the planet grand central
at the planet
yes
yeah you can buy used ones on ebay you
can specifically specify the range while
you're looking
forum in which frequency to go based off
of the systems that you have work and
there are companies that are making them
i just know that motor oil isn't these
are motorola pagers probably circuit 90
2000-2001 right before they stopped but
there are systems out there are still
making pages and they're utilizing old
pages later man thanks for coming
so once i was spoofing pages i also
wanted to show that the same thing
applies I can sniff the same pages that
i just sent first example is again what
i said when i sent act upon it
I'm so as you can see in this message
here I send grandcentral hack the planet
and you can also see that so that's the
multi mangy that i was talking about
earlier and how you can use rtfm pipe
that through multi-monitor ng and you
can decode box AG and flex and then
they're on the bottom is meeting with
PDW well showing the exact say I've
first message is the same and then i
sent a spoof and they're on the bottom i
sent a spoof that the doctor FTR I work
for the forward-looking threat research
team at trend micro I we need morphine
in room 42 and then FTR rules or all the
message that you actually saw it sent if
it's this easy just a spoof pages and
we're just sending them out now granted
we all have ethics and we wouldn't do
this but a criminal would especially if
they wanted extra drugs or knew somebody
in the hospital or as we were mentioning
earlier you can see things like SMS to
pagers maybe send a message to pay a
doctor and ask them tell them there's an
emergency and they need to leave the
room that they need to go take care of
something or even worse he sent out and
you learn all of the cap codes are in
the region are you being utilized inside
of one hospital and you send an event
like a bomb threat page that they
everyone needs to leave the hospital
no because you're on the the receive
only you can go and start figuring out
the signal strengths or anything like
that i'm sure you could but I don't have
the equipment to do that you'd have to
talk to the three-letter agency
yes yeah in that case it would have been
at this research had to be 210 with that
same log parabolic antenna i also have a
standard antenna for it
yeah but you can do it
yeah yep so then you'd be surprised how
much the sum of those sdrs how high they
can start transmitting tail again we can
send pages i can send anything I want
and we should meet in Grand Central and
hack the planet potential attack
scenarios i mentioned a lot of these
already you can declare emergencies
intercept calls possibly steal a dead
person's identity as sin pages to the
pharmacy move patients within facilities
say you don't want the next to you
anymore because they smell real bad
that's the most of the 91 pretty you can
start playing with the imagination and
figuring out potential malicious things
you can do a solution to stop using
pagers but if you can't move to the
encrypted pages or in canada for example
they don't broadcast the name they only
send out the medical record number so
that there's another layer of obscurity
that you can you need to figure out that
it's not a person's name
but even then you can start finding out
things or if you knew your own medical
record number or somebody else's medical
row but it makes it a little more
complex I'm overtime anyway so anybody
got any questions I'll shoot him out
Martin bosses tattoo any questions i
think we and kind of just went through
yet what's up might get my pages those
ones that i sent or not in the US but
yes other than the FCC can transcend
contract transmits but they have to be
looking for it
no yes I yeah I don't know it depended
on vendors when I looked at him
somewhere using AES somewhere just
tripled as some quoted proprietary
encryption we didn't really dive too
much into that specific but if you're
interested in it there's that they
usually have their manuals our lease
sales sheets available on the web sites
any other questions
no well thanks looks like we planned out
some pizza had some beer ever always
good