everyone's in here so i will start my
name is Nick ano this talk is called
plus 1 million minus zero kind of a
shout hub to a shout out to get because
i'm going to talk about how me and a
couple of my colleagues generated over a
million lines of code for a clone of an
online game and the video just went out
my computer is not liking it
please come back Oh skype is going crazy
on me go away
ok let's let's hope it works so the
project was actually done by these guys
down here mostly I'm kind of a technical
expert when it comes to this game
because I've been hacking it for a long
time so I helped them a lot when they
needed help reverse engineering packets
or data structures and stuff but really
everyone but need did the hard work and
I'm just here to talk about it
so who are we we are a mixed bag of like
a mix international bag of game hackers
developers and so on and what are we
doing we're using bots and game hacks
and we are we are basically cloning an
online game so by capturing packets
capturing the data that comes from a
game to the game client we're going to
clone all of that data so we can run our
own custom server and why because well
we want to for the most part so i'm 23
years old i am the author of game
hacking developing autonomous box for
online games i'm the CEO and lead
engineer at example . that's a bought
for the game will be talking about i
work at bromium the senior security
engineer where an endpoint security
company and this is my third time
speaking at Derby con which i think is
the best a conference serious so your
takeaways are going to be like a cool
like cool ways to apply your hacking
techniques to non hacking tasks I mean
it's still hacking but it's it's
non-conventional when you're hacking
games a lot of people look at hacking is
like cybercriminal vs like security
specialist
and i think the video just went away
again sorry my laptop really doesn't
like anything see this didn't happen
when I was giving the talk at work for
practice but it always happens to me
after become so loose can't give me a
break i'm sorry
ok now we're here now we're here again
now let's hope it stays like this
ok I'm just going to step away from the
computer I feel like bumping it is
moving stuff can you guys all hear me
well without the mic ok hopefully pick
something up so and it's we're just
gonna get an example of how you can
apply your technical skills too
whimsical projects and you're not gonna
learn to juggle what i mean by that is
this is a very specific thing we did for
a very specific game you're going to get
some cool ideas and you're going to
learn about game hacking but you're not
really going to be able to reproduce
this one-to-one because you've probably
never even heard of game we're going to
talk about but there will be some open
source stuff at the end so you can learn
how the internals of everything works so
background information so the game we're
going to be talking about his game
called tibia it's a 2d FML it's been
around for over 15 years now on there's
millions of players from all over the
world but mostly Brazilians are people
from polling people from Sweden it's
created by a german company and it's
ruled by box right now about ninety-five
percent of the people who are playing
are actually bought at this point and
probably about forty percent of them are
using my bottle so if we look at the
architecture of tibia we have the tibia
Klein on the players computer it
connects to a login server this red line
right here that's actually secured with
RSA the client has an embedded public
key by which it will encrypt the like
the accounting the password and a few
other things as well as
a 16-byte xt key which will be used
later it'll send it to login server
login server will spit
ok the login server will spit back a
list of characters and IP addresses that
can be connected to so it'll basically
say character number one connected this
IP address on this port character number
two and then the user just sees a list
of characters clicks on them and then
the client knows what to connect to that
will be important in a minute if we get
the slides back
this is getting really annoying i know i
hate me right now too
yes we haven't had an hdmi to vga
adapter right now
no because it does have hdmi like okay
this guy is going to be a savior we're
going to switch over really quick and
then i'm going to talk very fast to try
to catch up to where I should be my
first dirty politics spent 20 minutes
just trying to get the video working so
this is already going better and that
was a different laptop right between as
in one
this is says its uses but this doesn't
yes can you get one on there for me and
maybe just work
ok let me switch back to this adapter
with the laptop over here you have so
great i should be this video ok is it
the device drivers on where are all of
theirs
raised
it's definitely a short as i move it is
man
ok no more problems please I'm not even
doing a demo and the demo gods already
shitting on me
so let's let's recap here we talked to
the login server / RSA get a list of
characters and IP addresses we get that
we select a character it connects to one
of the many game servers which is I
begin by login server cool now let's
look at open tibia open tibia is an
ecosystem of open-source software to run
custom tibia servers some guys back in
$MONTH 2001 reverse-engineer the
protocol made an open source project
since then it's been growing it's been
very stable and the amount of players on
open tibia actually rivals the amount on
the real game just because there's like
hundreds of servers out there so how
that works
we have this guy right here called an IP
changer so inside the tibia client there
is a list of login server domain names
and there's a public RSA key with IP
changer does is it changes the RSA key
to a different public key that the OT
server has a private key for just using
right process memory it's pretty simple
as in there is a long string and then it
changes those domain names also using
right process memory to the domain names
that point to the OT login server and
then the OT login server can spit back
its own IP addresses and character list
and then the client will connect to the
game server that way so really our end
goal here is we wanted to create our own
open tibia server but we didn't want to
like do all the hard parts of making the
content we just wanted to rip it off
some people would call that stealing on
call it just very meticulously
documenting the game in formats that can
be used to show the game we're almost
there
if I don't touch it will wear
I'm just gonna switch laptops really
where it really you
and we're gonna roll in a slightly older
version of the renovation it seems like
okay now I want to see the thing again
we're back i'll let this one boot and
we'll talk
doesn't this suck okay try to pull
screening yeah so I'm just going to boot
up this other laptop and then we're
gonna go from here
I'm so sorry Oh windows update
ok let's let's roll without slide before
I think I can I think I can make it
happen
I am so sorry so oh my god there's so
many like gifts and diagrams that I made
and they took me so long and tortuous
killed announce that I'm hdmi going to
vga um I think my laptop is just putting
the power cord know you want me to try
to strike power some don't
oh that's your one here we have one here
also comes up yet . however the adapter
just to see often get the adapter
yeah
oh just make sure that one gets back to
that adapter and vice versa you know I
didn't know that was a thing
look at your table manners when we do is
make sure that Michael gets back to
Christian the top that we have no has GA
which no one has so this guy right here
that's no good i tried it it looks very
similar but it's not ok so let's see if
putting our on this thing work
ok so that is director Stan changes
let's hope this power works this is
really my life right now and I want
well okay going to have yeah let's let's
see so let's talk about how we generated
the map so it's a two-dimensional
tile-based maps you can think of it as
like a two-dimensional array more or
less it's actually three dimensional get
into that soon
it's extremely large so there's roughly
13 million titles on the map that's not
including blank tiles and stuff it's
like four billion square tiles it's
literally like 65 65 thousand by 65,000
nearly so it's really big but there's a
lot of empty tiles and completely
server-side so that's the inherent
problem here
the server stores a map and it gives it
to the client on a need-to-know basis
and there's no way to spoof your
location in the game you can't say i'm
at this place in the game now I'm here
and I'm here so you can teleport around
infinitely fast and get the server to
tell you everything
it controls everything there is so we
need to walk everywhere in the game if
we want to intercept the entire map so
how do we do that
so first let's look at the map structure
so it's this 15
by 13 grid you can kind of see how its
laid out here and it looks like this so
these white tiles are what you saw on
screen these grey tiles are too tight
i'll buffer off-screen so when you move
around
you don't seem like a black space or
anything it'll just load the next row so
if i take a step to the right it will
load a new row here this road will get
added to the on-screen stuff the green
row will get added to the off screen on
the left and it just drops this entire
row same happens if I'm moving down if I
moving diagonal it's a combination of
both but basically as you move around in
this game the server just send you
exactly what you need to know depending
on to what you already had which was a
full screen which you get login so it's
not actually two-dimensional though
because we have 16 floors top floor 0
bottom is 15 ground floor seven and you
can kind of see how even as I'm going up
floors you can see the lower floor so
those must also be kept in memory right
there are some rules for how their
captain memory but due to the display
issues we don't have time for those so
we come to a few conclusions we can
either dump this map from memory and we
know the structure of it in memory but
it's too volatile
it's always changing as you move around
you have to be in sync with the game's
main thread to dump this because it's a
very complex structure it could be
changing half of it when you've already
read it and then you're out of sync
right I can we hook the drawing layer
and just intercept what's being drawn to
the screen
yes that's actually very common when
you're working with games you hook the
stuff that draws sprites and you look at
the sprite IDs you tie those two the
item ids and then you can determine
what's being drawn and we're but it's
very slow doing it that way but can we
intercept the packets and dump the map
information
yes and it's very efficient that's the
way the client gets the data it's the
most most readable serialize form i mean
it's not actually serialize or not text
packets there's a protocol but we can do
it because we know that structure so how
can we intercept the packets a guy
called sharp apptrackr this was actually
written long ago by a guy called Ian
over Miller he's a facebook now used to
be a Microsoft it's an open source
project that does justice and intercept
map pockets but it's all this is like
from 2009 it
out-of-date a lot of stuff has changed
so we're going to use that and where
will get all of our data to be cast
recordings were going to talk about that
in a second and will it work
yes it did so let's look at the
architecture of the two things we just
talked about sharp map tracker is an
open source network proxy that generates
otm map files as the type of map files
used by the server from captured back
packets and we have a fork with
additional functionality which we're
going to talk about and we've also
updated it to work with the latest
version of the game which was important
because it was all so how that works is
it intercepts this connection right here
and intercepts the login server
connection so over rights RSA key in the
tea plant will show source code for this
you can see how it all works too but it
intercepts this RSA connection by
overriding the domain names and RSA key
and overwrites domain names to localhost
it connects to the map tracker with a
custom RSA key that then gets the data
re-encrypt it with the right RSA key and
then send it along
just when it comes when the login server
spits back the domain and bar the IPS
for the game servers it also override
those with localhost and acts as a
man-in-the-middle on the game server
connection that way can intercept the
game server patents and then there's to
be a cast so this is a third-party cast
and replay system for tibia
it works by if one of you guys is
playing the game the entire state of the
game that you know about is there
because the server sent it to you right
it's entirely server-based so you do
something your action goes to the server
the server determines what the world
looks like now in central an update so
the entire picture of the game as
rendered by the client can be deduced
from the pockets so this is basically
like twitch but for this game in that
instead of recording video it records
the packets and then it replays them to
the viewer and there came client
automatically generates the game state
and draws everything so it works similar
to charm apptrackr intercepts all this
stuff up here but instead of processing
the game packets it spits it out to its
own set of servers so this is a
broadcaster and then the viewer taxes
like it doesn't even act as
man-in-the-middle here it just acts as a
login server so you login with no
account number no password and the list
of characters is the list of broadcast
you can watch you connect to a broadcast
and then it connects you to be service
which replaced the packets to you and
you have the whole view of the game so
this is like the main part of our
project and you're going to see why so
what is our plan how are we going to
take this map and duplicate it
we're going to scrape tibia casts
archive and we're going to grab millions
of recorded sessions so this is hundreds
of thousands of people playing the game
over millions of sessions we have all of
those packets ready to be replayed we
don't have to go anywhere we don't have
to play the game all the data is right
there then we're going to rewire sharp
apptrackr to pretend it's the game
client without a game plan we're just
going to connect the map tracker to
columbia cast and replay the packets to
it
no tibia client no drawing no overhead
so we can do this very fast and we're
going to instrument this on a massive
farm and then we're just going to stitch
everything together so of all these
casts will be able to stitch together
all the map data sent to us by the
recorded sessions and then when there's
some places we might have multiple
places that there's different stuff for
the same location we'll just use
majority rules or whatever we saw most
or whatever we saw first is what we use
and stitch it all together we have a map
profite so did it work
it did we had a hundred 30 megabytes of
binary generated that's 12 million tiles
and 16 million items so a tile is
defined as literally the ground tile so
if there's grass it will be like a grass
style but there can be loose items on
top of that like chest and ladders and
decorations and stuff so there were 12
million times with 16 million total
items on the map and we got 121
replication we skipped over a few cities
because we weren't ready to cook the
quest for them yet but for the city's we
wanted and the quest we wanted we had
the exact game map without having to
like play the game without having to sit
there and map it out manually it was
pretty cool
so that was kind of the easy part
because the map formats very
well-documented and then we have stuff
like spawns so sponsors can be thought
of as x y&z locations of a creature so a
game would be pretty boring if you have
no creatures you walk around this empty
map and you do nothing
it's not fun so we need to put monsters
ermita put NBC's there and when you do
this on the OT server is represented as
an xml file with the name of the
creature and its location so that's what
we want to generate but it's very tricky
to perfecting will see why so let's
first look at npcs NPCs are pretty basic
they can't despawn and they're typically
always in the same location they might
be behind a counter or they might be in
a shop what happened we were doing so
well
oh I just wanted to troll me and get our
hands on this again always switch
screens
okay so they're typically in a set
location so determining where we want to
put an npc isn't really a problem
there's very few duplicates to npc stay
in the same place is not a complex game
where like there might be whether in the
game that makes them run away or there
might be situations where you go away
it's pretty simple and that where you
see an npc it might move around a little
bit but it's probably gonna be there
ok so really all we need to know is how
far that npc can wander and where my
spawn monsters are a bit different they
can die because you can kill a monster
right the point of a lot of video games
to go around and hunt monsters you can
kill them they can die they go away that
message stuff up because if we're
looking at a tibia cast and the guys
walking through a place where all the
monsters have already died then we're
going to say there's no monsters there
we need some way of figuring that out
they can also spawn mobs so you don't
just see one demon 00 you don't just
like one demon or
control you see like five trolls are
like three demons together and what
might happen there might be a player who
kills half of those and then the person
on the cast walks by he only sees two
trolls instead of five trolls so how do
we figure all that stuff out
ah now this is just weird
it's doing screen cutting i'm gonna
leave the mouse there i'm tired of
moving it
so what does this mean accurate spawn
locations are important accurate mob
counts are important and these things
are hard much like a V so we're going to
sort of plan we're going to run this at
the same time as the map tracking on the
same farm using the same infrastructure
of multiple tibia cast fit sharp
apptrackr we're going to improve sharp
apptrackr to track the name the unique
identifier and initial location of every
monster so if you have a group of demons
five demons each one will have unique
identifier you kill them all five more
respondents have a different set of
unique idea identifiers from the last
five but they're each unique to the
monster so we track the initial location
for each monster meaning for each unique
identifier and I don't know what now my
screen is just messed up and we were ok
so plan for NPCs we're just gonna
determine the npc location after farm
run using majority rules and we're just
going to allow an npc to wander in a
bounding rectangle of all the positions
that was seen on fnp-c if you imagine if
he's using like here and here and here
and here and it was seen most of the
time right here this is where we'll put
it and will allow to walk around in a
square that encapsulates all the
locations we saw it on that works pretty
well
monsters are a bit harder so the
monsters were going to cluster monsters
with same name in close proximity so
about five tiles away so we see 5 demons
the first one we see we're going to say
this is a new cluster of demons and then
we see another demon within five squares
of that we're gonna add it to that
cluster and then added to that cluster
in that cluster and we're going to do
this multiple times on the same
recording if a player passes the same
location multiple times in a time span
will do it on different recordings will
take all this data and then we'll match
up all the different clusters so we will
match them based on monster named and
centroid location so we calculated
centroid of all the monsters in an area
so if there's a bunch of demons we
basically calculate the central point
where they're standing and then we say
if we have two groups of demons and
their centroids are within like 10
squares or of each other or something
like that
we're going to say those are the same
cluster that we saw at different points
of time and then we'll take the average
size of a cluster plus the standard
deviation divided by two so if sometimes
we saw four demons and sometimes we saw
six demons the average amount of demons
we saw was five standard deviation is
like one ish we divide it around we end
up with five demons they're roughly I
think it just likes to switch which
screen is doing what at random
I think it's time for a new laptop
google chrome crash then on crashed so
we got that how much time do I have
enough time will be good so we did all
of this and we ended up with 58,000
almost 15,000 creatures on the map that
was a hundred twenty-five thousand lines
of code we ended up generating but it
wasn't perfect
npc spawns were great but some changes
had to be made
sometimes there might be an npc with the
same name in two different locations we
didn't account for that mean you would
be easier to do my hand so you might
take a boat to an island and then p
see on the boat on the mainland might be
the same and you see on the boat on that
island because he's the one who took you
there so we had a account for cases like
that manually and then monsters we had a
bunch of weird cases with monsters
sometimes a sponsor far too large
because we took a bunch of different
clusters and match them together and the
treatment of been sometimes sponsor far
too small because they were being
heavily farmed so there's places in the
game that are just always being farmed
always being bought it so if that's the
case no matter what data we have
there's going to be no monsters
therefore there was killing them so
those were far too small we address that
by hand so we basically just a lot of
monster swans by hand but the base was
there we just had to adjust adjust
counts and stuff like that so npc data
now we know where NPCs are but there
needs to be code for nbc's we can see
it's a the NP seen it is standing here
on the map but how do we know what he
does so it'll come back so NBC's do a
few things they wear different outfits
they can move at different speeds so
some might walk really quickly or some
walk really slowly in the game that
matters in some quests and it's kind of
just a nice aesthetic to have so we
wanted to track that stuff they have
trade dialogues displaying the items
that can be bought and sold so I go to
npc and I type high and then I type
trade a dialog pops up showing a list of
all the items that npcs willing to sell
for sell to me and buy from me and at
what cost
so we want that data because shop and
PCs must exist in our version of game
and they can have conversations we can
see these conversations essentially ask
question and answer the player says one
thing
npc said something back or says nothing
player says another thing then peace
either either responder doesn't so we
can record these conversations as like a
question-and-answer dialogue and
automatically plug these into the npc
scripts the assumption is a lot everyone
playing the game will talk to every NPC
of these once so most of the stuff we
can get that way about to come back or
not
ok so we're going to run this at the
same time as other things on our
tracking farm
we're also going to improve our track
again to track outfit speeds trade
dialogues and conversations for each npc
we're going to do that data sensors no
variations so if there's one npc that
every single person talk to and every
single cast recording that we had we
really don't care because it's all the
same so we just do you take the first
instance of each line from each npc and
then from the deep data automatically
going to generate Lewis scripts which is
a language used their for each npc so
the outfit speed is pretty simple those
are just the combination of numbers the
question and answers are put into a lua
table and yeah and the buy/sell list is
also a table is Ellis we also catch with
the map tracker so 873 npcs we
automatically generated all the
conversations we automatically generated
all their outfits everything that we
needed to make the game seemed like a
game however a lot of conversations that
you have with NPCs and video games are
related to quests some things you just
can't say to an npc unless you unlock to
start request some things they won't say
to you unless you've unlocked a certain
quests and sometimes saying something to
an NDC unlocks a quest that was i I
don't know any algorithms that can do
that automatically so we did that by
hand afterwards we basically made our
code generator leave blank spaces there
we just plugged in a few numbers when
coding quest by hand
yes some npcs exist in multiple
locations and behave differently in each
so going back to the previous example
that boat and pc on the mainland might
say a certain set of things and on the
island might say different side of
things we fix that manually is coming up
with an algorithm would take twice as
long as actually just fixing it and then
we also just that outfit and speed data
that we got for the NPC's we also just
grab it for monsters because why not
monsters also have that data we plug
that into our monsters some of them cast
case spells so hate spell speed them up
so we just took the highest speed we saw
for each unique monster now we're
talking unique monster by name
so we took let's say all the speeds that
we saw a demon have we threw away the
maximum one average them together use
that as its base speed and then we added
at a spell to code saying it can cast a
spell and the moat the high-speed we
ever saw is a speed we gave it for the a
spells so we automatically generated
some part of monsters there and then
some non-negligible back up non
negligible amount of data was gathered
by scraping a wiki website that's kept
really up-to-date with some npc stuff
and some monster stuff i would go into
detail on that but the talks too long I
didn't have time but you can just think
we w get a bunch of pages and then we
throw rag fact red X at them then we
grab the results of the red X we plug it
into our scripts and work done there was
a lot of data there but yeah so now item
data so items are combination of
multiple things and items are one of the
most important things in the games you
have a sword and it doesn't do anything
it's a shitty sore you can't use it so
we need to know all of the data about is
not just swords we're talking like
chests we're talking decorations you can
put your house we're talking potions all
of these things have attributes such as
the item identify our name the sprites
that will be used to draw that item a
type so is it a piece of ground is it a
weapon is it a border on the ground so
basically something that matches two
rounds together seamlessly and looks
nice
is it an armor isn't a helmet what is it
then there might be a text description
how much does it weigh so you can pick
up an item it weighs something because
you can't just get infinite amounts of
stuff on and then how much it costs to
sell it or buy it from an npc and then
it can have many different stats so it
can have zero or many of attack defense
tak modifier defense modifier speed
skill level magick level increase level
increase level requirement a bunch of
other stuff so the name sprites
animations are handled by the client we
give the client a number and it knows
its supposed to draw this thing it's
supposed to have this name
and an animated that way and the npc
stuff
the purchase and resale value we had
from tracking the trade dialogues on NBC
so we just kind of clone that data over
and the rest of the information is
server cited so how do we get this
information
it's all in the server side on a
need-to-know basis
so how do you get this from the server
you shift and click on an item it gives
you text that looks like this you can
see 1850 you see a fire sword attack 24
physical plus 11 fire defense 20 plus 1
it can only be wielded by players of
level 50 or higher 23 ounces the blade
is magic flow there's a large variation
of different strings for different types
of items and different types of stats we
wrote a lot of wrecks for this so if you
don't know what Rex is it's a pattern
matching language you write a pattern
that matches some strange you say the
string first starts with any characters
that arts of opening parentheses and
then you'll see ATK and then you'll see
a colon and then you put parentheses say
i want to capture this value and / d +
means any amount of digits and that'll
capture the attack on that string right
so we brought a bunch of different right
axis to capture all the stuff from all
the different variations of strings like
this and then on our past farm we just
intercepted all the luck messages and
ran the red X but this wasn't sufficient
because people who are playing the game
and broadcasting up they are running
around like let me look at all of my
items they know what their items do
people want to watch them play the game
so we had very I don't know the number
but it was like less than five percent
of the items that we needed had been
looked at our past farm so what are we
gonna do about this
how can we track the remaining items
incoming example . so come on it'll come
back so we're going to use example .
example bought is the box i wrote for
the game and let me just get it on the
slide that we need so when it comes back
we will have it
you're aggressive just like it again
variation turn it on and off again
ok we're back so no bot is the
longest-running active bought for tibia
and open tibia it was made by me
it automates gameplay reads memory
captures packets and it's luis
scriptable the Lewis script ability is
really what we used here so if you
imagine the tibia clients this guy right
here it takes data from login server
takes data from game server takes mouse
and keyboard input it does some stuff
with it and then it spits it out your
computer monitor a very bad diagram but
this is what it looks like when example
. subjected so I intercept all network
data all mouse and keyboard input i have
all my own logic down here I intercept
stuff from the gamestate by reading
memory when the game tries to draw stuff
with the graphics engine i hook a bunch
of functions so i can see everything
that's being drawn and then before and
after its drawn i can draw my own stuff
on top so it gives us god mode in the
game really what we're going to use here
is our drawing layer so drawing stuff on
and then the gamestate memory reading
for met reading map data in the live
memory and then the loo engine so this
is our backup plan so we already had our
plan it failed there wasn't enough stuff
being looked at on tibia cast we need a
backup plan that was to write an example
bot script highlight any items that were
in our data set so this script would
basically open our file that defines all
the items that our server had it would
read them and it would say okay what
information are we lacking and then if
we see an item pop up in the game that
we don't have in our data set is just
going to highlight its going to put a
little square around it
and we'll see that we don't have that
item and then we can look at it we just
look at it manually
why does an example . do it
automatically while we were doing this
on high level characters and doing it
automatically can get us banned because
there's a lot of stuff on the map that
the player can actually click on because
it's obstructed by roofs or like
different floors on the map and stuff
and the bar doesn't go through the whole
thing like as a player you click on
stuff
the Bob doesn't do that it just sends
packets so it could potentially send
packets the player never would have sent
we're doing all this stuff on our
high-level characters we send bad
packets we get back so we decided to
just do manual I'm so and then what we
did is we wrote a script that when we
get an incoming look message we save
that to a file and then we just ran our
reg axes and later
so basically it was this process of play
the game see stuff that's highlighted
click on it it saves all the message we
get to a file and then we run that
through our Rex's later right and we
just keep doing that doing that doing
that narrowing down the list of items
and we're done so it took a while I
didn't do this part luckily this was
done mostly by a guy named nico his name
was on the first slide german guy very
smart and very dedicated such that there
are twenty-three thousand items in the
game and he probably walked around and
looked at like nineteen thousand items
just clicking on them every time the box
that I don't know what this is
and eventually we had 52 thousand lines
of xml generated we had twenty-four
thousand items tract and we also had
about a megabyte of a binary item data
generated so there's two different file
types there's a binary file that does
like attributes like attack and defense
stuff and as then there's an XML which
does like description and some other
stuff I don't know why there's two files
for it but and then let's just combine
the results that we got from that so we
ended up generating a hundred 30
megabytes map data we already saw that
combining the thailand item counts
almost 30 million items were tracked so
here's some rough back-of-the-envelope
math and i forgot i was using markdown
so there's actually supposed to be a
multiply here and multiply here but they
don't show up because they ended up just
italicized 15
um I added this is the last minute right
before the talk so the screen as we saw
is 19 x 15 tiles and then we could story
floors in memory of time on just some
rough math about ninety percent of
screens when I say screens were talking
about just that 19 x 15 grid on any
floor is empty space so we're going to
multiply by 10 at the end and we're
gonna take our 12,000 tiles that we
tracked we're gonna divide by the amount
of times we see / screen then x 10
because it's only about their about 90%
empty we can see about 55,000 screens
had to be seen that's 55,000 unique
non-overlapping locations in the game
that we had to see to generate all this
data so in our millions of tibia cast
that we watched there was a lot of
diversity in there and there's very few
places that we didn't catch on tibia
casserole few but a lot of places we
caught so then we've already discussed
this 57,000 feature spawned response on
xml 225,000 lines then 23,000 items we
just saw that 873 npcs track with over
9000 lines of conversations so the
conversation between NPCs and players we
auto-generate it is somewhere over 9000
it I couldn't give you an exact number
because a lot of that was modified when
he went plugged in quests and we didn't
keep the information of where it was at
on and then 899 monsters tracked so
really when I say tracked we got the
speed and outfit from the server when
we're doing in DC data the rest of the
stuff was automatically generated from
tibia . wikihow.com which we did by w
getting a bunch of crap and that red
xing it and this is what our private get
home depot looks like so we have a
hundred 31,000 committed you'll see like
deletions but that's just where
overriding the stock information that
comes with the server with our own so it
comes with some data and what we call
the data pack we replaced it with all
our stuff so you see 430,000 from riding
this is the guy who did all of the item
looking at stuff that's why he's got so
many lines 41,000 from this guy 672
thousand from him hundred 31,000 there
and then 1000 here this was a guy who
just did the changes to sharp apptrackr
so about a hundred or a thousand lines
of code change in sharm apptrackr to
make it do what we needed to do on this
is including the scripts that we used to
paste it to like connect everything
together those are just like a bunch of
wacky python scripts or whatever we
needed at the time and resources this
presentation I mean if you can't get all
three of these just get the presentation
link it's on github written in markdown
don't know why it needed but people do
this so I'm doing it to our open tibia
this is a couple hundred thousand lines
of code if you ever want to know how
game server is made or if you want to
just play with making your own game
server get in to game development it's
not a really advanced game but it's
really fun to play with its what started
me encoding and hacking so the Forgotten
server is on github all the codes there
and then our edition of sharp apptrackr
is also on github with some of the
changes we've made and questions no
questions okay it went out again