welcome to more sleep rest develop my
name is true branch social security
analyst aise hote OBS and what's going
on here in here as well as a massive
security i love to learn Omnitech and
also breaking it and I love to play
sports re-edited lose a little bit about
ISE we are based in Baltimore deliver a
high-end custom assessment results we
also discuss the new web technologies
and I'm trying to become quality right
freshly gaps so this gave me the
motivation to put together this top so
give you guys a little bit of background
about rests comparison between rest and
so well let's go over some rest concepts
that all over comments curious states
that developers to make my apologies use
your contestant and also artificial so
press residential representational
transfer state for state transfer chart
it is stainless client-server casual
communication protocol there are
similarities between resting be because
. building find friends also mean
contributor of each breast also uses for
all crud operations create read update
and delete so rest were still there
isn't a specification that finds rest
like numerals easier to create
documentation for reference guide cable
as well as the RESTful API also make use
of all HTTP methods some other hand uses
still protocols which change data is
bound by so specification so say break
one requirement your API is in something
always uses the ACP post method for all
let's get a look at a couple simple
question left have a restful but as you
see here i am submitting individuals to
an end . moving the whole method which
is the rest request which is you know
pretty standard
alright so quest and simple method also
request particles method but within the
body and actually contain the operation
so in this example i am reading a post
request so stressed but I'm actually
getting they are stock price of IBM so
from the body of a simple present it
will contain the operation so let's meet
you
HTTP methods you have get host which are
pretty popular delete which is useful
resource patch which is used to modify
the resource but not replace input which
is used to replace resources the updated
version or to create resources we have
other methods such as up options head
injuries there anymore just said you
missed you
that's good i wanted those in here we're
testing . guys will come across that
assumes we're going to bed which give
you more information about whatever
you're testing
all you should be pretty familiar have a
multi-level on your level popular level
also has on her level 1 300 level i
could go to be so what's the data format
of a rest we got there isn't one arrest
wait I can deliver xmo plain text or
JSON whatever you want
so the next question is how does the
finer server know the format help needed
and that is the header content type the
client server sends this header values
weather is next class X amount or
application / space on telling the
server client formats ati could return
most full data types such as xml json
text as well so contribution question
here is how does the server know what
the data format to be clients in the
server and step header which contains
the 484 minute then server either sends
the data and not perform at or air say
hey I don't support this format try
again so what's the touch on resource
your eyes
there are two types of static and also a
restful so here i am using a blog
service
example.com blackball name is the blog
resource blog has a static web page you
go to URL the webpage will be delivered
now press wri is a bit different have
the same resource have to save up for of
example.com / blogs which contains all
the blocks that are hosted by service
and then to access the lobby will use
the block ID
which is not generated whenever
resources to treat now better to use the
second example because the uri stay the
same web apps change is also independent
of the primary those best practices use
the second example went on building out
the resolution yet so research
relationships it's better to group
resources that belong to another
resource in a subfolder so it is clear
that say a comment log this comment
belongs to a particular plot so here we
have example.com left comments / comedy
this method put comments in his own
folder and you access a comment by his
comment is common idea sorry
this trees full blog comments as
separate and this relationship between
the blog comments now instead these
comments should be on stored as
black-on-black blogs blog ID and then
within that directory comments voted
should contain the comments for that
particular plot as you see here the
second sample grow now this method keeps
the relationship between a blog comments
keeps it more organized simplicity
so let's go over concept all stops as i
call it not too sure how to pronounce
that it is more detail stands for Hyper
media has an engine of application see
this is a concept where server sends the
clients URL client doesn't have to deal
with your of instruction
let's see what this looks like
so here we have a sample response from
the server containing the URL to the
blog comments as well as offers program
we also have other information such as
black IV authors handle her name as well
as the that was created so you might be
asking yourself how do I know my epi is
restful fully restful almost restful or
not it off to determine this we use the
richest in maturity model take a look at
this
so there are three months three levels
level 0 saying hey you risk your guys
and wrestle at all pretty much so let's
go through the other levels level one is
the use of resources so you would access
resources by its ID that having a static
web page but the replaceable also
contains the operation to be performed
so they you make a request to get a
block you still use the post method but
within the request was a block-level to
comes in when you start to use HTTP
methods post clubbed post did foot patch
as well as those your recipe i will be a
level-three if you implement a tox type
of controls now either this guidelines
there are no strict rules to really
define by a restful api just guidelines
you might give you a general idea
so a couple useful tools
postman postman is the chrome plugin
that developers use mean I guess
security uh successors could use as well
this is easier for developers to test
area yes the great UI distributed earth
as me and I was a great tool to assess a
story there is a screenshot shows man
like i said the GUI is very nice
it allows developers to send all
different types of requests it also
keeps a history so you can go back and
revisit and change parameters you like
10 different now takes us two points at
the speed of her purpose a web
application test platform is comprised
of several tools for this papel bees and
repeater but I also has functionality
for you to buzz dates as well as
intercept and modify request from
serving so a couple security concerns we
had when we test trouble
yes developers want to protect against
unauthorized or an authenticated
modification of protected assets they
also want to protect against
authenticated on the right access to
protect that says as well as then again
we played that Christoph i created a
sample API supply
yeah I used clothes even leave in
disgrace pretty much Talos package all
the dependencies for the project my you
sprint which is restful web service API
to secure my points and tomcat
so how do we go about protecting the
rest of week guys
first you can start by protecting basic
amendments is it so not every month is
for every resource should Wycliffe Bible
methods and we should not allow it's the
delete method for critical files like
users should be able to delete
particular pop so what does this look
like in spring me to annotate points
with a lot of momentum here i append the
method parameter here saying OK cable
quest I'm sending two blogs and my son
will return all blocks and that's what
it looks like in jersey jersey division
of jax-rs which is a java api for
restful webservices same thing here just
annotated this point with get around so
let's touch on one JSON web token I come
across this more recently we were using
JSON web tokens instead of cookies taste
what's open for you to identify the
sender stateless so it contains all the
information needed to authenticate the
user as well as verified that smoking is
actually valid JSON format its base 64
encoded sense it's not a cookie you can
secure a JSON web token with the usual
security flags just here in HTTP only
this actual talking his sand and the
authorization header is usually used for
authentication and setup authorization
even though its scent and our position
had a party could use it
authorization so we use it walks in the
server check the credentials
everything's good created JSON web token
our job then for each request the client
will send this JSON web token with
requests to authenticate yourself and to
verify so what so it is made up of three
parts the header payload the signature
the header contains daughter used to
create a signature as well as the token
type the payload contains a plain
statement about the entity easily the
username as well as maybe about the
token such as expiration date issuer its
own support so here is a sample job here
we have the header the algorithm used
here is H max shop 23 says type of
tokens that JSON web token the payload
contains the issuer which is he branched
me subject which is using an expiration
date
now the signature is computed by taking
in basic for the header . the basis for
each max shot better wherever you want
to use hashing algorithm to previous
signal the format hood JSON web token is
header that pillow passenger is an
example of one is the shorter version
he's very much longer so JSON web token
should not contain sensitive information
because they're not corrected they're
just a 64 encoding you could although
scripture see someone using JSON web
pressure the secret used to create a
signature should be secure server side
because you don't want you here
you know for your own sake so securing
it . with JSON web tokens should verify
the signatures set a short expiration
date always communicate over secure
communication channel and secure signing
Secret Service I'd also 29 sensitive
information you have to scripture to get
so let's send a request to rm1 blocks
which returns all the blogs and notice i
have not included the JSON web token is
request and let's see what is returned
we would be received all blocks Reserve
which should happen and the user is in
authenticated or authorized to use any
blogs about a valid JSON web token so
let's go to the koo sow 4.4 for the
request is received by the end . we
should create some type of filter or
interceptor that intercepts all of us
and then verifies the JSON web token is
bringing the created or i created a
filter which intercepts the WebSocket
extract the user information and
invalidates the never checks out the
request will be sent to them . global
response will be delivered to the user
let's take a look at the valid method so
after the information extracted from the
token the user just checked also the
expiration of symptoms checked as well
as if the user has some change your
password before was created will often
make their saying hey you have to
we authenticate yourself that you change
your password after this took mr. even
less the same request without a JSON web
token that we have implemented our
filter and we received before one task
and you're on all the box which is great
exactly want to happen because you don't
have a json request so once you sit back
there and not the blocks now let's in a
request with a forage JSON web token and
see what happens in a request to the
server returned to 41 on the rice
responds just like you want to happen
because Jason so it is invalid
so we also want to protect sensitive
resources and how do we do that
implement access controls their pro bass
or user-level base or combination of
both
so your incessant kind of come across
applications where they are housed in a
multi-tenant environment so in this
environment you don't want to have
clients accessing other clients this
shouldn't happen at all so we need to
you met a permission level of some sort
so pretty much to offer plus and i
receive a valid JSON to again use their
password as user password
this is a user-level account that have
stored in my yeah let's get the blogs
blog every blogs the brand created one
added created one user created the other
one
let's see if we can delete block so then
other we request
I want you to leave that is block around
user-level account so i should be to
delete someone else
hello and i received 200 that's ok which
shouldn't happen because i am not the
altar of that lock let's see what the
code looks like to hear you have a 10.7
into the only method so what this point
does it extracts the ID fetches a blog
and then remove the block here we have
no access controls implement which never
happened with the coach should look like
this take the trillion extract the user
information
username as well as the roles of that
user then I don't have to check here i'm
getting a blog author and i'm comparing
to the username that checks out the blog
is deleted that doesn't check out the
second check check repaired by the
permissions of that user is check to see
if it has a role of Adam I haven't been
this because admin should be able to do
apply even though I was created by
something else somebody else if both
these checks go check out the air
returns and you're not authorized to
perform this action so now that we have
our access controls implemented and once
again the same request request to the
blog's last two . and we return with uh
you're not authorized to perform this
action that
so input validation the service should
always validate and coming dated said
always check the content-type to make
sure that the factory site is supported
by this import the server should never
assume the content-type and the constant
should always be checked and it's like
to be based on the data in that request
it off talking vice versa
it's not a former level status code
should return
let's see how to spring you can just add
the students equals whatever data type
you want within actually . now spraying
automatically handles errors so okay
receive requests any texts last xml the
sprinkle actually handle the error and
error message back to the time and it's
a little bit look like in jersey plus
central west to the server containing
the constant light to flies that smell
I'm return with the 415 status code and
hey unsupported media type i can read
this type of data back let's try to send
the same request but in this case you
change the content type to a police
chase on which is provided . and see
what happens and return with a format
that will plus saying that hey the data
format is it right you know
board early race don't find it so get
the data format is wrong
so output encoding security under should
always be same of all requests elbow up
in all responses sorry
content types should always maintain the
correct content types of servers sending
json content-type header should include
the application / t stop also X content
type options no snitch should also be
set so that the browser won't try to
detect different content type of it in
the one that is why i put that rubber
talk pretty fast my blog
di will be available on github basically
uh partially based it off of already
working demo spring also presentation
will be available on our company's
website and if you have any questions
ask now or send money no I also have a
couple drinks for tonight so if you come
to the jury room and talk about
wrestling and
give you a drink p
I
yeah
all that is left up
sorry about that
very soon
ok
yeah