right blah i'm gonna go ahead and get
started
there we go that way alright thanks
everyone my name is especially McIntyre
and we talked about the windows
subsystem for linux today
alright so we'll go over a little bit
about me and we'll go over what the
windows subsystem for linux is awesome
the implementation details of how it
works and then the attacker note so with
this talk i really want to take the
approach of looking at it from two
aspects i want to provide information
that may be useful for people that
really want to dive deep into the
windows kernel one actually like no
house functioning people that might be
interesting to exploit development
things of that nature
I also on the other hand wanted to give
information that be useful for pen
testers that way if you run across this
in an environment you know a little bit
about it you know the types of
information that are applicable to you
so hopefully when it's done you'll have
a you'll have that knowledge I just
little bit about me my name is Spencer
bacteria on this is my third for time
speaking at Derby come on really excited
to be here
I were Christian the research innovation
apartment we do special projects on
internal tool and vulnerability
development i work on a bunch of open
source projects and I like to Windows
kernel things some stuff about me
windows in Colonel so on the subsystem
for linux so what exactly it is it so it
was Microsoft's initiative to allow the
native execution of x86 64 bit elf
executables on windows so prior to 12
subsystem for linux coming out the only
way you can do this would be you have to
utilize some sort of virtualization
technology and so you have to that layer
in between where your FX cables running
in the windows kernel you have like
you've been to some along those lines so
there's a lot more overhead there so you
have a big performance increase so the
wsl is not virtualization at all and so
because of that there's a huge enormous
increase and what they have claimed is
that you get near-native execution times
of the 64 bit of executable as if your
war on a full-blown linux system with
comparable hardware capabilities as the
actual functionality is provided by two
drivers that we talked a little bit more
a lot more about this DLX core and the
LSS that army these two drivers are
providing this functionality
this is Microsoft's diagram i did not
create this diagram this was on their
blog I'm so there's credit down there
very Bob I don't make this this is how
it actually gets started up so when you
actually going you run bash txt that's a
portable executable and that's going to
communicate to the LX session management
service that's running this thing going
to communicate down into the windows
kernel and it's going to start up a new
instance of the LX on session for your
particular user so that's an important
thing to know for an attackers
perspective will get on in a little bit
is that one user is logged in and they
start bash multiple times in multiple
CMG's all those are sharing the same
environment so those are all interacting
it's only started once per when the user
logs in and so when those the last of
those bash files at her
bosch commands I've been run close out
that is when the session is then
terminated so there's one regardless how
many instances bash that you're running
so all shared
I mean once the Alex Cora starts up it
starts up don't knit process and that's
when the actual executable bash runs and
that's when you have all your access to
like to realign library relations all
that native functionality that is linux
users were used to having inside of our
passion environment so that those two
drivers that just mentioned on the LSS
driver actually is is very very small
there's not a whole lot of functionality
in there on the primary thing that it
does is it cause the initialization LX
cordiality score is much much larger
believe size-wise it's approximately 20
times larger
it's where all of the assist calls are
implemented is where all the files of
the filesystem logic is all implemented
that's all in LX core access to sort of
the driver that sits on top of it though
and when alex s gets loaded by windows
during the boot process it calls the
initialization in LX core which I starts
up the driver object and that is what is
actually maintained but most of the
functionality that you're going to be
dealing with this provided by alex is
called things like that are all actually
implemented in LX core the much larger
of the two drivers so there's a couple
of different ways that windows able to
provide this functionality to to the
windows users will provide this linux
functionality and a lot of these RV
the the system calls that are utilized
as well as the filesystem sort of in
linux everything on is not everything
but just about everything is accessible
via file if you want to get Colonel
information there's a file you can read
out about that if you want to know like
what address is a process hazards that
there's finally can read about that like
proc file system as opposed to windows
in Windows everything is is an object
and those objects are then accessed by
the win32 API that Microsoft has exposed
it's a pretty different architecture so
we're going to talk about the six calls
that are actually supported by microsoft
to allow these executables to interact
with the colonel as well as the file
systems but within the context of each
one of the Linux processes that are
running these are not full-blown native
windows processes these are actually
referred to as pico processes people
processes are very lightweight small
container processes they've actually
been around for awhile they will done as
and created as part of window of
Microsoft's project robert which
intended to create a the capability for
Microsoft to in the future utilize other
sorts of technologies i I've looked into
it i cannot find another practical
application of where people processes
are used to my knowledge of the wsl
system is the only place that people
processes are actually used on but they
are there the container processes that
do not have all of the overhead of a of
a windows process and the reason why is
because these Linux processes that are
running they don't need to have NT dll
available they're not be making any of
the windows system calls they don't have
any of that I'm so this people process
is also limiting what an attacker can
actually see about a linux process from
within the windows environment and vice
versa
yes like i mentioned one of the
important things that there's no pad tab
and tll in addition to that the shared
region on of the user 32 the shared
region that's map between the colonel
and the processes that on people they're
familiar the colonel explication are
used to utilizing that region also is
not map so it's not it's not available
because the learning process is
presumably are not going to be utilizing
no legitimate Linux processes going to
expect to be able to access up the
handle table information from Windows
and Windows kernel does still provide
I'd the scheduling functionality the
memory management things like that but
the rest of of the process
it's basically if you process the hollow
process
I'm so the people process also get a
separate syscall dispatcher there is an
additional six call dispatch there's
exactly one that is available on the
system and when that LX SS driver and
the Alex core drivers are loaded they
register themselves as a picot process
is called dispatchers so there are
providers meaning that when the people
processes are actually started and the
transition is made into Colonel land
because one of those of Linux processes
is making a system call windows knows
that this is a picot process so it's
going to route that system called to the
provider that is has registered itself
as as the driver in this case can be LX
or so the system calls are the primary
way by which all the Linux processes are
going to be able to interact with the
host operating system as going to be
windows there is no linux kernel
strictly speaking inside of Windows
Microsoft is claimed as a completely
clean room implementation meaning that
all of the system calls that they
support were written by them by looking
at the man pages during the prototypes
are all set and things like that so
there's a couple of variations i will
talk about the attack recession section
for fingerprinting but it's a clear was
supposed to be a cleanroom
implementation so there's no linux
kernel that is technically running into
it just appears that way to expose be
the system calls so when i did my
analysis on one of the things i want to
do is always know what all system calls
were actually supporting this is going
to be one of the when the attack
surfaces that someone running inside of
the linux container would have into the
windows environment so at the time they
did this on this build 14 385 I'm I
compared the colonel that claim to be
running the version of that Colonel to
the number of system calls that were in
the linux kernel source tree for that
there are about sixty-three percent
coverage of all this is calls that that
version of the links Colonel supported
about sixty-three percent were offered
by a by Microsoft exposed to these
binaries on someone's that were missing
read some of the the 32-bit equivalents
I don't really know this i'm not much of
the linux kernel guy but actually build
32-bit equivalents are the newer
virgins a lot of us some of the older
system calls on linux are a 16-bit some
of the newer 32-bit equivalents are some
of the ones that are actually missing
presumably microsoft is still catching
up and they need to support more of
these calls so as they continue to work
on and improve the ws else probably one
of the areas where we can see that the
gap of that coverage shrink as they
start to head and more
ok so like I mentioned when a linux
process is running it's going to be this
people process and when it needs to
communicate something to the colonel for
example it needs to open a file create a
socket anything along those lines going
to have to do that via system call and
so it's going to use its own ABI and
it's going to make that transition into
the kernel and when the colonel is past
the context is going to recognize the
fact that it is coming from the request
is coming from a picot process and
you're gonna write that to the
appropriate driver that's me that LX
core driver the syscall convention is
utilized by linux binaries they follow
the system Davi which is a slightly
different calling convention then what
Microsoft uses because there is no
translation between this it is actually
the responsibility of the the pico
system called dispatcher on to parse or
not possible utilize all the arguments
in the native representation so it
doesn't matter the calling convention
which is how I which is very important
instrumental and not having to change
the linux binaries because they are
expecting to be able to make the system
calls in the native linux convention
which is different than the microsoft
once i'm so the calling convention is
slightly different four lengths they
utilize a six of the registers as
opposed for on bitch much more akin to a
a fast car to mention if you're used to
32-bit remainder of the arguments are
stored on the stack this is important so
if you are going through in your debug
you wanted the system calls you need to
remember that even though you're in
windy bugger that they're calling
convention was actually from the system
Davi not from Microsoft's calling
convention
alright so moving beyond the system
calls there are other file systems that
Microsoft has exposed to these expire so
there are two main file systems that are
utilized one is the root file system
where you have your HTC directory
there's home directory all of all of
that information the second is on the
drive file system which is how the Linux
processes can access all of the the root
of the windows drive so in your drive
file system you're going to have your c
drive and everything beyond that you're
going to be able to have accessible from
the links processes on so there's a
couple other the standard process uh see
any file systems the practice file
system so you can get basic information
if you needed to find like every match
things like that but these are the two
primary file systems that allow access
to be able to read files off of it
one of the things i found very
interesting through this implementation
is that because the linux binaries that
are running have access to the full root
of the drive
barring any permission issues that will
talk about the the attacker section
linux has access to read all of the
files off of the root filesystem the
reverse is not entirely correct you're
not according to Microsoft documentation
you're not able to read the files in
like the ECC director anything like that
so presumably anti-religious not be able
to scan that was kind of interesting to
you could potentially hide a file within
the linux file systems now that's
according to the documentation i did
however find a small discrepancy and
that's because within the windows user
that is running the wsl environment
within their home directory in their app
data some of the Linux files that are
created do exist there so strictly
speaking from Microsoft documentation I
i don't know why that discrepancy is
there but i want to point it out soon
you've seen that tyrion haha excellent
there we go I'm not crazy let it be
known
alright so the drive file system on
despite being rude if you are starting
up your wsl environment you elevate
yourself into rude on one of the first
things that think I was like oh like
let's just drop in MLS file and go get
some access we'll be able to break out
of the windows environment
wouldn't that be great unfortunately
doesn't work that way and the reason why
it doesn't work that way is that one of
the things I'm really be harping on
throughout the remainder of this
presentation is really doesn't mean
anything in the wsl context doesn't get
you anything when you elevate yourself
from pseudo into to root level access
the token that is the permissions of
your Pico process that those don't
change and so when you are
making your system calls on a lot of the
system calls are actually provided on my
windows when there's an applicable one
that can be utilized over some of the
other ones i cant and are then filled by
the links Corp forgot to mention that
but the process no system calls that are
actually implemented on by windows
utilizing the existing infrastructure
those are so going to utilize the native
token and things like that when you
elevate yourself to route that token
doesn't change it really doesn't mean
anything to the greater Windows host
operating system is strictly within your
wsl environment you can like read access
the shadow file that's great for you but
unfortunately that's not even shared
within other users wsl environment so
elevating yourself too rude not really
gonna be the best way to do anything
alright so this is just a real quick
demonstration of showing that so this
could potentially be a hiccup for users
that aren't necessarily used to to
working in this type of environment so
if you're in the wsl environment and you
have a sensitive file and you want to
protect it
maybe you would mark it as owned by root
and only readable by rear but truly i
can do a whole lot for you on so in this
case we're putting a super-secret onto a
secret text file which oman eating it
and we're taking a look at making sure
the toe McMahon actually did execute
successfully but then we take a look at
it the file permissions are still 777 so
might be a hiccup for some users so
point being if your pen tester on it
would probably be a little bit
advantageous to look for file
permissions within the dr.s because you
may you may get lucky
so I context right into our attacker
knows I'm going a little bit quickly
here trying to manage my time
appropriately so one of the first things
that you probably want to do is like if
you're an attacker pentester you're in a
Windows environment you know they're
running Windows 10 maybe they have wsl
you won't be able to identify am I in
wsl I went into this thinking it'd
probably be really difficult turns out
actually ridiculously easy you can
pretty easily identify that the linux
session the linux session that you're on
is actually uh is actually windows have
a couple of obvious ones and i want to
break these out into obvious and
behavioral because if Microsoft Word to
change them they're probably change the
obvious one son my personal appearance
opinion and experience the less likely
change idea that
behavior once but within the obvious
ones there's actually it says microsoft
in the product version i highly doubt
any like legitimately into distribution
is going to actually have microsoft and
they're just check for the dr mounted in
the / mount directory so like I said
that dr s is going to have / mount / c /
mount / d you have to drive things like
that if you're looking in there you're
probably going to have on those drives
more interesting one to be some of the
behavioral clues on Silva's exactly one
module that can float up into the system
modules which seems kind of a little bit
sketchy from normal linux users
perspective is that you know that you're
probably have a few loaded kernel module
running you need to have drivers and
like that i'm running through on my
system i need to add like a wireless
driver our graph display driver there's
a number of drivers that are loaded on
my system to to be in an environment
where claims that only one kernel
modules loaded it's pretty indicative
that something is something is going
wrong in the proc file system that
releases in her exposed information
regarding the running processes there
are missing fields that are entirely
implemented this could change my
microsoft as they improve their support
they're probably going to on expand on
the proc file systems now price changes
well another one that I found very
interesting this last one is actually my
favorite i ran across this was testing
one of the metasploit of halos and
that's actually on the checks on the
nmap system call are actually much more
strict so in that third argument where
you're supposed to specify some of the
some of the flags on on Linux you can
specify all any of the flags that are
defined and you specify additional facts
that are undefined it just it just
ignores that they don't do anything on
Windows however if you specify flag that
is undefined to the M map system call it
will return an error so you can have the
exact same function with this extra 0 x
1000 that's an undefined flag and
that'll run successfully on linux but on
Windows it'll turn there's that's kind
of interesting behavior including that's
actually because of the implementation
that Microsoft used for that system call
so I'm like is mentioned i found that
was looking through some medicine
playlist so another thing that I assumed
a lot of investors be very interesting
as like if I'm looking at a wsl
environment what payload options do I
have which one is that these are going
to work
I'm so up here in the right the right
are gonna be the payloads that actually
tried in which one of them were
unsuccessful so there's the brand-new on
metal payload don't know if anybody
follows of medical development because
it's really cool payload that is like
the future of the linux meterpreter I'm
system that one unfortunately did not
work and the reason why was exactly
because of this map system called they
may be changing it in the future version
on but because medical aid has a
preference towards wanting to keep the
shellcode much smaller it would expand
the size out a little bit more to clean
up the arguments on so just kind of
fluke that I was found but it actually
is in that particular stage or that why
that payload is not working on the shell
the unstaged she'll reverse tcp worked
correctly on the x86 up meterpreter
reverse tcp does not on and that's
because it's the x86 version microsoft
the wsl project is intended to run
64-bit binaries and because of that
32-bit lxq balls are not are not support
you can't run a 32 bit of executable in
wsl at this point on normal full-blown
linux distributions you can run 32-bit
bynars like I could run out 286
interpreter on my floor system please
don't do that but you could do that on
wsl it is very much focused on like just
the just 64 bit and last not least my
personal favorite the Python interpreter
does work on fully-featured for the most
part on slide caveat to that but you get
your session back you can interact with
it you can you can run commands on this
presumably because the installation that
python that included in the linux
standard base is present in the wsl
environment she can utilize the Python
interpreter I say that it is mostly
supported and that's because on at the
time I testing i believe it's probably
another one of the things that Microsoft
is going to eventually change very soon
is the ifconfig man was not entirely
sport you get errors out of that I'm and
so retrieving IP addresses and things
like that utilizing the functionality
that the Python
actually does it by interacting those
files on the expose the information to
the colonel on that information was not
entirely available so you'll have
trouble with your right trying to
retrieve the IP addresses like the eye
of commitment but most of everything
else work while you can get a shell you
upload download files on believe you can
route through it so all that good stuff
additionally might be interested in what
up the clinic's Colonel protections are
available since we know that there's not
a linux kernel actually running in there
so what types of protections are
actually provided by the linux kernel
you have things like data execution
prevention or depth you have a SLR no
page mapping things like that i tested
all three of these the very basic
implementations on and they are all
they're all implemented specifically
when it comes to is LR believe the
reason why this was actually implemented
is because the functions necessary to
allocate the memory are some of the
functions that are already available in
the windows api so the system call in LX
core is not the filling it in cell it's
forwarding those onto the windows
implementation so all the function
features function is actually there is
being leveraged ok so cross process
access so if you are in a minute process
what can you get from a windows process
and vice versus the types of things you
need to break out of the environment of
so from linux process you can't access
the windows processes this is
unfortunate because windows once again
provides access to this processes as
objects that are accessible through the
win32 API that you can access from the
linux environment windows however can
list Linux processes if you load up in
proc explore you'll see a bunch of Linux
processes you're in bash your Python all
those things are all listed out as a
child processes of the unit process the
kids do not do not match up as you would
expect the lower number of kids are in
the linux environment so this process
identifier is don't match up from what
you're seeing in the windows environment
one of the things that you actually can
do is you can access d from windows you
can access a ham slide ahead you're
actually so I covered on all that run
behind a little bit i'm from windows
into links so you can access very
minimal amount of information I'm so
windows allows access to the process
given through to api for objects like i
just mentioned so the way you do that is
actually utilizing the open process
function and you pass in the different
arguments on that provide the level of
access that you need to it according to
the Microsoft documentation on you're
not supposed to be able to use the
process query limited information
however when I did in my testing i was
able to use the process query limited
information get basic information that
the pico process on because it is a
picot process though you cannot do
things like open it with the ability to
read and write memory you can't create a
thread you can't do all those things
that you could for a normal full windows
managed on process which can use in
query limited information which
basically allows you to check the exit
code when the process exit and you can
call the synchronize meaning that you
can wait for that process to exit on so
this is slightly interesting because as
us linux users know in linux the exit
code of processes is actually somewhat
important there's a standard list of
Mexico's that mean different things so
from the windows environment you could
find a running process theoretically
wait for to exit and extract information
out of that for you so you can get
information out on steelo eight bits of
the windows status code corresponding
vertices meet it's the 2nd by that
allows you just have to be shipped over
8 times you can get that on the exit
code from from the linux process
alright elected mission across user
access so if you have multiple users
running within the wsl environment so
specific to each one of the users so you
can't actually access each other's files
the file systems are our independent
when i check this actually 11 user
starts it up it has to download a large
amount of data from Microsoft to have
all like the Linux files and everything
and when you go over to another user
despite the fact that one user had
already done that they have to download
it all as well so those file systems are
our independent unfortunately if you get
root level access than one wsl
environment you're not going to be able
to extract the other user shadow file
and that is meet i'm saying that i am up
i think that's about it well there's our
my closing thoughts like I said route
really doesn't mean anything on some of
these nuances are trying to trip up new
users I'm so i got this really sweet
desktop because I signed up for the
windows insider program in order to be
able to test all this cool ninja cat I'm
and those are my references
thank you everyone