alright well i know we're already a
little over so i guess we'll go ahead
and get started because of this to
stable talk but this this talk was
originally designed to be more of our
long talks so we cut down like
seventy-five percent of entrusting put
into as much as we can so if you guys
have any specific questions or anything
feel free to ask us afterwards grow
pretty powerful who are you no one
really cares we're just going to talk
about again we're going to talk about
pci baseline configuration things like
that versus real-world attacks on with
the tango checkbox security isn't a bad
start but it's just that start
I doesn't make your security I you know
it's not a comprehensive thing it's just
a start and tempest yeah duh you know
there's some that are genuinely
concerned when you do security most of
them are if you see a lot of
corporations they follow frameworks and
compliance and standards all we're doing
this pin test because of PCI compliant
and so that's the only driving factor
behind their security culture and that's
that's kind of what this talk is about
it is it's aiming at getting away from
just doing security for the sake of
insecurity and minimum efforts and then
overlooking some possible compromises
yep so yeah I get this for the record is
again really high-level don't want to
read all of the points one by one but
it's really hard to cut all this stuff
down really quick you feel like anything
about threats limitations equals a false
sense of security
you know hey I did a pcr a pentax ok
cool what you do with this segmentation
testing that's cool we just networks
scans and tests
here's this nasus output in this 50-page
no pen test report and then they accept
that this is the way it works in q SI is
oftentimes will be like okay that's good
to go and then this company and the
client those that you know may not have
a full grasp of the risks are out there
except that ok cool we're good and it's
installing this fall securities I going
to self-defense class
making one self-defense class and I'm
good to go because i know three
techniques and this just not how it
works so i talked about scoping clients
often are very ports coping I they come
in and say hey we're a huge network but
here are four hundred IPS and oh yeah at
the domain controller is out of scope so
don't hit that ok well not connected to
your network then so and you know those
are things to consider like what are you
putting in the scope that you've got you
know I attackers they often take the
approach of you know focusing on low
hanging fruit so they come in and
they're able to plug in at and they are
they look at all the things that you
excluded the Assessors from looking at
at there's so much that's left wide open
so you know well even with a low-hanging
fruit you know it's not always when we
think of loading free we think oh ok
well this is an outdated apache web
server this they didn't have this
Microsoft patch or whatever just the
easy easy easy exploitable stuff below
hanging fruit is beyond just the
technical aspect when you look at
security threats you look at social
engineering is one of the main comp
catalyst for compromises right and
oftentimes they don't include that in
those tests they don't include it in the
networking that our perp in tests they
just focus on okay well segmentation and
I'm not harping just on pci this is for
a lot of standards even if you look at
NIST and stop people just use this and
they just go bioorg out of compliance or
we do you do we fell here that's all I
worry about it's all you worry about is
your great card you know and that
doesn't embody the full encompasses
thing of security culture and then
there's the whole idea of hey let's make
sure we get this checkbox checked so
that we're not having to pay money and
fines and that's their whole motivator
in you know a and you know their
security so a legitimate concerns for
the company so say your bank
obviously you're legitimate concern is
not letting attacker get to client
information credit card numbers things
like that so you've got to got to
consider these things whenever you're
having a penetration test done
you know just come in and say hey at ok
is trying to get your domain admin you
know that might not be that the jackpot
for the point of the assessment you've
got to consider you know why are you
having this test perform so you know and
ends outside of just you know the why I
identifying those risk and in thinking
outside of the box thinking outside of
the store
I don't want them to get access to this
is my most sensitive area around since
the data thinking about the smaller stop
it is a low-hanging fruit that's often
the the window the break to get into the
big you know metal building right over i
mean it's it's it's the easy way in and
a lot of people overlook that stuff
especially when it comes to the human
element of social engineering and
physical state security as well so I
something that I here all the time in it
and it's really stupid is when someone
comes in and they have on scan and they
pass it off as a pen test so just to be
clear a bone scan is not a penetration
test I make sure you have accessories
that are actually exporting things are
actually checking out things and not
just you know coming in and running
messages or you know in map or something
like that and then giving you all the
the output from that so and then you
know IP range versus individual ip's so
again this is kind of what I've touched
on a few minutes ago they only provide
certainties why not just give us the
laksa you know what is coming there like
a real world attacker would do whatever
they can get
we're going to go after so I stop
limiting the Assessors as well
anyone in the risk with that I know from
some kind of the blue team side as you
know you're gonna break supple well you
don't want you to hit this box we won't
don't want you to do this because you
know this is a legacy application and
you know it's been sitting on this
ancient artifact forever and always
touching it because you might break it
and that's when you need to look at
yourself you know your infrastructure if
it's that easy to knock something over
to you know there's a risk their denial
of service is very very often
it is not included in pen test at least
the ones we do because people are
frightened mile service you can run
checks all you want but does it actually
work you know things like that and
setting this up there safe ways of doing
this if you do have a dev environment or
you know the test environment there's
ways of doing this replicating that same
kind of threat even outside of just the
human elements
yeah it's Tim talked about you know a
legacy systems and things like that at
what does erat development lifecycle
look like with your applications and
things are you do you have patch
management are you actually keeping
those things update and keeping an eye
on that or do you just wait until once a
year when a group of guys come in and
and do an assessment and say hey here is
a thousand outdated you know whatever so
you got to keep keep touch on those
things you gotta make sure to to keep
them up-to-date and follow through with
those in legacy understand that that's a
neat for certain things but i really
mean you can't get something redevelop
to secure something especially if it's
that important that you have to keep it
around that long maybe put some effort
into fixing that a long time ago
security was always kind of at the
bottom of the totem pole when it came to
priority is production production or
whatever at least in my experiences and
i think that you know because of these
big compromises that you see you know
it's it's becoming a lot more prevalent
and important it's raising out finally
interior so you do have ways to justify
doing more extensive stuff like this and
go on to the next slide here are you
know we mentioned weighing you're
risking such but the most important
thing I think on this slide is the
comprehensive security awareness
training program
most of the time people just say oh yeah
we do an annual security awareness
training we have some online quiz they
click through they send blah blah
supervisor hey they did this they got an
80 out of 100 it happens and then thats
that's fine but you just recycling the
same old junk and I'm forgive me for
saying that but you know a lot of times
it's the same old stop content of
generic security awareness stuff or
straight out of your policies and a lot
of corporate Burbage thrown into it
but you miss a lot of connecting with
the people and saying hey here's here's
some threads here some real life
examples here's your stomach don't ya
know they can apply to your personal
life to even outside of work
we're all part of the human firewall and
so prevalent as one of the first layers
of security for whatever your compliance
or whatever is 0 or pci tells you to
test its it's the culturing and shaping
your your employee body into into really
supporting that you're going to like my
blog uh yeah so incident handling and
response you guys use that covered
you know what do you do when shit hits
the fan I so partial disclosure for his
pleasure going in cold so when you have
an assessment you know what what is it
are you providing a scope or they just
plugging in and seeing what they can get
to or are you providing you know full
code for code reviews and everything so
you've got to look at what you know what
you would have done what needs to happen
as far as like your your current
security posture for your company if
you've never done in the assessments or
anything before you probably want to
consider what can you do to start from
the ground up instead of just what can
we do right now to just get a check box
so you know i know some of the way so
how do we handle incident handling and
response
you know I know some tests are only like
a week-long right you can spend that
first day just doing it from an external
perspective if you're you know if you're
doing kind of a partial whitelist had no
shining type of approach they're still
weighs 22 still kind of have that view
outside of it
I'm you have granted you don't have as
much time to try to do that but even I
even with on-site stuff you're doing a
red team work some kind of covert
physical or social engineering having I
know oftentimes we use the fake letter
of authorization to test incident
response so we'll do stop to try to
intentionally get caught and then they
catch us you know we give them the fake
letter and they look at it and oh yeah
you're good to go and they don't call
follow through so know that your
incident response sucks when it comes to
that layer of security don't just test
the the technical layer of security
because you know
once you're in you drop some dropbox or
whatever then you know you're you're in
no we're good
because you have to be connected to our
network we have an open network jack in
your lobby that has dhcp connected to
your production network and kidding me
in the getting and that's happened
see ya next to the water home so scopus
pentesting this obviously i think is
ideal but when you look at the reality
of things that's usually a lot of money
usually not in the budget unfortunately
so let's say I deal you know scope was
confessing so you include the entire
gamut let us close to social engineering
engineering let's come in look at
physical what is everything how can we
try to gain unauthorized access into
anything obviously again unless you have
more money than you know what to do with
that's not necessarily always possible
but definitely things to consider
instead of just focusing on an internal
assessment as 10 and I've talked about
also include the other areas as you're
able to know there's a lot of pentest
companies out there that do just you
know for their external penetration sex
but you just focus on the network and
application layers they don't they don't
include that social engineering aspect
and you know you have to wonder with the
amount of compromises visit you know
that happened and it being because the
fishing or cold calls and spirit
whatever that this stuff is is a big
issue and it's time for you know not
only is his pen testers but you know the
blue side that you guys you know we have
to work together to try to understand
what you're trying to protect and how
you can protect it and it's not this you
know Jason Street an awesome talk i
think it was at a one of the b-sides
worrying that he had talked about this
red vs blue thing and getting rid of
that nonsense and I think it's so
important especially for this kind of
check box approach that we get rid of
this
well here's our safe here's how we can
safely talk to these pentester guys and
what we kind of want to do and really
just listen and and have open
conversation dialogue that's the most
important thing
and you know something I've heard to its
get analogy it's like at whenever we
going to do an internal contester
external or whatever it is you have the
guys that have worked at the company for
years and they they maybe even helped
set up the network and so they're
they're confident that you're not going
to find anything or maybe they don't
want the extra work when you do and so
it's basically the equivalent and
walking into a place and telling someone
that their baby is ugly it doesn't
usually you know it doesn't go over very
well so just kind of changing that
mentality of you know help us help you
is also a good way to approach it
so we've already a very touching this 30
can just walk in
probably you know I have RFID corners
and on stuff but you care so you don't
need it because oftentimes people just
they don't pay attention to the color of
the badge and sound anything like that
they just see that you have something
around your neck looks like kind of what
they have around their neck and you're
good to go and but people don't you know
consider that you can have all the no
piggybacking no tailgating signs you
want but when people become this very
routine especially as a large volume of
traffic coming in and out of places or
there's a lot of contractors that come
in and out
it's so easy to just walk in here and so
you know even if you you have a guy on
site during a test
no hey he's here for partial disclosure
of my nose hearing sounds the visitor
log Bob all give the pen tester day to
just see if he can walk in and get to
wherever it is he normally plugs in if
he does then you kind of gotta you
weaseled a little free assessment of
that kind of the first layer of security
on our internal network test at school
so at X definitely you know let let the
person in the assessment look at your
digital footprint yo utilizing open
source intelligence are they able to
quickly find anything that's unsecured
or maybe your developer ask for help in
a few years ago on a development forum
and provided legitimate database
credentials for someone to help and
those are still active and I've actually
found that through
web assessment before unfortunately I
you know look for things like that or
I've even found usernames or database
again database credentials or even the
entire database schema from someone
asking for help and that stuff was
archived and no longer required access
to that email account thanks to google
and i was able to utilize those
credentials just from doing some basic
searching through the internet again and
that kind of opens up like let us let us
go after anything that you have like
anything that you own
that's connected to the Internet let us
see you know especially internet things
mean a lot of that stuff sucks it's
pretty easy to get into that leverage
those things so those are just things to
consider when you are having an
assessment coming out
don't you know the limited to kind of
screw yourself over essentially an
attacker doesn't have the rules of
engagement
they don't care they have all the time
in the world to if you know if they're
sitting there slowly picking at you and
you know so if we consider this stuff
psycho ok what we want to a good real
world view help honor we are ok cool so
here's kind of our attack methodology
but we use you guys get one we're not
really comfortable with this because it
can make our employees not trust are so
you know we can't do this because of
blah blah blah and I'm sorry but you're
not getting a real world first attack
the advantage of you in and even if you
have one contestant come in maybe that
pen tester didn't not going to find
everything that some you know
government-funded cyberterrorism group
is going to find so it's things like
this you need to consider too and that's
why I think you're also going to see
that advanced persistent threat testing
our apt testing is becoming more is
being more accepted from from clients
there there little open to doing like a
longer engagement like a three to
six-month engagement or simple yeah then
a you know like don't they don't carry
the fish so a lot of times with social
engineering stuff they will exclude CEOs
or anyone sort of in that arena and the
executives because they don't want to
end up person they don't want to
inconvenience that person an attacker
doesn't care that's usually the first
person that you offer anyway who has the
most access let's go out for the admin
group or the CEO who feels like he also
also have admin access for whatever
reason stronger security awareness
programs you know if you have remote
offices outside of the corporate office
and you have people coming in then what
happens is you get caught in this grinds
in this routine you do your thing and if
that routines disrupted sometimes you
don't even notice
I you know for example I recent
engagement idea is a social engineering
engagement I had a keylogger on me and
they didn't have badges but I made a
fake badge anyway and said I was from
corporate and I walked in and it was
just two ladies working office i told
him i was there to fix the network
connectivity had they been having some
issues and of course everybody has never
connectivity issues and let me plug in
and do my thing but you know they didn't
ask
they didn't look at you know where those
badges come from or who are you again
for calling us are out of coffee
I also brought him coffee to like I at I
just like was really tired and she was
gonna get well I don't use this and i
got like three cups of copies take as an
example so but yeah you know it'sit's
you're not a jerk for a it what happens
is some employees or they feel like
they're being a jerk question anybody or
challenging by oh this dudes cock
muhammad and his badge
well I've seen him here before several
times i know that he works here
how do you know he didn't get fired like
the day before and he's now you know
really mad you know it's things like
this to consider outside of just the
generic vanilla security awareness
programs it
I'm so regular regular reporting for
compliance broader windows open scopes
specific drills etc these are different
ways of doing a more robust security
awareness program one of the things that
that we do is we have a training where
it's kind of a Q&A a hacker Q&A you have
a you know your PowerPoint you talk
about different ways you do stuff and
they get to see tools be demonstrated or
whatever this is always a good way it
leaves a
the impression doing on-site assessment
or whatever that involves like social
engineering is always great because
sometimes you can have that as part of
your training
well last year branch and she had
whatever you know here's what happened
you are you allowed so and so you're not
pointing out individuals being get the
idea that sticks in the people that
that's that's real things that happens
those companies to your oh wow I didn't
know that happen that's crazy and it
sticks with people more than just
checking on some you know freaking
interactive quiz that you have to take
once a year
yeah and something that at M&I like to
do with that security awareness training
that we provide is that when we're going
in and we actually show people okay here
this isn't under the door tool
here's how it works and show video or
these are lockpick set pic walk and
another thing that really gets attention
is when you have a rogue access point on
or something like the Wi-Fi pineapple
and while you're giving the top you're
actually getting people's phones to
connect to you and then you can show
that on the screen and they say oh you
know crap that's my phone
well then you have their attention or
staying with bluetooth things like that
and like 10 set it goes beyond the
boring
I you know just click power . test that
you do sitting at a computer where your
everybody just you know searches doesn't
control left to the PDF document and
poster with a hook right officials are
not really studying like going to study
this I've gotta gotta really pass this
test today they don't care they just
want to move through it but when you can
give them a real world example like that
you're going to get their attention and
they're going to remember that more so
again that kind of goes well you know
doing the same old thing with the same
animal results not this security
awareness begin with your internal
external assessments and so on you know
in the disaster recovery to disaster
recovery business continuity oftentimes
you have to do a test without you have
to do your annual disaster recovery test
or whatever you can always include this
as part of your off your tabletop
exercises and stuff to you know think
outside of the box outside of just the
kind of standard structure of security
awareness and I mean
disaster recovery and business
continuity is a part of that especially
when you look at denial of service or
physical threats you what all the boils
down to is culture and installing this
security culture into your company into
your executives the guys that make you
guys and gals that make the decisions
it's very important that you know
they're on board and i think this is
always a good i open ur c right to do
this and at one time we did a wireless
security assessment one of the
executives we have like an evil AP up
and connected to it we're going to put
out some is a is exchanged credentials
and so here he was very open to what we
had to say after we were able to do that
there was another time that the point
contact you know he was like yeah you
guys can do whatever you're not gonna be
able to do whatever you're not gonna be
able to do anything to gain access to
anything i love when they say that in
the HR room like where they keep all the
employee files lights were all but it
was opal our cubicles and the cubicles
are blocking that door so they can see
unless they stood up so I snuck in there
as the digging through and found his
employee file and I went over to relate
on his desk musical uses like man you
know it's it's more than just that it's
more than just what you're thinking of a
pen test and/or physical assessment or
whatever you shape your verbiage you
used two types of attack methodologies
that you guys have but you know it's
more than that and i think that it's
important that we always as an infosec
community office defense whatever
executives you know people that never
touch the keyboard but we all get on
board with you know listening to every
everybody and having open dialogue about
real rescue real threats and how can we
help us and still this culture and our
people it so again that we had to cut
this down and extensively so I have that
is basically it for us and now we're at
times if anybody has any questions you
will be always want to chat for a bit
but i think yes
yeah except