yeah all right
hey thanks for comin this is a hacking
and protecting sharepoint before I just
before i get started i know you guys
know I don't know I saw the movie Edward
Snowden coming off seeing it now that
movie so good i don't know how much of
its Hollywood but i would say if I saw
that movie when I was a young buck i
would probably want to work for the NSA
even though they've done him a pretty
good pretty bad deal so little bit about
me
my name is Michael Wharton I'm a project
MVP i do a lot with sharepoint and
project server and I do a lot with
powershell and hacking has been somewhat
of a hobby for me
the other thing I like to read a lot of
comics some these are just some of my
favorites
there's one called hacktivist is kinda
was kind of cool comic ever read and
then right now I'm reading a book called
Damien has been written about 15-20
years ago that's real good and it's
about a process it's running while also
like a lot of hardware I i have my this
this is a picture of my workstation got
my rack with a bunch of servers in there
and then I've got a machine they like to
play with for high performance and I put
different i basically melt ice i put a
big block of ice in the bucket and just
have the coolers of chill the process
and you see how fast i can get it but
this is about sharepoint and hacking and
show you some things how how to hack
sure . and then i'm gonna show you some
ways to protect it
so this this will be the agenda that
will be talking about how many out
currently work with SharePoint or seeing
sharepoint looks like it roughly half
maybe everybody I don't know anyway just
to give a little definition with
sharepoint is it it's been around for
some time and it's a collaborative tool
for sharing documents and searching for
things and you have a basic element box
will just cost you points standard often
comes free and then if you pay a little
bit more you get the enterprise version
that's built on top of this the standard
and it has a other features in there
like business intelligence and
dashboards and a lot of other of
services it runs if you've never seen
sharepoint this is what it kind of looks
like there's a team site is very easily
configurable you can throw up together
sites customize and modified at web
parts and because it's so flexible you
don't have to be an IT guy to work with
it and then the other side of this thing
called sharepoint central and that this
is worthy at administrators can
configure sharepoint and this just a
screenshot of what that looks like
but probably which most he didn't know
where hopefully we should pay something
new about sharepoint it really started
back in nineteen eighty-five it was a
software package called a mere front
page one point of is anybody remember
that the old-timers in here and the
reason I bring it up the company was
called premier Technologies Incorporated
and there's this acronym vti and if you
worked with sharepoint you stuck--you
you'll see this VTS is so it's been
around it's been around a long time and
the reason is Microsoft ball front page
and then they rebranded its front page
and then it went through many years of
generations and enhancements in fact one
time Microsoft has had hundreds of
thousands of these front pages web sites
though at one point they said
let's put this into a package and then
later around 2,000 it became sharepoint
and it's gone through many different
generations to what it to what it is
today
now just again a little bit about the
architect easily you have in users that
play out
oh honey that time myself and users at
mcleod go through afar firewall will be
a couple of that maybe one or more front
and servers will talk to a back-end
servers and then we'll talk to get could
talk to the sequel database these this
this is what they refer to as a
sharepoint farm and that can be many
different ways this can be architect and
then if you're on the inside of the
firewall you have internal users and
talk to the front end and they do what
they do share . now the other thing i
want to point out is somewhat for those
who worked with windows and internet
information server if you've ever been
to their internet internet information
services and kind of browse and here
you'll start seeing this BTW a stuff and
this is today you still see these
acronyms or names called vti and this is
important because when i talk about
happy you're going to see this over and
over again
so what we'll get into more about the
hacking part but i just kind of found
this interesting this is a page from the
e details . com it shows up all the
vulnerabilities are currently found and
you can if you go to this web page and
then click on products you'll get a
search bar and if you is in that search
bar type of sharepoint server g-type
sharepoint you're not going
we'll get some some smaller this if you
type sharepoint server you'll get all
the vulnerabilities you can see how they
kind of program out
into different categories for each year
and then also broke them down into
different areas where there's a
vulnerability that the thing I would say
about these vulnerabilities SharePoint's
actually pretty secure
most of these vulnerabilities are really
coming out of Excel Word outlook and and
all these other tools attached to it
so who are the sharepoint hackers oh
thank you
first button so you want to share .
hackers well last year I was in a tight
i spoke here on power show and I said
who the hackers and few people raise
their hands
so how many people are hackers in it
nobody's with it but having our pin
testers that's when so much that was a
pen testers and then there's the dark
army who knows with the anybody with the
dark army is no there's a TV series
called mr. robot gotta watch that that
thing that is just an awesome awesome TV
series it just ended up the second
season yesterday but there's some really
good hackers in there but also the
sharepoint hackers are employees we have
we have to trust the employees and we
also given permission and anything but
actually we probably shouldn't give it
permission to do things because they can
taking damage sharepoint and then
there's developers we never want to
trust them but they can also hack the
system and the administrators they're
given the power to basically have
sharepoint so that so you have different
ways that this can be a hat now the
hacking methods for sharepoint that
there's several of 1 i'll just call
brute force and i'll give you some
examples of that and that's where you
just go in there either manually or ro
write a script and you start looking for
things that are wrong and sharepoint and
my favorite way to do that is using the
search engine
the search engine because in Google you
can type this type inurl colon and give
a last part of this extension right here
underscored layouts and view list and it
will show you all the websites that have
that in search now if you see that that
means those websites are anonymous and
and when it when i say anonymously if
you can
at that point you can go into sharepoint
and start browsing around two areas that
you're not really probably shouldn't be
looking at again I said SharePoint's
very it's a it's a very secure product
and where it fails is where people make
it anonymous and exposed to the outside
if it's on the inside it's not quite a
big quite a big deal and I am gonna give
you some examples of that now the other
way of doing it is using being and they
call it in stream and I don't think it
works quite as well but it can also
display some pages for you some of
hacking methods is a port scanning there
are a lot of services and endpoints and
sharepoint that you that you can attach
to and pull up and and what you want to
do is it is sharepoint is misconfigured
your servers will then be misconfigured
and i will talk more about that but it's
these port scans that you wanna run
through your network because in
sharepoint you don't want to just open
up everything you want to open up only
the port's the chair . needs which we'll
talk about we talk about protecting it
oh I and and that's what i was saying
here or uh then he wrecks external
sharepoint sites if your sharepoint is
not set up properly then your servers
are going to be easier to hack because
they're not gonna be set up properly and
then there's this to this website called
showed a in that if you go to this
showdown site it will it will also show
you all
all the servers in the world that are
showing up the showing sharepoint in the
in their descriptions so some of the key
things I search for is this extension
right here layouts you list
this is a big potential leak for data
because once you get in there you're on
their site you can search for vti band
again if you if you're seeing this
finish it's indicating this is an
anonymous site and you don't need any
credentials for logging in these other
variations in fact this was actually
real interesting if you say layout /
user dis dat aspx and force equals true
and then put an ID of zero it'll pull
back a user record it and once it pulls
it back you can in a full information
like their username their email address
their first and last name and just
general information that might be found
in the sharepoint profile and I've got a
script that will iterate through zero
through a hundred and and find although
the users on sharepoint site now I was
running through this haven't done this
top and when I was running the last
night or so and I what I have found is
Microsoft is actually tighten up their
security and some of these some of these
routines don't work as well as they used
to before patches were blood and then
you can also look for the frontpage
extensions and then these in points that
i was referring to and here's an example
of a where he's w get and we'll also
what i did i found some websites using
the view list and once i saw that once
those lister once was a sight show
I'll plug that site name in here and
then I do this w get and it'll download
all the documents basically actually in
this example it takes all the PDF
documents and all the sub directories
have sharepoint and a load them locally
to your disk drive or wherever you
choose to put them and this is that
powershell i was referring to earlier
where we can list all the data 1 through
X this is a function in powershell
basically where you can iterate through
the pages and then you pass the strength
to it here's the internet pages i
specify the site your own I say layouts
user ID is P . hey aspx and say one
through a hundred and then lists all the
users it finds one through a hundred i
was i was going to do a demo I then I
remember i'm going to hackers convention
and I don't really wanna expose myself
to the head to the network and if you've
ever liked to death if you have been to
DEFCON I mean I really don't recommend
you turn on your telephone
anyway this is an example i made i may
go ahead if we have time i may go ahead
and do some this but here's where I'm
going into google and then I type by in
your own and basically take this right
here and basically what it did its
listing all these sites that are
sharepoint sites and not only the
sharepoint sites are their anonymous so
if i do if i can click on any of these
like texas governor government i'm on
their sharepoint site in fact I on the
previous page i took one of those links
and clicked on it
and this is what I got so if you if you
sing sharepoint you know this is just a
SharePoint site i'm looking at all the
documents scripts templates images and
I'm on their site and that's kind of
pain to me that sounds really dangerous
because I go in here and click that sign
in and when i type that when i click on
sign in i can get a username password
prompt and at that point I've gone
through all the firewalls I've gone
through all the servers and now and now
i'm on the active directory answering a
username password problem and at that
point i can i can bring force usernames
and passwords
anyway that's um that was from this
previous site i mean when i did this
that you're all right there i click on
one of those links and then I got this
and for the most part you click on any
of those links and you you will see
sharepoint if I was if i wanted to
narrow it down further
I could put the last few letters like
Kim Il for military or government
government and then layouts and then I
see all the military installations that
have that extension is you
united states marine corps civilian
training army for the government
these are government sites like theirs
theirs earlier we saw Texas US Treasury
kind of scary that's and again all these
are anonymous sites that are being
pulled up and so here's an example i
clicked this the sign and when I did
that this was a charlotte county and i
got a username password prompt so I've
gone past all I've gone through all this
port
I mean all the firewalls I've gone
through all the servers and now i'm
talking to the active directory
so before I leave this one thing i would
suggest is whenever you set up anonymous
make sure you do it right and then also
you may not wanna be made you may want
to use some kind of other authentication
versus the Active Directory
authentication we use with the call
forms base
this right here is just a list of all
the different year olds that you can
search for it and what's interesting
about these girls are this there's many
different categories that you can look
at but like this first list of
categories these are all administrative
murals that you can search for and if
you can get to then you're actually
you're actually talking to the
SharePoint central admin and brush you
get here you're getting past a lot of
things this other this is SP disco i'm
not quite i'm a developer now but one
time this
these were web services or SharePoint
and . services like it i can access and
then after I can ask access and I could
I can then column pass parameter 2
parameters to it and then pull
information back or execute things and
when you when you do call it looks like
something like this again most of these
are functions that are being called and
so going back to this w get there's a
there's a windows w get that I've style
called gnu windows 32 and then I went on
there and execute that script and what I
did that Henry had something like this
and basically what it did that that site
that i went to it basically downloaded
all the PDFs from there once i got the
PS I can you know start
searching their documents for other
information that i want to leave him out
of it
this show day and sites kind of
interesting because this also will how
much time always done
okay all right well uh that uh let me
just summarize let's go down to the end
this was about protection i'll be
publishing these uh these uh the slide
deck and you know this information off
the slide deck that the final thoughts
is published your sharepoint correctly
make sure if you set up anonymous that
you lock it down make security a
priority within a sharepoint a pen test
your site in fact when you go back to
your office
make sure when you do that year old
thing make sure your site's don't show
up and if they do then you need to fix
it I wouldn't tell anybody
they showed up i fix it and then tell me
fix it and then also make sure your
latest patches are up-to-date on your
servers and with that we don't have time
for questions but thank you for coming
out today