repin la by Sarah thank you know this is
a sticker required to sign it
don't be jelly Joel sounds like you're
right you want to do this okay
hi everybody good morning I'm and I
managing need Herman and this is just a
normal and we're going to spend a little
bit of time talking this morning about
hacking in pop culture specifically gods
of geek mythology packing in popular
culture so in mass media journalism
hackers have been portrayed as these
sort of faceless boogieman they're
anonymous and more than one sense of the
word becoming sort of their own very
convenient plot device of vigilante
criminal or scapegoat or a sort of
modern-day folk devil with a very
well-known and stereotypical social
profile we all know this guy the hacker
their mail
they're white they're immature and
lacking in social graces or soft skills
resulting isolation many are overweight
live in their parents cave like
basements and are motivated by selfish
goals with hunger for power of chaos
and yet um entertainment media finds
hackers fascinating screen white writers
love introducing a hacker character and
wat because a hacker can create conflict
or save the day in one fell swoop in a
forceful compelling and believable way
that audiences except with the same sort
of mysterious and limitless power that
they would a witch or a wizard or a
dragon he accept their real at least
they're real in the audience's
perception so a mysterious and seemingly
limitless amount of power i want you to
think for a minute about the the
implications of that and we're going to
come back to that in just a minute but
for a little bit we're going to take a
closer look at some of the good the bad
and the ugly and film ok said the closer
look
we're gonna enhance enhance enhance
don't forget it and so we're pleased to
bring you the leet hacker profiles
confidential first one on one of my
favorites and her problem in your closet
starts was David Lightman for more games
in 1983 you guys have all seen the movie
i'm correct this is what I by I grew up
on wanting to be like so much more being
so fucking cool change your fuckin
school grades on your computer and ship
but David Lightman is a high school
student who connects is a few of his
classmates but he does connect with
attendees accompany college attendees
and also a girl in his class he finds
himself in trouble after looking for an
unrelated game looking for unreleased
games by war dialing and connecting to
the war operations plan response whopper
computer and almost starts world war
three with the Soviet Union who you guys
know about real genius the show real
genius you get a chance check it out
it's really great 1985 got tons of
montages from the eighties it's really
sweet but
this one Laszlo hollyfield a character
from there is a long-term student was
recluse school of geniuses he's smart
but he holds little social skills
probably know a few of us that might fit
that category
he leverages statistics and preset
content rules to win a vast majority of
major prizes and a snack food contest
this guy lives in a closet the past an
elevator that goes to the basement in a
school of geniuses and this is lhasa
hollyfield well to be fair it's a secret
lair that you access through a clock oh
yes yes that's just a closet Martin
Marty Bishop also known as bryce from
sneakers is another one of the
characters that we thought really sat
out and exemplified the hacker
stereotypes but this guy is more than SC
style he's the owner of a tiger team
security company with the team
specialized employees his main focus
appears to be in management social
engineering like I said he has a
previous long-term relationship and
several friends which you know make them
kind of well-balanced that he connects
with he gets in trouble with a few
unscrupulous people and you know maybe a
few nation states and finally was able
to come out ahead Dennis Nedry you guys
know this guy right
Jurassic uh-oh he's a computer
programmer jurassic park and due to
financial problems and low salary
sounds like a few people maybe not
getting the street in their organization
he accepted an offer from a competing
company to smuggle dinosaur DNA from his
employer he creates a backdoor program
that disables the park security so we
can escape without notice and of course
he gets eaten by the life source
zerocool from hackers I know this is a
staple of a lot of other people that got
their start you know he's a computer
whiz the aid of the age of personal
computers just getting started and after
getting coffee age of 11 he's court
ordered to have no contact with the
computers are touch-tone phones and as
1830 gets an opportunity once again to
jump in his computers and immediately
begins hacking only to find other people
are doing the exact same
and he jumps himself into the world of
hacking in new york city hack the planet
the planet Gibson trust your technical
lost all of those things
another one that kind of stable that I
can't grow up with but may not everyone
may not think of it as a hacker its of
course Michael Bolton wait Michael
Bolton Michael Bolton I mean is that his
actual name is an actual name just like
the ask on singers if you had my note in
fan
yeah move aside you guys get a chance of
funny or die did a skit with the real
Michael Bolton in several the scenes and
office space
it's very fucking good you should take a
look at that up so he's a program with
an attack working on a the year 2008 bug
and accounting software and a few other
programmers decide to frog the company
we're rounding transactions and stealing
differences only regret decision as he
might be going to the pound you in the
ass prison
yeah so next one is neo from the matrix
again from the nineteen nineties 99
thomas anderson also known as neo is an
item hackers always felt the world just
wasn't right and after meeting a few
unusual characters who finds out the the
world as he know is not old seems to be
it is an accepting that might mean
radical shift of perception so neo from
the matrix again this is kinda before he
kind of learns everything that his
environment exists daily jobson from
swordfish you guys remember this movie
right when he gets compelled to hack can
jump back in Stanley is out on parole
after hacking the IBM carnivore program
and is banned from using computers have
from being held at gunpoint Stanley is
thrusted back into hacking being forced
to support terrorism plots by creating a
worm or a possible losses daughter I
don't want to I don't want to get too
much off track here but i'm not sure if
the gun . was the most memorable part of
that
scene for me personally I so we move on
a like Halle Berry so acting has never
been not disputed on that so Elliot
Alderson from mr. robot is a cyber
security engineer hacker who suffers
from social anxiety disorder clinical
depression spends his time hacking in
private
lockpicking bag packing the private
lives of people around him and he meets
an anarchist who convinces him the best
thing would be to take down the largest
corporation in the world now mr. robot
has been praised over and over again as
being more authentic and real life in
his portrayal of its the exploits but we
kind of included him because he does fit
some of the closer stereotypes both in
his wearing of the hoodies and the mass
persona that him and his crew get kind
of fun adopt Lisbeth Salander with a
girl with dragon tattoo
she's a blackjack with unique skills and
great demand corporations she gets hired
to find information she uses a unique
talents to assist an underground
political journalist by an anonymously
leaving information about political
figures on the reporters machine
ok so wait a minute those profiles they
don't fit the hacker stereotype at all
I mean that's what that's what the bar
graph was supposed to be for all the bar
graphs were supposed to show really low
marks that they all had poor physique
and and that they were mature and they
had bad social skills and they were all
wicked so why why does the route
why don't the research results show that
what we're going to cover
ok so it's definitely true that some of
those hackers and film fit into the
stereotype but when we started this
research I was really expecting that
they were going to adhere to it a little
bit more i thought that that's where the
stereotype came from so if it didn't
come from film where did they come from
is a serious i was likely grew out of a
mishmash of understand misunderstood
nerd culture from somewhat closer
academia and the scientists and
engineers who are some of the first to
use computer technology wisely and also
to the hardcore gamers bent on BTW
the latest conquest or boss ok but one
thing is for sure that Hollywood is not
the source of the perpetuation of this
myth or the stereotype though it's
certainly guilty of creating some Sal we
shall we say amped-up visualizations
that do not accurately portray exploits
in a more realistic sense their little
bit more flashy than real exploits to
say the least
we see those in the hack in conclusion
of the hackers movie
Hugh Jackman's cubes and swordfish and
countless other films and shows
historically realistically exploits
aren't exciting to the average Joe views
viewer because they simply don't
understand what's happening and what's
up and why what reasons
Hollywood has tended us to create an
amped-up visualizations for the perfect
of dramatic effect
no more different than a police car
chases in favorite site heist movies
okay but that's true across a variety of
different industries as you just
mentioned with the heights I mean how
many times have we seen a bank robbery
in a film when in reality the amount of
times the bank has been robbed with a
dramatic shootout are something you
could count on one hand in the history
of our country
um what's of concern is this overarching
across-the-board characterization of
hackers as this all-powerful unbeatable
techno wizard with seemingly limitless
amounts of power
have you ever heard that old saying that
locks only keep honest people out
ok so guess what your average Joe user
that's what they think about your
security protocols because they
you're up against this guy and
particularly considering the majority of
Americans that are living today reached
adulthood without ever having any
contact with anything like what we
consider to be a modern personal
computer
I mean maybe they used a graphing
calculator or a slide rule or an ATM but
nothing like the laptop that i'm using
right now or my smartphone i mean
remember we went to the moon with a
computer that had a less sophisticated
system than the smartphone that is in
your pocket right now and the average
user doesn't have much more
understanding of the inner workings of
how that technology works or how to
control it then they do a witch or
wizard or a dragon so what does that
mean as a blue team information security
professionals we must experience a
tremendous amount of frustration from
users not following protocol particular
because their experience with hacking is
limited to what they see in their
screens that that we basically feed them
and has digested by the press and the
Hollywood the press tells them that
hackers are responsible for all kinds of
crime even though it's not necessarily
an accurate labeling sarah palin's email
getting hacked
ok this guy did not get into sarah
palin's email because of his amazing
technological powers
um you know not to overstate my
intelligence but I could do the kind of
research that this guy did and I'm not
an information technology security
professional he got in by using
Wikipedia to look up the answers to her
security questions i'm not saying that
that's not still dishonest but it's
nothing like an all-powerful
technological wizard with limitless
power who can hack no matter what you do
that they saw on TV and average Joe user
could thwart an attack like this by
simply choosing a more difficult to
obtain and tell that dude they do not
release on the security questions or
generate fictitious information that
they put for their security questions
what is the press do it they partially
due to create clickbait hysteria for the
equivalent of selling newspapers looking
for the next link in reading the the
refresh on the screen but probably at
least partially because the same
legitimate lack of understanding that
plagues their readers they need to dumb
it down to the fifth-grade reading level
the hacking stereotype the techno wizard
is just more than irritating campy and
accurate and it creates a culture which
undermines the authority of the blue
team community making it more easily for
public to fall prey to security threats
after all if the evil haxorus can
compromise your computer after 30
seconds of pounding on a keyboard
no matter what you do what is the point
of following security protocol and these
average so users who have bought into
this myth that they are powerless
against hackers they are not just the
corporate environment users who make our
blue team ursday today cleanup duties a
busy work living hell
they're your lawmakers and they are busy
compromising national security and
making overly vague laws without a
significant understanding of real life
hacking in an age where it's so much
more with an age where so much more
under threat because it's not the state
anymore it's our personal information or
financial assets are cars or energy
distributions are critical
infrastructure and our state secrets
different hackers a nation states have
never been more dangerous or the
information more valuable or more
powerful as an industry so what's the
point the point is the next time you
grumble about hacker stereotypes I want
you to think about this talk and I want
you to remember that I know that this
one is insulting
it hurts your feelings it hurts your ego
but this one
this one is much much more damaging in
terms of how it is shaping the world
that we live in and the legal climate
which will prosecute cyber crimes in the
future thank you questions any message
on
I don't know if everybody can hear
Charles James I don't know if everybody
can hear James I knew it was a British
king
I don't everybody in here James but the
question that James just asked was isn't
the infosec community part of the
problem because when we see a major hack
happen a lot of the things that we see
happen over and over again in the news
is that beeping big companies were
compromised using like basic stuff that
we all know so comfy got hacked and what
happened was maybe that they had a bunch
of default passwords and hoops hackers
got in
honestly I think that it lies down to it
at all but a disconnect between our blue
team or just our IT departments and the
aight guarantee security side you know
we have we come here to conferences but
there are you know hundreds of thousands
of other professionals that are not here
they're not continuing to try to learn
about best practices and how to improve
how to make small measurable changes the
last training that they were kind of
involved when was when they went from
novell to active directory in two
thousand there they are not following
you know removing different ciphers and
and cleanup passwords and checking for
common hashes you're so mean
so I think the short answer is yes I
mean absolutely the community can def
we improve and be smarter and be better
and be more diligent but as long as your
average Joe user believes that no matter
what they do they're gonna get hacked
as long as they have this this belief in
their own paralysis
it's not that they aren't scared of
threats it's not that they are capable
of figuring out like hey maybe i should
use answer security questions that
aren't available widely on wikipedia
it's not that they can't figure that out
it's that they're still paralyzed by
their own fear of hackers that they
can't they can't take that step
it's not something that they feel like
they can't even protect against so the
escalade that to Horry change that to a
home invasion or something of that
nature they may put minor protections in
place but today every time make sure
that they put their car in the drive and
in lakhs only keep honest people out in
there in the garage so people don't want
her driving by are aware that their home
or not home such as your question James
thank you
yes he just made the comment that the
many of the techniques that we're
learning out in these hallways at this
conference will only keep honest people
out and the true black hat hackers have
access to technology and strategies that
are above our capability of defending
against I think that's what you said
when I think our defense ability does
directly depends on the capabilities of
the blue team side and yeah there are we
we are in a global world so you can face
people with extreme talent on the far
end of the spectrum but most case we are
not the people in this room are not
techno Wizards we just have diligence
and are willing to look for flaws and
system but for the most part the evil
acts towards in cyberspace are not
technical lizards either even though
that's totally what i saw in the movie
swordfish
monitoring they're not dogs cracked
yes their gods in the mythology but only
in the mythology it's a legend
yes well i think the other problem on
the other side of the spectrum is that
there are large companies that
perpetuate this but it is marketing
technique to get in and then that's
verging on the other end all day I talk
to these security guys I thought this
company in red is so over whoa you know
if you eventually his comment was that
many large corporations who are trying
to sell snake-oil solutions prey upon
this public belief in this stereotype
for the purpose of making money and
you're absolutely right they do it for
the same reason that that the press does
it
the press is trying to sell newspapers
and oh yeah their job is kind of to
inform us this day and age we demand
that they entertain us as well and one
of the things that we find most
entertaining is being frightened even
when you know some of that fright is not
correctly directed or is not based on
totally factual information properly
attributed their properly attributed um
you know that's exactly what that's
exactly the sort of thing you're looking
at there so that's a very astute
parallel yes you're absolutely right
anyone else yet go ahead so true he was
just talking about a comparison between
lead actors lead characters protagonist
or antagonist so villains or heroes vs.
there either the team around them or the
people are hacking against i think a
really good example of that is the movie
sneakers if this had been a longer talk
we definitely would have profile the
entire team such a dynamic cast of
characters really really interesting
characterizations to look at their a the
movie hackers actually would've been a
really good one to do multiple character
profiles profiles as well I think
there's a lot of really interesting
culture there in the movie sneakers
um Martin bar
I smart Marty bishops team I wouldn't
have scored as high on the bar graph
matrix as he would have at in terms of
beating a hacker stereotype Marty Bishop
does very very well versus I'm
struggling here dan Aykroyd character
don't call the character named well but
i mean he he discusses how his wife left
him because he was playing too much
computer hacker stuff there's also River
Phoenix's character whose social skills
are so lousy as cute as he is his social
skills are so lousy that when he has the
opportunity to make a demand everybody
else is making outrageous demands he
demands a cute girls phone number
because apparently this is the only
opportunity he's going to have to get
one that's that's sad
she was pretty hot I mean she's
definitely cute
any other questions thank you so much
for your indulgence we appreciate it