great well i'm gonna go ahead and get
started is pretty much about two o'clock
so i just start out so you know we've
all had that you know that point where
we work and securities interesting saw
this is a talk that was about 45 minutes
talking trying to jam it into a stable
talk so so this the long story short is
when I your insecurities you're on your
ear hearing your software in your group
and you get an alert and you go
immediately you jump into in into
instant response you're determining the
cause and it turns out to be that
missing patch or that outdated
application it's still out there or
maybe just bad configuration that you
can you say and what happens when this
goes on indefinitely one of your
co-workers of one of my co-workers will
say oh my gosh only opposite just done
their job and patch that machine and fix
that configuration we wouldn't have this
problem and be sitting here doing this
response for like you know eight hours
or twelve hours or however long
uh-huh however long it took and how many
guys have ever said that I heard anyone
say that just just wanting a couple yeah
so um you know what happens in that you
know occurs is lot of times i've already
gotten no ops and I'm eventually you
know after everything is calm down
wander over and reach be talking to them
and their sit there griping about
security that how security is always
yelling at them and complaining about
option complaining how bad offices and
that security just says expect opposite
fix all their problems that security has
a top should be fixing and so suddenly
both sides since the other group is
completely incompetent and as a result
neither group can work or will work each
other will work with each other and how
many sound that sounds million where you
work now or places you work in the past
yeah so um you know we've all lived
through this and we've all are living
through this and so on i decided to try
and do a little bit of talk about what
i've $FULLPHONENUM what i've seen has
caused this problem and some of the
methods I've seen that help resolve this
problem and
basically calling security a and
operations bridging the gap so just a
little bit about me I've been about 15
years in infosec I've done a variety of
jobs in information security
I'm i got some great letters after my
name that means something somebody I'm
and generally my biggest problem that I
that the things i want to do or flat
vastly greater than the time I have to
do them in on but you know what ideally
when you know you have these two groups
is that they really should be working
out together but arm often the problem
is that they're barely civil toward each
other while they're harboring some kind
of deep respect and disrespect or
outright contempt toward each other and
so at best we have a tenuous line of
communication and cooperation one that
really can break at any any moment and
what was interesting is that a talks
earlier in this conference of I both
Carlos Perez and Jason Street mentioned
that the that this communication is the
one of the critical things on that needs
to happen between operations and
security
so what are some of the reasons for this
friction well I believe that there are
both fundamental issues that are going
on on and some technical issues that are
causes divided and so to really uh talk
about how do we build this bridge
between these two groups let's just
start a first with the fundamentals
so first the first fundamental that we
have to really go over is bad staff
structure and so what do I mean by that
on what i mean by bad staff structures
we have a repeat we have two long lines
of authoritative of communication that
go way up before their two sides
actually talk to each other and it
and so these two groups are stovepipe
they operate not on an isolation and
this really causes problems between
communication between notifications and
coordination between the two groups and
so what happens is since one group
doesn't actually have to talk to the
other group on they often leave the
other group a decisions that affect both
groups so this causes resentment and
friction and this especially happens in
places without strong leadership that
direct or demand or require that kind of
a coordination between the two of them
it also this kind of structure also
presents a sari prevents resolution of
disagreements you know like 12 kids
disagree i'm an arbitrator usually a
parent or guardian is close by but in
this case you know how long are far too
options security have to go to get
resolution it takes you know escalation
escalation escalation and the longer and
further that is the less likely things
will be brought up to be resolved and so
again conflict and resentment build up
on another challenge is when on security
and compliance or bundled together and
many industries compliances is critical
to meet regulations but the problem
comes when compliance tasks are placed
into the security team and security is
viewed now as compliance and once
compliance has met no one feels the need
to do any more security and we know
compliance is not the same as security
so how do we fix these two things well
first we need to change your step
uh so sorry fix these two things so
first we need to change our staff
structure by moving the junction between
the two groups lower into the hierarchy
we can do this physically or we can do
this virtually with the CCB or some kind
of single manager of but most
importantly that Junction needs to be
some so have some kind of authoritative
a capability this Junction doesn't
always replace it does not replace
direct communication between the two
groups at the bottom but I it does allow
for shorter of shorter try
full time for resolution for
communication for coordination where
when one group had it feels like their
priorities don't match up the request of
the other group and allows for a shorter
time period to work those things out
the second thing we need to do is move
compliance out of security security ops
should work together to be compliant but
with the compliance is integrated in
security and often prevents an objective
viewpoint by compliance to truly audit
what security is doing and what ops are
doing to meet the regulations or the
compliance requirements of the
organization and so if it's a-so its
integrated again it's hard for them to
be objective
the second issue the second fundamental
issue that are often causes conflict is
that the goals are thought are our
thoughts are bogging ille operations
once things to work they value uptime
functionality through put security on
the other hand we value what our
namesake says security protection
authorization authentication permissions
validations verifications but not
necessarily restrictions because I think
we need to view security as we want to
authorize people who have authorized
access to perform authorized activity
all the time
the challenge is the road to achieving
these two goals isn't always in parallel
and a large effort needs to be put forth
to make to achieve the achieve that kind
of cooperation that kind of operational
of conduct capability so not pressing my
slides here sorry
so the suggestion really then is to that
working together requires that kind of
court coordination cooperation and some
compromise management really needs to
get involved needs to provide the
guidance and set priorities for the
entire for both groups so that they know
what they need to go what understand
their level of risk that the
organization is a
is ready to accept so that both groups
have that kind of the those boundaries
to operate within so they know where
they can go know what they can ask of
the other group and know when they kind
of need to go through and get a
exceptions also operation and security
need to align their efforts with the
organization's mission and goals for
instance if you're running store and
your advertising the fact that you have
the fastest checkout times faster than
your competitors and insecurity comes
along and adds a step to that process is
that really in line with the company's
goals it's not going to get a it's going
to have a very hard time getting that
approved if it really has a chance at
all so creating an operationally secure
environment takes a lot of time and
effort i'm not saying that this is easy
or simple or one-step process but it is
a that it has to be a focused continual
effort so the third fundamental issue is
really the question of who's doing what
and this comes down to a lack of
guidance on a lack of the policy that
are referred to as the last in the last
point on one of the first things is does
each group have their own procedures for
the same situation and you know for
server goes down and the security team
runs off and they say oh my gosh we got
to see if it was a security incident was
this some kind of it on they start going
into a little bit of their incident
restocked response procedures
meanwhile options running off saying
well we got to get the server backup and
so you know options trying to free you
know to troubleshoot the the crash
trying to restart the services there on
you know they're installing or
uninstalling on patches and and software
and applications and you know security
is over here trying to get logs and
maybe it's a vm so ops just goes you
know goes revert and suddenly I
securities gone what the heck just
happened to my logs and so they're
stepping all over each other both trying
to do their jobs because there they have
different uh
a proper procedures for the same
situation so on and so they're all the
challenge that comes in is there may be
confusion over reporting and and
responsibilities taken that same server
situation security may be reporting that
as an incident because they feel hey
this is something that's wrong and in so
now you have an incident response report
you have it's going up through that
channel but meanwhile options just
saying oh it's a downtime thing you know
so it's another tick on the down time
maybe that's reportable maybe it's not
suddenly each of those reports each of
those uh follow-throughs and follow ups
are generating different kinds of
responses from management on and who's
stepping on who's who's supposed to give
what information who and that's causing
a additional confusion so on one of the
examples of from my from my organization
was we had a we had a new tool that was
a that something could it was doing a
really good job at detecting down adword
downloads just from your browser from
going to browsers and so we're like hey
this tool can you do auto remediation
can you know detect it go but we're just
wiping it out this minute we detected
well we didn't really have there was no
actual uh policy or procedure in place
to to do to do that auto removal and
while both sides and that in that
situation said yet that makes sense
it took a long time to actually get
those procedures in place to find the
right person to sign off on that to get
both sides to agree on for something
that everyone agreed yeah we probably
should just auto remove that stuff
because it shouldn't be there
and now that we have a good capability
let's just turn that on and so it's that
top cover that policy cover that was in
place prior to that so that goes right
into this suggested solution which is
armed designating roles and
responsibilities and developing SOPs so
that those SNP's are they're ready for
you
to apply to situations as they come up
but the other important part of sops and
and policies that aren't written out is
that you need to also have a methodology
for those situations that don't meet
something that's already written so how
to handle the exceptions have a handle
on those odd situations that may not may
fall out of scope with what is already
in place so now that you've gotten your
your fundamental issues that we talked
about the fundamental fundamental issues
of pillars really are there how do we
really build the bridge how do we build
that on the things that really now
smooth the communication between the two
groups on so one of the first things
that is just a well-worn path that
always seems to come up it is the
constant of a disagreement over scanning
and patching and security figurations I
you know how this works security does a
vulnerability scan they're doing a full
ability assessment and they basically
take the results bundle them up wrap
them up there over the wall and say ops
could you fix all that and then the next
week they come back to run the same skin
to look at and go up they still haven't
fixed it and they bundle it up throw it
over there again on and meanwhile
options on the other saying of options
on the other hand gun you know why you
yelling at us about this you know what
what they always the same old story the
same old thing these things are critical
on you know that particular
configuration breaks the application on
you know and you know both you know the
other thing i heard a lot when i talk to
cops people that you know security every
time they come over about a
vulnerability about a configuration they
just all they do is they just basically
they just talk down to us they just
condescending like you know don't you
know how to do this it's so small it's
so easy you should know how to do this
and the ops hates that Nate once they
start hearing that tone coming from
security they just go you know what I
don't hear them they're going to talk
down to me like I'm a first-year admin
and you know I don't want to talk to
them
so uh you know we really need to stop
that kind of cycle on and figure out how
to really make this work a better for us
so the first thing and I that we should
that we should everyone should have and
understand it sometimes resources are
challenging but i'm going to talk about
it several times that really building
and using testbed I mean a testament is
really going to save your your your
capabilities your ability to work
together as an environment
l just a lot and I'm going to repeat
that several times now whatever testbed
you can build build it if it if it
emulates you know one server and one
workstation in your 2500 the device
environment okay at least you have
something something to at least rollout
you know patches and configs and do some
kind of testing but with nothing then
your test basically becomes your
operational environment we know with
this has been said before that is not a
good thing to use your op environment as
your test fit we're not Microsoft so
that's an old joke they don't do that
anymore but as much alright so developed
a test plan for patching into for
patching and configuration changes so
you can deploy patches and make config
changes in an environment so that it
doesn't impact your users or your
customers and so that uh and so that
you're able to determine the operational
impact of the security impact of the
changes prior to rolling them out the
second thing you need to do need to do
is review as security what we need to do
is your view and prioritize the patches
that are that are that we found to be
deficient arms just let stopped on the
whole bundle over the wall and expecting
ops to fix everything
so let's take the time to review what
was found and prioritize what needs to
be patched and protected we do that with
whatever intelligence we can gather what
are what we know they are advertised at
what we know our advertisers well we
know our adversaries thereafter and what
vulnerabilities that are currently being
exploited on and so this means really
communicating with operations so that
they understand why one week we may all
be all up in arms
about the ph CP vulnerability on the
customer facing a server and the next
week we're screaming about microsoft
macros that are hitting HR so there you
know we don't without context they just
think security is being on a multi
personality a schizophrenic and so uh
but we provide them like hey look we
noticed this is going on here they
understand what's going on and so we
have to temper that so provide them
context and priority on the the things
that we find the deficiencies also
provide suggestions on fixing the
problem on if you idea identify problem
within ops or within the areas of their
responsibilities engage with them to
find a solution for example of you know
a lot of times vulnerability scanners
will just say hey you're Adobe's two
revisions behind for that you know their
options going on well i know i deployed
the patch so you have to help work with
them to find out which version applies
to wishing machine and sometimes even
what profile directory on that machine
the vulnerability scanner maybe maybe
targeting sometimes I vulnerability
scanner just looks for certain dll with
a certain version on the entire CD drive
and it's hidden in some directory that
ops you know that that some install put
somewhere that ops doesn't know about to
help me figure that out on and then
finally help them develop alternative
mitigations we all know that there are
some applications and some
configurations and some things in the
environment that we just that just have
to be that way to help them to develop
work with them to develop things that
still protect uh what needs to be
protected
uh while you know even though we can't
change the primary issue
um OH finally when things do improve
make sure ops kicks credit for what they
did not just say hey look we made this
place place better by beating up on ops
until they did what we said no but when
everyone has a stake in done fixing the
problem
everyone has buy into the fine
solution and everyone should get the
kudos for the second technical problem
to overcome really is when ops employees
new servers or new capabilities arm and
that deployment is being driven fast and
then securities comfortable with or even
without securities knowledge you know
that just happens you know you're
monitoring your firewall and you're like
whoa what's this traffic coming from
this IP I don't even know about you call
up pops and they're like oh that's the
new management server for the ipad you
going a what server be what iPads so uh
you know but a lot of times those things
are not you know the opposite and so to
wake up and one morning and decide to
just put the server on basically
somebody came down from on high and said
I want this I want it now and make it
happen and offices scrambling to meet a
customer or management requirements and
so we we're seen on you know we're
seeing as basically the holdup because
rolled up business were holding up
progress and holding up customer
requirements on so this is again a great
a situation that really builds up uh
build up in foster resentment and
frustration between the group to group
so how do we limit this damage well a
couple things first
again test that uses a lot you know use
it to ops and make sure that what
they're getting works in the way that
they wanted to insecurity can perform a
reasonable security evaluation to
determine how to monitor activity how to
secure the device and the two of them
work together so that actually works a
works in a manner that needs to that
meets the requirement then this is where
a good CCB good configuration control
board or whatever you want to call it is
really gold because you're able to bring
down if you do this right op spring
security in as early as possible into
the problem the process of deploying
these new things deploying these tools
or or application for our changes and so
the CCB really should ensure that all
parties that need to be involved are
tied into the life cycle from
requirements planning to engineering to
deployment to retirement on and so each
party has their input and can work
toward a common solution and so I want
to also say that part of that common
solution is making sure she's security
understands the problem that Ops is
trying to solve I've seen security put
so many restrictions on a new
application or new system that ops can't
actually use it to do what they wanted
to do well now you've just wasted a
whole lot of ops money and a whole lot
of ops time to solve nothing on and so
again resentment on and what are the
other thing that happens is you end up
with shadow IT those things that uh
customers and a officer whoever start
doing on the side that you don't know
anything about because they need to get
their job done so we also just real
quick need to acknowledge that there are
times and when the requirement for new
Apple system is comes to hot so high or
so much we needed that you just have to
roll it out and this is again where you
have to work with ops to understand
what's going on
get whatever a thing is they're out in
deployed yet be able to work with them
so you can come from behind and say okay
now that we've got it out there let's
figure out how to secure it how and
doing it in a manner that still meets
the requirement or still gets the thing
job done so the final technical
challenges when security to supply a
security that's when we decide to
implement new tools or new process and
so we're doing we're stoked about this
whoo hoo more security more tools more
bells and whistles more blinky lights
more things in clothes off and protected
all op ceases more things breaking more
customers calling more you yelling from
on high because something isn't working
so what do we do to resolve this again
test fit on it from our site we when we
want this we gotta get our ops involved
earlier in the planning the big thing is
if we can eat our own dog
food on you know we we deployed a new uh
host-based security system are not hbss
something completely different but
that's a number on but we you know and
so we made sure that that client was
deployed to our machines first now the
other thing when you eat your own dog
food
don't take shortcuts around it you know
we do you really have to make sure you
emulate the user we like for instance
who uses no script on in your browser
you know those of you do or something
similar you know we're perfect line
gonna allow that don't allow that you
know and clicking that nine times very
very wait webpage that we go to
well guess what your users don't like
that they don't want they want you know
they don't want to click anything we
want to just go so if you know so make
sure we evaluate in the mindset of the
users when we either on dog food and
then do a phased implementation so that
you can roll it back quickly or get it
back it out something bad is going on so
I'm pretty much out of time so i'm not
going to go through my additional tips
but i do want to wrap up by saying that
really uh want to thank a couple people
talk to Jason Street I talk to young
lady named k and co worker Brian who
really helped by providing some
additional input into this and then uh
the key to all these solutions is
communication both Jason and Carlos
Perez talk about when the two groups
even when the two groups are hostile to
each other on humble communication will
break through that hostility making sure
that both groups understand that they're
on the same team and there were and that
working together makes everyone looks
good on once that happens that really is
what starts to lower the barriers that
ends helped start the process to
building the bridge so that's my talk if
you have any questions we may have a
couple minutes for questions arm so yes
right thing ever i have not I hadn't
really heard of that but that's a good
idea
write it down so we so yes require so
the scorecard is such you know doesn't
have doesn't carry a punishment but it
does carry reward
I like that that's good so one more
alright last one yeah so one of the
things that's more than some operations
something so try to find somebody in the
office on that has an interest towards
your pasta that they can help foster
that relationship building right there
okay cool alright well thanks appreciate
that thanks