i guess i can start whenever no one
really gave me a heads-up or anything so
i'm chris lopez bein my talks really
about my childhood hacking adventures
and how I grew up packing diablo 2 i'm
going to talk a lot about diablo 2 um
there's way more involved with this but
first I'm gonna tell you a little bit
about myself and my professional
experience and that sort of thing so
really who I am I like right now this
quote really sums up my life and I'm
actually going to read it to you
I'm learning to understand rather than
immediately judge or to be judged i
cannot find sorry I'm not used to
speaking with a mic like this i cannot
blindly follow the crowd and accept
their approach
I will not allow myself to indulge in
the usual manipulating game roll clip
roll creation
fortunately for me my self knowledge has
transcended that that and I have become
to understand that life is best to be
lived not to be conceptualized I'm happy
because I'm growing daily and honestly
not knowing where the limit lies to be
certain everyday there can be a new
revelation or new discovery at church
their memory of the past misfortunes has
added more to my bank of 42 that's kind
of like my monitor on life right now and
so really I'm a Red Team guy like I've
always been breaking things that's
always what I've been interested in i
just kind of fell into it when I was
younger so and I get really excited when
i bypassed things like recently bypass
silence and I think my exact words were
f yeah dad censoring the language there
since I know we have younger people in
the room and Joe yeah I'm really a gamer
first like the reason I got into hacking
was from playing video games and I'm
getting like a lot of the games that I
played throughout the years and kind of
the different concepts i was introduced
to and what's leading up to what I'm
doing now
so like clouds building their hardcore
gamer because they're sent home playing
xbox a lot i used to be a professional
gamer and I played like 18 hours a day
so it takes a lot of work like 10 people
don't really view playing video games as
work but you're actually doing it
professionally like you have to play
every day it's in your contract a lot of
people don't get that dealer so I'm a
hacker second really that was from you
know playing video games and start
learning about different acts within
video games and then start actually
hacking the video games and just start
started to hack people that were playing
the games and seeing all the items and
stuff
so you know I can pretty much a Gibson
my professional experience couple
different companies and I worked for
discover trust my spot allows an interim
they're doing on their vulnerability
assessment in developing their
vulnerability scanner and MasterCard did
some consulting there i'm currently at a
grocery store chain called snoops in the
st. Louis area but I'm not here
representing them today so i kinda going
to go into like a little bit of my
gaming escapades and like really
everything started out with Dawson like
I'm sure plenty of people in the room
remember this and actually installing
daus games
does anyone know what this game is ok
one person that seen my talk before just
admires pirates you know you've probably
heard of it before civilization that's
pretty big game series but I started out
really like playing pirates and stuff
it's just really cool game there wasn't
any like hacking stuff that we did with
it but you know I was like my first
introduction to computers was installing
games and boss like already familiar
with command line and doing that sort of
thing that's why I was preached that's
so important so you know then we got
into like were Crafton i started
learning about things like map pack and
that sort of thing that they actually
are hacks for games and that you can
kind of cheat at him and you know
learning about cheat codes and stuff
like that another game we played was
team fortress classic this is when we
really learn like you could actually
like script things within games and like
instantly build uh you know it hurt or
something like that and upgrade it
really quickly so far craft same sort of
thing like map pack if you look at this
map the mini-map in the bottom left hand
corner you'll see that everything is
actually revealed and that's because of
like this is a screenshot whenever using
that back and so you know one of the
first things I kind of learned about in
terms of like Jackson games and how you
can gain a competitive advantage from
that and Socko deeper into that more
about starcraft and then no diablo was
really like the big game but first game
that like really started like getting
more into the acts of like you know
everything was third sub client-side so
you could like get any item you want and
everything with your character for
anyone played the original Diablo you
guys know what I'm talking about
but now really the habla to is my was my
bread and butter of what
I got into hacking or how I got into
hacking rather and so like when we first
started off playing diablo 2 huh you
know mostly it's like I wanted to be
rich in this game and play in these
rooms called Paula PK which was like if
you're a paladin and I was like a pvp
channel and room so you could join up in
the game and the return events and stuff
like that if you played all the time and
you really needed have like the best
gear to compete in there so the whole
thing was like we're trying to get rich
to compete in like these little peepee
tournaments or rooms and so we did a lot
of screaming and stuff like that like
there's certain places in diablo where
you can like drop an item behind like a
stand like this and then i can actually
pick up from the other side so he would
do a lot of that and like even classic
spamming on battlenet like a blizzard
employees I'm your CD key and stuff like
that or like in your account information
then we started to meet more people
through aim all things and so we got
connected with these a little attackers
community and this guy started teach us
how to find item duplication methods
like all right it's gonna be awesome
like will do all these items you know
get all the 2020s OJ's and you know
we'll be rich I'll be able to get all
the items that we want and then compete
in this BP stuff so we learn about like
mousepads map pack and the thing we
ended up doing with mousepads map pack
was like super funny but I'm not gonna
get into that yet i'm going to focus
more on some of the item duplication
methods that we had with my brother and
I personally found my other ones that
actually wrote uh you know the little
program for it in the end that was
written bb or whatever it was back then
but you know we were apart and active
part of those hackers community and
we're actually an admin and you know
we've been there since 2002 where some
of the people that ran it you know the
name is redacted here but that actually
is our account so really like we're the
ones that did fine like the infamous
charsi and Boop and so like what you
would do essentially is just walk up to
char c get some information
drop your item get some information from
that and then interact with charts again
and plug all that information back end
and so really like whenever you look at
this like we were really just kids
playing with numbers like you know it's
simple as like finding charsi so you
need to find the idea of Charles II more
lols exes are that would be charges ID
every time and so there's a program
called you to hack at a bunch of hackers
already wrote to reverse-engineer the
diablo 2 protocol and so you can just
drop an item and then you can see all
the packets since they had figured
everything out and all the data
structures down and I so it's really
cool you know you just like Ramsey to
hack you click on chart see that you
found the idea of chart see you drop
your item you pick it back up you get
the item of the ID and then you go to
char C and you send the same in boot
packets and just replace the X's and
disease and it was simple as that
you know you would have the item would
be in the boo and then another one would
drop on the ground so you just did that
over and over again and that's how we
got rich we can finally can be allocated
lpk like awesome you know I can finally
have one of the best characters in there
and and you know be one of the best few
beers in diablo 2 and that was it went
well for a while but you know there's
there's certain aspects these things
that you don't think about and was it
can actually track all this so like
whenever you play diablo 2 hardcore like
a common thing was like you get the
windows be a key back in the day and you
get stuck and then you die and then like
whenever you lose on hardcore mode your
character is dead you lose everything
game over
and so like what blizzard did to us up
like patching the chart she do they
removed all the duplicate items from
battle net and so then you know it was
like we hit the Windows key and playing
hardcore and you know we're back to back
to squared 0 and so like this one are we
starting a different approach and we met
with the guys from the mall before and
afters them we can go on google and
shout about security but we started
looking at you know Trojans like net
double and we're also admins on blues
hackers so we got this idea there's map
pack there's all these other hacks that
everyone uses the play diablo 2 weather
like you're trying to do more nefarious
stuff like me or just play the game
doesn't like just no one played that
game without map pack siren was getting
that back and arrow was getting a
getting the link to map pack from blizz
hackers well guess what I was the person
providing that link and if you ever went
to was hackers and down
the map pack from the links that we
posted up there these are like this
whenever we got introduced to critters
and binders and so we had an
undetectable version of net double-ought
that was buying it with every hack that
came out and so every new hack that came
out we're the ones being notified since
we were part of that community we post
up and say hey like get your hacks from
here and we would have mousepads website
on there there be a couple geo city
sights in there you probably avoid those
so like they were download map pack from
our site and we will get a message on if
anyone remembers icq we get their IP and
this is whenever network address
translation didn't exist yet so like
everyone's just plug straight into their
cable modem has 56 k whatever it may
have been back in those days and so
super funny we would probably change and
connect up and really using like Proctor
Chainz as a metaphor here not the actual
tool proxy chains itself is not only
used but but anyway like to practice
exchange connect up you know they'd be
playing diablo we shut down the elbow to
get their password we change it to
something else would steal all their
items transfer over to our account and
then we lock them out the accounts and
we just did that over and over again all
day i have stories of like when friends
came over and like like an eighth grader
a freshman in high school and like maybe
it was like the first time after us like
partying and the next morning i'm
sitting there just like hacking gobble
two accounts my buddy's like wait are
you hacking people right now like yeah
like it's super easy like I just going
to download this and then I just take
all their stop basically because I'm
keylogging everything that they do
they're logging into your account
like that's how we primarily got rich
and like really profited in diablo 2
that was very successful and you know we
never really told me the police hackers
people about this because we weren't
being very nice lady called social
engineering but really I was just being
a huge dick have you want to be asked
with it like everyone says like social
engineering is like almost time you're
just abusing people's trust and I can
call it social engineering you want to
but really just kind of being mean
certainly like what most people think is
like you know in this scenario like I
would have just like profit or not but
what successful know is like get to fail
a bunch of times and you only learn from
failure
I
you know you don't really learn too much
success so we failed a bunch like we
lost all of our items over and over
again but we didn't give up and we got
more creative and more nefarious so it's
kind of like transition away from like
the Diablo hacking days i was really
involved with this game called delta
which defense of the ancients and so
like I did actually used to play for
evil genius in this game I played the
original map for like I'm one of the
people has been around the DOTA
community longer than anyone like i used
to talk to I strong and you'll daily
which of the people that I strikes the
guy that made dota2 with valve and
everything it's just a huge game noun
have actually opted to go to the
International which is like a 20 million
dollar tournament for dota instead of
DEFCON the past two years but this is
the original map and i was one of the
best players ever at this specific map
but then it came out with a new one and
so some of the stuff like methods that I
came up with i'm not actually going to
play these videos due to time
constraints but some of the methods that
we came up with my team back then like
create blocking and pulling and stuff
like that were the ones that kind of
invented all that and now I you know
people at these 20 million dollar
tournaments actually still employ these
methods today so it's really cool to see
that like we're the ones I kind of came
up with these unique ideas and now
people are still using them to win like
20 million dollars so it's kind of
insane but you never heard of it before
before i go check it out yet so great
blocking is like in DotA you have a
non-player characters that are going up
the lanes and the whole objective of
photos that killed the other teams
ancient and so these non-player
characters are kind of like battling the
whole time those towers in each lane so
what you would do is you would stand in
front of the creeps and block them so
they wouldn't be smooth slower and then
I you know there were hills and stuff
and you if you are up on a hill and your
point was down the hill there was a
mischance whenever they try and hit you
up hill so by blocking the creeps you
actually get a significant advantage and
other things like pulling we point to
other uh usual camps so that all those
unions actually deny experience your
opponent they don't get any experience
or cold so it's like a different way of
looking at the game vs like everyone
like focus on killing each other for a
long time than we realize like others
all this efficiency and stuff we can do
on the map
kind of people around I'm so again it's
the same thing like I failed over and
over again before I successful even with
like the gaming stuff so my open-source
escapades like the main thing that I've
known for is the hydro project and
specifically anhydride project was the
person that made the new linux work on
the device so like touch screen all that
like their here's a screenshot our
picture i took of my iphone 3g running
ubuntu this is like the first time we
ever actually read a bunch you want to
the iphone which was super cool and so
it ended up turning into a pretty cool
thing I contribute to open open open
embedded and they asked me to come speak
and wondering with them at the first
jailbreak on but i was a college student
I can't afford to go so but this was the
end results actually did look very
mobile
unfortunately this specific phone still
on my car like a year and a half ago so
I don't have it anymore I could probably
do it all but it was a lot of work and
so it was like don't probably the only
iphone the world i was booting like four
or five different operating systems and
everything was working on it that sort
of thing but there's a lot of work so
again you know it was like fail fail
fail fail and succeed like I can't tell
you how much time we spent getting the
touchscreen to work and stuff like that
we just kept having to try new ideas
different drivers and I eventually just
got a little to work with GV def which
is very generic Linux driver almost kind
of known for CTF arm so my first
conference security conference was def
con 16 I went out there I was 21 years
old and I i met a guy there from the
team sap it's he invited me to complete
the CTF team because i was working on
the hydro project is one of those things
where I was like with like everything
that I've done up to this point I've
just been following passion like diablo
2 I was just trying to be like the best
at that game dota the same thing and
then like with divers project i just
thought that was really cool and so I
started out just writing documentation
for that if you go out and you go to
hydrate project wiki you'll see on the
person that originally created the
installation guide developer guide so on
and so forth
it's really like an extreme power user
and then some guy was trying to get a
bunch of the pork up to work on it and
boot now it's like taking need some help
and that's kind of how all that started
the is so the first SETI really played
in was def con 17 qualifiers and we got
like 16 3 cool away from
actually making it that happened over
like the next few years and then I just
kind of got discouraged because being
that close i'm not actually making it
can be kind of heartbreaking
this is me at DEFCON 16 or 17 and
someone put backtrack on a kiosk at the
Riviera had no idea who would do that
arm and I like actually went to illinois
state university university for a while
I went to a tech school straight out of
high school and then transferred to ISU
and so I was doing all the hydride
project stuff they're starting getting
involved a lot more collegiate
competition so like CCDC if you guys are
familiar with that which is more about
your defending against professional red
teamers all day and i personally don't
like that competition nearly as much
it's sometimes fun but there's another
competition i competed in the National
Cyber League actually did end up winning
this and being out students from MIT and
stuff like that so i can say i'm a
national cyber champion but I don't know
how cool that is so you know he's like
one of my favorite pictures ever have
myself wearing a hat all day like she
was winter and like they came in like to
do pictures like that you have to take
the head off on like okay so i'm
actually really like this picture just
because it's like I don't know why they
didn't make us put our arms around each
other or something but we just looked
really lanky and kind of derby here not
now thank you
that's a Ben 10 shirt you have to be
special to get one of those now I'm so
like we also i also just collected
everything from CTF time with the team
that I hooked up with was just trying to
play in all the cts that I could and
like it was quite a while for actually
had success in it you know like I would
only solve like a challenge or two in
each CTF but I would learn something and
then I would always look at like all the
people on my team there write-ups all
the rights that come out and I learn
more tips and tricks that way so we want
a couple different CCS cts like besides
Chicago besides Detroit from the whole
besides joint task force again another
shout-out to bend for doing that stuff
but I created a security club that only
state university university coll is X of
the guys are in the room shout out to
them and that was a really positive
thing but there's a lot of is a sec
Adam I actually gave a talk on that
circle city con I I know some of you
were at that time at that talk
go check it out on youtube I can't have
too much time to like really delve into
things so this is actually a screenshot
from the talk on youtube but again there
was one of those things like even with
ISU second all the CTF stuff like this
the same theme right like I failed and
failed and failed and failed and then I
finally succeeded like failure is only
like you only have failure when you give
up on something when you give up that's
when you failed i am sure some things
might not actually be like possible to
physics or something but you know like
the main thing is like don't don't give
up on yourself don't give up on the
stuff that you believe in don't give up
on your passions and like to keep moving
forward because i can't tell you how
many times that I just wanted to stop
doing it all to be honest like yes
Israel so like really getting into like
Python like my methodology of how I
approach things now like I played this
game called Megaman right like I i guess
if you're younger you might not be
familiar with it but mega man-like it
was just a platformer game for nintendo
regular nintendo and is a game that I
really really liked but a couple years
we gonna notice this pattern right like
megaman and kind of application security
and even just like hacking in general
but you know like Kevin Megaman your
application with me and you have this
controller input right well with web
application has a keyboard as your input
and like yeah there may be a lot more
buttons and stuff on the web application
side but it's still kind of the same
concept right and so like the main thing
that I ask myself is like all right
what's the inputs like what can I do
with that input like how does it like
how does the boss actually work what I'm
fighting like actually we're like does
it just a dodge me for a while like what
weapons is vulnerable to that sort of
thing so it's the same really like the
same thing with applications if you
think about it like you have this input
and you're just trying to figure out
what you can do with input to make
something break her to feed something so
i would really like to show this boss
fight but unfortunately i probably don't
have time
so what the main part like with this
like boss fight is like in megaman
whenever you first like approach the
boss you can see like he has a bunch of
different weapons that he's searching
through there
like when we first approached boss like
you would get different weapons from
defeating other bosses and so like
certain bosses were vulnerable to
certain weapons so if you cycle through
all your weapons and fire each one to
see like what did the most damage to it
that's the process of fuzzing really and
so like I was one of those things where
I never thought that you know I learned
too much for video games but really like
games like this
Tommy actually how to plus things and
that's something that's very important
industry if you want to do more security
research specifically even if you just
want to be like a really skilled
pentester it's something that's
important so anyway like you can see in
that video like he found the weapon that
was vulnerable to he started firing it
and the boss was taking a lot more
damage there was a pattern to it so like
this kind of transitions to what I'm
doing now and so I'm actually trying to
develop a video game and i would say i'm
trying i actually am doing this so the
first person that's it's called
conscious hacker and the whole premise
of the game really is the gardener
interested in infosec and so how many
people have here have played like some
war games before like over the wires
smash the stack stuff like that if you
haven't I highly encourage you to go out
and check some of those out how many
people in your plate like a steam game
before know like the same console and
like it drops down
ok cool a lot more hands they're so like
if you can imagine a platformer where
you're the premise of the game is to
hack or secure a computer-controlled
door and so it's going to work very much
seen console-style and it's i'm actually
linking up real systems into the game
much like war games so like it's I'm not
like I'm not faking it i'm not trying to
emulate it i'm giving them the real
thing and I'm gonna hold their hand
along the way to a certain degree i
would get into like the different like
styles of teaching within infosec itself
but i don't have five minutes left if
you're more interested in that I have
some great analogies with ballet
specifically and how they teach ballet
and how that's actually like the
offensive security try harder attitude
as well not sure if they even know that
that's the style teaching they're using
but that's what they're doing
so anyway come talk to me later and i'll
tell you more about that
anyway like I said you have a full game
design document and I'm very close to
being to the point where I could
actually Kickstarter GoFundMe that sort
of thing so i have a gentleman who used
to work on world warcraft and leave
legend that's been guiding me through
this is aliases l mass if you google him
you'll see that he was a big part of
warcraft world of warcraft and did a lot
for the legends as well so he's kind of
guiding you through the process of
actually creating a successful game
whereas i'm doing all the security part
of it and he's connecting me with people
to hire for game design and stuff like
that because i can't specifically for
him so I think it's gonna be really cool
thing like so like one of the main
mistakes I made in the beginning was I
was just just went straight in and
started developing right like alright
cool you know i got these rooms and
stuff like red and blue doors and like
it's gonna be really sweets and then
like you can run around in the rooms
whatnot but I'm like well how's the game
actually going to work like what you do
in it so you know I kind of like hit
that wall that's when I really started
to reach out and get a real game
designer involved to help guide me
through building a successful video game
and some of the puzzle ideas that i have
to actually implement the ideas like you
hack or secure this computer controlled
or and then whatever you learn in that
lesson we're going to reflect it in the
platformer level in the boss as well so
that we're trying to reinforce things
that way and you know there's gonna be
friendly in nbc's if any of you guys did
the sands holiday hacking challenge last
year like that was super cool if you
haven't looked at that i highly
encourage you to go check it out because
they had friendly npcs based on like
real people from sands that were
instructors and they gave enough
information to actually work through
these CTF challenges and like that would
actually was a challenge to like someone
did win that but they gave information
where you can get all the way through it
and I actually did manage to get all the
way through with all the information
that they provided so seeing that
reminded me that like mentorship can
also happen through like non play
non-player characters and not many
people actually have a contact sands to
see what was going on there like oh well
you're overthinking it like look at this
hint here in the game which I thought
was really cool again it's the same
thing same to you
themes in my talk like what most people
think wonderful
no what successful people know you fail
fail fail fail fail and finally you'll
succeed so I've already been failing at
making this game for like a year to now
arm and so I decided you know I can't do
everything I need to realize what I'm
good at and what I'm not good at I need
to contact people that are good at the
things that I'm not good at to make this
successful I'm so really I like have
this like kinda change the world type of
attitude right like with this like no
one's really doing this right now except
for effector 35 the guys from Victor 35
they do a binary ninja I'm they actually
have a couple RPG games out there that
they used to teach reversing and exploit
development i highly recommend checking
out other stuff is actually really cool
but there they have more like a training
model sort of thing they're not like
selling games are like just putting
games out there for people to play like
I think you like really I think you
could ya gone and i played around with
it a bit arm anyway i would highly
recommend checking that out and so I'm
doing is different from them
not exactly like starting hardcore
reversers or anything like that like I
want to build like the next generation
of sis admins and that sort of thing
like we need to hit home earlier with
security and build a security mindset
while we're teaching IT so the light is
like I really want to change the world
and i hope you guys do to thank you