sure we're ready oh alright already
ok let us know when you're ready
all good okay awesome alright so real
quick
obviously obligatory disclaimer these
opinions are around don't reflect any
path previous or current or future
employee this isn't a bridge talk we put
together after about 18 months works
this is like crazy accelerated but one
in particular if you guys so I'm camera
crack i'm the vp of user experience and
product strategy macys.com my name's
Keith Conway I'm not user experience
consultant work with Cameron a lot of
help and slowly but I do a lot of you
explore different kind of groups and
this is kind of our experience on what
we did at macys so they made the talk is
nobody gets fired for choosing IBM but
maybe they should so when I went to
business school in the eighties this was
a common thing that everybody told me
when i left school and actually started
work i heard this more and more which
always interested me because I always
kind of wondered why so in the fifties
as we now IBM kind of decided to send
sales people around the world to
essentially cell systems worldwide to
emerging companies large-scale fortune
500 companies
I'm and became this pervasive force in
business around the world and it solved
a bunch of unmet customer needed allowed
come companies to do things that they
had never been able to do before weather
is automating their P&L making inventory
highly available etcetera they were
doing this largely by implementing these
monolithic systems and at the time that
was innovative
as we warned on we started neglecting
customer need we've actually to some
degree made this a part of our corporate
culture and I've spent the last 20 years
of my career actually kind of cleaning
up after these giant IBM implementations
we're essentially at some point the
business actually isn't about serving
the customer anymore actually working
you know its primary goal it's actually
serving the Beast it's maintaining the
system it's becoming a culture of know
and it's essentially this endless
patchwork of what we can do based on
what the system will support at that
point innovation starts to become legacy
and the minute we start forgetting who
are customer is what they need the
business starts to die and ultimately
our legacy starts to kill us
so that's what we're really here to kind
of talk to you guys about it's not about
ivy and specifically any technological
innovation was an innovation because
it's solved on that customer needs
return about that you did something
valuable but over time your competitors
anybody else can do that because the
rate of change of technologies evolution
is just so fast right now so we're here
to talk more about how do you actually
save yourself from yourself as a large
corporation or larger organization and
two main things you need is solving on
that customer needs build a great
company like these are your kind of
mentality because a lot of talk about
social engineering red teaming kind of
these ideas that were folding you guys
all know about there's a lot of a
preconceived notions about its the
fairies to get living behavior they're
very specific kind of attacking vectors
that come to mind and in order to move a
large organization towards collective
action you need 12 which is the customer
a great company and then if you're not
returning value then you're not finding
a way to speed the innovation back to
keep it alive and then fourth you have
to do is without shutting the company
off because if you're like an oil and
gas company if you're a bank
you can't just stop and then forgive me
know make sure things can keep working
on that really is the brilliant trick
that IBM has kind of lock this all into
our business cease to exist even even
intraday if we should any of this stuff
down so we're locked in
so our goal today is to try and get you
guys as smart as possible as fast as
possible to kind of give you a framework
to use this on your own
hopefully you guys work for large
companies to you know to apply centers
on your own so the first thing i do is
assess the environment you going to
build a message to craft the message
find the right people and then it's all
about timing
so the first thing is assessing the
environments defining how and where the
technology is inhibiting you your
organization and kind of the larger
thing that you're after its kind of
going outside your four walls as well
and understanding what's going on in the
economic environment around you or the
market that you plan
I'm for us we plan a global market so we
have to look at this from around the
world what is the space retail doing in
this particular example I mean how is
the economic environment around us
actually affecting the business and then
finally it's kinda gave the culture and
deciding where the human factor is you
know again because this I
self-fulfilling prophecies to some
degree of servicing the system starts to
define how culture works is bringing
these things together understanding them
in describing them in ways that the the
human beings can actually understand so
you can break the thing down so real
quick
no matter what message you have the sea
level of the board they have to like get
behind it and everything to get behind
it you have to speak their language
which is your revenue profit loss p need
to understand what these things are
understand now we live in a global
market right now like it doesn't matter
what you do macro not macroeconomic
trends are going to affect you have to
be an MBA to kind of do this you know
enough to kind of speak the language
they listened to you when you know
you're actually talking which brings us
the right part so like we said the sea
level has to evangelize not just by if
you buy and then you're just like okay
hey we agree but they're not going to go
back and actually put on the earnings
calls are not going to put that back
down in the organization this is
basically just like an academic
experiment so we're actually gonna go
through some of the examples we have
later but we're going to give you the
framework right now so we did is we
built an org chart or telling you to do
is build an org chart do a threat
assessment certain people you can work
with starting collaborate would
certainly probably wanna go
or because they're going to see you as a
threat and then what you want to do is
plot you run across multiple domains in
parallel so it's not just one person you
want to kind of make you run through you
have to be able to go through find
partners in marketing merchandising
other different parts of the
organization that you can see ideas too
so that you're going to go up here and
even though they're going to take credit
for little ideas the whole rising tide
is going to float your boat like over
there that's the trick I mean everybody
kind of knows that when storming the
castle you're not getting the King
immediately you have to sort of work
with the levels that you're working with
so for us it was all about trying to
figure out what that level was like
Keith said that we could see the message
to kind of get our message up to the
king
so to speak I'm so timing is everything
and it is we're saying it it's that
proper seating of a particular part of
the message that you want to resonate
its building that common framework of
language for your entire audience it's
going broad it's looking across the
organization and deciding where your
friends are where your foes are and
seeing the appropriate message to each
of those groups and having that message
rise up and then once a common language
or a carrier waves developed its kind of
dropping the next part of the message
until your building that curiosity to
the point where eventually you're going
up continue to rinse repeat this the
curiosity sort of builds people begin to
understand this you start to have less
friction in the organization so that
means that you're having we're talking
about these concepts become more and
more fluid and then ultimately curiosity
builds to the point and you've hit
enough of the sort of key players in
your organization that you get the
invite to kind of come and talk to the
sea level person
alright so our process was kind of like
a random hodgepodge of social
engineering red teaming and design
thinking and for us we're using the kind
of definition that Chris had Maggie
Michelle Fincher kind of positive which
is essentially influencing people to
take decisions which they didn't think
or know they should or should not have
taken and
Chris and Michelle really in the apse
class made an awesome . about not losing
the teaching moment where if you're
tricking if you kind of if you're
trippin somebody are using kind of
nefarious behavior kind of manipulation
then someone's gonna catch that and it's
not going to be a lasting way to build a
relationship moving forward and as we go
back like this whole sparking curiosity
new people ideas in retail retail is
like a very technologically kind of
archaic and yeah mentality we're
literally stuck in the fifties right now
with mainframes and whatnot so giving
people the confidence to speak up and
ask questions without afraid to just be
wrong or not understand what's going on
allows them to actually participate
beyond just saying okay you do this you
do that I'm being very tactical and just
do this right now right so that's a
social engineering part the red teaming
is more state of mind for us and micah
zenko had a really good book about red
teaming you check it out and he kinda
posted that as like a state of mind also
how you just being devil's advocate and
that's what we're kind of doing we're
not being devil's advocate for sake of
being devil's advocate but trying to
really understand where the
opportunities lie for the customer that
business and how to actually feed that
back into the system and then our
background is in design that's where
design thinking comes from tim brown to
CEO of i do they did a design thinking
trying to put design in place so it
didn't exist before and that's kind of
home where we come from
so what we're gonna do now is go through
a handful of slides from our deck we
can't show you what we actually did for
the whole thing its proprietary
obviously but we're going to talk to
kind of just different different bits
and pieces can give you guys an idea
so when we build our deck like my
background came from a film sound and
special effect the major at savannah
college of art design so for me this is
kind of like a visual storyboard wrapped
up as a business plan and a strategic
vision for the company and the goal is
could the CEO and the board understand
what's going on but also get down to an
associate level employee who you might
have three kids and working multiple
jobs and not really care about the
finance at the company so as we talked
about earlier the main issue that we
kept running into the technology is in
heaven
bring the user experience that business
processes everything else that people
don't understand what's going on we
would have meetings where we installed
kiosks that would be you'd push the
kiosk and what nme it wouldn't even
slide and I'm like an Instagram for
somebody to work with and his kid is
standing in front of an LCD or a giant
TV screen and trying to swipe the screen
thinking it's like a giant iPad right
now so they didn't get the mental models
transferring through to all the
generations so we're like okay look in
10 years a phone is going to be as fast
as your brain has been less than a
thousand dollars and that's going to
absolutely change just everything right
now I mean think about we're living in a
time right now where the cycles and
evolution of Technology escalating so
fast that you can really see beyond the
horizon Ray Kurzweil talks about this
people singular university I mean timing
whatever is not really relevant but it's
just that the idea to get them to think
about technologies not just changing the
business is changing customer behavior
change society changing everything
secondarily we lost half our market
capitalization matters six months and to
a point where to hedge funds are trying
to do architect a hostile takeover
because a real estate was worth more
than what the stock is actually worth
and so we talked about this and you hear
about this morning's call when they
start listening and so we would
literally sit on their earnings call and
text back and forth and take notes and
then ask our bosses ask our bosses
bosses like what about this what's going
on here and you hear certain things
you're like how does the market actually
receive this is value and if they are is
this what are our board is actually
proceedings value as well and why is it
and again you know I'd be up at 2am
watching Bloomberg on my phone for i
passed out and it's like a quarter of
all gdp or economic output in the world
is a negative interest rate territory
and what that means is that i'm a bank
i'm giving you guys alone
that means i am paying you interest for
the benefit of taking a loan from me
which makes absolutely no sense
whatsoever and that is gorgeous comments
really crazy bizarre land with finance
and everything and that's that feeds
back to essentially how we get debt how
we pay for more expansion how we grow
the business
and again this is how you communicate
and things are actually important to the
top level so before we leave that the
fascinating thing about this is is we
got smarter about this we started to be
very predictive we introduce air within
the couple of days if anything was
happening globally we could predict
within probably about a point or two
what are in stock price could do
I'm so if we wanted to be in the various
we actually probably could have made a
lot of money doing that but between the
two of us we were actually predicting
where the stock was going to go before
the stock went there so the second thing
that we talked about in and coming out
we're showing you sort of in practice is
the message and again the message needs
to be bold it needs to be easily
understood and it kind of needs to be in
your face and we try to keep this and
you're seeing again these actual
tactical slides I'm the got our execs to
pay attention and it's literally like
look we are slaves to the machine we are
at this point Q managers and meanwhile
our customers daily are telling us about
these problems and we're ignoring them
and it was only at the point where you
can start to see these really bold
examples that you start to catch hold
right and again this is another example
one of the articles that i dread as we
were doing this was this idea about
English lawyers they still wear these
wigs in 2016 have done this for more
than a hundred eighty years
the bottom line is there's nothing in
any English law that says they need to
do this they just simply do it because
nobody told them to stop
it's a pretty good metaphor for what
goes on in a giant corporation and it
was like all right is everybody away
like can you hear me in the back
so once we know again kind of
established this carrier wave now it's
time to to load payload on
so this was we went through probably 15
20 different major passes of our deck
and our deck was always one slaw one
slide one idea and it was simple enough
so that if this land on somebody else's
desk they could just read through it
like someone's having a conversation
with them during lunch and be like oh ok
action like I can actually get this and
it wasn't this giant time of a
powerpoint just dance of all information
that no one really cares about and won't
read and won't retain later so we talked
earlier about having you know your title
your concept in seven or eight words and
this is one of the ones we came up with
which was like the new baseline
simplicity convenience and trust and
everything was always so complicated and
you always end up with these ideas of
self-preservation people working to get
funding to kind of potentially keep
their own part of the beat them working
and for us were like look it's really
really easy simplicity whereas if you
have an idea in your head it's one click
once y 1 action had done conveniences
like give someone their time back don't
make them searching we had issues and if
you look on any of the financial crisis
many blogs anything out about fashion
today in retail people can't find what
they want if they're in smaller towns
and their sizes that I don't correlate
with what they want and just won't
necessarily want to listen to the
customer and making people have to work
harder and trust this is not only the
security part here for that everyone
cares about but also are you being
consistent you actually gaining trust
from your users from a constituent see
from your base and it was really simple
it was the best customer experience wins
that was this is actually our whole
mantra and ironing your kind of funny
thing is we'll go to render meanings and
someone to say oh ok we'll talk to
somebody and they're like oh hey you
this implicit convenient trust people
okay cool i got to know you guys did
that like were yeah i mean i literally
just came from Cincinnati Ohio so I've
never been the Cincinnati Ohio before
for a company but i guess we have like a
giant corporate presence there and
amazingly somebody came into this
meeting that i was happy i was in
training all week and somebody I never
met before comes in and says exactly
what keith said and actually has the
deck was like how did you get this deck
I'm and it turns out that it's so
pervasive at this point in our company
that people
anybody who's a decision maker and at
some level across
kind of a wide swath of the the area
that were in is somehow going to copy
this deck
I mean it was fascinating in in the work
team that i was in there was somebody
who's been kind of it's an archrival but
arrival on the last six years of my
existence there and all of a sudden
she's just like Jackson the deck to I
get it it's it's good you think it's a
hundred slides right
ya think anybody really yeah it was like
okay she actually has the deck crazy on
but the sort of friction if you will
between us largely is kind of been
mitigated because everybody has this
understanding now we're no longer
working against one other it's like okay
we're on the simplicity and convenience
bar right securities on the trust part
there's no more what they what are we
saying how do we mean this what how does
it work
what do we do with it Mikey said again
we're kind of showing you techniques at
this point like we've kept things too
simple messaging eight words or less
right and these important concepts will
pause will have these visuals will go
through a bunch of different visual so
that everybody can get kind of their
understanding of it right what does it
mean the technology wasn't illegal
wasn't into privacy and we have visuals
that go with that we tailor these decks
so that everybody again has that common
framework of language but some sort of
concept that resonates with them so this
is like the second slide of our deck and
this was from the Arizona boneyard it's
actually an old hydrogen bomb or nuclear
bomb test positive yet called the
physics package though and then the text
is actually our kind of what our company
our brand is saying out to the world to
try and reboot our stock and it's like
okay we're gonna feed this back in the
system and it's a metaphor of ok we have
a huge is it to make it's not gonna be
easy as going to a little work and you
know but there's also a lot of power a
lot of opportunity I mean for us it's
like if your macy's is giant retailer
and it's what you do one kind of
e-commerce that you've done the mall so
the only thing to do anything more
interesting to do something bigger with
a lot more skilled a lot more
complexity and this really excites
that's really excited about this is can
we actually find a way to get people to
move this large Titanic or monolith
forward in a way that people like doing
the work that they're doing creating
good jobs you know
good good money for them value for the
business customers are psyched and this
is kind of you know again one of the
ways that kind of grab people's
attention to slide to the like what am I
looking at and it's a pleasure people
are wearing suits everyday not you know
it's not like a silicon valley kind of
startup kind of culture so we talked
about doing our org chart and common
threat assessment we literally sat down
one day had coffee and so we had a
blackout all the names for
confidentiality but we literally looked
at okay who's in our chunk of the
company right now not the whole thing at
was one John enchilada but ok here's
what we know he has been the longest on
one time with the threat assessment a
little bit yeah sure
so being essentially like i was saying
before what we did is we kind of looked
at everybody and decided who is an ally
who is a potential threat who needs to
be brought along and what is the trigger
point that they need to have to be
brought along right it's not just simply
a blanket message of okay this is what
we're doing you have no choice in this
matter
it literally is seating them with the
information the pivot point that's the
thing that they care about right because
it's not the people are lining up in
these companies and mindlessly doing
their job actually do care
it's just kind of fighting that . that
says do you care about this
yes great it's almost like human BFF the
thing about that's like it literally is
ok what is the point of of access
yeah well it's a lot of times is
reporting it a lot of times they were
breathing the same air for so long that
they couldn't see beyond their own small
piece of the puzzle and that they just
couldn't realize that there's actually a
simple solve with tech or if I actually
work with somebody else to do
attribution or whatever they can
actually not only solve their problem
but three or four other people's
problems and that's we start putting
this together with kind of multiple
people in parallel kind of push this
thing forward
and so lastly this is one thing that
we're shining and this is it it's a
humorous anecdote but again once you get
to that point where people are listening
you need to make sure that they really
understand what the message was because
at some point when you're dealing with
the high pair up extra lines of your
organization they're gonna assume that
they know more than you do on so we
research the daylights out of most of
our use case it isn't this was one that
was one literally hilarious but it
actually was challenged by the chief
omni-channel officer and ultimately the
CEO of our company around both inventory
and availability and essentially it was
like this thing's been available for six
years it's been sitting on a shelf
actually there are six of them that were
sitting on a shelf for six years on the
the hilarious thing was we spent money
to actually search engine optimize this
and we spend money to search engine
market that so you could find this
through google and then we're on the
call talking about this and the chief
omni-channel officers essentially like
now this is not true it's like any you
can hear the keys moving right he's
googling and he's like David Cameron and
then it's like yeah but this is this is
one of those things we would ship
directly from a vendor we don't happen
like you're you're not thinking about it
right way and the essentially the chief
customer experience officer calls out
it says it's in stock it says you can
pick it up in store was like geez so
candid sort of give us that . so the
next time he was in San Francisco and I
was handing him the books that were on
Keith reading list I made sure that he
had the bookmark actually the other the
other four are right in my office so
other execs will be getting these as
well but it but it does really kind of
Hammer that point home right it's a very
physical tangible example of something
that you can you can bring forward to
say
it really is this way it's a wake-up
call
yeah so this was the last slide of our
deck is kind of full circle from the
beginning Dec we started with the bunker
buster and the kind of brand cool it is
aware but on this actually works because
for us our goal was to try to figure out
how do we pick the corporate strategy
and would approve that is that if they
talked about on the earnings call and
they actually did that and the last
earnings call the stock went up i think
between three or six dollars which is if
you do the math in stock price and how
many outstanding shares it's almost like
1.5 1.8 billion dollars a market cab
which isn't which isn't all of us but
the things we did got to them and they
actually put on the earnings call so it
works and then now it's like okay the
next thing for us is that now the CEO
said yes
how do we actually get them to do it and
keep moving forward because it's a
hundred and sixty thousand person
company that's still trying to move
ahead in the future and that's our talk
thank you guys and not that I'm trying
to stick at the IBM but one one more
thing
so one of the questions that we got
asses we were talking about this is how
pervasive is this problem is this really
every you know large companies problem
this is actually from IBM itself for the
system z which is the precursory it's
the you know semi current version of the
system that they developed in the
sixties which were actually running is
401 and you can see right here 22 of the
top 25 us retailers are still on system
z 71 percent of the global fortune 500
companies are running system z eighty
percent of the world's corporate data
resides were originates in system z so
it's it really is that pervasive thanks
thanks guys
it's true
the problem is if you're running that
the blade in a single data center and
i'm not saying that we're doing that but
redundancy might be a bit of a problem
system