everybody to characteristics of emotech
infections I am Brad Duncan I'm a threat
intelligence analyst with Palo Alto
networks unit 42 team uh I also
volunteer for the internet Storm Center
do some Diaries their infosec blogs for
lack of a better term I tweet at malware
underscore traffic on Twitter usually
very dry boring technical tweets every
once in a while I'll post a meme or
something and then I'll post a lot of
pcapp and malware samples to my blog at
malware traffic Dash analysis.net
foreign
it's interesting when I submitted this
proposal
for this talk to the committee imotet
was active and very much uh daily uh
spammer where we would get various email
examples for emotech on a daily basis
submitted to virus total and I would see
it in my spam traps and now it's uh
since about mid-july it's been quiet the
botnet the infrastructure behind
neemotet is still there it's still alive
it's still occasionally doing things but
it's not spamming so this
emotec is uh what I would call dormant
right now
but we'll look at what emoted is
um I'll describe how my lab environment
is set up
to look at some examples of emotec
infection traffic which is uh we'll have
two examples that we'll cover here and
then other malware that is active that's
kind of filling that hole that emotec
left has left open since it's gone
dormant
so originally discovered in 2014
the emotech is uh was first a banking
Trojan discovered as a banking Trojan
and it's kind of morphed uh it's a what
we call a modular malware which means
that uh um it has functions that are
sent as separate modules from the
initial infection so for example you
have a Spam bot module that will usually
appear in my lab environment we'll see
it uh spam bot activity happen on an
infected Windows host approximately 30
to 45 minutes after the initial
infection
but uh it is back door it is a spam bot
and it does uh provide follow-up malware
usually Cobalt strike but we've uh we've
seen other types of malware as well this
the Cobalt strength ties in with the
emotec being an initial access broker
which means the criminal group behind
emotet likes to
make extra money I guess by selling
access to the hosts the infected Windows
hosts that are part of its botnet and
then these other criminals will use
Cobalt strike to then map out the
environment
and uh see if there's anything of a high
value Target and then usually it'll drop
ransomware uh whoever the
additional criminal is so
uh when you hear stories about Conti
ransomware uh attacks in the past year
or so some of those can be directly
attributed to an initial imhotet
infection by someone who was tricked by
a emoted Spam body email
so there are currently two emoted
botnets they act exactly the same I'm
not sure how certain people who track
these things uh separate these two
botnets out they call it epoch4 for one
botnet Epoch five for the other botnet
the reason they call it four and five is
because before the 2021 takedown of
emotech where it was gone for about 11
months came back in November of last
year before that
uh absence there were three botnets and
they were called Epoch one Epoch II and
Epoch three uh just nicknames by
security researchers uh for the
infrastructure behind emoted
uh in recent years as I've said imotet
infections have been publicly documented
as leading to ransomware now here is the
chain of events for atypical emotec
infection for the last few months last
two or three months
it was consistently something like this
before it went quiet in mid-july 2022.
so you would have a thread hijacked
email and sometimes these emails
wouldn't be threat hijacked but they're
always impersonating somebody
some stolen email address
that was taken from a previously
emotec infected host because part of
what emotec does when it affects a
Windows host is if you have a email
client like Outlook or Thunderbird and
you've got a bunch of emails in there
it will take that information and we'll
send it up to the botnet and then the uh
emote botnet that infrastructure will
regurgitate that information and use it
for thread hijacked emails impersonating
a legitimate a sender and including
those email chains
but these emails
um
for the last two or three months before
it went silent always contained
attachments so it was either a password
protected zip archive sometimes not
password protected but mostly password
protected that contain an Excel
spreadsheet a Microsoft Excel
spreadsheet specially crafted to with a
macro with malicious code designed to
infect a vulnerable computer with emotec
a vulnerable computer and a victim would
enable macros on a vulnerable Windows
host and that would generate traffic to
retrieve a Windows binary
Windows dll File in this case for emotec
and it would run it on the infected
Windows host now you would see traffic
wouldn't be just one
HTTP or HTTP request it'd usually be
about three or four or five URLs that
would retrieve emotec dlls and this
would be a redundancy because
these URLs will change frequently
because they're easily detectable as
hosting malware they'll get taken
offline
so therefore you have usually four or
five different URLs that are all
triggered to retrieve an emotec dll and
hopefully one of them will still be
active
and then once the motet dll is run
that's when we start seeing the command
control traffic to servers on the IMO 10
botnet and then from there you see the
follow-up activity like spam bot
activity or Cobalt strike from what I've
seen in my lab and then possibly in a
worst case scenario something like
ransomware
so here's an example of an email that
has a password protected zip archive as
an attachment and this is a thread
hijacked email between it was stolen on
a formerly infected Windows host that I
infected with emotec my lab environment
I'll populate my mail client with emails
back and forth between email accounts
that I control
and one of them was a in this case it
was Gmail account that I used uh named
with a nickname Dom uh don Bertram
and what we do here and Martin uh
somebody I forget was the name of the
recipient I've got everything shaded out
here because I'm not going to share my
honey pot email addresses with you guys
at least not publicly
so if anybody's curious you can ask me
about there is a couple I will share
publicly here in this presentation but
those are considered burned
we have a uh you can't see it because I
haven't scrolled down but we have uh the
legitimate email chain between these two
email accounts that I control
that I've set up and uh it says hello
Martin archive password 723 have a great
day Don Bertram
and then whatever you know great work on
this morning's presentation whatever
that email chain was
now if you guys got an email like this
from someone that you knew or at least
that claimed to be some though from
someone that you knew this would be uh
relatively easy to detect uh just
because if you look at the from line of
this it says Don Bertram as the name or
the nickname but if you look at the
email that is not Dom Bertram's Gmail
account email it is uh
something.it is an Italian
email provider an Italian email address
you open that password protected zip
archive and then within that password
protected zip archive there is an Excel
spreadsheet that Excel spreadsheet for
the last two or three months at emotech
was actively spamming was sending out
Excel spreadsheets that looked exactly
like this
um I think uh sometimes the the little
gray shaded area with the warning would
be yellow or to be pink but it it would
look exactly the same and you'll notice
that there are seven spreadsheets tabs
in this particular spreadsheet
and if you look at the workbook
properties you'll see a couple of uh
consistent things like the author I
think was always in this case dream
and
um
last modified I don't know I think they
were all RGS sgk but the thing with this
is the work the sheets in the workbook
were all protected
so I can't go in and look at the macro
code for this particular spreadsheet
without knowing whatever password that
was used to protect these particular
sheets in this workbook
so the only easy way quick and easy way
for me to figure out what what those
URLs is is to detonate it in a
environment or a sandbox
So speaking of lab environments we'll
look at my lab environment that I will
use to
um detonate emotent malware to check it
in the environment now I will use active
directory environments a lot of
sandboxes especially the free ones or
relatively cheap ones that are available
even a lot of the
Enterprise solutions for example Palo
Alto networks has a live type of sandbox
environment called Wildfire but that's a
single Standalone Windows host right or
maybe it's running them on two different
ones you know one Windows 10 one maybe
Windows 7 or something like that but
it's not an active directory environment
I like to use active directory
environments because that's how you see
Cobalt strike
so a malware like emotec or cacbot or
iced ID
is not going to send Cobalt strike to
sell that access to that host to an
initial access broker because a
standalone Windows host is generally not
part of a high value Target right you
want an active directory environment
with hundreds of clients and various
interesting servers that could be uh
that could be either exploited or
targeted for ransomware
but uh what I'll generally do in a
virtualized environment in this MacBook
that I have here for example I'm running
either
VMware Fusion or virtualbox those are
two of them on a Linux host I can run
the KVM system in qemu I've tried that
before with uh with the relatively good
success
and then
those are generally it I do have a
physical environment that I'll use for
certain families of malware that are
very resistant to running properly in a
virtual environment so instead of uh I'm
not I'm not as technically proficient as
some people who can alter their virtual
environments to disguise the fact that
they're virtual right so I I just it's
easier for me just to you know pick up a
couple of laptops on eBay and an old
Cisco switch and you know just set up an
environment in my home lab and this is
how I do it here plus the benefit of
having a physical setup like this
is that you can add as many windows
clients as you have ports in your switch
and then I could usually just do a span
port on a Cisco switch to any one of
those clients if I'm detonating what's
that on there I can just span that Port
into another Port where I'm monitoring
it on a computer that I'm using TCB dump
or Wireshark to record the pcap
I like to have fun with my virtual
environments it's not all just uh
monotonous although there is monotony
and routine although it is routine uh
stuff that I do every day I'd like to
have a little fun so uh for example uh
for a while there a short while I was
using an environment uh that was Batman
and Robin right so
um this is not the this is not the
modern Batman right the the the guy
that's facing the whispery deep voice
this is the Adam West Batman of the late
1960s uh with uh Adam West and Bert Ward
right so this is uh Batman would use
aol.com right he's a little older
generation uh and then Robin who's a
little more young a little more hip he
would use something relatively newer
like Yahoo
at least that's the way I see it
um
so I'll come up with these conversations
off the top of my head uh this is uh
this is one of the an example of the
emails that I'll send where um and I try
and imitate the Adam West uh version of
Batman uh vocally but it doesn't work
out it sounds more like the Christopher
Lloyd character uh Doc in Back to the
Future it's like
we gotta defeat the Joker it doesn't
sound anything like Adam West
but this is type of emails that uh that
all Less in between these two accounts
I'm using Thunderbird to uh
to
uh as the email client in my environment
and you can see uh what I have up here
uh I started near the end of June I had
this going for a couple of weeks those
accounts are still there though so feel
free feel free to send anything you want
to any of these emails
doubt I'll be I'll doubt I'll be using
it much after today
but uh you can see some of these emails
have attachments and they're uh they're
all reply based emails these are thread
hijacked emails
um I I shouldn't say thread hijacked
emails uh sometimes that are not exactly
thread hijacked like this one
so yeah it's uh
please open the attached document it's
got a Excel spreadsheet and this is
emotech right and uh but there is no uh
email chain on this one
the subject is r e and then the
the uh recipient's email address
and there uh there is no actual
uh legitimate email chain that has gone
back and forth here so we'll kind of see
that sometimes with emotec it will just
uh put your email address to kind of
pretend that there was a conversation
anyway the attachment whether it's a
within a zip archive that's password
protected or whether it's directly
attached to the email itself is the same
type of Excel spreadsheet that we looked
at earlier
now
this exact email
from July 11th
with this exact attachment
I ran it earlier this week
remember how I said there's uh usually
four or five urls
that are generated after by the macro
code in that malicious document well we
do have
we do have https and HTTP based urls
and one of those actually worked
one of the HTTP URLs now what's
interesting here
is uh when I ran this just through my
home internet to check my internet
service provider it was blocked
so I tethered through my phone
and my phone allowed this to that
internet connection through my phone
allowed this this Windows dll to come
through right this is this is a URL that
has been hosting malware since as early
as
July 11th
and it's still active
all right it took that URL
that macro code from that malicious uh
Microsoft Excel document and it saved it
saves it to a under the infected users
app data local directory it creates a
new directory of random alphabetic
characters
and it saves it and it runs it and it
remains persistent through a Windows
registry update through the most
commonly used
Windows registry update to keep malware
persistent it's the hkey current user
software Microsoft Windows current
version run that particular you know
under the HK CU registry hive
and red server
32.exe is what is used to run it so it
doesn't have an entry point like you
would use if you were using run dll32
so with that in mind let's take a look
at our first example now the Wireshark
displays that are showing here that I'm
showing here and there are some of you
that I see that have uh
participated in the workshop that I ran
earlier this week it is my customized
Wireshark column display all right and
you can find out how to set that up in
the same way that I use it by looking at
the Wireshark Workshop videos that I
have posted through my employer Palo
Alto networks if you Google Wireshark
Workshop Duncan you should find that
link to all that has a Palo Alto
networks page that is on my blog posts
and articles
through the company
that I've used to do that now this first
infection example
is from the 7th of June
so I've posted the traffic online at my
malware trafficanalysis.net blog I did a
tweet about it through the unit 42 Intel
handle
on Twitter dumpsterfire though Twitter
is it is it is very useful you may have
heard of the term infosec Twitter that's
uh that is a thing figure about anywhere
from 50 to 100
Twitter accounts that that are primarily
geared towards tweeting
or retweeting technical information now
granted the unit 42 Intel handles uh
specifically you know it's doing more
than just these type of tweets it's a
little promotional as well and promoting
the unit 42 blog and everything but uh
my particular uh you know I'll retweet
this through my Twitter handle as well
the at malware underscore traffic
there's a lot of people on Twitter like
I said about 50 to 100 that consistently
tweet technical details
but this particular pcap that is
available on my blog site
is an active directory environment
and I'm using crypto punch.data as a uh
as a domain that is not registered by
the way I'll go through I'll go through
a domain registrar just to check to make
sure that whatever domains I'm setting
up for my active directory environments
are not already registered because I
have posted information before on stuff
that I didn't realize was registered by
somebody and have got an email saying
hey uh
you uh you you're posting this uh
information that implies that our
network is compromised and uh they asked
me to take it down and I can only say
yes
but this is the active directory
environment
I want to infect my an active directory
environment with the emotec because if I
don't I won't see Cobalt strike if they
send it and it's about a 50 50 shot if
they actually send it sometimes less
than that depends on what time of the
day
U.S time wherever what time of the day
that I am infecting a Windows host as to
whether I might or might not see Cobalt
strike
foreign
so I have this in Wireshark this
particular P CAP
from the 7th of June 2022
there are two https URLs and one HTTP
URL that that were generated by the
Excel Macro for that emotec dll
and those are here
now we don't know what those uh two
first two URLs are
unless you submit the uh the malware to
a Sandbox environment that has some sort
of uh man in the middle set up to where
you can uh
decrypt that https traffic which is what
I did in this case
so the only one that we could look at
that we could actually follow the TCP
stream for and see if something was
returned
is uh visibly is that last HTTP URL
so in Wireshark this is one of the first
tricks that I learned as a analyst
using Wireshark when I was first
starting out was you follow the TCP
Stream So you left click on that
particular frame in your column display
and you follow the TCP string bring up a
menu and follow the TCP stream in this
case this particular URL did not return
anything
so the emotec dll or dlls would have
been through the https traffic that's
not going to be available in the pcap if
you go to that blog entry on my site I
retrieve the two
dlls that were actually retrieved over
https from the infected Windows host
itself
if we go back to our pcap and use the
basic web filter
you'll see that there is https activity
to various IP addresses over TCP port
8080 and TCP Port 443
and that's just a list of everything
right there all right you'll notice that
there are a lot of IP addresses over
those two various reports it's not
limited to Port 443 or 8080 those are
just the most common ones sometimes
they'll see it over https traffic over
TCP port 7080.
now
um
one of the things that you can trigger
of an alert for on the network traffic
is the certificate data from the
certificates that are used to establish
that TLS connection this is TLS version
1.2 so there is a certificate that is
sent
that we can actually see the data for if
if this were TLS version 1.3 we could
not do this
so I would filter on
tls.handshake.type equals 11 and in this
case I'm just going anything with that
particular
data which I filter for that to look at
the certificate data for any https
traffic over TCP port 8080.
if I go to the frame details and I'll
expand my way down to look at the
certificate data
so I'm going through transport layer
security handshake protocol certificate
handshake protocol certificate going all
the way down until I see the certificate
issuer data and there's a bunch of RDS
sequence items
and these are the sequence items uh
illustrate they they have the values of
the issuer data for this particular
certificate
and this is a self-signed certificate
so uh when you set up an https server or
web server that does https you need to
have a certificate a public and a
private in order to establish that TLS
connection
so this is the public certificate
and you can actually you could have when
this was still active you could go you
could have gone uh back in June on June
7th you could have uh plugged that IP
address and Port into your web browser
and it would go to the site now any
uh web browsers any normal web browser
is going to look at that and say hey
this is this is a big security risk
because this is a self-signed
certificate it is not a recognized
certificate Authority so Chrome Mozilla
Firefox I'm sorry Chrome Firefox
Microsoft Edge Safari they're not going
to show it
immediately but they'll let you accept
the risk and continue now what we can do
on this particular page that shows up we
can click on that view certificate link
and we would find out that everything
that we saw in Wireshark that we could
find out in Wireshark we would find here
thank you
and you could use something like openssh
to generate these types of certificates
which is what I assume that the
criminals do when they set these up
because it's completely free now this
traffic doesn't use a web browser to
establish that connection for that https
data to go back and forth right it's the
malware itself that's doing that
so it's not using a web browser so there
is absolutely no problem whatsoever for
malware to establish a command controls
Channel over https traffic for a server
that's using a self-signed certificate
and we see that commonly
we commonly see that and they're I
believe the emerging threats open rule
Set uh has a at least an informational
signature that triggers on certificate
issuer data that comes over uh prior to
that TLS connection being established
where it's triggering on stuff like
example.com or Global Security as an
organization
for this particular pcap this particular
example you know we've seen emotec but
the more interesting thing with an email
infection is do we see Cobalt strike
with uh emotec or any other malware
because Cobalt strike is that precursor
to other activity this is an initial
access broker providing access to that
infected Windows host to another
criminal group
so we see this uh because emotech always
uses IP addresses for its command
control traffic without domains without
any Associated domains if you start
seeing a bunch of https entries
as you were looking through Wireshark
using this particular basic web filter
and you see multiple
https entries uh multiple entries per
minute it's probably Cobalt strike and
what we have here is uh I forget how
many minutes this is after the initial
infection
what we see uh https traffic to
lentgen.com
now I already knew I already can look at
this and know that yeah this is Cobalt
strike traffic but
uh and the certificate is a let's
encrypt certificate for this uh
particular web server but
um it isn't uh just uh I who have uh you
know used the unit 42 Intel handle
through Twitter to tweet that there were
have been other accounts that have also
discovered this as a Cobalt strike
domain
foreign
is it turns an infected Windows host
into a Spam bot
and if you're not already familiar with
TCP ports 465 587 and 25. those are TCP
ports associated with SMTP traffic
when I use my basic web filter and I
start seeing entries that show TCP Port
465 and 587 and 25 then I know okay I've
got some spam bot activity here
especially if I'm not seeing any actual
domains that are coming up here so I can
filter an easy way to check and see if
you have possible spam bot activity
in a pcap
on a traffic that you're investigating
for a possibly infected Windows host is
to filter on SMTP and we'll notice here
that uh basically you'll see the SMTP
commands that establish the TLs tunnel
and then everything after that is
encrypted
so and you'll see more than one in this
case I see three separate public IP
addresses
to those SMTP based TCP ports using
those TCP ports associated with SMTP
now a Windows client on a normal basis
even if it's set up to to get SMTP
traffic from a single mail server for
its mail client it's not going to go to
different
IP addresses
for SMTP traffic you're not going to see
three four five or normally with emotec
you're seeing dozens of different IP
addresses and dozens of DNS queries to
various mail server domains every minute
every minute or two
and that's not normal that's spam bot
activity
now with the spambot activity regardless
of the malware if there is any
unencrypted SMTP traffic and there's an
email that's sent over you can do a
quick check by filtering on
smtp.data.fragment
in this example we do not see that
so every everything that was sent over
SMTP for this particular example was all
encrypted
and uh quite literally I think if I
would have waited long enough I would
have found some unencrypted SMTP traffic
but uh we're talking uh we're talking
hundreds of megabytes or gigabytes of
data depending on how long you have to
wait it generates a lot of traffic
emotec spambot activity generates a lot
of traffic
so for this particular example this
first example of emotec
uh we see https traffic for the emotec
dll
one unsuccessful
https request we see command control
traffic for emotech over https using
that self-signed certificate and it's
always that specific self-signed
certificate issuer right example.com it
Department all that stuff right it's
that that particular set of
values for the certificate issuer is not
unique to emotech but emotec always uses
that particular set of values
and then we saw https Cobalt strike
traffic
and you'll notice that that doesn't stay
up very long before it stops in my
particular environment because I'm
generally just using one domain
controller and one client right so it's
not going to take somebody very long to
quickly map out that environment
and say oh you know good Lord this is
nothing worth my time and then uh just
quit and then we see encrypted SMTP
traffic for uh spambot activity
so let's look at our second example
of emotech traffic this one is from the
fifth of July
a little a little less than a month
after the previous example in this one
I've actually got uh 10 examples of
emotec mouse spam
from the uh from the days leading up to
January I'm sorry July 5th and then we
have this one this one does not contain
Cobalt strike but it does contain spam
bot activity
and it does contain
some emoted dlls that were sent over
unencrypted HTTP which we can export
from the pcapp
and there is some unencrypted SMTP
traffic that contains email examples
spammed out by this host
that is now or was then part of an
emotec botnet
so if I load this in Wireshark with my
special link crafted customized
Wireshark column display and the filters
that I use
use my basic web filter and I can see
three HTTP URLs and one https apparently
a URL once again this is TLS encrypted
traffic I can see the domain
uh if it's TLS version 1.2 I can see the
domain in the certificate issue
but um
if I follow the TCP stream for any one
of those green lines up there those urls
on July 5th I would uh I would see that
there was a Windows executable file or
Windows dll File that was returned from
that server uh this particular one uh
Zona information.es
which I believe es is uh Spain if I'm
not mistaken right so this is a domain
this is a legitimate domain these URLs
that are hosting
these emotec dll files are almost always
legitimate websites that have been
compromised and being used to host
these uh these emoted dll files
the command control servers are
different those are specially
established usually through fraud
accounts through some sort of service
provider somewhere but these
you wouldn't want to block everything
from this uh particular site then again
maybe you would
but uh this particular URL yes you could
block it you could safely block it
so you'll notice that a Windows
executable file or a Windows dll File
the first two bytes of either one of
those files shows up as the ASCII
characters m z
and then you'll usually see a line that
says this program cannot be run in DOS
mode maybe not that exact wording but
something along those lines
and then you may see some text strings
that indicate some of the packed
executable headers for this particular
packed executable or uh
p-e-d-l-l
now again we can export
these objects that were sent over
unencrypted hddb traffic
by using the export objects function in
Wireshark
all right so I could go to my file menu
my export objects menu and then select
HTTP objects and you'll notice when you
do that with this particular pcap that
all three of those unencrypted HTTP URLs
returned
525 kilobyte file
um
and what I can do with these is when I
save these I can do a in a Linux
environment for example I could do a
file command to check to confirm that
these are uh you know executable or dll
files in this case it's a 64-bit Windows
dll File I'll find that by using the
file command I'll do a Shaw sum command
to get that Shaw 256 hash
and then
I'll check that file hash and virus
total or better yet I'll just do a
Google search
to see if that particular file has been
submitted to any of the publicly
available online sandboxes
and then check and see if the
information that they have matches the
indicators that I'm seeing in this pcap
the Zenni know does anyone know why that
I wouldn't just submit
this Windows executable file or this
Windows dll File to virus total directly
yeah
tip your head he knows that
you found his malware yeah exactly right
that's what you were saying as well that
yeah you don't want to do it because
this uh you know if it is a targeted
attack right
this I don't care if you know what SEMA
did submit that stuff to virus total
because these things are generally have
a different file hash every anyway each
time you retrieve that dll from that URL
uh there's some sort of hash busting or
something going on there where it's uh
generating a slightly different file
every time but you're exactly right and
that's another one of the things that
we're taught early on when you're doing
some you know near real-time analysis
and investigations of suspicious
activity is yeah don't submit the file
sample to virustotal or anything else
online check that shot 256 hash first uh
sir if you'd like to come up you can
pick one of these three items here
thank you
now in this particular example I have
unencrypted SMTP traffic that contains
emails
that are the same type of thread
hijacked emails that I was discussing
earlier right I can filter on
smtp.data.fragment
and we can see that there are what are
there 9 10 examples here
eight examples nine
I can follow the TCP stream for any one
of those and I can see some of the SMTP
traffic that led to this all right I can
see that it is a
um
uh Japanese uh mail server that this is
uh this is uh being used so what's
happening here is that infected
host that's acting as a Spam bot it's
not sending it directly from itself it's
using this uh Japanese email account
that's been compromised to relay the
message to that address that email
address that ends in Dot gov.cl
and the beauty of this is
and I've had this happen to me with the
email accounts that I'll use uh uh you
know as spambot traps so I'm infecting a
Windows host and uh not only does it
Steely email data it seals the username
and password for that email account
and then I'll uh I'll start seeing
bounce back emails in these email
accounts
that uh from email addresses that are no
longer active right I don't see these
emails sent in my sent box in my sent
queue because it's not being sent from
that account that account is being used
as a relay so the only way I will know
if my account has been compromised and
is spamming is if I get these bounce
back emails from email accounts that no
longer exist or no longer work and I've
had that I've had my uh the email the
various email providers shut some of my
email accounts down because they've been
used as uh you know for spam activity
and I wasn't aware of it and it's like
oh I'm sorry change the password can I
have it back
you can export these emails from uh from
the PCAT right we can go file export
objects and this time select IMF
IMF stands for internet mail format
this brings up your IMF object list it
has all of those email files in the EML
format and you can use an email client
I use Thunderbird I don't think I think
Outlook Outlook might open them I don't
know if the windows based Outlook will I
know the Mac based Outlook will but I'm
not sure about the windows windows is
kind of Windows based Outlook is kind of
screwy
I'm not saying that officially
but anyway this is uh this is the type
of thing that we uh for that uh Batman
uh email that was spoof that I showed
earlier this is the part that wasn't
being shown
right so uh this is obviously it's going
to a DOT CL email address
I'm not uh certain does anybody know
what country that is
Chile okay so we're uh we're looking at
uh I believe Spanish here right
and this is not a thread hijacked email
but this is pretending to be an email
that was uh you know formally sent to
that recipient from a
you know whoever Patricia sochin is
what that was uh that name was taken
from a uh address book stolen from a
previously infected emotech host
so other malware that we see now that
emoted is quiet once again ever since
mid-july quite literally July 15th was
the last evidence that I have of email
that was sent from epoch4 or Epoch 5
either one of those botnets so the
infrastructure that botnet
infrastructure is still alive
and still occasionally uh you know you
get a heartbeat or something
metaphorically speaking from it
but uh it's not really doing anything
the other malware that has also been
active while emotec was active but seems
to be even more active now is uh
bumblebee iced ID and cackbot
those three malware families yes sir
how it was shut down I don't know how it
was shut down and I wouldn't even say it
was shut down it just stopped right it
just kind of decided to go to sleep and
we would see that occasionally right
sometimes you'd see a week or two of a
break where there would be no spamming
and like we're still seeing now the
button and infrastructure would still be
there those servers would still be
online but uh the current theory amongst
uh some people uh as we fellow security
researchers as we kind of chatted is uh
you know possibly the whole uh Ukraine
conflict might be a reason that this is
emotet has been attributed to some
russia-based threat actor
starting
I don't know
I don't know I mean it's uh at this
point information uh emotec is an
information stealer so but it's not
specifically banking malware at this
point in time so
um I think it
nobody knows the exact reason why
emotech has now gone dormant
if he likes her you can pick one of the
I neglected to mention this at the
beginning but uh I gotta give away some
prizes I figure anyone who's uh
interested enough to pay attention
through my drone of this highly
technical information and uh is curious
enough to ask a question they deserve a
reward sir
yes sir
record for stuff in his videos do you
ever use security hunting or elastic or
so the question is do I ever use uh
other security tools like security Union
or elasticsearch or whatever the the
short answer is no
the longer answer is occasionally I have
used security Union
I
before I joined Palo Alto networks I had
gotten access to the emerging threats
Pro rule set
and I am a big big fan of security Union
so um I have used security onion I don't
do it so much anymore but I'll use that
in conjunction with the emerging threat
opens or the emerging threat Pro rule
set if there's traffic that I don't know
what it is right and I need to see if
there's any network-based signatures on
the traffic to help me identify the
malware
but uh realistically what happens is uh
now I've got access to uh restricted
Channels with fellow security
researchers where I can just reach out
and grab somebody or poke somebody and
say hey in poke who pokes people anymore
online but uh metaphorically I can just
reach out and say hey do you or you guys
know what this is and usually somebody
much smarter than me will be able to
find that out and then I can I can share
that information and
nine times out of ten it's something
that's already posted online
but uh sometimes this stuff can be hard
to find so if you'd like to come up uh
if you want to get
the last prize
and I see despite that being the last
prize we still have some more questions
yes ma'am
thank you
um
estimated emails yeah of uh you mean
just like overall yes
I don't have an esta an actual amount
estimated but what I can tell you
the volume of emotech emails that uh get
sent out whenever the spam bot is active
whenever the botnet is active telling
the botnet post to start spamming all
right so what will happen is on a single
host when I'm doing it and this sounds
kind of bad because what I'm doing is
I'm detonating this malware in a live
environment uh I'm doing something like
tethering through my phone or going over
a VPN but these emails are getting sent
out now I comfort Myself by saying well
if I'm not doing it somebody else is
doing it right
but uh you know really that's just a
kind of a cop-out
but what happens is I can get an idea of
what's Happening you know live in real
time and what will be happening remember
how I said there was a lot of you know
hundreds of megabytes of gigabytes of
traffic within an hour or two's uh worth
of time so if you look at the traffic
you're seeing quite literally uh you
know dozens of emails sent every second
from one single host
dozens of emails sent
almost every second
you know up to that much so there's an
ebb and flow to it
but uh so you know if I don't shut these
off after a certain amount of time you
know they'll be sending gigabytes of
data out of spam bot traffic hundreds
thousands of emails just from one single
host
now multiply that by how many hosts may
be active at any given time on uh you
know either one of those bot Nets
and you've got uh you know you've got
conceivably hundreds of thousands of
messages that are going out every single
day that these botnets are active
spamming out and that's probably
hundreds of thousands just as a general
figures probably a conservative estimate
in my personal opinion but you're not
going to get a good number because uh
from security vendors
from security vendors because we're all
looking at different uh different uh
different customer base right so there's
no centralized Authority that's
tabulating that information so we can
only guess but I can I can give you that
as a conservative estimate you said you
had another question
okay
gotcha gotcha yeah just uh anyone that
isn't able to answer can grab me after
that you sir with the glasses
how soon after I detonate the malware am
I starting to see the spambot activity
or the Cobalt strike spam bot activity
almost always consistently whenever the
spam bot uh span the botnets are active
pushing out spam bot 30 to 45 minutes
almost consistently within that time
frame whenever the the it's actively
sending out spam
uh Cobalt strike can be anytime so uh
sometimes it'll be you know within 10-15
minutes uh other times it could be hours
and hours later and uh if I were to ever
let these hosts run for like weeks at a
time I may be able to give you a uh
different answer but uh normally you
know I can let these things run for you
know if it's not spamming I'll let it
run just see okay when do I start seeing
something interesting other than spam
body I'm sorry command control traffic
and for Cobalt strike I think what
happens is when these criminals are
selling access to the botnet to other
criminals and using Cobalt strike for
that it kind of all goes out at the same
time so I've had two different hosts uh
using two different public IPS that get
hit you know all infect them about the
same time
or even different times of the day and
when they get when they start getting
the Cobalt strike for example it will be
the same time regardless of when I
started the infection so I think those
Cobalt strike deployments are going to
multiple machines at the same time and
it's just based on uh whatever the
threat actor is doing to distribute that
access to hosts in the botnet
you sir in the green shirt
okay anyone else
yes
how often do I see tiered exploitation I
see it quite frequently okay almost uh
almost uh you know let's say uh 15 of
the time at least yes sir
yes
Microsoft has disabled the macros by
default and you are correct uh what
we're seeing a lot of right now is uh uh
attachments uh that are disk images ISO
files and they will have a window
shortcut and they'll have a hidden file
somewhere on the image that is a Mount
usually a malware dll you double click
the Windows shortcut the only visible
file it runs the malware whatever it is
CAC bot bumblebee uh iced ID whatever
but I think that's it I will take
anybody else's question thank you guys
very much
[Applause]