I must have scared half of you guys out
of here I'm sorry
hello everybody way in the back
how's it going all right so who am I uh
I'm David girvin I shouldn't be in Tech
people made mistakes I ended up here I'm
really not understand a background as a
ship captain and an engineer and stupid
things like that but somehow I hacked my
way into Tech and I've worked for some
companies like one password and we act
purple and bit Discovery and now I am a
senior product engineer
product security engineer of
architecture I don't know I have some
stupid titles I don't really care about
but it works
so I have a very different view on how
these things should be and I think one
of my values in the industry is I see
when things suck so I'll be pointing out
things that suck and making fun of
everybody in different places if you're
in sales I'm already sorry because I
make fun of you a lot but those are my
kids and my wife who are way too good
for me and yeah some other weird things
in there I don't need to read them all
right okay okay what are we going to
talk about
uh we're going to outline building an
appsec program uh with a different
perspective on management integration
I'll go over the cool tool stuff and
Technical stlc and all that kind of
stuff that you need to like have in
place but everybody talks about that
stuff right it's not a big deal you can
like look up any of Tanya Jenkins stuff
and there's a million things on like how
to set up your tooling and everything
but I'm more interested in Social
Engineering uh for good I used to do it
for bad now we do it for good uh I'm not
one of those like I went to college and
was a good person I was a crappy person
and very good at sneaking into places
and figuring these kind of things out
and went the other direction now I try
to do it for good uh I have some
interesting thoughts appsec is sales if
you suck at sales you suck at appsec so
these are like skills we can all learn
and think differently being a part of a
team is super important to me and uh
everything I failed at which is a lot of
things so I I'm uh grossly incompetent
um warning Concepts and thoughts are
based on anecdotal experiences from
building application Security Programs
at places like one password and all
these other fancy companies uh if you
disagree with it it's perfectly fine if
you need to email me and complain about
my talk or any views I have that is my
email address
um if you find me abrasive and sarcastic
but somewhat Charming you are correct so
and if you hang toilet paper over the
back of the roll please leave now you're
not welcome in this talk because you're
a psychopath so what can we think about
here syllabus this is what we're going
to run through I don't need to read all
this stuff right but um these are things
that and you can grab my uh slides uh
just hit me up on LinkedIn or whatever
or maybe we'll put it on the website I
don't know how besides Augusta works but
um I have a bunch of this stuff in here
and these are great blueprints like when
you're thinking about it it just doesn't
go for just appsec I use this for
everything because I build Out programs
teams at our company I love hiring and
that kind of stuff too so
okay what is appsec application security
or product security is a team program
designed to protect all of your code you
own that means everybody that has code
should have an appsec team no matter how
small the company you know unless you
like Farm it out which is fine too
um that includes the code your engineers
write as well as third party party
libraries and open source tools you use
yes if you hack together a bunch of crap
using every third party Library known to
man you are still responsible for that
it's also tools that you use you know
you're running all these open source
tools there's vulnerability in there you
are responsible
it's a strong relationship with
engineering and sea level stakeholders I
know I look like a cartoon and someone
who does not speak well I've spent most
of my life chasing surf around the world
I'm not like a normal human and I can
still speak to the sea level every day
and do it's internal sales you are
selling to your engineering team because
they don't like you because you're the
who said your code sucks now
you got to fix it and they said I spent
seven months building it that specific
way because I thought it was right
that's a big hurdle to get over
uh we'll go through that don't worry uh
it's a smart use of tools and testing uh
I should have like bolded smart there
because everybody throws every tool they
can find especially open source ones
that stuff and that's not really the way
to go it's an understanding that if
business doesn't flow there's no product
secure this is a huge issue in appsec
and we're starting to like mature in a
way that's really interesting and we're
seeing that we are actually a part of
the business if we don't produce profit
we do not get paid so we can't just
roadblock everybody we have to like
relax a little bit I can't just push our
glasses up and scream
it's not old school grumpy gatekeeping
if you're that guy stop it no one likes
you at all especially people like me who
come from outside the industry I worked
in construction for years on the
engineering side of things those guys
exist there too and no one liked them
there either it's not dumping a thousand
volumes on engineering and saying fix it
this is I I do Consulting with my
company with it's called honey badger
engineering for a reason because it's
just ridiculous but anytime I get caught
into Consulting that's happened they
started an abstract program they said
screw you I ran sassed uh yelling when
someone something can't get fixed right
away you have to be the nicest person in
the world or at least be sarcastic
enough to convince people that you're
nice
building a wall and starting a war with
engineering that is how you ruin a
program immediately and I've picked up
the pieces from multiple people who
started it that way because they were
way better at appsec than me but they
weren't good at this side
why spend money here yeah there's a lot
of memes I'm like 12. so uh I'm really
older than I look but uh 2020 the
average cost of business affected by a
data breach the United States is 8.64
million
that's a lot of money especially since
half of cyber security companies in my
opinion are vaporware and they're put up
by VC companies they're just trying to
get absorbed so if you if you lose money
and you don't make money guess what
you're doubles suck so reputational
damage can be far worse than uh the
original dollar lost
I am huge on this so I threat model
companies a lot of the times and do SWOT
analysis for their space because I have
a nerd on the side for business which is
very opposite but my day job is very
nerdy but I nerd out on like how
business works and like you know uh
the two big companies I've worked for
which was one password in Red Canary I
told both of them their biggest
fear shouldn't be the data actually lost
which would suck I mean obviously it's
if anybody ever lost trust with them
um because people trust their password
manager and they really trust Canary
they literally have all of your
Telemetry from every single endpoint you
have in your company so
um it's a different kind of way to start
thinking about it
um it's estimated that we lose 250 to
600 billion dollars of intellectual
property being stolen every year that's
why you go to China and you see all the
BMWs but they're not BMWs and they weigh
like 6 000 pounds it's very strange
um hopefully your insurance mandates it
I know insurance is a bad word but it
needs to it needs we need it for policy
and Regulation and stuff not in the real
world but in cyber security uh it's not
2004 and you're a damn adult that's my
favorite line in this whole thing
because I keep telling myself that every
morning in the mirror I try to tell
myself that
all right first one let's go over hiring
controversial take soft skills are more
than important than being a Smee I know
this is really weird I know I exactly
it just uh if you didn't hear the the
breath on the recording it was there
um hot takes are so hot right now
if you're a jerk nothing will get done
at knapsec this is not pin testing I
love pin testing I'm an offensive
security guy if I could just break crap
and laugh all day I would I mean it'd
just be amazing but that's not the
reality your first hire in my opinion oh
this is my opinion right it's I'm full
of crap anyway so uh 50 50 mix of
amazing soft skills and application
security if you can find that one guy or
lady or whoever is going to be
um
I don't want to tell your principal
engineer but whatever everybody needs
someone that's going to Mentor well you
need that person to be balanced uh if
they're just super technical but they
suck at talking to people they will not
Mentor well I promise you and if they're
not technical enough but they're really
friendly
well then they're going to look stupid
in a meeting at some point if they're
the upper range of people I've been that
person multiple times
high level of understanding of apps
that's okay you know around the people
that I work with I work with some of the
best engineers in my opinion in the
world I would say that I'm non-technical
I'm obviously technical I code and I
break and all that kind of stuff but I
am Matt Graber is one of my colleagues I
am not sitting there finding new dll
injections from Microsoft before they
hit the market and that kind of stuff
um
but
you know it's I have a very good
overarching understanding of how
security works because I'm a bad guy and
uh and I loved that part of it
um you don't need 10 years of Dev
experience stop trying to find the
Unicorn everybody wraps Up's like I want
to get that senior web engineer who fell
in love with security and works 10 hours
a day and then studies for four hours a
night and never talks to their family
that's the guy that I want and I wanted
to do it for a hundred thousand dollars
a year that person does not exist and if
you do find him guess what someone like
dragos or someone else is going to grab
him and pay him a quarter million
dollars a year and you're like dang it
so don't look for that
um you need to find people from
everywhere you need to find good Bridge
Builders this is a huge huge huge deal
it's such a hard skill to find it's very
easy to burn Bridges
uh but you need to look for that in your
interview process and and
you know I'm the uh extrovert that
adopts all the introverts in my company
I'm like quarterly hackathons we all
meet up in Denver I take everybody that
doesn't have friends basically they have
friends but not in the office right and
I take them to the bar and buy them
steak and make them get drunk and talk
to people and um that's also kind of
like how I pair up people on my team if
you get someone who's just this awesome
software developer and they want their
soft skills to work you need to buddy
that person up with someone who's going
to let them grow and they'll grow them
too I mean I have a guy who's wrote half
the code for simgrip on my team now I'm
very thankful I stole him but he helps
me with my like deeper python
understanding and I help him not tell
Engineers they're stupid it's like it's
a mutual relationship and it's wonderful
and we're good buddies if you just
walked in I'm super sarcastic I don't
really call my Engineers stupid they're
way smarter than me
um
appsec has insane salaries you probably
can't afford it if you can then build a
better team than me and and do the talk
like right like I wish I could just pay
everybody a quarter million dollars
uh and this is just a plug for me funny
sarcastic people can be great bridge
Builders we work primarily with
Engineers it's a different audience than
traditional infosec
and that's really true GRC people
corpsec people in my opinion you want a
different personality type
there are more of the disciplinarians
and in reality because they have to be
they can enforce those things you know
if you're downloading some sort of
malware porn thing on your on your
workbox then you should be told you're
being stupid right like that's NADA but
you know if you're dealing with super
smart engineers and you're like I just
don't think we should use that Library
you shouldn't be forceful you need to
learn you know it's a different it's a
different vibe
yes that is literally I have a baby
about that old I think she made that
face to me earlier
um and I never noticed that so hiring uh
posing view hire Rockstar security
developers fixed all the bad code so I
have friends like Jim manicode and and
all these like super famous abstract
people who are all developers and
they're like no we don't need appsec
teams we need real security developers
and they go in there and they fix
everything for everybody and that's
their job and I'm like well one if you
get a really deep code set like we have
uh you're not gonna unless you're in
that deep every day you have no idea
what's going on there you know people
should write notes in their code they
don't so no one knows what's going on
you're just trying to figure things out
and you don't have time for that but two
that does not scale at all
um so even if you can find them it's
very hard there's not enough of them
so it will never scale like that's great
when you have 100 people right what
about when you have ten thousand and
eight thousand of them are developers I
mean we have to be able to scale at
appsec or you end up like all the other
companies that get breached because they
don't have web security right
um what else do I write here I forgot
they can easily uh become a block for
engineering I see that all the time
because it becomes schmee versus me it's
like I'm smarter than you and I'm
smarter than you and everybody's so
smart and then nothing gets done and
then everybody's like I don't talk with
that team now because they're dick heads
like that's your biggest fear that's how
you should go into appsec it's like we
don't want we want to be the cool guys
okay so this is a big deal for me uh
leadership I'm really really really
passionate about leadership because
from coming from multiple Industries and
coming into into a leadership position
in security kind of right off the bat
and being in Tech
uh leadership sucks especially in
security and I have some great friends
of mine I've had some hard conversations
with because I see how they lead their
teams and not at our company like we're
just friends and I'm like you're a dick
like don't do that like you need to
change things and they don't even get it
you know a lot of people were just
really good at what they did and they
got put into leadership and that's not
necessarily the best skill set for that
so
um
this is where many teams fail good
security person isn't necessarily a good
team leader if your team leader doesn't
genuinely care about the individual's
success as well as the teams you get
shitty middle management and there's so
much
as far as the eyes can see that's the
meme I should put there but uh man so
don't ever forget that you can your HR
team which is this is their job and they
forget this needs to build out paths to
success for individual contributors and
people leaders
such a big deal like if someone can't
get to principal and make great money
the only way to make good money is to go
into the leadership and people leading
but they suck at people leading guess
what everybody suffers for that so
you know have hard conversations with uh
HR people about this kind of stuff
because it's important especially if you
want to retain talent because Talent
will leave in a heartbeat
so my things servant-minded leadership
this means your customer focused team
you're leading your team so they're your
customer so you're customer focused all
the time
um you're actually focused on your team
members success and leading from the
front doing the work you're the block
person you're not throwing your team
under the bus you know if your team
screws up you take the hit
it's hard stuff you know it's it's
really it's really difficult to get your
brain around that stuff sometimes
especially when they do something really
stupid but um you know everybody around
me was like and I'm not even the
director right now at our company I'm
actually like some weird shitty middle
management thing
um but I care about all the guys on my
team I guess I'm the that the lead
engineer or something it's like when we
have one-on-ones I'm actually asking
them like hey dude what do you want to
do like where what what's going to be
interesting where do you want to go with
your career how can I help you with that
and even if it means them going
somewhere else you know
um these are real people you know it's
not just about you and the company and
it's it's a but when you do that and
people see the sincerity of it they bust
their ass for you not only do that but
they do better work they feel more
comfortable and there's not this like I
have to get over this person on the team
and I have to be better than them and
blah blah blah it cuts all that crap out
we have a very honest company I just
turned on a giant pay raise to leave my
company and go do a CSO job somewhere
else and I won't because there's such
good leadership there right now so it's
trickle down
um
humility and honesty uh makes up for not
knowing everything gives team the chance
to shine yeah oh man if you can lead
from the front with I don't know that
does anybody else know the answer to
this I don't want to make the wrong
decision here and you give someone else
a chance to step up and like show that
they knew something there it's such a
big boost especially for younger
Engineers you got guys in their 20s uh
that means the world I've actually had
guys slack me after meetings and be like
dude thanks for giving me the chance to
talk about that it meant the world to me
and I'm like cool yeah I didn't know and
I didn't want to sound like a dick so I
said I don't know
um it's always worse to to try to be
like know it all boss guy
um honest visibility be open where
you're crushing it where you need help
such a big deal we have a very very my
team is very mean uh in a loving way
we're all actually tight we make fun of
each other constantly but we're also
incredibly honest with everything uh
when we know we suck at something we're
just open about it because we don't
worry about getting fired because we're
all tight we're not trying to throw each
other the bus
um like when it comes to like some of my
code I'm like my code is trash please
don't look at that you can go fix it I'm
gonna go run a tool and like make some
speech somewhere and then we'll be good
you know and they know that
um taking responsibility for your
failures and learn to care about other
people which is so difficult
have you guys met people
have you ever driven a car
people suck
and you have to somehow care about them
every day as the boss that is so hard to
do like just driving from from Rome
because we were evacuated by families
were from Florida stay at my buddy's
house to drive over here to do this talk
today I'm like I have my kids in the
back and I'm like trying to hold it
together like I'm gonna murder half the
people on this road because people are
driving like idiots and like I have the
kids in the car and then I like always
think about this and I'm like these are
people the real people somehow have to
care about them I don't know how to do
that right now but when it comes to your
team you know people are going to be
butts and you just somehow have to be
like okay well I'm bleeding and this is
servant minded leadership which is
I'm just going to kind of figure out how
to make your life better it's where you
stop being a butt and I'm gonna tell you
you're a butt so that's an important
part of it too it's that Honesty part
this guy haunts my dreams because the
first actually both companies that came
in there was this guy
and this guy burned so many damn Bridges
I have bought so many beers so many
dinners had to talk about the stupidest
thing why are some people into small
dogs I don't want to hear about your dog
but I will do this if I can build a
bridge between you and my team to make
sure this happens and then I have
fantasies of kicking your small dog
um sorry German Shepherd guy I just this
is my life
every company will be different but
here's how I try to place us
um as appsec team we view our position
as internal sales customer service a
hundred percent similar to like modern
I.T programs if you're IT company or
like your it team does not see itself as
internal sales to the rest of the
company you need to go grab that
director and be like you're 10 years
behind this is how we do things now have
good customer service
um it's a a really weird thing we touch
sea level that sounds gross I'm going to
change that product managers Engineers
managers I.T and sales and GRC
I work with those people weekly that
sounds insane right you think I should
just be like hacking code all day and
running burp Suite until my fingers
bleed but um no it's like we can produce
a massive amount of value like we know
vulnerabilities better than most people
we can actually portray risk better than
GRC can because we see the actual
technical side of it as opposed to I
mean there's technical GRC people but
most of them are more compliance right
so this is how you build that value this
is how we become one of the most
important teams because we're one of the
most expensive teams in a company when
you start building it out
uh I do want my team to be loved by the
company it's really important for me my
team is rock stars at our company like
really like people when we fly into
Denver everybody gets together people
want to go out uh and hang out with a
bar with us and last time we went to
like open mic night and uh went and saw
a comedy show stand-up show together
took a bunch of the people from the
company it's important I want people to
think of us that way because it that's
how you get stuff done uh we should add
value to security and everything we
touch and that's a really big thing if
you're not actually adding value you
know you can tell I have a business
background if you're not adding value
you are not valuable oh that's a hard
one to get around when you think like
I'm just fixing stuff
no you're just wasting money now if it's
actually not valuable stuff so you got
to be real poignant on on how you look
at all those things yes this is my world
I'm a threat modeler because I am a
criminal so I know how to think this way
and other people like that's a great
skill set I'm like this is just because
my brain's broken so uh
absec path the normal one is always a
good tool run tools sin volts two
engineering about them not being
ignored I can't believe these idiots
they don't care about us that's how
appsec is or has been at least right
that sucks
um
so threat modeling should help you find
real areas of concern and exploitable
vulnerabilities this is what you should
start before you run a single tool
this is everything this is how you
should do this before you hire so you
know who to hire so you know what kind
of what kind of blind spots you have on
your side what are your weaknesses you
need to build out a procedure for threat
modeling so others can learn and
Implement you shouldn't be the only
person threat modeling I have every one
of my Engineers on my embedded teams
connect threat model now and they're
good at it they're better than me they
find all kinds of stuff
um
you shouldn't be threat modeling alone I
usually try and have an engineer sales
engineer or architect related thing with
threat models I invite people in that
normally wouldn't be there because they
think differently a diverse mindset and
a diverse group of people are going to
find diverse vulnerabilities
this is an awesome chance to build
Bridges with engineering especially if
they have never done this before they
get so excited it's like Teach an
engineer how to run burp Suite or take
them into a threat modeling meeting give
them a beer everybody's so yeah and then
we can do this and did you know that we
keep plain text passwords and I'm like
what the
no no we don't do that and then I have
to like you know reel it back in but you
find that stuff with the engineers you
don't find that stuff on I mean yeah
you'll find plain text passwords on your
own because that's dumb but you don't
find the real vulnerabilities until
you're like oh yeah yeah we SSH into
that box and we all share the same
password
okay that's another time that my
appendix burst when in a meeting you
know and it's it's not going to happen
though unless you bring them in so make
it fun
at beer food drink and black hoodies
give them black hoodies they think
they're hacking just give them black
hoodie like here this is our company
black hoodie now you're a hacker sweet
um and this is like my perfect threat
model
um but you know that's how it works
government Overlord so yeah I made this
big joke about the feds last time and uh
and then I didn't read the schedule at
RVA SEC and the FBI followed my talk
and they were like I was like tell my
FBI Handler you know I hope you got my
Christmas present and the guy's on there
he's like Dave I didn't get your
Christmas present and you've been bad
and I was like
shoot so
okay sdlc secure software development
life cycle yay this is what everybody
thinks appsec is and it is this is this
is our road map
road map uh secure sdlc is implementing
a set of controls to secure your
software development life cycle your
threat model first like I just said you
can't secure what you don't understand
pushing left is not always the right
place to start I know if there's a sales
person in here they're like that's wrong
you need relationships built on
Implement all these controls if you not
you will get ignored you have to build
those relationships first this is super
hard but like I know every engineering
manager I know our VP engineering very
very well I have buy-in from product I
did all of that before I started even
running tools or anything
um
you got to start with one control you
got to plan out the next year and then
you got to constantly adjust when people
like throw a fit about it you have to be
flexible many things won't work and you
won't understand your work culture until
you screw up and you piss a lot of
people off but if you're cool and you're
humble and you're like I'm so sorry you
know I baked you a Turkey
um they're gonna be like okay it's not
that bad he gave us turkey you know
whatever I don't know what you're gonna
make them but after implementing control
step back and build a plan for
continuous Improvement my KR is every
single month continuous Improvement is a
giant one there
it's boring
but it actually works these tools I
don't care who you have you have Snick
it's going to take you I know it's like
sneaky sneaky I don't know you have that
one it's going to take you a year to get
that right
don't listen to a single sales person
they're all liars except ours they're
good
um
any of these guys that sell appsec tools
they take so long to tune and it's not
just like the false positive stuff it's
getting your vulnerability management
process down it's figuring out what is
false positives and actually can't be
exploited as opposed to just things you
know that like oh that shouldn't be a
big deal until that third party library
that we had accidentally dropped
something and now they can compound
everything and now we're screwed
it takes a long time to get these things
so continuous improvements massive and
it builds trust with your engineering
team if they see you
suck a little less each quarter on how
you address vulnerabilities and how much
time you wasted of theirs they're like
okay those guys are doing their thing
they're maturing it's a young team
um
what else did I put in there
if a control is a blocking control start
it as an education and suggestion
control slowly move it to blocking to
mandatory make sure you have buy-in and
written policy
write your policies you need
that's the stick right you don't ever
want to use the stick but you're like no
you can't write your own crypto dum-dum
they're like why not I'm an amazing
developer like it's in the policy
I put that as number one you were never
allowed to do that
um it makes a huge difference but if
it's a blocking control if you're
putting something in your CI CD pipeline
it's a tool and somehow it has blocking
don't do it
don't do it for a full year I know that
sounds crazy
wait to see how many times you would
have screwed up prod
before you have the balls to block it
really like threat model take your time
on everything it's really important
because that's a super way to like burn
all that value that you made they're
like you're just wasting our time now I
had to have 22 Engineers this weekend
roll that back because we couldn't get
it out in time and then we pushed it too
fast and you know it gets it can get bad
step for each control I actually have
these written down on my desk it sounds
silly but I have to remind myself
because I get ahead of myself and just
run through things so you want to learn
what are we going to solve technology we
use what part of the company do we need
to understand uh enumerate
plan get all the people involved and
start putting everything together design
look at how to implement the control in
your company it needs to be a holistic
approach don't just read anybody's book
on apps that can be like that's how we
do it think for yourself you're all
intelligent people if you're an appsec
there's no dummies here
um you need to get your approval and
your buy-in before you execute that's a
huge huge deal and you need to figure
out who actually you need that approval
and buying from it's a big deal you miss
that one person and you screw up their
team and you jam them up you're going to
have a rough day right so execute do
your plan right and then improve that's
the other thing you figure out where
they're pissed you go hey I'm so sorry I
screwed this up please let me come back
and fix it and make it better for you
okay this is my sdlc plan uh that I like
kind of I mean
this is the basic stuff right these are
the controls you want to implement
um that's really small and I don't have
glasses on uh but yeah so you know sras
threat modeling uh you know you got all
these different uh companies in here
that you can just buy and do stuff with
and they make your day suck every day
and then you have to have calls with
their sales people every other week and
you just learn to hate them
sorry I zoned out a little
um you know but uh these are the things
you have to cover you know it's kind of
hard I'm not going to go through all
that there's a million talks about that
but my slides are here or if you just
hit me up on LinkedIn I'll tell you what
I'm thinking first control
boom should be holistic I like that word
based on your company
don't start with stats that's not
holistic that just pisses everybody off
SAS has is a very important tool that
static analysis security testing if you
don't know super important tons of false
positives makes everybody angry don't
start with SAS that is a good way to
just plummet your program and it's
expensive
um and if you do one uh find one that
you can tune
very easily that's I'm not going to like
give Brands and stuff uh pick and
control with low false except for Red
Canary you can always use them uh pick
control with low false positives for
your first one this is huge writing
policy to back up your Patrol like we
talked about you need to be thoughtful
set your tone for the entire security
program this is so much bigger than you
understand in the beginning that first
control
is like if you can kind of go okay with
it people like okay they didn't burn the
house down yet you know but you will
piss someone off cookies and beer help
it's true
okay don't there's a trigger warning
don't get dazzled by shift left
everybody knapsack shift left shift left
shut up it's a horrible way to start
you should shift left after you have a
mature program
sometimes you're better off shifting
right fewer false positives the further
right you go the farther left you go you
have tons and tons of more false
positives
uh shifting left will still be a goal
but sometimes it's easier to start right
next controls
different for every team holistic
approach uh you have a budget and a lot
of code
you could try saster SCA
um
I wouldn't say SAS I just put that in
there I'd say you know
try SCA that's a lot better all your
third party analysis uh are you
overwhelmed is it just you and you're
like I'm drowning security Champions or
slackbot my slackbot's gangster my
slackbot will tell you how dumb you are
when you do something and it'll also
give you praise it's like hey good job
buddy
you didn't write your own crypto today
um hired some folks
yes we have a team now embedded security
Engineers I'm very passionate about this
we are one to one right now that's not
realistic for anybody I mean that's like
oh one to three is fine you can sit
through three 15-minute
um stand-ups right and you can do that
two times a week and you actually know
what code is going on you know what
issues the engineers are actually
working on at that moment massive thing
if you have enough people
uh sort of fancy new product coming out
if you talk to your product team do you
know your product team if you don't know
your product team
get to know them because those are the
guys that are like we're gonna build
this thing and I don't know how
engineering Works we're gonna plug stuff
into it and then it's going to do these
things and then everybody's gonna lose
their data all right if you become
friends with them you can threat model
or do sras right off the bat security
risk assessments are kind of like old
school you know but we still do them
because they kind of
make you look at at the engineering and
the code and everything so it can be
important
um what worked for me
for my first ones for this last let's
get to go with Red Canary that's what
this one is Dash and thread modeling
that's how I started I love dast
Das Das it's cheap no one cares about it
anybody can buy burp sweet
zap sucks
um but you know it's
it's amazing run run desk you're
actually finding real
problems in production
don't run on production if you can't
handle it like don't just go ha and then
you crash production uh it's it's great
if you have a safe place you can run it
locally or something like that
um but it's a great place to start
because when you do find things it'll be
a manageable list like you run your even
if it's just burp spider or something
like that it'll run through and it's
going to give you like what 30 or 40
things you're like okay I can one person
can go through this and tell which ones
are false positives and then you go hey
I broke into your system here
don't do it that way but it actually
gives you something real
um and then the threat modeling side is
amazing to start that way if that's your
first control you're going to not only
do threat modeling but you're going to
teach each team how to do threat
modeling and you're going to do it with
them that one builds Bridges doesn't
cost the company well it costs a little
time so that is a real thing but you can
do it and manual find some scary stuff
got kubernetes
how many of those spots you think are
written as root I promise you a few of
them are you want to see someone break a
container out go watch e in cold water
it happens so you will find some really
really good stuff that way and you build
those relationships which are super
important uh
embedded with engineering like I said a
minute ago I jumped ahead on my slide
sorry uh when you're for a mature team
and you're growing this is the most
successful thing I've had if you don't
have enough Engineers I have this thing
that I call the security task force or
so we're um we're a Red Canary we're all
like bird names like we're the flock
right so I keep trying to get them to be
the murder Squad because it's the crows
and they're in the black hats but it
hasn't caught on yet they just think I'm
weird I'm like let's go murder Squad and
they're like no David sit down
um but whatever that's the other way to
do it you can embed these engineers and
they sit in on the stand-ups and they
help with stuff and they're it's amazing
when you have a security engineer in
stand up and they're like hey how should
we connect to this third-party API and
the guy's like oh we should do that and
secure you guys like oh hey I think if
we do it this way we don't really have
to worry about any security issues
because that way can can be good or it
can be a little off and they're like oh
cool thanks for making me not rewrite
this entire API connection
it's so powerful to have secure embedded
Securities but
not everybody can do that there's two of
you there's three of you right what do
you do
get buy-in build trust you don't have to
hire 10 security Engineers you can go in
work your butt off a couple years in
your VP of engineering is like those
guys are solid they've been doing such a
good job security task force
get a two-week Sprint rotation with
developers on the security team
you will work on real development
problems you'll work on backlog you know
old Tech whatever you got a patch or
whatever but you have these people for
two weeks
let's all run burp Suite today let's
just destroy some crap where offensive
security but these are regular Engineers
they leave with a security mindset they
leave that two-week Sprint with like oh
the security guys do cool stuff we could
do cool stuff it's like you know it's
like a advanced version of security
Champions I hate security Champions it's
the name of it bothers me it sounds like
some real creepy thing like but that's
another way to do this if you don't have
the Manpower
um
yeah then there's the things and the
words I wrote
build trust have you seen how many times
I said build trust
it's amazing tools yay what do we want
all the tools why because we never ever
ever want to stop looking at false
positives for the rest of our lives
oh man I'm like become a minimalist with
tools I'm trying to lower it and lower
it and lower it even the big name
companies because I spend a lot of money
I'm pulling out some of their newer
features because they suck
they're not tested they're giving me all
this trash they're built they're burning
my value right now they're burning my
trust with engineering and I don't care
what I have to do like there's some
great you know open source stuff out
there like Sim grip open source and even
the Snick open source and like some of
those they may not be
Ai and machine learning which is all Bs
anyways but they can like you can tune
them real easily so you can be like okay
I know I have one problem
these group of people keep writing
passwords the wrong way and they're not
using this so I can search for that you
can start minimalizing this where you
don't have to use these giant companies
that just bombard you with crap all day
if I have to sit in one more sales
trying to re-hire me meeting thing
I'm going to lose my mind
but
um don't trust the hype sales people can
be sketchy I know I was one of them uh
the less tools you do the job adequately
the better uh looking at 17 things a day
is the path to the dark side that's how
you turn into that guy from before
build a plan before you acquire the
tools this is so big
that like list of things that's how I
started and then I had all my team
members there's a lot of us there's
eight of us we're we're beast mode team
because we got buy-in from the beginning
so we had budget and I'm like hey
we're going to take a control one at a
time we're all going to look at and
we're all going to compare and I built a
little thing in Excel and it's like does
this do this plus five points does this
do this plus seven points for each
control so I could so I had to be more
pragmatic because these sneaky sales
vendors know that I like whiskey and
they're like hey Dave we sent you a
hundred dollar bottle of whiskey you
know just for checking our demo out I'm
like you sneaky and then it's even worse
when you push code you know I've written
a few rules for some of these companies
and I started getting their t-shirts and
I'm like oh I have T-shirts now I I
could use them next year you know it's
it's all it's a bad social engineering
we're doing the good social engineering
uh spend time real time testing tools I
spent like 30 days on each control
minimum I got pocs from all the people
that were supposedly good and I pounded
into them I looked at everything we had
discussions like very like straight up
fights at one point over certain tools
because people were passionate about
this that are in appsec
um which I encourage I want us as long
as we're not being rude to each other to
basically yell about things it's good
um we tested all the tools and then we
made it really really rational decisions
and we're already changing some from our
second year uh second yeah second year
acquisition stuff so you know that's
that continuous Improvement side you're
not going to pick and people lie they
say things can do things that they can't
and then you're like wow you're a
billion dollar company and a
three-year-old wrote your API and it
crashes every single day cool I'm glad
we gave you seventy thousand dollars you
know it's it's insane you don't find
that stuff out until later because they
hide it in the pocs so be ready to tell
people there's a chance we'll roll this
over because we don't want to burn our
value right
um tune improve before you get another
tool spend some time on it it doesn't
have to be fast showing you know
whoever's doing your budget VP
engineering c-suite whatever CTO showing
them how fast you're moving and how much
you've Acquired and burned through your
budget is not show anything like it to
us it does because we're like look at
all we did if you get one tool and then
you spend the next month making it
perfect as perfect as you can before you
roll it out you're testing it locally
and making sure you're not just going to
destroy everybody the people up top
appreciate that because redoing
something engineering wise costs a lot
more than doing it the right time right
so spend some time it's a slow process
don't get you know worried about it and
explain all those things up front for
whoever your buy-in is
uh no budget no toys
yeah so how do we get budget
hey what's our time sorry on this one 3
45 to 4 4 okay cool uh we're fine
how do we budget apps that program this
really is the internet if you didn't
know this if you don't work in appsec
with third-party libraries
when that idiot didn't sign the stuff
for Ruby last year we're a ruby shop I
had an aneurysm like I was like what am
I gonna do we have all these customers
we have to fix this things and Nancy
can't use it because he didn't change
his licensing and blah blah blah blah
blah
have backup plans for your third party
libraries you know and have them written
down I know that sounds crazy but I
literally have a list of what we have
you know on a Excel spreadsheet because
I'm in Tech and then next to it I have
competitors that I can grab because I
don't you can't memorize all this crap
there's so much so I know like okay we
just lost that because of a
vulnerability we can't patch let's see
who we can plug in there
um it's work but it's it makes things go
fast
so sometimes you can't
open source tools that's what you got to
do they still cost they still cost money
it's just Manpower they cost more for
tuning for all these kind of things and
I'm getting pretty burnt out on a lot of
the vendors that build off the open
source and they're like oh built you
this amazing GUI it's going to work
better so you pay us money and then it
doesn't you're like cool
so you really have to decide like what
are we going to build where are we going
to buy it's it's a really tricky thing
um but you can slowly show value which
will earn a new budget but you have to
be upfront about it be like I'm going to
prove to you that we're a team that's
worth money in this company
we're gonna and and we're gonna do that
here's my plan
so you don't jam up engineering
uh you plan everything out Implement
control slowly in fact it'd be super
open with everybody that has buy-in on
this it's massive deal you need to tell
people because they're going to spend
100 Grand 200 Grand if you're at like
Amex we're half my team because I stole
them uh used to be I mean they spend
like three four or five million a year
on their security tools right so
earn that trust and you can just be open
from the beginning
um you got to plan everything out you
got to keep your metrics and findings
remediation we'll talk about metrics
metrics suck but you I have like a few
things that help me and you have to
build those bridges you really do and
you got to keep that communication I
have one-on-ones with so many people in
my company that are like 30 minute like
coffee morning I have like this big
espresso machine so I'm always like
making espressos and hanging out with
people and it seems like I'm wasting
time I'm not when I need to get
something done I'm the person that
anybody in security I'm the whole it
team will go to because I I care about
people and we've built relationships and
we're friends
um
now with some value you do these things
you got to learn to communicate a
business-based audience to a
business-based audience if you can show
Executives why financially it's good for
your company you'll get a real budget
being able to communicate effectively
with c-suite and board it's what uh you
know that's how you can get an exploit
cost the company how much money okay
this is how it works that's that's hard
to communicate if you're not used to it
if you're just used to working with
Engineers I career coach a bunch of
people like as part of like my wife and
I's Ministry is get people
from poorer areas or you know places
where they never heard that you can make
real money in Tech into Tech and the
number one thing I do and it doesn't
matter if you're you know black white
Latino like whatever
if you're from that area I make you go
to Toastmasters before you even start
anything
and people are like that's weird I'm
like no it's not do you know how many
interviews I have were guys smart but he
can't even say his own name because he's
never had to like communicate things
properly how are you going to tell
the CEO that we're going to lose 40
million dollars if they don't spend 150
000 on engineering right now to fix a
problem
you know that's the difference between a
hundred thousand dollar abstract job and
a 250 000 abstract jog is being able to
communicate that line that's the
difference between a CSO and like
someone who's going to tap out a
principal and they're never going to
move into in into any of that stuff so
it's huge and um like I used to do bids
with my company and I worked across that
and I know I talk like a dumb Surfer
because I'm from Hawaii and everything
but uh I know how to like get value get
distress if something's really bad I can
I can go through and tell people in a
way that works for me and works for them
and it's sounds silly but it's massive
useful metrics
God I hate metrics so you might hear
have to build their own metrics
yes you feel my pain bro
they suck so much and I've like lost my
mind because I hate Splunk I don't know
the language I'm always trying to like
Google it on stack exchange like how do
you make a pie chart and Splunk and then
I'm like I hate this
keyboard against the wall
um okay this is what I do they're so
hard but I figured out what metrics need
to do
I like hacked metrics
at least for my head because I'm so
pragmatic I have to like figure these
things out so I can follow a path
um they need to tell a story
and the social engineering part What
story do they need to tell for who
you have to figure out what that person
thinks and what they want from their job
and I've actually asked people this
because half time csos will ask you for
metrics and you're like I'm like what
are you trying to get from this
and they don't know they're just so
ingrained in it that they have no idea
what they're doing and you're like okay
we really need to figure this out before
I go and waste a bunch of time and
Splunk and cry for the next six weeks
um so now I make them
I make my metrics tell a story and I
make them tell a story that's going to
fix the question that needs to be asked
by whoever it is asking me for it and
they have to like put their time into I
don't ever anymore when someone's like I
want some metrics on that tool like no
I'm not gonna waste time on that tell me
what you want answered and I will build
you a beautiful colorful story
in horrible Splunk dashboards you know
um but that that really is what it is
and it's It's tricky because
you know it can be the little things
like
well we had this many vulnerabilities
last month and we only have this many
this month and it's like did that really
help us
I mean it showed that somebody updated
one package
what's our risk there like what what
percentage of risk do we reduce on the
company like then you got to build a few
more things because you're like okay I'm
now telling a story I'm showing the
c-suite that we lowered reduce lowered
the risk reduction by 15 this quarter
because we knocked out 1500 critical
vulnerabilities that couldn't be
exploited but if something fell apart
they could you know what I mean and this
is all ethereal this is a little hard to
like get in there and figure out but now
you're showing like okay well if this is
real we might have saved the company a
million dollars okay you guys are worth
a little bit more now you know we were
ahead because we had all this fixed when
that patch came out we could actually
patch because we're on the correct
version of Ruby on Rails right now
instead of you know six years behind
because no one will change any of their
code like those kind of things that's
massive because I'd be like hey we
patched this we wouldn't have been able
to patch it and we would have got busted
on this one it's like when um
uh uh what was it called HTTP smuggling
I found that at our company uh using
burp and I was like oh my gosh we have
to figure this out it like got in there
with engineering and spent much time it
was Amazon's fault stupid Cloud Player
uh but then I called them you know and
and had it fixed but it was like one of
those things if we wouldn't had our
ducks in the row and we weren't
organized and I wouldn't have already
proved value when I called cloudflare
they probably wouldn't like kick rocks
but we were big dog it wasn't right
Canary
um but those kind of things are huge
um so
you need to have some sort of view on
things
education training is massive I'm in
charge of this at our company right now
for this quarter
it's the hardest thing there is but I
I'm so passionate about it but I'm also
so burnt out on it because it's so
tricky but
um education training can't suck
I don't know how to tell anybody does
that you know like I've bought the big
vendors and I've I've used our own and
I don't even know what I wrote on here
actually
uh social engineer security culture in
your company that's so important uh
onboarding from the beginning you need
to do it uh be passionate about teaching
I'm just running through this because
I'm going to change it
um
yeah
Okay cool so that that's all true still
uh this is where I'm at right now with
it though because I just revamped this
again
I have a company that gives the little
training where the engineers can go in
and we do a quarterly training and they
have to do their apps like training and
blah blah blah blah
and they do it because I begged them
literally they didn't they like threw a
fit in the beginning but I had enough
invested that I'm like bro how many
times have I got the bar tab for you
guys like you're gonna do this it's
gonna take you an hour a quarter
um and then I also because the new guys
don't know any better everybody comes
along gets that training uh they have
like I built out a special one just for
onboarding to make sure we hit all the
basics for our code base what like we
could see them introducing you don't
need to hit them with a bunch of stuff
like
that they can't use if you cannot be SQL
injected don't make them train on SQL
injection
um but now
I built a couple ctfs that we all did
and now I'm doing some stuff where I'm
looking at all the metrics from there
right seeing where we fail over and over
what stuff we actually hit on I'm like
okay okay well this team works for uh
Linux agent we built our own you know
and this team Works mostly with the
Microsoft stuff and this team is our
Cloud team
they all have a security engineer
so the next step for us is they're going
to do lunch and learns with their team
that are pinpointed to their weakest
points so it's actually interesting to
them because they know they suck at it
every engineer knows they suck at what
they suck at like especially if you just
get busted on it you know with multiple
times with different tools
so now we're pinpointing we're getting a
little bit better but it's still a long
way to go this is the hardest one if you
can figure out how to train people and
make security fun in your company and
every company has a different culture
you're going to win because then I mean
my whole thing is to work myself out of
a job I've already almost done that I
hired a lot of people are smarter than
me I'm like okay maybe I'll just go to
sales make giant money now but it's the
same thing with this stuff if I can make
all my Engineers into security people
why would I even want to uh be around
anymore I'm okay I'll go do something
else I'll make canoes
uh social engineering security culture
culture good social engineering learns
what is beneficial to both parties this
is my sales background knows the
audience has buy-in from all parties
needed builds a culture based on trust
and visibility servant leadership bad
social engineering self-focused goals
are you just trying to get stuff done
for you if you're not adding value to
whoever you're doing it to then it's not
good does not benefit all parties
involved manipulation zero visibility
uses a stick instead of the carrot so I
was going to be a physical penetration
guy I can break into anything in the
world like I grew up first job as a
locksmith I love all that crap uh then I
had kids I'm like okay I actually want
to be home for my kids but it's a
massive thing the bad side of social
engineering I'm very good at it I can
walk in anywhere even with this big
stupid mustache I when I was like 15 I
snuck into tons and tons of concerts by
just walking backstage and acting like I
was supposed to be there and that kind
of stuff
that is the side though that I see in
security they're just like oh man you
know you need to do this and do this and
like there's like Dave told me to be
nice to you I was like no you have to
offer them something in return there has
to be something there yeah I'm going to
take you out and you know make you talk
to people and eat good food and drink
beer and stuff like that but
that's not me getting him do it I'm
always giving them value somehow
and you have to figure out what it is
for yours you know I've had instances
where we fix code it makes their life a
thousand times better because their
code's more organized they have testing
in place now and they're not getting
jammed up when they're trying to push to
prod anymore because it's not a tangled
mess that's huge value you just got to
figure out what it's going to be for
your little team that you're working
with
um yeah we went through all this stuff
continuous Improvement
I'm on this next quarter I'm running
continuous Improvement I hate it because
it's vulnerability reduction all that
kind of stuff uh but it's so important
one should you control can ruin your
whole program uh constantly improve
everything you implement uh why would
anybody take it seriously if the team
doesn't care which happens all the time
right you have Sloppy code you have
Sloppy tools you have Sloppy findings
you don't know why are they going to
respect you right you know it's like one
of those things like I'm definitely that
guy like makes my bed in the morning
even though I'm like the biggest Dirtbag
I like lived in Vans half my life and
I'm like I'm gonna make my bed in the
morning this is gonna you know you can
respect me now but it's the same thing
you gotta like take care of your stuff
um refine the obvious things first get a
recurring meeting with engineering
managers uh to critique controls huge
get a meeting once a month please tell
me what I'm doing that's making you
angry and sucks
I say it just like that and there was oh
yeah this was my time to kick you right
in the balls Dave
um but it's so important because you get
honest feedback and they love it they're
like oh you're actually you actually
care about this stuff instead of
fighting in like a stupid meeting about
it
um refined controls by studying your
super sweet new metrics automate
everything you can because working sucks
um be customer focused to your
engineering team and be objective just
because it's your favorite tool does not
mean it does not suck
usually it's always my favorite tool
that I have to like roll back I'm like
dang it failed again and I failed many
times
uh some ways forward
ah yeah easy stuff try to find the most
uh obvious things first wait
is that a different one oh yeah it was
sorry
oh no that was it I didn't even know I
hit it okay yeah so and that's pretty
much it it's it's a weird talk right
it's appsec without all the cool
technical stuff and I didn't show you
how many times I've broken something
hacking people is a hell of a lot harder
than hacking code but is the most
important thing and that's why appsec
Engineers are making more than just
about anybody right now it's stupid
money so uh I'm on LinkedIn I'm super
open to this stuff if if you ever need
questions asked or anything like that
just I'm I'll I'll talk with you if you
need like business stuff I have a
consulting company you think but does
anybody have any questions
oh whoa okay let's we'll go this way is
that cool
for education
uh yes if there are any training methods
that work better than others in my
experience uh no
you know what I've the only thing I
found is an individual approach on
trying to figure out
what helps people and and how to get
them excited that security task force
thing does more than any of the
educational stuff if I can sit down like
uh like our ctfs that we have because we
have quarterly get togethers that are
work because we're all remote
um our CTF hackathon stuff goes
people get so excited about that kind of
stuff and then you can be like okay cool
and like while you're there because
you're actually involved you're like hey
let's do this I'm going to show you guys
how to use burp real quick or you know
like I'm going to show you guys how to
throw a SCA scan on all your code real
quick to look at your third party
libraries like that kind of stuff goes
super good and it's not it's almost like
not teaching but teaching you're
secretly teaching yeah so is that
hopefully at all
what do you think people can get well
yeah at my company they get behind the
idea my CEO wrote half the code we're
all security people at Red Canary I'm
cheating
most places no
you're not going to get
uh the c-suite of a non-technical
company behind security but you can
learn to communicate risk to them on and
on financial level to the point where
they're like
we don't like this but we're scared to
death of these guys like and it sounds
bad but that's the only way that I've
seen it really work and I've sat down in
meetings where people hired me on to
Consulting and I talked to the CEOs and
I like went through some stuff and I'm
like
I'm gonna take my consulting fee for
this meeting but we're going to cut it
off from that because you guys aren't
ready for security and and that's gnarly
because you think I just take money but
I actually have
you know some ethics
but it is no point I mean I have kids I
don't want to waste my time with people
who aren't trying to like better their
business right so yeah it's it's that
threat modeling thing I threat model
everything my wife hates it she's like
you're such a damn nerd but I threat
model everything like you know I would
look at my audience see what their
weaknesses are see what the value that
we can give them
okay
so maybe a dumb question but just to
confirm there's there isn't like a
Security Plus for developers there's
just some kind of class or just in
general like big developers this is how
you security oh there's a hundred
the problem is developers don't want to
do them uh it slows them down developers
want to create hit their kpis or KRS
whatever and move on to their next cool
little feature they want to build right
um
is if a developer usually has any
interest in security they become an
appsec engineer
it's very difficult because and you're
just giving them more time like at least
all the developers I know work too much
and they have hard deadlines and if
you're like hey we have this five hour
course that you need to do or like
Security Plus is like a 25 hour course
they're like kick rocks nerd like that
is not happening I'm building code I'm
doing my thing I've been doing this for
20 years don't tell me what to do and
it's it's it's a different mentality
like you have to get them to care about
security and then it's almost
self-learning like it really is like I I
generally think if you can hack that
culture in there they stop uh
caring about the little education you
have to do and they start doing their
own education
does that answer you
kind of sorry none of my answers are
like yay
oh yeah uh these guys
so I'm gonna go
[Music]
is one of you blue team
interested in Blue Team okay here we go
here we go here we go I don't want to
give you something you don't want
sweet those are for asking good
questions and sticking around for the
last talk it's like five of you
awesome guys again I'm David thank you
so much for coming I really appreciate
it
[Applause]