it's amazing my dress has pockets I'm so
glad
all right as I said before but now that
you can actually hear me my name is
Rachel Jones
um I wanted to introduce myself a little
bit because this uh topic is really near
and dear to my heart and has really
followed my career these past 10 years
yes I'm old I know it's sad but um the
reason I put this slide up here I'm
currently a cyber Analyst at Savannah
River National Lab I'm getting a my PhD
in Aerospace science I'm very excited
and focused about uh satellite cyber
security which is a subject I don't
think we talk about enough of but uh
before we get into that I kind of want
to take you guys 10 years ago when I
first heard of satellite cyber security
I was actually a
I was at the International Space
University yes I know such a university
exists it's for a bunch of space nerds
uh it's in Strasbourg France we had
about 47 students from 45 different
nations it was great and one of those I
was one of the eight selected for the
U.S to go to this University I felt
really excited and I was going to use my
powers to really influence the space
world
and that's when I heard about this this
is probably one of the coolest things uh
if you guys ever like for fun read uh
economic papers on us and China you
might have came across this oh if you
don't don't worry
um a lot of people didn't so this was uh
the first time I'd ever heard about a
satellite being hacked and not just one
satellite this was two satellites
getting hacked four different times and
the first time this actually appeared in
public was in this U.S to China report
to Congress it was published in 2011 but
supposedly the hacks happened about 2007
and 2008 and for those that don't know a
lot about satellites there's there's two
different types of hacking let's say in
this article it tries to distinguish the
landsat 7 which is a weather satellite
from NASA and the Terra am satellite
which is also a weather satellite I know
Minor Details but in one case with the
Terra they actually were able to take
over command and control
for that satellite which means in theory
that the attackers were able to actually
move the satellite and could reposition
it for their needs now this is 10 years
ago me so please forgive me
um I'm like oh my God this is the
coolest thing ever I can't believe they
can do that for satellites I didn't
really think about some of the questions
that my classmates had like well how'd
they do that I'm like I don't know but
this report said it happened yes
that's all we needed to know
but there was a lot of questions back
then no one knew how it was accomplished
no one knew if it was accomplished uh
we'd have a lot of conflicting ideas on
this and from those ideas we kind of
looked at
I decided Well what do space
professionals believe you know the
people that are actually building the
satellites controlling the satellites I
mean do they think the cyber security of
satellites is a risk and this is back in
2012 so it's not modern day and all
these ugly wonderful things I'll get
into hadn't happened yet and one of my
questions was is it's an international
environment if you think about moving
the command and control of one satellite
you could actually Ram it into another
ones yes uh that would create an
international issue in this environment
means that one thing being insecure
would affect other things around it so
you really want to have like all the
things be secure this isn't just make
sure your company is good but imagine if
you're another company that you have to
make sure all the other companies are
good too so that your things aren't
damaged so with satellites that are very
Dynamic different ways of looking at
their security needs so I wanted to do a
survey of the space professionals and
really look at what do they believe
I mean you can have all the policies in
the world but if you don't actually have
people that believe in those policies
and are willing to actually follow the
policies it doesn't mean much so my
survey back when in 2012 looked at
things like
what do they actually think the threats
were so the first and yes I know this is
an eye test so I hope you can see so I
first wanted to know what did they
actually think were the three biggest
threats to satellites in orbit this is
2012 I surveyed about 135 different
people in 22 different countries and
most of my results were from Europe and
North America but I did get a good
represented at least like five percent
from other nations and I divided them
geographically to be Asia South
South America and Africa kind of make
sure I got the little bit of everyone
and these were the three things that
they thought were the most important
risk to satellite so space debris
Collision space weather mechanical
failure now you notice I'll have a lot
of other things up here lasers from the
ground uh asteroid Collision uh what
actually got pretty high up there 11
computer failure due to user error
I like that one
um and then I asked a couple other
questions
space professionals do you think a
satellite you could actually get data
from it yes I know I wish I could have
rewarded those questions I would have
done it a little bit different but I
asked them do they think that a
satellite could be hacked likely 34
percent all right
do you think someone could get command
and control of a satellite like I told
about earlier most of them didn't think
that was likely I'm like the government
report said so
but no they still didn't believe it uh
I'm not going to share all the questions
with you I just kind of picked out six
that I thought were most interesting so
I thought attribution do you think you
could prove one person actually hacked
it
yeah
we kind of got no on that one
and then three other questions I was
going to share with you
um if an attack on a satellite happened
uh do you think it should be announced
publicly you have this commercial
satellite that was attacked should they
actually have some announcement in the
public that it was attacked
I don't want to say 50 50 because it's
not but it was pretty close here 45 to
41. who should investigate if a
satellite gets an attack
most people thought the country of
registration but you can see it's
closely followed by an international
organization and then my favorite
should there be security minimums for
satellites 68 said yes
all right since then
what has happened today I'm going to go
over probably the four biggest we got
three papers and one course that kind of
really describes the modern literature
coming from about 2019 to to current
and these really go over kind of what is
going on in this satellite cyber
security field uh this first paper I
recommend it just because it's a really
good basic and primer for people that
might not know satellite cyber security
and what we're talking about here and I
bring this up because I really want to
explain you you have different
components when you talk about where the
weaknesses is and where the
vulnerabilities are I like to say my
professor says if you really want to
work the cyber security of satellites
you have to know the space side and the
Cyber side almost equally that's why I'm
getting my PhD in Aerospace science and
others are getting their phds in cyber
so really here this breaks down the
segments um space segment ground segment
user segment they don't spell it out but
there's also a link segment how the
satellites and ground actually talk to
each other in this paper here spells out
a new trend they say in the past mostly
it has been like jamming attacks from
the ground to the satellite but now
we've actually seen more space basic
attacks so we're going from satellite to
attacking other satellites and that's
the rising Trend but this paper also
calls out some really good things about
what we're doing to protect Satellites
with the new use of software-defined
radios and other methodologies that
we're going in to harden the Cyber
Electronics aboard them
so moving on
this next paper I don't know if you know
Aerospace Corporation but they're kind
of like a think tank for the dod and
they produce this paper was really nice
um
kind of explains the Gambit of things
and if you notice in this paper it
actually breaks out the different types
of attacks used in each segment of the
space infrastructure so you got attacks
that are common to the space segment the
user segment the link segment and the
ground segment so what's going after
these guys
foreign
and now yeah this is an eye chart I just
wanted to throw you what it looks like
in the paper but this paper really goes
good to lay out the policies and the
guidelines that are being developed for
the space cyber security field so if you
want more this is the paper that's the
chart
now this paper is probably one of my
favorites okay
so
a lot of attacks have been said in the
media going against satellites anyone
ever heard of any of these attacks right
here you got the compromise of the NASA
jet propulsion lab uh remember I talked
about the landsat seven up there the
NOAA observation
this paper makes claim that none of the
attacks ever happened
I know it's really fun um I I don't want
to say this is a great conspiracy paper
read but it shows you the other side of
what to think about so most of the
reporting for various instances
reference classified documents that
people don't have access to they
reference things that are disputed so
when I talk about the landsat 7
it was actually supposedly done by a
compromise of a ground station and what
this author did was they actually talked
to the ground station the ground
station's like no that didn't happen
and they're like we don't know what the
government's talking about and it just
kind of shows you the other side when
you're investigating instances like this
did it really happen it's hard to know
because not a lot of people want to talk
about it
and uh the final thing I'll mention here
is this uh this is a Class by aiaa and
they give a good breakdown and one of
the good things that they actually
developed is the space domain cyber
security framework that kind of lists
the various segments and the different
tacts that correlate to those segments
and what you're going to be targeting
they're a different way of laying out
the framework and kind of going at it
and these are some of their good case
studies of cyber attacks to satellites
there might be some overlap between the
last slide and this side
but it's really interesting and I call
this out particularly because when
you're dealing with a space environment
which is an environment that's not here
terrestrally you have a different
outside influences that you might not
have with computers here yes it's
possible statistically a lot of things
but when you're dealing with radiation
impacts to non-hardened cyber materials
you have a component called bit flip so
I don't know if how familiar with you
guys but if you hit a a bit it actually
flips the zero to a one or vice versa
for some reason coders tell me that that
messes up with their code or something I
don't know why they can't just like deal
with that but there's environmental
impacts of being an extreme cold hot you
know radiation inducing environment that
we just don't have here on Earth and
these make it really hard I mean I know
there's a lot of blue teamers forensics
analysts in here well do you know if
that's an attacker or is that just an
environmental bit flip did they did
someone purposely go into that or did
something else happen and I like this
publication and what they put out
because they really analyzed what does
those other things look like where do we
need to go and what can or how we can
just stimulate between the two
but you know I I really wanted to see
hey
it's been 10 years I wonder what space
profession
now that we have all these lovely
documents and we've had new case studies
like you know the bias act that just
happened we had the you know Defcon
presentation of the SDR going on taking
over the Canadian decommissioned
satellite
I wonder what space professionals think
now
well
I can tell you one thing
cyber's up on the list
looking back we now have the the top
three threats to satellites
cyber is actually number three
and just because I don't think you'd
remember what the you know random bar
charts I showed you two seconds or five
minutes ago looks like I have them
compared up here
um so with this survey it went out to
space professionals I got a total of 130
respondents it was done anonymously so I
don't know who the respondents are I can
tell you most of them about 50 percent
were from North America
Europe and South America were the the
second leading contributors and um
because uh my survey skills have
improved from SurveyMonkey I I was now
able to also add some other categories
which is really nice because I got some
great responses in the other categories
one of which I'm pretty sure if I had
included it it would have dramatically
changed my entire survey they said the
best way to kill a satellite is to
destroy its funding
um
I uh I think they won but I was talking
about once this satellite was actually
in orbit and successful
not that it can't be killed by funding
moving on
um
the first question you know we went a
little bit of change uh whenever you do
statistics and study numbers uh we use
the word significant to actually mean
something uh it's greater than one
standard deviation away
and uh I also like to look at like what
the the shape it makes
so you see this one is actually a little
bit more than the others because the the
other options were a little bit less
here but if you look down here
kind of get like two bumps now
that's because
before when everyone said not likely if
you notice all the other choices yeah
all of them were below 20 well now we
have 32 and 33 that actually like almost
half and half yes or no they're a little
bit torn here and you can see the space
professionals don't know
uh they they think they could have but
more likely
moving on to the next few questions if
we look at it here we we still have the
same about half and half yes and no but
uh mandatory reporting has actually
increased a little bit
if you compare it to our 45 yes 41 no we
now have 52 yes and 34 no if you do the
math it's not a significant change but
it does does show that there is change
in the market and there is change in the
ideas and that they might be receptive
um to policy implications
here um
it's I promise this has been 10 years
but it does look almost similar to the
one done in
2012 for the which country or which
entity should be
investigating a possible hack to a
satellite
but the biggest change is the the number
of people that actually thinks a
mandatory security minimum should be
implicated
so we go from a 68 to an 84 percent
big numbers and I'm really glad they
feel that way
because
there is
current policy in the work that is
looking towards
um creating better communication and
better guidance for cyber security of
satellites so
I brought this up for these are the most
relevant policy documents that deal with
the cyber security of satellites
spd5 and then there's actually an
upcoming nist framework that's
specifically going to address it it's in
draft two
um
it closed for comments in early spring
so I'm not sure what we're waiting on
but I'm hoping that it'll come out soon
for a fullness document or another draft
and I've also included some wonderful
sayings of people that will say things
firmer than I will
uh because I'm glad they said it and can
be attributed and I don't have to be
all right
now uh if you want to study this
yourself
I uh I actually have a lot of references
up here I know you guys are so excited
for your Academia work
and then even more whoo
but uh I I figured I went through that a
little fast just because I know we were
trying to make up on time
um but I'm open for questions
and I have some giveaways for good
questions
uh how
can we apply our current things like
agents to the satellites and what limits
or issues would go along with that
okay uh when you say agents do you mean
operators builders
security agents
well that's an interesting question
uh
you can
it depends on which component you're
trying to verify for example uh nowadays
ground stations which are the devices
that are actually used to control the
satellite or monitor the satellite can
be made by a local high schooler anyone
can make a ground station to actually
look at the footprint of a satellite but
ground stations that are used to command
and control are completely different
those ground stations are supposedly
more secure but they're also on the
cloud
uh there are Amazon web services that
offers uh ground stations for satellites
that you can do from anywhere
so the same applications that you would
use for creating a secure Cloud
infrastructure could be utilized in the
ground station for that but really it's
building it with security in mind from
the beginning
many satellites are created by
universities by other countries they're
created by anyone that really can afford
to put it up there I mean I think you
could you as an individual wanted to put
up a satellite and you had a spare I
don't know thirty thousand dollars you
could
um and right now it's not limited to
what you could put up there except by
the launch provider
that's it so you pay enough money and
you can make it happen
I know doesn't that make you feel warm
and fuzzy
like
they're putting up a lot more satellites
to cover internet is that proliferation
going to have other impacts as well it's
a really broad question sorry
no that that's a
lot it is and and you're really dealing
with two different issues here so the
number of satellites and the different
orbits in space that that's one issue
that's actually delegated by the um itu
International telecommunications Union
they they monitor what orbits they can
be there and when you're talking about
Leo satellites which is where we're
finding the large
constellations you're you're looking at
um
most of those they now have a mandated
de-orbit period so they're really
getting up there quickly and they're
really hopefully
coming down quickly or at least with a
plan but uh your very limited orbits are
your Geo satellites in a very special
geosynchronous range and that's actually
a political nightmare because uh the
allocation for those are very
competitive and getting them up there
and making sure they come down is a huge
ordeal
um so but then you're also dealing with
frequency Wars I don't know if you've
heard that uh but the frequency
allocation here in the U.S I'm actually
getting some popcorn I'm enjoying
watching the debates uh every now and
then they'll have an auction I'm just
like ooh is starlink gonna lose
everything
is our 5G gonna lose everything let's
see who wins so you're dealing with a
very congested environment and um the
first come first serve doesn't really
always hold true there
kind of crowd sourcing
your hand test security because I know
there's been open competitions like
Hackensack and
swap my Society
are they
interested in the results of those kinds
of things to integrate that in or is
I have to say it really depends on the
company
um some of my my classmates actually
went on to found Spire which is a
cubesat company and I I know from my
research and me telling them about the
dangers that they probably integrated it
in but other companies might not see it
that way imagine if you are let's say a
new country launching your very first
satellite you just want it to work
like it getting up there without blowing
up it's responding when it needs to
um you really don't think about security
when you're at that level so
it's one of those things where security
is more as an afterthought than from the
beginning because when we talk about the
landsat 7 one of the biggest things that
I heard from my fellow classmates were
why would they hack a science experiment
I mean don't they know that that science
is for mankind no one would ever ever
hack my precious satellite that I'm
doing precious science with
what good would it come so you you have
to kind of overcome that mindset of why
would someone do this to they'll
probably do it if they can and you what
you need to do is make it a little bit
difficult for them so they're not just
the average person can do it
I think that's also being attributed to
more cots
secure kind of I don't want to say
modular builds of satellites that are
kind of developing so nowadays instead
of developing your own power source or
your own this and that component you can
buy one off the shelf and hopefully
those on the Shelf components have a
little bit more Security in them
so what do we do then for existing
satellite infrastructure it's it's much
easier for me to take a satellite and
build it now and build it with security
in mind but what about like GPS
satellites that have been up there for
25 30 years what about some of these
other satellites that are just kind of
Legacy equipment that still has to be
maintained it's still there we still
have to know about it and
I am really am glad you asked that
question I think it it needs to be asked
more often I can tell you that with
modern satellites how they're trying to
overcome that uh
inevitability that the technology and
the material that you put out into space
is going to be outdated very quickly
especially with the rapid involvement of
chips and components here on Earth is
they're using software to find radios
where they can modularly update the the
hardware to you know patching basically
and that has made a huge difference in
our space industry
so a secure encryption key is 256 bits
which like is small enough you could
physically build that into a circuit to
not worry about stuff being
this being over
it so what are the design constraints
for satellites that make the naive
approach
build in your key
attending everything
so you only have trust
ing a ground station going to your C2
what are the design constraints that
don't make that
you did not
solution
I I like how One industry might think
one thing and another industry will
think something else I don't know the
specific answer to your question but I
will give you a scenario that's often
posed to cyber security I guess people
in the when we're drinking after hours
is let's say you have a group on Mars
and they have a medical emergency and
you really need to talk to them right
then and there well whenever you design
that packet of communications if you
encrypt it it's already going to take
more than seven minutes to get there
maybe even longer you're adding in a
larger file which is going to increase
the time and you're also adding into the
complexity of that communication Network
so it's more how do you design something
that's encrypted and small and can be
communicated quickly
that whole physics thing it gets in the
way it's horrible I I hate it
sometimes
you know a lot of like Star Lincoln's
other things
are Telecom base
is
hope or perceive that there might be
competitive government guidelines for
these telecom companies for
um
their satellites that they put in space
but there could be concerns about
somebody
going from their consumer Network to the
OT size of that satellite when they're
getting
access
to remain in control of other satellites
but something is being thought about or
well that that is
that is something that's being thought
about I can tell you that one of the
things that I'm looking forward to is is
next year I just got funding we're going
to build a cyber security of satellites
Lab at Savannah River National Lab and
we're going to integrate a Hardware in
the loop satellite design so that we can
look at some of those issues
I think it's particularly important that
those issues are looked at especially
with the the new policy move for
government instead of launching their
own individual satellites they're
thinking of more taking on payloads of
other satellites or other commercial
entities and you always wonder if you're
plugging in this payload and you don't
know what it is and you're plugging it
into your Hardware is not going to
interfere with something on your
Hardware how do you create the the
diodes that you need to make sure that
information isn't spread to places that
it shouldn't be
um it's a major concern right now
um if you have an answer or a solution I
would love to talk to you afterwards
that's it for this talk