all right so hello everyone thank you
for joining this stuff today so yeah I
am Rommel and I'm a model researcher and
I'm based here in Singapore so my talk
today is entitled inter enough
internet-of-things battle of the bots so
to give you an idea this talk is based
on our research for the past year and
since we we were monitoring Mirai botnet
and all related samples to it
so let's take a look so here is a
overview of what we'll be discussing
today
so first is a brief introduction of
Mirai second is anti analysis and
encryption of its configuration if there
are any changes the next one is the our
lab setup and honeypot so how did we get
all the samples that will be presented
today and lastly it's the malaria
variance so we will compare them from
the original source code of me ride and
the changes of the variance then lastly
is the popular variants so with the
overview so just to refresh your memory
on Mirai so we just take a look on some
news that made two years ago so the
first one is the first attack on Krebs
on security so this guy is famous
journalist in computer security and the
attack cost aside to be offline for four
days and the record traffic was around
620 gigabyte per second next attack is
against in its infrastructure so it made
popular websites like Twitter Spotify
and reddit unavailable to users so we
can see already like the immediate
impact of Mirai 2 years ago so not only
that so another study showed that DDoS
is also bad for businesses that are
being targeted so roughly 8% of Dean's
customers base stop using their services
after they were after
were apart so this was also a huge loss
to bean the next are you talk about the
first appearance of Mirai
so it was coded by minus n PI or his aka
and the source code was released in hub
forums on September 20 2016 so this is
the actual post by Anna senpai and he
also released the source code in this
post so the good news is since certain
information from his posting this
posting led to identifying the authors
so fast forward after all the
investigations the author behind this
mirror botnet was pleaded guilty last
December 2017 so when there's a good
news there's also some bad news since
this is now open source the source code
of Mirai so anyone can use it
including you or me or like any cyber
criminal can just reuse the code and
they can create their own botnet so in
this course and maybe when they create
their own botnet botnet they can also
have the same impact as merrily on what
they did like to Dean and Krebs so now
this is the problem that we have and
many called many variants or we can say
copycats of Mirai have been modifying
the source code to infect more and more
IOT devices so we will take a more
detailed look on mirror variants later
on so if any of you maybe have looked up
the source code of Mariah so these are
the main components included in the
source code so we have the command and
control server we have the report server
we have the loader and we have the bot
so this bot here this is the one that is
installed in the infected device so this
is the payload so this bot has three
functions first is their attack so this
is this includes the DDoS attacks next
is the killer this is the one functions
to stop the
processes like maybe other botnets are
running there so it can kill those
processes then scanner so this is to
infect more IOT devices so it acts like
it acts like sour worm who to have
better understanding on how the
infection chain works by MRI so we have
here restart here so the infected IOT
device so the bot module is installed
here and then what it does is that's a
telnet port scan so it uses the default
credentials so it already has a list of
default credentials then after
successfully successfully logging in
that IOT device it will report the IP
and the credentials to the report server
so this is was the other component that
we mentioned then having the IP and
credentials already so we have here the
loader so this loader will be the one
who will install the bot in the infected
device so now we will have another
infected device so once this device is
infected it will just repeat the same
process so it will scan again some
random IPS then if it's in fact that if
it's vulnerable then it will infect this
and another thing once it's infected
it will report now to the C&C server
like telling them telling the C&C that
this device is infected and it can
already receive commands like whichever
the CSE wants then next is we have here
the botnet botnet admin so at the bottom
that what net admin can sell or rent out
the use of the botnets here so he can
rent it out or sell to a botnet user or
let's say a fraudster here so once the
fraudster gets access to the botnet he
can send commands to the C&C server then
the C&C server will send attack commands
to the infected devices then this
infected devices will do a DDoS to its
target so basically this is the
infection chain of Mirai and justice
summary so this are the attacks
available to me right so this is all in
the source code the next is we have the
anti analysis and the encryption of the
configuration table of Mirai so this is
the binary hex view of one of the mirror
samples that we encountered so else the
header so most samples is not encrypted
by any custom powers like when we
compare it to Windows so usually it is
just backed by upx so basically if it's
just backed by upx it should be easily
be decompressed but what the variants
authors do is they change this one so
this would be the proper header should
be upx exclamation point but this one is
changed by SMD J so what happens is if
we use the upx tool to decompress this
file it will fail so if we do automation
then it cannot decrypt I cannot
decompress the sample properly so what
we do we just change this value here to
its proper header which is upx and we
are able to decompress it easily and
then next one is so not only snd J we
found that numerous values were change
in those upx headers so we have around
18 different headers that been has been
modified so Disorderlies if you have an
Vivian idea on the configuration table
that we are talking about so this again
is based on our source code so we have
here is the C&C domain we have the CNC
port the table scan domain and scan CB
port so for this values the in hex these
are the encrypted ones so to decrypt
this when this is the crypt
you will get this value so CNC changed
me so for those variants they just
change this one to change their own CNC
and goes the same with the others so how
does the decryption of Mira work so
let's take a look here about to the crib
so basically it has a table key here so
here I just happened here to see here so
this is our dead beef so what it does
it's just use our xor algorithm so it's
quite simple so it XOR each byte of this
table key so if we XOR each byte each
other we'll get a value of 0 x 22 and
this value here when we accelerate the
encrypted configuration table we should
be able to dump the configuration table
when example here is the C&C port so I
showed it in the previous slide so we
have 22 and 35 so XOR in 22 to 22 is 0
then X or 22 235 is 17 hex or 23 in
decimal so I computed this yesterday so
it should be correct so next one since
we already know that Maria just uses our
XOR algorithm so this are the XOR keys
that we were able to identify that
malaria burials are using so
approximately 47 different XOR kiss use
and this are the top 5 that we found so
purchase the dead beef or C or X 22 so
this includes Mirai so we found that 27
variants are using this and we have 54
45 then another interesting is this 0 so
13 variants are using it so it means
that the configuration table was not
encrypted so we can see everything the
CNC the port that it uses so we can see
everything maybe it was used for testing
purposes or maybe they just forgot to
encrypt the configuration and next is
caching life
samples with our honeypot so we started
a project last year in our team so we
call it the KY project or kill all I Oh
T botnets project so we just use static
analysis then we automate the decryption
of the configuration table so as
mentioned it just uses XOR algorithm so
it should be we could automate this
process the next is and packing of known
powers so it it just uses upx so we just
decompress it upx and see if the header
is correct if it's not then we just
change it to upx then we will be able to
decompress it then after the
decompressing it we can get the
configuration table then also we collect
the CNC servers and download URLs
through the result of this project for
the past year we collected around 21,000
samples then from this 21,000 samples we
got 15,000 samples that are related to
me right botnet the next one is we
identified 120 variants 130 violence is
a lot but I'll explain here how we were
able to get this much then we have Bluff
listed around 500 plus command and
control servers so just an overview of
our honeypot so we use a low blow
interaction honeypot so we have here our
product here so we use FortiGate so this
is the one facing the internet so every
traffic that goes into port 23 and 23 23
23 I will be routed to our test network
so once it's inside the test network so
our 48 again or any router it will
direct the traffic to our virtual
machine so this virtual machine has two
components so first is the backend so
this one is one that collects all the
data from our honeypot and this one here
is the honeypot itself so all the data
gathered here the samples the URL
being downloaded we'll go back here to
our type system and this guy will be
trial system will be the one to be to
analyze the data yeah and next so how do
we identify the mirror variants so
originally minerally was named after by
the strings or a command this being
busybox me right and me right up let not
phone so this is not a valid command so
it it is here since these are commands
to determine if it has successfully
brute force its way to our target and
IOT device so Mirai was named with the
string so the same with the variant so
we have here an example from convict
configuration table of amira variant so
it it changes you changes this one so
beam busybox
OMG a so we can just name this variant
or OMG then next this is the all the
variants that we were able to identify
for the past year so this is a word
cloud so the bigger the word means that
it has more samples so we it's pretty
obvious already on who are the big names
here sorry
yeah and you can also take a look on
some of them maybe you you have
encountered them or heard before like
Masuda maybe or okiru so yeah these are
all the variants that we have identified
so next slide so this is the variant
count so before 2018 we only identified
14 versions of mirai but now in the
european tape in it suddenly jump 41 in
January so this also is in lines since
by this time instead of using brute
force logins
manera variants were using known
exploits so yeah that was a big change
so we can also see the trend
that it's going up every month so by
August we already have 127 minute
variants active so here is a sample
count for each month of 2018 that we
process so generally we had 2000 so if
you can see like every month we almost
process more than more than a thousand
samples then for example here at me we
only have like one thousand four hundred
five
so comparing it to the previous slide so
April had 76 but May had 81 so there was
only an increase by five so it would
mean that since there are only five new
variants then there were also less
samples that we were that were being
processed then another example here is
July so this was the peak so we had a
lot of samples here so as we can see
July here so from 98 from June it jumped
to 117 so they were 19 new variants in
July so just last month so now just to
filter out more the data so we have a
sample count per variant so most samples
are still in me right so this shows that
a lot of people or a lot of cyber
criminals are testing right maybe a lot
of them are script kiddies who wants to
learn using the bots but a few are
really are skillful on want to modify in
the bot so again here we have the top 5
mirai sora o re Jojo and Daddy l33t so
now we proceed to the targeted
architectures by MRI so all this here
Arijit the boss can be built the bot can
be built compatible for this
architecture so all of this here we have
our meats super edge spark Motorola
Intel PowerPC AMD and IBM then next not
only this Mira
audience and exploits to his its arsenal
it also wants to target more devices so
by doing this it adds a new architecture
to target so this is the art
international are compact processor so
this was discovered January 2018 just
this year so it was initially used by
Akira Berlin and this is this was quite
a big nuisance around 1.5 billion
products are dispatched per year using
this processor so if okiru could in fact
like just a portion of these devices
then it could be a big botnet then after
okiru so other variants also joining the
arc architecture so we have this six
here
Masuda or me root sauce chicken wings
and wicked so now we will take a look at
the exploits so it's quite a lot so we
were able to detect 28 exploits being
used by the mineral variants so at least
16 16 of them are an unauthenticated
exploits meaning that doesn't need to
have to login or doesn't mid-valley
potentials to exploit an IOT device so
this is quite dangerous then 14 of the
exploits are from 2017 and 2018 so for
users that don't pass their IOT device
even though they change their password
are still vulnerable by these exploits
so we have here the brands that are
affected by the 28 exploits so it ranges
from routers modems CCTV DVR IP cameras
web apps and also minor software
products so for the specific vulnerable
product maybe you can just check online
on which a product is vulnerable to this
then now we will proceed on the main
variants by MRI so Satori
or okiru so it was believed to be coded
by Nexus data so this name was always in
the configuration table
and this is one of the most popular
modification of Mirai so the loader was
embedded in its pot then it included the
architecture art architecture tastarga
so as we mentioned a while ago then it
uses exploits to spread and one version
of it mines cryptocurrency so let's take
a look on it at its timeline so we first
saw this on December 2017
so this CBE 2017 17 to 1/5 buy from
Huawei so this is our remote code
execution so by the time there were no
details of this exploit so we assume
that this vulnerability used by this
botnet was zero day and it was in fact a
zero day and other exploits here are
from 2014 from Realty targeting the
realtek SDK then we have here the CVE
2017 from the Wi-Fi come so this one is
also important since around 185,000
Wi-Fi cameras are vulnerable to this one
this exploit and we have here docume OS
command injection to d-link and HTTP
basic authentication bypass in go ahead
web then the interesting stuff in this
one is this TV here right here so it
targets the Claymore miner software so
what the botnet do is it scans port 3 3
3 then it targets the claimer software
mining so what it what it do it changes
the destination wallet so instead of
going to the host or the proper user it
changes the destination wallet to its
own so as you can see there are command
here so we try to check the value of
this wallet and as of general from I
think it just been used for a month so
the last payout was January 29 2018 and
it has been paid around 3.33 at areum so
on generally the value of at areum was I
think around one thousand US dollar but
now it drop already so by January it
earned around 3.3 K US dollar in a month
because of this one and now we have the
next version we call it OMG or oo MGA so
this turns out II devices into proxy
servers so it contains still the
original mirror I so it can still attack
it has the killer and the scanner
functions then it uses brute force to
login so you don't have any exploit then
we discovered this in February 2018 so
it uses the three proxy it's a it is an
open-source proxy server and how how
does it turn the IOT device to a proxy
server so it generates two random parts
for HTTP and sub proxies as you can see
here then from there it will try to
allow traffic by so for the proxy to
work properly so if I roll a firewall
rule must be added to allow the traffic
on the randomly generated ports so once
the ports are generated they are
reported at the C&C so we have here the
command to add the firewall rule to that
to that port that generated port so this
was also significant in cyber criminals
can also earn money by renting out this
proxy servers to other criminals who
wants to hide their identity or their
location so next we we just sum up this
Orissa wicked and Omni variants since
the since we believe that they were
coded by the same malware author so the
author calls himself weekend so with
this friend called karma of hope so
sorry you Sora the this botnet uses
original Linux so this is a cross
compiler so
it is much easier for the authors to
compile the bot in different
architectures then this variance or
commonly uses exploits other than
default passwords and one of the sample
that we found includes 11 exploits in it
so again we will try to show a timeline
who may be I think it's too small but
the first that we discovered was over
Lisa it was November 2017 so for this
time it was just using default passwords
but as 2018 came he added exploits like
every month then just June think this is
June so we found a sample that includes
all this exploits so so this version
takes advantage of using known exploit
so these are all known exploits rather
than discovering zero day since this is
also practical since users don't usually
update their products and many users are
just used and forget so with the number
of exploits in it so how does this
variants are to switch exploit the use
in the vulnerable device so what it does
is scan specific ports by initiating a
rocket scene so for example here it
tries to connect to this part so we have
888 443 80 and 81 so if it was able to
establish or check that this up this
port is open it will use the
corresponding exploit so for example
port 88 is found to be open it will use
the RCE Netgear dgn 1000 exploit so it
was the same with other exploits
mentioned and to finish it up so this
one is just like from omni botnet so it
was just mocking Brian Krebs so this is
the face of Brian Krebs here so for
vulnerability devices so maybe start
getting web servers or and it tries to
remove the HTML login that HTML
the file here so when it once it removes
this one it will download it will
download this one meme so this is this
is the download URL and it will replace
it to be as the login that HTML so if
you're the infected user then you go to
your login that HTML you will see the
screen in your IOT device so it says it
says here use stop right there so once
your router fix no problem send an email
to Krebs on security at gmail.com and
we'll have it fixed awesome and Scarface
is your daddy and now some final
thoughts on Mira barians and our talk
today so we still expect more exploits
that will be added and then still more
vines will be appearing then another
thing also is a modification of
encryption of configuration tables since
it's already predictable maybe some
malware author will try to change it
then next is other means to monetize in
fact that IOT devices other than crypto
mining and proxy servers so as of now we
have many hub views experimented and
modified the code for their own liking
and purpose variants have many variants
want to have a piece of the IOT pie and
they are battling to compromise more and
more vulnerability IOT devices so the
question still remains who will be the
next me right thank you and thank you
very much for mal yeah thank you are
there any questions from the audience
ok if there are no further questions
please keep your mind that rimmel will
be available for the rest of the day
here at a conference
so ask any questions that may come to
mind later on thank you again rimmel