I'll be very brief I have 15 minutes I
don't want to steal time from the
full tracks that will follow so I go
very very fast well first of all I'd
like to introduce myself in 30 seconds
I'm the director of crowd fans I don't
know if you heard about this company
it's a new company so you probably never
heard before about it it's a company
that deals with buying and refining
testing documenting and reselling
zero-days exploits in my previous lives
I was the head of cyber security for
KPMG I was a military officer I was
member of the national security of
cerveteri in Italy and many other things
I've been working in the cyber security
field since when it wasn't called cyber
actually basically I started 20 years
ago so I'm probably the oldest in the
room which sucks but that's how it is so
I've seen this market developed over
time from you know before Windows 3.1 to
today hmm crowd fence is there is a
dubai-based company the reason why it's
pace in device basically because it's a
really cool place to do business
nowadays it was established in 2017
after two years of studying designing
learning and discussing with lawyers and
with ethical hackers other researchers
and so on because we wanted to do to
create something innovative and it
publicly launched in April 2000 18 the
mission briefly is to modernize this
market which is still working with
logics that were developed over time
historically in the past 15 20 years
from the ground up with with No
you know understanding of the issues
that we're going to to emerge so
nowadays distilled a market we think is
not up to date with the how much
strategic it has become nowadays we're
talking about nation-states wanting to
buy this stuff to perform investigations
intelligence activities or to support
military activities and but the market
has remained the same so we want to
modernize to support researchers and
that's why we're sponsoring this this
this safety is track to make it more
transparent as much as possible more
efficient and so on we support law
enforcement and in Intel agencies so we
are buying zero days which can be used
for information gathering activities and
we don't support the development of
cyber weapons so for example when
someone offers us a zero days for
critical infrastructure gear ICS SCADA
IOT healthcare wearables and so on we
usually decline when we launch enough in
April we offered a 10 million bounty
said 10 million dollars
bug bounty and as of today we paid out
off of that amount to researchers and if
you go on our website you will see that
we have published a list of target
systems and a list of classes or
families of exploits that we are mostly
interested into and of course we are
keeping
we are continuing to look for
researchers and brokers and customers
and today we're here because we we are
you know willing to meet the community
to talk with the community to discuss
our ideas to receive your suggestions or
your criticism in a few days we will
launch what we called internally the VRP
the VRP means vulnerability research
platform it's a web-based platform that
we design at first for our internal
activities and after a certain point we
decided that we wanted to open it up to
the community so the idea is to create a
process to streamline and standardize
the submission discussion testing
pricing and purchasing of zero-days for
these the kind of customers that we have
so for information gathering activities
for law enforcement and intelligence
agencies it was designed to be legal
highly confidential and to simplify the
process nowadays when we start talking
with the researcher about his or her
findings we always have a lot of issues
because of you know time zones people
trying to use known PGP encrypted emails
all the time trying to talk with us
about amazing zero days on what's up you
know this stuff must end it's impossible
to do this kind of stuff in through
these channels and in this way so this
application is hopefully a way to set a
standard in the market we will of course
improve it all and and expand it but the
version 1 of the platform will be
released in the next few days
of course it's undergoing a lot of
security testing as you can imagine we
are then testing it to death
it's based on full end-to-end encryption
and about back-end architecture is
pretty weird because the server doesn't
know what it's dealing with at all so
it's not your typical web application so
what are the results from the first few
months we can already tell that the
results of this approach are that
sellers can sell their findings faster
and at higher prices and customers
receive higher quality products because
in our lab we test documentary write
expand polish refine their code nowadays
what happens there's a lot of scammers
around but even if you are not dealing
with a scammer what you receive is a
piece of code written on a napkin in the
toilet ninety percent of the time which
is not what our customers are expecting
in terms of quality reliability and and
so on
these must change we are willing to pay
huge bounties but the quality must be up
to the prices hmm by the way for example
for iOS chain we just paid ten times as
much Apple is paying with their bug
bounty program so this means something I
mean it means that somebody is willing
to pay to buy that stuff at that price
which is interesting both for
researchers and for us and at the same
time that quality must increase in over
time which is our wish we want just to
do that so if you want to join the VP of
course you can join for free and it's
open to everyone we will select we will
filter the submissions depending on
what would be submitted so if you're
going to submit us at zero day for
hacking a nuclear power station we will
probably refuse to go further and but in
other cases our team will interact with
you and start a conversation about your
finding about reliability issues
artifacts whatever until we find a good
understanding of what it is and what it
does without seeing the code then we
will define a fair price and after that
we will find a way to complete the to
sign a contract which is automatically
generated by the platform and digitally
signed by both sides because what
happens today is that you buy an apple
and then you receive a banana which
happens all the times and then you don't
have ways to say look you sold me an
apple but this is a Vanna and of course
you can follow us on Twitter you can
talk to me while I'm here or write me an
email you can find our public PGP key on
our website you can write to info at car
fans calm you can talk with Christina
which is sitting there if you have any
media question this said I finish I
think I'm like two minutes I still have
two minutes but I leave it to the other
speakers thanks for coming thanks for
listening enjoy this track and see you
later bye
[Applause]
thank you so much Andrea for kicking off
our day and thank you and your company
crowd fans for sponsoring our COMSEC
track let's give it up one more time for
Andrea
[Applause]