thank you thank you everybody and let's
speak about Wi-Fi phishing and red
teaming so usual introduction you can
just see it later on the slides it's not
important so what we are going to speak
about today so I will give up very very
quick introduction about the topics then
we will speak briefly about what is WPA
and wpa2 Enterprise another very quick
introduction about the basic for WPA
enterprise
aking and then what knew about this this
talk like actually it's not something
very new but these are something that we
encountered in a red teaming engagement
so I want to speak about this experience
so a quick note about red teaming red
teaming usually as of as objective not
to stress every defense mechanism that
is in place to protect an asset but
instead is to obtain a goal or one of
these asset so the difference from my
normal assessment is that I don't I
don't care to stress all the physical
security stuff cyber security and human
security I'm only interested in getting
one of the critical asset that I have
the goal this is just a quick
introduction about a red teaming
engagement so why are we interested
during a red teaming engagement on Wi-Fi
and specifically enterprise Wi-Fi
networks because usually we have
hundreds if not thousands of different
users and each user usually can choose
his own password so it's very possible
to find a weak password to connect to
the enterprise Wi-Fi network we can try
to reuse the credential for for example
OWA in access email access and whatever
because often the authentication in
place is sort of single sign-on so we
can use the same credential for
being inside the enterprise network that
also means that we can either direct
access to the company intranet network
and that's very useful for getting the
goal that we spoke before and moreover
since most of the time we are speaking
about windows-based Network we can also
launch a series of other attacks on the
network that we all know like responder
and it's kind of fun
and finally usually enterprise Wi-Fi
network also provides us interred access
that is also very useful to exfiltrate
the data that we are interested in so
that's what makes enterprise Wi-Fi a
very interesting point of entry during a
red teaming engagement and the last
thing that I forgot to put here is that
we can get this kind of access remote I
mean I don't have to get inside the
facility usually so what's the security
in WPA enterprise so WPA enterprise -
poor dynamic delivery of master keys
that means that heavy user as his own
password and therefore his own
encryption key and so if even if I know
the key to access the network I cannot
decrypt the traffic of other users the
authentication relies on the 802.1 X
authentication standard that basically
gives me our array our framework in
which I can create my own authentication
methods that are the EAP methods and
that depends on the infrastructure that
I want to build usually on open source
usually this kind of authentication is
based on open source software that is
free radius or more recently or say PD
and this is also what we use to attack
this network we will use a patch version
of this kind of software so as I said we
have a lot of different authentication
methods that we can develop using this
framework here but most of the time the
idea is the following so when the client
gives the Authenticator and then we
videoed indication server so the
Authenticator
never stores the the keys the secrets
from the password so even UVA have a
vulnerability inside our router we don't
have direct access to the credentials of
the user
he said standard WPA personal the keys
or the password to access the network is
stored inside the router of course
because there's the router that handle
the authentication in this case the root
are only handled the communication
between the client and the
authentication server it usually is
inside the intranet or inside a network
so we do request to authenticate then
the Authenticator forward our request to
the radius server
and then the radius server sent to the
client ok to authenticate me to use this
specific method that will be see later
the client will do stuff like encrypting
the key and all these kind of things
there is a and Shake in here and then if
the password is correct in the encrypted
password is correct the radio send an
acceptance packet so there is another
difference between standard WPA and
enterprise that the usually in
enterprise network we also validate the
certificate of the so at least of the
server so that means that when I try to
connect that to a new network I have to
accept the certificate that the server
is presenting and then I will use this
certificate to encapsulate and encrypt
my data for the authentication and the
communication so these are some of the
available methods that are the most
common one actually the most common one
is probably PAP that is the small
standard that windows will use but also
EAP TLS is quite it's not very common
because it requires one step that is
really not very straightforward to
implement that is the certificate
installed inside of the clients so if I
want the server to validate the clients
also so to avoid me in the middle
attacks I also need to push my
certificate to all my
clients in order to that for them to be
able to validate the server so this is
the main issue here and that's why P EAP
is the most used one at the moment so
what is P aap basically we have a pastor
bed password-based authentication for
the device and a certificate based
authentication for the server the source
for the clients to verify the server
actually the password-based
authentication can also be implemented
with the certificate or smart cards
nowadays but you know when you speak
into Wi-Fi network most of the time we
only had the password because I want to
be able to access also from my mobile
phone etc this mode most pop as I said
is the most popular enterprise Wi-Fi
security mechanism and again the PAP has
his own standards and the most used one
is EAP mschap with you most of you
already probably saw this kind of of
stander here because it has native
support on all the windows machine also
the old ones and as we know in
enterprise network there is always a
Windows XP machine somewhere that needs
to be connected to the network so that's
why this is still the most standard one
okay that was the very quick
introduction about
WPA enterprise so what will you what how
can we attack Windows sorry WPA
enterprise network so basically we use
as a set patch version of of--steak PD
yeah that basically allow me not only to
obtain the - sorry - a try to
authenticate the client but it also
prompts me and then write me the
credentials of the encrypted credential
that the user ID try to to use to attack
to connect the network so the idea is
that sorry the idea is that we create a
fake network probably the same name as
the real one or a similar name and try
to lure the user into connect to our
network and the fourth to send with us
the encrypted credential that
we need to crack so as I said bit but as
I said before PAP but also eap-tls
use a server-side certificate so the
user have to connect I have to accept
the certificate that the server presents
so when I create my own fake access
point the user will be get will get a
prompt saying wait the certificate is
changed do you want to accept it or not
most of the time the people said ok
accept it but sometimes there is an
option sorry these already spoke about I
will tell you how we talked about the
option later so most of the time the
user will accept the prompt and then he
stole the new certificate and send a
credential ok quick thing about mschap
with you most of you probably already
know but ok we speak about that also
later on and that's fine so what do we
use during a red teaming attack to to
get this kind of information so in red
teaming as I said we can do everything
right we can go on client side drop some
some I don't know for like raspberry pi
and then wait we don't have a very
specific time limit so we can attack on
the night on the day everything so for
example in this case what we use is a
very simple drop box machine which is
basically our Asbury pie with some
custom software of some modification of
our standard Kali Linux an external
battery to let you run for like a couple
of days and then forget about that of
course an external on Wi-Fi antenna to
get in longer range because when the
clients when their victims
try to connects they will try to connect
the most powerful networking at the time
so we want to be the most powerful
natural the time and then optionally we
also use sometimes 3G or 4G dongle so
that we can connect actually that drop
machine connects back to us and we can
query for for credential and check the
status of the machine or reboot it or
reset if something goes wrong and
sometime you also use some 3d printers
to create a proper box for putting the
Dropbox machine and then hide it
somewhere like I don't know maybe you
saw in the street is like a poison rat
box that is very common no one want to
touch it because says paws on dead so
it's it's pretty convenient to store
drop box machine okay so that's that's
quite easy I mean this is common
knowledge nothing new here but during
one of the our engagement we found an
issue that basically our victims didn't
get the prompt for the new certificate
therefore they could not connect to our
fake access point so we started to
investigate the problem we try to
reproduce with our own devices and we
found sorry and we found that there is
an option on Windows machines that
allows the computer to automatically
drop any certificate it is not in a
trusted Microsoft root CA
so basically when we generate our own
certificate of course our certificate is
self generated right so it's not present
in our in a standard trust Microsoft
root CA and therefore the victim machine
automatically drop it and doesn't even
prompt the user to accept the new
certificate the for no credential the
for which cannot access the victim hash
or password so what what's the idea the
idea is to get a trusted Microsoft root
CA certificate so this is the portion of
the root certificate in Microsoft
Windows at the moment this is updated
like I think yesterday or something like
that so do you know how many of you
recognize this name here no one
this is let's encrypt SIA so Microsoft
recently added the let's encrypt CR to
the trusted root of the Windows machines
so that means that we can get a free
certificate that we can use to
authenticate the sorry to validate our
certificate to the clients and therefore
from them to accept a new certificate
and enter their credential so to wrap up
the idea the idea is to create a
phishing domain a standard phishing
domain something that is similar to the
corporation we want attack I here used
like how my company's the website is
opposing force dot IT I try to use up
for that IT and then maybe a subdomain
to make it more realistic ok then we use
third bots that is the tool that let's
encrypt provides us to create a new
certificate for our subdomain we save
the certificate on the new mesh on the
our Dropbox machine inside the AUSA APD
WP directory food chain and the private
key these are the two files that we need
and then we can finally get the
credential from the victim so in this
way we can bypass the option that
windows a set to validate a certificate
before prompting the user so what are we
trying to do now the idea now is to
developing a small tool and was more
script that automatically will get us
illumine obtain the specific certificate
certificate from from the third bot and
set up the fake access point with with
such certificates so using esos APD in
that way we can just execute the script
on the Dropbox deploy the Dropbox and
forget about that for a couple of days
and then check for the credential so
this is the idea and that's we plan to
do two
release the tool on github in I don't
know maybe a couple of weeks now still
trying to figure out what is the best
provider for domains and these kind of
things so that that's my very simple
talk in my opinion one the the we
actually spent a couple of days to
figure out what's the problem there and
this kind of engagement so maybe some of
you will face the same issue and now you
have a possible answer for that so
please ask me some question because then
we have lunch and we can forget about
this thank you very much
any questions from the audience okay
well do keep in mind that if you do come
up with any questions you'll be around
so don't have lunch like you where is
the final ok so right now it's time for
a lunch we'll start back up in one hour
so be here at 2 p.m. to catch up with
the next track for all the paying
attorneys there will be lunch on the
ground floor in the lobby at the room
ashen elk so I hope to see you again in
one hour and give it up one more time
for Mateo thank you
[Applause]