hello everyone I know it's quite late
and it's almost the end of the
conference so everyone's who wants to go
to go for a drink afterwards so I'll try
to be very brief first of all I'd like
to thank everyone for contributing to
this conference and in particular the
hack in the box team which has done an
amazing job so far and I also want to
thank all the speakers the trainers and
of course the attendees and and
volunteers so just a few information
about where we stand with hacking the
box in Singapore G SEC today so it was
again an amazing event the event was
structured around five different
technical trainings very hands-on
technical trainings aiming at educating
of skilling cybersecurity professionals
in the area of source code auditing
threat intelligence gathering etc we
also had a amazing opportunity to
discuss in depth very interesting topics
across two different tracks and one
panel discussion there was also a great
platform to showcase the skills of
cybersecurity professionals during the
CTF competition which was co-organized
with exit EF China team and the very
first edu CTF developed by hacking the
box which showcased level of skills at a
very high level and what's really
interesting about the hack in the box
jisuk Singapore conference is the fact
it's a really intimate setting which
really enables the high level of
interaction high quality discussions is
very difficult to summarize the richness
of the content of such a conference so I
decided to choose three different topics
that were recurring themes and recurring
interesting challenges that were
mentioned during the conference so the
first one is the rise of IOT and the
fact that we know that by 2020 there
will be twenty billion devices in
circulation
and this is very relevant given the fact
that 70% of current devices have basic
level of vulnerabilities and this is on
one side very challenging because we
know that the risk associated to
discovering vulnerabilities can have a
great cascade risk towards not only the
device itself but the entire industry
this is the consumer perspective side
but there's also of course the smart
nation smart country perspective which
also needs to basically improve the
level of security to protect their
critical infrastructures the second area
which was discussed this afternoon by
Salvador was essentially the complexity
the increase of complexity in the
digital payment
attacks so basically we're seeing some
kind of paradox in which basically the
attacks in order to conduct digital
payment are becoming more complex by the
same time the barriers or the way you
can enable those attacks is becoming
easier so basically what he was
discussing is that with even basic
supporting technologies such as NFC
involving NFC SDR you are able to
conduct such attacks for a few dozen
dollars finally a very interesting topic
that was mentioned yesterday during the
panel discussion was the lack of
regulation in regard to the zero-day
market and this poses very interesting
challenges the first one is that there's
a mismatch between demand and supply of
exploits in fact Andrea from crowd fans
was kind enough to share some
some stats and basically show that 5%
only of the exploits are actually
purchased by those third-party providers
or third-party companies and that is
partially because some of the exploits
discovered are either too dangerous to
be shared or simply they're not relevant
for the market and in the context of the
lack of regulation this poses very
interesting challenges because we all
know that those exploits if they fall
into
ille intended organizations people or
countries well it's going to be generate
additional issues so if we try to put
these three main challenges into
perspective and we try to identify
potential high-level initial solutions
we can say that first for IOT devices
well the first thing to do is to try to
challenge the current paradigm of having
all the internet connected to all the
devices connected to the Internet
do we really need to have for example a
bottle of waters trousers or pillows
connected to the Internet so this
mindset needs to evolve the second thing
is we need to really rethink the value
chain from the vendor orient perspective
in the sense that we need to be able to
understand better the security measures
before the products get released to
market and it means that the vendors and
OMS need to take an active role and
active stance at pressuring the
suppliers in providing cyber in
providing security reports of course
this is very difficult to implement when
you think about it but it can be done at
certain level of industries certain
level of sectors and this is a first
step towards improving the security
levels and one of the most important
initiative that can be developed is of
course to raise the awareness of the end
consumers so if you are able to generate
a demand driven change in security
levels you're going to be able to have
devices that are more secure by
definition so if you are able to explain
to the consumers that they need to pay
eighty dollars their camera instead of
ten dollars but it will be a secured
camera that would be a very good step of
course there's always the regulation
aspect that needs to be taken into
consideration especially when it comes
to to software reinforcements when it
comes to the second area of challenge
and the digital payment in the context
of the NFC ecosystem well most of the
financial institutions don't take
is a big risk because they think of it
as an accepted risk however Salvador
showed this afternoon that the amount
that can be intercepted can be easily
scaled up which poses even more
challenges so essentially they need to
find alternative layers of protection
against relay and replay attacks in
their products finally when we come
about the third aspect which is
improving the zero day market well in
particular there is an urgent need to
reinforce and provide clearer
regulations and guidelines and this
needs to be done at the trans industry
trans national level in order to be
really effective and to generate some
kind of cooperation this can be done by
either having better classifications
around the vulnerabilities better
pricing models and also disclosures of
dangerous vulnerabilities so as you can
see most and some of the recommendations
around regulations but we need to be
very careful with regulation Alan Wilson
famous American politician said that the
more regulation you put the less
personal freedom you have so we need to
find exact balance between personal
freedom and of course regulation without
falling into the trap of compliance
thank you
[Applause]