so welcome to my presentation so what
are we going to talk about today is
actually a research that I mean the main
point about it is to show how to start
from from scratch then get to the point
where you have volun ability and if
there's something I really emphasize on
taking from this presentation is the
actual process of doing the research so
our agenda for today
first I'll briefly cover sandbox
concepts for the sandbox usages and why
we need yet then we'll go to some more
specific use cases but still talk about
high-level things that we'll go through
the entire path that got me to find this
and I was vulnerability and I also talk
about a technique I used to not a debug
the kernel but to make sure it's easier
to to trace that and finally I'll show
some lazy did thing I did to the buggy
Apple processes before we start with a
presentation to the second it's about
myself my name is Adam donenfeld I've
been a security researcher for the last
couple of years I focus mainly on mobile
platforms but I also have a little bit
of experience with PC my research is
really vulnerability assessment and
exploitation right now I work at the
Imperium as an iOS researcher and I also
like to present my mobile in conferences
and I also live non-new up I moved from
Israel to Amsterdam yeah so sandbox so
offering system wants to protect
sensitive attack surfaces and it does
that using Sun boxing that's something
that the tendency to actually use
sandbox to make the attack surface
smaller is something that we've seen in
iOS I mean everyone does that but iOS
the Apple started doing that in the last
five years
more than more than ever because I
realized that instead of trying to fix
certain bugs it's just much much better
I mean it's much more practical to
actually just close the talk surfaces we
also see I mean like in we also saw that
example in Windows in window to K but
Apple has been doing that for a lot of
different mechanisms now putting aside
knowing the attack surface send hooks is
also pretty useful if you want to
prevent apps from accessing specific
information for instance a fleshlight
application is not supposed to be able
to read off fingerprints and call off D
for instance which is responsible for
some publication security things on the
device he's not supposed to be able to
access or calendar or camera so that's
that's the you know the known use case
for sandbox but as we can see Apple
actually introduced new sandbox rules
because of vulnerabilities a famous case
was in 2015 when mouth dude I think that
was the guy he found an attack from
airdrop some I think it was a traversal
which just got route act we've got a
Getti root access on the device because
sharing B which is the demon elbow of
users was running if I remember
correctly as root without sandbox
so just Apple just put it into the
sandbox and I even if you have an elbow
of vulnerability
it will fill it another one to make sure
you can elevate your privileges and we
also saw that recently I mean for the
photos of you who used to jailbreak your
phones seven eight years ago of the
symlinks restrictions that now we have
on AF see that's why we don't see a lot
of USB vulnerabilities like before and
if some of you remember my research from
last year I presented the fully working
kernel exploits
in like 99% success rates walking pretty
much instantly but still in the same box
escape so
even if you have a kennel exploit if you
have something that prevents you from
accessing this certain attack surface
then then you still have a lot of fold
to do so actually sandbox in my opinion
is much better than closing specific
bugs at least cost-effective wise it's
much I mean as an attacker I would like
to have bugs fixed and not attack
surfaces being closed but sometimes an
app does need some specific permissions
elevated permissions like sometimes I
mean Instagram wants to be able to use
your camera so Apple doesn't want to
give it direct access to the camera
driver but it still wants see Instagram
to be able to use the camera so
technically speaking if an app wants to
utilize the camera not a request
and our PC to use the camera but
literally ask the device to use the
camera it will just ask I mean okay the
different example here video decoding if
you want to encode a video you have to
talk with the video encoding driver if
you want to do it in how to accelerate
it the way and that that's how an app
would normally do that but an iOS we
have media server which is a broken on
in that case because if I'm an app if
I'm a video app I'm not going to talk
with a video encoder but rather I'll
speak with I asked the media server to
do that encoding for me and then me the
server will reply back with the encoded
video now what media server does here is
making sure I'm not trying to pound the
kernel and make sure that I do what
Apple wants me to do so even if I
somehow have one a built-in AV video
encoder like Ziva I'm still not good I
mean I'm still not good to go from an
unprivileged app because only media
server can speak can communicate with AV
video encoder so with that said like
every good presentation in iris
vulnerabilities a surface
some of you have talked about herself is
too much here because awaitin because
it's not relevant to the inveterate
entirely relevant representation so in a
single sentence i OS AI surface is an
object in iOS so if i'm process a and i
wasn't a lot of information to process
be instead of sending it five gigabytes
i can just map it in process be and all
process be has to know is a certain ID
so it makes everything much more faster
and it's mainly used for transit for
transferring frame buffer information in
graphic stuff so our surface cannot only
map information but it also have a
certain set of properties literally a
dictionary key value based properties
but if i want to create an a surface
object and i want to put some poverty's
then the kernel does verify that i'm not
trying to put some weird values in them
so yeah one year ago i found a
vulnerability in a surface which
actually i never thought about it so
there is one of the properties that we
have in our surface is something called
a plane there's a sized base and it has
a lot of them so there was a problem
here that's the planes I'm controlling
plane size and plane base and there are
a lot of different planes so here it
takes the plane base I'm giving it it
takes the plane size it combines them
together and then it checks if the last
plane base we had overlaps with the new
one and what I didn't think about you
guys Cupertino is that this is a sine X
it's if I'm putting a negative value
just we will just treat it like unsigned
int and this way I can make a buffer
over here so what it lets me do is
putting a very big plane size because I
can put a negative sign base and then I
can override it then I can go and I mean
put a very big size here which is
something Apple obviously doesn't want
us to have so
unfortunately from an attackers
perspective even though the even though
that looks like a powerful vulnerability
I'll surface only saves the planes s
value as a property so even if we have a
big plane size number here it's still
not good enough to actually pound
something directly from the aisle
surface kernel driver we have to get
something else use that property and
make sure that for example user mode the
demon of an adult camel driver uses that
value without because an adult person
and Colonel young drivers assume that
these properties are sanitized so
basically what we wanna know is what
uses our surface and obviously we want
to go straight to the killer
so instead of looking for user more
processes I will start looking for camel
drivers that use a surface so the way we
do that is our surface is an object
which we create using the I'll surface
root user client so if I may use a
permit process I'm just creating a
handle to this specific interface
exposed by the earth surface kernel
driver if you wanna see if you wanna
obtain a handle to an eye surface object
like I said before each other surface
object has an ID so drivers do that
using the iOS surface routes service
it's a kernel service and as a user mode
process we cannot not directly we cannot
use that but other drivers can now the
way drivers use other services in the
system is literally by their name soil
surface root register it registers
itself as IO chorus root which means
that if a driver who uses I have surface
this string will be in a driver so in
the most now out in simplest way I was
just starting to look for the string
ioco surface routes in the camel cash
which yielded list of cannon drivers
that uses the users aisle surface now
like I said before more
of these not most but like the camera
interface is closed is closed from
sandbox we use media server to
communicate with a driver some are some
of them are not accessible from the
sandbox some aren't but that's the list
of the others that actually utilize IO
surface so our vulnerability was about
the property plane in the earth surface
object and because most if not think all
of the drivers we have here actually
closed source so again going the most
dumbest approach I was just looking for
the string plane in all of these drivers
and then a debug string appeared and a
very interesting debugging actually Pai
surface test get playing ba-ba-ba-ba-ba
and we see that the use plane seal and
our surface objects again I don't really
I mean from from the first view it
doesn't really mean a lot but it's a
good direction because the other ones
didn't have anything to do with planes
at at least voluntary in terms of
strings so going today to the place
where we I had that string string
I saw the following code I hope it's
readable so I assumed okay so in the
drivers in action you
they have V tables so if I want to check
whether an object uses a specific colors
a specific function that's a V table
offset and that's what it calls the
function so what I assumed because of
that string is that each eight here is a
nice surface object and when I took
offset 110 in the eye surface V table I
saw that it was indeed the jet plane
size and they actually use the the
parameters that this function expects is
just a single one which is the plane ID
so x0 is the surface itself because it's
a virtual call and w1 is the plane ID
now again this is
just an assumption but it's a very good
one in my opinion because we bait we saw
like actual debug strings and because
the probability that this offset will
match the the actual string is is not so
high so if it does match it's a good
sign
now if you guys remember the
vulnerability was a controllable plane
size and we see that we have a mem set
without control with with the plane size
with a TS which we don't know yet what
the eighties are and to be honest I
still don't know what the eighties out
till today and we offered something I'm
not sure what yet but it looks like a
very good start because we can control
you can calm em set in the kernel with
an arbitrary length so yeah so like I
said we get the plane size puts it in
Peaks 23 6 23 is the length parameter
which is being called to memset you
remove the assembly code above it but it
was just a duplication of this one so
this memset calls the same function but
put here zero so it was 0 here but it's
the same it's the same thing so ok it
can be recapping here we have of an
override with a TS with an arbitrary
length sounds interesting but to
actually do something with that we have
to actually understand why Apple D 5500
is and I'm gonna say D 5500 because this
is too long we said so many times in a
presentation so the 5500 is a video
decoding visor if we have accelerated
video decoding which is unfortunately
not accessible from the sandbox but
we'll see an interesting approach soon
and to communicate with the driver we
have to use like I said before a media
server D so if I'm in app and I want to
have a decoded video I'm sending the
code my video please request so media
server D which checks that I'm not
trying to mess
with anything because this driver is
extremely I mean it's like like a glass
I mean you you you I don't know it was
like I mean if you have actual access to
this driver at least if you had it
wasn't that complicated to get it to
crash and if you guys ever took a look
at media server day the same thing some
of the Reggie teammate api's crash media
server day so media server was making
sure we're not trying to do anything
anything bad here
then it forwarded the request to the
5500 the 5500 sent the decoded video
back to media server day which send it
back to us so a very unfortunate thing
happened while I was doing this research
I fell silently closed this
vulnerability that was the only to
assembly letter that was that was
everything they needed to actually fix
the vulnerability and I'm not sure who
found that or who reported that but I
never saw any credits on the security
advisory and I was still furious about
what I saw because the mem said we date
is something I don't understand and
surfaces are always fun when it comes to
iOS so I kept with the with my you know
with my thoughts about the 5500 so I
wanted to know how we get to this
function because I was just looking up a
string so I wasn't exactly sure how I'm
going to get execution here because just
in the middle of the driver and the
driver is not open sourced and no
documented at all in fact if I if you
google that the only things you see are
questions we just mentioned that as a
loaded extension so looking up access to
this function first of all there were
like billions of them and again all
sources so go figure that word means
some of them were actually virtual so it
don't really have an xref you have to
either write your own tools to help you
with virtual calls or just yes
and again how can you actually make sure
that this function is eventually reached
because if you have so many functions I
mean how can you know that
and instand I knew that this is going to
happen a lot
the okay I have a function let's get
reached and for that I have had an
interesting approach I took the yellow
project thanks for a look at the desk
marco grassy for that by the way and
they have a remap page macro the head I
mean it's not today it doesn't work
anymore as fun as far as I know which
was disabling kpp for a Centon page so
what I did I just used I just disabled
the kpp for a specific page and then I
overrode false traction on the adverse I
was trying to trace so ultimately my
goal was to give specific channel
address in my project and whenever this
address was executed I wanted to be
notified about it and we wanted to see
all of the visitors in that certain
moment so what I did I call it yellow
plus plus let's say that I wanted to
trace the execution context in address
118 I first called rima page on the
entire page then I allocated the
shellcode which just pushed all of the
registers to the stack called K printf
had some false tabs here and then just
returned back then what I did I overrode
the code here in hundred and eighteen so
that it will actually jump to my
shellcode instead of executing that
specific instruction and the other life
like I said before was with LDR x16
loading eight bytes up front then
calling the address and then calling the
jumping door at specific shelter address
and then what I also did was on running
the phone instruction of about here I
put them here so then the execution will
seamlessly go back to the to where it
was I also changed the heads of the seal
but I didn't like put it in there
square but there is also some
modifications to x30 so it goes back to
you know to the appropriate address and
not 2 1 1 C and this way every time
118 was executed I was notified about it
and I was actually surprised because it
was it worked better than I expected and
it's it was extremely powerful when for
me at least for me when I was walking on
a calendar rifles close those once at
least so around the around the place
where I saw the string with the memset I
saw the same behavior again same
approach some length I'm not sure
exactly what it did but again I can
assume it might somehow be related to
our surface and again this 80 with mem
sets on something I'm not sure what it
was and ok and I stood at this point I
can start reversing like a decent person
the driver and for that I because I did
cannot tracing technique so I'm not
going to go deeply in that but basically
you have to I mean there are some key
rules when when you start reversing in
rifle first of all you have to know
where the V table saw and where they
point to and if you can automate that
that would be fantastic you have to know
the entry points to the driver all of
the in Linux it's iocked else in iOS is
no it's external methods most of the
times and again I highly recommend
automating that it is possible to do
that manually but it's it's really not
fun and I mean a lot of people claim to
have to release tools about it thinks he
goes did we actually released something
about it but I yes but I Department
works well on that and I and I think
writing something that's only way while
you start developing something is
actually a very good approach ok so like
we said before 80 the memset 80 was had
something to do it
I was surface in the drive
so let's examine the earth surface
usages in the driver so like before a
simple string search for a surface in
the specific driver and allocate kala
memory that lookup surface failed which
is perfect because that's where they
look up the i/o surface objects now I
put this coding took a snippet in C
because because it was too long for the
if it would be in assembly now what I
did here is I assumed
v.24 is an our surface object so while
all of that can be might be false I did
know this some very unique unique
pattern for usage of surface objects and
that is like I said before with our
surface you can map in from a map memory
from process a to process B and the way
Apple do that is using something called
IO memory descriptor so I saw that there
was a function a via table function in
our surface which created and I see an
IO memory skip o object again this was
just an yes but I saw that offset wise
it was calling the same API that you
would go when you actually use word in a
purple user file surface so I remember
the script or map which returns us an
object called IO memory map it's not
really relevant here but the thing is it
does look like a nice surface pattern it
was it's a lot of guessing and you know
you cannot abyssion for 100% but it does
look like in terms of the offsets it
looks like a nice surface usage so and
that's that's the thing I mean that's
interesting party if any even if you're
not sure about it just guessing might be
a good start now okay the offsets I saw
here in this strata calls office props
somehow match the same offsets I saw in
memset again Allah JJ allegations but it
looked like the same thing so then I
just use the characteristic technique I
showed you before and I saw that this
was indeed
surface object and that yeah I mean in
the 12-member I didn't get to diversity
but this was for sure and a surface
object because I was just tracing the
the address of the v-- table and it
matters much match the one that types of
a said so I knew that for sure that this
is an air surface object here now the
thing is obviously because of
vulnerability was with the plane size we
want to be able to supply our own outer
surface object that's that's the thing
so for that I had to reverse the actual
call for media server because like I
said it's not accessible from the
sandbox but because this API gets a lot
of user mode objects a lot of
complicated ones I assume maybe we can
somehow affect the if not the actual
arrival surface subject maybe its
properties so I know that media server
is the one that calls the 5500 mainly
because it always crashes when you when
you call it when you use it and when you
when I searched up the string D 5500 I
actually didn't see in the media server
and the closest approach the closest
thing was something called video toolbox
which I saw first time when I started
this research because it had some video
decoding related functions so yeah we
have to reverse with the toolbox now
this is really painful because it's in
something called a liter of cache which
is so in iOS you don't actually have
libraries you have a big file called a
lead shelf cache which is like I think
modern gigabytes now now Ida seven
claims to support it I beg to differ
it's a very bad implementation I'm not
sure who's to blame but even though
neither seven it wasn't that good but
before that didn't even claim to support
it so I was actually working on an IDE a
Python script so because if you put it
in a Python you just don't have branches
for most of the functions so I created
an Ida Python script
made sure that we have those branches
and two days later the release later
seven so I just I walked like at least a
full day on that script maybe even two
days and then I didn't even have to use
it but happens
so a no apparent usage of D 5500 in
villa 2 toolbox as well so at this point
I was a little bit lost because like you
cannot debug media server D or this
extension while it runs on meter every
day so I guess maybe there is another
framework involved and she was just
looking up the string D 5500 in the
entire Dalek short cache which took like
2 days to load in Ida and then I found
that there was an interesting unknown
framework called h.264 h8 which actually
did a proper usage of the API is to talk
with the driver so I did see that in a
function called Apple D 5500 decode same
internal there was this API which is the
API Apple supplies if you want to use
exposed interface of drivers so every
time you call that function you actually
send the request a request to a rival so
the actual exported function in h.264 h8
was this one this long function but
unfortunately didn't have any xrefs and
i mean most of the code I'm saying most
because sometimes it does happen but
most of the codes isn't written not to
be used so I thought it might be maybe
inevitable of something and because Ida
and dieter - aren't so good friends yet
maybe it just didn't parse it so then I
was like ok I'll just search the address
in Ida and see if I find something
interesting and yeah I found it in a V
table in something that looks like a V
table which also didn't have an XF and
then I started going with the same
technique of okay if it doesn't have X
roof it's just because either doesn't
and then I just started searching for
the others again and I saw that there
was a V table and another V table like
thing which was contained in another
variable so eventually this one did have
symbols edit did have xref sorry and
going back up the stack the stack trace
an object a call which was which is
named blahblah the calculate instance
was actually being called and if we can
see here specific video formats were
given to a function which is not really
I mean there are a lot of functions I'm
not going to do it to each one of them
but I still wanna show you the hierarchy
so the function h.264 h8 register which
calls this one also didn't have access
but it did appear a string somewhere so
what I realized is that it doesn't it
actually uses DL open and there seem to
call that which i think is weird
considering the use of dial job - so
again this is the floor I had to go from
the moment I yeah I send a request to
media server till a driver was being
used so I'm sending an explicit quest to
media server X PC is by the way some ap
as some IPC mechanism that Apple creates
basically you can send information
easily in a dictionary or a nice objects
style so you do that using an
undocumented API called VT the
computation session create which is
getting I mean you actually call that in
your process in its first I remember
that's the actual same function which is
being called in media server and there's
like a check if your media server then
do something otherwise just send stuff
to media server so this function calls
the open DL theme which calls h.264
register which calls this function which
creates an object with a V table which
is another V table which is another
function so this wasn't fun at all to
the first but we have to do that so I
mean
main problem was lit seriously Ida not
even because you know it's just extra
food string search but the super slow
so this API I mean all the VT the
compression blah blah blah while things
actually documented in a sense that you
know what the parameters they are
expecting and I figure out perhaps this
is I mean that sounds like something
that is related to our surface because
it's actually decoding frames so maybe
that's the thing that that's the thing I
mean none of the 80s actually talked
about an iOS surface ID being given to
an API but it must be those somewhere so
this function I mean this function was
calling this function within the h.264
h8 framework and then completely
undocumented
I saw the following code awhile
dictionary appeals then you can you
could supply I mean I just reversed the
entire chain of chain I showed you then
I saw that if you supply the dictionary
I mean the the API you can receive a
dictionary and if you supply this
dictionary it gets some parameters this
is completely undocumented and it's
accessible from the sandbox and I mean
if there's a good in my experience if
there is another surface there is a bug
so I mean at the moment I saw that I was
like okay finally something good is
going here and I obviously obviously had
no idea what of the teks and offset why
were or what lifestyle was I did all
that kind of a surface ID sounds like
the actual surface area we give to the
driver so yeah like I said it absurdly
receives an i/o surface ID receive some
offsets and I wanted to check whether
this was the surface the surface we saw
in the kernel and using the kel-tec the
IRS general tracing technique I did and
it was indeed the specific a surface
object we specified this is another
example how this was useful because
without having that I cannot think on a
on a on a way to actually
make sure that this was our surface
object so understood that what I
supplied here was going directly to the
channel and it was accessible from the
sandbox because media server they just
used it and pass for the request to the
driver so our objective was to get to
the memset yes I hope you remember I
mean at that point we already had
control on the earth surface we supplied
so I just used the IO IO SEL and tracing
technique on the memset area now this is
the mem set and this is a tile of the
textile of the try what is what we
supplied in this dictionary and if you
see here and interesting thing I love
it's y-intercept X are being given here
and these are all our surface properties
we fully control or at least in a very
good I mean yeah I mean it depends on
other properties sometimes but in that
case I don't think there was any
restriction if I remember correctly and
this was given to plane offset one here
which is being used till that's the
length now not only we control the
length we can also control the offset
from where we start overriding so this
is much more powerful because I mean
operating a lot of things is one thing
making sure where you actually start
overriding is extremely powerful because
if you can actually utilize this memset
and you can write this a tea on a
specific length field on on a different
object so I mean this is good enough to
start walking your way into a very
powerful right primitive on the channel
so I mean once you have the offset
control this well this is a completely
different game so there was one problem
though I mean and if I put the kernel
technique a testing technique here I saw
this verse indeed my my properties but
context some other data unknown I mean
this this expression
was was always preventing the cod flow
from going into the memset again
twenty-something functions dipped in the
diver I mean how do you find out what
this is so because there's no source
code there are no extras because it's a
struct offset so how to find out what it
is so I looked at the assembly and that
was ultimately the check they took
something for offset four for eight and
then they took the six byte from it and
they ended it with six thirty
I've absolutely I mean I had absolutely
no idea all it was and then I did there
again most dumbest approach I just
dumped the entire Bible text section and
started wrapping so that is same I mean
nothing
no magics it was just dumping the kernel
literally dropping the offsets with STL
and unfortunately here there was a good
candidate I mean that was the only store
in to offset four four eight so I went
to this address
then I mean if it's the only one then we
can assume we can stay actually safely
assume that this was the about objects
were looking at but here we had X 28 now
not sure how how much pain you had from
reversing rebels in iOS but X 28 is the
is a function of the oil subject so
every time you release the ref count on
an object they use the offset X 28 yeah
I think yeah X 28 next one is rating so
you cannot graphics 28 on a calendar
either you have hundreds of matches and
in this point I unfortunately had to
start the first thing like 15 functions
and again you cannot have the compiler
set you serious left to go fully offsets
and hope that eventually you find
something useful so again I think this I
mean this was really I mean I was a
little bit miserable at that time but
again I was in the other hand here
memset so and eventually I got to that
point so I saw what they put in the x28
I mean they said here we have two peaks
28 from from which is being given to
four four eight so as I said it was the
six byte and I saw there was some
calculation which I'll translate for you
that was the arithmetic that was done
and being put in that specific thing now
again it's the middle of nowhere we have
no idea what we're looking at but again
1b0 is a little bit less common so I did
the same approach I just grabbed one b0
with STR which yielded the falling
offset which yielded the following
interesting interesting extreme h.264
f/w set PPS and SPS no idea what it is
yet
now that's something you didn't know
about it I never liked h.264 and I never
know anything about h.264 except that
that's what I download when I want to
see movies and again for looking on the
cheque
I literally googled the I mean I just
looked it on the the function and and I
saw another interesting string ABC
decoder power said unsupported Nalu
length size sorry googled ABC Nalu and
the first resource was welcome to h.264
thank you and we I mean at that point I
understood that having the standard
might be useful I would try to be to be
honest I would refrain from I mean I
would try to do anything I mean reading
the standard is seriously the last thing
you wanna do but it was very useful
eventually nuisance it will cease and
why so I'll summarize it for you a video
is actually is actually a bunch of null
units and Malu so just a bunch of Na
units so you can actually H everything
you see in the video file is a null
object and I'm not sure if you can see
anything from here
so I'll try to zoom because there are a
few fields which are important so there
is a lot of things in null objects and
to be honest I am not really sure what
they all mean because I mean people do a
PhD on that yes
and but there some header offsets in
this specific object which are very
important here are they forbidden zero
bit which is I have no idea why they put
that but that's standard so yeah we
always have to comply nullified EC which
I'm still I mean it wasn't relevant to
the research and I didn't have to
understand what it was
I mean assume it I assume it's a
reference but I cannot give a guarantee
on that but now unit type is something
very interesting because this defines
how it process the null object so I mean
we had a lot of things here but after
them after them everything that happened
was based on this null unit type so
again each null object as a type and I
mean now that we know that and we know
that we are talking about value of null
objects in the kernel how do we find
where the kernel processes the the
specific object beit's based on its type
so i got into that specific code and so
0 null if i DC with idea c and this
label which is being called here now
here there is a branch not 0 and the and
i mean if this is if this is 0 and this
is 5 this string is being printed now
going back to the manual we did see that
now fi DC and we did see unit ID so it
might be I mean I was confident enough
to assume that they might come after
each other in destruct in the kernel and
as you can see they just popped them
from the object constitutively I mean in
the same order so and I saw the the old
idea which is
so again I just cook I mean I just you
looked for the string idea in the manual
and that's why sometimes many are
important but really vicious and I found
out that number five in a Linotype is
Suffolk called ideal and as we saw here
hey let's we saw here there was a
comparison to five so now we know that
not only this is a null object we
actually know some very important
offsets in that object and at that point
it was much easier to go and see the
actual processing of the object and then
what I saw I mean and there I mean there
are a lot of null types I'm gonna go
through the important ones for the
specific research but there are billions
of them and I would be surprised if
there are vulnerabilities there unless
Apple revamped the entire driver so the
first one that we have that we have the
robot is some little SPS so if we have a
driver if you have a video so there are
a bunch of properties for a short video
video sequence so just like a few second
it depends it can be a few seconds can
be it can actually actually be the
entire movie but just a bunch of
properties for specific devotion PPS
picture parameter set is the same thing
like SPS but for pictures so a bunch of
a bunch of pictures had PPS like
properties like PPS and there was also
something called idea which is seriously
like a BMP it was a standalone image so
for those of you a little bit more
familiar with video the compare video
encoding I mean if you have like a
picture and then you have only the the
modifications between each frame and
that's what is stored in the file so
idea was a complete standalone image so
you couldn't go I mean it didn't need
any other frame to be parsed and other
friends so based on the last on the idea
they had before them
so for each SPS so for each short video
sorry for each
video sequence the idea null was the
first one so this is how it looks in the
video you have the SPS objects the PPS
object points to the SPS and then we
have an idea object and afterwards what
if we have the frames so this must
always be the first one and this must
always point to SPS by by ID by day by
the way each I mean they have a specific
ID and they just point to each other
going back to the research we had the
string said PPS and SPS and then I
figured maybe one b0 is actually an SPS
object PPS objects so what I did I
seriously sent a video to be decoded and
then I checked using the tracing
technique if it was what one b0 was and
it indeed looked like the SPS I was
sending in the video now and note about
it I started using ffmpeg because I was
too lazy to you know actually go and
post videos on my own but then I found
out that sometimes all these public
tools are not enough so it was I mean it
sounds powder than it actually is there
a lot of actually good persons in github
for h.264 videos so just to sum I mean I
just thought my own tools to decodes and
to create and to post videos and I know
it's a lot of infrastructure sometimes
but eventually it was it at least in my
opinion because this saved me a lot of
time in you know open
1:01 editor and starts writing beats so
like I said 1b0 was our SPS object which
was sufficient to understand the
mysterious
memset expression that we didn't have
back then if you remember so if a now if
an a property called Homa format IDC is
zero we can get to the memset so what I
did and by the way this means I mean if
this is zero it means the video is
monochromatic so only black and white so
in controls the if I if I'm not mistaken
because again it's a standard so it's
got all the colors or the video
so what it is I was just using the tools
I wrote I chaired the video it's
chloroform at IDC zero and I tried to
decode it so the way you do that
with the API we call the very long
function name see a video form a
description a its form a 264 parameter
sets from when I want H form H 264
parameter sets because I'm not going to
say that every time this initializes the
session with the witch media server and
it receives PP s and s PS properties the
session is the session needs the output
from this function the session creation
a API and then we call VT the
compression session decodes frame and
then nothing happens now you know I'm
not sure if how it looks now but I was
you know imagine your work like two
weeks just to get to a specific
instruction and then you're like ok and
finally I'm finally getting there and no
nothing happened I was very very
frustrated at that moment so I mean I
saw that we didn't even get to the point
where the driver was being used and then
the first immediate surfer D and I saw
that media server checks if koma format
IDC is not zero
and if it's zero it denies the request
now at this point I'm like you know
after all this verse engineering in the
tools everything but then in a rainy day
I know it necessarily never rained and I
was still in Ezra back then so in a
sunny day yet depressing one I get the
h.264 format which revealed the
following so each frame pointed to a PA
to a PPS object and every PPS object I
mean by ID supported by ID and every
yeah and every PPS object pointed also
by ready to to an SMS object and like I
said SPS objects had the whole format ID
see now this got me thinking why do they
need an ID for an SPS object if there is
only one because if you look at the
ffmpeg if you download the video from
YouTube and you use ffmpeg to analyze it
there's always one SV PSPs object also
when you know when you pause the video
they
never have more than one and of course I
don't I don't wanna start writing my own
video with bits so I usually just
downloaded the video and post it and
maybe modified it but then it's got my
thingy maybe there's more than one SPS
object and then I read the following
don't worry
there is a nice infographic later on I
hope you can see it I cannot zoom
because it's too white so bla bla bla
bla bla it's most one sequence yeah each
sequence parameter set so each SPS is
initially considered not active at the
start of the operation of the recording
process its most one SPS is considered
active within a given moment during the
operation of the decoding process and
the activation of any particular SPS
results in the deactivation of the
previously active SPS if any which means
that stand unwise I mean I never saw any
video utilizing that functionality but
the standard says so so we have to
comply you could have theoretically a
lot of SPS objects and a lot of PPS
objects and each PPS object could point
to a different SPS object so that was
completely no serious relationship in
terms of they cannot on each SPS can
only be perturbed by a single PPS I mean
you could just point to whatever you
want and in terms of design this
function was receiving only and as a
single SPS and a single PPS object and
because these are it's video packets
which are being sent as synchronously
this function couldn't get these ones I
mean I mean if I was this function could
only get the first SPS that was being
used because this could be sent later on
after we already started the decoding
and this one was checking the Oklahoma
format IDC field so basically what I
could do is let's say that we send back
- this Square and this square decodes
the video packets so if I'm sending a
frame and this is currently active and
you know that's the current state of the
the compression of the state machine
this slice could point to PPS - which
points to PPS 1 which deactivates which
points to a space one which deactivates
pacifier zero so again I thought that a
lot of there could be more than a single
SPS object and because this is only
called once and only in the beginning I
had the following idea I'll just create
a normal session with media server and
I'll send it's a nice colorful video and
then I'll just send it an SBS packet
with soma format IDC equals zero so like
hey I'm a colorful video and all of a
sudden a packet which changes the entire
video - and one of harmonic 1 and if you
think about it that's it doesn't make
any sense but standardized it's legal so
then I could just hear that the PPS to
point to this new SBS and then I send a
slice which pointed to the SPS which
pointed to a PPS and then finally L got
to the web set after two weeks I found
it I mean it took me two weeks from the
moment I saw the map set to get at this
point which is I mean more frustrating
than it sounds but it was seriously and
I mean it was very anticipated so again
the code flow I sent a normally looking
video yeah that is how videos look like
if you open them in 1-0-1 editor then I
carry the new SPS object in the new PPS
object with a pointer to the SPS then a
new idea because idea must be the first
slice that is used in the SPS which
point the PPS to the SPS and so on
finally crash let's go to Apple and now
this was around blackett last year and
all of a sudden the most modern
operating system in the world it's
always the most operating system in the
world went out and ok cool so I looked
at the better I remember it
I was seeking the Vegas and yeah that's
what you do when you're sick from the
weather in Vegas and suddenly it doesn't
crash anymore and you saw the way I was
going through to get it crashing and I
mean I was super disappointed that they
didn't crash and so I checked age to 60
a camel driver and I saw that there was
no apparent change in the driver which
was good because the vulnerability was
eventually in the camel driver and not
in the user mode components but aged to
65 I mean the private framework which
said the canvas server study is changed
the canvas surface ID string no longer
appears in the framework and I know it
sounds way that I'm talking about
strings in a framework but seriously
have no idea what this user ID on these
frameworks so Apple realized that having
this in a dictionary in an undocumented
ich chanel is a very happy way to treat
the tile decoded videos italic coding
videos from normally coding so they just
created created a new API 204 decoding
and a new API for tile decoding if I
remember correctly back then
sadly coding wasn't documented yet but
it will call the API it was already
there now at that point I just if you
have kernel rewrite then you can use the
bug server to to actually debug I mean
you can launch the bug server and
connect a media server but it doesn't
work if you do it out of out of the box
and then I went to some all dvd-video
page which tells you that the bug server
needed the following the following
entitlements it also did involved and
then I said maybe I'll just give the
same entitlements to me the server and
then I'll try to launch the bug server
and attach it to meteor server then it
worked
I could debug media server and the main
reason I wanted to debug media server is
first of all I wanted to go to the API
where it's called away where it sent a
request to the driver and
the values and see if the crush still
happens a second if I want to see what
they actually did in the new API there
it was just faster debugging than using
Iida the back then so like I said they
understood that it was a hack so they
added a new bunch of VT tile the
compression api's whose debug server and
I changed the values and it crashed
again so what I understood eventually is
that there's just a new API not a
documented one unfortunately so here
there is like a 64-bit integer which
gets the offset X and offset Y that we
saw in the dictionary Civic pixel buffer
has inside it an i/o surface ID if you
creating a CV pixel buffer with another
surface object so it will just use the
same surface ID to the drive oh yeah so
then instead of using the dictionary you
could just call this API and it would
crush instantly but again it was not
mended so it did take me a while to find
it out so in terms of okay in terms of
disclosure I found it I don't know I
mean there was a gap between iOS better
still you know it took me a while to get
back to the research and then I reported
a month later I will confirmed it and in
the end of January they deployed it to
their devices I know that it's it might
be a little bit old compared I mean now
but I mean there are some takeaways I
really want you guys to take from this
representation sometimes okay
many else this we don't like them yeah
and I mean I could I mean I really hate
I read quite a few in my life and it was
never a fun thing to do but sometimes
the super useful without the manual I
would never think about creating a new
SPS object so you know that's what got
me eventually to trigger the
vulnerability in some structure work the
kernel tracing technique
I mean without it I would probably give
up at some
because you have no idea how powerful I
mean we probably have if you ever worked
with drivers it just insane it you can
debug or at least trace a code execution
in the device so it was working even
days or weeks on something like that if
you can later on debug the kernel and
like always
iOS is a really good platform but it
still has a way to go and usually I mean
another vulnerability itself wasn't
certainly complicated but I think the
path there was I mean I think it's
sometimes more interesting than an
actual exploit I mean if I compare it to
my last two prior to the presentation
that it last year this was much more
complicated so we have is we have like
35 seconds for Q&A so thank you I hope
you enjoy the presentation I know it
wasn't easy
thank you very much Adam for a very
interesting talk and also for being the
speaker who comes closest to the time
line thank you very much
perfect timing as well because this
breaks is for lunch we have an hour for
lunch and we will see you back here for
lunch I'm available on Twitter and if
you have any question you can catch me
later we'll be happy to answer yep any
questions as well you also be there at
lunch - yeah so versus free to join it
and join you thank you thank you