alright thanks everybody for sticking
around I know it's been a long weekend
not literally but figuratively so
hopefully you're all still with me to
talks left to go somebody is all right
so who is this jerk on stage my name is
Darren camp I do security research for
duo security co.labs team if you don't
know duo we do two-factor authentication
and our labs group does proactive
security research I'll know quickly that
I did this research with my colleague
Mikhail davidoff who deserves a lot of
the credit he's not here today but he's
an equal partner in all of this so what
the heck am I talking about I am talking
about the windows while 64 subsystem
which I will be tail in a bit and I am
demonstrating a mostly simple ahmet bye
pass using that subsystem can I get a
show of hands who knows what emed is or
if anybody's deployed or used it okay if
you don't know what it is I'll mention
that a bit and if I could also go to
show of hands who's got like some
exploit development experience or knows
like what like return oriented
programming and things like that are ok
few you so if you don't don't worry I'll
also note that this research we figured
it would be a blog post and then it
became a 19-page paper and now I'm
trying to trying to crush a 19-page
paper into a 30 page or 30 slide
presentation so we'll see how that goes
all right so just a quick refresher x86
64 chips which is what you know most of
you are running in your laptop's these
days or on your desktops execute in one
of two modes long mode which would be a
64-bit operating system and legacy mode
which is how you run a 16 or 32 bit
operating system when you're executing
in long mode there's also the
compatibility sub mode which allows you
to execute 16 and 32 bit pieces of code
so windows on Windows is the or the
while 64 subsystem is how windows
execute 32-bit software on a 64-bit
operating system this is what keeps all
of your you know 32-bit things running
it's largely transparent to the
applications that are executing in that
environment however you can
programmatically determine whether or
not you're running inside of it it does
have implications to how the registry
behaves how file system i/o works
exception handling and how system calls
or dispatch which is probably the most
important thing for this presentation
and it is absolutely holding back system
security overall so there's a lot of
prior work dealing with this subsystem I
absolutely not the first person to
tackle this and certainly won't be the
last the closest presentation related to
what I'm talking about today is the
first one why user mode hooking sucks
bypassing comodo internet security in
2003 @ can SEC West and Vancouver there
was a presentation on by passing a SLR
and data execution prevention using a
artifact of how this subsystem works
really elegant attack which is now
defunct there was a presentation at
source Boston this year on developing
interesting Rob gadgets that abuse the
wild 64 subsystem at least that was part
of the presentation and then a
presentation at source seattle on
obfuscation to defeat static analysis
using cross mode coding which is a super
long presentation name it beats mine but
the point here is that you know
switching between modes can confuse a
whole bunch of static analysis and
dynamic analysis tools and of course
there's a ton of different blog posts on
how the sub system works and different
ways to abuse it and we're things to do
with it so why does this matter we took
a look at some real-world authentication
data talking to our service I can't
share the full numbers with you but I
can assure you they're sizeable eighty
percent of the browsers based on the
user agent authenticating with our
service or 32-bit processes running on
64-bit versions of Windows so let's
think about this a little bit the year
is 2015 the first x86 64 chips were
released
by md in 2003 and eighty percent of
browsers are still 32 bit software it's
kind of a sad state of affairs and of
course sixteen percent of those were
actually just share 32 bit and four
percent claim to be 64-bit processes so
why is this valuable to attackers I kind
of briefly mentioned this so there are
some subsystem yo singh Chrissy's in the
past that have decreased overall system
security that was the can sec
presentation that i was talking about
when it comes to developing rob chains
you're limited to what instructions are
available to you you know by switching
modes you get a different interpretation
so you've got more potential Rob gadgets
available to you anti emulation and
obfuscation opportunities right so when
I say anti emulations or obfuscation
think about things like a piece of shell
code that does a pivot to 64-bit mode
decodes with an 8-byte xor key and then
pivots back stuff that really trivial
emulators are not going to handle well
and of course the focus of this
presentation is on bypassing quote by
passing hooks in protected mode code
which I'll get into in a little bit here
so some high-level internals the
subsystem is implemented implemented
entirely in user mode there's no support
from the colonel all while 64 processes
have for 64-bit modules in them the
first three obviously make up that
subsystem and then the fourth being a
64-bit copy of NT dll which contains all
of your all of your system calls and
things like that so the while 64 dll is
the subsystem in entry point it's
responsible for marshalling system calls
exceptions filesystem and registry
redirection that's the big one the
second is primarily there to support
mode switches saving cpu context to and
from 32 and 64-bit mode and then the
while 64 wing dll does additional
marshalling for windowing and console
subsystems the details of how those
behave isn't too important for this
presentation but i'll let you keep that
in mind
and then of course there are 32-bit
copies of and 64-bit copies of important
system management structures so each
thread has a 32 and 64-bit copy of the
threat environment block there's a 64
and 32 bit process environment block and
then there's 32 and 64-bit stacks and
keeps I'll let this slide ride for a
little bit I stole this from a Microsoft
presentation but this is sort of how the
different components interact so the top
you've got curl mode components and at
the bottom we've got user mode
components as you can see all the
interaction proxies through well 64 and
pops out at the end at anti dll with the
exception of the windowing subsystem
little liquid courage all right so this
is what things look like in memory this
is important for X for the exploitation
stuff I'm going to demo so the tab and
the peb are it fixed offsets from their
32-bit counterparts so despite being
subject to address of a dress layout
randomization or a SLR you can if you
can find their 32-bit the 32-bit
structure you can find the 64-bit
structure on Windows 7 all of those
modules I was talking about the load
order is fixed so again they're subject
to a SLR but if you can find one of them
everything is going to be predictably
aligned from there additionally the
64-bit copy of NT dll is always located
in a dress before below 4 gigabytes and
it is at a fixed offset from the 32-bit
copy of NT dll this particular factor
was big and being able to make this
exploit work easily on Windows 8 this is
not true whether or not this is an
explicit mitigation or just a
architectural change microsoft made i
don't know but it's except it's it's
much more difficult to pull this off on
windows 8 it's definitely possible but
that load order changes and the copy of
NT dll 64 is always a map than an
address above the above 4 gigabytes
okay so long mode transition so how does
how does this stuff switch back and
forth windows uses two special segment
numbers hex 23 for 32-bit and hex 33 for
64-bit to switch between modes and this
works with overlapping code segments so
a code segment is determined whether or
not it's 64 or 32 bit by the L bit in
the segment descriptor if it's set it's
64 bit if it's not it's a 32-bit segment
all of these transitions are generally
invoked through a far jump or call so as
you can see here this is the this is the
function that is typically used to
transition modes and you'll see the hex
33 at the beginning so that's the
special segment number anything after
that branch would be executed as 64 bit
code so system call invocation so if you
think back to the diagram I just showed
you this is this is sort of what it
looks like in code it's not the complete
process but you can see there is a
function pointer inside the thread
environment block so a call is made to
that function pointer which switches
modes and from there there's a bunch of
plumbing that basically deals with the
different calling conventions and
converting arguments and so on and so
forth but that all ends up you know
proxying through to the 64-bit copy of
that system call after you switch after
you switch modes you get access to the
higher order registers this is not
necessary for pulling this trick off but
it's useful especially on Windows 8 or
10 the high-order registers contain a
lot of useful information that will help
you gain context after you transition
mode so this is really good if you need
to do continuation of execution with
your exploit or repair program state but
like I said it's not that's not
necessary for for everything
so by passing hooks so this is the meat
of things first and foremost this is a
pretty old trick like this concept dates
back to like the anti virtual dost
machine and like old versions of Windows
NT this is not really a new idea i'm
just putting a new spin on it the key
here is that any time you have some sort
of security tool like an antivirus
Prioress or something like that they're
gonna want to hook functionality inside
things like anti dll because this is
where all your low-level functionality
happens right module loading creating
new processes all the things that
attackers like to abuse the 64-bit copy
in a 32-bit you're in a while 64 process
i should say is often difficult or
impractical the hook for a variety of
architectural reasons this has been used
in the past as i said that prior
presentation i talked about to defeat
things like antivirus but i'm going to
do this in a shellcode payload which can
be a little bit finicky but you can make
it work in practice so II met for those
of you who don't know II met is the
enhanced mitigation experience toolkit
it is a runtime exploit mitigation tool
provided by Microsoft what it does is
inject a dll into the process that you
want to protect and that DLL hooks a
bunch of functionality inside ntg ll it
sets a bunch of hardware breakpoints it
does a bunch of stuff to intercept and
try and inspect things that you know
exploit dev like two of you abuse this
will break most off-the-shelf exploits
like pretty much anything in metasploit
or something like that you apply II met
to the process it probably won't work
out of the box and the key here is that
most of the mitigations use function
hooks and those hooks do not affect the
64-bit copy of NT dll so look mom no
hooks so this is the 32-bit copy that
has been intercepted by e met you can
see that the function prologue has been
overwritten by an unconditional jump
that jumped lands in sight emed
where it does a bunch of additional
processing to do sanity checks on the
process if it if it thinks that things
aren't saying it bails out if you look
at the in the same process the 64-bit
implementation which is what ends up
getting called at the very end there's
obviously no hook it's just a raw system
call so we got this to work sort of as a
trial in a very contrived way and we
decided that you know we wanted to do
this for real let's take a real-world
vulnerability and see if we can do this
turns out getting it to work with a real
vulnerability is a little harder but we
got it to go we took a metasploit
exploit that is obviously publicly
available for a use after free flaw
affecting Adobe Flash you guys think
back to the rust presentation yesterday
that was a dangling pointer example use
after freefly is a dangling pointer so
this is exactly the kind of stuff that
he was talking about trying to prevent
I'm not going to go deep into the bug
but if you want to know more about it
there's really great analysis from both
core security technologies and trend
micro in order to make the exploit work
we only had to make rather minor
modifications we had to give it the
ability to understand and parse pe32
plus modules being the 64-bit version of
PE files which is portable executable or
the X cubed format windows uses and of
course we had to change how the rob
chain worked so a little more in the
original exploit there was a really
popular technique that was recently
killed that uses it sprays the heap with
vectors and then you smash the size of
one of them and what happens is you're
able to use that to do an outbound read
so you can use this as an Oracle to
defeat things like a SLR you can read
our betray process memory and figure out
where things are this is sort of the
first stage of the exploit it uses that
to scan backwards through memory looking
for the header of the flash module in
memory and then from there you can use
the import & exports it exports sections
to forward
all other modules and other functions in
memory to build your payload and to
build Rob gadgets it doesn't actually
work on well 64 process of processes out
of the box it's fairly easy to fix it's
just a broken gadget search this is
pretty much the bar these days for like
a modern browser vulnerability right so
you you build an information leak so
that you can understand the layout of
memory you discover your Rob gadgets
assemble your you know your funky chain
of things to disable you know
non-executable memory permissions and
stuff like that you cause what's called
a stack pivot which means you know often
you're taking control of an object
that's on the heap so you need to build
a synthetic stack since you're on the
heat you often have you know at the time
crash you have a register that's
pointing to that location on the heap so
you use something like an exchange espec
X or whatever register is pointing at
your object and you pivot the stack
pointer to point at the heap and then
you build a synthetic stack so usually
your wrap chain does something like
change memory protections so it'll do
like a virtual protect change the memory
permissions of your second stage payload
you fall into that you know you do
whatever a nefarious thing it is you
want to do and then you resume the
process and as I said this the original
exploit won't survive a night so return
oriented programming we didn't have to
change a lot in the original exploit
instead of using the higher-level like
virtual protect function you have to you
there's no colonel 230 kernel32 or
Colonel base module in the 64-bit
context so you don't get all those
convenient high level functions you have
to use the low-level implementations
which tends to require you know a little
more initialization and effort on your
part so instead of using virtual protect
you would use anti protect virtual
memory and this this right here is
pretty much the crux
the entire technique is basically built
on the red f instruction and instead of
like a normal function return which
would pop your return address off the
stack when your turn from a function
afar return will pop the code segment so
you start your wrap chain by popping the
code segment off the stack so that hex
33 and you pivot modes and then you do
everything off of the 64-bit copy of NT
dll so this is sort of what the sequence
looks like right you do the stack pivot
as I mentioned you return into log mode
you do your reproduction of memory so
you can execute the shellcode you inject
it into memory you fall into your second
stage payload theoretically you profit
and if you're not as lazy as I am you
actually repair the process state and
make everything run nicely which I
didn't do cuz some way too lazy of
course it's never that easy there's
always a catch so the first catch is
symbol resolution as I said the original
exploits cancer memory resolves
everything using import and export
tables none of those 32-bit modules
directly import code from the 64-bit
modules so we need a way to find them as
I said this is way easier on Windows 7
remember how I mention that there
there's a static offset well as long as
you can leak or resolve the base address
of the 32-bit copy of NT dll you can win
because all you have to do is take that
address subtract that hex value and
you'll find the 64-bit copy on windows 8
that won't work you've got to be a
little more clever so the second thing
is payload development like I said you
don't have access to Colonel 32 or
Colonel base so you don't get all the
convenient high level win API functions
you're used to you can't do things like
just call load library or win exec you
have to use their load their low-level
counterparts so LDR load dll NT curate
create process
in order to make these work there's a
lot more initialization and and and
stuff you have to set up right it's
there's a lot more going under the hood
when you call those functions and we
take a lot of that for granted this
results in bigger uglier shellcode in
the case of a browser vulnerability this
isn't so bad because you don't tend to
have a lot of problems with space to
store things right so like you've got
this small stack buffer but you have to
keep things in you've got a giant heat
that you can stash everything on but it
does result in much uglier shellcode so
this is pretty much the you know the C
equivalent the high level approximation
of what we built I'll note that this is
not doing all the proper initialization
as I mentioned so we're like this would
be a win exact call it would be
literally like you know one line of code
this isn't even complete this is super
hacky and if you were to do this you
know as a real-world adversary this is
not how you would want to do it but this
works for a contrived example all right
so I've got two VMs ones just hosting
metasploit and the other is a vulnerable
system and this will just this will just
execute an arbitrary command and run the
calculator assuming it works
you thank you I was told not to put
memes in my presentation so I put memes
in my presentation take that mark okay
um so I didn't do this on 18 but we have
a couple potential solutions loser
you're familiar with windows shell code
development you can do it like a more
traditional payload where you do symbol
resolution via the 64-bit copy of the
peb you might have to do this in pure
Rob it's this is really vulnerability
specific how you how you do this so
really depends on the context you have
in the vulnerability you're exploiting
or if the vulnerability can be triggered
more than once you might be able to do
something like build a 32-bit chain
depending on whether or not you met
would mess with you they leaked contents
of those higher order registers I
mentioned earlier back and then you
built a secondary stage and then
triggered the bug again again this is
all very vulnerability specific as to
whether or not it would work and
alternative payload implementation so I
mentioned that you know you've got to
write more complicated payloads it's not
as simple as like you know one function
call for a lot of things you would do
well 64 dll actually has rapper
functions that encapsulate all of that
functionality the major problem is that
they're not exported so you have to
indirectly resolve them and a potential
solution to that is there's a function
called while 64 system service yex that
function is exported and it uses a giant
jung table to dispatch all those mt dll
functions so you can probably do
indirect resolution through the through
that but I haven't tested it so in
conclusion Yvette is significantly more
effective on pure 32 or 64-bit processes
I don't want to I don't want to play it
down like if you're not using it you
probably should it said it'll break most
office off-the-shelf stuff but it works
far better if it's if it's protecting a
peer 32 or 64-bit processes well 64
processes and less effective and
well 64 strikes again it's been the
cause of like multiple security issues
or at least multiple security bypasses
this is a classic case of you know
legacy components impeding security our
desire for compatibility holding back
you know enhancements to our software
this is this is an optional component in
server core so if you're not running
32-bit software and you're running a
Windows Server you may want to make sure
that that's not running of course this
technique does have limitations I had to
jump through a lot more hoops it's a lot
less reliable which is frankly proof
that you should probably be using
something like II met to protect
processes from exploitation that's all I
got so questions it was 16 point 0 point
0 points something it is in the slides
so and it's also I should mention there
is the full paper is available on this
so to go to the duel labs website you
can actually read you know the full
explanation of how all this works all
the stuff that i glossed over and kind
of hand waved is better explained there
yes this is this is a vulnerability in
patch for several months so yep yeah yes
but I mean the technique is is you know
agnostic of vulnerabilities it just
happened to be a good phoner ability for
demonstrating it with anybody else any
hecklers
I have no idea i mean that's that's why
i said i don't know if that change is an
explicit mitigation or an architectural
thing but the erase i mean i'm sure more
reverse engineering i mean it's a
decent-sized subsystem so i'm sure more
reverse engineering might reveal that
but i don't have an answer for you all i
know is it made my life easier that's it
okay thanks guys