hey everybody my name is Alex I am gonna
be talking a little bit about some
hardware hacking stuff that I learned
recently when I say recently I mean like
last week so yeah
so the backstory to all of this at first
before I continue could everybody hear
me in the back and can everybody see the
slides okay awesome it's four by three
and stuff so the squares a little small
whatever so anyway I'm a bit of a green
geek as much as possible I like to buy
used laptops I like to you know keep
stuff out of the landfill if I can it
still worked perfectly fine for running
vim and stuff like that so you know yeah
editor work time
so I bought a think pad recently my
first thing pad ever got at home
realized I needed a password to get into
the BIOS so that was a bit disappointing
I could still boot from the desk I could
boot into Windows which the guy gave it
to me with I could get into I could boot
from CDs and stuff so I could install
Linux or whatever so it was okay I
contacted the seller and he of course
didn't know the password didn't know
that there was a password so I do a
little googling find a page that says if
you remove the coin cell battery you
know like you'd find on a desktop
motherboard or whatever that would reset
the password so I tried that and then
when I rebooted the date and time were
unset so every time you booted it wanted
to go into the BIOS to set it but it
needed the password so now I just
couldn't his laptop at all so now I have
a brick what what am I supposed to do
with that so of course the answer to
that is hack all the things so the guys
who actually like did all the work I
just kind of journaled Ben Bergman who
presented yesterday and Andrew or who is
also a presenter so thank you guys so
I'm gonna talk about what they did and
what I learned in the process from that
this is a retelling of past events so
it's not meant to be a guide that you
should follow necessarily but it ended
up working in the end so you know
whatever if the path if it kind of if
the tenses get confusing past tense
present tense I apologize for that
so there's a lot of stuff online about
these about this these laptops and their
passwords lots of angry people on forums
lots of like free sketchy Windows tools
when you download let me get like
malware warnings in Chrome and stuff
like that
so things that I learned right away just
googling the password is meant to be a
security feature it's not just you know
convenience or whatever it's not it's
meant to be secure it the password is
stored in an EVP ROM I electrically
erasable programmable read-only memory
it's separate from the bios separate
from everything else it's like its own
little special chip so when you lose
power it doesn't erase or anything like
that
separate from the PPM as well and the
EEPROM is paired to the motherboard so
if you swap the appear on with another
motherboard or another laptop where you
know the password you'll get an error
message like system has been tampered
with or something like that so it's it's
fairly secure at first first brush blush
so not too much guesswork we we have a
lot of material we can read lots of
stuff we can refer to
so obviously step number one is to
disassemble the laptop to things that
helped a lot we're taking pictures of
each layer so you can kind of reroute
the wires when you put it back together
and also pushing the screws through a
little piece of paper where they're kind
of a proximate location is that was
Ben's idea and that was like a huge help
so you end up with something like this
which looks pretty sad because it's like
yeah it's just like the internal metal
frame and the keyboard is just hanging
off the cable and stuff like that so
what you're gonna want to do is you're
gonna wanna look for the EP ROM which
will look something like that once you
find it you're gonna want to look for
the manufacturer which in this case is
an XP and there's a model number along
the top if you google that you'll find a
datasheet which you absolutely need for
the next steps where this EEPROM is
located it's different for every think
pad but there's like tons of websites
that say where it is so so the datasheet
is gonna tell you what the chip does so
it's gonna confirm whether it's an
EEPROM or not it's gonna tell you what
each of the pins are for what the
voltages are that it tolerates stuff
like that so we did find the datasheet
for this it is definitely any prom it
has some interesting security features
in addition to just being an EEPROM
there's like a pin where if you hold it
high then you can't write to the chip
anymore there's a separate bit of memory
within the chip that controls which
pages are writable and stuff like that
so it has like some access control stuff
like that but the most important thing
that they data she told us is that it's
addressed and talked to using ITC so ITC
is a bus it's it's a way for a bunch of
devices and assistants to talk to each
other it's fairly low speed
to USB or Ethernet or whatever so a
quick rundown of how I PC works there
are masters in their slaves masters
generate a clock signal and slaves
receive it so masters dictate how fast
the communication is masters initiate
transfers slaves don't get to do that
they just have to respond when a master
does initiate a transfer and ITC gives
you two primitives you can write to a
slave or you can read from a slave and
that's it
slaves have addresses just like Ethernet
or whatever and masters use those
addresses to say which slave they're
talking to so we know the rest of the
computer talks to this chip over i2c so
ideally so we don't have to change
anything or whatever we want to try and
sniff the computer talking to that chip
so maybe we'll see the password that way
so the tool used for that at first is a
logic analyzer it has some probes that
you connect to the pins of the chip and
it will sample those pins many millions
of times per second you know 2 or 4 20
megahertz or up to like 100 megahertz or
or faster depending on how expensive it
is and it'll record whether each of
those samples each of the sample pins
was a high or low a digital one or a
digital 0 and it'll you know keep track
of all of them and then so you can
analyze that later you basically get
like this kind of square waveform and
then the software for these they can
decode a whole lot of protocols
including IPC which is really good for
us so this is the pin out for the
particular EP ROM there's 8 pins but we
only care about three of them we only
have two tap three of them in order to
get the ITC signal so bottom right
there's Sdn SEL that's data and clock
respectively so the clock keeps the
master and slave in sync and then the
data is that SDA is what the actual data
goes over VSS and the bottom left is
ground so you want to have that hooked
up as well so we hook up the logic
analyzer to the chip ground first
I guess that's important for electrical
safety reasons I don't really know how
electricity works though so
and then you help the other two probes
you just pick any two probes and hook
them up to the other two pins and yeah
and then so when you go to initiate
capture you're gonna want you're gonna
have to pick a sample rate you know that
the logic analyzer can do anything up to
its maximum rate which might be a
hundred megahertz down to like ten
kilohertz
ten thousand times per second so the
general rule of thumb is you want to
capture as fast as possible there's a
whole lot of math about like sample
rates like the Nyquist Shannon sample
theorem which I don't understand at all
so general rule of thumb is sample as
fast as possible so ITC runs at many
speeds and you're from 10 kilohertz to a
few megahertz so it's the best students
do the fastest as possible so so what
you're gonna wanna do is you're gonna
want to start the capture before the
laptop is turned on and then you power
it on wait for the you know 10 second
boot or whatever to happen and then
we're not moved about you know post and
stuff like that and then eventually
you'll come to that terrible password
screen again guess a couple passwords
it's gonna tell you that they're wrong
because you don't know the password if
you do why are you doing this and then
once you're done then you start to stop
the capture and so at that point you've
captured everything you could possibly
care about because the computer has
confirmed that you have the wrong
password so if it was going to read it
from the EEPROM it has probably done it
somewhere in that capture so that was
really handy a bit different from what
we did was that we use this really nice
Sally a logic analyzer these are about
250 bucks we have one of these at Skull
space when you look crowdfunded it or
whatever it can do all one big capture
like that it can it can stream samples
continually to the computer and and
store them for later use or yeah so an
alternative to that is a logic shrimp so
this is only 30 bucks it's all open
source hardware that software they use
like the front end for it is open source
it's fast enough to capture i2c because
it's 20 megahertz ITC is like 400
kilohertz or 1 megahertz something like
that so it's fast enough so I can't
scream continually to the computer but
it does have a trigger functionality so
what you can do is when the computer
turns on the data and clock lines are
gonna go high and they're gonna stay
like that as long as the bus is idle so
in the software in the logic stream
software you just
eh as soon as the lines go low start
capturing and so as soon as an ITC
transaction starts it will capture the
whole thing so it's definitely possible
to do all this with much cheaper
hardware than we used and in fact the
all these screen shots that have
waveforms like this are actually from
the logic shrimp on a on a ThinkPad
EEPROM so it's definitely doable so once
you get a capture its gonna look
something like this this is zoomed way
in there's quite a bit more but it's
hard to see what's going on if you're
not zoomed in so you get the clock line
on the top or well the third one I guess
and the bottom one is the data and then
you just tell it to decode so you you
tell it that the clock line is the third
one and the bottom one is the data line
and you get something like that so I'll
just kind of switch back and forth so
you can kind of see the difference so it
tells us basically that bytes are being
read and written it will tell us what
the addresses are that the i2c slave
addresses that are being read and
written from so we saw a lot of
interesting strings in this capture
right away we saw the the word think pad
as like ASCII bytes we saw the word T
400 which is the model number of the
laptop we saw the serial number we're
like hey that looks like a serial number
and we looked at what was on the laptop
and sure enough it was a serial number
so nothing was obviously a password
though so we took the three of us three
amigos took the capture home to study it
and one week later Andrew sends me an
IRC message of some ungodly hour like 4
o'clock in the morning on a work night
and he's like he's like hey man I
figured out everything we need to know
so there's two possibilities for the
password it's either stored encrypted in
which case we're kind of screwed or it's
stored as keyboard scan code so it's not
stored as ASCII bytes like in any way
that you open in a text editor and
understand its course towards keyboards
keyboard scan codes which are kind of
like the little individual numbers that
each key on the keyboard gets it's like
a yeah so he also figured out exactly
how the chip is addressed like if you
want to read byte number 50 how you do
that and it turns out that's kind of
complicated which I'll get to in a
little bit and so he also figured out
where the address where the password is
stored in the chip like the exact
address that the password to store that
so using that he was able to confirm
that the password was being read but
trying to decode that with with the scan
code tables we found online couldn't
decode it so it's about 16 bytes said
address 0 X 3 3 8 X 3 3 8 and it was
being read all 16 bytes but couldn't be
decoded so it's a very good chance that
it was encrypted so we tried the logic
analyzer tried being passive didn't work
so that means that we have to end up
being a little bit more invasive which
means where you're going to try the bus
pirate so this is another pretty cheap
piece of equipment about 30 bucks made
by the same guys as the logic shrimp
dangerous prototypes again open-source
hardware they called the universal
serial interface so if you have a serial
protocol like i2c or SPI or you aren't
or anything like that it's good chance
they can speak it it has a nice little
like shell not a shell it's like a it's
kind of like a little command line that
you can use you open putty or your
favorite terminal emulator and connect
to it over a serial line and you can
like type commands and stuff like that
and it will run it will do like things
in the i2c or SPI protocol for you so
super super handy so they hook it up the
same way that we had the logic analyzer
hooked up just the three pins to be care
about that's the clock data and ground
and then we owe an apology wise in terms
of what the bus looks like now there's
slaves and masters right and i2c is a
multi master bus as well as a multi
slave bus so it's okay to have the bus
prior to hook up like this it's gonna
act as a master talking to the slave
appear on the computer also has some
master in there that's talking to the EP
Ron but they're able to not step on each
other I don't know exactly how that
works but apparently it's okay to do
that
so when you open up a shell you guys
might not be able to read this in the
back now that I realize but hopefully
that will be recorded okay so when you
first get a console to it it's in high Z
high impedance mode which means that
it's not providing power to anything
it's not gonna block your chips or
anything so you switch it into IPC mode
by switching to you hit em and pick the
mode you want and pick a speed and then
yeah so now there were an ITC mode
there's a couple of really cool features
that the bus pirate has for i2c the
first one is the address scan mode so
IPC addresses are only seven bits
there's an extended mode where they're
ten bits but in this case it's only
seven bits so what it'll do is it's just
gonna guess all of them it's kind of
like a port scan you know you just
try all open the ports and see which
ones respond so we can do that in i2c
supports that I guess so yeah so that
you just use the macro one and put it in
parentheses which means to run that
macro and then you're gonna want to
compare these addresses to the datasheet
because if they're wrong that means
there might be other devices on the bus
and you don't want to mess with those
because you don't know if they are so
this particular IPC or I'm sorry this
particular EP ROM has four ITC addresses
so this looks like eight but really it's
just four because each one supports read
and write so that might be confusing but
yeah so when you want to initiate a
communication with an ITC slave you send
a full byte even though each slave
address is only seven bits you send a
byte the first seven bits of that byte
are the slave address the last bit is
the that says whether you want to write
to the slave or read from the slave so
some data sheets will show you the full
byte that you need to send in order to
write or read from a slave sometimes
it'll just show the seven bits so you'll
see you might see that in either so it's
really handy that the bus pirate shows
you both it shows you both 0 x8 and also
the 54 that's like it shifted with one
bit or whatever so so I'm not explaining
that super well but if you end up
digging at i2c you will definitely come
across this so before we erase the
before we erase the EP rom we want to
try make a backup in case we make a
mistake so we had to figure out how the
you know the full details of how to
address the prom shake with time here ok
so like I said there's 4 i2c addresses
that this one EEPROM exposes and each of
them has 256 bytes you know and so it's
a it's a 1 kilobyte EEPROM each gets 256
bytes and each of those turn 56 bytes is
further subdivided into two pages so
that is kind of confusing and bit us in
the but a couple of times when you want
to read so this is where the terminology
gets a little confusing so ITC gives you
the ability to read and write but you're
also reading and writing to a physical
storage device at EEPROM so I'm gonna
use the term send and receive to mean I
to see read and write and I'm gonna say
read and write to me right
and reading to the EPROM so when you
want to read from the EEPROM you send a
single byte to which ever address you
want to get the page for and that byte
is where to start within the page and
then you receive from the EEPROM that's
same at the same address but the read
address versus the right address and it
will just keep standing you bytes within
that page it'll give you all the
sequential bytes if you read more than
hundred 28 bytes so it's gonna wrap back
to the beginning of or if you read to
the end of the page it's going to read
that wrap back to the beginning and just
give you from the beginning so we didn't
initially realize that each page was was
like that we didn't realize there were
128 byte pages so he tried reading 256
bytes from each of the addresses that's
we had a doubled up copy of page 1 page
3 page 5 and page 7 and we had no copy
of page 2 page 4 page 6 and page 8 so be
skeptical of everything you're doing and
double-check everything because you know
as they say measure measure twice cut
once double check the datasheet and that
sort of thing anyway this is the bus
pirate command that you'd use to read
the first page so as I mentioned you
send in a single byte which is zero in
this case to the first epoch you see
address and then you receive from that
address but in read mode you receive 128
bytes it gives you all of them and then
you do the same for the remaining so
that each pair of lines is for the first
and second page of each address and then
you get the whole basically get a whole
backup of the yeah pull back up so we
end up with that basically that's a hex
dump of the entire 1k EEPROM you can see
some of the strings we saw earlier the
ThinkPad and p400 and the serial number
I actually blanked out the serial number
so don't try to hack me with that or
something so at this point we're ready
to try and wipe we have we're ready to
try and wipe the password we have the
full backup it can restore it if we need
it theoretically so back to the front
page layout writing is basically the
same as reading you say where you want
to start you send it the a byte of where
you want to start and then you just keep
sending more bytes and it will put them
in there but so there's 128 byte pages
but when you're writing that's further
subdivided into 16 byte blocks they just
keep making up different terms for
organizing
so the password is 16 bytes so
convenient we can write the whole
password in in one write command so
funny story while we were figuring all
this stuff out Andrew said to me hey man
just make sure you hang on to your
backup because I think I just
accidentally overdosed something so we
of course pulled a copy of all the hold
of pages off and sure enough you had
overwritten the first byte of the user
string with a zero so we were able to
fix that which is good because
apparently if you are not careful with
erasing the password you'll get a like a
CRC error or a system has been tampered
with there things like that so there is
some integrity checking going on so it
was backup was super useful so we have a
backup
we know that the password is at hex
address 0 X 3 3 8 so that is 784 or
something like that I didn't write Oh 8
24 in decimal so there's a 1,024 bytes
it's address 824 in decimal so that ends
up being page 7 and it's 56 bytes into
that first page right into that page 7
and that's the fourth EP ROM address so
you're just dividing the address into
120 byte chunks and that tells you where
it is like modular arithmetic I guess so
we cross our fingers do the right
command we're writing 16 zeros to the
56:56 byte within that first page of
that IP address I cut a little bit out
because it's the same thing over and
over again so we did the right cross her
fingers made a copy of the page to make
sure that we had written it correctly
and only the first eight bytes have been
written so we were like what happened
what did we do wrong so double check the
datasheet double check our math it turns
out that the 16 byte password actually
straddles to 16 byte block pages so the
first eight bytes is in one block and
the second 8 bytes is in another block
so set up a second right - instead of 56
we instead write to 64 which is 8 bytes
over so it's in the next block and we
only write 8 bytes and then we make a
copy and double check so we those are
the original bytes the red ones and then
down in the bottom that's the new bytes
this is V bin diff by the way just like
a linux and curses program so yeah we
were able to erase the bytes at at this
point
you know moment of truth time to reboot
so I have a little video this is the
original oh I don't know if I can
actually play that yeah it's not playing
for me so anyway basically we we reboot
the computer and it you get the little
post screen the little ThinkPad logo and
then it tells you the date time or unset
and then the bios is open and you can
change things in it reset the password
and everything and we did a bunch of
high-fiving and swearing and stuff like
that so it all ended up working out so
the password that were actually or I'm
sorry the computer we're using for
registration is that same computer so I
totally worked thanks for listening
I don't think I have any time for
questions maybe one quick question sure
I didn't we thought about doing that but
I figured there's a built-in TPM like
there's a trusted platform module in the
laptop which can do like proper
encryption so I assume and this is I'm
assuming I shouldn't assume but I assume
that the crypto is good and that we
would not be able to break it so but I
said maybe that's a good future project
if someone's looking to you hey thank
you