hello folks so today I'm going to talk
reasonably high level about modern
implementation of TLS in enterprise no
one person controls everything in fact
the infrastructure controls you most of
the time so Who am I well really I'm
nobody as Ron noted but if I must um it
turns out I did you know loaded up calc
last night it turns out I've been doing
internet crap for 19 years I feel like
ancient person but I'm young in my
department good yes um so did CSU of em
I went on to system administration to
pay for my degree and did a bunch of
stuff after that some some of you know
it some you don't doesn't really matter
and i was doing shadow infosec for a
long time basically the annoying guy in
departments at like you're doing it
wrong so now I get to tell people yeah
you're doing it wrong but how can I help
you fix it so that's the picture was
made by a friend of mine because I got a
reputation for being the guy that says
no a lot and so I embrace it I say no
Lutz but now I say no but how can we
turn that into a yes later so what is
TLS well everybody in this room knows
what it is it's essentially we all call
it ssl we all use the term ssl the term
ssl should just die in a fire preferably
now preferably even 10 years ago
essentially we're going to you can't
have a conversation without context and
the context for SSL is broken people
understand it but they all understand it
wrong including me most of the time I
screw it up essentially what TLS is it's
a channel for communication that does
two things in tooth
only you get encryption which is
ninety-nine percent of what of what
people understand TLS to be and trust
either federated or consolidated but
trust is just as important if not more
important than the encryption we just
don't talk about it or we don't leverage
it properly so let's not talk about ssl
anymore you know if you want to use the
gnu/linux crap that's fine use TLS / SSL
or just say TLS when people say SSL try
to steer the conversation away because
like I said you can't really have a
conversation when people understand
things differently so start with
something fresh well I've seen a lot of
implementations I've implemented a lot
of bad ones and the the only inside I
had was for TLS it's the screw we hammer
into literally everything well screws
definitely not the right tool for this
job the hammer well because we love
smashing things but the end result is
you get a broken piece of wood or you
get a broken whatever you're trying to
hammer this into so yes you get the
little check mark that says encrypted
but you're not getting much else in fact
you're losing more in terms of
functionality support costs you name it
you're not providing anything other than
pain for the people behind the scenes so
we have lots of problems mostly they're
just configuration configuration and
understanding of how to apply TLS two
things most of the time is just a check
box vendors like to provide you one
click install also one click fail so
lots of things especially middleware
will enable client authentication but
not tell you how to use it so you've got
sessions or two servers talking to each
other using TLS as the you know session
transport and the first step is okay try
to authenticate the client servers like
auto what do I do with this I don't talk
that way do server authentication only
so you've just wasted a bunch of the
handshake time and you've provided no
value you've produced great error error
messages but nobody looks at those
anyway we also see people using San
certs our wildcard cert sore basically
using certificates to get around their
understanding as opposed to applying
them appropriately a common thing I've
seen is creating a sensor which is the
host name fully qualified domain name
and then the short version IE the domain
name chopped off that's just to get the
little green checkmark but you've just
given away all of your infrastructure at
that point because anything dot nothing
can be matched by anything so what
exactly are you getting out of that
certificate nothing really wildcard
certificates star not anything not
anything well you get encryption but
you've just thrown trust out the window
there are there are really good use
cases for it like farming and load
balancers that have farms of services
underneath but most of the time you can
get away without using it such as using
a sand certificate with the name of the
specific host as well as the virtual IP
or virtual host name another really
expensive thing that was popular is to
use third-party cas for internal stuff
why bother why are you spending hundreds
of dollars a year on certificates that
the outside world will never see is
because you don't trust yourself well in
many cases that's true but in my
experience auditors love to see external
trust like it gives you something you
don't already have so you need to
leverage your internal cas if you don't
have one well you probably do you just
don't know what it's called if you have
80 you have an internal CA you just
don't know you're using it another thing
that's a little bit more common now
because browsers love to complain is
serving your endpoint certificates with
out the full chain the certificate is
good but your browser will crap all over
it saying I don't know this guy well
it really does it just can't get the
full chain from the connection to
compare to its local trust or so it says
an you did it wrong I see this time and
time again it's it's the easiest thing
to mess up and self-signed certificates
you find any tutorial about how to
enable TLS on anything and it will tell
you how to create a self-signed
certificate but I don't tell you how to
use it or when it's appropriate so it's
pretty much never appropriate because
developers use it to save time because
asking for anything as well wasting your
time or it takes ten years to get a
certificate so we'll just use
self-signed and call it a day well then
you don't get any of the trust
functionality that TLS offers you so if
you have a CA make sure you can
provision them really fast to have the
developers actually use your
infrastructure as opposed to work around
it which is what i did for most of my
career so the other big challenge in
gigantic corporations especially ones
that take your money or know lots of
very sensitive things about you is
regulations for me their pain in the ass
but i also like that they're there they
keep the organization in check but not
necessarily in a useful way regulations
tend to be super vague you must have an
ex or you must do X and then p and then
Q and yes we know those don't all fit
together but you have to do them anyways
so traditionally like at least what I'm
seeing now and what I'm living through
now is that regulations are telling us
we must use technology X so expensive
spear sharpeners for the dull edge of
the spear we're not poking anybody with
it we're not getting any attack surface
reduced we're just implementing
technology and hoping that it does
something good for us in many cases they
can the regulations are good the problem
is is that we have to find a way to
integrate it into our infrastructure so
that we're not just wasting time and
money so for instance SSL inspection
I've seen a number of products that will
say yeah we do TLS expect
inspection but the only cipher we
support is null with null and no well
that's great you don't get encryption
you don't get trust you get nothing so
what's the value of your product uh so
how do you integrate this stuff well you
have to cuz regulations say you must so
let's think about it a little
differently let's first talk about wha
laughs is a generally a new thing and by
new i just mean that people are now
using them exactly so think of it as a
load balancer with a with grep
essentially there are some learning
facilities and it can be very useful
especially in giant infrastructures that
don't change or that move at a glacial
pace because you can bolt the stuff on
and then gain a little bit of time to
remediate the back end it's not really
how that how the sales people like to
sell it to you because they're just like
oh well this Indian you're good and you
never have to touch anything no it's a
great starting point and for
applications especially support folks
that are just learning to use that 20
year old mainframe application that
someone wrote that retired five years
ago before you started it allows you the
ability to understand what your
application does the profiling
self-learning can be extremely valuable
figuring out how exactly your
application is doing something as
opposed to we just run it and we deal
with complaints as we get it so it gives
you a little bit of insight if you apply
it appropriately so well laughs are
mostly terrible if you just think about
them a different way they can be
extremely useful the other really big
challenge that browsers right now our
ramming down everyone's throat is
perfect forward secrecy well
diffie-hellman a gong show at the moment
but at the same time it is very useful
if you use you know non-standard curves
and you decide to use non common primes
like the one not the one in the Box
generated 2k or higher one and apply
play it to your web server application
server they do very good things the
problem is you get the nice political
scare tactic that all over inspection is
now dark we can't see anything we have
no intelligence well you didn't in the
first place but now you have even less
so the best part about going blind is
that you don't even know you're blind
all of your inspections stuff will go
and it's just traffic I can't see it's
got to be good right pass it on I
haven't seen a tool yet or an inspection
service that will go I can't decrypt
this or I can't see this let's send an
alert that's right for giant amounts of
false positives but if you're wanting to
be able to inspect anything knowing what
you can't and can't inspect is probably
where you should be spending your time
finding tools that you know lets you
filter that out that's very very
difficult so in enterprises in large
infrastructure we tend to want to paint
things with very large brushes we have
one color and one really large brush and
everything gets painted with it why
efficiency or money or we're too lazy to
learn so how do you deal with this do
you just consider all of your encrypted
traffic collateral damage and just not
inspect it or do you think through the
problem a little more so this is a
typical infrastructure that you would
see for applications in NT r enterprise
insert your buzz word here I would call
this highly Fela bilar katek chur try to
go from the tubes right down to your
application server with a single path
twice yeah it's not going to happen not
only is every vertical line a different
group in your organization but you can't
tell what path any packet is going
either because it's netted seven ways
from hell or someone forgot to turn on
x-forwarded-for in in a proxy so you
can't tell where things are coming and
going so you can have all the inspection
in the world but all you're looking for
is application bugs you're not really
seeing
how things are running so how can we
change things and move some of that
inspection get some value out of it but
also have nice and clean security for
your customers things that you want to
face if I want to talk to a company I
would prefer that they put a little bit
more effort into securing the front end
and then the back end I really don't
care about it's going to be squishy as
long as it's not accessible well I hope
they solve it but in reality as a
consumer I don't really care so how can
we leverage that well we can do the
stupid thing and just encrypt everything
if you ask anybody in an ISO
organization can I do this can I use
this protocol the answer will be yes
okay well that doesn't solve any
problems for me in fact it creates more
now my inspection stuff nothing so
either have to move it around which
again it will still see nothing or I can
just say it's collateral damage but I'm
secure according to qualis I got my
little A+ that's got to mean something
right well let's try it again let's use
SSL termination previously it was a
technique used because TLS is slow
encryption is slow well it's not but we
do need to put a nice clean secured
interface to our customers so lets do
TLS here the bot that the buck stops
here everything else is widely open well
that solves one problem but introduces
three more problems that introduces is
yes you get inspection but you've lost
trust in your infrastructure you have no
means of determining exfiltration of
data because you've only got one thing
in and you're not really talking you're
just letting things out without even
looking at it properly so that's not a
solution either now notice that I'm just
drawing boxes I'm not really changing
the infrastructure except in this case
I'm putting the IPS behind
the control point where the control
point is like a laugh or a load bouncer
or some other form of Earth reverse
proxy so that's a subtle change it
allows me inspection after that point
but I've only got solved one of my
problems so that's not good either so
let's try again so here's here's the
interesting thing if you disable teal
our PFS or perfect forward secrecy
diffie-hellman you name it choose your
acronym of the day essentially if you
hide it or if you disable it you get
your inspection back you install your
private keys on your inspection devices
even sell your certificates and a
private keys on inspection device sorry
that that is a really important point
and you get all your inspection back but
let's use the TLS trust layer a little
bit better so what is what is the trust
layer mean well a certificate authority
is a person or a thing or an
organization that provides you with
certificates that says this one is good
this one is not good you have an
external one for people that don't trust
you which is the world and that's the
way it should be and but you also have
an internal CA and use that internal CA
to provision all your internal
infrastructure in your demarcation point
is the load balancer wife layer we're
just assuming HTTP but this will work
for all TLS style implementations so
what you get now is you can implement
mutual authentication on your back end
so that wasted client certificate
configuration well now let's use it
let's say I will only talk two things I
only that I trust for the CA that I
provision all of the default ones will
just remove them so when something
you're not expecting talks to this layer
of of your application it fails and this
it does exactly what it's supposed to do
it fails we look at the logs we were
mediate call assert do whatever you need
to do but at least now you have that
intelligence before you just assumed
everything was great because no one was
screaming at you
so just by that subtle change we've
solved not only the problem of my
inspection stuff goes dark but we've
also increased the availability and
reliability of our back-end
infrastructure the only thing is you got
to train people and that's really really
hard well the other thing since we're
talking about web based stuff what about
those fancy new headers like STS HST are
essentially HST s public key pinning all
that other good stuff well that's great
if you're talking with browsers and you
should use them but they also introduce
problems specifically the public key
pinning is great but if in the in the
previous infrastructure each one of you
flying administered by somebody else how
do you know when you replace the
certificate that the pin changed well
that's a great way to create an outage
so you need a lot more coordination
there you need a lot more process are
you getting the benefit out of pinning
that you would by not using it at all
and you don't need pinning for sts to
work it's preferred it helps but it's
not necessarily required so use it
appropriately and then put it in later
after you worked out the process CSP
it's great if your browser's adhere to
it but java applications don't so it
also breaks things if you let's just say
you have hundreds of applications in
your enterprise odds are a huge portion
of them or third party do you know how
they work do you know how they're
implemented do you know if they're using
frames or third-party cookies or content
type negotiation you don't know so in
implementing this stuff on your lap or
on your head end it's great but expect
things to break that's okay failure is
good you just have to know what to do
with it and be able to work through it
so what are some solutions well the
first thing trust between application
layers is by far the most common thing I
see is problems if your Java logs have
anything that say pkix odds are you
didn't include your cas in the trust or
I see this so often I wrote a script
called defang JVM which just looks for
every CA certs file on a system and
injects our common trust cas i also use
it to disable export export crypto
because a lot of three-letter companies
will ship things to Canada with export
crypto enabled and not tell you which is
fun but you have to really really be
looking at things to to catch it and
then remediate it no cipher suites
available so if you get really down in
the weeds and you're like I'm going to
lock this thing down a hundred percent
you're going to break it and the error
message you're going to get is either no
protocols available or no snow common
cipher Suites so in this one it's more
or less trial and error because most of
the logs won't tell you what ciphers it
tried and you can use openssl s client
or Wireshark to see what the endpoints
are negotiating and then do your own
overlap but most of the time it's
because you've disabled sslv3 for some
really old app or some really old
appliance and it won't get updated so
first check that then go deep down with
those two other options when the thing
the whole public chain issue when you
serve the chain along with your
certificate that's pretty recent that
things fail because usually it would
look and try to do validate up the chain
on its own by it i mean the client now
the client saying well i'm only going to
validate against myself once you tell me
what I'm going to validate so it looks
at the chain make sure that you've
served the entire chain and then
compares it to its own trust or the
communication for that was really really
bad so a lot of sites broke really
really quickly I am still seeing two
this day I'm still trying to get a piece
of infrastructure get to get updated to
send the full chain like everything is
right all the configuration is correct
it's just missing the chain bundle and
it's a very very hard thing to
communicate because uh it validates for
me well try going outside for a bit the
world is actually different than what
you see in the window so and finally the
usual browsers complaining about invalid
names well this is a good thing because
well like the previous talk from
yesterday dns buzzing uh men in the
middle attacks these errors are there
for a reason now if you've gone through
that the due diligence of set everything
up appropriately these errors are
something for you to action not mitigate
by throwing in a sense or wild card or
something just to get that little check
box and the business happy look at it
take the time don't just do quick fixes
well so how do we fix these problems in
enterprises well essentially it's
consultancy you have to find someone in
your organization that tries to
understand this stuff and then educate
rather everyone from developers to
operations staff take the time to walk
people through listen to their problems
and try to help them not only be
compliant but show them the benefits of
being compliant without any effort like
the previous example of throwing a laugh
in front of something to get qualis to
give you an a instead of a see that has
value you can give that for almost no
effort so do it the more the more value
you provide someone the higher the
probability that when you say they're
doing something wrong they'll listen to
you because if all you say is no well
eventually people are going to start
ignoring you so turn that no into it yet
and make sure that you provision things
for developers faster than they can
break it themselves
finally don't be afraid of meat you a
lot it's super super powerful the
problem is it's nobody really uses it
some good resources Ivan Ristic spoke
bulletproof TLS it's expensive but it's
really well written it's focused on
browsing and not the ca infrastructure
that's a big hole in the market right
now but it's better than nothing in fact
I recommend it highly openssl s client
and s server there are the most
important tools in my toolbox I use them
more than I use wireshark or anything
else they're also if you want to see how
things are changing on the real internet
the trust where the internet movement
basically scans for stuff and provides
reports it's a nice high level saying
are you going in the right direction as
everyone else and then the see a browser
form cas are in notoriously difficult to
manage and they're even worse to
implement so use the standards other
people develop for you well I got the
deck online I didn't say most of what
was on the slides so feel free to take a
look at the slide more in-depth you can
email me use the Twitter or whatever or
if you don't want to listen to me get
some better headphones are there any
questions
okay typically when you're browsing you
authenticate the server the server
doesn't authenticate you it's not just a
bad Russian joke it's the way we browse
the Internet today mutual authentication
bridges that gap by saying I'm going to
apply a certificate to my clients as
well as servers so not only do i
authenticate the server the server
authenticates me right yeah you would
you wouldn't hand them to them you would
install them in workstations you would
deploy them via ad or whatever it also
it also makes SSO trivial to implement
where SSO is single sign-on well export
grade crypto is essentially those tsa
locks that that Adrian talked about last
night do you have do you have encryption
yes oh that's great I have keys I have
locks but they're really crappily
implemented so they can be broken in
real time or they're easy to inspect so
for regulations that's great because I
can break everything and I don't have
and I give this false sense of security
to users the US had this thing called an
export policy that said strong crypto is
not allowed to be sold from the u.s. to
anywhere else in the world well
everywhere else in the world said screw
you we'll just sell it instead so it
solves nothing but gives us regulatory
bodies at least some form of useless
comfort the problem is is that a lot of
third-party software and a lot of
infrastructure is sold from US companies
and they enable this export encryption
by default and make it really difficult
for you to turn it off it's a huge
problem and it's getting worse the only
way to solve it is to start keeping
vendors to task so going I need to
disable this kind of cipher suite why
doesn't your application let me do it
and
not by their crap when they won't give
you a satisfactory answer unfortunately
it's the only way to do it it's not very
good on the business side because now
you're slowing projects down but it's
the only way to get rid of this export
problem is is that a good answer okay