and maybe using the most but we're going
existing out
yeah it's off closer you are to see
everyone to allow all right good morning
my name is matt bianco on the senior
systems engineers and let's go and going
to talk about addressing your cloud
security risks just some things that
need to be aware of you know as you're
going down the road of thinking about
cloud and what that means your
organization is going to be things in
here that that may seem familiar but
there's certain things in here that you
probably never thought so just a quick
poll here how many people have actually
started down the path of cloud security
oh cool all right so is that question a
year-and-a-half ago there was no hands
right so we're definitely making
progress in them up now one thing I'll
tell you if you can ask a question asked
questions make this interactive happy to
do that like it that way
one question I will not answer is
anything about architecture because
that'll it's a texas-sized rat hole and
we will get derailed for 15 minutes on
that ok but i do is slide at the end if
we have time if not can come and talk to
me and I don't can get from cadres clock
is going to cover architecture himself
so as I mentioned come and talk to me
after I want to know more about how do
you implement this how does it fit the
environment etc and I ok when we talk
about five security but what's
interesting is as you may think
immediately
well that means that you wanna you just
want to block things that you want to
stop it from happening right and that's
not the case at all
cloud security is their cloud is a good
fit right
I use cloud everyday I doesn't use cloud
in here if anybody raise their hands
right but we all use it even cherry
grocery list with my life on an iCloud
you know that's that's cloud gmail
dropbox I mean the things that we do you
know a personal level that's all
lots of clouds fantastic and there's a
lot of business needs for cloud if you
think about it right i mean we can spit
up an appt we don't have to pull in
servers we don't have to pay for power
quick to marketing is all kinds of
reasons why cloud is where is white
larger organizations are adopting clap
it makes perfect sense but we do
obviously have to wrap some security
around it in order for it to me you know
where we wanted to be like our internal
networks like it tackles so if we talk
about the way things used to be this is
very basics like that there's a purpose
to this right we had our point to it you
know our our internal network here right
with our servers and everything used to
be consolidated in one place it seems
easy
obviously those things were still
getting packed all the time right
because users are obvious ability
and if we wanted to our in our day was
all internal he wanted to connect to
that data we just connected because we
already on the network
we are outside the network it was very
simple right we had back in and and all
those good old days
however if you look at what's in here
Gateway's firewalls IPS . that sort of
thing all the tools that were using
today were built for that scenario right
now what we're trying to do is take
those tools somehow extends out into the
lab and that doesn't work as they
weren't built for that what they were
built for is this right so we we just
can't use those tools to that extent
what we see some tools out there that
are trying to adapt proxies and things
that are trying to mold on it has be
offerings to what they already have it
is the architectures are all wrong
let me push you are so the problem with
the problem with cloud is also the
solution or the solution is the problem
either way there's . 2000 identified
cloud so first thing we need to do is
again five legs clout and that is not a
URL based website that you just go to
consume you know like cnn.com or
espn.com those aren't typically security
risk other than maybe drive back malware
you know I'm not worried about people
getting into ESPN are accomplished with
my fantasy team which is over to by the
way so you don't want to see that but
that's that's also the solution right
there's all these great apps out there
twenty-two thousand plus of them that
are available for every line of business
you think about it finance HR everything
that we can figure even coating happens
in the flour in fact I've been in a
couple startups now let's go is my third
one and every company that's coming out
of California that is a startup
doesn't ever by a single server so there
is no servers in our company whatsoever
not even one because everything that we
do is involved from our mail for our
development right everything because we
can collaborate on a very easily and
hopefully we're in a good position
because we offer cloud security so we
are right but that is a staggering
number we'll talk a little bit more
about why that matters now we have this
this evenin this hybrid approach but
definitely everything they are dated
that once wasn't in the cloud or
on-premise is not moving to the cloud
and end to something said I could make
the argument we wanted there is there's
probably a significant security controls
around some of the absent that are out
there you're not Microsoft is one of
them a lot of work there's carriers
sounds like it's not true but it
actually is it is Microsoft right so
when people want to access data now
we're accessing it from every we can get
to it from no matter where we are but
that introduces additional problems into
this because now if you look where our
perimeter was our perimeter is the
end-user right so you have to think in
terms of cloud security is your
perimeter is end-user it is not in the
four walls it's not your data center
anymore even if you haven't adopted a
cloud that it's still the end user
because they still have the ability to
take data and move it to your own
personal versions of things so this is
based on our own data points and this is
absolutely true in fact the numbers
below are a little bit generous i'll
talk about that when we do risk
assessment is very easy thing to do you
can grab proxy watchin and firewall logs
things and and and tell people at a
glance what the overall issues are what
we find on averages there's a thousand
asses numbers actually changed a little
bit
there's a thousand apps that are being
used in every organization and that I've
never seen the number below 700 and I
see that number between five and six
thousand or larger organizations so
imagine that five thousand applications
that are being utilized the question
becomes how many of those are section by
the company so quick definition of
sanction vs suns unsanctioned pretty
civilization is means it's been an IT
vetted they have some administrative
control over the application right
control users that get into now remember
at no time did they control the app they
can't go and say hey microsoft for
onedrive use different Christian they
can't do that right or add this feature
they can ask but you know that that
doesn't necessarily happen so that means
that invite way that ten percent for
section applications is very generous as
if the number is a thousand that means a
hundred absolutely essential variety i
haven't come across a single company yet
400 applications were actually section
when people think about this they're
thinking in terms of 3x five apps right
that means that number is probably
closer to one percent meeting once below
is everything that's on station and
that's somewhere between nineteen ninety
nine percent so when you're talking
about security strategy it has to
encompass this entire thing it can't be
that top line and we'll talk about
generation one Cassidy's vs generation
to cassidys and what differences are one
of them is that top line that was
generation one cast which is let's just
control the same connects right but as
you can see if the majority of the app
usage and the majority of the data
that's going out is going into
unsanctioned apps then we control thing
the other part of this is is a cell
inspection right
Cassie should be doing SSO inspection
automatically because a hundred percent
of the traffic that is going to these
cloud houses is SSL or TLS encryption so
without it you don't have any visibility
you're basically back to the days of a
proxy which is locker allow strength
alright so quick poll here how how much
data or business David you think exist
in the cloud today
anybody have an answer that's actually
write less than you realize
because we're really in the footnotes is
a percentage and we have presented to
throw so when yeah yeah it's thirty
percent right now so close and rapidly
growing because what I see even over the
last year is very large organizations
that are really starting to adopt that's
large organizations tail a lot of data
right small organizations have adopted
for for a few years because it's easy
for them to implement but now we're
seeing the adoption of these large
organizations because they don't want to
pay a center-right my servers anymore
fact microsoft doesn't want to sell you
server licenses anymore
safeway trying to do that recently tried
by server 2012 and microsoft says they
wanted to use office 365 they don't want
to sell it to you because they want
everybody moving into that platform
there's a lot of good reasons for that
so if we have thirty percent right that
means this ever-increasing amount of
data that's going to cloud but we're
still susceptible to the same things
that we always have it we still have to
worry about data breaches now go back to
that other statement where you don't
control the application so the best that
you can do in this scenario is to make
sure you have a resource where you can
set out applications for you ever use
find out which applications are actually
being used and made sure that the one
that you choose or the handle that you
choose fall in line with your appliance
so when you get into
audience you're not failing those
because you can't make them change the
appt right you want to fail those a
panel the rest of this i'm going to talk
about because you guys are all else here
this is why we're here because the last
two points right . getting out and
really i'm at the crux of this that is
the point we don't control the app right
what we do control the data so obviously
in any cloud security strategy data has
to be the most important thing and
that's where our location how do we
protect the data from the user to
wherever its go and that's what we're
going to be going to discuss any
questions thus far
awesome-o income before
alright here we go this was talking
about division fail bought into the
residence is so the question becomes how
are you dressing and risk today and I
can answer that question i talked to a
lot of companies right I get pretty good
picture of their infrastructure and
going back to that second slide that I
showed their addressing it the same way
they address the internal needs and
that's it right which is we have proxies
have firewalls we have a deal that sort
of thing again none of that extends to
the cloud easily and it certainly
doesn't see the cloud in the way that
the cloud needs to be seen or audit in
and take action up so when you go down
this path you should be asking you that
question how do our current controls
work for Cloud usage and the short
answer again is it does so you need a
new strategy for that and that's where
Cassidy's came into existence now if we
go back to that original picture
this was the strategy back in $MONTH
2005 which was able to walk right these
are proxies you just block everything so
yeah so that's not really sustainable
right and in any kind of cloud strategy
because we want the club to be used so
have been blocking via strategy you know
it just doesn't work and it's never
going to work because that's not the
world that anymore
it worked in 2005 because we didn't have
mobile app usage that we have now I mean
everybody's connected to your browsers
and they weren't a lot of times back
then by the way so that wasn't that hard
so you're just doing your else filter
2005 was easy for a few years ago
first-generation Cassidy's came out and
said all right here's your strategy
let's section one app and then we'll
lock everything else so similar strategy
but now you have one half that you're
allowed to use again it's not blocking
is never going to be a sustainable
strategy so if you come to be after this
and say hey Matt tell me how I can block
better i'm not going to answer that
because that's not a strategy right so
anyway and one of the reasons why that
is not a strategy is because we what we
find is that they end up opening up and
punching holes through those to begin
with
alright so they try to block everything
and then HR passes we don't need all
these apps and then finance houses i
need all these apps right now also you
have what we call exceptions for all
happening and what we actually found is
that ninety percent of the cloud app
usage is actually from blocked apps
because they've opened them up and those
are based on all the assessments that
that so right there is one reason why
blocking doesn't work the other reason
is blocking is a non-friend typically
solution so as soon as you leave or you
pick up your mobile phone and go on the
LTE network
you can go wherever you want right a lot
of holes in blocking strategies that
doesn't save you from anything
so the question becomes what we do and
we have by the way you know you can just
find another half is probably far less
secure to use and is not in your proxy
category list and just use that that's
what people do eventually if you're
blocking dropbox and places where they
want data to your just gonna find it
happen you're not blocking and that's
typically the security on those is his
terror but you don't go to their website
the one that I picked out all the time
zippyshare right we see that be used in
places and you're not going to go to
zippyshare on their website and they're
gonna tell you ate by the way this
happens the job right
nobody says that they're going to say
hey you get one get $MONEY free stories
how great is that
but when if you have the ability of that
out that app it has no security only
piece of security that it adds is SL
which is easy to do is you just buy a
couple certificates right but there's no
encryption at rest their clients . and
this is a place that people are
potentially data without that SL
inspection or candidate is right that so
the way you should think about cloud
security is it being enable technology
not a disabled technology right again
blocking doesn't work so you have to
enable what people are going to use
anyway you're going to figure it out
just let him use it but let them use it
safely and that should really be how
you're approaching cloud security
security we're trying too hard wired a
little bit to figure out ways to stop
people from doing things or stop people
from getting infected things or you know
it's all about stopping so when we talk
about security
it's a little weird to talk about
enabling but you'll find that this
strategy yields much more security than
you're blocking strategy because this
strategy will allow users to do they do
and you can protect them wherever they
are doesn't matter if they're not grab
off grab manage devices on manage device
we can protect and so the other part of
this got the six steps yet but it will
be up to 30 minutes talking the other
part that I find it's a little bit
difficult is since this is kind of a
newer space where as i mentioned before
really have the foothills of this
exploding right as people adopt more and
more the security becomes more and more
important
it's still a little difficult to talk to
leadership about about this whole
process and why it's important so we
actually need to provide them something
that they can reference that shows them
what the issue is and any Casby
typically there's a few that don't but
most of them did will come in the grab
some oxy logs from your firewall and
said they will do some magic on the back
and force those laws and they'll tell
you what the problem is they basically
create a story for you and you can take
that story and you can add it to your
leadership and say you know it by the
way I wonder where this but we're using
1500 apps you thought it was 20 and we
don't have any way of knowing what kind
of data that is going through your visit
vast majority of companies are doing SL
inspection right this is definitely
something I know I is a very very small
percentage of companies are doing SL
inspection on traffic and even when they
are they're not seeing in the context of
cloud because cloud speaks API right so
that's his cell inspection is great if
you're just looking at all the data if
you don't understand the context of
where users trying to do you're missing
the boat a lot of the most companies are
doing a solid session so now they're I
talk to a customer
not too long ago we were sitting across
the table and leave it out there trying
to convince their leadership will allow
them to SL suspect that track
and she said today statistically we are
blind to forty percent of our traffic
going through
yeah we can see the headers right we can
see where it's going but that's it
it doesn't tell us what the payload is
we can't inspect the document we don't
know that sensitive data going out to
the valley we have no way of knowing
we're flying to forty percent of that
next year is going to be sixty percent
few years or not to be eighty percent
because slz so in any strategy the
question you need to ask is how r us
self-respecting my traffic and in today
Cassidy's will have to have to do that
automatically so if you have an ssl
project that's been sitting on the shelf
waiting for you to figure out how that's
gonna hit performance
what kind of appliances you're going to
divide and all of that stuff which is a
huge cost look at this to replace that
project because it has to be done anyway
and by the way the Estall inspection is
happening in the cloud it's not
happening at your premises no
performance it right cloud much more
robust so that's something to think
about when you're approaching this is
this will take two projects that you
really have a solid eight so this is
something i just threw it I thought was
pretty interesting
it's going talking to leadership about
it this is the National Association of
corporate directors it's just a website
that is dedicated to you know leadership
and collaboration season and there's
some questions out here and i love this
it says questions directors and asked to
assess the board side literacy so i
would love to get this question your
back and you see exactly what back for
their but you know basically the
question that they're talking about is
how do we know that our ground rules are
protected our intellectual property you
know we work for car manufacturers are
drawings of our future cars or concept
cars and how to make sure that stuff is
is protected if we're blinded forty
percent of our traffic today i will be
sure that hasn't gotten out right right
and got into something
so this strategy with what I just talked
about right that that risk assessment
that you can get down by anybody and to
some extent you can probably do it
yourself if you you know what your real
because what we'll what a cloud security
broker will do is look at those 20,000
app specifically because those apps are
places where you can put data corporate
dated and that includes things like
Facebook where you can post you know
credit card numbers you can close that
twitter post on facebook so you have to
look at all of those places where data
click potentially go right so ask them
this question popped down every
successful in front of them and you know
I was like to say once you see it you
can't unsee it can bury your head back
in san diego didn't see that you know
there's 1500 apps or more that are being
used we have no visibility into the data
so we have no idea what our exposure
really is the only way that we're going
to know that is to get a cast be get in
line with that traffic fully SL
inspected automatically and then look at
it from a policy that's the only way
that we're going to know that are
sensitive data is getting out of this
organization or that somebody is going
home putting something on dropbox going
home working on it the whole day just
shared it out
unintentionally publicly to the world
what stops that have not none of the
total size of blue balls and other tools
that yes go to their friends house each
downloaded document editing back
yeah all of that those scenarios have to
be protected right so you can start
seeing where those tools that you have
internally start falling all right and
you need to be able to protect that
exact sorry
and the only way to do it is is with the
next generation of fans
ok so one of the
exactly to talk about them which is very
important is all the ways people can
access products so if I ask you today
and said hey what you know how do you
access cloud I know you're going to say
well no problem and comparatively the
browser is actually the easiest thing to
control these browsers we can redirect
right we can get in front of browsers
browsers are always easy but it's easier
than the other ways but that only
accounts believe in a 50-percent of the
the access to products so the other one
is six clients and and find ways my
laptop's morning's presentation it's
syncing files the box behind the seeds
that is not going to go through a
reverse proxy and that's what a lot of
casual cell is a syncline is hard code
hard-coded you go directly to the
application so you can't get it to
redirect anywhere
the only way to solve that use cases to
get in front of it forward proxy and
intercept the track because it's going
can't redirect it anywhere so mobile
apps right how many people in here pick
up their phone and say you know what I'm
going to go to office 365 and i'm just
going to use the browser you should want
nobody does that right i mean you
download the app you download if you're
going to box you download box app if you
salesforce you download the Salesforce
and moving to use the browser accepted
to quick google search everything else
we downloaded apple and so these are the
same as implies you cannot redirect an
appt only way to get to do this in front
of the app in a foreign proxy mode so
you can intercept the traffic rather
than try to steer itself and then
something people don't think about a lot
are in the app ecosystem so if i have
sales force is probably a hundred 100
apps that connect into Salesforce and
can manipulate data all day about how
you protect that so these when you think
about your policy security strategy it's
all of these things
you can't just protect the browser and
say you know we're good because that
gives you a fraction of the issue
coverage you have to cover all of these
everyone to get 360-degree coverage for
your letters and if we if we do that
right and we get in line with that
traffic can see it as hell inspecting it
allows us to ask some questions and if
you ask them today in our risky
activities taking place is sensitive
data the answers to that is you probably
have no idea
unfortunately but that's the truth
that's the world live but you can and
how about you know it's coming from a
managed or unmanaged device is
supporting a case that you talk about is
it on the network is it off the network
is it is managed to get the same access
the unmanaged devices that all we can do
that with that on our internal networks
right but we can't do it in the clouds I
mean you can if you're growing up so
that has the ability to see all of that
stuff and then adjust how what how and
what you can access based on that fact
and then threat protection will talk
about about that but you know it all
falls into the same so all right one
thing I'll fill this out one thing I
want to cover here is gonna be able to
see the date of the right way to so if
you look at proxy long and firewall logs
you're going to see HTTP transactions
back and forth like crazy and then
report on and say you know what somebody
went to Google Drive that's a hundred
sessions
HTTP raw sessions report if you go to
box being out is 24 the same activity
which was user logs in browsers an empty
folder upload file chairs pop there's a
hundred activity report right so Roxie
Hart they don't session eyes the data so
it looks very messy and it's very
inaccurate it may mislead us into
thinking that there's more google drive
usage there is Box because we're just
looking at session right so one thing
you can do is specialized that they you
can see
it's one session out of all of that that
user went in the uploaded file file
server that's one second
same thing with box right so now the
data actually starts making a lot more
sense then when you're just looking at
proxy to try to make decisions on
another view of that is if you just you
an empty folder will drive it's still a
hundred session you know is that's how
Google works that seven box
neither one are right it is how they
reported and how many transactions it
taste you know actually the things so
that doesn't really do us any good so
here's one of the things i want you to
walk away with to this is critical when
you're talking about your class
securities traded in order to do this
correctly in order to be an enablement
technology yet more secure
you have to see the activities that
happen inside of every app not just your
section F every single app need to be
able to see what is that user Ewing
inside of zippyshare right because if
you see that call that API inspection
because that's how we talked to collapse
so being able to see those API calls and
exactly what they're doing normalize
those we can see what upload is share
and edit opposed to create and then when
you go to your policy engine you can say
you know what these apps
I'm not going to upload to especially
not a perfect data so now we haven't
blocked the app but we now protected
user from doing something stupid moving
our data doesn't belong right and now
we're out of that blocking script now
we're just blocking risky behavior
rather than try to block the apps will
talk about something that kind of
couples with that those are critical to
your clouds here strategy so when you're
getting this out when you're talking to
companies actually asking this question
how people you see the activities inside
the app because that couples with GOP
with policy and you can create policy
around that which has nothing to do
again with blocking that
I finally got it
so six steps some of these recovered
before right step one is to discover the
problem and this is remember talking to
your leadership
this is the part where you're going to
present them with you know a story which
is just a report that says this is how
many actually using and you know this is
how much data is going back and forth
those apps these are all the risk X so
therefore these are our risk users so
it's very straightforward put it in the
context of cloud uses this is derived
from proxy logs which you know is that
what I've already talked about that is
very high-level 30,000 foot view of the
problem because they don't have the baby
I inspection they're not going to see
the activities in the apps but it's a
great starting place to tell the problem
that if you already know the problem any
as i mentioned before can make all the
canopy's pretty much offer offer this
for free just call up and say how to do
this week if your problem you can skip
over this part is more of a commodity
right this is this is not a strategy
that's not a
it's not a strategy so your strategies
and block let me tell me the problem
i'll just use that information of all
talk about that so you need that
information potential to move to stage
two which is the holy grail in my
opinion of what it can be doing and that
is remaining exfiltration data that's
really the heart of what this stuff is
right we are providing the data from
getting where it doesn't belong
that's what it has we should be doing
now there's a lot of ways we can do this
we talk about it says in here sanction
to unsanctioned now so you know what
prevents your user you know you have a
sanctioned out let's say that you're
saving office 365 sharepoint your users
pull the file on there that says you
don't want to work on this all 10
personal locks or personal line drive
you know what stops them from doing that
so yeah we can control data at rest
inside of the sanction app that's
important
create files in there we can for
Mallory's want to do all of those things
but unless you're taking care of the
data in motion you you're missing
ninety-five percent of it was so that's
dangerous
alright so we talked about this pretty
much length you know it should be an
enabling technology and i'll be asked to
use there's no getting away from it
anymore
we have downloaded customer he said I
just need you guys because I can't
listen to my entire department you're
driving me crazy
great they all they do is complain
because I'm for blocking us i just need
to enable it and insecurity again that
that has to be your strategy coupled
with you know that SL inspection that I
inspection all of those things are what
you don't have today the most part right
that this is going to give you and is
rapidly evolving itouch
this to this which is allow being able
to detect managers and manage devices so
we we do that internal and if i plug my
laptop one of your networks I better not
be able to get up I have a whole
instances some networks but actually so
you want to make sure that the same
applies to the cloud there has to be
some audit on the end whether that's a
certificate check or you gonna be you
know ops wat audience on the employees
to ca are you running this kind of
encryption attached to this domain are
you running these processes you have
these files installed as you do your
manage device right and if you're manage
device and you get all the access that
you should get to your class especially
sanction was but if you're not a managed
device then you should be extremely
limited so if I go home and try to go
into our corporate box of help and I get
my wife's computer it should know that
that is not my corporate device living
in your viewing only or maybe nothing
right so that's a very important piece
of the world because get users of you
perimeter need to know a little bit
about that user before they get to our
idea and their device so we cannot talk
about different ways that you can do
that but it certainly built it
hi Step five is is all about threat
detection so this is also been rapidly
evolving probably the last six months
i'd say $MONEY in cash and that is the
ability to obviously detect malware in
sanctioned apps which is it as data at
rest so be able to scan any file has
been dropped in the same chap but also
emotion so David going to any cloud and
and the goal here is to stop the cloud
propagation of matter because if i put a
smaller oven in our corporate box
account or onedrive and then I'm sharing
it with a bunch of people well they just
got more fun syncing files now I just
pull the file down automatically to my
to my end right so it has to be robust
and it can't just be okay by the way we
only am you know one of the beginning of
ours
I mean it has to be that it has to be
dynamic sandboxing same stuff you're
doing internally has to be done for word
cloud data and then used for on top of
that anomaly detection so who's bulk
uploading downloading files are logging
in from two different locations and
given period of time writing sharing
credentials into an avid user behavior
analytics is a big term in the industry
right now is built into cloud usage I'm
pretty predictable so I wake up in the
morning go to the same things i usually
go to Nobu similar files so it's pretty
steady but it'd be very easy Asian my
behavior if i log in from China at three
in the morning and go to have something
on an extreme example but that's the
kind of stuff that needs to be looked at
right again extending this stuff that
we're doing internally this work very
well now into cloud because you don't
protect ya protected
oh and there's one other thing with
ransom layer so what one of the new
things that's coming out is I don't know
this is you need to cloud but being able
to detect how files are being encrypted
and I don't have all the expert details
on this yet but when something somebody
gets it as trying to create data in your
station application and impossibly
that's not using your pc encrypted or
some other checks is doing its gonna be
able to stop it right now the files it
doesn't create the first couple will
obviously be restored from previous
versions so that's all in the works of
take care of ransomware lot of people
stuff
and then the last one is coaching user
training in this probably at first
glance doesn't seem like it's an
important part but this is actually one
of my favorites if we're behind a proxy
and we go to a website that we're not
allowed to go to what happened he throws
us a big abrasive alert that says you
you're not doing it right and that's
that's not how casually this so Casspi
is going to you're going to try to move
sensitive data to a place you should be
PT idea eh I mean whatever compliance
you have a little bored when you do that
it's going to pop up something up and
say you know this is this is not the
place you should be putting this data so
we're not allowed to do it and by the
way here is the place where you shoot in
our section application or internally or
network this doesn't go outside the
airport
you know so you do that enough times the
users will learn you know and they're
automatically going to go to the desired
if you send out an email saying hey by
the way to prefer everybody put
everything in box please
and here's the link was going to
remember that he's gonna care you know
nobody's going to care about that so
your real-time educate users to what you
want them to do real-time pop that up
and you can brand in any way you want
and you have to say you have a redirect
automatically to the desire baby that's
an important piece of Apple process and
in order to do that obviously we can go
back and look at the API inspection all
of those activities a policy on to stop
that message up all stuff that we were
talking so I think this is probably the
last slide and his talks about you know
the first generation cavs vs second i
think it's important to differentiate
between the two one week and his first
came out two years ago
their goal was to tell you the problem
right i think there's a commercial after
a series commercial get companies
termite potter paint and he's taking a
termite all over the place and they say
we can do body as well I'm just honored
i don't do anything about it right and
that's kind of what Casby was in LA came
out tell me the problem just blocking
strategy which of course we know it
doesn't sustain or it doesn't do you
know it doesn't look at any activity
it's not doing us or is doing basic do
so
regex and keyword matches things and it
basically wasn't doing any threat
detection so very very basic then we're
going to you know now the second
generation of Cassidy's that is that
hundred percent coverage for all the
apps you know blocking those activities
not the app itself and then true
enterprise-class deal and that's
important right that's probably one of
the things when you're going down this
path you want to ask about how
enterprise classes you deal is really at
the end of the day we're seeing
activities but your ability to attack
that comes from your heel and policy so
that is one of the most important pieces
of any one of these products is how
enterprises do proximity analysis and or
logic fingerprinting exact match all of
the stuff that you know that we need
internally at me for the possible so you
want to ask that question you really
want to test out those deal edges
because if you can't if you can see it
but not enforce it can't see it
obviously it's so good it's what you're
only as good as your policy behind and
then obviously all the threat
intelligence that I talked about all of
that now is built into these products
you can see these very robust is a long
wait very short time so there's a lot to
look at those are the things that you
want to focus on when you go through
this process all the stuff i talk about
those activities right those are
important video engine that should be
your strategy going forward because you
want a future prove yourself whatever
you end up with a lot of these out there
they're not future they'll cover you for
out for six months right and then a year
from now you'll be like well I really
want to stop this from going into
unsanctioned that hard we can't do that
right now you're getting another project
so this is a summary i'm not going to go
through and questions questions
awesome well thank you for your time