expert everyone say that the computer
forensic investigators probably like 10
years just about in federal court state
courts few times in the postwar that
sucks you in here purchases difficult
alright so can you do me a favor keep
not BS meter so people when asked where
he was head case studies and I watch
them sometimes i'm sitting there
thinking I don't know that's about
cracked it so if you sit on your
business me root of all everybody knows
him everyone will crack
who here has leveraged different
forensics solves problem not be enough
it's a response just like civil
litigations you hope so if you're
looking for a digital frames class it's
going to make your eyes bleed this is
not it this is not going to help you
pass the certification exam i'm just
going to give the basics of digital
forensics but I used to give those types
types of talks and what people they look
to your stories how did your language is
what problems did you solve and so will
go through the basics but then i'm going
to show you where each one of these are
case studies that out some of them are
old enough for 45 years old but the same
things happen it's just different people
when i'm too lazy to continue to redact
information such as you send stuff to
talk about digital forensics basics
we'll talk about how it works you know
what we're looking to accomplish how we
do things and they will talk about these
decks and you'll ask yourself never
stops
seriously they really did that and then
there's gonna be some pro tips when the
proteins are don't do stupid things on
computers because we'll figure it out
what we would what we do seems very
complex and very difficult and there is
a level of complexity
it's not as hard as well make it out to
be it's not like you see on CSI you know
text within our hard working well in
rooms and we're just not nearly as
attractive is no speak so it's real
difference what you sit there and this
is gonna be boring to me you're sorry
nice to meet you see peace alright so
some digital forensics basis a little so
I do a lot of things in response i do a
lot of civil litigation we work a lot of
cases trade secret that is what I do a
lot of i do some hot sex course i'm from
Knoxville Tennessee can't tell
and so we don't do Tennessee's no
problem or step so it's real house takes
divorce or just a little bit expensive
item also child custody
there's a lot of money involved and i
have a couple of those cases it will go
through we don't do i do a water tray to
do a lot of spoliation of evidence do a
lot of concealing other people doing and
many times are actually . as neutral
there's not a lot of forensics people in
knoxville tennessee and so I work
sometimes the court will appoint as a
neutral to work for Botox and that's
kind of hard so just of digital
forensics basics people think for
instance is just recovering deleted
information it's not there's so much
more to it
I don't know that I've ever had one case
The Smoking Gun is something that
someone deleted its activities
it's what they're doing is what they're
trying to cover up yeah sometimes the
content and information is important but
also time instant responses when i get
the value of information we do keyword
search is born but it's extremely
valuable when you're looking at an
operating system but by default Windows
7 is about 800,000 bottles when your
time to find what you're looking for
digital communications i just call this
email but i have a twenty-two-year-old
they have no idea what email this so now
it's just digital communications
Internet activities we spend a lot of
time analyzing internet and i'm going to
go through more of these in debt
pictures and movies
yeah pictures we do a lot of moment of
US currency so sometimes i just have to
have the phone back like this because of
the pictures that have been on pump five
activities will talk about the
importance of time learning activities
external use storage usage metadata and
accept data most people know this now
but some people still don't know when it
comes to accept data application
execution histories and anti forensics
is my favorite i love it with someone's
trying to hide something stuff we
analyze you know there's nothing or
Sarah here computer servers memory for
instance i'm going to do a lot more that
even in civil litigation so we do a lot
of different response mobile devices
truth is I probably analyzed more mobile
devices now than i do computers and
that's a completely i had some slides
about mobile but my tops only 15 minutes
and not 60 so i cut those output mobiles
are completely different animal
it's different tools at the different
methodology cloud storage not
necessarily the stores with the
interaction with the storage removable
media is huge and trying to do with that
we doing with gps devices and I don't
have a case study on GPS here but we
actually worked the case in which a
tractor-trailer with the wrong way down
a one-way street hit someone killed him
well his testimony was that he did not
go down that way or there was some type
of confusion as to what happened and the
defense actually i recently had a GPS
device and have wings and every few
seconds it shows and we showed that he
did exactly what the police report set
so that if your defense attorney locking
but we kept him from litigating
something for a long time that he was
gonna lose watches the pics i've not
analyzed and watch it but I saw a case
fits in which you have people that are
drawing whether it's disability or
something else everyone's where fits now
so you're John disability because you
can't walk more than a hundred feet but
you were gonna fit
let me get my hands on that fit into the
pit so the fit a lon
you're not supposed to be able to do
certain things but you know you're doing
your 10,000 steps a day
something's kind of struck what stranger
I don't work that well but I've seen
that so as an expert witness this is as
basic as digital forensics gets I have
to explain things to judges juries and
determine any attorneys judges are good
so attorneys are extremely smart until
it comes to technology they struggle
with that so i have to come up with
analogies to teach them things and so my
goal is it my twelve-year-old she's
pretty smart girls mother if not we're
open understand what I'm talking about
that a judge or jury or the attorneys
with so this is the analogy that I use
so if you remember to show how old are
longtime going when I went to lover i
want to book i went to the card catalog
system to the decimal system i pulled
the card there . to the book on the
shelf
that's how computers work it's that
simple so when you delete a bottle so
for what it's worth we pretty much just
intention that happy they need to name
it something they made it delete the way
the way the week works is the same thing
that if someone were to take that car
and related they're still reference to
it here in the book is still on the
shelves until someone puts a book in its
place
that's how file systems work so sticking
with thank you sir
sticking with Microsoft's file system
HDFS it has the master file table
it has an entry invest file table that
points to the physical sector that the
word document exists off so when you hit
the delete button all you're doing is
removing that injury so 44 . time is
still gonna be in the mft table until
another file over rocks and it's still
going to be able to hard drive that's
all the leaky ducts because we're too
lazy to wait for 20 it out so that's how
we recover deleted information keyword
search anytime anything at any point
stop and ask me a question for football
necessary keyword search it is boring
but you know people start documents in
places other than my dog there's
temporary office there's downloads
there's a lot of other places and when
you need to calm down
Amelia documents to find things of
interest keyword searching works
I'm so it's extremely valuable but it's
morning so lots of times we're doing
discovery and forensics of the kids the
attorney says we want to know what they
were doing and also we want all
documents that have these terms so we
run the keywords weekend excellent we
use access data safety k which is used
ET search which has access to it as much
better than any place up so we didn't
exit very flexible so we can do all
these things and or not the thing with
an index that's kind of frustrating is
there certain always characters like a
heightened or a period or a dash it does
not index those google so when I need to
search for an IP address that becomes a
pain because it's not going to have that
dog index that's right to do something
for a proximity search so i can do one
on to within one word of 168 and i'm
going to get that out there except
summit I want plum within Bob words of
payer that's the proximity you can do
stemming and fuzzy and incentive we
don't do any criminal investigations
sometimes were hired as an ex is a it's
open expert for the defense we don't do
tell photography but we trying to work
with a capital and they have word lists
that for every case the issue we have
trade secret theft so what sometimes
they know what they're looking for
not the sexiest thing in forensics but
it's still important to help you get
down to what you're looking for so
communications conventional email really
doesn't
so we're looking at outlook we're
looking at PS days within LSTs that's
getting a lot more difficult
the people of them too LOL 365 so now
you just have an OSD so we're still
looking into eventually males webmail
used to be extremely fruitful for us
gmail hotmail email all those were
awesome because it would catch the
entire webpage on the device so we know
there's a case study later when i was
able to recover recover hundreds of
young male from the device because it's
catched since they look to the JSON
language very little is left on the drop
and it's frustrating i can see to and
from the date i give you time analysis
and see maybe they access the file to
upload it but not nearly as much as what
we used to get and it's extremely
frustrated we do look at attachments
people still use their business email
accounts to attach contact list and
sensitive files and send it to the gmail
i don't know i don't want to do it
doesn't bother me because it makes me
successful but they still do it
social networking communication facebook
messages this is huge for us especially
when we are working the divorce case
when you're using facebook Messenger
it's catching all that to the drop these
little snippets so we have scripts that
will pick all that up in a spreadsheet
put in college or and what I pissed in
we'll talk text messaging a little bit
later when it comes to mobile devices no
actually will talk about now so mobile
devices there are very few things are
actually a text message so that was
enough
so when it's blue that's not a text
message that's awful that's obvious when
it's green
that's a text mrs. Finch what's act if
it's all of these other third-party
those are not text messages and what
throws attorney's office there are well
we'll just call Kari get those Texas
well first off the carrier doesn't have
the pair of the Texas they have the
metadata and they only have the metadata
for real text messages so I had to
explain to them that that's not going to
answer your question because text
messages are really there's not a lot of
text messaging left internet history so
internet histories tell a story it's
phenomenal haven't submitted a history
test or just if you look at some with
google queries and if you're interested
in seeing this you can actually I want
them because I don't have time &
freelance but I'm use google when you're
logged in it keeps all of your search
queries it keeps every video you're
watching keeps everything that you're
doing while you're logged into google
and you can actually go looking
search histories and you can see your
search histories and when you go back
through that I do that from time to time
you like
yeah i forgot about that you know if
there's a health problem if there's
something I'm worried about there's
something bad i plan on doing I'm like
if you remember what was the young girl
that was killed
listen Casey Anthony that is a great
case as to how you have to be very
careful but that whole case hands on
those on those searches or whatever that
was the forensic platform didn't read it
properly but that's the only evidence
they had was that search query for
whatever that whatever the poison was so
don't get your search histories if you
don't turn it off
we recover deleted internet history and
it's not it's trivial to do that with
the right software we don't do about
hand we have software that doesn't we
don't care what browser you use so we've
seen where something for you use
Internet Explorer to do their normal
stuff and then they'll switch over the
firefox to do different stuff and they
make their bodies covered with they're
gonna start thinking well you know i'm
just using her next let's hope we don't
care
forensic software reviews we choose
every browser even see monkeys on that
list because the attackers use that for
some reason so we don't care what
browser you're using we're going to get
back first case to facebook check so
that's not going to us there was a
suspected affair doing this for 10 years
yes sir I was just as is the history
still there when you use the firebox
it's not kidding don't use it that much
and probably a private browsing time if
not all of its going to be there
please look like shards of glass you can
pick up some other but you're not going
to get all of it but if it's in the
index file so in every browser does it
differently keeping me when you delete
your internet history
it doesn't even zero out that file it
just kind of deleted it starts a new you
can get that but when you're in browsing
mode it's unlikely we're gonna get all
but we see that you went into private
browsing mode which to me would raise
suspicion so when I see that
automatically on your timeline second
are what are they doing it why so there
are legitimate reasons I guess go to
private browsing moment when I
that I think something malicious may be
about to have a question
so there are suspected fair Deucalion
sorry prospect call me said I think my
wife is having an affair with someone
from high school on facebook magnetic
head up on facebook again if you've
heard this one before so he said I want
to take a look at so for some reason he
tells her i'm sending this off to a
computer forensics company and they're
going to take a look at what you think
she did she goes right clears the chat
history i also have some proof that she
cleared the chat history from facebook
not from the cash on the drive then she
deleted her and histories I didn't care
i was still able to get back to Leni to
chat messages and it was exactly what he
thought that was just that one person
and we were able to get all the internet
history back to so it really doesn't
matter if you delete the internet
histories and browsing mode hurts
we'll talk about anti forensics efforts
which is like a bull in a china shop to
me is worse we'll talk about that with
you there are ways to get around it most
of the time we're gonna cover or have a
reason to suspect something's going on
this is one of the most simple cases
I've ever work and the Attorney steel
tells this story every time she has an
opportunity so we were brought in for a
workplace injury there was a father a
medical facility and so the claim was a
diminished quality of life the claim was
that she was having uncontrollable
seizures which is a diminished quality
of life um somehow we were able to
normally have to create a very good case
to be able to someone's personal
computer somehow internal was able to
get it and I analyzed so I went through
and looking at everything and sometimes
it's the simple stuff I spent days on
this case trying to find something on
the internet research she would research
symptoms of her condition overall
doctors now pointing up in time I've got
a headache i'm pretty sure I'm gonna die
according to energy she would do that
but working closely with the attorney
its timing
she only did it about three or four
times and I asked about the state she
said I don't know why those are days
before hearings she would research the
symptoms right before the hearings and
that she would demonstrate those
symptoms during the hearings so that was
used then she started looking at workers
compensation calculate
yeah if you're following for workers
comp you're gonna be looking at that
this one thankyou researches what
computer forensics box let me tell you
what about little time that you start
for that there was one time that they
actually starts for my day's been good
friends explained by myself and just
kind of freaky because building
forensics like all the goods so we have
that was pretty good and then I started
looking at when are slowly lifted the
pictures flip through the pictures and
she went on vacation a few times her you
can pull it together for the same i get
your family school vacation you're gonna
go
she was also going to the owners of our
game anyone been in stadium not so we
can hold a hundred two thousand people
and it's straight up and down
I won't even drink beer at the tailgate
before the game because I'm afraid I
can't get up the steps it is that state
the order tomorrow get those 20 or
30,000 people there so it's hard to get
up-and-down think she's on the field
alright then finally I run across a
couple that my attorney to finally sink
your teeth into this is her
that's our time so if you're a good
defensive start a 60-second real quick
captain needa fitness there was a bear
we had to jump you the other kid jumped
and we're going after their snakes you
may be able to get mom maybe the judge
the jury on tonight or I will let that
slide
good luck with this that's her jumping
off the bridge and I know that bridge
that during this time of year is about
20 feet from the water we want this case
it didn't take some awesome CS hasta I
just had to look at the pictures because
people don't realize iphone users you
plug your computer when you plug your
phone into maybe do an update or
something or sick of a playlist if you
don't do that we hear it creates a
backup of your phone to your computer
that's where stuff like this comes from
people don't realize that it's there we
want to guess I'll activity shoes so I
wasn't one top somewhere they were
talking about mac addresses Mac without
access and change i will take a step
from ntfs has come back be so there's
modified access change and for board is
extremely important because there's two
types of metadata there's filesystem
metadata and dinners application day
my assistant today is when files copy to
that device application metadata says
when that document was created more so
you can have a document for the modified
date that's before the creation things
because of that is hard to explain but
that's the board date when was the
document for work not when it was great
so we know what documents are created
modified access deleted Conda it's very
difficult to know exactly what if I was
too weak
we know that it's deleted and we know
what it was last access you can behind
and sales to leave it at that time but
I'm very conservative because I've been
kicked in the teeth
lots of counsel the same here's a good
one we know what documents are open when
you double click an icon to open a
document it creates them to call a link
file in that link file even without the
document itself
I know when you open that document the
first time I know the last time I love
the size of the document and I don't
want that document is located
specifically network share USB Drive
that can be huge for instance if someone
turns in their resignation on sep tember
not concept / 20th in September 19 I see
the development customer list of xls
from a USB drop we need to go to figure
out with a USB drivers so we know where
that's coming from external mas usage
again none of this is most of its not to
most people but every time you plug into
USB demas we know every USB storage we
know mobile phones we know anything you
plug into that USB port tattoos that
system with a lot of different artifacts
it logs registries we know the first we
always even XP we know the first and
last comment about was you and that can
be key is I sho sho Pistons sometimes I
know each time starting with windows
seven started putting things in the vid
walk every time in juice that's big
because now I know first time every time
and last time and sometimes I know how
all you can see when it's plugged it in
and you can see when they upload and
that's you can be
he also model and serial number is huge
when you're looking for advice
here's an example that oh ok studio so
it was a discovery very politically
charged discovery matter in which the
reference this case with four times
because
still screwed up everything you could
have done losing the case was thrown out
because i'm going to do i'm actually
it's settled reviews about to be thrown
up ask for a bunch of documents with
specific file names from the computers
and all your video we need this
discovery and then we're also going to
look and see if you didn't yank so you
can see we know the internet we know the
product we know the serial number we
know the driver was associated with it
we know the first time we know the last
time we know be installed a that's a lot
of pretty valuable information when
you're piecing together tama the leg
files that was referencing you have told
you about this is that same cruiser
drive everything is redacted here was a
filing with keywords and he was supposed
to provide during discover if you've
ever been in litigation you don't move
up with the discovery process because
that's everything is based off if you
want with the discovery process
sanctions or the case thrown up all
these file names were specific to what
he was supposed to produce so we knew
that he has a USB drive and I know the
exact USB drop that has these files on
that he didn't produce that was huge in
our favor
so let's talk about intellectual
property theft there's a fine line
between intellectual property and trade
secret but this one was intellectual
property little background so medical
device manufacturer create a device that
not a lot of people to larger company in
the same sector trying to buy them about
three times and each time they tell them
so they hired hit their lead engineer
that designed the product for passing on
your products so the lead engineer lift
went to work for the parent to talk
about and that helps
they're like we're missing some emails
from his email box of manufacturer we
need to get these back and related to
get my output mattress
yes but your league engineer went to
work for the competition is trying to
buy you three times and you're just
worried about simulated diamond
yep can I take a look around some other
stuff you just don't spend too much
money each other every time 1222 he
resigned from the government 12-2 not a
big deal but what I'm looking for is a
change in behavior whether you realize
it or not everyday you do the same
things on your computer when i'm alive
i'm investigating a person you set that
baseline they're doing the same things
when they start doing this
the things you start to get on that 22
before is target company can come work
for another big deal let me know I kind
of know pet 12-team he copied the
projects folder from the network share
to the desktop folder of his laptop I
know it's confusing
laptop desktop / I'll be the project
folder there not a big deal huge deal
he had 35 to people because he said we
will never make copies of our DWG sounds
no seller no solidworks files are too
everybody a copy because if there's a
copy one of the drop
they sent the wrong side to a
manufacturing retirement costing tens of
thousands of dollars
he just had to change the behavior he
copied their every one of those designs
to his laptop when he told everyone else
not to do that and to never remember
from the puncture see copy down you can
see there's eggs from the desktop you
can see the date then copied it and i'll
explain the headaches you're just a
minute 1222 it 110v power is the laptop
on he's an engineer we all work late
he had this laptop three years nothing
never been powered down past 930 change
your behavior as the device powered on
it found a new USB device it never
simple
so you can see here first i'm connected
december $MONTH twenty-second 611 so
this is UTC offset five hours for non
upset non-members thought of hours you
got one way I know vendor product and I
don't see remember when you think about
to happen here
how was it up and then he moved the
project's poser over to the USB drive
and i know we moved it because three
times when you turn the laptop off of
two or three that's 50 minutes when you
move a file or a group of files first
you have to copy it and then you deleted
that's what the red X mates so we were
able to recover all of those files we
got ripped a black hardware three times
50 minutes to move it and emulated still
took us four years to win this case
application executions so we know the
first execution date and time of every
application we know the last as we know
the last execution date time we don't
know you know first time last time we
don't have many times we can't see
everything in between
we don't have many many times we know
the user to execute the application so
windows has something called prefix and
when it tries to do from a binary
perspective is to be more efficient and
loads a piece of in a PDF PDF file and
it keeps the last hundred twenty-eight
so I know the last hundred twenty
programs and then I can recover deleted
PDF files and rolled off and see more
that's where the entire system that
every two years about that which is the
registry file for user also has
something called user system that has
the same things so we know what
applications where and lots of time
today that can be huge community is so
let's start with what would be
considered an easy trade secret theft so
this was a high very helicopter about
Pilar organization in which one of their
lead people are one of their best people
resign domain school on a six so they
contact me contact me immediately so
we're really worried because we know he
wants to set up a competing business we
need to know what's going off looking to
do queries how do i think another email
account to gmail and other user here is
that other people don't use on that sees
what he's trying to do you can
synchronize outlook with gmail so right
here already know he's gonna find a way
to get this data
he's probably got I just need to figure
it out i find the copy sensitive
information to a USB Drive show that was
dropbox was installed on march third of
$MONTH 2011 and then uninstalled may six
right before you resign so ask my condom
like what's the significance of marks
third and she said oh I remember that's
the day that he got into an argument
with the partners as the direction of
the offer so soon as that are happening
here we have a plan to install dropbox
yesterday you can see here they removed
it and this is a big deal for you it's
called it the government stuff
the application execution as i said i
know we know if executed self i see on
the day i'm a lab at one-thirty know 12
13 p.m. he executed and remove so he
went into the Avenue control panel and
remove drugs China the tracks then on
makeshift which was the day before first
time connected then installed a kingston
datatraveler serial number first time
that device has never been used
you can see what's about to happen here
he went into a so if your BR person what
has the most valuable information out of
the CRM or out
so what most people don't realize he
went into outlook and explore today when
you do that it creates this map file on
the local Drive of what you're doing so
csb of an angular which is the address
book and calendar in the email which is
the email so I know this is happening
how can i top this USB Drive i know we
just plugged in this map file has the
path the name and what was exported so
you know the timeline you can see plug
in the USB drop explore every bit of
this stuff so through this we were able
to get his home computer stuff
oh so we did the analysis of the whole
machine that argument was really easy
with the court record look we got this
this and this gives the stuff what you
did when he installed dropbox he started
moving over the business secret stuff
it's dropbox sync it up you went home
install dropbox and it's down to some
computer for you . the next day after
makes when he went home he had a
different USB Drive helping all that
stuff out the dropbox folder under the
USB drive and then the dropbox from home
with you and we obviously want this case
metadata so metadata is just information
about information that can be extremely
valuable in the right context so for
instance we don't want to file this is
mainly office . adobe not so much we
know when the file was created access we
can see the summers we can see the past
10 offers of a document sometimes we can
see the track changes on that's way back
to work those three but sometimes we can
see what those changes were because
let's scrub the document prior history
reading histories we don't wanna
documents been print so even now I can
tell you the last time of documents been
printed because it's tagged email his
email headers spreadsheets you know
what's awesome about spreadsheets is
that if you just print a spreadsheet you
don't see the orders and all that we've
had cases in which the formula was the
problem not the results office documents
pictures you know this is a surprise
anything but pictures have you have
location services turned on your phone
and take a picture it has a lot of stuff
can remain model resolution you know
what we do it also has at altitude
$OPERAND longitude latitude where you
were standing when you took the picture
so this can be real and in cases like
divorce cases when someone's not
supposed to be a certain place we made
on the stance that no I've never been
there and then we have a picture of this
is worried because this phone and also
we don't know we don't just get Tracy
but when someone's looking for a runaway
if you can get them to take a picture so
i will send it to you sometimes you can
get this but it's kind of scary that
there's that much info
one thing to keep in mind when you
upload your pictures to social media
they scrub this because they realize the
implications of that
here's a case that you just call me
today this was last year i think so
story there was a teacher and opiates
which will create spaces like the secret
city that's where we enrich uranium is
like blowing stuff up so he was a
teacher there allegedly had write up
some type of school credit card number
defendant day three carries away of shut
up shut up to the head and incentives a
suicide with family was pretty well off
and I just would not let it die
nope they would let it rest they want to
prove that they really need help in this
case of you
so think there was a document that the
model and state law enforcement that was
named to love of my life and it was
actually it's supposed to be you know
the litter which he was claiming is
going to suicide note
so this was a knoxville news suicide no
family house computer created the
afternoon before his death . . this
document was created was about four
times after . according to the
statements from the hottest hairstyles
for my memo
according to them including the parents
email to local media didn't include the
actual author of the document not need
to talk
remember also stated the nodes and four
times after happened . so i was very
conservative this this is simple right
click properties they put this thing to
rest you can see the document was
created on july 24th called the love of
my life
here's the kicker any document on $MONTH
twenty-fourth could have been renamed to
that that won't change the modified date
of the document to change the following
and I can see there was modified on
Tuesday April twenty-eighth the 2,000
2015 4 days before the document was
given to me for analysis
the other thing is i was on the phone
with her and she said yeah there's been
a couple of times when i close the
document and asked me if i wanted to
save it so i did didn't mess anything up
too much
why are you saying this right when you
look at a document yet so she knew this
was coming
I don't think she did anything wrong she
just wanted the case to go away
last time five answers every sound on so
you know it's a matter so if it all
sound over his account of course it's
going to be create their revision number
so we can be remitted more violence four
times revision 1 is the original four
times since that so kind of Atlanta it's
simple stuff like this that when you see
a doctor has been modified horsemen
given to be used
alright I've got to set the states for
this one of the smallest piece of
evidence this is that one case i was
referring to what happened here was
there was a large company that was being
sued by a small really small competitor
and what's called a ketone because the
government was up involved if citizen
can bring suit against a private party
on behalf of the government and they
give me whatever the findings are
whatever resolutions thank you part of
that so this dude had a small company
that competed with this huge company he
finds a key top suit because they were
doing reps supposed to work things out
with the government is it takes a lot of
money to pop suit the assumption is he's
being funded by someone else that also
has vested interest in that company
loses this awesome
this guy has a lot so we're all thinking
he's involved we haven't been able to
type to it so we got the computers
desktop laptop keyword searching 5,000
docks and
the first dog that the document that the
Attorney looked at she called me and she
said I've never done this before but
this seems strange to me
what is it so she just looked at the
properties during any discovery which
platform you can you see that you have
to do this but the title of the document
was a court filing that he had filed
against them six weeks before
alright the author of the document was
the gather we were suspected it was his
wife so he used his wife's computer to
create a document to file against this
company gave it to him so that time into
the whole thing it didn't solve the case
but it was kinda suspicious because they
can't even depositions and testimonies
no no he has nothing to do with this and
does you know how that happened
so this just more accepted this is my
favorite place that's my drama you know
the accepted you just click on a link
and it will take you know this demo will
show you an exact locations to wear with
anything while we're going to tell you
before you left
you've got a little time to figure out
where I live and opportunistic separates
I so I love this this is any effort to
consider destroy evidence
the overwhelming majority of the time it
looks like a role in a china shop
because you're going to see zero net
files you're going to see applications
if executed with names like ccleaner so
they're special program ccleaner on the
unit is if you run ccleaner get if you
run ccleaner and every artifact and i'm
really looking for linked files jump
lists which is a new top of the pile
internet history is temporary files it's
all gone i cannot get it back but Mr
Le's get is another one
Blake claim and so the truth is the only
way you really get rid of a file truly
get rid of it is when you run these
applications it over rocks those sectors
of the disc with zeros and ones and you
don't get it back after that butt-ugly
the show mr. robot shows how to get
through
yes mr. robot is very talented the NSA
is also very talented i know i'm talking
about slamming it with a hammer and then
burning it is
yeah but see when the course requested
that it's really hard to get around it
so that's yes you will not get it back
when that happens you know if you can
take it shooting it's fun you know
there's a lot of fun ways to get rid of
our crowd loves but you have to reduce
something to the course you need to
produce something that's not in pieces
hurt system utilities actually cause a
lot of problems defrag is my nemesis
because you have all these deleted files
over here daddy Frank's job is to
reorganize the files on the disk it's
going to overwrite those files that i
want this cleanup obviously you know so
I bring this up because same difference
a couple times when we have helped rob
the preservation letters to the opposing
side so this was stated specifically and
it is further ordered the entry of this
order
yeah do will not engage in any activity
that could potentially damage data
stored on the computer hard drive
this would include installing programs
that limit or replicate data normal
captured during internet activity and
programs that alter or living on
allocate space black space or the
windows registry file or running
utilities against the harddrive such as
reformatting or defrag anyone want to
guess what he did
soon after receiving use this as I mean
us what he was going to do
lucky I can't make this up desktop
computer so i told you we know the
implications are executed clean manager
has the windows disk cleanup you too
he received the order i think on 9 15 or
9 15 or 9 20 that order windale meaning
it was signed in and give it to rain
clean manager 928 930 actually that's
UTC so that's like 430 afternoon the
desktop of you ready for a first-time
december $YEAR 13 last time December
25th we showed up on December 27 to pick
up the laptop and desktop
they're take 25th read it six times
because once gonna be good enough i need
to run five more towels
the judge love this about the way and
hey you're going on the desktop let's be
consistent doing on the laptop also
claimed manager this one was vista this
one's XP play manager is this cleanup
random 110 which is after he's been
given the order not to let the time one
comes in handy dandy runs deep red three
dollars if that wasn't enough he also
said leave the internet history him up
so he use firefox when you decided to do
was to kill the internet histories then
leave about two hours worth of history
they'll never notice that there's two
hours of history this happened five
hours before we showed up to pick up the
computers so he deleted the histories
and even try to recover because why he
tried to delete and you've got back so
this is slowly and evidence and it
didn't work out
we finally won that case this one so
everyone has that case that the proud of
that keep referring to this was the
third forensics case fireworks started
on in 2007 and they didn't finish until
2000 let you comfortable because this
one's good this one set precedent so
reports that President that commercial
spyler candy bar tab and simple so we
have this young attorney young
attractive tell me something similar
young attractive attorney Mary's
established business and this is all
public and i'll leave the link if you
want something entertaining the great
this is it so he owns a lumber yard
that's r2p sales two home depots and
wells he's well-established so he had an
issue with fidelity in the past has a
couple of kids and they have a habit of
getting into trouble so what she decided
was that we really need to monitor these
kids activities on computer because you
know kids get into a log truck there
were eight computers and his lumber yard
office they only install it onto the two
computers that he uses she also have a
prenup agreement in place that states if
you cheat on me I take you to the
cleaners
let's see where this was going
what she did with every time an email it
to him it was automatically redirected
to her yahoo mail account through the
spectra soft blush they relayed that
product because I was about six lawsuits
against them so you can see this is
going to email it was rerouted to her
you see it flashing report so this is
the actual diagram been together for
testimonials and corporate week in this
case the email will be sent to rule and
I can't disclose names because it's all
put the email will be sent the boy clone
before it landed on the drive and this
is what was important because the term
was contemporaneous with transmission
before it landed on the drop it
redirected it to her that made a heart
attack
what she would do if she would take
emails from female business associates
and sit back to her she would modify
them to make it look like rolling was
having an affair with them she would
copy these texts off of yahoo mail can't
put in a word document and did you find
to produce in discovery
that's just the beginning so that's
what's happening there is there's a link
there if you just search clumsy go Henry
I analyzed seven confuse unless his
computers and allowance was able to get
her computer based on some stuff I
recovered hundreds of yahoo emails in
full-time just what was going on every
meal yet i have a binder this stick
their work so through discrepancies and
emails being produced in discovery
here's what brought to light is a small
number offices windows for workgroups
she used that while she used that lumber
yard has her law office from time to
time it was a weekend in the admin
assistant when help
what do people do when they go to shut
their computers off that computer was
the print server for the company so
crystal golden box and plugs into USB
Drive says she's never seen USB drop
opens three documents from the USB
dropped as I could see them and print
them because monday is gonna be hearing
they print because the computers all
admin assistant comes in on Monday
morning hours of the computer is what
spits out on the print Elster emails see
dr. she texting the wrong way cause is
very expensive
you know divorce attorney before
starting college me and I have this case
it worked on a lot
it gets better so she was producing
false documents and discovery and
seasoned attorney is the discovery
process is safe and testimony she stated
so in deposition
I don't have your USB Drive I know she
plugged into a USB Drive which trickles
talking through this i was able to get
her laptop computer
the first thing I did was look for that
USB Drive I knew the serial number of
the model number they matched so I
notice you've been using that we've
gotten that wrong way which was my
client through this and there's even
more to them into really kept saying
bill there was an international
agreement that one file was not popular
with the courts and I don't want to
interrupt your agreement is but we've
got other stuff anymore . he said it's
important because what I sound is what
is not locals five this will never
happen is you she was using Windows
works ms works whatever whatever that
was the night that he signed the end
enough to agreement that ended up would
have cost him a lot of money there were
two of them copy print one of them was
the one that he signed one of them is
the one that was filed that had another
paragraph that make her a very wealthy
woman in the temporary Prince dreams i
was able to pull both of those outfits
show they will click she had him sign it
and she changed the back page of filing
with the course she's still practicing
on the state of Tennessee I'm sorry she
still has her losses
I don't think she's press so it was an
awesome case instead k small if you just
if you just Google climb kou maybe we go
there's a lot of good stuff up for me to
based on opinion but I join everybody
left on the story you want to ask a
question ever limit as R let it be using
linux about know what happens when your
targets are using look I don't have as
much so there's a there's a couple files
and the it depends on what I'm looking
for is what i'm looking for activities
commands and stuff like that there is a
hidden file in the root of each user it
shows all the commands the better you're
mainly looking at timeline stuff
linux and OSX is not as fruitful from an
activity perspective you're looking at
walks and you're looking a little bit of
activity you don't have windows
industry that's where i'm getting a lot
of the stuff from yeah there's not as
much there now minutes from when I our
side
yeah you know we can be pretty
successful there i don't think i've ever
encountered uses linux yes i did once it
has a real pain but i found one cast
webpages what they were looking for but
yeah it's about I don't enjoy minutes or
Mac actually I'm a Mac user and i can do
it i just know that the artifacts it's
not as fruitful and I'm afraid of
missing circle you're hoping that all
bad guys stick with the most haha sports
/ they're not bad guys they just did
that things don't we do it so if I'm
looking for photography or you know
things that they should be doing on the
internet I can still do the same
internet analysis i can still do keyword
searching is to town Line else's I just
don't have the windows registry is that
I've made and pointers and stuff like
that i have on windows it's just much
more proof your question how about
virtual machines if you really want to
be a bad guy getting rid of something
and to where no one's going to find it
even mr. robot have a virtual machine on
your device power of the virtual machine
do your website have a virtual machine
snap it power up the device to your bad
stuff refer to snapshot unless it's
going to records anywhere there's a
record that you reverted to snapshot but
there's not gonna be anything there many
times if you get an experience and
experience forensic analyst will
overlook you a video missed especially
if its virtual box or one of the others
it's not for you where they'll see the
prefix or something like what's that
just keep moving on there's only been
twice I've encountered that I've not
seen anyone do what I've just described
but on ya 3pm to be a real have a
desktop with 40 days for him and it's a
real you doing is a repurposed sir from
test like I'm sorry like a test lab yeah
well on the nineties but the tip that
question was going to be you could
create a virtual machine entirely and
never yeah but there's going to be
different with the other line OS unless
they're mens style esxi or something
it's like a windows video I'm going to
see the point or two that began to the
virtual thoughts even
vmware you're gonna have to load that
from you can't keep a ramdisk there all
the time you're going to load it from
some of this persistence with some
mystics problem is you don't have any
every time you shot that's everything
well I'm not trying to figure out how to
be your profession good Father's Day and
I'm trying to understand the limits of
what you're doing cause it's if you have
someone that knows whenever someone this
does digital forensics
yeah i mean even if you take that the
prefetch stuff does to me but if you
rename ccleaner dhc-2 nope ntsc unless
we're going to match up the ashes
probably not going to catch it so yeah
there's different ways you can get
around it but there's always gonna be
some slip up somewhere
yeah so there's less it may be something
very small but there's going to be a
slip-up somewhere because you can't be
that perfect all the time you don't pick
me up
all right now this was real quick
government contractors one got cfl with
the computer company computer company
start beating the model the kids and we
found that two days before he left he
uploaded the huge bandit and losing
because i can't see what's in the cloud
but i can see the activity in the
interactions with the cloud
this is a bit and i'm about to run a
tunnel site company are split is a
manufacturer of the device they got into
an argument one would start competing
company and the other ones staying and
somehow the competing companies
competing be new everything going on and
company yet and you know the president's
like yeah some people have bits and
pieces of this but I'm the only person
that knows everything that email note my
office so we call the full recipe is it
sweep the place and gossip nothing here
I don't do an awful he didn't may be
able to help you soon be off in the
afternoon and a couple of things but
nothing that was their assets in your
computer so this was after a sum of the
spyware and a reputation for being
upfront vs Power but what happened here
is that once i got it and started
looking i can see through user since
someone ran a tw6 so it goes
oh that's where watch it was funny about
that is on their website stated house
spyware is so still not even the NSA can
do work for me was previously mechana
saying I don't even need so i took a DVD
eventually friends again is converted to
a video is a must include up first thing
I did was reach out to data . when
watching better . com
so obviously didn't audit network
communications it was even HTTP not even
https something are its active it's
there
I know what's going on if I could just
add that to a person we've got something
so just using parts are core here
whatever you want to call it the top i
can see here I have the account RB I
have a computer and i have a login ID
someone have used a credit card number
to connect so I don't have something
about that time the FBI stepped in and
told I don't know what happened with it
but I had it too much and I have a good
relationship the FBI smoking fun but I
added this one on a silver platter and
this is what i call the Triple Crown
mirror so this dude internet talk about
internet insider threats this guy is
companies in California this guy was
fired from his company without thinking
it through and we work to help people to
have plants get rid your sowlaty person
they didn't follow any contacts what
they gave us a fire they disable his ID
account resetting the domain
administrator account and forgot about
stuff like 10 ppm log me in i was access
was removed on 124 two-and-a-half months
later guess it's kind of ticked at this
point someone connected into VPN went
straight to the main controller started
working on cracking passwords care
benefits of craft was the links 125
someone comes back into it installs b
and c est you because since they're
sensitive computers and CCTV systems
that have VNC start promoting and so
this person knew exactly where they were
going what they were doing
I'll I got fired 11pm to almost up to
so you can access it appears on the CCTV
must have more attention on
closed-circuit recordings like a month
there are six months
evenin deleted certain frames sorry
someone he or she may be started access
and bottoms like credit card and blow .
email because this person may be the
supervisor does the supervisors name
clearance data should be stored
clearance date anyway but he starts
accessing that bonus letters credit card
info scan documents he knows he or she
was around this stuff is it starts
access to joining someone connected back
into the computer recover the password
from the previous thing was being used
we don't have subpoena power so i don't
know all the other piece matched up I
know to give to the BPM marks they
access used-book mail from they had a
small business server so you got
everything is on that one server you
gotta change ID everything databases
that's what is connected to you she was
connected to use webmail to access the
Attic director's email and purchasing
manager say some previous credit felt
the pale he started placing online
orders you can see the owner's through
the web cache then start searching more
credit card info so you know you can
distribute the load so when you do that
little even if even a flywheel search
research and windows the registry keeps
that car credit car realize the season
truck has brought idea so the operating
system is on see everything else is on
deep databases exchange that's what
problems with their attention because
he's like I need to destroy the evidence
let our drops he wasn't responding you
can't format a drive that you're logged
into so he was able to format the drive
and the email they were able two weeks
but all these artifacts left on Sandra I
don't know whatever happens this when
they turn it over to the FBI last one
which is a good look from a global
perspective that means we can about the
hostage divorce this one with a stakes
so there's the suspected of better with
an executive he goes on vacation with
this payment and for some reason decided
to use the Sun ipad to continue a
conversation with his mistress
so as soon as he moved in with his
account and send her that first message
it downloaded the entire thread to that
happen to us son sees it is it small
alternate turn
with me because everything synced up and
so I didn't really have spent a lot of
time on this one to recover as you can
see you know it's tough you're not and
is this is heard that was talking to I'm
here just text me when you get here now
can I had to remove some of it because
it's being recorded
you're incredible was just thinking
about things talking to his betty was it
the same girl agree but officially
realize you're not 25 lots of fun from
Abby probably die because she's all that
told her a lot
all nighter but not in the office today
I'm tired today the game is find a very
tired
guess what he lost everything
any questions on only spawn story honey
honey I'm any questions on this is my
favorite moves a lot to resume finds
internet search history from that
evening you've got you off not allowed
to do it just makes it rather just
confess it or not I really appreciate
just how we have any questions or
comments or and you didn't throw the
ball one time which means i didn't BSU
it up after section enjoy help who you
with something of interest from your
sisters