and we going excellent so good afternoon
I am Christian network from sign
Cleveland Ohio and we're going to talk
today about the use of covert
communications in modern cyberattacks so
because first and foremost we're going
to talk about just is the fundamental k
communications that exist within the
full constructive attack and in both
i'll touch on a few different points
around command control and exploration
but really did a couple tenants I guess
before we get into that we remind
ourselves is when you look at these
types of tau communications the
operative is much like the Beastie Boy
slow and low and it's going to be don't
get caught right so there's going to be
automatic control in communications that
exists within you know different
elements of the attack they have to be
spaced out over several thousand seconds
potentially i mentioned before that
these types of channels are used for
command control and also exploration of
the cycling of get out of the
environment
the other thing we have to acknowledge
two is that when we look at the hackers
we look at some of these nation state
entities they're not wants they're
actually pretty smart people and they're
gonna do their best to conceal their
identity and hide in the rocket pop so
that's really a few tenants we're going
to talk about relative to his
communications so we look at the faces
of a cyberattack many of you heard of
early spread out studied in detail
around kill chain theory some of the
models that exist you know probably most
common is the Lockheed approach and
really there's there's a few elements
when you're looking at behavior and
that's what does that's a kind of you
know the approach that we take with
cybersecurity is around behavior that
network and we look at the life cycle of
an attack so when you look at just one
of the elements right there's a there's
a few phases one is around kind of this
opportunistic type of thread it now
think of rattling courthouse and you
know top 30 things you didn't know about
Donald Trump you go to one of those
click eight sites and it's just a
pockmarked and littered with different
you know click fraud add objects within
the site you may get infected with some
kind of Bitcoin mining or paper install
type of the you know you know piece of
code but the ones that are most
concerning is around he's targeted
threats and the types of threats that
usually resulting in a couple things one
of it
identifying propala organization so I
had the desire to break into your
company or your organization and really
the goal is to establish that position
on the inside network now i can take
advantage of Nancy and accounting center
a spear phishing email and know that
with a high degree probability should be
open it up
I'm a throw to the old tried-and-true
method of Thrones and USB keys in the
parking lot C with pickup rate is but
nonetheless we know that there's going
to be a position established on the
inside and then ultimately once i have
that position we're going to follow this
pace of events typically including over
Constance type of pattern on the inside
the network find out where the
high-value data Liz how to get to that
data is really privileged to the system
that does have access to it or
credentials that have access to it and
then ultimately how I get it acquired
and incited out-of-network so that's
really approached in my company takes in
terms of evaluating the faces of attack
especially when you're on the inside
network so just fill this out but really
the purpose of this conversation this
talk is around hitting communications so
when we look at command-and-control
customers
and control you know rats for example
where some of the techniques that modern
cyberattacks so let's talk a little bit
about CNC servers to begin with the one
thing we can be sure of is that the the
smart guys the smartest hackers out
there that are going to recycle and
reuse the same identities behind command
control structure what they'll do is
they'll rotate domains very frequent
basis so you'll have if you do who is on
one of their domain you'll see that it
was registered eight hours ago which is
a little bit sketchy you'll see that it
has no alphanumeric sequence within the
actual domain name that can be
pronouncing the language in the world
right so those are a few judges obvious
indicators that it's a little bit dicey
so we will see your domain generation
algorithms will also see the use of
tunnels right so protocols like dns that
they have some tumbling elements within
a also to the legitimate use of you know
what I guess a corporate environment
might consider is acceptable use gmail
example Google Drive Dropbox and then
ultimately to when we look at these
artifacts right in the reuse of just
domains and in IT spaces and other
elements of identity that increases the
chances of getting caught these boats
are going to do that but what we like to
do a vector as we evaluate our behavior
we don't get signatures we don't look at
and accept things at face value
ok you know it is what it is
no it's around behavior and when you
look at some of the artifacts and in and
contents within a behavioral sequence we
look at things that can change says such
as IP address such as URL protocol and
so forth
fundamentally the underlying behavior is
not especially when we're looking at you
know things like mad control it
things like exfiltration so you can you
can disguise something a hundred
different ways but on the wire is going
to be very truthful and we're going to
see that behavior the other thing too
that we also do with my company is that
our source of truth are network-based
packets we're not looking at system logs
are not looking at Flo's we're actually
evaluating the whole construct of the
packet and there's a lot of useful
material within the packet itself not
just the payload and in terms of files
could be leaving the environment but
also to around Cade's what is my what is
the how rigid is my communication
pattern in channel is it very 86,400
seconds on the . for example one you
know once every 24 hours words there is
a tier VIII somewhat of a client-server
relationship and then also too much
popular station and disguising oneself
hiding within protocols tamil within a
total type of thing so these are some of
the you know if you look at detecting
some beasts covert communications again
it's around looking at behavior so
really there's a few approaches that we
take the vector side is our product is
built around supervised learning and
unsupervised learning based algorithms
i'll give you an example of supervised
learning it's really a concept around
analysis of prior samples of malware
prior samples of data to build and
construct a model right so if you one of
the examples one of the algorithms you
use around corals so if we saw your
browser at university of louisville vs
want to jpmorgan chase they're pretty
much gonna be the exact same right so
that that would be an example of what we
would consider supervised learning it's
basically what we call local or global
learning meaning that we don't need any
local context or awareness of elements
to unique to your organization
on the other hand on supervises more
open with all local learning and
thinking about like authentication
patterns anybody work at a hospital or
working in healthcare system in this
room now
okay well so a large hospital they're
going to run three shifts right so
they're going to have you know employees
on staff and in authenticating
throughout the day and so when you see
three ships of authentication compared
to let's say a bank where take five that
profile is going to look a little bit
different so from learning in a
behavioral element the unsupervised is
going to be more globally significant as
we define these outlets so let's talk
about hiding within encryption right and
you know what will get up into a little
bit more about encryption and how and
how because this is kind of problem
space today in terms of visibility so
there's a there's a study out there from
sampai that suggest anybody read the
sorry well these familiar with it is
basically suggesting that this year 2016
was going to be seventy percent of
internet traffic is going to be
encrypted so that's not only going to
include you know the facebook traffic of
the world and they recently made that
change but also I malicious traffic is
going to be encrypted and that kind of
gives the attacker a little bit of an
edge in terms of you know concealing
what exactly they're doing with that
payload the good news is there's still
some evidence within the packet headers
that give us an indication of malicious
behavior is any up and then also to just
the whole concept around description SL
offload and when you look around as i
talked to my customers that's one of
these top of mine projects and ideas I
have so much encrypted traffic i don't
have any visibility now I need to start
thinking about something
project in that space and then also to
when you're looking at you know just
encryption and a hiding place for
attackers there's a few elements around
just the the actual session itself if
you think about a normal client-server
session usually the commands originated
from the client side they're the ones
commanding the server the server is
responding to commands and you can see
directionality as a relates to that
session with in SL session that still is
is is very true so you can you can see
directionality even in spite of
Christian so just a couple questions
guys are guys analysis up so number one
you guys just do you decrypt network
traffic or security inspection today
show hands
yes all traffic is a decrypted one some
traffic is selectively decrypted by
policy no traffic is decrypt I'm not
today but i'm planning the future
ok so that kind of gives us an idea that
you know one individual of about thirty
years actually
decrypting traffic sir if you don't mind
what I what industry are you in banking
okay that makes sense and is that
something that you are doing proactive
leaders at baseball policy is policy
ok catch up so . haga song when you look
at also to at the individual session or
individual love you know component light
this quote is from sherlock holmes with
it while the individual man is insoluble
puzzle in the aggregate becomes a
mathematical certainty and so when you
look at the math and statistics around
behavior you can put together patterns
even within you know encryption so if
you take a day of science-based approach
some of the models reveal some very
predictable things such as kids you know
is that is decadence and commute
education pattern between a
client-server very rigid predictable so
that's one element
the second thing is around the
rationality and losing control session
if it appears to be remotely controlled
from the outside coming in that's
another very good indication that
there's suspect later the third around
automation vs human-driven types of
sessions automation is very consider- or
if it's a very rigid set of instructions
coming back and forth exact same white
sequences is prevalent on the wire and
the experience itself that becomes a
very you know predictable indication of
you know the title you know encrypted
malicious behavior so those are the
types of things that we would look at
within these patterns right command
control instructions
what am I am remotely controlling
offending remember i'm an offending
party rolling controlling a machine that
i have a position on i have encrypted
tunnel in between that so I'm firing
down instructions on what I want this
individual next remote access for
example and then also to maybe it's a
dropper that's encrypted and firing down
our updates so that's really one element
around encryption the next thing is
around getting Thomas right so we look
at our friend for norton he discovers it
and you framed his way out of shape for
all intensive purposes it was a hidden
tunnel so what are hidden tunnels right
when we look at techniques you fight
attackers it's basically an embedded
tunnel within a accepted protocol you
know what are the common ones use DNS
right HTTP ssl so when you look at what
are the types of things that folks would
use within a hidden tunnel again it goes
in command control the instructions
right so I want
make sure that traffic is allowed out
from the perimeter firewall so therefore
i'm going to use a protocol that
everybody allows out dns and I'm gonna
bury my control instructions within the
actual name of the dns text field for
example the other thing that it's used
for is a exfiltration so if i wanted to
just piecemeal data out of the
environment that would be another use
case behind and title so i just touched
on this a little bit hit messages data
embedded within the dns text field at
this point I'm within the are RFC think
it's what 255 characters is allowed in
the text field you know it were just a
line allowing dns out then you know is
there a signature that can really
identify those patterns right it's going
to be you know kind of moving target and
then also to require some intelligence
around pattern so we just a little demo
here we show and be open water sure go
ahead and start so just as an experience
is you see that should enable
I just stupid ass look up will say
Google like how well try to use policy
outlining me give you an example of this
so if i do a standard look up on let's
just say Ohio . god I can see 72 bytes
in the request and i can see 88 response
if i do a gig on the same domain name
will see this quality record come back
as well as the MX record in the normal a
record right so I look at these are the
typical behavior that we would see in
dns queries for example is going to
follow very rigid pattern now I see a
dns all might look something like this
go ahead and find a hidden tunnel he get
this is this is a little unusual
so I see a query this actual domain name
go to the bottom I can see that the
length is to infinity two characters
which is very short of Max going to the
RFC and I can see this just sequence of
garbage right so what I see here is the
query going from the actual client who's
saying it off to the command control we
can infer that there is a program that
can be pretty or use this type of
information in return
CC is the response to my query now is
also 312 bites it's not normal like a
you know a 10 character or fewer type of
domain it's a much larger than my
response i can see here's my queries
response 328 bites so that the behavior
looks a lot different and you can
converge is based off of the tax people
then the dns query that its command
control or external type of behavior
so the other you know so HTTP is also
another example where we see this type
of behavior we see it in optional fields
within HTTP headers the river for
example that where there's not a mandate
to actually use any of those headers but
malicious behavior they do stop commands
into those headers for purposes of
control Rexville types of patterns
difficult to detect if you're using just
rudimentary security methods we also
have a we publish a report every six
months and it's basically a survey our
existing customers we allow our
customers to opt in and basically share
metadata actions that are hurting their
networks and really this is what we've
seen relative to hidden Thomas right so
we saw approximately fifty percent you
know command control and exploration
within SLA HTTP or HTTPS all mostly
exfiltration we saw some command control
and then with dns we saw all command
control so this is kind of an
interesting I guess sample set
I'm interested to see how that shakes
out you know the year-end and see how
are these lands but ultimately these are
types of tunnels that we do detect on
you think it's hiding within around
hiding within allowed applications
because any Walking Dead fans in the
room
yeah so we all know how the
you-know-what this model looks like
right you cover yourself with zombie
guts and you can kind of obvious
navigate amongst you know the allow dead
numbers so what's the use cases around
this is things like one Drive Dropbox
gmail what appear to be legitimate
applications that are permitted
I and organizational security policy
anybody hear about this one here we're
out this attacking this there's a piece
of command control malware that lived
inside of Google drafts folder i'm not
talking about that general that was
having an affair with some high profile
ladies need to exchange messages in
their graph older but basically what
this look like was there was a command
control session that was running within
the drafts folder of gmail and
effectively is this piece of malware
running on machine allow Congress
invisible internet explorer instance to
run within the machine itself and it was
sitting height on commands to pull down
you know what those next sequences are
so think about this right as you're
looking at a security approachin and we
have what filtering tools out there we
have you know email stand and everything
else attackers are using known good you
know types of applications out there to
effectively established rccnz habits
right in this is kind of aids that the
whitelist blacklist theory gmail is kind
of known good and now we get out of this
threat intelligence concept that you
know if I'm hiding within own good and
that kind of eradicate that will model
away at least it disproves that this is
bullet i know same thing there's others
instances where dropboxes uses going as
command control or some event with
the singapore that use dropbox so it's
again it's around identifying the
behavior not necessarily the name
species so there's a study out there i
think one of the statistics are that you
know somewhere between 15 to 18 thousand
new species or december every year on
the planet so that's roughly 40 to 50 a
day there's some studies out there
suggesting that there's almost a million
variants of malware malicious code that
comes out every day I didn't personally
can't qualify for qualified happen we
know it's somewhere between hundreds of
thousands upwards of $MONEY million if
we took that approach right so everybody
learned about you know can fill came
over great so we try to organize all the
days of classes of species on the planet
would be very difficult to do from
Albert perspective special that we were
taking the approach that we had a name
them all and then create a signature for
all of that so my database of you know
signatures grew exponentially by a
million per day that's something that I
can't scale so a better approach is
looking at the behavior now if I'm an
attacker or one of these guys and only
software factories up in Ukraine for
example my job is to write code and you
know rehashes to you know basically have
a threat intelligence speeds and I sell
that other people the behavior is going
to look the same but even though the
hash is different so that's really do
approach that we take and again we're
looking at what's actually happening go
to take into account this is gmail
command-and-control drafts folder type
of the situation there's some very
useful things that we can see the
Haverly rather than just trust it
okay i have infected eye holes that's
going to gmail therefore it must be the
gym so as a matter of
you know looking beyond the actual names
an ounce of the activity and looking at
the burbs
so in you know you have a footnote here
is it really matter if a scan originated
from a laptop tonight we don't
necessarily carry and . care about what
we saw
so again we saw and then just kind of
capitalize on this what we saw is this
type of pulling instructions and this is
an actual algorithm and detection of you
fire it's based on you know command
sending down commands and then the
offender the infected holes facing say
what's happening actually very
sequential rigid set of instructions
I'm sorry for getting up with seek it's
good to remove the slide together all
ask the question anyway I guess any
thoughts or comments around what do you
think poses the greatest risk would you
say consumer based applications out the
dropboxes the gmails and so forth about
cloud 80 us on ground about tools kind
of mixed bag
nonetheless though we know that average
degree continue ball and figure out the
next you know way to get going to use
techniques that eventually it's washed
out remote access Game of Thrones fans
anybody so you know so grand is the kid
is being
lifted up by this guy named hold or if
you've never seen the show and he's got
these really cool capabilities one of
which is what they call a war in the
show and that allows you to see things
through the eyes of an animal he also
has the ability to you know how to
shape-shift and you know actually jump
into other living creatures and noodles
and the prequel power to happen
effectively its remote control remote
access is able to remotely control
another living entity and so when you
look at remote access right you think
about rats do you think about tools like
VNC you think about tools like you know
just even using in and take advantage of
some of these administrative tools out
there is anybody secure their uh their
Island boards or even just their
management coordinator service server
guys in the room anybody worried about
just I love a security or even those up
management words mean you know again
these are all there's plenty of tools
out there to gain access to other
systems so when you're up the there's
good things to think about when you're
looking for remote access now we showed
you the kind of constructive an attack
by and large a lot of the elements are
fully automated so automatic controls
automated program three machine gets
infected he executes the payload and
then there's a an automated control at
some point though once I've applied you
know maybe some recon drive done a
number of different things on the inside
I found a vm that's in the lab it's a
patched and that's my my is inside
source that I'm gonna continue to go out
there and control control excuse me
eventually there's going to be a shift
wrong automation human hands on the
keyboard where the actual precision of
happening in acquiring data chips from
that automation to that
so it's you against this is concept
around you know hidden communication
what we see
so there's this last rat attack of this
class rat program that have a few years
ago was discovered by RSA and
effectively it was it was discovered in
China and he evaded AV tools invaded a
number of different techniques that all
the makings and characteristics of a rat
but using traditional security methods
it was largely undiscovered four . three
years you know so there's a nice little
ride of its uh you know probably a
20-page document that is on the RSA
website but effectively what they did is
they stole assert that was used by
legitimate you know entity a valid
certificate and then disposed of it once
they establish their you know the actual
drop around that . and it went largely
intact so again it's one of those things
that you have to look at what types of
technologies of eight signatures and can
still execute their purpose i'll say
that one more time business or bank
transactions and you know this allow
state you usually have that everything
while there
yeah good question are you guys heard
that it's kind of hard question but I
repeat the question was that you really
have to
was it one more time your previous labs
valid tiny offer happening
yes should you look at your service in
the star to the party
yeah I think that's a fair statement in
this case that happened within China so
she was trying on China crime which is
but yeah I would agree with that
statement
ok so i think we're near the end we're
going to talk a little bit on an
organization that if you notice that
shows on here that I like breaking bad
fans anywhere okay so we know that
Heisenberg remained fairly anonymous
even in the presence of is a
brother-in-law was DEA agent who knew
Heisenberg was he was related to
walterwhite and yet you know he was
still able to remain anonymous up until
the end of season 6 and all right there
again we know this is a technique that
we see relative to attack the behavior
so the common techniques is the use of
Torah here and that's really to disguise
your resource and disguise you know in
office gate where you originate problems
you may use this type of channel to you
know conceal your identity and something
that there's encryption involved there's
a there's customization ball by the
attacking entities and it's really not
you know it's it's an evolving and
ever-changing type of network so hard to
get Rob now there are things that you
can see and readily
identify the matter of perspective so
you know tor browser is very easy to
identify you don't want to fall a lot of
them use 9001 right so it's one of those
things that you can see this behavior
this type of channel occurring as it
relates to you know optimization so
worth the other thing too is uh when you
look at traffic bouncing around on the
inside so we have a detection called
stage transfer hot one and two and
that's basically you know concealing
where traffic is originating hurries is
bouncing through and basically what
we're looking for is a way out so you've
seen his type of pattern inside
I've captured and acquired high-value
data and my goal is to get outside of
the network you may see some of this
staging some of this transfer between
holes in order to explore tree design
data so last but not least i really
wanted to touch on the other pieces to
when there's a focus on identification
and in different patterns right it's
worth mentioning to that there's a lot
of non-human driven devices that reside
within a given Network anybody in
manufacturing and industrial environment
within the room so there's a study
within the plant floor that there's a 10
to 1 ratio of non-human devices such as
a you know plc or some type of you know
control that has an IP address is
attached to the network versus the
laptops of the human that the these
types of devices so it's worth noting
that when we look at behavior we should
just look exclusively at laptops or it
is exclusively at devices that were
familiar with there's a whole bunch of
weird stuff out there is getting an IP
address we did a little experiment
doctor throughout threat labs you can
locate about read up on this case study
but it's basically the ability to
deploy functioning backdoor the ability
to leverage things like infusion pumps
or other non-traditional devices as a
way on
so when you look at the hospital right
there's there's a couple interesting
things even like a university you can
freely walk in and out
nobody's going to really check to see
who you are gonna be a guest you can
just go start rolling through the the
hospital and there's really no controls
as to what you can and can't do
I mean now if you wanted to have social
engineer by yourself code even better
but for the most part you can walk in
and find a network jack within the
hospital you can find a device that has
the ability to solve back door on it
same thing with in you know university
is you just pose as a student or faculty
member
so the point being is that
non-traditional devices that have in the
way these things go right you think
about if I'm a hard-working hospital my
hire a company to roll out you know
10,000 fusion palms they're going to put
the same password on every single level
they're not authenticated the ad is
going to be default and we're going to
be very little controls their job is to
get the installation done as quickly as
possible now to secure the environment
so this is kind of the new set of
threats were looking at in terms of
command control in terms of back doors
and so forth and that sort of thing so
that's I up against it right now I think
we have a few more minutes but again
really what I wanted to touch on is just
a high-level summary of some of the in
command control types of sessions that
we can see in modern cyberattacks
hitting exfiltration where some of the
techniques that are used again a couple
things to look at behavior is very
relevant posts signature look at the
pattern and look at the case look at
where the session originates from
where's the control live
and also two packets or source of truth
right so short a very few
man-in-the-middle or package
installation techniques there is a lot
of integrity in terms of what those with
that source will yield terms of
forensics questions comments thoughts so
i'll be eight minutes back it really
appreciate you guys taking session