mark fisher I'm one of the organizers on
the rest were really glad he managed to
hang out with us all dates been there I
think a pretty amazing day I want to
thank the rest of the Coordinating
Committee there's Mike and mix around
here somewhere it's been huge working
with all these folks be says dilemma is
a very special they also want to give a
very big thank you to the red shirt team
from kiss you guys did a fantastic job
today I'll make sure Amy knows and you
like a little special extra note on your
next exam so so let's talk so I managed
IT security at Moorside hospital it is
the baby factory all right the people I
work for they do help care they don't do
IT security and yet it's my job to
essentially sell the program and as I
talk with people I realized we're not
good at this so take a moment examine
yourself right in our community people
see themselves in a lot of different
ways right and if you look within our
community we have these sub communities
and these sub-communities sometimes I
mean people who think aren't the cyber
hacker type right we all know these guys
and girls that they're just cyber
hackers right and in ninja lead people
some folks see themselves as a friendly
superhero out there to save the day and
be happy with the business and I just
I'm doing awesome today
and lastly we have the economic last
it's the person that no one understands
in deep in his heart he has desires to
rule the world right generally all of us
fall into one or more of these things
but the problem the issue is is the
people of business that we deal with
don't see us the way we see ourselves
they see us as wizards and explain we
dress funny right we really do we have
strange implements that do bizarre and
amazing things that they don't
understand and most importantly we we
have women in our community who are
generally smarter faster better than the
guys kick ass harder but always the
second building what is up with that so
this is me well talking about again
touch with me one thing I do the
Southern Fried security podcast the
number one atlanta-based information
security podcast Andrew nothing personal
and I'm something I'm really proud of
that Johnson this year who's also on the
podcast in she's actually supposed to be
doing interpretive dance right now there
it is see ivette if you want like a
stickers we have those so shall we begin
and let's let's talk through this thing
so the first thing that we need to do is
get rid of this language that we use
amongst ourselves which is really
effective and really efficient the
challenges is that when we turn around
and use that with the people in the
business it sounds like this take a
moment I know I'm crossing multiple mean
things but this is how we sound to the
business right which causes them to look
at us with this expression on their face
right and in the past that was okay
right if you've been in information
security for a while there were the days
when the business just threw metric
boatloads of money at us to make
problems go away and we said magic words
right hey we bought all these shiny
boxes that blinky lights right and had
engineers questionable personal hygiene
that managed to Donald A Center didn't
work so how do you fix it all right you
need to be able to explain the processes
and the technologies we use to your
organization in ways they understand the
number one way people learn and if
you're a parent you know this it's by
analogy so I've been health care right
so I had a conversation my second week
at the hospital talking about signature
antiviruses we were about to do a pretty
substantial renewal with their signature
AV company and not my CI to but my co is
that I read an article that said it
wasn't worth it why are we doing this I
have a great chief operating officer and
I use this city rabies at the flu
vaccine you know it works great for the
strings they planned for it but the
other strings that have mutated out not
so much this year's flu vaccine is only
about fifteen percent active fifty
percent effective against the majority
of the strings that are going around
does that sound like the antivirus that
we actually put on our end points so
also use real life as an analogy that
was asked on a previous deploy what
intrusion detection was all about and
it's like a gate guard right she'll look
at the cars coming through and she'll
follow the procedure but you know so
what it really wants to get past the
gate guard they can isn't that right
error so what do you have to do is well
if you're going to communicate
effectively with the business please for
all that is holy if you only hear one
thing today hear this you must fight the
urge to prove you're the smartest person
in the room this is the number one
cardinal sin all of us you included do
on a regular basis and we doing in the
center community and that's okay right
because there's this one-upsmanship we'd
love to do to each other right and
that's okay right you start doing this
with you know the HR director or the
supply chain people and you're not
seeing as as someone who's fun to be
around haha your look you're a dick
right the next thing we need to do is
reduce the amount of fud in the
environment right and i'm looking at
vendor time so recognizing there's about
to be the most r AG episode of the
podcast ever that we're actually we
recorded a commercial for a new movie
that's going to get released on maple
first and that will be in the next
episode let's face it we start talk
about harp leave in shellshock and
poodle and free in all this other crap
that's in our environment the media the
mass media is picking it up in our
business people are seeing it right it's
completely unfiltered it's ninety-nine
percent utter bull crap and what's
happening is some of us are wondering
Wow my boss is scared the CFO is scared
eggcellent
I build new IDs coming on yep don't
don't do that so what should you do
because if the end of it if you keep
doing this you've known another murder
remember she just wanted bitched and
whined in the bathroom all the time and
no one went to go talk to her except
harrying that they're a bunch of times
something yeah okay but no one wants to
be around this person ever so what do
you do we're the coolest things to the
health care is me this concept called
the sbar where's carpinello left it used
to work for me all right as far as a way
the in health care when patients are
being transitioned from one location of
care to another for example out of the
back of an ambulance into the emergency
department when the shift changes on a
med surg floor they talk about the
situation what's going on with the
patient the background how did we get
here an assessment an unemotional
assessment and then a recommendation of
what what you have to do to deal with
the patient I actually had a my team
where you they let CJ got it going yeah
I see what you did to me I'm having my
folks do this this is how we talk about
information security line horror it's
amazing how you take all of the stupid
hype out of the conversation by going
situation background assessment
recommendation and if you do talk
specifically this way to hear your your
business leadership if you think through
it this way you start becoming
incredibly credible right Annie
um in health care we frown on smothering
people with pillows so in my environment
good and we'll talk more about that in a
second you're getting ahead of me
alright the next thing we have to do is
we had to realize what our mission is in
information security this this Dilbert
makes me cry and laugh at the same time
because how many of us have worked we're
working for or with or had someone like
more tact work for us I have how'd it
was a fired more deck it was awesome so
you need to be able to get context right
you need to be able to talk to the
business in terms they understand so if
you don't get invited to the meetings of
the business anymore they avoid you what
you they seemed come into the hallway
and like guys are going in the women's
restroom to get away your hand or your
emails just go out to the ether you
might be that guy nobody likes that guy
how many of your the Phoenix project
remember John the BIA in the book don't
be John don't be John so let's talk
about goals and objectives for an
information security department again
I've run the information scrubbing
Northside Hospital we generate more new
people in our building than any other
hospital in the United States except one
parkland regional Dallas Texas 25 to 27
thousand babies a year come out of our
moments are it is awesome alright so we
have three hospitals 154 different
locations 13,000 employees tens of
thousands of biomedical devices these
are windows ce e devices windows XP
devices that are connected to machines
there
two people so given what you know and
you've been all to you you're all cas
ESPYs right what is the number-one
mission of the information security
program yeah they've heard some people
put the speech before it's ensure
patient safety when you come to my
hospital when you come to my cancer
center when you come to my Brady ology
clinic or you're just visiting your
family doctor you're not coming there to
get hurt by a malfunction infusion pump
a badly acting x-ray machine or a
computerized physician order entry
system that can't dispense the correct
prescriptions right there's this concept
in medan healthcare called Sentinel
events I'm even referred hospitals like
amputating the wrong leg we're moving
the wrong these are Sentinel events
right and they're huge my goal my number
one goal is to protect patient safety so
what's number two well some people who
work for me in the passage cancers
what's number two seriously in case you
gotta vote for that what else data
privacy all good answers all wrong fine
next is quality patient care so I don't
want you to get hurt or killed that's
number one but I also want the quality
of the patient care for the two almost 2
million encounters a year that we do at
Northside Hospital to be less than what
that caregiver needs them to be I cannot
put the security environment between the
person the physician the mid-level
whatever caregiver between that position
and you do you want a host ids system
between the positions decision to treat
you and your kid if you do d faxes just
that was true love is about it you don't
want that so then number three ensure
the security of sensitive data so i
actually breached this to our directors
meeting and when I through the golden
from one of those ensure patient safety
there were audible gasps because they
were assuming that I was coming in as
the brand new security guy to preach
fire doomed damnation and destruction on
them the talk about PCI HIPAA all the
things all the cybers right but on that
patient safety so when I start talking
about patient safety i talk about
information security in the context of
patient safety one the immediately
simmons trap that's not because I start
making we we make decisions knowingly in
northside that if you are on the outs
it's you're reducing your security
posture maybe I am but I'm getting out
of the way equality
impact on the quality patient care and I
that means other compensating controls
I'm going to turn on to make up for it
now we return you gain credibility
because your goals and objectives are
aligned with the goals and objectives of
business this is exactly physicians care
about right there's no card more
powerful deploying health care than the
patient safety card now how does that
work for being so some of you may have
heard me rant about biomedical devices
now biomedical and scada systems are
very close kissing cousins so just give
you a sense of how things work we talked
a little about you siiii devices XP
devices that are attached to people
there are brands of infusion pumps and
these are the pumps that are connected
to multiple vials which go through it
does chemotherapy for people
chemotherapy sessions can last anywhere
from 90 minutes to four and a half hours
these are XP service pack 1 machines all
right embedded there's no ed there's no
security controls on them what so ever
so how many of you are red team people
or pen testers okay you get it on
network on a segment what's the first
thing interview scandals their use by
the XP service pack one machine right
your eyes wide a little bit right your
eyes dilate you get a little bit moist
up in the armpits you're like I had
white 16 gazillion exploits I haven't
had a chance to use in like seven years
you line them up you hit the metasploit
button I use the tactic and you have no
idea was a confusion right but you just
dumped four hours of chemotherapy drugs
into a person
minutes what just happened you killed
somebody because you're eatin and why
wasn't your intention your intention
wasn't to the domain controller right
though that's the that's the thinks of
when I talk about biomedical devices
being patient safety issues I'm gaining
a huge amount of traction inside the
environment because it's scaring my
leadership it's scaring my positions
because they get that right I hate that
scenario out they get it and we are
making huge investments to fix this
problem so what do you think now I know
some of you are probably thinking
bullshit we are information security
people we hear about confidentiality
integrity availability I have a cissp on
my wall that says so I know this because
I interview people for positions on my
team who essentially tell me that none
of them worked for me right what I'm
saying is that some of these people want
to be the cyber ninja they want to be
the friendly superhero they want to be
the iconoclast and they can't imagine
themselves in any other role the
challenge is they're wrong the days of
being able to have a successful career
in information security and being the
superhero the iconoclast the cyber ninja
are over can you get a job doing it
absolutely will you ever be a manager or
director or a see so nope not anymore
the muggles need us okay they really
really do they need our help we need
their money their staff and their
ability to run our organizations
effectively because I would be dressed
if you should have a look at the way
this conference got organized
information security people should not
run organizations okay seriously so you
have a choice do you go to the nurse I'd
do you keep trying to be a cyber ninja
do you keep trying to be that calm
unless the iconoclasts are really the
one the scare me all right or do you
realize as a wizard your job is to be
able to talk to muggles in ways they
understand and help them now my hope is
you joined this band you come on this
journey I'm taking me and my folks on
because this is going to vary your time
an information security for years when i
first got us CISOs complain what we
don't have a seat at the table but
business doesn't listen to us it is true
really well guess what they do now I
meet with my CEO of every month for two
hours all right I have a seat at the
table a lot of my peers have a seat of
the table unfortunately too many of my
peers have no idea what the flippity do
with it all right because they're still
in super hear about or worse their
counter class okay this is me if this
resonates with you I would love to talk
with you more about it more importantly
if this doesn't resonate with you I want
to know who you are now if I ever see
you posted on John
I can simply move it to the other side
because this is the path of information
security home forwarding it really is we
can't be what we've been to the outside
world now internally we are a messed-up
family right and I wouldn't have it any
other way right but when we start
talking with the people out there we
have to talk to them differently so with
that thanks very much we have a little
bit of questions
I so I joined I joined Northside about
10 miles ago before that I spent three
and a half years at wellstar health
system here in town prior to that my
experience with the health care system
was taking my kids to pediatric Edie's
that's one of things you have to learn
is everyone's mission is different for
Gil i'm looking at Andrew and Phil right
there there in a totally different
industry and the business mission is
different than mine but knowing the two
of them they're aligning themselves with
the mission of the business that's what
you have to do there's another question
over here and yes
but you're you're on the phone with help
higher education right so there's sort
of its balance in healthcare week
between education right quality
education and spirit across the cap oh I
only know one person has it worse and he
is the C so for emery so he's got the
university and he's got a hospital
yeah so again the whole time at the end
of it is you look at the institution
right and you look at what their goals
and values are right and you have to map
what you're doing to that and if you're
and if your top two three missions don't
exactly near the organization's you're
just you're disconnected right and
you'll never be able to get the
credibility of attraction in the
collaboration you really need want and
deserve yes sir when terms of medical
being a regulated professional medical
side and not have a regulation do you
find that so let's top so questions
right a bit though well not regulated as
you get so here's a challenge most of
the regulations to health care to go
toward the privacy confidentiality of
data points and most healthcare
providers I think are doing a horribly
reasonable job the challenge is the
thing that I'm most worried about in
biomedical is regulated by the FDA the
FDA's drive for a
places to marry recently was efficacy
does the device work in India sterile
environment can you guarantee it will
hurt somebody and that's why yes well
hospital environments are not sterile
not even he is past the challenge and
the FDA is working with the National
authorized that joining them working
group to talk about how do we harden
problem is there are literally millions
of them in place right now that can't be
upgraded can't be patched they cost
literally trillions of dollars to
replace and most your community health
care providers do not have initial
wherewithal even if new heart of ice
that were available that could afford a
replacement I meant more like from the
Magnetic respect though they beginning
to talk from the people side medical
side are they being the top doctors
about the importance of the spidery I'm
sorry listeners to the question yes
those conversations up so the questions
the conversations are happening with
physician leadership in my world we
talked with positional years and
explaining them what's going on their
physicians or it is naturally more tuned
to technology and they get
interested in it some of them don't it's
like any organization where they
generally all get concerned is there are
certain aspects of compliance where
physicians are held individually and
severally liable understanding of the
malfunctioning of a device is not
not right now pleasures with the XP
service pack 1 embedded devices can we
share what we're doing no we have NDA's
in place with a couple of people but my
goal is to by the end of the year be
able to actually publish something other
questions sir leadership role imagine
any other oh yeah here's something did
you guys know that XP service pack 1
embedded is still supported by microsoft
you can still buy stuff with that yeah
don't sweat it it has a 15-year
appreciations head
so the overall I think the way in the
end we come here we're going to do is
much like if you ever talk with Tom
Wilson this team from the Southern
Company the way that they're protecting
the SCADA systems and the nuclear plants
is you essentially create a separate
control network that is completely
access control as secure as you can
possibly make it that's where all those
devices live they have an administrative
network for the rest of it end of day
that's how things are having to work
with us because we just can't replace
all these devices other questions it's
fantastic thinking all right so what I
want to do Chris you have CFP results
CFP CTF alright so we've already been
talking about CFP for the next be sides
of the land that's why I've had it over
so