are you all right we should be good to
go because you can stand up owning the
easier it is for everybody and everybody
else last time the last year and down
the west and think that you're
interesting that that that choice was
made because the last several months
malware is actually kind of exploded
especially in the news maybe you were
paying attention to the news for our get
some of the some of the higher-profile
want to highlight here first the one
that just that came out very recently
because the NSO group selling iphone 0
days now I'll go ahead and give a cot
iphones security is closely time to OS
10 security will see why in just a
second edition that kind of wet your
appetite a little bit for ruts what's
there so we have a penis that group 0
day for iphones we also have well also
have a key ranger and a few other like
well known here we go up taking malware
vulnerabilities basically this talk is
kind of what you need to know as far as
not just what's out there but also the
vulnerabilities that exists within
the list n itself now I'm not going to
release the 20 days right now but you're
seeking to secure a even from your home
all the way through a business there's
maximum network this is the information
that you're probably going to need to
know to go back to my slides though
security engineer by day research
security 9i particular work on
large-scale systems so it's not it's
entirely security-related although we we
have security stuff that flows through
the system the real design part in the
research partners is already beginning
because i recently got my few limbs that
happened kinda simultaneously I don't
want mother to change to the less than
downloading these mods for games and
both of those kind of making really
nervous and I started thinking about
like what
whoa i can recognize a malware
installation or malware infestation on
window system and I would know
relatively where to go look you know are
older and registering stuff like that
but when i go to look when it comes to a
mac system and that's pretty much with
this is boring
lots of research went into all that so
one thing that kind of jumps out of us
well most of you probably use all i want
my $MONEY and the title talk was
exciting row and Peter dangerous because
max domi viruses right yeah i mean yet
we laugh and obviously going to disprove
that but the reason why that's important
is because um up until $MONTH 2012 cells
actually sold max own website one of the
features was
max don't get easy- still backing the
mac vs pc it and will bother advertising
now they changed it since 2012 to say
max are secured by design
they don't have the grandiose claims of
maximum viruses and the reason for that
is flashback came out in $MONTH 2012
controls and thousands systems soon as
they came out social engineering was
used as far as getting people to install
flash plugin this is still that max
didn't have flash plugin is
pre-installed and just so the one of the
major avenues for attack format right
now is ask that you not that people are
going to need that they're going to go
hunting for so flash plugins or job
stepping out now these things get
unfairly blamed lot of times I flashes
case they were insecure but anyway in
this case it was a social engineering to
get the flash plugin installed and it
generated revenue through well as so one
thing to take away our right Alice
rather immature and most of them just
add we're so this one generated revenues
were just displaying ads a key thing
that that dumb and two points to it one
it contained advanced features that
weren't used it was actually stubs and
home that researchers that and they
could have added a lot more features to
Adam community truly bad room kids back
doors all the stuff that was a modular
application but it didn't have those and
the second thing is weirdly
sophisticated just for ad where I'm
going to be the case throughout this
talk that
the iOS platform and while the phone and
the laptop the laptop is the staging
ground for what goes on
it's targeting the poem so and there's
several reasons for that
so anyway then we have a flashback part
to 2014 and this is um so in tako
company called intake Oh bought these
sinkholes that work from the first
flashback when they were looking for is
how many people remain unaffected as
time goes on
the good news is it was only about
twenty thousands of people that remain
totally lost access singles
the bad news is there's still 20
thousand so Matt doesn't good travels a
good job pushing people to update soon
as he comes out and they really you know
nice interface for that but they still
some of the same problem windows servers
which is not everybody days systems
fascination best they should in fact how
many of you have updated your iOS
devices to latest 935 no one especially
after I go through the what that means
as far as the updates but we'll get to
that in just a second so flashback part2
must researchers considered a nobody
view because it's covered in another day
and so you just update your device and
your final but um i would submit that is
still a big deal because this shows
activity and flashback part 2 was not
just residual flash they were actually
iterating on that design going forward
so this one in one of them so there's
lots of different flash flash back part
two is really just a catch-all for the
different barriers that came out after
the first one and the variance of some
of the variants were job so long
you saw a lot of Apple morning John lat
no java and java is there were some
vulnerabilities passel however some of
it was just they were taken off guard so
right around our apples taken off guard
because people are updating the software
and there's there's this vulnerable
space so one yet drive-by downloads
blaming job on that and then the last
event that I'll talk about the dream and
the setup this is key Ranger released in
February 2016 believe it was the first
os10 rain somewhere and it was delivered
through signed application so did not
say to so that was worth noting its
signed application so it was well the
fake versions of flash version of Java
not necessarily signed actually the
unpatched b vm that really was
yeah that was assigned out so key Ranger
first os10 ransomware delivered this
year i just saw a couple of days ago
there's another variant on key Ranger
that's just come out so all that to say
is that forgiven all that malware is on
the rise it down
it wasn't slow through the years ago a
200-year now we're seeing about 10 day
and it's nowhere near the volume windows
of a windows mountains you see but you
think the macs are completely in the
clear or not
now that said I'm going to kind of take
her that I don't want to to say that
maximum clearance still have all my iOS
devices and then OS tens but let's go
through the unique attack you are
securing a system and you just want to
make sure that URL your family's here
you're secure first you're gonna have to
know what is it about Apple that makes
it different fundamentally prolly
windows system and there's basically
four different areas that have come up
with
there's the boot up process the caramel
is the way that software install and
something called macho which is the
binary format that uses name is anybody
know the native format for windows of
the time you're in fact executable 32 so
and that's interesting because as we go
into blue process in the beginning every
so Apple security rises and falls on the
move process especially on the iOS
device so I'm going to sew an
abbreviated boot sequence with being in
power the device on and in ages past it
was the bios that was the first thing
that was giving him and now it is
something called the efi the extended
mom I forget what you have my stance but
even that's the equivalent of the bias
in most of the species that's what
handles running so ef5 was developed by
Intel and oddly enough it runs packed
executable learning to either Susan so
all of your iOS devices actually run a
windows executable in order to reboot
the whole myself now it's just a p38
it's a small file however if you can
take control of that file and you can
take control everything but because of
that Apple is really really concerned
about making sure that their food of
sequins is as secure as possible for
instance your own well if I sits on a
fat32 partition you usually don't see it
um this is where your firmware
protections are so I'm on your iOS
device you've got a pass code before you
can get into your advice this boot
sequence is what throws up the password
spring first you log into that persist
the past
back through the term so the efi system
is really important to handles the disk
for the if you have a whole disk
encryption solve all so you can kind of
really stressing that this is the most
important part of though especially iOS
been process the boot process is also
one handles when your battery's dead
you plug your power cord him BF is one
handles living the pictures back for
that it's booting that is charging and
then it also runs another application
once it's gotten to a certain charge and
flips it over to actually putting your
entire system so if you're wondering why
it is as you type in your password but
you still haven't letting before you get
into your system that's because the
system has an action booty just went to
the EF is part you were put into
provincials and it still has to go
through the rest of the boot process we
haven't even touched the curly and after
the boot process after fi did we go down
to loading the colonel
that's where kernel extensions are
loaded and that's also where dynamic
libraries are loaded
these are those of you who are
programmers pretty much all softwares my
these dynamic libraries include things
like coconut framework is used on them
well it's used on both OS 10 and iOS but
in the boot process you can know
especially when iOS because of the
limited down networking all that they
will reload whole bunch of libraries
that's important because if you control
these libraries pretty old system one of
the preloaded libraries is the image
processing library that's actually what
934 date supposedly just so this is
where this becomes important when it
comes to taking control system now
before I go too far in the efi section
here a list
pi star and rebel efi so back Jones
the most was the idea is I halls install
android that actually have the idol is
going to look at other still pictures
are there so some people that down still
keep one around for sale by now but that
kicked off an entire row of that that's
where the jailbreaking the anti
jailbreaking everything else is out now
the pi-star vs rebel efi revelry and
finds a company that came pi star was a
company that started up and they wanted
to take this was around the same time
also with devices disease in phillips so
i started this bright idea we're just
going to call it is that boosts the
system is the ER fine already has to do
is get control to a two girl and was
Colonel takes over and does all of these
do so they decided to write a young a
bootloader efi just to get that horrible
harbor whole 80s days that alarm so
these guys entire company just for
selling a caution when all the way
through up to the Supreme Court and the
Supreme Court ruled that the bootloader
is copyrighted and this is why your iOS
device that's why they're able to resist
in jail breaking details now because of
this rule so as long as this ruling
stays in place they control the entire
stack of the iOS lies not always not
here on the laptop so that's where the
difference as far as boot loading begins
and yes this is important because if
Apple can guarantee everything from boot
through the colonel for the iOS device
then a lot of these other security
practices that they have in place
hello you can be sure that they're
giving you good in
fashion not possible get them and sing
it um the boot process also handles
launch d which we'll get into a second
launch d is the America everything that
auto starts on Mac starts to launch the
launch T is the Indian of the mornings
work so everything runs the subsurface
watch the launch day loads were called
keyless files that's either xml when
they could be compiled a list that
usually are filed but you're on your own
is 10 devices laptop they're usually
just plain text which means you can just
came to go and see what they're doing
this is one handles regularly getting
jobs and also handles pretty much any
loading know Kate x kernel extensions
also drivers so any of that stuff goes
through launch T well usually specified
a meatless so another another aspect of
this in the mood is the firmware dma how
many have you heard the firmware DNA
came out several years ago
yeah so it's interesting how many of
these vulnerabilities exist and then
there's there quietly patched and anyway
max max security usually get some get
swept up in the lab so for whatever it's
worth so the firewire dma to make DNA
for direct memory axles so fire by our
standards as the firearm can just read
and write memory on whatever device is
connected to which is an obvious problem
so the this this is also what's could
also be going concern are considered a
later time but max solution that was
when the device boots up if it has a
password set then direct memory access
is denied
if the device if the device is already
booted up then you connect something
like a firewire to it that you do
whatever
want to now if the device is already
booted up in your realm they usually
have other controls and the way so it's
not as bad as anything but another
aspect of this is when you're charging
your device connected through the itunes
and you're sinking your device and all
that the route the boot process plays a
role there to move on and kinda want to
get through the colonel real quick its
kind of dense but I want to get to the
the package application stuff like that
but so the colonel is another attack
surface interesting note about this the
OS 10 colonel in some this is the logo
with the lowest in curls zmu but most
people don't
it's not distinctly map it's actually a
hybrid of armed well bsd which can be
considered like the new interface
deposits interface and then there's a
much a mock Colonel the mock turtle was
developed at nest if you remember your
Apple history child goes over the next
next is really awesome technology
including my they also know they also
had a precursor to use xcode and a bunch
of little stuff they split some I was a
Michael wedding ever heard of a
microkernel microwave so there's
basically two you have a model with the
colonel that handles all the device
access or micro girl that split into
multiple pieces
the problem with a microkernel yeah
the problem with a micro level is that
you have a bunch of pieces that are also
their memory and they're not tightly
integrated like they're not all in the
same address space
impossible minor ones when past messages
all these other places and so the whole
system doesn't fail in one piece sales
so if your device does something crazy
and it writes memory the wrong wedding
entire drug down however the problem
that you run into my girls is that being
really slow so apples been lobbying
hearing facing that problem it's really
good that the idea is academic sound
problem is in the real world we don't
really we're not willing to wait for
advices and just a problem that is more
secure so it's because of these
compromises that some securities laws
and have come on and there's really good
presentations on a lot of these
securities laws and I have links to him
towards the end so I run over this stuff
while i'm talking but overall there's
and outs later the last aspect is the
macho format it's similar to elf but the
biggest difference L being the the
binary format one is using native
natively but the biggest difference is
native code signs for this means that
dumb some other random trivial details
the magic bites border cafe babe which
is the same as the java class by which I
think kind of fueled view between that
apple and job of some great because it's
aggravating the binaries contain the
same magic the real immoral figure was
so the fact that they the fact that
macho supports cosine name one is a
fundamental piece of OS 10 security so I
mean you're trying to developing
applications
groans 10 or islands
anybody getting similar cultural change
I don't applications for Android and I
released for android to the playskool
battlezone so recently androids place or
hostile action free you release it all
three anything aapl.o last chance but I
dollars and I used to get really why
$100 the reason is because in order to
run anything on iOS device it has to be
signed by Apple themselves so they can
restrict their that's why can't decide
anything else I was less remember since
they controlled Boone they control
everything below it
they could do the same thing for almost
ten but most of us use our backs room
most of us install third-party
applications for mac although they're
moving in that direction for OS x
version of OS 10 mac OS is going to have
not only so in the mac OS now are always
doing now cosine is when wired or is
turned on by default him to explicitly
disable that no that's an analyst so so
much of format was designed to work with
that much
Colonel and inside of it has some pretty
solid engineering principles but dumb
course the performance problems plagued
it for a while one of the things that
they came up with two to bypass some
that performance problem was the concept
of ports and they're not networking
boards and it's not even really
important in the sense that your own
communicating well you're communicating
but it's not over wireless is in
internal communication
and the idea is that what am I macho
binary you can request a service you
performed by somebody so I masked design
and you said internal mass in the girl
says I have the ability to handle that
here is a hole into my memory space you
know go do some recent vulnerability
that was actually released at the black
hat issue last year was basically d
Dawson the colonel in this kernel and
have one of those folks and then of
course if you provide the running
program looking in your code program so
these are like native vulnerabilities
now i have not seen malware in a while
take control of that but like come on
you know that where it's what you don't
know that's gonna bite you
so other interesting things about macho
format is that it supports natively
universal binary format and up until two
virgins back os10 there were some traces
of powerpc code that was still bundled
in the bottoms just kind of weird
because I haven't sold those in a really
long time
another aspect of macho is the notion of
resource board best way to describe
resources like how many windows
environment plz provide certain
resources that always moving out and I
was the most awesome example similar
thing exists for 40 instead with the
exception that no s10 everything can
have resource force is actually a native
thing that supported by the filesystem
it's supported by the the OSL
pretty the software installation so when
I first transitioned over to Mac the
installation process was really a google
i found to be aggravated because I was
used to there's a full install program
it puts things on the disc and you know
where it needs to go and then usually
usually windows programs can uninstall /
and injection to put all that Kalyn
there's that nice add remove programs
well the difference in Mak is
applications are just minors or the most
common thing that you'll see in your
applications folder our application
bubbles is really just a folder . have
extension natively Mac loves working
with archives that's actually supported
transparently in the journal of a bunch
of different compression formats dmg is
one of the rate of it basically an iso
file that you can mount your Mountain
event from the system that's why these
towns show up and go to install stuff
and then you drag that over into the
applications all you're doing is
overriding whatever was there so some of
the problems with dmg is that there's
there's really no magic bites to
determine whether files
OMG for those of you doing network
security and you really want to find out
fast what type of files being that one
the bad news is for the dmg the only
spec is the last 512 bytes of the file
will have is cody KO something in the
last 512 bytes file so you would have to
go through the entire final just to get
into the variant and see if it's dmg now
the way I've gotten around as most dmg
impact as gzip files and so will get to
ya
most of my packages of file so dmg is
natively compressed because it would
impress also supports native encryption
fact when you go to update your iOS
device
what you're doing is you're downloading
and angie and in the system is basically
. into that dmg as the amount . the next
time the device boots up so when you see
the updating mac OS whatever it's coming
from a dmg file now the closest would
get to an installation program in the
Apple world is a PKG PKG our DM jeans
wrapped with aim basically scripts so
there's a bill of materials involved
there give you an idea about the second
so its native pkgs are usually natively
compressed as our format that some by
spec it doesn't have to be as are so
those are as they must be able to use
tar and Jesus together largest combined
bolo collection travel and the last
common way to install applications
through app store which is doing the
same thing the others are except their
song and enforce code-signing down the
law
so now we have sufficiently pointed out
how may be wrong that I want to dial
this back because this doesn't need to
be a code Rick most of us within the
business that our iOS devices best
advice was generally secure and they are
and here's the things that Apple's tried
to do so the bootloader which enforces
apple's walled garden there is the young
firewall system that that is what
protects the whole disk encryption this
is what also if you have a password set
on your device and i encourage you to go
in boot device in the mains put at least
put a password on because that blocks a
whole lot of threats like the direct
through the direct memory and direct
memory access also works some other
physical access issues for your iOS
device in blocks plug-in you know that
evil plug attacks and why aren't we in
today
about the charging station out there a
possibility that being equal flugtag
having a password on your device would
actually mitigate that especially your
iOS device
um of course Apple was one of the first
ones to provide a SLR address space
layout randomization everywhere on all
every part of their system whereas with
others it was kind of slowly roll down
over time there's was almost a sea
change overnight
everything is AIS our gamekeeper which
macho binaries also have what are called
filing file attributes this is part of
the filesystem and sell each file and
have any number of attributes most of
them only have a handful of so-so
gatekeepers when you download on yet
when you download an application of
binary from the internet is tagged as
this game in event and then gatekeepers
what is what throws of the dialogue to
say you download the internet will show
you when i run it and you probably see
more you can just double-click on it
especially in safari have to go find it
right click on it and open it and it's a
behavioral thing but these are the types
of protections that are going on the
background another one that's there's a
file quarantine works along with gate
gate keeper x protect there's actually a
hash lookup service in OS 10 um where
are you
so a lot of these viruses the reason why
so there's the 600,000 and after that is
what spurred apple on to quickly put out
all of these pieces so a lot of the
virus show you towards the interior that
you should still an eye out for they
don't have the penetration is the first
one because Apple themselves can
remotely convicted hashes so X protect
and then what's coming up next is
Sandman sandboxing this is already baked
into the Cardinal they're still working
out some bugs
that basically containerization in the
Apple environment in applications that
are installed via the app store are
running sandboxes so it's not just that
is signed and that's another part of it
is another built-in protections
application signed it's really hard to
get somebody's cosine although that is
something that has has happened as well
so last part Application Firewall apple
has its own eating any code that is
installed that is not sign is subject to
the application firewall and if it
thinks that your application is doing
some battle for example if you're
running intelligent you're writing an
application you're trying to run it run
it on the privilege pours over 5,000
think or know below 665 yet then it
complains about that
however if it's signed a lot of those
restrictions of all the way and that's
why Mac malware now seeks the most
attractive target is assigned
applications with developers are
careless keys so with that I want to go
over the stone survey of mac malware and
this is the popular back mount where
this is the type of stuff that you'll
run into when you are i think my
daughter comes to these are the types of
things that I'm worried about actually
being our system
mackeeper is the number one arm because
the number one attack vector is
developers and don't have a tight
control over their security there cosine
practices companies that are kinda shady
in the first place that keeper they're
going to be the number-one target an
hour so they come out with a lot of
press release mackeeper is action
company but they come out press releases
thing that people just
you know in tarnishing the name and
release in malware under the name is not
then the reason why they're being picked
on us because they are careless with
keys cosine so because of that Matt
keeper is usually the source of adware a
lot of it's not necessarily delicious
most places that you see on the virus
total was classified as low potential in
one application and like I said most of
the stuff is kind of in a shading realm
opinion spy is another one that same
category
it's um well this one's really does
cross the line malware little stream
information back not necessarily
privileged information but it's getting
there and that's important because we
get to a later stage that is actually
full malware Eleanor came out about four
or five months ago and that was a true
backdoor capturing commanding control
its reach those pretty limited
maybe ten twenty thousand bread and
because because Apple has done a good
job so far of locking down these threads
my remember my fears from the beginning
that mac is the state around the u.s.
tens and staging ground for what goes on
the iOS the real difference between the
iOS and that there's there's very few
differences between eyeless and and the
OS 10 so moving along you've got wire
lurker for awhile wire lurker which
actually targeted both iOS and mac
installed which installs a malicious
applications and steals actually steals
personally identifiable information and
it also tried many of these viruses sink
out other things that are installed on
the system and this one was no different
it looked for
program called just going to the name is
a mac of fire firewall client looking at
that little soldier
yeah little switches that is the number
one target lot of these applications so
the plug those guys because it actually
if the malware is targeting into its a
good indication it's pretty good and
pretty capable of blocking allow this
bad stuff that defender is another one
fishing key Ranger like i mentioned
before is ransomware and then you've got
several others so like I said the bow
oh there's also Pegasus exploit which
also affected iOS and add win rap keen
app that was thinking about key now is
the next evolution of that came out of
august sorry for these slides together
um key now came out and it actually
dumps credentials from the four tries to
dump credentials from the keychain
there's actually proof of concepts for
attacking the keychains well scripts
that you can use and move into that just
a little bit but before I go I go on
there's actually a few other slides that
are a few other not slides but I
mentioned earlier the applications that
were poorly developed end up being the
attack pic so going forward what you
should really look for is so the sparkle
updater back in February a researcher
noticed that anything using the sparkle
updater which is a lot of open source
utilities you know people use the same
sort of transport mediums
other commonalities so VLC is a good
example let's say uses something called
Sparkle up so you can as in most things
security secur everything that you know
about but it's an application itself is
doing bad things then it makes it a lot
harder for Apple to come along and say
you know this is bad so several
applications we got into the habit of
updating themselves not waiting for the
user to go to the appstore anything else
so plc is one of those it'll say they
always want to go do that
what it do what it did was it wouldn't
download the EMT baggage and then shut
itself off transfer that the background
including backup so there was not in
active member that to evangelist and
like it was a lot of man-hours pretty
mature based on Windows an hour so Mac
malware this isn't this is a
vulnerability and the sparkle update a
lot of other utilities use this is an
ottoman big feature if it was a
vulnerability because it used HTTP
installation ESO could be hijacked go to
any other place and download an update
their one that just came out recently
like just came out recently was drop box
Dropbox actually without letting you
know installs into the accessibility tab
a hook that they put it the reason why
that's bad because they effectively have
root privileges on the box and a lot of
their stuff when they when they're
installing it's not clear to the user
you're not just giving it the ability to
install you're also giving the ability
to control your system this is a
vulnerability not an active exploiting
but if it does become an export than
your strongbox with you
a source gallery now they did respond
today and i was just reading it 15 hours
ago i was just reading a little bit of
earlier but i'm pretty sure that
a good explanation why they need those
why they need that access my point is
applications themselves and the
developers for those applications are
are the targets today for mac malware
another source i mentioned the firewire
direct memory access of physical or
abilities also include USB so this is
another proof of concept issued recently
and the basic idea is a USB device that
presents itself as so it presents itself
as a network device and because of the
way the kernel extensions are loaded it
done it the first thing Mac does it have
the launcher service and ask the device
you know do you have any gaming network
services so it'll run dat discovery on a
new what it sees as a network device and
so you can have a USB device that
presents itself as a network device and
then also runs a dhcp server and that
can bypass security considering security
controls backup to backup and Colonel so
it's interesting that this ends up being
a cross-platform attack both Mac and
Windows um so my thanks for attending
there's three things I wanted to point
out the handouts are available visit
dress i'm going to leave this up there
also tweeted out later
I'm there was an enormous amount of
material for this talk and nothing else
only with the emotion that malware is a
rich the technology that maximum based
on is 30 years old is his old is
battle-tested but there's still a lot of
security research that has yet to be
done on that we're just scratching so
this year we had security researchers
turn their eyes you man
more so than other years and they found
three almost several several other
abilities in rapid succession and I
think that we're we're just starting the
Sea Eagles take max seriously isn't as a
turtle in fact to kind of bolster that
argument Apple couple months ago just
announced a bug bounty program which
later that adamantly opposed to before
now they will pay 200 thousand dollars
lifelines a vulnerability and the
caramel which again entire system
however security company came out right
after that said that they would pay five
miles over now that all sounds well and
good but if you go back and i encourage
you to read this
actually i'll leave the slider but i
encourage you to read in the endzone
license their stuff for 600,000 so mag
is the law of supply and demand Mac
vulnerabilities are highly valued now
because they're highly value the good
news for the average person is they're
probably not been targeting you
the highly valued malware you're
probably just gonna get AdWords step
however attention was running on your
back
utilities didn't have time to get these
utilities but to that i wanted to point
out well
no just pay attention to what goes on in
the distance very awesome and the hotel
anybody who's using a mac probably use
homebrew anyway so this whole bring
towel or a bunch of utilities or not
they're not necessarily security could
be using for instance one of them is a
launch d command that you can go through
and dumped out what's been running for
example this this is the launch T
command like an X and here's everything
that starts on my system at startup but
to give you an idea of the attack
surface that's on a Mac if i look at all
the system stuff that started up
then all the sudden like to start
scrolling for a while every one of these
could have something going on with it
just to give you an idea now not all of
them are that they're pretty well put
together anyway but you still probably
10 that's the good news is for windows
the windows vs mac malware environment
is willing
transparent match was won if it's not a
launch date doesn't run so with that
I'll open the floor up for questions and
let me switch back to slides one burning
. so they know everything that the
debugging utilities os10 xcode
everything's going to know ya ya feel
that got started
no TV is one of violence is not you know
girl stuff is like GV g so that you
don't interrupt they also showed their
own version Malik really so publisher is
30 albury no actually he's raised
questions you know what was the
there was a web-based or product that
solves a little app with that really
gives that after the grip of this bunch
but I heard your earth is the louse
having an era when you get you want i
was for iphone alright was over here is
Miles applications . Hillary and we
should set up some mitigation you go
into the aisles their evil maybe it's
just the last very much shaking
reporting yeah