autism program sheet there always is
usually thursday so if you wanna roll
Wow big crap Pickers last talk today
hope everybody's had a wonderful day I
certainly have a few tops got a few
buttons up front
that's good lunch so it's been a good
day as we jump into this talk a little
bit about me my first foray into your
programming was similar to duck i'm not
actually mode yards about commodore
vic-20 at age 13 I started writing a
basic hopes and peace for loops and go
to use I have lots to go to his back
then i would hope I'm past that at this
point but after i graduated from college
and its markings a system administrator
then I moved on into true software
development riding in knr see which you
might want to remember that for later on
then into java and I did some 8086
assembly 6502 assembly and some 370
assembly on the thing I'm probably the
most proud of this picture is the bottom
corner that's be playing beach
volleyball with my two children who are
probably both in high school and both
participating in the Air Force cyber
defense competition this year and they
were both in last year my daughter being
a senior will be a team captain this
year which is awesome and our high
schools put together four teams you know
I do work from home for four fire i
mentioned that for my boss is looking
for me and I'm just happen to be away
from keyboard my dog there takes care of
my keyboard for me and you know punching
once in awhile so so quickly jinda state
software what la angel
I don't fall into the trap that we're
talking about then we'll look at some
ways to fix it all
throw a conclusion out there i'll ask
you guys for questions and then I've got
a couple of really nice giveaways to do
at the end so you guys are here so you
obviously understand the scope of
software software is everywhere
dozens and dozens of operating systems
hundreds of programming languages are
thousands of professional software
developers summer really good and some
are not hundreds of thousands of
applications billions millions even
billions bonds poker games who likes to
play games right
I your entertainment we all have netflix
we all have no higher tivo some people
have tivo some are still people are
still at arbonne are you do your taxes
online you pay your taxes online it's in
healthcare everywhere you got software
controlling on harmonica tourism things
like that in the energy sector you have
applications go out and see how much
electricity you could use and pull it
back so you don't have the guys running
around checking the meters on the
twenty-third of the month anymore which
is job my father actually did well in
transportation all seen the videos from
defcon people hacking into cars and turn
off the ABS system all the moving
it's just everywhere and along with that
everywhere there's problems see that
this number came from the National these
numbers came from the National
vulnerability database number of
reported problems with software that
we're going you know this is
vulnerabilities so it's gone up although
i'm happy to say that in $MONTH 2015 if
you're down a little bit but still the
the number went down the costs went up
on
hanuman Institute reported that the cost
of cybercrime was up almost twenty
percent in $MONTH 2015 federal
government has also passed legislation
holding companies liable for not
protecting their electronic records
under the Obama care if you're not
taking care of your records and you get
hacks ten thousand dollars per record
for every person's record to be
compromised and there's also civil
liability that top couple doors down
earlier where they mentioned that one
large retailer had multiple lawsuits
possible breach they had a couple years
ago so I'm just the fact that you have
to defend yourself in court and you have
to get yourself on network plus I think
we can all agree
compliance is not equal security PCI
compliant does not mean that you're
secure means your attacks are smaller
but it doesn't mean that you're secure
on federal agencies i work for the dod
for six years now you have died cab its
cap FedRAMP FISMA all those are just
check boxes if all you're doing is
checking the checkboxes you're not doing
it right
so any developers in room 1 and I ask
what language
and if you worked in an agile
development environment for gossip I had
that on the personal uh so for those of
you who who haven't heard might not be
super familiar with it i'll do a really
quick run three armed and you actually
begin eighties still in high school at
that time you had waterfall and you had
from the villain side of it from the
process out of it you know somebody
would come up with an idea
somebody with storyboarding that they
handoff the idea storyboarded out they
handed off to the developers who get it
done then go to the testers and textures
to check it and you have a loop there we
go back and forth a few times and then
eventually sometimes five years later
you actually get something out the door
that people were using as agile as it
born back in on you don't really pass it
from team to team anymore its organic as
soon as i get a little piece of code
ready i handed off to the tester and all
goes through it but the pretty much the
same time he the idea is by keeping a
team together and keep focused talk
about more minute you can do things
faster and more efficiently but will
argue more efficiently in a few minutes
palm several agile methodologies through
in software development community street
extreme programming scribe adaptive
software development crystal featured
giving driven development pragmatic
programming that the people and lots
more on in 2001 groups from different
agile programming disciplines came
together came up with the agile
manifesto
maybe you could give us a little bit of
that it's been a long time I but the
idea was to develop software in a way
that meets your environment not
necessarily having a cookie cutter way
handling it off from shop to shop move a
little further forward here on agile
development was added to the project
manager book of knowledge in 2013
practiced by many organizations all over
the world so if you look at fire is
doing it
microsoft does it as far as agile
development goes even in our retailers
yogurt and just for reference if you
wanted to go get your PMP certification
and agile development the average
starting salary in Georgia is about
86,000 dollars a year for a net for a
PMP certified as a project manager so so
now is a guy like to say that wraps it
can see the spotter where there lots of
commercial and government agencies and
falling in so
so we all have ideas I've had ideas from
the time I was a kid things I would like
to do so the idea with agile teams is
somebody comes up with an idea
you handed to an agile team they go off
and do what they do they have something
production radiant bring it back to you
on it does have some advantages glass
half full guy asking you to gather work
with his developers more visibility and
control project they're running the show
good or bad to run the show on and by
empowering the team you're hoping to
harness the entrepreneurial spirit Apple
did this back in the early nineties
ladies early nineties hand team project
it if the project took off and did
really well they were very much rewarded
for if they weren't then if you want
they weren't never applied for
unemployment in san jose other
advantages the idea is to set a
sustainable pace
we've all been through up my exams
coming up
got it gotta cram for it that study for
got a deadline gotta hustle hustle
the idea is break it up into chunks that
are manageable and medial and you
actually deliver stuff on time and
encourage developers to meet commitments
cause they are committing to what they
agree manageable amount of work over a
given period of time on it also focuses
on the stakeholders give you constant
organization today you're trying to
develop something to detect
catalog and then all of a sudden that
that piece of malware disappears then it
might get the prioritize that you had
finished developing here and then the
last bullet there as you supposed to
deliver production-ready these
developments and we'll talk about that a
little bit disadvantages
so give a little bit more about my
experience working with scrum teams on 2
comments are both here in North America
commercial and government
I'll see very mature teams of developers
who then you know 10 15 years in
business 20 years in the business on
when the entire teams that way or fast
Georgie the teams at Lake are usually
very successful if you take a group of
developers less than five years of
experience each arm throw them into an
environment like this you're going to
spend a lot of money and you're gonna
get a lot of nothing one other thing is
agile teams don't hear you have a system
architect wall you don't have somebody
who's looking at the whole picture which
is very very important so you cannot
very quickly become too focused and
forget the fact that you need to update
the backend processes are changing UI
and you end up with problems and
production because you deliver
production area code are another thing
is if your stakeholders are
argumentative and shuffle priorities
drastically with every spring it can
quickly become whack-a-mole
oh we got this bug that's immediately
the highest priority let's break this
brand huddle up
start over you can just like with the
intelligence beads and alerts can
quickly become like them all home
it's so focused on short successes that
you can lose your long-term vision I
gets a little bit of work done i get
patted on the back i get this little
piece of work done and I get paid on the
back of this little piece of work done i
get back on the back but the thing that
i missed was this little piece of work
to be here this will this work with me
here but I wanted to go over there so it
cannot it truly requires strong project
management strong leadership and the
stakeholders have to agree on a
direction for whatever your building
it's not going to work um the other
thing is you're always focused on
short-term successes there seems to be a
tendency for developers to just grab
whatever the flavor of the day is that
will do most of what they want to do
right short augmentation for it and now
and then push it out the door so that
they meet their deadlines the the good
side of that is to collaborate bats out
of that is on not all of these libraries
and very well tested from a functional
or from a security standpoint on the
other piece of it i'm on top more on the
next slide is easy to swallow individual
team members when the teams are not
located so pair programming goes out the
window when you've got guys in for six
time zones apart on which is where i was
with managing teams in Europe when I
lived in Iran little bit more into the
disadvantages you're trying to build a
functional team you can feel
production-ready code with a group of
five to seven individuals are it really
really requires strong multi-discipline
backgrounds need to have a successful
team and got seven people you've got to
have an architect have functional tester
you gotta load tester you've got to have
a lead developer you have a couple of
developers gotta have somebody can be a
security assessor uh usually you need
somebody to do in test if you're going
to be doing any serious releases and you
need somebody who can build the platform
from the work on and you only have seven
people and you can kill your project for
two weeks I want to take my kid is so
you really need people who can reach
across multi-discipline and are willing
to do so I've seen teams fail epically
they had a developer who also knew how
to work on the platform but he said I
used to do that now I don't want to do
is write code so when the platform
needed to fix the guy who's better at it
was away nothing will work and this is
my favorite one
my absolute favorite fallacy of agile
development defining done so you doing
window you get a four-week window
whatever happens to be one day window
your delivery production-ready code what
defines done is it done when you get
when it actually composite developers
desktop now because it develop is it
done when you complete functional
testing know what about documentation
internal documentation so that the
operation people for it
what about external documentation so
that other people who are actually
buying this product can actually use it
did you do any security testing did you
do any low test you don't know exactly
what frame person's gonna be running it
on here on what seems to happen with
done is they do say it's done soon as it
finishes functional testing and then
after the spring is over they'll add a
week of load testing we can security
testing a week for documentation we in
staging in another way to roll outs and
by the time it actually rolls out
they've completed two more Sprint's and
how everybody behind the chain is behind
so your documentation is weeks behind
production-ready so I said I'm an
optimist going to talk about fixing the
most important priority as far as I'm
concerned being a project manager
multiple teams and one going being a
developer at one point and now being on
the security side of the house builder
team extremely careful agile evangelist
will preach that changing your team
anytime during the life cycle of the
product has been passed to three springs
reestablishing velocity i can guarantee
you that a security breach or non lo
tested code is going to cost you a lot
more than three springs will throw
targets name out on out on the table
here
what did it cost them the breach that
they had and they're still paying for it
on 67 guys you can't have more than one
kid fresh out of college
you can't do it there's just not enough
even if you guys you know move to
Antarctica living in an igloo it's been
24 hours a day together building
whatever this is
if you've got more than 1i an
experienced guy
it's too much weight to pull for the
rest of the team actually successful
it's just not going to happen and then
the last piece here is team stability is
not greater than skill mix if you're
trying to if you've got a team and
they've been assigned a project and the
project direction changes a little bit
now you need somebody with some
networking background or now you need
somebody with hunting experience if
you're doing it's not necessarily
software development you're working on
the three Sprint's to re-establish a
steady velocity and make your mix of
skills correct take the guy who is not
fight skill sets that you want moving to
another team bring in the guys got skill
set that you want because if you don't
you're gonna regret it
the other side of that is are you
talking about having experienced
developers agile teams are treated like
startups there was a quote from IBM in
the early nineties that's it
we have no idea what they're doing
you just know they're going to build
something you give them a bunch of money
and they bring something back arm even
very mature developers are not
necessarily motivated to do that so
responsibility chart up there
I've actually had that hanging in my
cube and had people ask me to take it
down
ah but it's important
commit to what you're going to do then
do what you committed to on
or close the great great player can top
the top wall along with that every team
member contributes directly to success
you got to remember that it's not
pulling their weight go to the collabnet
documentation for certified scrummaster
they encourage the other team members to
encourage pull on everything short of
ostracize 14-member to get them to
actually hold her way you gotta do it if
you've got a bunch of
non-confrontational people that have
experienced and you got one guy who's
not pulling his weight i'm here in
trouble goes back to building your team
carefully and on the project that i'm
currently working on the third bullet is
probably one of the biggest pain points
in my life
the team will accept a hundred and
twenty points where the work and they
know they can only do 60 but they still
accept all this into this into their
sprints and then they don't make I've
got to go back to the customer on the
other end and say for the stakeholders
or whoever happens to be and say you
know we were really trying to get that
feature out to you this quarter but it
didn't happen when it happens two or
three quarters in the road becomes a
real sore spot for her for the customers
and for the people who have to break so
committed to what you can do then the
bottom . is actually
collaboration talking about multi
functional discipline our
multi-discipline personnel they need to
communicate about everything on the
second bullet as pair programming is not
just about you
I sorry im a jak certified secure
programmer I look at things differently
than the guy who's got the CIS degree in
10 years of software development
experience i turning out code for
brochure where when he looks in my code
he's going to look at different things
than I look at my look is its it teaches
it helps each team member become more
multi-discipline just can't i can't say
enough about I could spend two hours
talking about just that the other thing
is the next thing on the list stand-ups
are not optional and require details for
several months at team member who came
into one of the scrum meetings and he
said oh I'm working on integrating
single sign-on into this dismiss it's
always write every day for three months
on me and I went back and fix it but I
need you need to come into your
stand-ups every day is as described on
time pass the ball around say what you
gotta say given up details to know that
if you do need help people who were
there it might be able to help you can
step up and help you right away you're
trying to develop products as if you
were a start-up and get out the door you
can't
you can't just hold information to
yourself stakeholders involved if
something changes they need to get
involved right away and at the end of
every sprint they need to check out the
work that was done and accepted and
reprioritize as quickly as possible so
you can get the next print started if
you don't keep up with rebar closet
we're not going to end up over there
were going somewhere out and don't be
tempted to single out team members house
of specials as I said security plus GX
certified secure programmer but I
shouldn't be the only one who's doing
security assessments on the software the
teams but together if you do that and I
win the lottery teams immediately and
one more thought on that one before I
move on there's a one particular team
member of bonds i said i would mention
at some point during the stop so that
you have to actually listen to the Holy
so George buddy this 13
alright so everybody's heard this
military time keep it simple sign modern
applications have dozens of moving parts
databases got some stuff you've got an
operating system you've got an
application platform got a front in
doing a model view controller you can
have that and actually multiple
languages you can have qs for handling
load but as mr. on so eloquently said
hear everything should be made as simple
as possible but not simpler
along with that I have another quote
love to put in at this point says there
are two ways in truck constructing the
software design one way is to make it so
simple but there are obviously no
deficiencies and the other is to make it
so complicated that there are are no
obvious deficiencies the first man that
is far more difficult when you pass it
off your operations people you pass it
off your customers who are actually
using it home it works if you make it so
complicated that nobody can understand
it there's a very high probability that
nobody can actually understand your
risks understand what you're building
you've handed the upper management has
handed the keys kingdom to the
development team or the security
operation see you doing software
development know your applications know
where they are know what's supposed to
be there at the same thing you hear
about networks
oh I didn't know that router was over
there sending SNMP data to Beijing or I
didn't know that firewall was configured
to allow all ports out there
and software oh I didn't know this guy
was using go
he was using a version it's like two
years old goes around know your
environment test environment pissed off
every build should kick off some
automated testing every hatch should
kick off on a larger set of testing
every release should kick off an even
bigger some another thing tension
third-party solutions the example that I
loved to use struts and struts came out
there was some example code to show you
how to put together your view controller
really really quick but it had across
process scripting flaw in the example I
can count
dozens of applications that up that I've
worked on
I've been to that actually copy and
paste this example code into their view
and now you have cross-site scripting
vulnerabilities in your production
application and it takes like 90 seconds
to test it and find it so you've got a
taste for third-party solutions in
addition to what you're working on
trying your development team as i said
earlier that the jack secure software
program it's no joke it's a hard test
study for it for a couple weeks and I
was to renew it so I already got it once
it's been a couple weeks studied for it
going through the materials again it
still was hard and that's what you need
you need something to make these guys
think not only about this little piece
of code that are writing within the
piece of code that's running on this
application server that's running on
this network it's on available to this
environment even if the environment
you're talking about is your customers
are think about how they're going to use
it about how they're going to use it
so that you don't end up with something
that you could very easily taken care of
and have to rush out patches or give
somebody some money back or even worse
have your name and your company's name
spread all over the news and the
internet and Twitter and everything else
the last piece there is gotta have your
stakeholders scrum master your project
manager all going to sit down together
and work out reduce your risks where it
makes sense if you're working on a piece
of software that's on going to be in a
car has absolutely no external network
connections
maybe you don't have to worry so much
about SH not being patched on but if
that same issue is on our Wi-Fi router
that's sitting on a hospital's Network
that has connections to all the other
devices and that's probably going to be
a much higher priority so sisters if
anybody has any questions for me at this
point you have a little more content and
take a break here get your breath
anybody have any questions
please
having just a little trouble here you
actually got a lot of suggestions
oh so you can see anybody from his
company in here but Tim Tom's doesn't
really really great web application
testing horse
ok so that's the longer developer course
that's four days I think it's actually
amazing to get this year actually just
as a refresher course for myself and not
have been doing web development but it
gave me on the detection side of the
house and gave me some more things to
look for
so I was looking at it from that side
another thing is the the GX pure Java
programmer if you doing stuff in java or
they also have the ASPCA sharp version
of it is amazing absolutely amazing and
afterwards you can get the certification
which is good for four years and you can
review it again for another four years
which is what i just did it will make
you think about it and they look at it
from both a java platform or sharp
platform and at the web platform so
there was tons of questions in there
about how to close known vulnerabilities
in tomcat jboss and is you're on the
other side of it
so those are
things that can do it and other things
if you've got access to somebody who's
in tester read some of the books in
theory I don't have any names right off
the top of my head like even my car
send me an email I can definitely do
some suggestions with applications
hacker's handbook is a good thank you
James
ah so lots of lots of information out
there the biggest thing is pick your
platform whether it be on them
microsoft side of the house or the java
side of the house or PHP or whatever it
happens to be and then focus there
because there's so much information
it'll seem like diving into an ocean if
you look if you try to attack on more
than one platform at the time so pick a
platform the concepts are going to be
the same just pick up the syntax when
you go to the next one so that's my best
advice pick one key to it and the
concepts of caring as long as your crew
goes so i dunno some credit around lots
of
recommendations there about the numbers
of the front the picture from my fellow
Americans happens to be one of my top
five favorite comedies which was found
about three hours away from here i'll
mention the how Apple does it that's
where the one of the quotes can prompt
it that are red in the bottom there we
were talking about targets and there's
the CNN article about target on these
slides are going to be up on the b-sides
website so going to try to write
anything down or take a picture this
article the second one out here the one
from security week is actually another
good place to get started seven
considerations to reduce your attack
surface and a wasp has a ton of
information out there if you're on it
doesn't matter what side of the house
round pick one then not finally thank
you guys for hanging around four o'clock
at the end on Thank You b-sides guests
for allowing me to speak with this great
polo
thank you to pinterest fell for talking
me into submitting my first see me last
year
Thank You fire out to be up to you to
have the day off yesterday to go to
security any conference can be here
today and then of course the big thank
you to scope on that happen to be happy
to assist put together logos down in the
bottom corner there so I nobody's
thought of any more questions I've got a
couple of the items here to give away
last call for questions
so southward has given this great
lockpicks it for me to give away so I
back my very first are on my agenda
slide I had a line that says don't fall
into the track from the movie my fellow
Americans you can finish the Senate
hopeful don't fall into the trap body
people he pulls the string out the
presidential doll don't fall into the
trap
nobody alright alright I'm going to tell
you the answer probably in the given
political climate is probably the wrong
thing to say but it's don't fall into
the trap Democrats are full of great
ah let's see another good question
who can remember what my first computer
was right here Commodore vic-20 yes sir
for the hacker playbook which was
graciously donated besides the vessel
he's just going on mom
we'll see if anybody remember two of the
processors that i wrote assembly
language for there were three or
multiple about one about yes sir