no wonder actually like st. Olaf has
been really awesome like almost another
actress now that was pretty awesome
we have your day and your order where we
have you know sitting on the floor so I
mean it's just been really today really
have to get off the market
I gotta be sure to give away first
person to raise your hand when you
sponsor this etf right
oh ok I'm gonna let me thinking it was
it 100 points are able to a little of
onions
alright alright often works hard
ok so in this last year the track so i
have you John board thanks Bill that
actually are everybody will love the
size board is a security and solutions
and a lot of things in the community
just as a person here so thanks Phil so
my name is John Kerry for this is a
company is my co-presenter we're talking
today about hiding within so this
defensive trash off the most part of it
has seen ya comin
we're going to talk a little bit more
today balls enhance education experience
toolkit so this is a pretty solution of
microsoft has had several years now
people have in their environments show
fans going to be well actually this
whole for ok so how many people feel
that they are pretty comfortable with
musicians cool it will plan on it up
another thing how many people they
really know the soul
ok very advanced all people it's one of
those things it seems like that might
talk about where there's a lot of times
people are using it but there
understand fully how is always hot
control and manage it and how to push it
to their environments so started talking
about pretty much the overview of limits
what it can do for us we're going to go
into using independent security
historical issues we're going to talk a
little bit of some of the law's passage
and a myriad of things that Microsoft
has done trying to get going is retold
it's not something that is a great
discussion about is ones with you know
you know how to use writing is very good
solution provided in slc all securities
or center is going to grate on things
right now for as many people know we're
looking at you know some next-generation
windows stuff coming out of the
woodworks and diet coke whores a lot of
things going on right now windows making
it more interoperable x lion server for
coming out so a lot of people think of
what are we doing moving forward to
maintain this tool and then a Michaels
gonna get a notice the demo we're going
to break everything down show you some
things about a minute show you that it
works sure that it doesn't sometimes and
o-obviously how to use it more
effectively and then we'll go to the
discussion questions so okay that's
twenty dollars with the metroids no
that's not what is your nominee is on
the there's a lot more people think that
those tools where you just very quickly
qualified you're trying the best and
bruising and you want but absolutely for
coming here today to go back and have a
game plan for uses more effectively as
well as up if you have an environment
where you train others from them as well
alright so you really have two handles
of recently a mystery boots got people a
little bit about be so for coming heroes
in seattle he's been a lot of time
over guys all then the building
community ever get the chance actually
had also right NW washington stop by
some their meetings they have like
meetups and stuff
the couple hundred developers get
together with the stash a lot of things
the college's school I do a lot of
things with charities the most part and
uh yeah they got some pull behind and
right now i'm working on that g security
also correct information technology on
board or a capital so next is a little
bit about me
you can read the slides pretty
self-explanatory
if you have her semester stag is
basically a vulnerability networking go
into your game so the whole flows all
the different bonobos you think about
for my strings of mines
I mean you name it we also have a web
web app intestine and women RC challenge
so once you have it you have it go smash
that or check it out and that's me
alright so begin to define a little bit
more buying and planning in better
detail so what it is why you should care
alright so basically looking back and
experience will get one of the things
about this is a lot of you and with
minors all visual i really was brought
forward and honest though we could
actually handle all the applications out
there in the wild a lot of people
running older server editions they have
applications are proprietary third party
and you have to maintain and simplest
hey I'm going to my operating system
patch everything for today and we're
going there was a lot of issues that we
did not angry for example 64-bit
application architectures so microsoft
security service and hey what can we do
to try to bring some of the software
patching homelessness is as patty vs but
it was the mentality and say what can we
do still need systems to protect against
advanced memory exploits convertibility
is out there so they came up with them
and for that purpose and its free still
maintained as we stated mitigate your
abilities and software so it's awkward
fall protection
we're ready to the slide later on a
little bit even explaining more about
the actual security tools work and then
I cyberattacks corruption so a lot of
things working with rock tax returns and
programming all discuss step farther
apart so luck command line line line
tells you there's different things for
us is just a week for the most part
people many people have actually worked
ok pull in right now is that we shared
some of these poses where you want to go
with it
rats and micro that is low and also
change your configuration is releasing
manage their the command line to it can
aid and detecting targeted attacks a lot
of people and cyber intelligence level
radio siren when you talk about how
great our controls you can actually
break down every school has control of
protection Foley have been and who are
these DLLs and all these processes so
when you use that effectively that can
help right so we're talking about a
maybe I want to see my browser
surprising hacks
right so you married and all and then
help you troubleshoot you get in step
forward and within that you can actually
control how certain applications utilize
its functions and then a heavy on every
protection but also SL thanks so you
have things that you might actually like
really mind and so this is opening
microsoft recently certified sighs how
many days there explicitly microsoft has
several it's not very warm though very
little warning pre-certified websites
you can work with getting one there is
really just something there are working
actively are now you know building into
that function so next like alright so
this is a breakdown of graduates . is
there really a whole but you know this
is actually break down all the nation's
efforts that Morris towards these are
all sizes and every one of these is able
to call on some of the work comment
you're gonna probably cultivated just
working with energy related programs so
breaking it down different programs lots
at its execution flow where things are
getting called in from our ties every
production functions to make sure that
we're not executing things from areas
memory that's you know not supposed to
be marked as rewrite this one really i
was going on that so what that looks
like that's all on Microsoft's official
documentation by the way
alright so using any with defenses so
we're going to actually get into talking
about this
so what cyber protection is to provide
32-bit legacy applications that were
older already that I asked my little wow
this is very common
so Michael works a lot with compound and
that is more than I think about this
here but not coder anything i wanted to
go already
awesome family yeah decided a little oil
very visual people we work along ie8 all
setup really low budget allows i do you
know British automated process for years
gross
so a lot of people there a little while
developing applications they don't
really designers and compilation process
is not Valerie everything else does a
lot for is really thought this little
bit more private parking lot of your
applications and features that provides
the ends so a lot of the older compilers
are you know always at a certain angle
on moving into the Prophet time we have
64-bit so the latest evidence under the
spell of 10 years and you know instead
of applications that are being pushed
down a little bit even today we don't
have a special so Microsoft Excel
software does maybe it doesn't have to
be provided finest protections it will
absolutely work to protect their
applications will see your butt is an
assault can absolutely save review it
may actually cause complex functionally
so the cracks and trying to protect them
memory actually causing not to work so
be cognizant of that and then on done it
for these courses required . about that
next
alright so this is kind of a
continuation on new tricks all platforms
really thats it's not what your Pony
though just be understanding that and a
lot of business that's a really good
thing today to talk about its you how
many people work with man security or
services are you a better one to so many
times to get the best of our clients
like hey I got the same i no want yous
all right yeah all the time and so many
people generally just to say what
Michaels gonna show you the demo what
you can do to actually I'm not just nude
women to use more effectively and then
you can have your sock into all options
for every single or double deduction is
the medications but that was not the
roscoe programs videos all this land is
like a higher level you know your
science forever then you know he's going
to act not never usually start working
correctly understand and take time to
basically all of these controls we're
not saying that you're going to get the
wii's everywhere and how we're doing
everything and operate all you just need
to do have the functional use
productions for profit colleges i said
earlier or maybe sure it's perfectly
options might be called in from other
libraries that are relevant portion as
late as an example of something that
flows careful because what it does is
it's actually going to run through the
process execution
that's a couple of times so think about
is I this is going and then ok really
should be colleges that jump return i'm
almost at obviously commands move around
so many little lightheaded
that happens a lot with LLC people just
are . happens right so the right is
exploit the transport . things and
everything comes from also other
application you got like something like
Windows Update running in the background
is really cool guys little pieces of
code memories already loaded from some
other process a little function and
you're trying to attack process so they
try to reach out there and say I want to
get a look-in something that i use is
legitimate
you know I didn't memory for windows
right now i should think this is great
work so don't really were smitten the
left side
I mean you have talent on the right side
it's part so Chris teasing him and a lot
of people tend to forget that there are
sea losses with a horse best are rags
your memory way was programmed you may
use places one of the things that man's
issues powers and also the gravitation
crash and then the bargain results when
sorry I want it on the slide because
it's more operational control but of
course it is good you sell your belly
but do not question how is always best
Trollocs play around a little bit you
can take all right and then SL paying
don't really depend on it right now 31
and got a little more lust for users to
be a little more control and hard as it
is to travel is quickly little bit
basically the past and it's had a bunch
of problems okay to say no yeah is
doesn't sell back again 474 pads rises
use blue hat technologies as you
microsoft hey so we're throwing that out
there
whoever thinks that they can actually
explain memories being protected by an
application we want to know why it's
cool right there was really creative
ideas so best in children ready ready
yeah right LOL actually going to jet
itself little production is kind of a
lot of tasks work today so it attacks
the cells like our memory is ballin so
one people decided they really some
really cool stuff to kind of moment but
anyways well 64 is one of the big issues
that we have today when running it at a
horizon year versus permitted wanna see
anything that is how a lot of issues
doesn't have 64-bit projections yet it
was while 64 fully developed so just
note that that's that's important is a
lot of browsers today I think the last
year's service and values and browsers
were actually busy been hit on a 64-bit
hypervisor layer and it was like hey I'm
protections but not my normal work
because they're all headed your resume
or so be careful with that next part so
blasting through this little bit more on
several folks and groups of men have my
ways to defeated blue that we're not
really quick about bringing labs jared
montz x-axis cello reasonable model
because it said I want a contact eric
sequel credible control and arrive for
protection so everything was innovation
that you're like oh they can with some
pretty good ideas about using stuff
that's already there how we get around
bypasses veins we can avoid color check
around ya Yin and work tables
thanks for is not real big on memory
that works and show we're gonna use
what's already out there running and you
know the average man has environment and
memory and start playing around in slc
we get around by pass thanks
alright so Jerry out that can get some
return oriented programming code
actually riding wordy and basically
durable hey you know I can take the
stuff that's out there i can actually
write my own custom shows one thing
gland is it will almost as brazen as a
lot of American families returning job
functions as well as callings you all
guys from other processes that was
pretty protective so by default and can
stop those autonomously George figured
out the custom handwriting things
basically cool stuff that's out there to
get my text
that's basically saying the same thing
Jared assume the attacker has control
over trigger you're gonna be using our
work a nine nicely and use it as an eye
on it and I know that American
production so all that research hires
only right so the defense of people we
need to be understanding a little bit
about what the vulnerabilities bring you
know other radioactive for the software
. so Jerry exactly that and knowing that
as an offensive guy he can basically
pick it apart because there's one
information on environmental controls
and he broke his little tools basically
next
alright so our checks we talked about
this a little bit just making sure that
it's not you know using legitimate calls
its not using returns and jobs all over
memories hat coming follow place because
obviously organized proper code normally
doesn't do these things which men
explain things to you know oxygen ball
over its and then we'll talk about the
library just make sure that it's not
loading a dll from somewhere has already
sitting on the same way I'm here but I'm
not really normally used in the process
is dirt was able to find a way to pull
in solids normally do use maybe like
it's legitimate kind of walk through the
game six and then obviously this is a
little man has been found he put that in
there is because it
in second place for the blue got
challenge that's another gentleman
microsoft didn't actually put Jared's
research into their improvements they
put the other guys and everything back
in the next version found it
alright so talk about then send exact
activity f on memory protect this we
talked about that make sure that
certainly the calls are coming from
marks at pages i know it doesn't really
I'm is be right to realize that it's
looking for that kind of stuff basically
and then simply sexy clothes were
especially flowing in from a run a few
instructions ahead and let me go try
this out its theoretically the man i
call this push that is that memory
ok that's say was i'm ok i'm actually
going to return the job is just starting
to like an obsolete . and then BF is
obviously the export tables are
legitimate is ok for them
alright so in summary basically like I
said ginger was able to bypass all the
controls using legitimate tools that
were microsoft microsoft has been saying
something very important and it is not
designed to be all you know process
solution was designed you design make
happens have to work harder to develop
more proactive customer always bypassing
these controls and sneaking through the
gate and a nutshell it was an intern
which is really the tool so moving
forward thinking of him as an intern
strategy
thanks alright so they said try harder
this is all sections you don't know I
said that also it was like a one which
are harder to head home and next so
basically all set this really cool thing
where object was like hey you know what
that's right is injecting himself like a
mature we make those things distribution
maintain that mask worked so how does
that work was intelligent process known
as you are 16 time deal objects and cell
fractions all-around process somewhere
memory women's track and it's hard on
all sectors able to find this also value
is that is all go in there right 20 i'll
link it out and show the little flags on
set and disabled on this process so they
didn't protect him and soul and
protections blur protecting the process
a little time wasn't protecting itself
from these things as well so that's five
and then also belong to the moment
alright so anyways we get we have
millions on a lot of l by Britain was
being viable that just be home so grab
yourself protected said 21 someone in
its neighborhood process however love in
place marriage is also arrival also said
ok fine i'll set Europe and it was about
next
alright um and then they did a lot more
. and then nutshell basically you're by
yourself today
go ahead and make that code is bad
around we're going to learn to it that
wasn't going all is ok I'm just going to
go wire-to-wire noted water is already
included in Windows naturally and now we
know where you live now and I think they
tried harder using it you know another
Cody's easy goals and devices i resolved
late around
oh you can't find our voters will find
whatever they want to do that again the
cpuid also said okay fine
why don't we just go to file and use
this device itself a natural process
than it used in on itself it's all
physical and you know this is adamant
that i talked about earlier people
decided in school and colorful and hey
so what you doing with you and I was
recently also had a memory banks
alright so basically moving forward here
in 52 related to much to didn't help
that or whatever we put a little more
protections in place we try to hide it a
little bit more
it worked for a while but not forever
and 55 k mother
that anyways next part so Microsoft
internal change anything
hey talking box to this because it is
not meant to stop stuff and people kept
thinking as well as for but in a
nutshell they try to hide this partner
again and another researcher came
forward and said okay I'm gonna find a
hiding to reverse that and then i'm
actually using himself to disable
sellers natural function and alright so
now my kids going to give them a demo
business going to walk through logically
was going on
ok so basically you so i'm going to go
through i'm going to show you what the
UI looks like to show you a command line
looks like to show you when using
interpreter or medicine boy to do a
piece exact to the box to migrate to
process is not protected by Emmett and
i'm going to protect that process and
i'm going to migrate it again and show
you I'm it actually captures it and then
we'll talk about the local gpo how to
add local GPs to it and show you from
commandline how you can view some of the
protections because from the google you
can't see group policy protections you
want to concede rebelling positive
protection from the command line and
we'll go over there so switch that ya
never see that fine it's not cut off
organism and all right so this is a this
is the main goal when you download and
install and this is what comes up and
there's some default applications that
are protected so like office suite
internet explorer course basically
microsoft core products and they have
some profile files and call there is
called your recommended software and
popular software they added some more
things in there for you that we
protected the best way to update those
things are to add all the application
that you want to add to the software
just come up here and click on add apps
and bring above the screen adaptation to
go to your directory find where
applications you want to go to see drive
down to program files and let's say you
want to protect
you know google chrome go hair Chrome
application and click on chrome and plug
it in and by default it selects
everything except for a few things that
may cause you know may cause an
application crash if you look at it you
can see it up there with the ones in
bold those are the ones that are
protected by default anything that's not
a bold as things that you had to the
software that makes sense right on the
John remember all these protections so
you can uncheck any one of these you
want to step is one of the ones that you
cannot check as enforced by windows 7 by
default it's system wide you can't you
can't change that when you go to just
uncheck different ones if you don't want
to protect those so what this means that
you if you add an application that you
have an application is crashing believe
that Emmett because it didn't start
crashing to install it go through and
check each protection one by one until
you find one is called an issue and then
re-enable the other ones that we do not
save on everything ok if you want to
change your default profiles it's right
under here just click on a custom
security maximum recommended and these
files are in the am a directory so you
navigate to the directory program files
commit to go deployment you got your
group policy and you've got your
protection files these are your your
default file that come with it right
what you need to do a group policy files
to copy these files in your windows
profile definitions and then your mother
provide definitions you have your
English us and our show and second
that's your basic UI down the bottom you
have these green checkmarks that lets
you know what what processes are
protected by a minute so we see the
green check that means images protecting
that process and there's no check that
means I'm it's not protected rights
basically in this version of your task
list so what we talked about earlier was
anything that's been applied by policy
you cannot see from this gooey so when
you look
when you go to your apps right this is
this is basically what is protected by
any right now you will not find anything
protected by group policy in this list
so if you're a sysadmin or irresponsible
to figure in an enterprise environment
and you wonder why all the applications
that you spend 23 hours configured are
showing up on your client systems as
well you have to explore the command
line and do with their and from the
command line just jump there you talk a
minute on a score confidence to go from
the directory or you configure
environments you running from anywhere
and dash dash list
press ENTER to give me your entire list
along with your GP 0 configured programs
so i went ahead and already configured
he's ahead of time and that's why you
see those two there by the flop to do
nothing there
your local computer and you want to
modify your local GP 0 obviously gb
edited that MSC bureau your editor and
you come into application configuration
you can see it's already enabled because
i added those to come down to so
obviously it will be not configured when
you initially started up go to enabled
click on the show and you can just in
the value name section you put path so
you can put you know c colon programs
whatever you want to put on you use a
regular expression you can say star
backslash whatever it's easy just to use
on star back slicing and even process
because you might have a typo in the
path that you type in or that in the
application might be installed somewhere
and it's you know not standard the other
thing is that it's kind of a downfall to
it is it works off the passage give it a
binary name so if you protect notepad or
protect chrome and somebody change the
name of Rome it's not gonna be protected
data for some reason they don't use
hashes of of the banners that are
windows or applications that well-known
which i think is something pressure due
at least with the core windows system32
buyers right there should be at least
check by hash and not just by the
pathname of the name of minor
so anything goes wrong value is what
protections you want to enable or
disable so you can do dash basically you
can read everything on the left-hand
side so down here it gives you exactly
what you need to configure that alright
so we'll move on from there if you want
to verify the process is being protected
by use process hacker some of you
probably use sysinternals our process
explored can do the same thing I just
before process hacker cool thing about
process occurs if you have somebody
create service on your box or does nice
things for a second give you an alert
service got created service got deleted
so that's kind of why I like using it
and just one thing that does that a
process explorer doesn't do so will
check and see what processes we have
protected right we said we can come to
the main screen and look at here we can
do from the console and so we see we
have a command commander Dax is
protected right
we also sort of command line is it
anyway it's not in here so let's add one
in the third on top okay so it's
protected right so it's got all the
default protections so let's see where
that dll is this on commander Dax here
is go to properties and process process
attacker private showing modules in the
student notepad be a lot easier
nope there's no compact plus plus
alright so note that this bus where's
that means running there is an app that
would be amazing
alright so if you do have a process
running Google properties or modules and
you can see around $TIME a.m. dilo
rights any process that you add to
Emmett and you want to verify this
actually protecting that process you can
come in here and check it out that when
there's also another tool and historical
this dll so this module think things
called a show you all the deals over
there if you happen to run in and you
don't see that deal owners probably cuz
that process is already right
you have to restart the process that way
you can can add that protection so if
you add add the binary 2m it while it's
still running it will protect it
you have to restart that process ok I
society various mine it's a 64 bit
processor same thing you'll see in a 64
an idea though my only an image . of
current version ended
alright so i'm going to show you a
process that's not protected
I'm gonna go to model the screen and i'm
going to use a i'm already connected and
see have to recreate session some
statistics said nothing fancy so
standard 2 i'm just using that is . to
do it and if you PS exacta box and it
will not detect that right doesn't
detect sequel injection it doesn't set
the tech you clicking on a binary gets
mighty Rochelle it detects things that
happen in memory to a process right so
wrong
see already there so let's find a
process that's not being protected see
or we can create
so and killing yeah alright so we'll run
ms paint again will double check that
it's not being protected by a minute and
by the way if I want to do that from the
command line i'll just do a minute I'll
do delete and then the path to ms payne
right or I'll do just you know Walker
backslash just mspaint start this pain
same thing you can do everything delete
all another thing know if you do you do
an app from from are you can't delete an
app from the command line that's a group
policy enabled application so discordant
a-plus-plus was at a good group policy
you can't from the command line to say
that you have to use good policy to that
there might be a consideration for using
group policy versus just using the doing
so anyway already removed that got
patron we're going to check the news
prosperity that's actually disabled
mspaint here properties go to modules
skeptical so we got ms64 under so it's
still still protecting that drive them
in this paints paints we should actually
do that off
ok fresh
watch that
alright so let's see if it was paint so
we got 6012 depend on my grades and so
if it's any buyers protected or process
to protect behind a little pop-up little
notification saying year protection and
detective or wear protection that
stopped mitigated it'll basically
turning process so we can see we
migrated successfully that process 6012
nothing happened right we can still
still move around still do stuff i can
drop the shell funny to you know it's
not trigger anything right now this user
has no clue that somebody's on a box
alright so now we're gonna protect I'm
going to turn the protection a lot of
pain is still running and show you that
it doesn't it still doesn't protect it
or detect that somebody's in that that
process so we'll go from the command
line just to show you that you can go
from the command line for those of you
that like the command line command set
not add and then you can just do you
star backslash mspaint having this pain
already in there yeah it's already in
space on
alright let's do a bit more ads in their
right mind
alright so when you adaptation to admit
it will give you this little statement
is an achievement you may need to
restart which is what I talked about
earlier if you don't restart it
it's not protected right so we have no
cat running will close it run it again
didn't want that I've got my setup so
whenever no padding around the bad plus
plus
alright so we got that running now when
we come back over here we'll see what
did that is for notepad and we've got
3716 no let's get out the show first and
my help
alright so once my grand you see images
detected BF detected motion detected and
mitigation will close the application
notepad.exe that's what happens when you
migrate when using material to migrate
to another process is protected by in it
you get that dedication determination
process the person interpreter show will
crash so it's still trying to migrate
but eventually crash my session will die
and life goes on right on this end
several things happen if you go to your
event longer right you'll see my login
so if you're doing remote login to get
capturing the black the logs and
anything that triggers on will say in it
so you can filter log of everything that
says in it and I'll tell you exactly
which process trigger so if you look
down here you guys in system32 ms paint
before that I to tell you that it was
enabled so this is when I added it will
give you all you default protections
everything that's enabled so it's pretty
detailed information for you know
anything that you need new protections
any questions so far alright so like I
said he had a group policy your local
policy
these are all configurations you only
get these settings once you copy those
files showed you in to show you the
directory so you take these files that's
in your deployment folder so you go to
deployment group policy you copy each
one of these when you go down to your
windows directory round windows and any
little profile definitions so the admx
files in here and in the other file goes
into this directory and then you open up
your local group policy editor these
these comparisons of available at the
under windows client and/or you can do a
search and look at everything as a
minute
alright that's pretty much it so that
goes into our recommendations as long as
there's a little bit of acid cycle power
on being active dude is that had
intended goals is slowly losing
something solid lines so as you notice
before when able to see anything
everything is moving around the library
just like that though using it correctly
fully-managed right we will see that
renders table litigation in there was a
lot that is drawn into that process and
protected that isn't one more thing then
so this is the xml file for the
recommended software that it comes about
fault so you have your office suite
that's pretty much what it looks like
and then if you want to create your own
custom file so let's say you have an
enterprise that you don't use Google+
some reason you just want to create a
custom profile this is what it looks
like you wouldn't do this by hand so
you're not going to just hack away at no
pay you go to application you add every
application you want on a test box and
then you export that so if you go to MIT
just do there's a feature to export the
current configuration and then you take
that file and maybe set up a share and
have
everybody every other box pulled from
that share or however you want to
distribute that XML hot that's also an
option group policy you can manually
configure everything that application
you can create a profile box and export
that and utilize that question
it's not any more protected than
anything else in the program followed
the virtual so it reads the
configuration file once it runs and it
doesn't keep rereading that follows you
you know all three starters election
nice
yes the planning on bringing the authors
and methodology was the answer the back
that static file box problem but if you
push it out the group policy then you
have to just like anything else
whenever anyone's and even as because
the use that's on that system it doesn't
run as system or any other user one says
that's that's probably a lot of these
applications if they run the same user
space malware runs in the same user
space there baby
both competed and obviously running as
an internal space is not a good idea
right so that's the problem we have
right now which is going to leave some
of the recommendations that we have
later when professional dancer most yeah
your question was already together
ice creams and lotions microsoft
products you know what it is like which
was anybody running
yeah so they they do admit there's
problems and conflicts and that's why
some things are off by default but if
carbon should fix a lot of those
problems
I don't know you're running to know the
current version i mean like what version
you're running because they just updated
passionate spot 151 now i don't remember
the exact date but I know there was five
there's like a recent one of 5.51 so try
that one see the other problems or just
disable uaf so it's not a it's not the
end all be all
there's just different layers that the
attack has to go through and have an
image is it's just going to be way
better than not having anything else and
I said to be able to give you that
problem just disable the same way that's
the microsoft recommended way of oh if
you have an application this compressive
conflict within one by one disabled them
and see which one cause of the problem
and just keep that one off will keep
everything Hillsong just basically we're
going to talk about goals were
researched out looking but it's
basically valley and my body said
earlier half day's proceeds so no nose
and based on just the roses bathroom
natural after buying right initially or
dance things passing it and then I
extensive list of politics but
application really cool and she has
immunity is well crowdsourcing
and then I control though as you travel
technology shadows back it'll be looking
into this is awesome
you're liable to get out there and get
dirty talk about do tell extensions are
going to use a supporting an earlier
that and remember how sit in the bus bar
potential base is productive remember
anybody heard of shadow set
yeah it's nothing
get ya up so we're going to wrap it up
any questions at this michael i will be
available as well and he catches my mind
so hopefully we did also injected a just
basically all understand it and it's not
perfect and I'll be all this time
it definitely has a lot of work that's
going on right now as we said there's
about what constituted that so fun and
we use it properly more effectively or
plain sight see it was like I will go to
questions are going to be the least we
have our girls sponsors roads out of
students office the event wasn't running
version human toe
well okay but can you guys are fast
no okay awesome and then uh ok that was
broken last reserves that you okay look
up and was then yesterday
no Jack last night
ok I could
you see what's the name of the command
line tool used to configure in it
you're the answer
uh let's see what's name of protection
that and mitigated when i migrated from
one process to the other
yeah yeah okay good job of elastic press
for the sponsors as well many ways of we
have an output and USB adapter as well
as a land turtle so you don't everyone
it's time from built
yeah thanks guys