ids choices so it is the mic on
I don't know i know it is known that
that would be a good thing that you are
ok how about now is that better
alright library actually now we're in
working order her so now that everybody
can actually hear what I'm saying
welcome
ah has said my name is forgotten or
Brian I talking about some IDs choices
and networks and network architecture i
sell little bit history slightly jaded
on ids kind of started at Sourcefire so
little bit of love for snort and
hopefully those people know it and ids
is hopefully yes no maybe
ok some of you anyway
all right arm so along the way i ended
up taking over a few things so running a
nice little CTF and running another
b-sides up in Maryland and hackerspace
and other strange things along the way
pretty much my entire career has been
around the sock world and defensive
architecture so that's been kind of fun
last soccer worked in we actually
combined these two things
does anyone know roughly what left is
supposed to represent plc industrial
control systems so i actually had the
pleasure of building probably one of the
first industrial control systems
security operation centers designed
around specifically monitoring a series
of power grids of power distribution
transmission and getting innocent
generations that was kind of fun lots of
interesting environment step snort in
arm now I end up the teaching folks
about norton sock work as well as
teaching a lovely class up in Maryland
and under . 3 so we end up teaching
water classes and allocated his hacker
spaces and free classes are always good
so I one more things over the years you
kind of put together the faces of sock
monitoring kind of the current status
quo a lot of socks I've walked into have
been somewhere around fat wailing kind
of sad but organizations tend to look at
ok we have tickets we need to close
tickets were getting alerts we don't
know what these mean we get more alerts
then we can deal with so we're going to
rush to close every single ticket we can
in not much thought of actually what can
we do to prevent these alerts in the
future lot of times like these issues
don't get fixed don't get addressed
no one's looking at how do we deal with
this problem one specific sock had a
million event today on the ids is 46
analysts clearly we were able to close
this tickets but not uncommon thing so
kind of call that flailing right if you
can't close most of your tickets
you're missing stuff and you don't know
what you're missing
it's kind of scary kind of the first
step in my mind
arguably wanted to can be interchanged I
want visibility in my network
what do I have whatwhat's there what
should be there and I'll seems kind of
obvious seems very similar to like sands
top 20 has things like an asset list
right along the same lines so visibility
and detection of known threats so what's
out there that everybody knows about
that there's solid rules for they've
been tested all over the place that we
know how to block we know how to prevent
we know how to deal with these things
when we get an alert for this it's not
going to be a false positive it's not
going to be some random thing it's going
to be an actual issue that we need to
deal with so those two things are kind
of the start
. when I end up walking the most stock
operations as the first two things we
discuss on this is where to go first
next is preventing the actual known
exploits right if you can block
ransomware neutrino and some other
exploit kits and really basic tax that
we know how to detect cleanly or not
seeing much only false positives clear
next step right seems reasonable
I've not found many organizations that
have gotten to this point where they're
effectively blocking all known exploits
that are clean that are you have alerts
for you know these are always going to
be true and then kind of the next phase
as much as the threat folks hate to hear
this to me once you have those known
threats dealt with then we can start to
really look at threats that we may not
have such a guarantee on things like
this bad IP address or this bad user
agent string that may or may not be an
actual issue might be just somebody with
love for internet explorer for dough for
example
Thank You HP I or it might know i would
rather deal with that after I've dealt
with known issues before I deal with the
supposed industrial control system
malware that was actually HP openview
thousands of times a day actually about
a hundred thousand so cumbersome story
time so there was a breach recently
getting well recently is arguable this
point but one of the most well-known
reaches as far as what they have
disclosed on how a breach actually
happened came through at least I got as
much as stories i have for any breach
have heard of so in this particular
retail example they had a lovely each
fact vendor up in Pennsylvania they got
phished
happens and most organizations at this
point if its large enough fishing is a
real problem and it's going to happen
our goal of security professionals is to
prevent it from going forward prevent
lateral movement and from them being
able to walk around the network for
months or years before we deal with it
seems like a reasonable possibility it's
good to try to prevent fishing but
trusting the user to do on a hundred
percent job of detecting good phishing
attempts probably not right
even IT security professionals get
fished it's hard sometimes
so kind of that . we're okay they got
fish fine they had saved the credentials
for our lovely retail target for remote
access again the ability one be able to
do remote access based on a single
credentials probably bad plan right
two-factor authentication is not that
expensive anymore we can reasonably do
that
not too hard take some work so they were
able to connect still the one the few
details that have been able to get was
what did they connect through today
pivot through or did they actually
connect from another site that would be
a fun question for anyone working at the
start at the target organization so if
they were hopefully they blocked it so
that only valid IP addresses when I
could have remote access that would be
another reasonable thing that they
probably didn't have set up so okay
each fact vendor now attacker gets into
the particular store and they're able to
get to the HVAC system makes sense then
they're able to move to the point of
sale network knots ago segmentation is
something we learned in the nineties in
theory but not yet today apparently we
still struggle with segmentation across
most IT networks to that
most almost all have segmentation issues
in different points so once they were in
the point-of-sale network they uploaded
some stage 1 malware seems fine grab
take a look around see what they are
playing with so that they were able to
ok learn the label and upload stage to
start to collect credit cards
ok in-memory malware kind of tough but
in this case I their protection systems
ironically fire i ended up detecting the
stage to shower so from that point there
was about a three-day period between
initial detection and when credit cards
being started being exfilled so a
three-day period one detection and they
still hadn't remediated it who knows how
long later so all the credit cards were
able to be exfilled so kind of a bad
response to detection but beyond that
what is the easiest way to find a ton of
data leaving your network anybody no
surprise if you have just a massive
mounted yes sir
netflow that's right when you see each
practice are you guys going over channel
that you don't necessarily transmit a
gig of data or whatever that is in text
worth of credit-card data right
regardless of the factors credit card
data if you have a gig of ftp and you
don't normally use that ftp outbound
kind of weird so netflow would have been
a fun way to detect that beyond any dlp
solutions that
yeah not a big fan of those haven't seen
much success with it
but before we go damning our particular
retailer we really have to be careful
his know the old saying people in glass
houses shouldn't throw stones right
is your organization really that much
different I mean kinda bad but like do
you have a full asset list of every
device you know what mac addresses
should be there
do you have good segmentation in your
network everywhere from say separation
between different departments so no HR
and finance should be on wouldn't say
restricted networks but more protected
than say you know random receiving and
shipping or whatever depending on what
your company does your certain areas
that you want to protect a little more
segments all having very flat networks
with very little segmentation is too
common today having two factor
authentication on every single remote
connection from outside in to me this
seems like it weekly reasonable thing
and not she not expensive to do anymore
it really isn't there's more and more
vendors in the space it's not just RSA
anymore they always had some options but
now things like duo and other companies
have done a good job of making it very
easy
oooff is free if you really have the
time to implement all of it so the
there's reasonable solutions out there
to work on these problems response time
the hall tickets under three days
probably the most difficult one for most
socks out there are a lot fall behind
quickly and never really catch up part
of that goes back to security
engineering but we'll come back to that
in a minute
application whitelisting especially one
a high-value devices so point-of-sale
systems as well as industrial control
systems come with one major awesome .
for protection we know exactly what's
going to be on there and most of them
are very similar so creating an
application whitelist for
your point-of-sale is trivial and you
can test it
industrial control systems little harder
but most organizations today have
servers and other things that they can
build application weightless profiles
for additionally endpoints you can do
application whitelisting pretty well
plate and test mode and see what's
triggering stuff and then enforce mode
so these are features out there that a
lot of organizations could easily
implement but they take time
engineering resources these things are
hard sometimes
so if you are under the same situation
where you had someone coming after you
helped how much different with the
organization be again while target was
go a great example of a breach where
they released all the information almost
there's not many where we have these
lovely case studies with a release
almost every detail but we trust to
learn from so that's kind of a hard
problem but specifically ids is kinda my
bread buttered potatoes of the sock
operation so talking about Matt narrow
little bit more detail so kind of the
four most common IDS's that I find today
in organizations snortin sir kata the
two almost brothers bro IDs now it's
kind of a different type of tool and
then fire i obviously they're here today
and having fun arm so break it down a
little bit i snort from what I've seen
is the most popular again condoms jaded
view given most of the time when being
brought in
I it's for snort Sourcefire type here
being open source and then the Concordat
support through Sourcefire at kind of
nice if you want to do big deployments
signature-based started out in 1998 kind
of an interesting story with Alan
sniffer and more was how the name came
about took some research to find it
suricata I kind of the offshoot of snort
in 2010
they fought this North project to go a
slightly different direction for shikata
still signature-based but kind of a
slightly different goal for sericata
over snort and probably the most known
difference is its multi-threaded
although if you're doing a deployment
big enough where a single thread is not
sufficient with reasonable hardware you
probably should you know looking at an
enterprise to lat . instead of an open
source but I've myself done cat 10-gig
deployments of open-source snort it's
doable it's difficult but doable bro ids
is actually the oldest of the group
started out are one National Labs 20
years ago over 20 years ago and come up
some interesting automated details you
can actually hold netflow a pro as well
which i thought was kind of interesting
first playing with it a lot of power but
probably to me the biggest component of
it is it gives you a lot more visibility
into what's going on in your network
today where we have ever changing
networks that no one has documentation
for a set lists are hard being able to
have a dynamic tool to do visibility and
to see what's in my network what's there
and notice changes not just netflow but
in data types can be really really
helpful in about 10 years ago is
actually when bro really started to get
going ironically through funding from
what I've seen primarily for industrial
control systems department of energy
actually pushed for bro really hard and
kind of funded a lot of its ability to
move to a bunt from a bunch of guys
doing development when they had free
time in the National Lab to a whole
unfunded projects that could sustain and
really make a huge difference over the
last few years it's gotten way more
popular with the ever-expanding networks
just get that visibility
in fire I kind of a customized norton
Luke mind with some other they called
magic and hunting arm unfortunately this
is the only closed source product of the
group also started about 10 years ago
but my only concern is you can't really
get detail of why something was detected
and work on false positives kinda have
to rely on them to do that and I like
fine to sell to me I you kind of come to
a crossroad
what should I use this is a common
question that a lot of words end up
looking at and just picking one without
really looking at differences so to me
kind of the the bro is a little bit off
on its own gives you visibility but not
really detection of threats so it gives
you number one in that lovely face ikol
not necessarily 23 maybe three maybe
it'll block started it doesn't even have
the ability to do blocking his three
prevention of known threats again rose
not something you can really drop
traffic so you come down primarily in my
head to snort first shark otter and also
. wise emerging threats firstsource fire
and these to kind of go at UH the
problem in two different ways so
Sourcefire insist and snort are designed
to look for specific threats they're
engineered to be better at looking for
explicit threats not necessarily IP
addresses or threat indicators whereas
suricata and emerging threats are
designed more around i hear this IP is
bad maybe we should look at it it's
actually engineered to be more efficient
on ip-based rules and other nom
guaranteed indicators so that's kind of
an interesting detail from literally
talking with developers last year at
security onion contrite after security
onion con based on the emerging threats
guy is finally getting that one
in the room and having the conversation
of why do you do IP baseball's force nor
their awful indesign they don't work
very well and I were primarily cercado
circuit design for that I don't know the
sales guy kind of cell ended up
contacting some of the developers for
psychotic turns out they do prioritize
ip-based rules way more than say I'll
others so one of the first things in the
analysis stack was ip-based Bulls seems
reasonable
it's a different methodology arm
Sourcefire and cisco well Sourcefire
says if you have an ip-based rule and
you think it's bad
that's called a firewall rule you block
it but and I don't know to me once
you've gotten your known threats that's
when you can start to take care of
maybe this is bad so there's place for
both but one is better one component one
of better another so security
engineering is kind of hard it's a
little complex like this so which logs
are helpful comment easy question once
you've been in a sock all the while but
when you start looking at how to
configure snort can be pretty daunting
there's roughly two thousand lines of
configuration for snort in addition to
the 30,000 ourselves a labels so it's a
lot of information a lot of choices and
the documentation once you know all
about it can be a decent enough reminder
but it doesn't really teach you how to
use the product how to configure it in
either snorter shark caught up both
running this problem
matter fact even while working at
Sourcefire after the best documentation
I've seen your house nor is designed
comes off the personal blog of somebody
who never worked in engineering
he worked in product support here and i
know this is unreadable at this distance
blind secret calm / wiki
as this lovely chart it literally goes
through the components of house nor
processes traffic piece by piece
this is the only document i have seen
that goes anywhere near this much detail
on how detection works at what stage of
certain things get thrown out when
certain components are analyzed traffic
in depending on how r what component has
an issue with traffic where text where
it drops where it falls over and then
again this is off a personal blog there
was no document remotely close to this
while I worked at Sourcefire and my
friends who are still there tell me they
still haven't seen anything like it
so kind of a hard problem when you
really don't have documentation for
design one how things work so deployment
kind of a mother fun detail obviously
security onion fan favorite here is one
of the deployment options out there
comes as nice oh really if you're going
for production
the ice is not so great you have six
different gooeys you really want a vm
with six cookies with all your company's
protected data and security are you
really gonna go through changing all the
passwords for all the gooey zall the
databases everything the Pat there is a
way to destroy deploy security onion via
package you choose the packages you want
please love God do not deploy the iso in
production for protection of your
organization i know there's guides
online of how to do with the package
system its way better rock and sm is
another tool similar to security onion a
couple of differences in that they chose
one buoy one database are one database
tool they have all the things together
and they added google stenographer which
is
kind of a cool open source free pack
full pack capture tool and then
autoStore same guy who did the design i
made a tool where you set up your system
and then you run his script and it will
download install the tools snore you
choose ago you choose things so much
easier
I'm different deployment options so
steps forward when you go back to your
organization get them get the sock to
start to really look at what's in their
network and start to look at what are
the things that are causing us the most
tickets if you have more tickets you can
manage like most everybody solving that
problem of okay ten percent of our
tickets are this particular rule good
place to start
does anyone have any question yes sir i
would probably never deploy all the
rules at once there's too many that are
applicable the environment arm pulled
pork is a lovely script that allows you
to categorically decide what roles to
use what was not to use i normally would
start with one of the predefined
policies so there's three available
security / connectivity connectivity
over security and balance and then turn
on and off categories and we'll types
based on that and turn off there's a
bunch of really annoying ones things
like echo request and echo reply
these aren't useful rules arm unless
you're just trying to drive yourself
insane
so there's a lot of those rules and so
turning on get starting with what you
think is about right and going adjusting
from there turning on specific threats
you are concerned about in certain ones
you aren't by OS x application
it's a good place to start it is a
living process it is something that
takes a significant amount of time to
work on other questions yes ma'am
so that's not necessarily is particular
to an IDs but more basic network
analysis that's something that's learned
there's not really a great mechanism to
learn how to identify good versus bad
yet it's kind of one of the heart
problems of the sock world and finding
an answer is kind of like how do you
learn decision-making right that's not a
question that i can answer in a minute
i'm still working on how to figure out
what the best way to teach basic network
analysis as far as is this bad or not
it's not an easy problem so that's a
different problem that's not a stage of
how far in and out in ability to see
your sock is that's more around your
people specifically do they have the
skills right this is more maturity of an
overall sock rather than maturity of
individuals if someone in the sock can't
figure out how detective traffic is bad
that's more of a fundamental people
problem arm and I know a lot of the way
that people start is literally jump in
and hope you don't drown again that's a
large problem for the sock community
that we haven't had answered a lot of it
is keep going
analyzing that particular traffic until
you know what it is if you don't know
what it is
figured out first the tenacity to do
that is hard
I'm out of time here i think i will be
around after
thing was know that that's really yes we
could give this