[Music]
welcome to last con again how many of
you were at my talk last year
dave was you were okay this is kind of a
follow-on talk it's the guy that hacked
his garage door opener this is a
follow-on to that what happened with all
of that I'll go into it a little bit
deeper here first I like to do some
audience polling so how many developers
Wow that number goes up every year the
percentage of the room anyway hackers
they put your hand up they won't tell
you they're hackers right serial killers
all look like everybody so my name is
Jason and I'm the CTO at a company
called as tech consulting what I'm going
to be talking about today is a
responsible disclosure I'm going to be
giving you a little bit of context from
the side of a researcher that found a
thing and working with an organization
to get them to fix that thing and I'm
also going to talk about what it looked
like inside that organization to have a
researcher knock on the door with some
bad news
right so Who am I I'm a knapsack
professional I've been working in the
application security business primarily
in a vendor space but I'm a consultant
as well I've done quite a few things in
the apps X space my first sequel
injection was in 98 so it's a guy named
Bob O'Neill there's an apostrophe and
his name I noticed that it caused
problems and that led me down a path
right and a lot of people that end up
like this works that way I'm also a
wireless and infrastructure security
person I read a lot of those releases
that come out about things but I work as
a wireless engineer for a while I do a
lot of stuff with api's we're all moving
to this world where api's control us and
I'd like to understand that so I've been
looking at that quite a bit and I do a
fair amount of work with a charity
organization called hackers for charity
if you ever see somebody with a t-shirt
or back my laptop's as I hacked
charities
we're not hacking charities we're
keeping them working
okay so our goal is to keep technology
running in places where that's difficult
I tweet most of its angry stuff United
so fair warning as some things that you
should probably know about me first of
all this talk doesn't have enough Star
Wars in it at all
you'll notice that later I sent this
talk to my boss and said what you know
what you think and he said not enough
Star Wars so that's in the fair warning
thing anybody here hiring two people in
the back or hiring what you hiring for
app ii red team i don't ask if anybody's
looking for a job because you could be
sitting next to the person that you work
with that doesn't you know you don't
want them to know you're looking for a
job so if you go have a candid
conversation with these gentlemen in the
back that's a good thing if you want to
do the type of research that led me to
those talk I am happy to sit down and
drink beer with you and show you things
if you want to set your laptop up and
make your cell phone work through your
laptop I want to do that too so pizza
and or barbeque might occur but happy to
do it please approach me afterwards if
you want to see the talk that I did
about when I did the research release
it's on the youtube channel if you go to
the YouTube channel for last con I'm the
still frame that they pulled out of the
video me like imagine what the talk you
know with what the speakers looked like
last year I'm the one that ended up on
the the cover as the glamour shot right
please don't go hacking Equifax it's not
fair to pick on those that we would put
in special classes so if you learn
anything here that you can apply don't
go after them and I'd love to hear from
you so if you want to come talk to me
please do that also I pace a lot so I
hope that doesn't bother everyone first
con anybody is this your first
conference one two great welcome to this
crazy little Club that we have you'll
probably see some of these people all
over the place this mic is bugging me
a little bit all right so this all
starts with you work for a company your
company develops us something it's
probably on the Internet right that's
these statements are probably
categorically true what happens if you
get a letter in the mail you get a tweet
you get somebody dropping stuff in your
web server logs whatever that is right
what happens at your organization if
this call comes in what I found out is
if you haven't thought about that at all
this is going to be a very long process
it's going to be extremely painful for
both people or for both sides both
organizations if you will and it's going
to be something that you really should
be considering an incident right you
probably have incident response policies
and if you don't I'm happy to chat with
you about that but this is basically an
incident that's occurring
no one has lost anything yet you hope
but this is an incident that now needs
to be looked after a lot of people take
these types of reports and they consider
them to be like having a pen test done
and getting a line in a pen test report
and I'm telling you right now if some
researcher has been banging on the door
and figured out a way to get in it's not
a good idea to take that stance right
you need to take it a little bit more
seriously than well we hired a company
and they ran an analyzer and it came up
with a thing this is somebody spent a
lot of time on you right in my research
it took me a couple of days to get
everything together right I made it work
in like five minutes but it was a couple
of days of why is it working
am I going to get penalized can I find
another person that has this and moved
the problem right this is a lot of time
that I spent on this if I wanted to take
it further right I could have I just
simply stopped where I was and said
there's a flaw I now need to notify
these guys and so I picked up the phone
and I made a phone call
basically what I'm saying basically I
got curious right I got curious about
things and as attackers attackers get
curious about things
curiosity is good right drives us
forward and so I noticed that the
Internet is now a physical world thing I
can turn the lights on in my house from
here I can open my garage door from here
I'm having kinetic interaction in the
physical world over completely
virtualized communication and so that
got me curious right what what does that
mean what are those things so I wanted
to look around my house and see well you
know I bought all those little things
and plug them in and loved it
what what have I done okay and so I
walked around and I started looking at
all the stuff that I'd plugged in and I
really wanted to understand what I
wanted to know was could somebody break
into my house through my garage door
opener or
unlock my front door or something worse
right when you talk about IOT hacking
you often hear about well your Bluetooth
signal is sending out your Wi-Fi
password if I'm close enough to pick up
the Bluetooth signal or see your Wi-Fi
password I'm pretty close right in my
opinion the the the problem with IOT or
the the problem that could become the
problem with IOT is our internet
connected refrigerators are all talking
back to an API surface what if I attack
that surface and turn all of the
connected refrigerators up to 80 degrees
right and spoil all the food well if I
can do that kind of thing right there's
worse things that can be done in more
places so that really that kinetic
physical thing is something that I
wanted to look at and so I I did so what
does that mean for you well somebody's
out there looking right if they haven't
started today maybe they'll start
tomorrow but pretty much guaranteed
they're gonna start what happens that
they find something are you ready for
that
is anybody ready for that it's often
hard to to gauge readiness on that kind
of thing a lot of people like to hide
behind their EULA or their terms and
conditions we started looking at this
little GPS tracking device a few months
ago in our research and one of the guys
said wait the terms and conditions say
right in it you're not allowed to do
security research on this thing and I
thought well that's a really weird thing
you know don't don't do research on us
like then that ticket work will say that
so that that seems odd right so I we
have lawyers right so I went to the
lawyers and I said all right
hypothetical situation here what are
these terms and conditions meet and she
said basically the precedents that are
available if you're doing this for
safety or for security for the general
public this type of research is
permitted especially if you find
something and so it's difficult for any
organization to duck behind their EULA
or behind their T's and C's and say oh
well you use this in a way that you're
not supposed to we're suing you because
you're doing this research for the
safety and security of others hopefully
this last line is important to
understand they're coming they're going
to be in right they're gonna make their
way in it's going to happen so you got
to be ready right so how is the
researcher going to get a hold of you
today yeah so if you have an active bug
bounty program that's a good way to do
that right that gives you a good way to
have communication actually communicate
of the researchers you may actually
attract real researchers that people
know it's a good way to do it
anybody else have abuse at or anything
like that some kind of email list nope
and that's the thing right so how are
you gonna get notified well I sent a
tweet right Chamberlin you got this
problem the customer service guys they
you know customer service these days all
hooked into Twitter right so they send
me a thing back DMS your problem and we
will
Polly help you so I do that though Oh
hmm that looks complicated please call
this number so I call in and I get the
customer service agents yes I'm a hacker
out in my driveway and I opened my
garage with my laptop okay um let me say
it different ways right so basically
what happened was they were trying to
talk me through resetting the pin that's
on the wall next to the garage door for
when I forget my transponder you know
they're like well will you just take the
battery out you push this into my hang
on no no no I don't need this to get the
door open I can open the door that's not
the problem right it's the problem is I
can open other doors right that's what
I'm trying to tell you I spent a lot of
time just dealing with customer service
right but how are they going to get to
you maybe some website contacts right
maybe you got something in your DNS
records you know you have to think about
somebody's outside your organization and
they're trying to get to you also once
the call comes in what do you do right
so there's really no standard way for a
researcher to report to you that means
you probably have no standard way to
further that right to push it forward
and that's something that really has to
be considered eventually we're gonna get
to somebody that understands what was
said on the phone so you're having an
incident what do you do for that what's
the thing that you have to do for that
when I was in the military we had things
like this posted at watch stations right
this is the FBI's suggested if someone
calls in a bomb threat what you should
do right and if you go down through this
list that's pretty good when is the bomb
going to explode this is what you're
supposed to be asking somebody reporting
a problem to you right when's the bomb
going to explode
what's it look like why did you do this
okay and then you'll notice that
questions section is pretty long and
it's all packed together really tight
can you imagine trying to you know
answer this thing on your first bomb
threat right
and then the exact wording of the threat
this is going to be hyper important for
analysis later
it's freehand you got to write it in
there remember exact and that's after
you've asked all this stuff and then
there's a bunch of this once you've
filled this form out who do you give it
to right does it go to the FBI does it
go to your boss where does it go right
so we got to have an understanding
what's missing here
well what's missing is the procedure
after this and that's where we really
start to run into problems so how are we
gonna get a hold of you well here's a
good place to start there's a kind of a
driving force these days of folks that
are trying to put together security dot
txt right what we want to do is like the
you know favit Co it's like robots.txt
right this is if you're trying to report
to somebody go to their domain slash
security txt and there's a format for
this thing that you can stick out there
to have people contact you that's a way
is it a good way is it a bad way well we
don't really know yet but a lot of
people are pushing for it ok since I'm
looking at your web page anyway why
don't you talk to me over my connection
right so here's an example of the Etsy
store they have an ex recruiting header
right where they say is code your craft
go to Etsy calm slash careers right
they're talking to people in the way
that they are going to see things how
many people are reading the ex
recruiting header right that aren't
really deep looking at the website give
me that stuff you know you could put
into comments on your HTML you could
just simply put a comment that says hey
if you need to report something to us
here's a URL that no you're never gonna
find anywhere else click this link right
see how gullible they are it'll be good
there's a robots.txt it tells the you
know Google BOTS and the page indexers
where they are and where they're not
allowed to go it's one of my favorite
things to go pull when I'm
looking at a website simply because
there's always sensitive data in here
right I don't want you indexing my
really sensitive thing and so it's a
great place to look for stuff right
you'll notice this one's got a lot of
forms in it
this is United's they have a lot of
forms that they don't want the bots to
crawl well why don't we just come up
with a humans txt this is how the server
communicates to the humans right in
order to convey a message something like
this right so if you find a weird air or
give us errors at or whatever that might
be
I'm saying there isn't a standard but
you know maybe we can create one you can
come up with a lot of creative ways to
do this but as soon as the call comes in
someone's got to deal with it right we
have to triage it in some way and we've
got to move a forward into the
organization could very well be that
customer service is where they're going
to end up that phone numbers everywhere
right oftentimes the sales number is
available for instance if you want to
talk to someone at Equifax you'd like to
go speak with a human being at Equifax
today the only person that you can talk
to is a salesperson everything else
refers you to a website or your
Congressman or whatever but you can call
a sales person there I've done it you
got to wade through a bunch of you know
VRU prompts and stuff but once you get
there you can say things like I'm just
really interested in all this data that
you have but can I get a cheaper
elsewhere
there's keywords that you should be
training your customer service folks on
right there around security and they're
around reporting incidents right and
really incident reporting responsible
disclosure and the words security should
be something they're listening for
anyway if you are not currently doing
security training with your customer
service group on a regular basis there's
conversations that we can have around
that but you should definitely be
impressing upon them that security is
important reporting an incident to us is
important etc but definitely you know
give them one of these things where it's
where's the bomb right is it going to go
off are you reporting a security
incident to me and I always recommend
drilling right I was in the military
drilling makes you ready for stuff right
so running drills is never a bad idea
even if it's on an irregular basis you
know only once a year or whatever but
drills should never be punitive right
they should always be a rewards base
good job you caught it or nobody caught
it so I finally get through right series
of tweets they give me a phone number I
call finally I get through to the
organization I explained to them I found
this thing
it's a replay attack against your garage
door I can open and close the door I can
open and close others doors I control
the entrance to the house right was the
thing that made them all perk up because
when I started saying things like I can
open the door and close the door they're
used to that activity right but when you
say I can get in the house well they
created a problem right so now they're
interested in the problem and they're
interested in the solution and then I
explained why I set off to do this
right you don't always end up with
somebody that's doing responsible
disclosure that you know really cares
about it they're just I found a thing
but here I was trying to trying to get
through so eventually they're going to
get through to your organization right
there's going to have to be somebody to
talk to about or maybe they won't get
through right if they don't get through
Brian Krebs is gonna notify you're right
or somebody like that it's it's it's
going to be important that you pay
attention to the stuff that comes in
someone's going to set up a time and
you're gonna have a discussion an adult
conversation with someone that's telling
you there's something wrong with
whatever it is that you have these are
not fun conversations to have right
it's not going to be super pleasant you
have to be careful though right if I
spent six months figuring out how to get
in and I tell you I can get in believe
me right and try to keep me out but you
got to react carefully with this the
researcher might be a little unhinged
that's certainly true in my case
so I finally get through I'm gonna sit
down and have a conversation with some
lawyers and that gonna be fun
right this is who they put me on the
phone with a product manager and two
lawyers step one call the lawyers right
maybe have a conversation that isn't
let's go legal right
the lawyers loved throwing around
culpable and liability right which I
just threw right back at them you know
you control the openings of lots of
people's homes would you like for me to
tell everyone that right you need to
back down a little bit so today so um I
wanted to have an adult conversation
with them so there's a sky out there
named yawn Albert yawn spends most of
his time finding cross-site scripting on
websites and telling people you've got
cross-site scripting on your website I
worked at Qualis several years ago we
stood up a new blog the guy that stood
it up forgot to put request dot validate
and search box yon found it right he was
really nice about it he sent us an email
right and said I've got cross-site
scripting on your website here's your
proof of concept right here's the link
you can click awfully nice of him right
I was at the time in charge of that so I
turned around to the guys and said hey
you forgot something go fix it so they
go fix it right so I get on the phone
with Yann because I want to understand
his motivation I want to understand what
he wants and his whole thing is he
doesn't like cross-site scripting right
everybody at when I was at Qualis
everybody was like see if he wants a job
or what does he want a t-shirt you know
what is it that he wants and he wants
less cross-site scripting and we've
that and he's happy but the thing that
you get with this and this becomes
important later and I talked about it
quite a bit later he's now going to
tweet thank you for fixing your
cross-site scripting you don't get off
the hook that easy okay he's still gonna
tell the world I found it on your
website but he tells him after you fix
it
right which is nice of him I guess
calling lawyers is gonna definitely make
the researcher take a big bite out of
his chair right we got to try to figure
out a good way to say we need to have a
discussion there may be lawyers present
just simply because there's going to be
legal water that you're treading on but
having them talk in the meeting is
probably a bad idea right and making the
lawyers be quiet probably won't be easy
I'm not sure you know because they're
gonna want to jump in and why did you do
this you know so the point that I'm
trying to make with all this is we're
going to have to go through the standard
workflow of change right this is called
the direct curve when change occurs this
first step is this change ain't
happening right we're gonna go into not
we refuse to accept the change we want
to live in the past
whereas you didn't know about this and
we didn't either but then what happens
is you go through time you resist the
change but are aware of it right flowing
through that you understand that there
is a need to change and then finally at
the end you're going to commit to or
conform to the change right so knowing
that your organization is going to go
through this curve right when they call
the problem doesn't exist oftentimes
when I hand in pen test reports we go
through the direct curve right we don't
have all these problems
wanna bet so I thought I'd start with
denial this one
happens to be in Africa
it's the Nile View casino right there
that's where hackers for charity is that
this is a ginger Uganda it's at the
headwaters of the Nile right was at the
beginning of denial
so it's an appropriate response when
something is defined not doing that like
that's too hard how many of you guys
have had some major change at work where
everybody just went wow we're never
gonna do that right we've all seen that
happen right sure I worked for an ISP
for a long time we built frame relay
networks all over the place and then
this weird IP VPN thing came out we
didn't have to do point-to-point
networks anymore as crazy
one of the old-school network engineers
locked herself in her office and refused
to come out until we told her that we
weren't gonna do that right that's
denial and it creates tension when you
tell the reporter who just spent six
months digging in on this thing that it
doesn't exist he's going to either or
she's going to throw up your refutable
evidence or run away and tell everyone
which is what you're trying to avoid
right we don't want that and it's a
little bit insulting right so what you
should be doing is trying to figure out
what the researchers motivation is
that's definitely important right
perhaps they want bragging rights maybe
they want a bounty right if you don't
have a bug bounty program maybe they're
trying to kind of coerce you into have
one they may try to extort you you know
I'm gonna put this information forward
if you don't X if that occurs standard
call law enforcement procedures apply
right like don't let them extort you yes
they're going to get angry you got to
figure out what they you know are gonna
do from that point but you know
negotiating with terrorists rarely works
so I have the meeting with them and they
say well we're going to go off and
validate these findings now during the
meeting I said how many people are on
your security team
and the answer was zero so how they're
gonna go off and validate the findings
is a little weird because you don't know
how to use any of the tools that I'd
know how to use right I've been using
burp suite for a while you are just new
to it right setting this up is not
simple you know so they're gonna go off
and validate my findings
they're not gonna validate my findings
right they're never gonna be able to
figure out what it is that I've done and
so it actually it will roll you back
around to the denial phase again if this
isn't handled right you have to give
them a lot of information they were
silent with me for several weeks right
when I was communicating with them
they're off validating the findings and
realistically they're just going off to
do whatever work it is that they have to
do from the researchers side I
understand I knocked on the door and
said oh hey your front yards on fire
right now they got to go put it out but
they already had fires going in the
backyard right so there's you know a lot
of stuff that they got to do but you got
to remember communication is a good idea
here I asked for a meeting at one point
because I was sick of them ignoring me
and I wanted to take the word redacted
out of my slide deck so that I could go
talk about this thing which I had done
and I got it CES week we're super busy
right which I understand you know there
this company makes a machine that picks
up a door because you're too lazy to get
out of your car right but then they put
it on the internet like and that's you
know that's questionable so alright fine
they went unanswered emails I was in
fairly constant like hey hey hey guys
come on
you know I've got a sales background you
can imagine right
but eventually they get back to me right
so my point what this stuff is don't be
this organization
and keep your enemies close keep talking
new right because if you're keeping the
researcher happy they're not turning
around and doing more research on the
problem that they found right because in
this time they may be going a little bit
deeper I may find a better way to
execute this that original Python script
that I wrote to iterate through all of
the possible consumer devices that would
open doors all over the planet didn't
work the first time right but maybe I
could come up with a way to make it work
you're gonna keep making me angry I'm
gonna put you in the public right and
that's what you want to try to avoid
treat responsible disclosure like any
ongoing incident Pony Monde says in that
IBM report that came out it takes about
70 days to notice somebody made it onto
your network right 70 days what were you
doing 70 days ago until now to change
that probably nothing right they sit in
your network for a long time and so
doing this kind of thing means that
incidents become long-term projects and
they always are right in addition to
that 70 days to statistic it takes
another hundred to get them out of your
network right so it's important to
understand you're going to be
communicating with this person a lot
after a while the denial starts to fade
away right and we start to move into the
resistance phase yeah maybe you're right
denial for me meant them saying that's
really hard to do how many of you guys
have heard that's those hackers in the
room right you you do a report that's
really hard to do who would do that
hackers that's who
the people that want in are the people
that do that what they when I knew
they'd moved out of that phase is when
they said to me well I've seen you spent
a lot of time on this right like I see
that you have buried yourself in this
thing and B since I could name their API
endpoints on the phone like they knew
right like I've spent some time with
this so now we're moving right now I
know we're gonna start making progress
and this has got to happen at your
organization the faster you can get down
here and start moving up there the
faster this all goes away right but if
you stay in the denial phase for a long
time and never write any code it's gonna
be a bummer but now we understand this
is happening we're really doing this
guys and we need to go get it fixed the
researcher will help you right they
started asking me questions how would
you hide our api's what is the thing
that you would do to solve the problem
that you're showing us right what are
the things that led you down this path
suddenly in the communication became
very fluid very help us right you
understand this we see that helped us
and the researcher wants to help you in
yan all bergs case if you get rid of
more cross-site scripting he's one you
know so let's help let's get some help
but have some respect for the researcher
right maybe they want some compensation
out of it maybe they don't maybe they
just won't mention whatever right fly
them out by a mistake
lime home whatever that thing is try to
figure out how to make this equitable
you're trying to encourage a behavior of
hey tell us if you find something in the
future the next phase is exploration
right we've given this some thought
we're gonna really work on this we've
engaged with an organization in my case
they stalled a little bit here and they
asked me like what would you do and I
said well the very first thing I'd do is
pen test this thing go hire somebody and
here's a list of organizations that do
that thing get somebody to bang on this
for a while perhaps stand up a bug
bounty I don't know right like you need
to go
after this a little bit harder but here
are the things that I would change
immediately and the first was pinning
the cert off the mobile app but they
didn't have any idea how to do that
where do I do that right you got to
remember people don't make mistakes
people do what they know how to do it
just so happens security counts on that
right you're not making a mistake you're
just not doing it right
there's a difference so when we start to
really move through this thing we see
that there is a need for this change
right and we've got to move your
organization internally is going to go
through this as well and you got to try
to keep them moving forward right in
this case moving forward meant they
actually had to shift into forward right
which was a good step and we started
really moving down the line for you guys
the researcher is gonna offer solutions
pay attention right because it's the
things that would have kept them out
right so you want to pay attention to
that kind of stuff some of the solutions
are harder than others right like oh
yeah we're running on you know old IBM
Java 10.4 stack and we just can't uplift
that thing ever right you know that kind
of stuff well guess what you still have
the flaw you need to come up with some
way to get out of this thing right full
pentest bug bounties like but you have
to also look at what happens when we
create a fix for this thing right look
at crack how many of you guys have wpa2
running at home right how many Wi-Fi
routers right everyone in the room well
when they fix crack and it's fixed how
do we get that deployed onto all of your
devices right all of your devices your
mobile apps or your mobile devices you
know your Windows Mac Linux machine you
have at home well if you're on Linux you
priority update it but the you know the
ramifications of we're fixing this could
be wide and ranging for them it meant
pushing a new mobile app right they fix
the app
and pushed it right and now they've gone
back and they really are connected
they're back in but the very first thing
that they did was push a new mobile app
with app insert right and some security
things that I suggested for them but you
look at Charlie Miller and Chris valasek
when they hacked into the Jeep over the
cellphone Network right the impact of
those fixes was pretty big
the cellphone Network had to change they
had to fix all the jeeps right or Fiats
or whatever they were they had to go fix
all the firmware on those things and
then they realized there's a bunch of
vehicles that are still out there I have
the problem so they mailed a USB key
around everybody they created a new
attack vector if you want me to say that
differently and they had to go you know
fix all that it's crazy to think about
but there has to be a way to push the
solution out and what about something
really difficult like ATMs right think
about the responsible disclosure that
Barnaby Jack had to go through right he
called Diebold and NCR and said hey with
a little bit of malware I can just make
the Machine pump the money out right to
which they were like yeah whatever right
they didn't really listen if you read
the whole history on this he went to
them and said you have this problem they
said ok we'll fix the problem and then
they went silent just like everybody
does right but then he said well I'm
taking this to DEFCON like I'm gonna
have an ATM pump money out on stage
that's happening right and it was really
that oh yeah this is gonna go into the
public eye that got them to get the
lawyers involved right
they issued cease and desist letters
they told Def Con that they'd had to
close like it was amazingly vicious the
way that they treated it and he's like
but you're outside of the period that it
would take to fix all this
but deploying new firmware and new
software out to a bunch of ATMs is not
just click and it go
right you ever been to an ATM at a gas
station you ever been to an ATM at a
bank there are different networks the
gas station ones are pull networks right
they dial-up and they go this is a
difficult problem but it doesn't change
the fact that Barnaby Jack figured this
out and should be able to tell people
about it it just you need to now go fix
your ATMs and at the end of the thing he
did Jack bought an ATM right but the
responsible disclosure that he had to go
through was extremely painful he you
know had to go through another one with
the medical stuff that he did
unfortunately we lost him in 13 so
eventually they're gone public people
are going to talk about it it's gonna be
amazing right now whether that going
public means oh yeah we can find 143
million Americans records in this one
website that only charges six Bitcoin
for it or going public could very well
be tweeting about it
hanging signs off freeways who knows you
don't get to control it right so that's
the tough bit in all this when it comes
out you lost control of this fact you
need to be ahead of it before it goes
public if it's fixed your mobile app
have that push out right and just work
with the research way we're pushing
tomorrow
it's going to populate out on the
servers you know everybody's gonna get
their update tomorrow night please don't
talk about it until Saturday right and
that's an easy conversation to have you
should expect though 30 days from the
day that a responsible disclosure occurs
30 days from the day that I tell you you
have a problem I'm telling the world you
have a problem that's the assumption
right in my case I negotiated 180 days
with them they were pitifully difficult
to deal with but they were extremely
happy that they were getting it fixed
they're just really slow you know like
they make a machine that picks up a door
you got it you know keep that in mind
but eventually you will lose control of
this information and when it gets
disseminated and I want to be labor that
point for a second you're going to lose
control of this information that is
happening so you need to be ready for
that right now whether that's your PR
team like in the case of Equifax needed
to hire new one or in the case of you
know Oracle with the CTO going crazy you
need a little bit better PR team one
that has empathy for the problem one
that has empathy for the people that are
affected by it but you will lose control
and the day that it happens you need to
react correctly now you could be in
control of the information you could say
a security researcher called us and told
us we had a flaw that's why you got a
push last night right now you're all
positive ahead of it you're moving
forward right rather than being reactive
so some keywords some things that you'll
notice in your organization when you're
moved to the exploring phase and what
the researcher will notice is that
you're starting to ask a lot more
questions right is there a way that we
can solve this problem is there a way
that you can help us more how do we take
a look at this a much deeper way and
then maybe offer beta option right you
get to see it before everybody else tell
me if you think we fixed it could you
bang on it again a man free research
right it's not a bad idea and once you
get through all that and you're moving
into commitment we're gonna solve this
problem or at least we're gonna tell
people we solved this problem right and
you're gonna move toward that and that's
great we're gonna go get to work right
Chamberlin back and they went and
tighten the security up on it they pin
assert the very first action they did
was they pin the cert I was happy with
that that was a great first step right
it proves to be more difficult now to do
the things that I did right and then
they started moving down the line
a little bit further right and they did
things like if you violate the
certificate they invalidate the session
that you presented right that's a nice
way to do that now I got a log back in
again
I gotta have certain negotiation work
you won't let me get to the login page
if my cert isn't right
that's a nice you know first step if you
will there's a lot more that they need
to do with the way they do things but it
was a pretty good you know kind of limp
in to this if you publish a fix and
start working on things and you get it
out there this is a great time to review
how did the incident go right this is a
good time to post-mortem what happened
when did they call you first
when was it fixed develop a timeline on
it when did we have that meeting with
the lawyers right and start to look at
how will we react to the next one
there's the next one coming right
somebody's always looking at things and
you may have to be worried about that
were you easy to get a hold of it's a
good question for the researcher right
how hard was it for you to get to me how
many layers of stuff were in between
right at any point where you're
dismissive of the findings or of the
researcher right that's something that
you really need to look at it consider
did you appreciate it did you show them
right like I say your alternative
notification paths of crying crits
right and that's not the way that you
want it to work you want to be a little
bit more in front of this kind of stuff
was a disclosure in any way helpful
finding some other flaw or some other
bug that you had if that's the case that
researcher needs credit on that too
right we looked at the thing you told us
about
and notice this other thing thank you
very much for finding these two things
it's really awesome of you
in summary people need to do their own
research right somebody's going to call
you someday and say there's a thing but
realistically you should know your
perimeter where are they going to be
doing this research where is the attack
point right now how can they get to you
you need to be approachable right some
of these are just soft skills maybe you
need to get on their side right bug
bounty programs brought up earlier is a
great idea the bug crop guys are here go
chat with them about it
I do that stuff I'm sure Dave does that
stuff since he works on that integration
there's you know plenty of opportunity
to work things out there yes
yeah when I'm having you and don't tell
you about it really depends right like a
lot of times you'll see somebody just
banging on you that's you know you're
trying to hit my WP dash admin I don't
have one that's a bot right that's not
research it's when really either trying
to find a specific thing and notify you
of it right I I really wanted to know
can I open the garage so birth is a
attack proxy it allows for you to sit
sits in between your web browser and
what it is that you're doing and
basically logs all of the things that
your browser goes don't fall into the
trap of going to ticketmaster.com
because it will crash burp does
ticketmasters crazy but if you human if
you go to any other website you'll
actually see like i type in my username
and password and hit enter i get to see
where the username and password is in
the Datagram that gets sent back to the
web server so it's a you know really
great tool for that what I did was I
hooked it up inside my laptop to listen
to my wireless interface and then I
joined the wireless network with my
phone
and then all of my apps everything my
phone was doing at that point it's going
over burp and I could watch it and then
replay it do whatever I wanted that's
how it worked one of the things that I
like to make sure that I get put out in
any of these parses I'm an educator I
love education if you want to be
educated in this thing I want to sit
down and educate you so if you would
like to have a session where we set this
all up and make it work or I hacked
stuff whatever that is I want to do that
right like I said in the beginning that
usually occurs over beers and jokes and
you know I used to be in the Navy a lot
of my friends will tell you you put a
couple of beers in this guy and the
stories are awesome so I'm happy to go
do all that if you're too shy raise your
hand and say yeah let's do that or
whatever I'm pretty easy to get a hold
of I'm on LinkedIn Twitter please come
right I'm happy to educate folks than I
want to every year I do this thanks to
the last column staff because they put
together an awesome conference every
year if you want to attend good
application security conferences there
are three in my opinion app SEC USA
which occurred this year at Disney last
on and Tim's he's sitting on the edge of
his chair AB setcap those are all really
good application security conferences
the staff here is always amazing bring
back a video game and and they're always
really good good folks to work with
there are vendors here everyone hates a
vendor please don't hate a vendor right
there trying to help solve problems they
paid a lot of money to sit out there and
watch you eat you know nachos stop by
ask them what they do right sometimes
they have things that might help you
sometimes they don't so take a look at
right and for the last point here
everybody in the room gets ten style
points you can apply them any way that
you'd like how do you sell it to your
boss I'll give you a card
[Laughter]
yeah all right well thanks everybody
[Applause]