[Music]
and congratulations for having step that
you're all 100% smarter now all right so
the contents will include one novel
topic and that is how to deceive machine
learning I'm sure that's something that
not all of you expected there will also
be a contest and Mark will be the judge
and hand out the $25 amazon gift
certificate that is B prize so my
metrics offers great promise
however spoofing is still very easy
Samsung cs8 that came out earlier this
year face detection was spoofed and then
a month later Starbuck from the Chaos
Computer Club successfully spoofed virus
detection maybe one of the first to give
an official account of how he spoofs
face ID by the way these slides are up
on SlideShare they're also posted on the
Alaskan site if you have any trouble
getting them just let me know
biometric recognition you all know what
that is
it's the automated recognition of a
person based off biometric and
behavioral characteristics so here's a
system for enrollment there's a live
capture you capture a digital image of
finger face voice whatever
ear print I print the print palm print
and then features are extracted in the
case of finger prints minutiae are
extracted and
scored and then a person will come up to
a sensor and or whatever the biometric
trait is and then there's a comparison
of the templates and based on how the
system is so this is a way it's a proxy
of your physical self in the digital
world but what's wrong with this picture
yes it is a question right so the
question is at normal practice to hash
and yes I'll talk about there are many
methods to hash or encrypt or transform
which you guess so that the template is
stored in a safe unruhe triva believes
not subject to reverse engineering and
I'll get to that but the other thing
that's wrong with this is depending on
the context the image is archived
especially in the mobile you space
Android varies but in the world of iOS
they document this they say they delete
the digital image as soon as they create
the template because there's really no
need to create a four of your digital
images why that's just you create an OPM
situation and the OPM Office of
Personnel Management 2015 the breach
resulted in 5.6 million fingerprints
being stolen so depending on the contact
you really don't want to store the
images so you really
the images are saved and why do you have
to ask if you're evaluating a biometrics
vendor some of them you're smart in
government or military and they're used
to saving the digital images and then
they turn around and they sell that
product on the commercial market so
unless you ask you don't know if the
images are being saved so a bit about
terms I use the word spoofing already
and they're spoofing anti-spoofing but
in the world of ISO they're very
specific and they say the word spoofing
can apply to many different contexts it
can be misinterpreted so they use terms
symbol to find them a presentation
attack is really trying to avoid being
recognized so you try to impersonate in
a biometrics recognition system and here
you see the real face and some attacks
some presentation attacks go to attack
mask attack replay attack replay attack
you can get a second phone take a
picture yourself and show that picture
to the first phone and then the second
rose
that's from computer vision it's just a
way to transform the top row so that a
computer can say yes or no that's the
real person or a fake and the other
thing to note about my metric system is
they may not be able to differentiate
between an attacker and a non-conforming
presentation what's a non-conforming
presentation David and I know this we've
worked at a place that has I were to be
sober at a place that has fingerprint
readers and if your finger is the least
bit damp the way we'll read so
okay try again so that that would be
non-conforming another non conformant
presentation with the and this is the
case with face ID if you have sunglasses
that block IR infrared then you you
can't use those with face ID when you
finally get the phone I haven't gotten
the phone I'm looking forward to getting
the iPhone ten but if you're going to
use specialized sunglasses they may not
work that would be a non-conforming
presentation so it's closer to call it
being we can get a little bit gory we
talked about this earlier another way to
do a recent presentation attack is with
mutilations and going from clockwise
from upper left taking toes and creating
fingerprints from the toes upper right
is just biting off the fingers the
fingerprints bottom left is acid burning
the finger and then on the bottom right
stitches on the finger precludes people
from properly presenting their
fingerprints so in in some cases people
go to great lengths to prevent or avoid
recognition term pad detection and this
can be done actively or passively and a
lot of time and attention is spent to
determine if if it's a live person or a
fake I say a picture what's the
difference between the picture of a
person or a live person and are they
using a 3d mask so let's look at valle
nur abilities and the classic attack
diagram so this vulnerability fishbone
diagram is minier told but it still
persists i had to block paint at the
bottom these are four categories they're
intrinsic failures administration
failures especially for enrollment
biometric overton assalatu your
biological biometrics they're not
secrets
you touch a glass all over the Internet
your voice has been recorded and then
you look at the infrastructure there
many vulnerabilities in terms of replay
a Trojan horse hill-climbing
who knows what hill climbing is that's
an iterative process where you almost do
trial and error to get something to work
and in 2012 a lot of hill climbing
attacks were presented so people made
harder to do these hill climbing attacks
in fact they started they started even
encrypting the scores or outputs from
biometric systems to prevent hill
climbing attacks you know it's a little
bit about watching biometric blockchain
solutions out there and some of them
still have some issues so this attack
diagram this is from Malina ratha he
wrote a landmark paper biometrics of
biometric recognition and this is any
other system we have attacks to override
a signal modify a probe but what's
really different is the presentation
attack at a sensor you would use a false
finger a fake voice etc and it's easy to
modify the decision but two things we'll
talk about are intercepting the image at
the sensor especially on an Android use
case and deceiving machine learning so
let's look at this who went to blackhat
USA back in 2015 so two guys from
fireEye
weigh-in Zhang presented a number of
ways to defeat biometric recognition
systems on Android and I'll cover two of
them and this one they had malware on
the phone and they were able to
intercept fingerprints at the sensor
this has been fixed what's the best way
to fix a vulnerability or a problem have
it out at at blackhat product
back home they're reorganizing and
making sure it's issued they
demonstrated that black hat was the
attacker can register his or her
additional fingerprint or override an
existing fingerprint on the phone so in
this case the user had registered three
fingers and the attacker wayne's and
they were able to register a fourth
finger that's been fixed - so who's
familiar with machine learning deep
neural networks all right do you know
how to deceive machine learning be
Tibetan close you're warm you're warm so
I have to warm up slides this is one
more up slide number one to warm up
slides before I get to the Reese
Witherspoon slide now the reason I have
warm up slides is that the Reese
Witherspoon's slide failed the husband
test showed my husband Mark David knows
my husband Mark and Kari have you met my
husband mark so he's a software
whisperer he is built deep neural
network systems and models he's my
resident expert I showed him the Reese
Witherspoon slide he goes no way and so
I went back I go I'll give you to warm
up slides to get to the Reese
Witherspoon slide
so here's warm-up number one on the Left
I apologize for the fuzzy image that's
how the researchers did it is a car and
was used to modify that on the left to
make the image on the right if you look
closely can you see those little dots
there's a little green and red dots this
is the modified picture that a deep
neural network identified as a cat now
to you and I that looks like another car
but to the deep neural network engine
that look like here's another example so
who knows of
temple the Monocacy temple in india on
the plaque is the unaltered image and
then in the little in the middle here
that's the distortion that was made and
they're just slight perturbations
distortions made and then here is the
the modified pictures on the right what
does it look like to you the same
building but to the deep neural network
it looked like an ostrich you are
sufficiently warmed up with the reese
witherspoon in this slide and you're
perfectly William willing you can you
can stay like my husband in the the
world of disbelief he wants to really
talk with the researchers I sent them
some email and said has that this been
reproduced I'm still waiting for a
response so anyway these were
researchers at CMU Carnegie Mellon and
UNC University of North Carolina and
they set some rules the attacker can't
attack a system until it has been
trained
you can't poison this system you can't
inject mislabeled data you can only
present a modified picture to the system
to defeat it and so what they did with
is starting to geek frames and they got
they printed out the modification and
affixed it to the frame you see the
pattern here in the middle picture and
some of you were able to make
witherspoon appear as or be classified
as Russell Crowe by a deep neural
network and the key is they wanted to be
able to have someone I can use my
glasses is it
yeah excellently they want to have
someone walk through an airport and fool
TSA or go through London with all the
closed-circuit TVs and not be recognized
or be recognized as someone else
these are researchers with a tiny budget
in a nation-state or someone else with a
large budget going to town with us
so attack mobile device and mark I'll
need you to come up to the front of the
room here's where the contest comes in
contest for the $25 Amazon card who
studied the OWASP top 10 earlier this
week anyone go to the tech okay did you
cover the mobile top 10 no ok well or
maybe you can extrapolate them because
there there's some similarities and for
an m6 look like they're related someone
but m4 is in secure authentication with
an N and m6 is in secure authorization
in the sea who knows what the difference
is between the two of those because
there is a distinction if the insecure
[Music]
authenticate identify user it's here
authorization to be failure you know
when someone active tries to login
failure just stopped for me
again mmm close close you've got the end
right but not the Z part the
authorization part what is authorization
mark you're supposed to be conducting I
see any way to raise their hand
optimization is about access I think I
know the uses but what kind of objects
is reusing not you access right what
objects can the user access or what does
the user allowed to do good good son
we have a winner so um someone said that
mobile is the new after several
immersive and mobile devices are growing
in number I'm sure that the bad guys
have a product roadmap just like we have
product roadmaps and they're looking at
this they're seeing that by 2021 600
million mobile devices with biometrics
natively supported from the manufacturer
and any number of face voice iris any
number of modalities and then I don't
know if I quite believe this but this is
from acuity research they say that by
2023 biometric authentication will
enable 1.3 seven trillion dollars in
payment and non payment transactions so
if I'm a bad guy that's a good target
just look at liveness detection with a
live person the skin and blood absorb
light differently than a dead person and
would line this detection you can see
that the iris will respond to light
there's heart rate of pulse and for
liveness detection you can also ask a
user to do something like blink smile
shake your head turn it right turn the
left but to all these different ways to
make sure that it's really a live person
presenting their biometric traits so
what's the matter with just blinking
maybe or they could be wearing a mask
when USAA came out they had one of the
things you had to do with this is an
early 2015 they came out with biometrics
for them the mobile app people were
creating the face they were about
printing out the face and then putting
it in with a cutout eyes just blinking
to defeat the system so with all the
issues around - detection many
organizations I picked just three here
are creating standards for liveness
detection the phyto alliance the first
one fast identity online alliance they
will have certification for biometrics
for finger and it's rumored to come out
later this year
ISO has a standard called 3107 that's
not zip code that's three zero one zero
seven and part four which is still in
draft form is for mobile devices and
then in Germany the federal office for
information security has a standard and
Safran Morpho is supposedly the first
vendor I'm not sure if the only Karen
might be able to talk about Gemalto but
they've achieved this certification for
liveness detection and I've heard about
this why I raised to find out what are
they done it says and new rigorous
certification and all it is is turn your
head to the right turn it down and see
the guy laughs he's doing the selfie
he's in a very precarious spot so to
turn his head left right would be
dangerous in fact where is this guy who
recognizes where he is yes
mmm Brazil Brazil what city Rio de
Janeiro and what statue yes yes quite
even our AV guy who Christ the Redeemer
right yeah so he's in no place to do
live dose detection and so I recently
evaluated over 50 biometric spenders and
they were at a loss for liveness
detection and I said well you know if
you just go to this contest this is give
them earlier this year was the
international joint conference on
biometrics and they feature liveness
detection competitions for iris
forefinger I said go there the
researchers with also in the future
liveness detection will have to account
for VR virtual reality these are
researchers from University of North
Carolina and by the way I have
non-disclosure agreements with some of
the biometrics vendors so I can't
reproduce what they have told me but I
can point to academia that's why a lot
of these slides point to what's going on
academia but with a very little bunch of
UNC researchers took a face off of
Facebook it took the pictures and they
did feature extraction characteristics
they created a 3d model textured it to
look like a face they added the eyes to
gaze correction they added expressions
and then they use a VR reality viewing
system and they successfully defeat
facial biometric recognition assistance
so this is something to look for in the
future if you're either shopping for a
building or even just using a system
different ways that convenient tabula
rasa that's an acronym this is an
organization out of Europe and they are
funded by the EC the European Commission
it's a conglomerate many many vendors
and organizations from around the world
contribute to this and just look at the
the red font here I won't go to all the
detail but they're looking at combining
multiple biometric traits don't just use
face don't use just iris use a
combination and they're also looking at
novel methods for liveness detection so
these reports will come out in the near
future
so we talked about blinking or turning
your head right there's some
alternatives for liveness detection or
presentation attack well you can use
algorithms in software or hardware and
this is raghavendran he does a lot of
research Christoph Bush David awful
knows and so if you if you computer how
to look at these different inputs it's
much better at determining the fake so
on the left is the real image then the
laser printer ink jet printer or a
replay attack using an iPad and if you
take some algorithms from computer
vision it makes it much easier for the
computer to tell the difference between
the fake and the real thing that's local
binary patterns that's just an algorithm
from computer vision
so there's some advantage and you look
at the the red font here you can
leverage machine learning much easier
the algorithms are in software if it's a
hardware it's more expensive it consumes
more power in some cases and it might be
slower let's say you're waiting for the
multiple heartbeats to ring in so we
talked a little about you have talked
about template protection biometric
template protection why is that
necessary
people can see the templates and this is
one example this is from work that
started back in 2009 and then the paper
was published in 2011 so this is nothing
new but researchers took the minutiae in
the upper left corner able from the
minutiae to recreate a fingerprint and
it used to be the case that if you ask
someone starting with just the template
can you reproduce the biometric example
and it used to be people said the answer
was no well the answer is yes and I've
had this debate with so many like those
50 vendors I've had this debate with so
many people I started referencing and I
print this out and I would cut paste
this and send us an e mails this is the
report this came out in June of this
year and the title is biometrics in
search of identity and security and the
authors are the who's who of the world
of biometrics mark Nixon Sebastian Mao
cell they come from Canada Finland UK
Italy France Switzerland so they they
made a special point to call this out
that it is possible to reverse-engineer
the templates
so now all of you will go away in some
contests by having this answer and so
there are different ways to protect
templates remember you asked about
hashing well if there's something called
cat's biometrics and it uses hashing
biometric encryption homework encryption
who knows what homomorphic encryption is
Karen I'm sorry this so that's what
that's when you operate on the data
that's encrypted and you get the same
answers if you operate it on it in the
clear but everything everything all the
data stays in the homomorphic or
encrypted state right right and so there
are there many ways to do biometric
template protection this is just a
sample and there are vendors looking
employing this or permutations of this
right now and they're not you need an
NDA to discuss exactly what they're
trying to build in but they now
recognize that it's possible to
reverse-engineer the templates so
they're taking action to protect it
and we'll go into detail these are
slides for reference but for cat scible
biometrics you transform the template
and then you compare everything and then
with biometric encryption let's say you
have a fingerprint you take the minutiae
or some characteristics and then use
that for key binding or key generation
and then we just talked about
homomorphic encryption where everything
stays encrypted the entire time and in
this example we even keep the score
encrypted so this just is just an
example that there are many ways to
protect the templates so if you ask a
biometrics vendor are you protecting the
the templates and they say no you can
point to them there are many options
that they do have so the biometric
templates are evolving one way to get
around
this ability to reverse-engineer a
biometric template is to make it much
more complex so instead of having just
one biometric modality in the template
some companies I'll name it this there's
one company called a brain out of the UK
and they're adding biological behavioral
and divides sensor inputs into the
template so instead of doing just a
point in time just a fingerprint or face
or voice from the mobile phone and
putting that in the template they're
adding dozens and dozens of inputs there
at the touch the touch screen the
pressure everything you do for it for
instance a banking transaction how do
you type how you swipe how you hold the
phone there adding the time location and
any number of biometrics and even if
you're not using your phone it's in your
pocket there they're keeping track of
how you walk they're keeping track of
your location so it's very accurate but
what's wrong with this picture if you're
concerned if you're about privacy person
like myself
that's very privacy invasive
so here we get to biomed biometrics and
watching by the way I'm no advocate of
biometrics and blotching but it's a big
buzzword there a lot of small startups
they're getting huge amounts of DC
funding just to do biometrics and
blockchain and it's biometrics and
watching because the blockchain is no
place to put any of your identity if
someone says oh you know they're doing a
biometric system and they're putting
your identity on the blockchain that's
that's the wrong answer
you can you go we'll go into why so who
has heard of watching I'm sure you're
all familiar ok here's one example who's
heard of ID 20/20 that's a project and
the problem statement is that there were
over a billion people that don't have an
officially officially recognizable
identity and so companies like Accenture
and Microsoft are donating a lot of
their time and money to create this
block chain based biometric system to
give these people longer refugees and
identity and they're using fingerprint
and iris first on the right hand side
Inc this is their basic philosophy and
strategy for biometrics and watching the
identities are decentralized that's my
definition of watching and they're
anchored by watching IDs they do have
the IDS are and it's linked to zero
trust data stores in other words the
biometrics are stored in a zero trust
fully active environment and we all know
by the end of these last few days
nothing's like that they are calling it
zero trust data stores that are
universally discoverable such as that's
one example and then this is another
example from IBM it's based on their
hyper ledger example and the object
store is where they're storing the
template data and the image data so
again if you have when the first
questions and I asked them why you
storing why do you store the image data
and part of the answer is this is for
government and Homeland Security
so if you look at the application for
this you can see it's Department of
Homeland Security TSA Interpol and what
their goal is is interoperability of
biometrics they all want to be able to
access or share the biometrics now there
are some concerns did anyone learn about
any of the vulnerabilities on the
watching last few days well your some
how is the cryptography handled is a
open source and peer reviewed what do
you do if you've lost the private keys
what do you do if the keys are stolen
private blockchains might not really be
as publicly decentralized as
cryptocurrency implementations that are
out there there might be single points
of failure subject to ddos there's a
superuser somewhere that's the whole
thing with launch then blocking the best
things that's life spread right well
somewhere there's a super user with
admin rights that can change anything on
the system right it's just it's really
just another piece of software and then
you might have some load or performance
issues at large scale and what when I
say that well we've gone from databases
to block blockchain mines how we really
create anything that's more secure and
if you're still storing the biometric
images especially in the clear then
there's arguably no advancement so the
other thing is there are numerous
blockchain implementations out there one
of the earlier the ID 2020
implementation was aetherium and many
experts claim it's difficult to
construct a threat model on which to
perform a risk assessment I've asked
some people for their threat model for
blockchain
and they haven't supplied any and they'd
say in in this world blockchain its
complex its emerging still still new
technology maybe poorly and probably
understood so here's from Dilbert and
the boss comes out to Burger goes I
think we should be a little watching
Burgos does he understand what he said
or is it something he saw in a trade
magazine and so he goes to his boss what
color do you want that blockchain he
goes I think mauve has the most ram
there's just a little of levity with all
this seriousness so what's gonna happen
in the future first risk and a caring
talked about risk earlier risk will
become more more important because there
are trade-offs if you're doing all this
risk mitigation it can have the user
experience the cost the performance and
so if you have a low risk application
maybe you don't go as far as if you have
a high risk application that needs more
mitigation and more liveness detection
and presentation attack detection this
is from China Kentucky Fried Chicken in
China
and this is where there's a video online
and I have references almost all the
slides a bottom left-hand corner she's
in China and she goes to Kentucky Fried
Chicken to order dinner she goes up to
the kiosk touch screen orders dinner and
there's a 3d camera and she enters her
phone number and walks away that's a
transaction in the future she'll just
smile and pay that's why it's called
smile to pay and then who's ready for
this is a more like it gets to bring
prints and using your mind as a
biometric mode for authentication who
reads ACM magazine ACM is - software
what I Triple E is Tom Hardware and the
authors are saying that law enforcement
made a huge arrest reviewed your mind
and they contend that that that gadget
that you have that's in your hand all
the time it's really a prosthetic part
of your mind which just so happens to
make phone calls and they also warn what
part of your thoughts you have to shield
or protect against surveillance or
inspection or detection of any kind
so there is some research going on in
this area the National Science
Foundation recently awarded over a
million dollars and they want to know
what are the vulnerabilities were the
strengths and weaknesses of brain
biometrics look forward to seeing that
was I just in November that was awarded
in time for gratitude without these
people doing research and being pioneers
of the field we wouldn't be where we are
today this is an eel chain he heeled it
he wrote the book on biometrics say
Bastion male cell he's doing research in
pad algorithms Nalina ratha with that
original attack diagram and christoph
Busch who does research in both Norway
and Germany and with that any questions
yeah but my kind of imagining about
battery-free you age your hair grows
skin says you might get a sunburn right
is anyone considering adaptively storing
that information so that say they don't
have an image from a year ago but they
actually adapt as you yes there are two
parts to that so the person is about you
age especially with face finger doesn't
change as rapidly but face does Anil
Jane says that facial biometrics have a
time staff they should be an update at
least once every three or four years and
then with face ID I don't have all the
research but there are implications and
inferences that they continually update
intently so the machine learning knows
well hey if you had a big full beard the
hot hit a lot of the face math for the
lower face that they would update the
template that would evolve over time but
yeah that's that's another challenge
with biometrics and if you if you have a
cut on your finger or your voice changes
with a cold they're all subject to
change that's why more and more people
are saying to don't rely on just one
biometric modality use a combination
good question
Cresta saw princess ring goodbye
hundreds of persecutions markedly if
they're happy they have nutritional
right i you separate listen to the whole
presentation right little a bit so you
can fill it all matters
Fedya - first up I seem to do that well
we just tried to add a pregnant woman
and so here the house you know Adam a
fine today
so what you see it would be a lower
grade five hundred if you find that evil
establish your identity or gender as you
can see somebody in a dress
the the brain biometrics is still fairly
new is still a lot of research although
as far back as 2013 people were using
brain waves as a form of biometric
recognition when I talked with who spoke
earlier at East Keith Blum research he
takes glasses and he has two sensors for
toe on either side for total of four so
four sensors to connect to the brain
he's doing physical physiological
physical and chemical detection but
you're right on with the thing with
they're all human beings we change we
evolve so and then you get back to the
aim great example where they include
your location your device type and then
it gets more complicated but you relying
on one modality is is really becoming
insecure
it's grabbing it but she won't ever get
baby though she would have to deny
access to Quebec get sick call South
Bend on profile and that's 100 he ever
did someone but he hasn't urged with
Bryson
so of course besides the turn weapon on
his feet
fascinated on tonight and informational
the girl skinny has diverged into this I
was tri-state was those technologies
Ostia
so just disagree swiped up its domestic
things and you try to see max Tennyson
alive who's being trusted under stress
at for devotional however would even
communicate right access to
right the part about under duress there
a lot of you can add the heart rate in
perspiration there other things out of
Israel El Al airlines they were
experimenting with different ways to get
biological readings on the person just
to detect if they were a terrorist
my partner actually interested in early
and
right are these and then you get back to
the brain waves the brain waves which
show cognition that they understood to a
bit committee a which means you were
stupid like my feet but if you if I
heard that it would register somehow in
my mind because I understand French that
way yeah
had
but those longer things that's what this
is closely connected as you're looking
these show factors but that really
weren't sure what you want what you do
with that information
otherwise we really said well you know I
don't want the chip either although I
know he's a college it
No
so I mean this stuff really scares me
actually because from a data privacy
point of view it really gives way too
much information about any person and in
my view and I imagine that there are
people as this develops on the other
side there folks is going to be
developing cloaking mechanisms like how
do you stop systems from getting
information about you and does it
doesn't mean like oh it's nearing
instead of smiling at smiling pay for
the glasses that make reese witherspoon
look like Russell glasses or you know
because I mean I would I'm pretty
uncomfortable with the level of data
that's already out there about me and my
family I mean God how much more do they
need and so and as a person who has a
privacy certification C IPP /e and
studying the GDP are your biometrics are
classified as sensitive data under the
GPR and you need to get consent before
you collect so I think this sees some
backlash and with that backlash more
people demanding that if your biometrics
are being collected that you have to
give consent or that you control that
there's something called
user manage access where you control all
of your
authentication identity attributes but
the horses left the bar in terms of
collecting our data and then even under
GDP are there are exceptions to getting
permission and if it's for Homeland
Security prevent terrorism they have all
the illicit exceptions they can still
collect your data but I think they're
gonna there's going to be a run on those
special glasses or something to make
cloaking easy that'd be a great startup
idea right
it's a question so I was curious if you
have a large organization that
implements a specific solution with
biometrics and we are only five minutes
or ability like it's by photographs for
example how should the organizational
situation so the states a large
organization and you're talking about
employees or customers either one so
they have an issue with that first they
should notify you know notification if
it's a the customers they should tell
them what happened and if it's employees
maybe they can do an internal memo or an
email but and then then they have to
remedy this the system but once your
your biometrics are out there they can't
be reset it's game over but at least
they can notify the people and you saw
it happen with the OPM breach 5.6
million fingerprints along with all the
security clearance information was
stolen it is out in the wild and and so
the other thing that you can do is if
you're a company and you're setting up
the biometrics in the first place you
can take measure to address all these
vulnerabilities but it's a it's game
over once they're out unless you're
going to stitch your fingers like that
and I would make sure yeah
so I kind of feel like we haven't really
hit on it that much except for you can
pointed it out during your talk there's
always a superuser right to me that's
the most important point you made in all
of this that there's always somebody who
has all the privileges yes you know and
and kind of to that same point security
the user is really the most vulnerable
part of the security system so it seems
like rather than spoofing the system and
I'm sure there will be more complicated
schools and more complicated detections
and all that but social engineering
instead of you know you don't need to
spoof the system to think you're the guy
who has access to the building you want
to get into you just need to get the guy
who has access to let you into the
building because he's already God right
so no matter no matter how complicated
the detection gets they're still social
engineering right and and you've
probably been to DEFCON and gone to the
social engineering village where you see
how how easy it is as soon as there's a
human element for spoofing the game over
there too and so so if you if you work
an environment where their fingerprint
readers there's the person the super
user the admin person and then there
might be five to ten other people they
have access to that system let's say
that your fingerprint reader isn't
working and you want to reset your
fingerprints and issue a new template
that person there might be multiple
other people that have access so it's
not even just the super user there might
be a number of people and they have
access then they can update that and
then who has where the if there's a
central database where is that stored
was so the point is well-taken that you
just have to get to the super user for
the blockchain the biometric system and
that that might be a much easier hack if
you will good point
well what about separation of duties and
constant longing for review that's how
y'all got to understand a we got right
if there are separation if you depending
on how large your organization is if
there's an organization maybe of just
200 people and they're using biometric
finger sensors at every door there might
be maybe one persons in charge of that
there might be three to five other
office people that have access to the
machine to update fingerprints or enroll
a new person so it just if it's an if
it's a small person who you know who
says they want but if it's a larger
company I could see where the separation
of duties definitely should be there
yeah that's good it's just yeah very
good
all right time for one more let's say
it's already said yeah thank you very
much