[Music]
so thank you everyone first we're coming
to our talk we're gonna give a quick
overview what this is about
it's basically how to get into security
if you're already an IT professional or
if you're not even IT yet this is a
really good talk for that we're gonna be
covering a lot of resources not just in
the realm of stuff that'll help you in
the job interview but also the resources
will help you kind of land that first
job kind of the technical resources
including like the social networking
side of it as well the hard and the soft
skills and much much more so with that
I'll go over Who I am
I'm Tommy Tommy do I'm a security
consultant at rapid7
I started an IT at the age of 16 and
since then I've been breaking stuff have
a background at am so what we'll cover
some more of this stuff later on but
also certifications and I'm also a
former Blue Team err internal security
I've since made the transition on
offensive security and I think that
about covers my side of it so I'm he
said I and I first started getting to
computers when I was 8 I was always
curious and seeing how things work then
I would take them apart and sometimes I
was able to put them back together not
always though so I have a like a whole
bunch of circuit cards under my bed that
I just never really fixed but so I was
always just curious on seeing how things
worked and I knew I wanted to be a
developer because I like video games and
I wanted to do my own video games they
make my own software and it was also
kind of different for me growing up
being a girl in IT or just in general
with liking computers it was kind of
frowned upon sometimes but it's just
something you had to work through and
yeah alright I'm also going to take my
uh my a stealthy 3m cover off of this
laptop
all right so education so I attended
Texas name University I was actually a
political science major I wanted to be a
lawyer horrible idea glad I didn't do
that because I fell in love my current
profession but I worked in several
campaigns and it was a lot of fun but
eventually I got into security and my
certifications I have the G CAH that's
the certified instant handling
certification through sans also the
CompTIA Network+ working towards my G
pen which is an offensive security
natured certification through sans and
also the OSC P so I think these kind of
certifications really help sort of fine
you know the knowledge of my security
career but we'll have another section on
certs that cover a little more about all
of them later on okay so I went to the
University of Texas at Brownsville and I
did study computer science I was a
little unsure about computer science
most excited to do robotics or at least
computer engineering to get a little bit
of electrical background but they had
computer science so I took computer
science it was like I said before it was
a little tough because there were only
like two girls in the whole computer
science degree but I mean we made it
work and you kind of sometimes kind of
have to show like prove to yourself and
prove to others that you know you're
good enough to be there I have my comp
Tia Security+ which we'll talk about
later and I also I'm studying for the
osep awesome so hopefully with this kind
of work experience side you'll kind of
see the transition and path that we've
came to be where we are today like I
mentioned earlier I started in tech at
the age of 16 and even before that it's
kind of like if you race cars you have
to you know learn how to work on them
and maintain them I did the same thing
with computers with gaming at a young
age and then yeah at age 16 when I
started out as a student tech at am that
was kind of the transition from the age
of like analog to digital so we were you
know installing Ethernet cards and that
was the pre service pack one day is on
Windows XP so lots of fun times with
worms and viruses such as like blaster
Code Red at the time so you
engage also was involved in high school
they had like a two-hour program to
basically do all sides of hardware and
software you like junior senior year so
I got a lot of experience that way early
on and then I eventually transitioned
from that student worker role in to a
NOC analyst role so if you're not
familiar for the NOC is it's just a
network operation center and I did that
at am and was kind of like a nerve
center basically for networking issues
and making sure that there's uptime in
resolving those issues so from there I
really picked up a lot of my bosch Linux
experience and also a lot of my
programming experience there as well
because when you're in understaffed
program you have to learn the automate a
lot of stuff and so moving on from that
I then went into our internal security
department at am where I first came in
and really some of the first things that
you do in a security department in that
type of an big in university environment
it would be a lot of log parsing log
analysis and analyzing packet captures
so that gave me a lot of really
substantial experience cutting my teeth
on on a lot of security topics by doing
that eventually transitioned to doing
incident response and the incident
response side of it really I guess gave
me perspective of what attackers were
doing on networks and it was super
useful to take those previous skills and
transitioned into what I do now and
offense and in the offense side of
things
I'm basically a security consultant like
Casella here and we're doing penetration
testing for clients so a penetrate
penetrate and tester is someone that
will simulate real-world attacks on
clients so yeah well like I said I
started with technical support and I was
doing everything from installing voice
over IP phones to networking and also
getting phone calls and it's like km ice
my screen is upside down
I press something and I don't know what
I did so I got all those kind of funny
phone calls but then I went to database
administrator for the University and I
was doing some database and integrating
with ASP
and just doing a web application but
after I finished college I moved to
Austin I wanted to get a developer job
but the whole catch-22 so I was like
well I'll go into in QA and then from
there I'll jump into development but I
found out that I was pretty good at
Quality Assurance just breaking things
and it was more fun sometimes than
building them but so it's just breaking
things and I've figured a lot of
vulnerabilities and I kind of started
liking it I stayed it was stayed with it
for six years but then after a while
kind of start getting a little bored of
it you know too repetitive and my
husband told me that I should follow my
passion which has always been security
but when I was growing up it wasn't
really a career so so I decided to
follow that and I started studying for
the come to us security plus and then a
little bit short after that I got and to
rapid7 which is really great company to
work for if you're doing like a beginner
entry-level they have different programs
well we'll come to that a little bit
later yeah get excited about that okay
so why are you interested why are you
here what drives you what this kind of
career requires you to always keep
learning new stuff it's not just like
you get a job and that's it I'm done
it's there's always new things coming up
so you have to have passion because
without passion you're gonna give up and
you're not gonna want to do this anymore
you're like well you know I feel like
I'm always having to breathe and study
and stuff and you know I want to do
something else so you kind of need this
to be in the security field all right so
I think to kind of transition
what is Zelda mentioned with passion is
certainly something that's going to be a
driver for all of the kind of things I'm
gonna
now and we were talking about this and
what we think that really makes a good
security professional and security
analyst which is kind of a generalist
term in our industry are really three
kind of technical areas that we think
are really they they really solidify
that foundation that you need in a lot
of these positions
first and foremost networking learn
tcp/ip it will open so many doors for
you and it's something near and dear to
me because that is the kind of like
large background that I came from it
really gives you that understanding of
how things not just move from A to B but
also to X Y Z like around the entire
world so having a solid understanding of
networking is really great operating
systems so preferably you know there's
Linux and Windows preferably become a
master of at least one of those that's
really going to I guess help you
understand certain environments you're
gonna be in with either your clients or
you know the company that you work for
and then the third section that I think
that really helps have a proficiency is
will be scripting and you don't need a
full view be a full-blown developer but
that certainly helps it come from a
development background or to be
interested in that but just having an
idea of scripting something like an
interpreted language like Python is very
useful and if you're gonna be working in
Windows environment or you prefer that
powershell of course is incredibly
useful
so really with those three technical I
guess foundations
it's those really set you up to with the
first step to build it then break it
mentality and security and you can
continue being a builder too if you want
that's totally awesome but what really
drives all three of those and what you
know keeps you interested in it is the
idea of having that passion and
continuous learning all the time
security is not a field that like we go
home at 5:00 and we're just like you
know hands off I'm done you always have
to be learning always have to be hacky
and always have to be you know continue
yourself it's such a dynamic field and
things change all the time you know
having that background will just take
you pretty far and now we go into
security positions so in security they
borrowed a lot of terms from the
military such as red teaming and blue
teaming and we
kind of help identify in this talk a lot
of different security positions based
off that kind of coloring system and
then they even have something called
purple teaming which we'll get to here
in a second so for the where I came from
was the blue team and ignore the green
lightsabers I had added in there anyways
because the Yoda is cool I don't know
about the other guy who he is so for the
blue team there this is really I think
it's from doing both sides of their jobs
and hearing what other people have done
it really is sometimes the harder job
because you're always under attack you
don't have that type of first strike
ability you're always going to be on the
on the defense so within the within blue
team within defense security jobs you
will usually be working on an internal
security team so under the title of like
a security analyst and kind of like what
I mentioned earlier what I was doing
you're gonna do a lot of times log
parsing looking to kind of build maybe
you have the IDS a security product that
gave you an alert you may have to go
track down and the logs and see what
happened from start to finish
maybe confirm that there is a breach or
an attack on your network and from there
you also can do Incident Response where
you're gonna have to go out and kind of
like put fires out for a company or
either of your internal company or you
could do a consulting realm of that as
as as well so and on top of that there's
also people that do reverse engineering
of malicious software usually that title
would just be like a malware analyst
they can have them in-house sometimes or
sometimes you can even write like
signatures for security products as well
and you can be a security researcher in
that side but yeah so blue team defense
where I came from I really like it
however I switched over to the red team
recently and it's yeah this is my
passion what I love and in with red
teaming you're going to also have
sometimes internal red teams and they'll
just be a group of penetration testers
that will attack their own company and
kind of I guess help sharpen you know
iron sharpens iron an idea they're
basically going to start helping the
defense get better by continually
attacking them because if you only have
maybe one incident or no incidents at
all a year you really
get that real-world experience you can
also do consulting like what we do as
penetration testers so yeah we'll
basically come in and attack a network
and kind of the demonstrate that
real-world threat rather be through
something like social engineering or
maybe you're sending phishing emails to
people to try to get them to click on it
or even physical assessments where
you're going to come in and maybe have
to pick some lock sneak into a company
do tailgating clone badges stuff like
that so it's really simulating some of
these attacks that do happen the
companies you can also be a security
researcher and kind of the manner that
people will reverse malware you can also
do security research to try to find
vulnerabilities and exploits and develop
those also for rapid7
like we developed for Metasploit so
there are people that that's what they
do or develop for these offensive
security tools and so another thing that
we wanted to talk about two or
certifications I can help you in the
security realm to get better so some of
the certifications as I mentioned I'm
wearing my sand shirt today too but for
sands I can't say how much how awesome
they are any more than they speak for
themselves they have the course that
really helped me in Sands to kind of I
guess get that mindset of what attackers
are doing it was the sans 504 instant
handling course was super useful and
then also took sans 560 which is the
offensive security course but sans is
awesome but they came to a little bit
pricey so if your employer can't pay for
it or you can't yourself you can also do
like a work-study program it's about
twelve hundred dollars but you basically
ta for the course for a week and yeah
sans is super awesome stuff and then
there's also offensive security which
covers the OS CP and that's very much a
penetration testers certification and it
really helps to do very practical real
world real world experience very
hands-on labs that you can then
demonstrate hey I can do this too
and like I was previously talking about
I have a Security+ which is a pretty
much entry-level security certification
it's not as expensive as though a CP or
even the C eh but it's a great
certification to get your feet wet and
it's not hands-on so it's more of theory
like like physical like locks and stuff
like that but it's also this disaster
recovery plan and just kind of it's like
has a management section and kind of a
little bit of the offensive side and
defensive but it's a good certification
to kind of get your feet wet and then
there's also the C eh which is the EC
Council and that one is a good
certification just to get a little bit
of it's a little bit more hands-on the
security plus but it's a good way to
learn the tools that you use that will
you use for doing penetration testing
something that we do want to bring up is
not all companies require certifications
and you kind of want just research the
company that or the kind of job that you
want and see if they require
certifications I personally think they
are worth it sometimes it's just a
little checkbox that HR needs to just
check off so you can get it further into
the interview process but they are
expensive so try to consider what your
goals are don't try to get all the
certifications because then it kind of
looks like you're not really like focus
and you just want to learn everything
and that could be a bad thing sometimes
but yeah so definitely recommend them
the the one that a lot of if you want to
go into penetration testing osep is the
standard for most of them so you can
always try to get something like that
yeah one more thing too so we also kind
of should've mentioned the CompTIA the
networking plus one is really good too
and one that we really like because it's
it's not just a certification but also
helps open doors of concepts that you
may not been introduced to through
their formal education or experience and
so yeah they're working plus for me and
I think really help solidify oh they're
these really cool concepts like tcp/ip
and it yeah so and they're not that
expensive either so it's something that
you can totally do on your own alright
so we'll cover InfoSec meetups so
another good way to get security
experience is also to do the social
aspect of it and one thing that we're
kind of fortunate here in Austin to have
are a lot of awesome meetups and your if
you're not from Austin there are other
great meetups too that will usually
happen through some of these
organizations something that's near and
dear to our hearts is aha the Austin
hacking Association they've been known
to go by a few other names associated
with that but it's here in Austin at the
end of every month and basically what
they cover are ten minute talks but
everything that's spoken inside that
talk stays within there and can't be
spoken outside of it but what's really
cool about that is you'll see sometimes
content that will be at a presentation
nationally or locally coming up so yeah
aha totally great way to meet some great
hackers if it's a little intimidating
crowd sometime so if you're not ready
for that there's also 2600 meetings from
the 2600 magazine and those are like at
Whole Foods every month as well downtown
but those are a little easier way to get
into meeting other security
professionals or networking with them
and they also do lock-picking there too
which is pretty cool well you guys might
be also familiar with oh wasps I mean
they're kind of the ones that are
sponsoring the last con but a wasp also
has meetings once a month at the end of
the month in National Instruments and
it's a great way to meet people they
have presentations like this and then
they also have study groups I think
right now one of them one of the books
are going through it's a black hat
python book and they're also doing the
web hacking hacker's handbook yeah which
is a great book to look over but they
also have a happy hour session locks
once a month so it's a great way to
socialize me people that
in industry it's also a great
opportunity just to you know get to know
them you never know they might know
about a job and might reference you or
something so it's always a great way to
meeting people and also the is c-squared
they do they meet once a month and
indeed you don't have to be certified to
go to this meeting so you can go and
like they also have presentations and
they have peat free pizza and everything
so something fun to check out I think
that also this afternoon they do have
awesome it's like at 3 o'clock on the
local infoset community talk as well so
that should be pretty interesting
another way to get some good practical
experience that's kind of can be quick
and dirty and expensive or capture the
flags one that we've been playing a lot
is hacked the box so hack the box is
awesome it's just basically it's kind of
like this etf's that we have here at
last con you're basically going to have
a point system and you'll have teams you
can get on with your friends and you can
do you know collective team rankings but
what's really coop up these or they
simulate real world networks and
machines that you may run into either if
you're a defender or if you're on the
often side of things and you can get
experience hacking attacking them
legally of course so to speak and yeah
you don't have to set up like your own
home lab which I will talk about here in
a second
but yeah they're just really good
practical experience to get on and I
think there's another one that you like
yeah well I'm just calling about hacking
the box to get into it you need to crack
them the invitation to even before you
can even sign up so you had to solve a
puzzle before you can even start playing
with it another capture the fact that I
like is over the wire and spend it this
is like the first level that you have to
do so you can complete you put it what
it has to do is like it's just a great
way to learn Linux you basically just
have to SSH into the box and find a
readme file that has a hash for the next
level and the levels get harder and
harder as they go
and you start learning new skills down
here you see the comments that you may
need to solve this problem they kind of
give you a little bit of hints it's like
okay you might need the LS command or
something so there it's really basic way
of learning Linux it's a lot of fun it
has kittens too so so that was kind of
the more practical very kind of you know
almost quick and dirty way to get
experience it's cool because you get to
keep rankings and stuff but with that
type of mentality I mentioned earlier
with first build it thing you have to
break it I really like home labbing and
home labbing can be a pretty inexpensive
way to get hands-on experience even if
you're not involved in IT yet so but one
of the foundational aspects of that is
the idea of virtualization so it really
helps to have a good understanding of
virtualization and if you're running
some type of virtualization product and
your desktop like VMware or VirtualBox
you can have different experience
I prefer VMware but you will have to pay
a license for that VirtualBox is awesome
too it's free just sometimes the setup
is a little different but I don't want
to start you know a war about between
the two but but they definitely have
their pros and cons but I prefer VMware
just because its ease of use for me also
if you have a bare metal machine just a
PC you can also run ESXi it's free and
it's just something that lets you manage
a bunch of virtual machines at once and
so that's a way that you could set up
you know maybe for 812 operating systems
and have your own simulated virtual
network and it also has virtual
networking included too so they can all
talk to each other and you can have
networking equipment involved in this
home lab the hardware that helps for
this I love that it's pictured the Intel
nook these run for about $300 or so and
they can get pretty beefy as far as like
how much RAM and the space you can get
on there and the processors are always
modern so these are super awesome what
I'll do is I'll get an Intel nook and
just put ESXi on it and then spin up a
bunch of different operating systems and
have my little network there that I can
bring up and down and if you're not
familiar virtualization there's also the
concept of snapshots where you can take
basically and snapshot of that machine
and time and save it so then if you
decide
your computer you can just rap spin up
that snapshot again or restore to it so
virtualization super great concept to
have in your tool set but when you're
building out that home lab when you're
deciding you know okay I have the
hardware what do I want to do next the
software that's out there for it are
things like Metasploit able which we
have a trap at 7:00 and it's all open
source is basically something that is
just a operating Linux operating system
that has a ton of common and popular
vulnerabilities that you'll either run
into an ax penetration test or you may
have on your own network so Metasploit
people is pretty awesome and then
there's also a security onion which is
kind of like the if you remember of Kali
Linux the offensive security
distribution this is like the defensive
one for defenders and there are a lot of
defensive tools on there like an IDS's
or log analysis tools or seems familiar
with those which bases you just log
aggregation tools and also good ideas to
build out your own domain controller I
think Microsoft has like student
licenses you can get if your student and
you can build out your own domain
controller and set up some clients and
associated with that domain controller
and then you can start attacking them
and you can start looking at the traffic
with things like a networked app I have
one pictured here
it's a throwing star from Great Scott
gadgets you can basically hook up
Ethernet cables to it and tap the
traffic send it to a distribution like
security onion and see your own attacks
against these systems in real time and I
think that's a really cool concept to
get into because then you're seeing
what's happening not only with your own
tools but you're seeing what it looks
like in your logs when you use those
tools and just having that practical
hands-on knowledge really helped me I
think get that kind of homework done at
home rather than having to look at stuff
like that on your own network at work
when you don't even know what it could
look like and also it's a great place to
play with tools that may crash maybe one
of the servers that you're working with
the client and so you can know maybe how
dangerous a tool could be so yeah it's
all super great stuff to get into and
also if you have a home lab it's really
good idea to also get like use Cisco
equipment off eBay or something like
that and especially if you're interested
in the networking
side of it and just get that use
networking equipment set up a switch at
home and you can hook up all your
different computers to it and yeah it's
a great inexpensive way to get
experience so let me think another laps
also goodwill is a good place to find
stuff like that too so the Raspberry Pi
I mean it's a very easy way inexpensive
way of playing with it you can install
Linux on it you can do so many things
but you could also build your own
pineapple so it's a good way to to play
we're around with things and unis I have
to be just hacking or anything just you
know try to make anything that you like
and learn the development skills if you
don't have them so it's just a great way
of learning things
yeah and to go off of that one thing
that I learned when I was in the NOC
position was I got a good hands on with
Linux experience and one of the things
you can do as a Linux from scratch
project and what's awesome about this is
you get to build your own custom Linux
distribution compiling your own kernel
and building everything from source and
it's a great way to understand how a
Linux works it's a super cool project
and you can get a little Raspberry Pi
and spin it up and decide to you know
blow it up when you're done with it so
yeah I like that and will speak on
conferences to some good conferences to
go to and we kind of get out of them
we're obviously at a pretty good good
one here last con something that is near
and dear to me is Derby con I've been
going for the past couple of years it's
in Louisville Kentucky every fall and
Derby con is about two thousand people
or so but what's really good about Derby
con it's a very kind of intimate very
social conference iron key does a really
good job of recording all the talks and
getting them up pretty quickly the same
day of so you don't have to go sit and
talks all day
you can also socialize with a lot of
people that are very active in the
security community there's one thing
known as Lobby con at Derby con where
they basically everyone just hangs out
in the lobby outside of the talks all
day so that's something that I really
enjoy
there's also besides so besides there's
really and depending on what city you're
in
besides can have a different kind of
crowd like an Augusta Georgia
that's the same week and they have
security onion conference so you have a
lot of blue team defenders and a guest
at that time for b-sides here in Austin
we have pretty offensive minded security
so you could have a lot of offensive
security professionals so depending
where you are besides it's another great
conference to get into and its name just
arrived as kind of the b-side of a tape
because Def Con talks were getting so
big and so people started to basically
hold their own conferences locally to be
able to speak and get out
and so yeah besides our awesome do you
want to talk on some of the other ones
so blackhead is more for the sea level
but it's also a great conference to go
to if you're looking for a job they have
just they have a lot of boots and
everything and get a lot information you
can even do interviews there black hat
is the week before Def Con and Las Vegas
and then obviously Def Con is in Las
Vegas also and there are really
different conferences one is really more
formal and that would be black hats more
formal and everything Def Con is could
be a big mess if you ever been it's but
it is a great conference to go they have
so many different talks to have
villagers whom you're interested in
Wi-Fi or if you're interested in
physical or lock-picking they have so
many different villages and one thing
that I do recommend is even though you
might want to go to every single talk
you should take some time to go and to
see the capture the flag so or just try
to be social and get to know people it's
a great way to just get connections and
do networking so don't miss opportunity
Def Con and all these conferences also
have them up on YouTube they take a lot
longer than their week on for sure but
you still can't see them later I think
that's about it and then yeah so some of
the additional resources that we really
enjoy our podcasts are a great way to
get experience and knowledge and
security
I guess realm paul security weekly is a
great resource I'll do this on my
commute basically just fire it up it's
very good especially if you're on the
defense side of things a good good job
covering both sides but they do also
news
that week and the longer podcasts will
get in there and do an interview of
people so you can go through the back
transcripts and look at people that have
talked and if that you know you like
that talk it's a great resources to
catch up on certain areas and then I
think you're a big fan of risky business
right yeah so risky business is also
another weekly podcast it's about an
hour they do just things that had been
going on that week about news and they
also interview people security experts
and certain fields but yeah it's a great
way to you know you have to deal with
traffic - we'll just you know listen to
it and then as far as getting into news
and new information about security
twitter's probably like hands down for
better or worse the the best resource
out there for information security
knowledge and yeah I really like Twitter
because you'll find things that like
someone's working on their project in
github though usually you know talk
about it on there first or get ideas
from people a lot of security things
like there's a vulnerability that just
came out or new exploits Twitter
sometimes a place that you'll find that
immediately also on reddit there's our
net sack that's very kind of research
focused a lot of their topics but what I
really like about it is when I first got
in security I was like media to Gold
understand every post on there because
all of them are very like technically
deep or at least get an idea of what
they're talking about so yeah I like red
it's our net sec subreddit but it's can
sometimes be a bit I guess intimidating
with its topics on there but I'm pretty
sure that like half the people that read
it don't get it as well so like me but
yeah it's so a great resource job
hunting so hopefully a lot of the kind
of things that we've been talking about
can help give you idea about you know
the technical social resources so that
when you do have that first sorry job
hunting interview you know you can be
pretty prepared for it so there are the
typical resources that go find jobs
liked on LinkedIn indeed
we are just talking about the net sec
subreddit they also have a quarterly
hiring thread as well and so you can go
on there and look at people but their
positions are and what have you
and then yeah so it's that those are
really good ways to get your kind of
idea of what a security job may be and
we are in these sites searching for
positions a security consultant will
usually be an offensive minded position
but it can also be defense as well and
if you're looking down there and you
type in like security analysts that's a
very super broad position but a lot of
times I'll also be like the defense side
of things so definitely take a look at
those job descriptions and get an idea
of what each one may be depending on
what you're looking for something to
consider before even looking for a
company is sometimes we've been in the
field doing other things like QA or IT
or development but something to consider
is are you willing to maybe go into an
entry-level position because it might be
a pay cut and so it just has to be are
you willing to do it because sometimes
like the golden handcuffs you know we
get to a level where we're seniors in
our current position and then we kind of
have to go to entry level and sometimes
you know it kind of it kind of sucks but
that's what you have to do also look for
the confer of the company what you think
the right fit is it's like do you want
like a relaxed culture or are they gonna
be more like kind of corporate jobs or
are they consulting this it's you have
to talk to customers you don't want to
do that just things like that also look
for companies that maybe have like
entry-level groups like for example
rapid7 has this security analyst group
where they get people from different
backgrounds like development QA blue
teams and they know they you might not
have the security background but you can
bring a different perspective to the
team so something like that is also like
a really great thing to look for yeah
and so also when you kind of find that
job and you hopefully go in for an
interview you know we were thinking
about some of the things that are
questions not just that you may be asked
but also things to ask you're the person
that's interviewing you so a good kind
of question to think of is that maybe
asked in your
Rolle would you want to know now that
you didn't before getting into it and
just kind of get an idea of you know
asking them about their current position
and how do they actually like it there
but on the flip side of that also
anything on your resume is obviously
going to be fair game so be proficient
if you do listed on your resume that you
do know it and really things like that
are gonna be you know your time to shine
and so definitely you know tell your
story and use examples of the things
that we kind of talked about earlier how
that kind of drive and passion and
develop these home labs and you know get
into the social side of things because
you may be asked about it eventually so
yeah something also to remember is the
technical interviews they'll probably
have an intrical so it just depends on
what kind of position is but for example
sometimes rapid7 for the security
analyst they'll have like a capture the
flag that you have to solve and you have
to report on before you get hired so
it's just something like use those
things the points that we mentioned
earlier like they're gonna ask you do
you have a home lab they want to know
that you you know are passionate about
it and are willing to learn and put the
extra effort ah contact info time so
yeah definitely feel free to reach out
to us if you have any questions on this
or had any questions buddy and the
resources I'm on Twitter as well so you
can go look at my ridiculous list of
people I follow if you're interested in
that sphere to look into so ah I think
we have time for questions as well so
Joe of any questions yes fanny
what is the number one thing that you
wish you knew before you started your
transition my transition my current role
now as a pen tester so I wish that I
knew so I was from a defense side of
things and and that idea everyone is
like a customer to us every every
department is and I moved into the
consulting role and in the consulting
role it's just very different because
you'll have a new client maybe a couple
clients a week and different calls and
so you're going to be running into
different companies all the time and
give me a lot of things anxiety because
of the transition of that was such a
rapid pace of change and you know you
work with a client and you may see them
every year or not but the consulting
mindset of where you're going in and you
know doing the best job you can and
doing a report then moving on that for
me kind of was a new experience
transitioning to that is very unusual I
think he started out in consulting and
we're used to that now that that that
way of thinking it it would just come
naturally but to me I had to adjust I
think to you know the the rapid pace of
moving through clients all the time
because I don't interact you know often
with other departments at my company
because you know I'm not having to make
sure that you know check their security
I'm doing it for another company so I
think that was something I wish I knew
it was going to be you know a difficult
experience getting into it just put that
mindset flip I said what what did you
have for me would be how social would be
I'm kind of an introvert so it I was
pretty amazed how social the people are
for sure we can be a bit overwhelming
Lee uh friendly so do we have any other
questions yes
so he talks about your past experiences
when how did you know you were ready to
make the switch to security from
wherever you are like you can do all
these things you can build a home lab or
whatever but at some point you're like
okay now I need to start applying for
jobs what was that like for you that's a
really good question actually thank you
for me I actually had a friend that went
over to our security department from
where I was in the NOC and I got to see
a lot of the cool things they were doing
I went in as an entry-level position and
I just basically studied studied up for
it I don't know if I was even really
technically as ready as looking back on
it as I could have been just it was
because I didn't realize I think the how
much there was to learn and get into it
and so fortunately I did get in as an
entry-level position and I don't I don't
think I didn't think I was ready for it
in the first week actually got into that
my team they sent me to DEFCON and like
the lights came on in my head and I was
like all these amazing things I could do
and yeah I really grew up in that role
and you know I saw what was it like for
you I just got tired of doing what I was
doing I wasn't happy anymore and that's
I just decided to follow my passion so
yeah I think I think in this kind of
position since you are going to go into
an entry level the sooner you do to it
this the better and I mean you don't
have to just quit your job and start
looking for positions and studying and
stuff but you know just take your own at
your own time feel comfortable with the
topics that you might be asked about do
we have any other questions Bueller no
one Bueller all right well yeah none
that will go ahead and end it a bit
early thank you everyone for coming out
to this talk and feel free to come up
and talk to us in person if you have any
questions that you don't want to yell at
a room about so yeah thank you everyone