[Music]
this talk is about IOT basically alright
that's the main thing you need to know
and I have it I've run through this talk
and first time I think it ended up being
two hours of the second time in a big 30
minutes so it'll fall somewhere
hopefully within an hour but anyway the
talk is going to be a little bit
different because I've done a lot of
talks and I get kind of bored with slide
presentations and stuff so there will be
no bio slide in this I will not include
a addenda slide because I think there
are ways to real estate I mean you're
here I'm gonna say this stuff I'm we
used to have a slide that says this is
what I'm going to talk about in
literally now and then I don't put any
memes in my slides I simply would hope
that I could actually say something
funny that you laugh without a picture
so and to me memes are kind of the new
version of bullet points from you know a
decade ago at presentation so why not
but anyway the main theme for this is
that there is more to IOT than just the
application itself if you're a
researcher and you're looking at this
stuff you have to look at something
beyond the app you need to look at where
that app resides within within its space
and most IOT setups to give you kind of
a rough idea you have on the left is the
thing which talks to a routing device
and then that talks to the the internet
and typically it's usually bluetooth to
talk to the routing device which is
often a phone or though it could be your
home router or whatever and then on to
the the Internet
I have Wi-Fi there but basically tcp/ip
and it's doing a web protocol kind of
thing on the things typically when I do
research on them I typically start with
I just want to get an idea what normal
usage actually is for the thing so I get
an idea of hey this you know this is
what the thing is supposed to do and
then I start coming up with some type of
attack scenario based upon the device
itself I don't just instantly start
saying hey I can do this hacking thing
or that hacking thing is know word is
this you'll see what I'm talking about
here in a minute as we move forward with
the Bluetooth stuff I had I took out a
whole bunch of slides there's a link at
the end excuse me
there's a link at the end of the
presentation here because I did a blog
post about Bluetooth hacking and tools
and stuff like that it's fairly detailed
and technical so there'll be a link to
that at the end so that'll kind of help
cover that area a little bit but
basically what I typically do is I try
to figure out can I fingerprint whatever
the thing is is there some way using the
Bluetooth stuff that's built into
fingerprint it and look at it see what
it could do
GATT characteristics I don't remember
off the top of my head accurately what
GATT stands for but it I think it says
for computer stuff and basically it's
like think of it as like on it from the
computer world it's like open ports ok
but it's for Bluetooth and you some of
these have read access some of them have
read/write and depending upon the
situation and what's been opened up
there you have it there's some actually
that are standard that are almost always
open for example the name of the device
when your Bluetooth scanning and you see
you know you know Sarah's iPhone
you know that's a a Bluetooth open port
so to speak that you're looking at I
also note that the pairing method how it
pairs some versions of Bluetooth and
depending on the device itself it may
allow more than one thing to pair to it
some only allow one thing and that's
kind of interesting the pairing methods
are worth discussing on their own the
first item is a numeric comparison
you've probably seen this where the
smart thing has a screen on it and it
displays a number and you make sure that
number matches on the on the other side
there's just works and yes that's how
it's written in the 2020 500 page
Bluetooth standard it's called just
works and it actually is exactly numeric
comparison but it's all zeros in so
there's just basically it's you know no
password as some people do and it's
become kind of popular where they do a
four digit passcode so that exists as
well that's not a part of the standard
the passkey method is a little more
secure it's basically a number is
generated on one side and then you enter
that number in on the other side and
then some math happens over Bluetooth
and they are now talking to each other
okay to put it extraordinarily simply
and then there's the out-of-band method
and that is there's some other method
and this is where you have to like it it
gets kind of difficult to actually do
the out-of-band method now I'll have an
example of that later on so you can say
oh okay that's what he meant by
out-of-band I also look at the Wi-Fi
traffic I typically use
the man-in-the-middle protocol of the
man-in-the-middle proxy tool and there's
a paper that I did on this also at the
end of the Hina presentation that I have
a link to and I kind of go into that a
little bit more in in detail but I use
that a lot and and just you know
basically Wireshark sniffing looking at
from the other side of the routing
device whatever it is talking to the
internet and looking to see does it do
actually because and they all talk web
protocols okay they they all seem to
talk web protocols for just for almost
exclusively so you're looking for a
welder than using SSL or are they using
a secure the thing are they doing
certificate pinning this is actually
fairly important does everyone know what
sir doesn't know what certificate
pinning is okay few people all right the
certificate pinning is I can't use that
man-in-the-middle proxy thing on let's
say Facebook for example because
Facebook has pinned their certificate
inside the app so they say I can only
talk securely to Facebook and I know
it's Facebook because I know what the
certificate is I've got a mathematical
thing process here to identify that
certificate as being the proper one and
so certificate pinning that prevents me
from setting up my own you know fake
Facebook page or Facebook server at
Starbucks and gathering people's
passwords as they connect up that kind
of thing and I also try to check just
are they doing basic web security stuff
since it's web protocols and I'm not
going to cover that but if really but
you know just things like you know
cross-site scripting you know just all
the normal things are they do
proper you know handling sessions and
things like that all that applies there
as well
okay app security I typically when I'm
looking at this stuff I'll I'll grab the
apk the Android version of the app and
then you can easily decompile the stuff
using apktool and which is a linux
utility I'll use that and I'll go
through and start looking at what
libraries were used as you know the most
popular programming language currently
at this time is what's the name of it
cut and paste is the is the and there's
that site real popular cut and paste no
that's not it it's Stack Overflow that's
where that's apparently the main library
that's being used so but what happens is
is people will just you know in toto
will grab libraries and bring them in
and use them so sometimes these
libraries may have security
vulnerabilities associated with them so
you want to make sure that they're using
the patched version of that finding an
outdated library can be a challenge
sometimes when you decompile it will
have version information in there and in
actual english other times it won't and
you have to be a kind of clever like if
you know that there's a vulnerability in
some library they're using and the
library the vulnerable version was 4.2
you could actually look through there
and say well I know that this specific
feature that I can readily identify the
library was introduced in version 4.6
liter around 4.6 and not on 4.2 so
they're kind of you know at least using
a current or at least a patched version
of that library
hard-coded credentials those show up in
the app sometimes I'll give an example
of that later on
and then
how they store the data are they storing
the data securely are they using
encryption you know with wherever they
are storing data and doing that kind of
stuff
hey dude I'm glad you're here to change
dude did you bring the little thing cool
thanks yeah I did no you didn't just
witness a drug deal this is actually
yeah completely a completely different
scenario there I also looked for you
know weak authentication you know are
they using some type of authentication
of the app is it like insecure this is
like really good timing Todd I
appreciate this because one of the first
things I wanted to talk about is now
kind of covered some basics here oh yeah
it's actually in pseudo one piece this
is an example oh you brought the we're
safe one yeah okay cool
no kind of kind of blew the whole thing
no okay pretend that this looks just
like that okay I'm not gonna oh I
shouldn't even have said what it was
that was probably a mistake yeah doesn't
matter we're not we're not really
recording this are we no sure surely not
anyway this is a personal protection
device it's what this is and it's not a
toaster or anything like that because I
decided to finally look at IOT stuff
maybe I should look at harder or serious
targets the a personal protection device
this particular one this is by a company
called roar and this is the Athena
device now what these are these are
mainly marketed towards women that if
they're they they put these on the
talked to a phone and if there's a
problem where they feel like they're
physically being threatened they press
the little recessed area there and it
can send alerts to people in their
contact list to say hey here's my GPS
coordinates bad shit's going down and
the reason it's on a discreet little
thing that can clip to like a you know
inside of a shirt bra strap on your on
your pants on a in just anywhere you can
clip it is that it's possible that if
someone was in a threatened environment
and they pull out their phone to call
911 or to call their friends that it
could cause things to escalate phone get
slapped out of the hand and bad things
happen so that's why it's supposed to be
discreet so they can just kind of you
know act like they're scratching or
whatnot now like I said it's mainly
aimed toward marketed toward women
however it's starting to be used to buy
let's say people that are going to
protests under repressive regimes people
that are like you know doing a human
rights work overseas that kind of thing
so these are being used sometimes in
hostile environments so it's kind of
important that they get security right
understanding that aspect of it this is
just one that I looked at out of
multiple if it's possible if someone
could get me some water that'd be great
so I I'll quit coughing they're getting
it there's a great shirt is handling it
back to our map okay so you understand
this particular device so we have on the
end we have roars Athena device talks to
a phone via bluetooth and then Wi-Fi on
to the cloud that web and all that so
kind of just going through some of the
things we talked about earlier the
pairing it uses just works that's not
great
but it's you know understandable that
they're I mean yes it's kind of
disappointing that someone used the same
security level that they would to pair
to a headphones you know did they do for
something that's meant for security
however poking around using tools like
gat tool on Linux
I tried querying all the typical GATT
ports and I could not talk to the thing
I could not I could connect up and the
first thing I would run I would be
instantly disconnected that is oh thank
you very much the entire talk people
just bring me random things up here on
the stage if just the way things are but
this was nice that it would actually the
Bluetooth implementation was put
together like this I really like that I
don't know how many people have heard of
what le privacy is this is what it is is
I think the Le comes from Low Energy
back in the old days when they had
Bluetooth classic and then Bluetooth Low
Energy or btle or ble or you'll see it
multiple ways before in 4.0 of the Pluto
spec they just jumbled it all together
le privacy is a way of making the thing
less noticeable two scans and to add a
little bit level of security to the
particular device and give an example of
that for the roar Athena how they do
their implementation of it is they the
Bluetooth has a essentially a MAC
address that's associated with it they
change that periodically I think in in
their case I think it's every 30 minutes
it'll get a new MAC address and the idea
being is that if someone is trying to
track an individual at best all they're
going to get is the MAC address they're
not going to get anything that actually
gives a name or says anything and the
MAC address change
every 30 minutes every time the button
is pressed it also changes the MAC
address and that's kind of cool as well
so every time the device has been
activated even to do the there's
different levels of alerts that you put
one two or three clicks and it does
stuff also if you hold the thing down at
90 decibel think it cuz yeah yeah it's
funny I'm on slack saying oh my god Todd
how do I turn this thing off
it's really annoying so like I had the
one taken apart and I just shorted it so
which which worked but but yeah if the
batteries dry have battery swapped it's
a typo so glad I found something wrong
in the slides while I'm up here
presenting it charges off a USB if the
battery is drained and then you start
recharging it new MAC address so that's
really nice that it has that level of
privacy because a lot of times there are
women out there that say I don't want to
wear a Fitbit because I'm afraid that my
my ex is going to track me using my
Fitbit and so you have something like
this and it makes total sense to
implement this kind of thing as far as
the app security goes all the libraries
were up to date they were storing their
stuff securely and they were using
certificate pinning from app on phone to
the interwebs so that was really nice
and they actually use same choices with
their encrypted web stuff which is which
is good the conclusion on this
particular device and is that they put a
whole bunch of security in place in
there as a researcher this was hard this
is a hard target and it was hard to
prove all this stuff you had to really
kind of dig just to see that things were
being done correctly
so it's kind of interesting just a quick
word on these things there's a couple of
these devices that we looked at outside
of this one that we found problems with
including one where there's a denial of
service where you can do stuff via
bluetooth and oh and it's trackable
completely and totally trackable and you
can knock it off line from the phone and
there's no indication in the app on the
phone that it's offline
that's a bad thing okay because you
could have someone there hitting the
button you know trying to you know
notify someone that something's wrong
and they think someone's on the way and
no one's on the way so that's that's a
bad thing all right on to something a
little lighter
the Apple watch okay how many people
here have an Apple watch
congratulations you have a decent secure
device believe it or not this one was a
complete alas pain to try to figure out
in our little diagram here the Apple
watch talks via bluetooth to the iPhone
and then from the iPhone via Wi-Fi or
del te to the to the interwebs some
people aren't aware of this but starting
with version 1.1 it was able to devil
watch was able to talk via Wi-Fi
directly to whatever means that the the
phone did so basically if you connect it
up via your phone via Wi-Fi to you know
some type of network and the network did
not does not have a paywall
or I agree to these terms click through
anything if you doesn't have anything
like that if the phone is talked to
before the watch knows about it and the
watch can use that same
connection okay and this is outside of
the new three version with the LTE thing
built into the watch this was back at
the very beginning when this thing first
came out and whatever was 2014 so that's
kind of interesting so yet another thing
to look at in this case the physical
security on it believe it or not having
a screen lock when you take the thing
off because the haptic feedback sensor
says oh he's not I'm not attached to an
arm anymore I'm gonna lock the screen
when I first looked at this stuff that
was not a common feature most other
smartwatches that were out there on the
market did not do that which is kind of
surprising because you can do things
like you know Apple pay and and things
like that and a lot of these other
watches they have fairly sensitive info
on them it is possible that a street
magician kind of pickpocket guy you know
the guy that's you know hey how's it
goin and you know and he like removes
your watch and stuff like you know it's
possible to do that with this to get
your to do undo the band and then get
your fingers underneath the sensor and
pull it off I mean think about how
practical that is and it doesn't work if
your hands are real cold believe it or
not but you can pull the watch off and
then you can proceed to I don't know run
to Starbucks and score some free drinks
or something with Apple pay
but basically though is that if you
don't have user access to the watch the
only thing the watch is good for is
telling time okay that's it even to wipe
it and reload it it still requires
access which is a you know a code a six
six did or eight digit code the
bluetooth pairing it is the most secure
method which is out-of-band
you hold the phone over the watch with
camera on and there's swirly bits on the
watch and the camera sees that and so
they're the out-of-band method is using
visuals and that's very cool and then
math happens in the background and stuff
like that as a backup they use the
passkey method which is the second most
secure method so the first one is and
the default one and the easiest one is
the the most secure one they've
implemented the le privacy thing on this
as well for them it's every 15 minutes
and if you power it off and and and
whatnot it'll come up with the new MAC
address to give you a a little bit of a
view here I'm sure everyone the back row
really appreciates it and probably even
in the front row appreciates when you
look at a thing here this took forever
to get because I had to do a whole lot
of stuff with uber tooth just to get a
decent capture about a day's worth of
just doing pairings you know and it's 15
minutes to wipe the damn thing and then
you got to start over if you missed the
first packet then you were screwed but I
did manage to get a complete pairing
just to kind of zoom in here a little
bit you can actually see that you know
where it's starting it's making you know
encryption requests encryption response
start the encryption etc the thing
that's cool about it is that's during
the pairing process it immediately
starts doing encryption as soon as you
pair the thing up and like I mentioned
the the privacy implementation was the
MAC address changes periodically and
then on top of that the first thing they
do and that encryption thing is they do
a diffi Hellman key exchange and they
rotate the diffie-hellman key every 15
minutes they've generated a new way
and so that means that if you were able
to somehow actually capture the
Bluetooth traffic with a Bluetooth
sniffer that data is encrypted and and
if you're a you know a nation-state
actor and have access to break if
you break the key you've basically got
15 minutes worth of the traffic and then
you're gonna have to break another key
okay so this is unbelievable levels of
security and it's why I have one on and
I even wore this like black hat and DEF
CON and the whole bit so I you know
because I figured well it'd be a nation
state that would if they're gonna do
anything that's that would be go after
that or guys the club that would hit me
or whatever is the other threat model
the Wi-Fi that happens via the watch I
also look at that just to just for grins
it's improved substantially since watch
OS 2 - most of the traffic is encrypted
we're saying choices there is very
little plain text I did see I saw a
plist come over in plain text related to
location services but it was signed so
that was good and I saw some small
graphics files also tied to location
services and I tried monkey in with
those and nothing really bad happened
except it wouldn't display the image
because it's a freaking watch and
there's not a lot of real estate there
to work with anyway and again talking
about the same choices this is typical
for most Apple stuff as you can see
there they're using you know the TLS RSA
with aes 256 cipher block chain stuff
and that's good okay
256 is heavy 128 I think is also common
because 128 uses less battery power
and everything so I know you'll see a
lot of apps on things but at least you
know this is like you know it's like wow
they're really going for it on this
basically it's in discoverable mode I'm
not sure if you know what discoverable
mode is basically it's on Bluetooth this
allows itself to actually be discovered
all Apple products if you turn bluetooth
on they are in discoverable mode which
is unfortunate but and it's the only
thing I have against them but there was
no exposed GATT characteristics that
gave up much information the only thing
I found were read only once and they
gave up normal stuff and then the whole
le privacy thing kind of killed that
whole idea all right I'm doing pretty
good on time
this next one you're gonna say what the
hell all right okay and I brought it
okay since I didn't have to fly here I
drove here but that's this is a this is
a smart tool if anyone has a let's see
NRF connect on their phone it's a nice
Bluetooth scanner you go ahead download
it if you want you can go ahead and look
for this thing it's gonna be fairly easy
to find and everything and feel free to
probe it and do whatever you want to
with it that's that's fine I I will
encourage you to hack it if you as it
were and I know because a lot of people
every time I talk about the tool people
just laughs our heads off over it
basically the way this is set up though
is this talks to does the usual stuff
bluetooth talks to the phone phone talks
Wi-Fi or or whatever to the interwebs
and just to kind of make sense of this
stupid
when I was I remember talking in the one
of the work slack channels saying yeah
I'm gonna be working on that power drill
and people await you were not making a
joke you're seriously gonna look at a
power tool alright the thing is with
this I don't know if you recognize
anyone recognizes the brand Milwaukee
Milwaukee tool if you're working with
tools for a living or if you're doing
serious serious construction work this
is the kind of thing that you're going
to be using without the Bluetooth part
which is called one key this is an
expensive tool this is the best tool I
have okay this is really the best tool I
have because I mean must list because
I'm not a construction guy I'm a
computer guy but this thing is great it
has four you see there on the on the far
side there it has four profiles for it
you can store those profiles you can
obviously you can you know scan and find
the device and whatnot that's me finding
the device and then before I pair it up
to it the thing that's interesting about
this where you actually start to see
some value for its industry is that
let's say if you're a contractor because
you can keep track of this not only on
your phone but also and keep an
inventory because they have other things
that have Bluetooth on them by the way I
you can store it on the web and has the
web has a nice nicer interface so you
could let's say you had four of these
and you're a contractor and you're
working a job and the guys are drilling
wood screws into wood and a couple of
them are over drilling and they're
cracking the wood and it's like oh we
got to replace that you crack the wood
because it's something that's going to
show well you can go in and put together
a profile that tweaks the torque and
then push the profile down to the tools
and now you're not having that problem
you're saving some money okay
other features that this thing has is
that you can assign a
state two it okay so you could say it's
available for checkout it's checked out
and you can say Bob checked it out and
so you know that Bob walked off with
this tool and he has it you can say it's
down for maintenance and you can say
it's lost or stolen we'll get back to
that one in a second you can take
pictures and attach them to the tools so
that way you know what your tool looks
like I guess but also you could take
pictures of the receipt so you have the
purchase date that kind of thing so now
you know like if you want to take it
back or you want to schedule maintenance
based upon when it went into service etc
so there's a lot of information that you
can gather and put together with these
tools now back to the stolen thing when
you mark the tools stolen you can
actually set it up and send it basically
a kill message that disables the tool
from working okay now it is kind of
convoluted you have to have this thing
has to be within your shot of the app
running on a phone for it to get the
signal however any phone any phone that
has the app for this
whether you're paired to the tool or not
if it spots a tool it uploads the GPS
coordinates of where it saw the tool at
okay so you kind of have a find my tool
thing with this which is that all of a
sudden becomes kind of neat now the
thing is the industry is going apeshit
over this because there's all said guys
saying hey man because like the example
I gave you if the guy addressing the
profile with the torque thing that's
from a forum that's from a tool for him
and it's guys saying this is great it's
saving me money but everyone's going
crazy about this they're asking for
features like can you put in something
that tells me that the tools been
dropped
you know if he's away put sensors and
said tools been drops because you know
Bob's an idiot I think he's breaking
tools by dropping him you know if he's
checked it out and he's been dropped in
his
I know it's Bob I need to go after you
know and tell them to stop drinking on
the job or whatever is causing him to
drop tools they even make a thing called
it's called the tick and it's a little
guy about this big it's expensive as
hell and all it is is the equivalent of
the Bluetooth tag thing inside here and
you can attach it to any tool or
lawnmowers or you know whatever just
attach it to your stuff and include even
could you know competitors tools and so
it's making huge waves in the industry
it's kind of become disruptive if we
dare use a an internet buzzword so
anyway so when I was looking at this
there's lots of things to look for I
wanted to look at the physical security
of the tool itself for you to send a
Bluetooth update to the tool there's on
the top here you have to actually switch
it to Bluetooth mode for it to have a
profile push down to it you can't push
one down to it while the things running
or whether it's in drill or drive mode
which is which is kind of cool
you could not write values that are out
of range so if this has an RPM of I
figure what it is I got 2500 rpm or
whatever you can't send 25,000 rpm to it
and then the guy uses it and it explodes
in his hand and you know mass chaos
ensues and all that that doesn't work
okay I tried altering a profile that was
stored on the phone and then pushing it
out to the drill and it just capped it
off at the max it didn't allow me to
write values beyond what it was supposed
to supposed to write which was kind of
cool it only has two values anyway which
is rpm and and torque okay but it's got
real fine adjustments on those some of
the issues with the bluetooth it's very
easy to remotely fingerprint these
things
the pairing has just works which is kind
of disappointing just to give you an
idea this is a scan of the from a phone
I had a bunch of stuff that was command
lines it was just easier to read and up
there at the top note that number there
is at zero zero zero six zero zero seven
etc okay that's a unique number for this
tool okay that's the Bluetooth name of
the device and the Mk II is a dead
giveaway that it's a Milwaukee tool
thing plus you look at the manufacturer
name string that's one of the GATT
characteristics and it says Milwaukee
tool the model number string is
interesting it says that ble 1 1 2 in
there highlighted in red
that tells me by you know googling that
and also by doing some other probes and
whatnot you know that this is you know
blue Giga is the people that put
together the Bluetooth chip on here so I
know what kind of Bluetooth
implementation it is this thing is
capable of getting a firmware update to
it the current version of firmware is
that ble 112 it does support encryption
they appear to be using it which is
interesting I think it was just on by
default and think don't know they're
using it but nonetheless that's you know
so there's but you can then just you
know the version of firmware naik and
not download that version 2 firmware for
the manufacturer you know start your
reverse engineering on that and really
go after the tool and in a different way
like the others that we looked at basic
security was a place on their
communication from app to cloud and I
know I talked about that before but this
is to give an example highlighted up
there in red there's a few settings that
and this is
this is a screenshot from a
man-in-the-middle proxy just to show you
because I had to they did certificate
pinning I had to defeat it and then get
in the middle with that by decompiling
the app turning off certificate pinning
in the code and then recompiling it and
signing it and loading it on the phone
but in there they're doing things like
to prevent things like you know
cross-site scripting and and just other
basic things that need to be there to
kind of help secure the web stuff
they've got it and they were using that
in there which is good they didn't have
a problem with us anymore everyone for
me with what bearer tokens are see a few
heads or nodding okay
after authentication that big blob of
text in the middle that's a token for
access to this server
it's a bearer token down in the JSON
down there toward the bottom and the
bottom red box it says type of token
bearer and then it has a user ID that's
associated with that okay so if you re
login or whatever you get a new token
however if you the expires in the age on
this thing typically on bearer tokens
you don't want them to be in an hour is
a good you know amount of time for a
bearer token this one expires after a
year and it's stored on the phone so
conceivably if the phone was broken into
then whammo they're gonna wreak havoc on
your tool inventory or whatever but I
mean nonetheless is you know this that
wasn't great they were doing there and
as is the kind of things that you know
it's a researcher you try to try to look
for with this stuff they did use
up-to-date libraries which is good
found nothing there and found yes they
were doing certificate pinning which I
had a defeat to get to that point you
know they use stored credentials that
did law we class words I'll talk about
that in a second
they had stored credentials in the app
they hard-coded them in okay that's not
good either
okay and just as an example of that this
is during again this is a request and
then there's the up there at the very
top and red is the is the hard-coded
password and that hard-coded password is
in the app is they use the set according
to looking at the source code it's the
same hard-coded password for their
development environment their beta
environment and their production
environment and the I don't know if you
could see the password that I have
I typically want up doing stuff I use
Hunter to is my password for everything
but I'm doing this goofy testing but
they demanded I have an uppercase
so it's capital H and then since it had
to be 8 character because they're really
being tight on security I had to make it
hunter 22 it's supposed to hunter 2 if
you don't know what hunter 2 is you need
to Google that stuff is kind of funny
anyway inside joke I saw a couple people
kind of got that one all right
conclusion so I actually got a couple of
CVS out of this this for the store
credentials in the app which is kind of
bad and the long-lived bearer token
which that's also kind of bad as well I
think it is CVE for this because it's
we're not worth it but you can do
fingerprint and tracking of the app via
bluetooth scanning and that's bad
because I don't know about you but I
don't just like put one drill in the
garage and that's the only tool I have
this is with all the other tools okay so
it is a beacon that says hey this guy
could afford at least one tool that was
expensive and if I'm a bad guy and I'm
prowling around a job site looking for
you know tools to steal and there's five
of those trailers parked on the property
it's pretty easy to figure out which
trailer has the tools in it okay
particularly the hand tools and stuff
and so you know and then of course you
know if you're smart you've got your
Bluetooth scanner and you're saying okay
I don't see any iPhones or fitbit's
nearby so there's no people around I'll
go now and steal the tool and whatnot so
to me that was kind of kind of bad the
interesting thing though is by using a
combination of the stored credentials
and setting up a dummy account getting
your in just a dummy account on the
Milwaukee website and using that to get
a your own bearer token you can go in at
that point you have enough data from
what you've gathered from the scan and
you can actually spoof the GPS location
as a tool which as a thief might come in
handy
so you could make sure that the tool
looks like it's not stolen
it's just something well and it's just
it's somewhere there in the garage maybe
little Timmy walked off with it and put
it under something I'll keep looking for
it
and you know or you know maybe Bob
clumsy Bob that drops tools maybe you
didn't put it the cabinet right you know
it's got to be around here somewhere
according to the stuff it's here on
property so I mean you can't or you can
you know send them anywhere just so you
know your enemy down the street that you
hate you know use his GPS coordinates so
you can do some kind of weird stuff like
that now all of these all three of these
things
the Apple watch the the R or Athena the
personal protection device and this tool
these were hard targets okay
they're very hard targets this is not
like some you know smart toaster or
whatever you know where it's you know I
mean those are kind of fun I guess you
know because you know they print out
what you can get toast that prints out
the weather report
the toast with the stuffer pick I'm
serious and are a picture a picture
which oh a picture on toast yeah nothing
bad could ever happen from a picture
being printed on toast you know for a
family breakfast yeah I can't think of a
single thing that I would do to that but
I mean it's kind is funny but it's kind
of pointless because you know big deal
you compromise a toaster big deal you're
you're tricking the guy was the smart
thermos who can't be asked to look at
how much water is in there he's actually
being told hey it's actually half-empty
when the apt is saying it's it's full
but anyway that's that's the end of my
presentation proper there are the links
as promised both the for the I did a
thing on the drill and that has some
fairly interesting stuff in it and
recently I did the link on the Bluetooth
stuff so you can grab that and there's
my contact info yeah just to repeat for
those that adhere are you run across
companies that are difficult to work
with yes
Milwaukee tool never responded okay
I actually involved us-cert that's right
your tax dollars at work trying to
secure power to the power drill and they
contacted Milwaukee tool and they
actually got a response from them and
all they did is acknowledge that yeah
he's right these are correct this is
these are flaws we need to fix it and
cert gave me the guy's email address
they copied me in on all future
communication and nothing came out of it
it is I mean for IOT it is not like it's
it's very similar to Microsoft in the
90s as a researcher there are people
just like what you're you're you're able
to print genitalia on toes
oh my god why would you want to do that
that's so terrible and their fix is well
we'll just you know make them upgrade to
a new toaster it's not to buy a new
toaster I mean they literally don't they
have no clue about most of this stuff
and also remember they're working under
weird constraints like you have someone
that says okay here's this little thing
where I can load my Bluetooth data on
and then they go in it's got this much
memory and they go to order them and
then China sends like 50,000 of these
things to them it turns out the ones
they sent to them have half the memory
but the orders already gone through and
they got to use these things and they're
gonna put him in whatever their
manufacturing said well okay we need to
take us memory you know whammo out comes
all the security features this is the
kind of thing that happens with IOT just
weird stuff word they don't even think
anything about Oh what's this library
certificate pinning we don't need that
you know look at all that space we just
saved all right we're good to go
ship and that's that's the world that's
the hardest part right there technically
I don't need to get permission from them
to do the talk to be a nice person do Oh
as a matter of course we have a we do
that 90-day thing that's that all the
kids are doing okay but with them we
actually went I think is over a hundred
and twenty days because we kept trying
to just give them a chance and
everything
some people have responded better I mean
like you know with the personal
protection devices they're taken
seriously one of the places that we
reported there they've responded another
one has not yet hopefully they will but
it's kind of a mixed bag I mean the
further down the the IOT importance in
society food chain you go the less
response you're going to get they were I
mean they literally know as long as
you're not doing anything that allows
that they think you're going to be
stealing something from them or you know
it helps to
say this affects end-user privacy in
some cases then they'll kind of response
to Oh privacy that's a bad thing you
know if it's compromised ok question was
where does an average consumer go to
find out security information on IOT
devices what's good was not there was
really not kind of a I mean I would hope
in the future that at some point is more
the stuff continues on that there's
going to be some type of kind of privacy
element to it like you know the instead
of saying security you say is user
privacy guaranteed with this product may
be someone like Consumer Reports can
kind of get involved in that saying this
device is unsafe because it allows bad
guys to you know break into your home
with your smart home stuff because I can
open all the doors blah blah yeah maybe
there's something along those lines but
right now there's really nothing outside
of us hoping that normals show up to
security conferences which looking
through the room I'd say that's not the
case now the personal attacks yes ok
question was on the personal security
devices that we've tested we will be
publishing that I'm not supposed to I
really don't want to say in a public
place we test the roar one is great ok
that one was done spot on a couple
others we tested weren't as good they're
there one of them was kind of bad but
you know I'm not suggesting that you
have to talk to me later because that
would be wrong for me to give you that
information
so but nonetheless we will be publishing
something hopefully in slightly less
than 90 days the Bluetooth standard in
us by the way it's not a brute - okay
the question was are there any standards
for the Bluetooth protocol which doesn't
exist it's a collection of protocols all
right
if I think I mentioned this if you
printed them off you're talking 2500
pages front and back I mean just massive
PDFs and that's plural PDFs describe
what's intuitive so and there's all
kinds of weird interpretations where
they use words like shell and could and
and so there's really no there's hardly
even standards within that itself okay
now do to places like cut and paste comm
but you know you know Stack Overflow it
you know and github is people get better
and they're focused on libraries and
using good libraries and these libraries
by default have good features turned on
things aren't nearly as bad and believe
it or not security is slowly improving
for IOT as long as they continue doing
their cutting and pasting and there's
some some you know weenie program are
out there saying no no you did it wrong
here's some more efficient way that's
that's insecure and then they post their
thing to a routine and things slowly get
improved so it is getting better but no
there are no standards there's several
people that have tried to do this I know
in Australia they've got a working group
together that's actually trying to make
real progress because they're trying to
get government buying to say everyone
has to meet this standard before you
sell bluetooth product to the government
of Australia and that's a good idea
and they are actually gaining traction
there and I think that's actually going
to happen but no the the protocols ms
and or the protocols involved are kind
of
all right well that's going to be it I
will be around
hit me up I'll be the guy carrying the
tool thank you very much
[Applause]