[Music]
all right well hopefully you're here to
see layer eight and why people are the
most important security tool that's what
I'll be talking about today my name is
Damon small I'll explain my little
nickname there here in a second before I
get started though I want to give a
shout out to last con and a wasp for
sponsoring this I'll be honest with you
this is my first time attending last con
but it's always been one of those
conferences that's very well spoken of
and I'm glad to be here glad to be in in
Austin I live in Houston but my employer
has an office here in Austin so it's
always great to to come into town and
speaking of my employer who is in CC
group I think I have the best job in the
world because it's part of my job to do
this I'm a technical director for NCC
group and all the tech directors are
expected to kind of be the face of
InfoSec and we're big believers and
advocating for InfoSec and the people
who do that so thanks to my employer and
of course my wife and editor my wife
isn't here but she gets to go through
all of my slide decks before I present
them and make sure they're coherent so
thanks time lastly I want to thank you I
have the pleasure of doing quite a bit
of public speaking but every time I get
up on stage you always wonder is anybody
gonna show up to see this thing it's you
know right after launch you're probably
sleepy it's Friday you're probably
looking forward to the happy hour but
thanks for coming much much appreciated
and speaking of my employer they are
happy to support me in doing this but
you do have to sit through a short
commercial ncc group if you've not heard
of us were based in Manchester United
Kingdom we have about 2000 employees
worldwide worldwide most of which are
billable consultants in North America
we've got about 200
consultants as well as some of the
management like me 35 total offices
globally we were formed in 1999 were
publicly traded on the London Stock
Exchange and this slides a little bit
out of date our fiscal year end in May
2017 we did 264 million pounds in
revenue so we like to think we're
reasonably good that what we do we offer
a lot of security services but you know
full you know full stack everyone likes
to say that but everything from
applications security to infrastructure
security and so on and so forth so we've
got you know if you can imagine 2,000
geeks that that's you know I've got at
least one of every kind of security geek
I think that exists and like I said a
lot of offices hoping bad houston to
that list soon but enough about them
let's talk about me chef if you come
over quick joke hi how do you know if
someone is the DEFCON presenter he'll
tell you I'm a Def Con presenter so if
you come see me in Las Vegas and I love
volunteering with the Wallace sheep I've
got a couple of my fellow Shepherds in
the room right now not many people know
who Damon is but a lot of people know
who chef is so you know coming up and if
you forget I've got it on my lab coat
here started in nightie and 95 been
started focusing on info 2nd 2001
Louisiana native go Tigers new tiger
fans in the wrong state on it all right
so I put this this is my introductory
slide I put it together quite a while
ago
and this was before the equifax thing
happened so if you want to make jokes
about my music degree go right ahead
it's fine because I went to grad school
and got a computer science degree so ha
I can use both sides of my brain started
off as a blue team err that's why the
blue lab coat I
the kind of token blue team guy that
works for a red team company done work
in healthcare for the DoD worked out at
Johnson Space Center for a little while
and of course oil and gas so that's me
so let's jump into what I'm talking
about in this concept of layer eight and
people being the most important security
tool by the way let me caveat this for
you I appreciate that I'm at the Lone
Star applications security conference
and all of the case studies are going to
show you you are really more layer 3
routing and switching sorts of things
however I think it's still relevant
because as I said me and my organization
we believe in advocating for information
security practitioners and that includes
you know app dev certainly so what
happened is I'm somewhat of a digital
packrat and I save I had written a
couple of white papers about a decade
ago and I stumbled across them
excuse me to click a button I stumbled
across those white papers and I thought
oh this is gonna be comical this is
something I wrote ten years ago it's
gonna be horrible and I read through and
there were white papers that described
an incident response that I was engaged
in and I read through it and I thought
huh this is actually still relevant it's
it's aged quite well unlike me and I
thought it's a good story that these
concepts from a decade ago are still
relevant and so I converted the white
papers into the slide deck and hopefully
it'll resonate with you as well I'll
it's again this is about the people but
I am going to talk about some techniques
that we use during the incident response
and they are simple and they are old but
they remain useful and I love telling
stories that love the sound of my own
voice as anybody I work with they'll
tell you that and coincidentally when I
initially authored this slide deck and
want to cry had just happened and I
realized that a lot of the techniques
that I described through
fighting the self-propagating worm from
a decade ago are still absolutely
relevant today in the context of more
advanced malicious software all right
audience poll how many of y'all well so
I first of all how many folks are
application developers okay are there
any routing and switching people in here
oh hey good it's my people all right
good thanks
do any of you and in the course of doing
what you're doing to use tools like PS
exec or TCP dump or wind dump you know
maybe from time to time okay come see
come stock I'm gonna be talking about
some of those tools and if you don't
know what they are and you're not a
routing and switching person don't worry
I'll try to make it relevant for you
anyway so if you work in an IT
department you know all IT departments
there's a lot of tools that cost money
you know technical controls that we
might implement in our environments and
you know time and money are finite
resources so you can't buy them all
businesses have to remain fiscally
responsible you know if I as a
consultant I'll freely admit I never
think your security budget is big enough
and I never think you hire third-party
consultancies enough right I mean sure
you should give me more money but I
wonder in the context of this you know
fiscal conservatism that we need to have
and the fact that you you know the bad
guys don't care what your budget is if
you're going to get attacked you're
going to get attacked so I wonder the
question I'll pose is are we overlooking
the value of human ingenuity and that
and the skills of our practitioners the
first case study the white paper was
actually called finding the needle I
thought it was extremely clever at the
time but it's yeah but whatever that's
what it was called and it was an
incident that occurred in December 2004
I worked for a hospital system at the
time
and it was just a normal day I think it
was Friday actually why do these
incidents always happen on Fridays the
the primary firewall failed that
separated the local area network from
the internet and it failed and all the
network team knew initially was that
there was a very large volume of traffic
on TCP 135 and there were also periodic
bursts of internet bound traffic on
various ephemeral ports high high ports
so in short there was just so much
traffic that the firewall fell over and
it became a very bad day for the for the
networking team so of course we
initially we thought okay this is some
malicious software that's causing
because something's gone horribly wrong
and we didn't know what it was we had
some barriers that prevented us from
quickly diagnosing the problem some of
the IP traffic appeared to be spoofed
and of course if it's a spoofed IP
address you know it's limited on what
that packets going to be able to do but
it made it difficult to determine you
know where the actual infected host was
this was a hospital and you know
hospitals like many businesses they had
a ton of third party supported systems
so these were systems that were on the
hospital's network but the hospital
itself didn't have access to them so you
know they were just kind of a tenant in
their data center so we had limited
access to to look at those machines and
figure out what was going on at the time
this hospital system had about 8,000
workstations that's not a very
impressive number by today's standards
but it was still a you know it's a
significant number of devices that it
was it was cumbersome and again this was
2004 so our networking team they had
protocol analyzers and things that could
give us a lot of statistics about the
network performance and what protocols
were being used but shockingly they
didn't really have any way to analyze
traffic in real time and now I can't
imagine and that
team now that wouldn't have that ability
but again it was 2004 number one and
number two as much as I enjoy the the
health care industry they just weren't
very sophisticated we weren't very
sophisticated at the time and our in our
network management capabilities and I
you know as one of the security guys I
went to them and said look I can sniff
traffic for you all you want you know
just give me access to a spam port and
I'll plug in and do the thing at that
time and maybe it still exists to some
degree now but security was very much
considered and the network folks didn't
like to give anybody access to their
infrastructure and they say oh you're
not a network engineer we can't give you
a span port it's gonna break all the
things and like alright man peace I'm
being my office if human would like some
help
and sure enough about an hour later you
know came captain hand and said yeah you
know so this sniffing thing you're
talking about it we've got a spam port
for you can you help us out I'm like
yeah sure so anyway the message is that
you know due to the limitations that as
an organization we were dealing with
they couldn't troubleshoot any more than
just saying yeah the firewalls down and
there's lots of traffic on 135 we don't
know what it is so they begrudgingly
engaged us and and then we started so
fundamentally and here's where I'm gonna
start talking more about the people more
coffee for there was four things we
needed to know from where the traffic
came to where it was going what was
causing it and how to get rid of it
right pretty basic things but we
couldn't answer those questions and so
let's keep this in mind and I'm going to
step through how each of these four
questions became answered so we started
off with exploring what kind of
detective methods we had I mentioned
already that the network team had
protocol and protocol analyzers but they
didn't have any
you know real way to analyze traffic in
real time we had commercial antivirus
but we unfortunately discovered that on
those 8,000 workstations and however
many servers we had it wasn't
necessarily fully functional on every
device that it was installed on right I
mean it's you know managing AV in an
enterprise's heart
we had an IPS and that was giving us
some telemetry that was useful and you
know wind dump which is the windows port
of TCP dump if you're not familiar with
the tool it allows you to it will
display all the network traffic that's
going through your network interface so
you can look at it in real time as it's
flying across the wire so this simple
command right here allowed us to see
that in by the way I was positioned on
the network at a significant egress
point so I could basically see maybe not
everything but most of the traffic that
was leaving the organization I was able
to see so this showed me everything that
was going to port 135 remember we did
know that that was the port that the
malicious traffic was on so by simply
issuing this command I all of a sudden
had more visibility into the network
than the network engineers themselves
had yeah so that was the kind of the
first step in trying to figure out where
the traffic was coming from so in doing
that and I'll show you what some of that
traffic looked like in a minute that
showed us where the traffic was coming
from so not only did it say hey here's
traffic from port 135 that would say you
know here's the source IP address here's
the destination and some other things as
well so we started compiling a list just
a you know who these infected hosts were
based on their IP address that allowed
us and by the way I admit you know you
say man a lot of these processes are
very very manual and yeah but that was
the you know what we had to do at the
time there are certainly more efficient
ways to do some of this stuff and I'm
certainly not suggesting this is the
best way but rather it is
a way and so anyway we gave the list of
the infected hosts so that the desktop
team could start looking at them and
figuring out okay why isn't antivirus
working and then you know running manual
scans and starting the cleanup in that
way based on those antivirus scans we
found at least a couple of different
self-propagating worms if you are
working in the industry at the time
you might remember there's a couple of
really bad vulnerabilities on our PC
decom and the LSS L SAS process that
runs on Windows boxes the interesting
thing about self-propagating worms as
many of you or all of you may know is
that they don't require human
interaction right that's why they're
they're called worms and not viruses so
you don't even have to be law been to a
computer if it's vulnerable and the worm
finds it it'll you know pop the box and
start trying to spread around the rest
of your network it looked a lot early on
in the investigation like blaster and
Sasser those are two worms that took
advantage of those two vulnerabilities
and of course patches existed for these
things but it was 2004 and I think the
organization's policy at the time was to
deploy patches every quarter whether the
systems needed it or not
so yeah they even weren't passed
so a little bit of context on botnet
worms a lot of times the command and
control is done by the the worm will
login to a malicious IRC channel there
was a period of time where I think you
know there was more botnet based traffic
on IRC than any legitimate traffic might
exist I'm sure that's still true today
so the worm with the software would log
into an IRC channel and then the bad guy
could issue commands through that IRC
channel and then of course the attacker
can use these zombie computers for
whatever he or she wants to you know
whatever sort of malicious activity
before anyone points this out yep
egress filtering rules on your firewall
will help solve a lot of that stuff but
I mean you know hey again it was 2004
who does he was doing egress filtering
in you know for so as it turns out in
addition to the traffic on port 135
there was so much traffic from the
zombie computers trying to log into the
IRC channel that that started having a
detrimental effect even though we were
getting rid of the 135 traffic all of a
sudden the IRC traffic started giving us
problems so what did we do we still
needed more data even though we had
started you know gathering lots of good
data antivirus continued to be of
limited value unfortunately and part of
it has to do with just how a worm works
as an aside your software people so
maybe you understand this I'm sure you
do
that when a worm exploits the
vulnerability a file doesn't get written
to a disk system until after the exploit
has been successful so this was before
think again you'll hear me say this
several times it was 2004 so most
antivirus products wouldn't do much in
memory they would just basically look at
files on a file system so the worm would
exploit the box then it would drop a
payload and then antivirus might notice
it but it was too late
been exploited so we enabled we had our
IPS so we said okay it's trying to login
to IRC channels there's no other -
excuse me legitimate use for IRC in this
organization so we set the IPS to block
any irce login defect and very quickly
found three different destination IP
addresses that were hosting these IRC
channels I've opted you skated the IP
addresses but they were you know 189 94
and 228 so we by blocking that we fixed
one problem but we also created another
problem for ourselves is is anyone
responsible for managing firewalls and
or IP s's or IDs letters in here it
might cool yeah
thank goodness some system for ease so
at the time we had our IPS positioned on
the dirty side of the firewall because
when the sales guy told us oh yeah put
it on the outside of your firewall and
it will block so much traffic that your
firewall will begin to work more
efficiently huh it is post-match so
since it was on the outside of the
firewall all those hosts that had their
addresses translated they all all of the
traffic appeared to be coming from the
same ip address I had no way now to see
what the actual internal IP address was
again it's 2004 I was young so yeah so
we realized oh great now we were
blocking this traffic but we have no
idea where the where the traffic is
coming from so we had to get creative
again no I always do that slide in the
wrong order okay that's what I just said
so anyway note to self put the IPS on
the inside of the firewall or have it on
both interfaces so yeah it was useful
for stopping the infected host but we
couldn't find him so when dump came to
the rescue again so now that we knew who
the malicious IRC channels were we knew
that all of the bots were going to be
communicating with those channels so we
just set up when dump to tell us show us
any traffic that went to any of those
three IP addresses that we had so that
solved the problem of figuring out where
the infected hosts were and that proved
to be very useful but also it was also
very cumbersome so if you've ever worked
with wind-up and if you haven't it's
okay but it basically I mean you can you
can dump all of the information that it
captures to a file but it is a little
cumbersome to manage and trying to you
know when you're quickly trying to
extract the IP addresses out of there so
what we did is we had snort running
somewhere and so we just set up a very
simple snort rule that all it did was
say it looks that you know if traffic's
coming from the home network and it's
going to the variable botnet was defined
as those same three IP addresses send us
an alert and so that way we could very
quickly alert on every time snort would
snort by the way was on the clean side
of the firewall it was on the inside so
we didn't have that NAT problem it was
easier to stand up a snort server than
it was to try and you know reconfigure
our perimeter so not only did snort
quickly give us an easily human readable
list of the infected hosts on the inside
but we were able to capture some of the
traffic and this is just you know kind
of like looking at a dead body this is
some of the traffic of the worm actually
logging in to the malicious IRC Channel
it's I won't go through what is
happening in each of these lines I just
thought it was interesting that while
the incident was happening we were able
to snag some of that traffic yeah and
this one was interesting because you can
see and the last line it's it says that
there's 4254 devices logged into it so
certainly modern botnets are much much
larger but you know at the time we
thought wow that's crazy there's 4,000
devices many
many of which were probably ours that
were logged in to that channel and you
can see here on the private message that
was sent to the bots it looks like the
bad guy started a scan of the 10.32
network on port 445 so that just shows
the point you know it's visually
demonstrating that you know once they
exploit a box the the bad guy will use
it to try and find other boxes and again
I just thought it was cool that we were
able to capture that and sure enough we
also saw that as the scan revealed
additional vulnerable hosts they got
exploited so that was helpful because it
means say well we should probably go
look at those hosts and clean them up
and then you can see in the last line
here at I don't know for sure but it
looks like the bad guy has launched a
distributed denial of service against
that dot 158 address and so now you know
your own organization's network
resources are being consumed to attack
somebody else so that sets up a whole
other part of the incident response
where you're like oh no we're gonna be
held accountable for hacking somebody
else's stuff so yeah again just an
interesting thing to see I think so we
had figured out through these steps that
we followed what the malicious software
it was we knew where the infected hosts
were and we understood how command and
control was what's happening so now it
was time to start on the cleanup process
so again antivirus was ineffective I'll
resist the urge to say that even when
properly configured and virus is
ineffective but no antivirus vendors in
your
so that wasn't really helpful again we
had these third-party supported devices
that we didn't have access to and we had
some biomedical devices and that's kind
of a whole other problem anybody do work
in healthcare perchance nah I'll save
the FDA v to paste or e for later then
so yeah we still had some problems that
we had to sort out so while we were
running snort and gathering the alerts
about who was infected the logs provided
us some additional useful information so
at this point we knew to where the
infected hosts were phoning home and we
knew which hosts were infected because
look there's the IP address right there
but more importantly we knew which port
the software was using that last thing
here this is port 1303 that's what the
software was using to communicate to the
remote IRC channel so once we have that
sorted out we could use F port which is
the tool that you can run that will tell
you which processes are running on a
remote host and more importantly which
port it's using so you can see this is
what the output of FF port looks like
and sure enough there's our buddy 13:03
being used by a process called W thirty
two USB 2.0 Windows service which would
be W 32 USB dot exe so you know they
they try and give them deceptive looking
file names so you might gloss over it
but because we had empirical data we
knew exactly which TCP port TCP port it
was we knew that was the offending
service so now that we had sorted out
that problem we had to get rid of it now
malicious software back in those days
not not to be that guy back in my day I
do have a great beard though I'm not
afraid to use it
malicious software was a little easier
to deal with in that
just simply had many times you had to
just stop the process and then delete it
and you were largely done so there yet
another tool that we had in our toolbox
called PS kill and you would issue that
command point it to the remote host and
tell it which specific process you
wanted to kill again in this case it's W
32 USB 2 so you run that and in less
than a second the process has stopped
you delete the file and off you go
so again a very very manual process
probably not the most efficient way to
do it but at the time that was the the
way we had once it was all said and done
we this was a really bad weekend for
this health care provider there were
many many botnets that were discovered
you can see based on the file names we
knew it was you know Spybot or week by
there's you know R and XR by you know
there was a bunch of them and a bunch of
specific infected files that we were
able to find and even though it was
tedious it was very effective and we
weren't having to you know guess whether
or not we had found all the all the
boxes or not so all of this having been
said oh right this is I love this story
knowing which through your turn this is
a story I really want to believe it's
true I don't know if it is or not but as
the story goes there was a machinist who
was called to work on a generator I
forget if it was Edison or a
Westinghouse generator but it wasn't
working right and the machinist walked
up you know took one look turned to
screw and the problem was solved and so
he gave the invoice to the business
owner who owned this thing and it was
for like you know ten thousand dollars
the guy said you turned a screw how in
the world is this ten thousand bucks you
better send me an itemized invoice and
as a consultant I'm used to hearing that
I get my you know invoices questioned
all the time
and so the machinist sent back sent back
an itemized invoice and it was you know
turning the screw one dollar
which screw to turn $999 so I kind of
thought of that it is again I freely
admit none of these techniques were
complicated none of these tools are hard
to use but in that very specific order
in gathering the information we gathered
it was very effective I think the lesson
that I learned at that time is
understanding the nature of a problem in
the context in which it exists is based
on the you know collective decades of
experience me and my team had at the
time is what resulted in us being
successful even though we were very
limited and our technical capabilities
that we had within that organization and
as I said earlier these techniques are
still relevant if you had yeah you know
for self-propagating software many of
these techniques would absolutely be
very effective so the next case study in
it was the same organization sadly I
hope that doesn't speak to my ability to
secure that organization when I was
working there's a web dev buffer
overflow that existed and a buddy of
mine from the web services team called
me it was on a weekend I remember
distinctly it was a Saturday I was at
home and he said hey Damon you want to
see a dead body
well web devs are kind of a strange
Bunch and I told Greg I was like I hope
that you're speaking euphemistically
right I don't know what you're talking
about he's like no no we got a server in
the DMZ that got popped and I'm trying
to do post-mortem on it and figure out
what in the world happened so the three
t things I'll talk about you know there
was a rogue FTP site that had been
installed on this box
the reason the web dev figured out that
something had gone horribly wrong
because he started getting alerts that
his disks were completely full and
spoiler here I'll show you how the
hacker was kind enough to patch our
server for us
you know if you're gonna hack things at
least you know provide a little value
I guess so anyway my buddy Greg logged
into the server and I know that's very
difficult to see but I mean clearly is
shows that looking at the C Drive in
system 32 it was filled up with all
kinds of things that had nothing to do
with with system 32 so I immediately we
did in that came to the rescue in in
this case and if you're not familiar
with in map it's colloquially stands for
network mapper and you can use it to
examine a device on your network and
figure out which network services are on
it
so everything looked pretty normal to us
except there were three services that we
weren't sure what they were 1978 2003
and 3460 so we quickly narrowed it down
to you know those three things or
probably have something to do with
what's going on so f port came to the
rescue again we're an F port against
that box it told us that port 2003 was
being used by a service called wim in G
in T and that's not to be confused with
the legitimate process that's called
when MGMT luckily I think Greg figured
that one out but yeah that that process
clearly didn't belong there
so great how do you figure out what's on
the other end of it we just simply tell
meted to port 2003 and this is what we
saw I'm not sure why those wild those
variables weren't defined but basically
we telnet it to that port and we saw you
know splash screen for the rogue FTP
site that Raz Stroh's installed for us
and you know it's pretty well designed
right and I've seen commercial products
that don't aren't that aesthetically
pleasing oh there's the rest of the yeah
and you can see I mean you
when you stand up a rogue FTP site you
know you want to know how much data is
available I mean there's a lot of very
useful you know metrics I thought man we
should you know import this into our you
know I I wonder if you'd sell us the
source code for this no and we found so
this guy was a little sloppy there is a
lot of artifacts left over on the screen
including an install script for the FTP
site I won't walk through it but it was
just another interesting artifact that
we found you can see what script the bad
guy ran to get all that installed on
there and and here's where he very
kindly patched our system for us I'm
sure by now this was probably a
commonplace thing but you know you look
through the script and you can see where
it's modifying registry the the
vulnerable registry entry and patching
it for us and you know jokes aside it's
not because this hacker was a nice
person but he or she didn't want anyone
else to gain unauthorized access to the
system so what now that hit the back
door was installed the best way to keep
other bad guys out of it is to patch it
so at least we didn't have that problem
to deal with and as soon as that
happened the software started looking
for more vulnerable systems again this
was the web WebDAV buffer overflow that
existed you know back in the day and we
found the logs where look there's a
bunch of systems where web dev wasn't
enabled the reason I obfuscated the
first two octets those IP addresses
because they were not on our network
those were routable IP addresses that
existed out on the internet somewhere so
again you know you run the risk of your
organization being blamed for attacking
somebody else's organization because
we've got infected hosts on it and your
network resources are being consumed for
malicious activity he left us this cart
ice razz world FXP i googled some of the
words yeah see 37 games worth of stuff I
mean that was a lot back then right I
mean it's not much now and yeah when I
googled some of those words I got a lot
of domains on the dot de TLD and I
quickly started closing windows and
again not going to that site never did
figure out what all that nonsense was
but I mean again you know pretty well
designed prophecy and so through these
two narratives I hope that I've shown
you know yeah it's extensively to say
isn't this neat me and my team figured
this out but as I was mulling over this
I realized that again to go back to my
opening comments that people really are
the most important security tool because
no organization is ever always going to
have everything they need to do whatever
it is they do and at some point you're
going to find yourself in a situation
where you've got to think creatively and
and overcome those obstacles
however we as humans are also part of
the problem I'll use the remaining
couple of minutes I have to talk about a
red team exercise I worked on it was
last year actually we strung together an
extremely complex nine step attack chain
and that sounds great and I had some
very talented again I'm a blue team guy
so I had some other people that had mad
skills but it wasn't just the hacking
all the things that made us successful
we got lucky at one at one point along
the way where we had gain unauthorized
access to a workstation and we were
tooling around the file system and this
was an admin an administrator of this
organization and there was a spreadsheet
I kid you not on his desktop that was
called administrator passwords dot CSV
so you don't have to be the best red
teamer in the world to figure out
that's a file I'm interested in so we
helped ourselves to a copy of it and
sure enough there was a bunch of
administrative passwords in that
spreadsheet so clearly had that admin
not made that poor decision the attack
chain may have stopped right there so
humans so humans are the solution to all
the security problems I think but we're
also the cause of many of them
furthermore with this client once we had
domain admin we were doing the read out
we'd given him the massive report and
we're going through it and he said yeah
you know we created ourselves a domain
admin account and we weren't even trying
to be stealthy we called it NCC admin
you know it's very obvious oh by the way
I forgot to make this joke
I love presenting at Norris conference
centers this is the second time I've
presented one because a lot of people
mistakenly think that NCC group has
sponsored the wireless that's a nice
point yeah exactly so you're welcome
anyway once we had domain admin they
didn't they didn't detect us and we
asked him about that we said you know
you really one of the recommendations
was you should monitor the domain admins
group and if it ever changes that you
just being alert is like yeah we do that
what huh well we were in domain admins
like three days and nobody you said
anything is yeah the monitoring system
was down and no one noticed and like
okay you know again you need to monitor
your your monitoring systems so I mean
you really do somebody should have
noticed you don't have to read this I
just thought it was a really cool
diagram of that attack chain and again
that looks impressive right all these
steps I mean holy smokes in CC guys are
great but yeah if it weren't for the
human error that happened in there
we may not have been quite as successful
so as I said several technological
challenges conspired against us you can
read that if you like I just ripped that
directly from the conclusion of the
white paper I wrote but again to
reiterate I really think that I hope
this resonates with you and I hope it'll
astray --tz--
point that it's our people that are
going to help us be successful in
fighting the information security
challenges that we face so great what
can we do and I'm happy to be wrong if
you disagree that's awesome I'm just
glad to be a part of the conversation
but I think that as information security
professionals especially if you're in a
leadership role and you have influence
on your budget in your organization's I
think we should spend on people first in
technology second build your team of
people and then make technological
decisions based on the capabilities of
those people make sure you consider the
skills that they have when you're making
technological decisions so when you're
looking at talking about technology
products or security products there's
often you know more than one way to skin
that cat right and so it's not about you
know sometimes there's a clear leader in
a in a given product line but sometimes
there are several products to choose
from so make sure you have your people
able to support whichever technologies
you decide on if you have gaps spend on
training first and hiring second I think
you know if you're not taking full
advantage of the people you already have
adding headcount might not fix it maybe
it will and as I described through the
first incident response you know is very
important that the network team be
willing to work with the security team I
don't know that organizationally and the
clients I work with that's not as much
of a problem now but still it's
important to be able to work across your
organizational silos and I've had people
you know disagree with a couple of these
points before and like I said that's
fine I'm happy to be wrong but as long
as we're having the conversation I think
we're moving in the right direction so
that is my story and I'm sticking to it
the irony of throwing up a big QR code
and security crowd is not lost on me
trust me there's not
this URL in there that's just my contact
information or if you prefer there's my
email address and you can find me on
Twitter and that having been said
comments questions no one threw anything
at me so I this is already a successful
yeah there you go
alright if there's nothing else I'll be
around the rest of the day thank you for
spending your afternoon with me is very
much appreciated and I'll be hanging out
feel free to buy me a beer or two