um this has become a bit of a tradition
in in recent years gifted for those who
don't know Peter soror better serve as
he was caught in his native and
Hungarian was a great security
researcher one of the leading antivirus
researchers wrote probably the standard
work on antivirus which still quite
relevant in which I recommend people to
read it
that's him here he sadly passed away in
2013 and to keep his memory alive we
decided to give an award every year in
his name to a great piece of technical
security research published in in a
12-month period between the 1st of July
and the 30th of June the next year this
is the fourth year that we're doing that
last year the own attack linesman from
Fox 81 from a paper he wrote on a target
attack in in Asia we can click up many
many nominations this year thanks for
those who think thanks to those who
submitted something we got a shortlist
of three but I want to give special
mention of of two papers the first is
the first honorable mention goes to a
paper called distributed vulnerability
assessment or actually it it's a long
piece of it's a combination of various
research papers and presentations by
people from secluded who outsider who
had a sponsor booth outside this room
and university of do now Fieros or
something along those lines in in
Hungary and and I mention it because
it's it's a great piece of research and
also do a a mistake on on my behalf it
wasn't it was submitted too late
so apologize to a Ferengi and then it's
true
and a second honorable mention is for a
paper on the on the bay Rock botnet
takedown and which is a very long
project but these people from Symantec
together with with the FBI and actually
a lemur merge who's going to talk about
this tomorrow afternoon and it's one of
these good news stories
that sometimes we in the fight against
against bad stuff on internet in general
and cybercrime in particular we're doing
quite well so you got three shortlist of
three I set mentioned then Liam emerge
you who was a good friend of of Peter
and and who's actually presented
tomorrow I already mentioned he will do
the Oscar thing and an opening envelope
and read out the winner so the first the
first nomination is the is the
well-known sha1 coalition paper now as
research papers go this one was very
unsurprising because it was a public
secret that even this group was working
on this piece of research at the same
time or or why it was actually nominated
is firstly because it's still an aborted
piece of research but also it was really
great paper and they did some really
clever stuff beyond the brute-forcing I
think if you if you actually seen the
details of you care about this stuff
this matters and it matters in industry
where where some people are still using
an md5 hashes and it's a personal pet
peeve of mine so maybe we stop doing
that the second the second nomination is
for a a que builder this is a
crowdsourced exploited by a carpet is
upon us or SRP for friends former home
sofas in Hungary when we think of
exploit kids we usually think of web
based exploit gates this is a builder
for malicious Word documents and not the
kind of Word documents where you have to
enable a macro but another kind that's
that's given a lot less attention but
it's used by quite a few criminal groups
and other kind of malicious actors and
Tapan has written quite a few papers and
on the subject it's been presenting
about this tomorrow and it shows an
important an important piece in the
chain of cybercrime and if it highlights
the highlight of cybercrime works but
also it it really describes how well
these the export kids work and how they
make the life of a malicious actor are
quite easy and thirdly there's a
research project called Iran threats by
Colin Anderson and Claudia Guarnieri
Claudia you may have seen speaking here
yesterday it's I think most of us are I
mean it's a very global audience here
but most of us are from what we call
Western countries and most of us focus
on threats facing that threaten people
in the Western countries face I think we
sometimes forget even though we're aware
of it that for members of civil society
in Iran there are some serious digital
threats that they face that are
different than the ones that we face and
it's I think it's very important it's
something that these guys both do in the
free time and I think for that reason
alone the domination is is well deserved
and okay that's so that's a short list
so I'd like now I'd like to ask Liam to
do that to the Oscar thing
I did by the way link from the fire
splittin Twitter account a blog post
Liam wrote in memory of Peters or almost
four years ago and please do read it
because it's really touching and thank
you and actually I might just say a
quick word about Peter and when I moved
to Los Angeles Matthew for 15 years now
and when I moved to Los Angeles about
ten years ago Peters or was somebody who
I really looked up to in the industry
and I had read his his book and I had
the great pleasure of actually working
on inside him in Los Angeles when I
moved there he was sitting at the
cubicle next to me and although he
wasn't my manager he wasn't in my direct
organization it was a great privilege
for me to be sitting beside somebody who
was who I respected so much and I always
remember when I moved there that I had a
difficult time settling in and I was a
lot of work to take on when I moved
there and he was the only person who
came up to me and he gave me
encouragement and told me that I was
doing a good job and just made me feel
like all the hard work was worth it and
that's something that always sticks out
to me so something I would like you to
take away today is to remember we've got
a lot of great people in the room here
we've got some legends of the industry
and we've got some junior people and
wherever you're at in your career there
are people who look up to you and it
only takes you a second to look at them
to look at the work that they're doing
and to give them encouragement and to
say you're doing a good job keep going
so spread the peace below
[Applause]
so now I have the opening envelope and
Martin said I should do the Oscar thing
and the Oscar thing this year was to
announce the wrong winner so I'm looking
forward to that okay and the winner is
Gabor zapatos from Sophos
we
thank you
[Applause]
I heard some people say that Gabbar
should have to give a speech which I
fully agree he will give a speech
tomorrow morning at 10 o'clock in the in
the green room where he will talk about
this very subject
yeah please enjoy the rest of your
dinner and the rest of the entertainment
have a great evening and see you all
tomorrow
[Applause]