welcome to the people who have joined us
we have Anton sharp enough and Robert
dubrovsky from ESET talking about
destroyer Goodman I'd like to begin by
saying that it's a great honor and
privilege to be standing on the stage of
piracy Bolton conference again I think
it's the fifth time for Anton's seventh
time for me and if I go back and think
about all the topics which we presented
each and every year the topic was more
sophisticated attack was more
sophisticated than the previous year so
I'm already kind of kind of dreading
what is gonna be the next big thing that
we're gonna submit for VB 2018 but today
we're talking about in destroyer it's
also privileged something which we
usually take for granted but the lights
around here the projector is working
which is great because in destroy a
piece of malware which can cause a
blackout in fact it already caused a
blackout in Ukraine last December so
it's a piece of malware to do something
like this but it's the first malware
specifically designed to cause a
blackout to attack power grids
automatically and for that reason we
consider it to be the biggest threat
against industrial control systems since
Stuxnet let's put this malware into the
context of the other previously known
malware families which were used against
ICS attacks and this is how such an
attack typically unfolds so you have an
industrial site which can be anything
from a uranium enrichment plant through
an automobile factory and manufacturing
plan anything it's got its specific
tailored ICS hardware and these devices
they're typically controlled and
monitored through workstations typically
running Windows and with human operators
sitting behind them and that was the
point of iteration in all the previously
known
our cases that's where the attacker got
in and through that they got access to
the rest of the ICS environment now the
individual families they differ in the
methods and their capability to
interfering with the ICS process within
destroyer it was as I said specifically
designed to attack power grids so it was
a electricity distribution substation or
distribution resort rands mission in the
last case which was which was targeted
so the commands which were being sent
from the malware to these devices were
tied to a timer which was built into the
malware that would activate it's
malicious payloads open circuit breakers
stop the flow of electricity so that's
the high-level overview of the threat
now with this capability in destroyer
joined this elite club of only three
previously known malware families which
were which were you know which were to
our knowledge to the knowledge of the
industry used in ICS attacks so Stuxnet
of course needs no introduction right it
was able to reprogram PLC's to change
the rotation speed of centrifuges
Havoc's the malware also known as
dragonfly or the operation energetic
bear mostly active around 2014 used to
target several industrial sites it's
interesting that this malware was also
abusing the opcd a protocol something
which industry is also abusing but
unlike in destroyer Havoc's was only
using it for espionage in the in a
reconnaissance phase of an attack it
didn't actually interfere with
industrial hardware as far as we know
now Symantec recently published research
about new dragonfly campaigns so I
recommend you read that as well it's
probably not the last we heard from this
group now black energy is a little bit
different from all these three other
malware families and that it wasn't
designed it wasn't specifically created
to a
I see environments instead it's a more
general-purpose cyber weapon we've been
monitoring this this malware for quite a
while now and we've already talked about
it at VB twice so I won't get into too
much details we monitored the evolution
of the threat and we watched all the
campaign's unfolding they were mostly
being spread through spearfishing
campaigns we even discovered a zero-day
in PowerPoint that it was using at one
time and over all those years there were
many many interesting targets many
interesting campaigns against many
interesting targets which were often
high-value targets so there was
government news media critical
infrastructure transportation and so on
but what's relevant to our topic today
of course is what happened on December
23rd of 2015 which was the culmination
of the attack that used black energy
against the Ukrainian power grid it was
the first time in history where malware
was used and aided a blackout
now as I already said black energies
have been different so from the other
ones its general purpose it's a modular
piece of malware you can see some
examples of plugins or modules which we
which we detected and analyzed so there
are reconnaissance modules and things
like that it doesn't have the direct
control the ability to directly control
the ICS so what they did was they only
used black energy as a vessel of gaining
access to the interim to the network of
the oboe and there goes the the
electricity distribution substations in
Ukraine and then they use legitimately
installed illusionary use remote access
software called radmann and then remote
connected remotely and then manually had
to click on buttons and open open
circuit breakers so in case you didn't
see this video this is a video taken by
one of the operators sitting behind that
work stage
at that afternoon tried to document look
somebody's remotely accessing my system
opening circuit breakers the mouse is
moving and it's not me touching the
mouse or the keyboard so that's the
actual SCADA software used to control
the substation okay let's move on to the
main topic of today in the sin destroyer
on December 17th to south 2016 notice
that's almost exactly one year after the
previous blackout so we were shocked
with a sense of deja boo' because there
was another one shortly after we got our
hands on samples which quickly became
the main suspect those were the industry
of samples we analyzed them we provided
our analysis back over to Ukraine
sometime after but we were not able to
go public with these findings until June
in order to not to interfere with
ongoing investigations so I've already
shown you what in destroyer is capable
of doing and what it did but we could
take a look at under the under the hood
how exactly it goes about doing that so
the control for the execution of the
malware begins with a main backdoor it's
not particularly interesting it's the
kind of malware all of all of us analyze
hundreds or thousands every day these
are the commands that it supports
perhaps the interesting one is the last
one in order to install itself to to
maintain to get persistence replaces the
image path registry value of a specified
service and puts it to a copy or a more
obfuscated version of itself that it
drops on to the system so the main
backdoor it also executes a couple of
other modules so you can think of all
these all these components as let's call
them supportive or
modules only a couple of them are worth
mentioning
for example there's an additional back
door the purpose of which is is a backup
mechanism so in case something happens
to the main back door they want to make
sure that they're they stay in if in
case the first one gets detected or
disabled and masquerades as a it's
basically a trojan eyes version of the
Windows notepad application and it's a
fully functional version of Windows
notepad which it's able to replace in
the system since it's running with admin
rights a couple of other modules there's
a port scanner which they chose to
implement by themselves instead of
instead of using the readily available
nmap for example there's a denial of
service tool which is interesting but
I'll get to that in in a later slide
because that actually directly
interferes with the i NC ICS operation
now here's a bit of detail which was
pretty unpublished so with the attackers
they got their hands on on this software
that's used in Ukraine it's an in-house
custom built piece of software used at
substations for collecting collecting
logs of habit has maps of the
environments and stuff like that you can
see some screenshots of this software
over here and they reverse engineer this
software was previously not known to
them that's something like this existed
and they found out that it's using a
database to store all this information
and the credentials to that ms SQL
database were hard-coded within the
binary so okay that's that's that's a
weakness that the attackers could abuse
and they did so they chose to execute
some of their shell commands during the
first reconnaissance phase of the attack
through this database through a
functionality called
XP CMD shell which they first had to
enable and then they were able to run
arbitrary shell commands on the on B
in the context of the database now this
brings obvious advantages of stealth so
it's less suspicious that these commands
are being being executed and also since
they stored some of the malicious
binaries within the database itself they
were also able to use it as a mechanism
of evading a VD tection but now we're
getting to the really interesting part
which is so the main one of the one of
the payloads the payload modules of
Industry are launched by a launcher
component not before talk about the
payloads we let's categorize them so
there were three distinct types of ways
that industry is able to interfere with
the operating with the operations of a
electricity distribution substation one
of them the first and the most important
one is directly controlling opening
circuit breakers through by directly
talking to these to these devices now
you may be asking so what are these
devices I keep on talking about all the
time so here are two examples from two
different vendors which are used
typically typically in Europe Siemens
and ABB so these are without going to
electrical engineering 101 these are
so-called intelligent electronic devices
typically protection relays the purpose
their purpose is to balance the power
grid to protect the environment from
power surges and so on now these devices
they're as I mentioned in the
introduction they're controlled and
operated by humans sitting behind
Windows workstations and they do so they
configure them through specialized SCADA
software - examples for you are shown
over here and remember this software
because it's going to be important
towards the end of our presentation
and the communication between those
controlling workstations and the devices
themselves
it happens through one of several there
are several possible i industrial
communication protocols that can be used
some of them are regionally specific
some of them operate through serial
connections some of them over TCP is not
really that important but the overall
idea is the same to control control
these same commands to these devices now
what's important to note is that in
destroyer abuses these protocols its
able to speak for which on tone-on-tone
will describe in more detail but it's no
it doesn't involve any any exploits it
doesn't involve any software
vulnerabilities per se it's abusing the
protocols in the way that they were
designed to be used but they were
designed decades ago without security in
mind particularly so now I had the
microphone over to Anton who will guide
you through the analysis of the payload
so that was me so Robert mentions the
exact timing of industro attack that's
job of the launcher company and the
launch of samples we analyzed what the
launch the payload models on December 17
shortly before power outage so it has
had coded time and we identified models
capable of control device it through for
communication protocols IC 101
I see one of 61 850 and OPC a lot of
them deals with their own configuration
files first 101
it requires configuration file here is
an example of such configuration it
communicates over serial connection so
attacker should define models in
configuration and first thing it does it
gives
the legitimate process on workstation
responsible for control the device in
takes over the device operates on
something that called Iowa information
observed object others think about above
them as Network part or registers there
are several types of Phyo a and but
payload is interesting only input
specific ones that can accept commands
it goes over range of iOS defined in
this range of I avoid the it defined in
configuration and it sends commands
sequence at first off then on and then
off again they idea behind 101 104
payload is very similar to 101 in that
sense that it sends on or off commands
that the devices but the few difference
it works over tcp/ip instead of qualm it
has many more configuration options as
you can see here it's possible to
specify multiple spatial entries with
different IP addresses and it will
connect to them in parallel that two or
three modes of operation here is in
configuration you can define mode
possible modes are arranged shift and
sequence but for one one and one of our
attackers they don't know the types of
highways that available so they have to
do some kind of brute force to find out
which will accept these commands and
arrange this shift is used to discover
iOS and sequence is used when once they
are known we would construct this
bracket
kids on the flight thankfully to
Versailles we can detect them and as you
can see here this is an example of
single command type Iowa on number 10
the payload can write towards the
console so attackers can can see the
all-time what's going on
also this it supports console not not
only console football but also logging
this is example demonstrate capability
of the pay award it tries to switch
circuit breakers to on or off in
infinite loop and the exact project
depends on configuration as on or off
continuously or flip flipping back and
forth between iterations 61 850 is a bit
different and bit more advanced like 104
it appraised on tcp/ip but thing is that
it functions even if IP others is not
defined in configuration it it has out
the discovery features so it can
discover these devices in the network it
does not appear 8 on Iowa but it
operates on named elements it looks for
these hard-coded names and they
correspond to circuit breakers and
switches so it's different approach but
same purpose to open our closed circuit
breakers the last payload is a step
above the rest
it's not more advanced but it appears on
a higher software abstraction well
technically OPC that access can be built
on top of 101 104 or 61 850 or even
Modbus it uses distributed come to
discover all running OPC servers in the
network obtains named items and it's
yours for this
specific tags then it writes bad what we
won tour items with these tags but what
does it mean let's use this a pool by IB
be to map the tag to actual command
meaning as you can see here CTO open off
is a breaking open execute command so
again same purpose opening circuit
breakers analyzing in the strip bingo
the bellows is a piece of cake for skill
the reverse engineer because they are
not office gated or know any anti
reversing mechanism put in place but
they only think that can and will flow
down your research is annoying cone
staff so to help analyze any future
mower that would use OPC da we released
this either Python script and it's
available you can check it so what it
does here is a screenshot from Ida Pro
here how it looks before the script and
here how it looks after ok so I think
all the reverse engineers in the room
can agree that this is much much better
so yeah so for different payloads doing
more or less the same thing it appears
that the authors of the malware they
really wanted to make sure that they get
those circuit breakers open
so obviously what is the impact so the
energizing a substation is is pretty
obvious and it actually happened we can
also speculate that perhaps they wanted
to do something more because they could
have used a lot much less sophisticated
piece of malware just to cause a
blackout as we witness in 2015 if you
remember the aurora test or our
generator test from back in 2007
it demonstrated how out of sync opening
and closing a circuit breakers could
lead to actual physical destruction of
an equipment so if you didn't didn't see
that or I recommend going to youtube
searching for that video of diesel
generator blowing up itself it's pretty
pretty interesting okay so that was the
first and most important type of payload
functionality but there were the second
type of functionality which directly
effects the ICS environment is a denial
denial of service attack caused by that
do s module that I've shown earlier and
its purpose is rendering protection
relays irresponsive it does so by
exploiting this vulnerability in Siemens
C protect devices so it's specific to
this one vendor that vulnerability is
described in this ics-cert advisory and
the way it works is that the module
sends specifically crafted UDP packets
to port 50,000 so knocking these devices
out serves to amplify the effect the
impact of the payload which Anton talked
about now Siemens did patch this
vulnerability and a firmware update but
you can probably imagine how often these
devices actually get updated and the
third and final type of payload
functionality discovered in in destroyer
is the data wiper module and its purpose
is to make recovery after the attack a
lot more difficult it goes not after the
devices the ICC's intelligent electronic
IDs intelligent electronic devices but
after the workstations used to configure
them it's launched by the launcher
components again depending on the
particular sample either one or two
hours after the payload modules were
executed and it goes after files with
these extensions now we've remembered
O's 2 examples of SCADA software that I
showed you earlier is going against
current is going after configuring
files of these these kinds of
applications so it will clear over right
wipe out the conflicts of SCADA software
furthermore it will render the Machine
unbootable by corrupting its registry
and finally it will crash crash it by
killing all including system processes
so what's going on from the perspective
of an operator working at a substation
so you have your protection your your
circuit breakers continuously being
reopened the substation the substation
is being de-energized your protection
relays are not responding and if you go
and sit down try to fix the problem you
find that your SCADA software is gone so
not the best scenario for for someone
like that and it's also another
demonstration of the importance of
backups offline backups so let's finish
off with a couple of takeaways as you've
seen as we've shown in distress
capabilities are rather versatile it was
the cause of the last Ukrainian blackout
but it's also really configurable and
can really easily be repurposed to
attack power grids and it's not just
limited to the Ukraine in other words
this attack could happen anywhere in the
world it's a scalable and dangerous
threat against ICS as we've said the
biggest since Stuxnet but the gist of
the threat is not just in the malware
itself but skill set and dedication of
the malware operator it's about it's not
just about coding the malware but it's
in their ability which they demonstrated
in Ukraine to become familiar with the
architecture of the industrial site that
they want to target so what devices
there are what commands to send to these
devices and what will happen is as a
result because this is not the typical
scenario that typical malware writers
are used to and finally the blackouts
which which occurred last December it
hit one it was a transmission
facility unlike in 2015 where they had
electricity distribution facilities but
it was one electricity transmission
facility in the north of Kiev so the
scale of the impact was was pretty large
this transmission facility produces more
power output than then all of the all of
the distribution and there go companies
in the 2015 attack combined but the
duration of the attack wasn't it didn't
take that long the power of the lights
worked out for that long which is kudos
to the Ukrainians that they were they
were able to recover so quickly it
lasted about one hour but the point I'm
trying to make is that if you have a
piece of malware a cyber weapon with
capabilities as we've demonstrated a
blackout of one hour around midnight is
probably not the worst you can do right
so it begs the question what happened
why was that either they were not a
hundred percent successful in their
attack or another hypothesis which is
what we believe is that it was not just
a demonstration of their abilities but
also a test they could be planning
something more so let's keep our eyes
open and thank you for your attention