okay hello everyone as has been said I'm
acoustic from a bust this is a lot
kuransky we used to be colleagues but
right now it is a joint presentation and
you may be wondering why such a silly
subtitle of this presentation to be
honest we already had one presentation
about spora this year during the
conference maybe some of you attended
anyone oh right so I hope you will enjoy
it even this part too and the motivation
for this presentation is that suddenly
after our presentation everything has
changed
once again I'm from I was previously
from AVG I'm in this industry not that
long for seven years I'm mostly
interested in ransomware and providing
the free decryption tools but I love
also the other kinds of malware hi my
name is eric kieron ski I've been in the
AV industry for 12 years mostly with AVG
where I started as a software developer
and later on I was responsible for the
behavioral detection and then I was with
a vast and recently I joined the ESET as
head of core technology development
sorry the agent of this presentation as
I said the first part we need to recap
some of our findings from the Cairo
conference we will try to make it short
but some of these details are necessary
for the later part where we depict the
complete changelog of Sporus since its
very first version and because every
presentation needs some statistics right
we will provide some of them all right
so why is for interesting first of all
it's one of the first runs firmware
that's our new trademark here and but
really so
it was it started to spread from Russia
which was which was quite uncommon
because most of the ransomware
try to avoid Russia and the post-soviet
countries so that was that was one of
the things that made Spore a really
interesting also it was from the
beginning of designed to be fully
offline so it never had any CNC servers
or whatsoever and and it had a very
simple and minimalistic design an
effective code - and some interesting
business models we will talk about those
later and and the most important thing
is that they got the encryption right
from the beginning it's not perfect but
it's good enough so it's it's it's so
far unbreakable yeah so this is the
recap about spreading spora love scripts
scripts of all kinds java scripts HD a
windows script files VBS you name it
usually they are spreading spora in a
way that the scripts contain the actual
payload which is the spore executable
over another script that contains the
Spore executable which is somehow
obfuscated it can be encoded it can be
cryptid whatever sometimes they drop
from this script also a decoy document
just to look more legit
also there was a chrome phone or Hoffler
phone campaign that is still in still in
use and still running that they used to
spread the payloads and the days
sometimes have creative crypt usage too
so just real pretty quickly this is the
first spreading mechanism that we saw
which poor odds pretty simple just a zip
attachment in
in the mail that will drop you an HD a
file that will drop you a highly
obfuscated J's file that will drop you a
decoy document and the spore executable
this is the hofler font scheme it's just
a trick they trick the user basically to
to believe they are installing a missing
font instead of that they are basically
downloading and running the actual Spore
executable yeah and the creative script
usage this may look like a header of a
PE file and it is a PE file but in the
overlay it has an H th script so this
was one of the things that they used
also and I don't know why but this file
is an HT a and the PE file in one you
can you can run it as an HT a if you see
it will just run itself through CNBC and
it's an actual B file - yeah those
scripts who love script no one but
what's most important is the PE file
right what's inside of spora executable
most of its versions Purab behaved like
some kind of twisted finite state
machine which tried to travel from the
initial state encrypt some files do some
spreading and finally exit with your pc
being unusable there was some
interesting fact that spora was able to
resume its execution from the last
executed state so it was some
somehow context-aware how was that
possible spur I used four different
types of files to store its details
about the infected machine and the
others it was a state file which is our
naming which contains most importantly
the last executed state also the list
file which contained the list of files
that will be encrypted or that were
already encrypted the key file with a
unique description of each victim
and finally neurons on payment nodes
inside of
htm' of most of the time in software
inside of the HTML there was one
important record we call it victim
record which contained most of the
necessary decryption keys the state file
the first one was quite easy to be used
for detection of spora and we did that
it is located inside of your update a
roaming directory with the name derived
from volume serial number of your drive
and inside of this encrypted file
encrypted because spora allowed set of
scripts but it also lost encryption and
everything is encrypted so it contains
the last executed state as well as some
of the encryption keys the other file
the list file contains files that will
be encrypted
spora chooses those files based on their
extension just like any other ransomware
what is interesting about spora it will
calculate your ransom payment based on a
number of files that are encrypted in
each group and the victim record as I
said this is the pure gold of spora
it contains the local RSA private key
this is mostly important this complete
record for ransom our operators to at
first calculate your ransom payment and
also after extracting this key they will
be able to provide you a paid decryption
tool enough about those four files
what spora does with your files that
will be encrypted sapore use a script
API for everything started from
generation of keys encryption export of
keys all of them by using crypto ok so
spora executables are really tiny
because there are no other external
libraries the encryption was really
solid from the first version so if I'm
correct
there are no free decryption tools
available for
fora no one was able to break it and
there are some glitches in the
encryption algorithm used across the
spora code however those glitches are
just small corner cases that cannot be
used for providing a free decryption to
each file encrypted by spora useless a
unique randomly generated aes-256
encryption key which will be after that
appended to the encrypted file together
with some chicks some for checking
whether the file was already encrypted
or not so they use some kind of safe
coding to protect the files for being
encrypted again I skipped some of the
states which we've described in detail
at Carrow because those are not so
important the last state I will mention
is the link form spreading this is
actually nothing new because the malware
forms are using this technique for years
it just means that spora tries to create
shortcuts that look alike folders in
your on your PC and if you double-click
those shortcuts spora will be executed
so actually those are all shortcuts and
those are the original folders so they
really look the same way by using this
method spora tries to spread to all
local drives but more importantly to
network drives to flash drives so
everyone everywhere this was actually
quite new for ransomware
so this was worm like spreading months
before gonna cry so wanna cry was not
the first worm in a case of run summer I
think it was poorer but maybe there are
also the others encryption madness used
by spora bear with me please this will
be a little bit technical
I would like to depict how spora
encrypts files so just imagine you've
got your fancy new PC or your documents
and suddenly you download its poor
executable
which contains a config this config is
once again encrypted and it contains
most importantly RSA master public key
its private version is only owned by us
power operators it will never reach the
infected PC and after the executions
pora will generate a new pair of RSA
keys we call them local keys each of
them is stored in a different location
the public key is stored inside of the
state file once again encrypted and
private key is stored inside of ransom
notes guess what it will be encrypted
again this is really over complicated by
spora operators they are using one-time
AES key for encrypting this private key
but if they they need to be able to
decrypt it so they need to store this
key once again inside over the ransom
note but once again not in an plaint
form but this will be encrypted by using
the master public key so that's why it
is transferred to the config so this
this part is really over complicated we
told us so at the Cairo conference and
the other day they fix that
but what's per our la loves to do is to
encrypt your files of course it's around
somewhere it uses a unique AES 256 key
as I said for encrypting each file the
key will be stored at the end of the
file and once again it will be encrypted
encrypted by what by the local RSA
public key so really complex everything
is encrypted encryption is everywhere
the last missing part is how to provide
a decryption tool all you need to do is
to go to the payment page by
double-clicking that HTML document and
those victim records will be passed
by using the HTTP GET or post request
from there the outers of spora will be
able to retrieve the RSA local private
key by using their master key and they
will be able to provide to the
decryption tool so it's payment time
yeah so spora authors did everything to
have the payment from the UX perspective
improve it and and so that the users
don't have to install anything on the
user's sorry victims yeah don't don't
have to install anything on their
computers the payment side itself is
hosted in tour and they registered
several proxy site proxy domains through
which you can very easily access the de
onion payment site yeah they were also
using 25-meter come for for some time
and now this this is this is really
changing now this the the payment side
is really really volatile right now
because they are changing it so this is
how it looked like at the beginning
spora just dropped an HTML file that had
amended all the information that they
needed to calculate the ransom to
decrypt your files and so on and so on
there is the unique user ID and if you
go further you you'll find this really
nice nicely looking page they had it
bilingual it was in Russian and in
English
you see they have a customer support
they had like purchase you can purchase
removal you can purchase immunity forest
or decryption anything and you are
paying with Bitcoin of course so this
this is the past then they they change
it a little bit
so so the the initial ransom message
looked like this only in Russia and when
you go further you will see the payment
side has also a slight redesign they
started to use the spora dot help at
gmail.com email address and this
basically says drop here an encrypted
file and I will tell you what you need
to do and you get into this side
notice the change there are only three
purchase options right now so they
basically removed the immunity and also
I think the removal from that package
and everything is in Russian you can
cannot change the language back to
English and if you encounter the new
West spohrer variants samples you will
most likely see this message this is an
HD a script that were that will drop
this message to you probably says
contacts for adult help at gmail.com and
the reason why why it's happening is
they used that onion site that's the
payment site actually in the HDA and
they they proxy it through a proxy
server that is most likely of fly
currently so then they have a fallback
to fall back to that message yeah and if
you go to that onion side you see
basically the redesign or or in progress
payment side I would say and it has a
nice message that says pora 2.0 so
that's that's the second version it's
non-functional currently so if you drop
a encrypted file there they will tell
you sorry an error in count we
encountered an error send us an email to
that email address okay so the Christian
decryption is really simple the
decryption tool is just a
self-extracting archives that will drop
you basically a Decrypter
see your key that can be used for
decrypting all your files and the CMD
file that CMD file you can see here
really simple because the the actual
Decrypter exe only knows how to decrypt
one file so they basically in the CMD
they implemented the enumeration of all
the local and network drives and all the
targeted extensions and they try to
decrypt every one every file on every
Drive basically and the most interesting
thing is immunization until until May it
was it was oh you were able to immunize
your computer against spora that'sthat's
the immunity immunity package there it
was really simple basically you have two
options you either could create the
mutex that they use that was generated
from the volume volume ID or even better
you could generate the state file and
basically you could mark in the state
file that you are in the last state so
everything went okay and then if you
place it in the directory spora will
read it and say okay I'm done so I have
nothing to do here
so some recap about spora I've been
digging deeper into spora and what I did
was that I basically unpacked each poor
executable that we've seen that means
thousands of samples and extracted the
inner packed samples from there I tried
to extract the compiler the compilation
timestamp this might be faked quite
easily but I think that this is not what
was done and I was able to restore some
kind of unofficial change lock of Sporus
comets I promise I'm not outer of Spira
I don't have access to their gate or
whatever repository they are using so
this is only my
library construction so everything
started at the beginning of January
where they released their bump new
consumer out there and what is important
to say is that everything was already
included in it at the time it was using
all those four files it was able to vibe
your shadow copies it was able to spread
like warm everything was in there
another interesting fact is that since
then spora outers are not adding new
features they are just removing them so
they are cutting down the code base into
the skeleton as I will show you so at
that time there was only a Russian
translation and the only thing they
added was after a few hours after the
initial release they've added the
English translation so it was a
billingual
after that they were trying to provide
test versions with and without the links
worth spreading
sometimes they created a new executable
without any changes and the first
remarkable thing that has changed was at
the beginning of the February that they
removed first of those four files they
try to minimize the food stamp footprint
of their code to be less detectable so
they removed LST files with a list of
encrypted files after that they were
trying also to reduce the other file the
key file they were not able at that time
to provide a functional solution so they
removed only part of it and the complete
file has been removed at the end of
February together with some kind I I'd
say it release 1.2 they even speeded up
the encryption a little bit by removing
some code checks so slicing down
something what is really functional and
after that that was all for three months
no changes we were quite happy to
provide a presentation back at Cairo
called spore a new kid on the block we
really enjoyed the after party at Cairo
the band was really great I'm not sure
whether some of them are in here so the
performance great big heart and after
our hangover this was probably our
expression when we've seen that spore
are released just one day after our
presentation a totally different and
totally updated version I call it
release 2.0 in there everything has
changes has changed the code similarity
measured by Ben Dave was like 50% so
they removed or totally redone half of
the code so it was not a minor change
they stopped using for example the
mutexes so mutex based detection of
spora was no longer possible well it was
but it took you much time to track all
the versions and all the differences
also the encryption of files was really
reward the content the structure the
limits everything was different the even
was able to remove the state file so one
was file and its content is from now on
stored at the end of the encrypted file
so they moved all the content to
encrypted files if you want if you want
to login into the payment site you need
to upload encrypted file from this
version and finally they removed also
the complete content of the ransom notes
inside of the HTML files which in this
version contained only a redirection to
payment side so they reduced four files
into zero so this was a drastic change
we were really shocked after that we've
been tracking down all the other changes
a lot was quiet lucky to intercept an
another attempt how to minimize porous
code during June this is the complete
code objects
the cue table just five kilobytes of
code just five functions that's it
nothing more you've got a fully
functional around somewhere on five
kilobytes how they did so the trick is
that they moved the complexity from
executable inside of a JavaScript so the
JavaScript dropped this executable and
it also executed spora by using
different arguments like generate
encryption key encrypt files and so on
but the main executable only contained
five kilobytes of code really
minimalistic however they were not
satisfied with the solution so the other
day they reverted this change and
continued to slice the code in a
different matter so this was the last
major change inside of spora which we
intercepted at the end of July
they removed even more checks so from
now on spora is no longer checking
whether the file was encrypted or not
they don't care also quite interesting
they removed the English translation why
would you do so so from now on it is
once again in Russian only again and
another changes and other changes they
also switched to HTA
from HTML because it was trendy at the
time between ransomware outers and the
last change we've noticed is from the
end of august waved when they released
probably by accident built with the
boxspring printout you can quite easily
analyze what's going on inside of code
thanks to their English commands and
yeah that's it to show you in a more
graphical way what is really changing in
Saito's pora this is some graph with
number of user functions contained
inside of spora they started back in
January with something like 50 functions
and they are reducing this
code complexity from a day-to-day up to
the five functions as I said but this
was reverted so now they are fine with
20 functions if you compare that number
with the other ransomware strains such
as scriptable Rocky crisis those are
hundreds of user functions so spora is
able to do the same thing but with only
minimum number of code so kudos to them
and what had happened in this met graph
so as I said the mutex name generation
is no longer possible and its detection
they also removed all of those four
files and their encryption so no longer
in use everything has been moved inside
of the encrypted files so the structure
is once again totally different and they
no longer providing a free initial
immunization tool they don't want to be
detected by us so they had to remove
that but at the same time they have no
product to be a salt so it's up to them
so everything has really changed okay so
I don't know if we have time but word of
warning before statistics those are just
lies of course
so statistics per month these are unique
users that were in the way where we
detected spora
so you can see in January Russia stands
out so it was going out from Russia but
right after that in February they they
spread all across the globe mainly
Poland Spain Italy France and and Brazil
Brazil was really really badly infected
and then they had lower numbers but
basically the graph looks the same
brazil is always always the first and
they had a new campaign in May where the
the numbers again went up but still
Brazil in the lead and then fall back to
Russia when they remove the English
language and they basically fall back to
Russia in June in July and August yeah
summary
yeah we've pretty much covered
everything what's here
I expect that the spohrer outdoors will
are preparing for for a new campaign
probably this this is of course just
speculation about what but from what
they do with the payment site and with
the executable I pretty much expect that
they are preparing for a new campaign
and of course tomorrow there will be a
total rewrite because we presented this
presentation so thank you very much I
don't know if we have time for questions
but we are happy to answer