22 cool thank you okay good morning some
of you may know me as a major
malfunction which is obviously my real
name sometimes I go undercover as Adam
Lori I do a lot of stuff on invisible
stuff generally so like bluetooth Wi-Fi
RFID now and today I'm going to talk
about far if Id probably most of you saw
Zach's excellent presentation yesterday
on access control systems I'm going to
be talking about the front ends rather
than the back ends but we'll be looking
at some of the same issues but from a
completely different angle you can see
my stuff on tripod org and RF idiot dog
which is where the the RFID stuff is try
phone apps mostly about the Bluetooth
and anyway you can own with that so
before we start you guys we do the
previously feeds on talked about the
DMCA to a certain extent and we've now
in the UK got some pretty dumb laws and
we've just updated our computer misuse
act and now we've got this new clause
which basically says if you if you
produce a tool that is likely to be used
in a computer crime then you've broken
the law so yeah which kind of makes life
difficult for researchers because until
the old tool starts to be used you don't
know what it's going to be used for and
if you think about it if you applied
that law to something like nmap then
clearly when the guy first row nmap and
published it there there's a good chance
that that would be used to look for
vulnerabilities and to break the law so
it's now a very gray area as to where we
stand as far as the law is concerned
well exactly so the question is does
that include screw the screw driver
manufacturer so I sort of look at the
parallel well if we applied that kind of
thinking to the physical world where
would we be now I spend a lot of time
sort of hanging out in hotels and stuff
and some of you may know that I'd tend
to fiddle with the technology in moto
and I was at a hotel recently and they
had there was a brand-new hotel and they
saw the state of the art and so I
thought I'd have some interesting things
to look at and I decided to look at
something physical rather than
electronic and see you know if we if we
applied those laws how would that work
in the physical world and so the tools
that I used are it's multi tool here so
obviously this is a dual purpose tool
and is therefore very evil and should be
immediately made illegal and these very
very dangerous objects the guy who came
up with these has really obviously a
very twisted mind and should be locked
up because these are very very bad at
which you'll see in a minute so I made a
little video of what I did which I'm
going to play for you and normally I ask
actually when I give my talks on
bluetooth there's three of us and we
take it in turns to who's going to be
the lead speaker and we had this kind of
competition going to see who can get the
most hands raised during a talk and you
couldn't just say right everyone raise
your hands you had to come up with an
actual question and so I thought of one
which I thought might win me the
competition so for this one I need to
know everyone raise your hands anyone
here has ever stayed in the hotel yeah I
where'd everyone in the room okay so
those people how many of you have ever
used the hotel safe okay about half of
you okay how many of those believe with
its secure none of you oh one of you
okay so why do you use it
yeah safer than leave handing it to the
guy as we walked out in reception okay
Sonia I made this little video of me
playing with the hotel safe and I showed
it to a guy who was another speaker at a
conference I was at and he's he said
well what would be really funny is if
you get someone to read out the brochure
for this hotel safe while you're doing
what you're doing so I asked for someone
from the audience preferably you know
someone female sexy got a good vibe now
in this case I don't need to ask because
I already have a volunteer that meets
all the criteria so maybe he'll come up
boots so basically she's going to read
out the brochure while I play the video
I've deleted the name of the
manufacturer to protect the criminally
negligent so you want to take that mike
fowler the podium musket and when I tell
you I'll show you the video after
because you don't get to see it which
isn't but i'll show you up it ok so when
i tell you if you could read that don't
we just test the mic friends were so
good with clothes ok so let's try this
ok go for
Peter electronic or mechanical working
system of fatality continuously research
as the development of new teachers
functions options and designs right
products from removable warlocks to a
variety of electronic systems of digital
keypad credit card readers or chip cards
state hospitality offers you products
and the forefront technology our tastes
are installed and the most prestigious
hotels and cruise lines throughout the
world hospitality warranty technical
service thank you so I mean there's a
serious side to that they you know in
the physical world we are getting and in
the security world in general we're
getting people pushing these products
which clearly don't live up to their
expectations and they're getting away
with it I mean this is not some crappy
run-down hotel that I was in this was a
brand-new hotel it's a state-of-the-art
save and they're able to just say you
know this is high security when it
clearly isn't now in the electronic
world we've got the situation where not
only are they getting away with doing
that but it's now illegal for anyone to
notice or to point it out to them so I
think that's bad and we should try and
really push to change that and to to
challenge that so any effort to be no
fight for dmca or the in the UK the
police and justice act should be
followed up vigorously really okay so
the reason we're actually here is talk
about RFID so as a kekkai Nestor day is
there any chance you could actually
point that light or kill it on something
that's right in my face
they're mostly passive chips okay well
that's fine then I'm happy can you turn
it off of it ok so we're mostly talking
about passive devices there are active
ones which have batteries and stuff but
the ones I've looked at so far a passive
now I'm not going to go into too much
detail about how they work
electronically but I am going to talk
about how they work at the kind of
protocol level and the look the logical
level some of you may have noticed the
title of my talk it was called hacking
RFID without soldering iron or a patent
attorney now there was a case recently a
company who shall remain nameless who
prevented a talk being presented at
black hat and again it's you know what
we're talking about the high not being
allowed to talk about insecurities
basically they threatened to sue the
company who are going to present under
patent laws because what they were doing
was cloning their devices and replaying
them and by doing so they had created a
device that used their patented
algorithm and therefore had breached
their patent and so rather than
addressing the problem they throw their
patent attorneys at it and say right
well I said problem solved you can't do
this because it would be breaching our
Payton so everyone's happy so we'll talk
a bit about their stuff as well so that
the two kinds of youth that these types
get generally used for is the idea only
type things which we'll talk about in
some detail and then the more advanced
ones are smart cards where you're
actually having a conversation with the
chip and again we'll talk about those in
more detail so the idea only stuff the
kind of things that's used for animal
IDs is probably the oldest tagged inner
ear tags that tell you which number this
cow is some hotels are now using them as
door entry keys car immobilizers
and sort of one-offs key part of stuff
at that luggage handling has anyone been
through Tokyo Airport recently yeah
you'll probably find if you look on your
bag you've got an RFID tag stuck to the
bag because they have automated systems
for directing the luggage okay okay so
apparently the tags look like an H and
the chips in the middle and the legs are
the antenna so they're quite easy to
spot and human implants which is a kind
of scary thing which again we're going
to talk about in more detail so this I
came across this cartoon to do with
human implants which I thought was quite
amusing now you'd have to put a hell of
a lot more than a camera and an mp3
player in it to get me to bend over to
have one of these installed Britta I
just thought that was that was kind of a
funny take on it so these two rather
nervous looking gentlemen are about to
have an implant done or in fact I think
he's just had one so this guy on the top
is a journalist and he's visiting a
beach I think it's in Spain where
they've signed up to this program where
all the beach vendors accept an RFID
chip as a kind of digital wallet and so
you can buy drinks and you can rent deck
chairs and you can you know go into
clubs and stuff like that by just having
your things can and it's kind of a good
idea you know it means you don't have to
take your wallet to the beach where it
might be Solan you can leave it in your
hotel safe instead where it will be
perfectly safe the other guy he's from
the Mexican government and they're
actually using this for access control
so basically he can get into parts of
the building that other people can't
because he has a chip implanted that
lets the reader know he's there
and in the UK they talked about putting
it in mental patients I think there's so
you know you have a completely gar gar
patient that walks out of a hospital you
can scan him and see who he is and send
him back to the right ward and I think
there's a lot of there's quite a lot of
it here being pushed by a company that
are promoting it for medical uses so I
think they're pushing it more on the
basis that if you have an accident you
can be identified and they can figure
out what your blood type is and all that
kind of stuff now the whole basis of all
this technology is that you've got a
unique ID okay absolutely guaranteed
that ID cannot be cloned you go to the
manufacturers websites and they will say
you know that we've got patented
algorithms this is not possible to
produce to I two units with the same ID
so I don't know if any of you were at
Def Con last year guy called Jonathan
West who has presented a device which
basically clones tags so and you can
download the source code and the
schematics for the device it's about 20
bucks worth of bits you can build that
and it will clone pretty much any RFID
tag so of course when that happens the
industry comes along and comes out with
a defense why this isn't a problem and I
sort of like to think about the the
scene where the techie comes back from
the conference and he goes to his
management and says oh my god you know
they're cloning our tags game over
anyone complain a tag and walk through
the door and the executives that I okay
well you know run along little techy
will think about this will come up with
a solution so thank God for the
executives because they came up with the
perfect solution
so it doesn't look like the original
what's your problem anyone can see that
smoke that so you know run along no
problem here so basically that was their
defense it's not really it's not really
a clone because it doesn't look like the
original so we don't have to worry about
the problem anymore so we got into an
argument about semantics rather than you
know dealing with the actual technical
issue but obviously you know we
understand that the reader doesn't
physically look at the device it just
reads the the tag and if it gets the
same ID and it's effectively the same
device so as far as the readers
concerned that equals that now when I
started researching this talk I had a
look you know Jonathan rest who says
device is there but there are also if
you search on the net there are a bunch
of different projects where they've done
similar stuff and you know these are all
fairly easy to find projects and in fact
this last one is a circuit city you know
do your own cloning device over the
weekend project so but not to worry none
of them look like a tag so we're all
perfectly safe this isn't an issue so I
took that as a challenge could we
actually get past the semantics argument
and really look at this and see if there
really is a issue here and to do that we
have to create a true clone so one that
not only has the same digital number
digital identity but physically the same
form factor okay so to do that first we
have to understand how the ID is
presented and how its structured and so
on so I took the example of animal
tagging now this is a standard called I
so 11 784 or ft XP and basically it has
three fields you get an ID and it
consists of three parts the first part
is a flag which just says if it's an
animal application or non
application then you get a three digit
country or manufacturer code and then
you get your local unique ID so the
country or the manufacturer will issue
the national ID and the way that's
actually transmitted from the tag to the
reader is you design it to work on a
particular frequency so most of these ID
only tags actually work in the 1 25
kilohertz range the smart cards tend to
work in 1356 megahertz you will transmit
the data at a certain bit rate which
tends to be frequency divided by some
factor of 2 you'll send it with a
particular encoding mechanism so whether
it's FSK or Manchester or by phase or
whatever and then you send a specific
bit pattern so some of these some of
these parameters are in common between
the different standards so they have a
header or a bit pattern structure that
allows them to identify themselves as
being tagged taipei instead of take type
thee even though the rest of the
parameters may be the same so if I was
to take an animal ID and read it on a
dumb reader what I would get is an eight
byte sequence of numbers and if you look
at the structure here so the first few
bites are the national ID and you've got
the country and then you've got the
application code and you have to perform
a few operations on that number to
actually translate it to the real IDs so
basically you take the raw ID you
reverse it reverse the bits you then
reverse each nibble you then right shift
the country code and that gives you the
decimal code which you can then look up
there's a website on I car door guy car
is the organization that control the
manufacturers IDs you can go and look
that up and so in this case ID 985
equates to dest Ron fearing and they've
issued the local
idea of 312 blah blah blah so that's
quite simple and this is all published
so you can download the specs and you
can read how that works in more detail
so if I want to encode the ID obviously
I just reverse that whole process I
create my 64 bit roar ID and then have
to add the binary headers so I stick a
header on the fixed bits in between the
the ID bytes is basically the headers
are a bunch of zeros so it's like a one
and nine zeros or something and so what
they do then is they break up the ID in
24 bit chunks and they stick a one every
four bits and what that does is it
prevents the header from being
accidentally repeated in the bit stream
so that the nine zeros can't exist in
the data because there's a one every
four bit so we now have our raw 128 bits
of data so how do we actually deliver
that to the reader I thought about this
from the manufacturers point of view if
I was a manufacturer making RFID chips
and there's this huge explosion of you
some proliferation of different
standards I wouldn't want to be making
from scratch every different type of
RFID tag so it seemed to me that what
they would do is they would produce a
tag that was able to be switched between
the different formats because that unit
that makes their life much easier lower
manufacturing costs stocking costs and
so on so I looked around the market and
sure enough I came across a couple of
tags that actually follow this
philosophy so there's a device called a
q5 and what the q5 does is it allows you
to set each of the parameters
independently so you can take you can
set the bit rate you can set the
modulation you've got 224 bits of user
programmable data I need to program 128
so that's plenty of room for me to put
my ID in and you can tell it how many
bytes to actually spit out when you get
to open up so these are dumb tags they
just they sit there and when they get
energized they start barfing the bit
pattern out so you tell it how many bits
of the 224 to actually spit out the
other approach is there's a device
called a high tag too and thats similar
in that you can program it to tell it to
use different parameters but it has
already pre-programmed personalities so
it has three different modes of
operation and they they translate to a
certain bit rate modulation and so on so
and those three modes actually as it
happens I equate to the most commonly
used ID or door entry systems car
immobilizers and animal tax so quite
handy the three things that we might
find interesting till we say okay so I
now know that this stuff exists and I
know how to produce the data so I
started looking around that you know
where can I get one of these and I had
an office you know we have a door entry
system at my office so I had a look at
that we actually moved office so it was
now redundant and I found that I could
actually reprogram my existing door tape
so if I just set the bit rate set the
modulation program the the ID into it it
should then behave like the thing I'm
trying to emulate so I'm going to give
you a quick demonstration of an access
control system it's not as pretty as ax
its is actually a bit of gaffer tape and
a battery and you know an LED rather
than a nice unit but
and actually this this raises an
interesting issue because obviously I
flew here how many people flew here to
view I can't see you anymore because I'm
busy looking good in the lights so I
flew here and I have a lot of stuff in
my bag which could be misinterpreted so
you know you've got that so I tend to
carry it in my hand luggage so I can
explain when when you know the officers
want to know why I've got things with
batteries and circuit boards and and so
on so I was coming through the security
checkpoint and in front of me there was
a couple with a newborn baby okay so
they've got their pram and they've got
their baby they got a bunch of luggage
and they're scanning it all through the
Machine and the white gets sent through
and the baby gets sent through and the
pram gets sent through and finally the
guys left on his own with a sort of
little zippy bag thing and inside the
bag there's six bottles of milk okay and
the customs of the security guy says
where you can't take liquids on board
and he's like okay well we've got a
12-hour flight we've got a newborn baby
this is his milk needs to go through so
he calls their supervisor over and the
supervisor said okay no that's fine
milks an exception in a baby milks
inception you can take that through but
you have to prove that it's milk first
so he has to take the lid off each
bottle and taste each one and first of
all I'm saying they're thinking hmm what
kind of milk is that
you really love your wife don't you
anyway so he takes each bottle and he
sends it to them by this point there's
you know this is all taking time and
there's a bit of a crowd building up
behind us and there's you know two or
three security guys the guy from the
machines come over and they're all kind
of milling around and I'm thinking great
that's all I need you know I've got a
bag full of electronic crap and there's
you know bits and pieces that they're
going to have to really look at if they
want me to pull it out and it's all up
on the screen and their circuits and
there's wires amid batteries and there's
all sorts of crap and I've now got these
three guys all standing there and a big
crowd of people behind me so they're
looking at it and they're looking at it
and sort of nudging each other and
talking and then one of them turns to me
and says no fluids in there are no fine
money go that's good so you know it's
crazy what what's happening at the
moment is people are focused on shoes
and fluids and anything else you know
just because it looks like a bomb that's
fine don't even bother checking what it
is it's not fluid so yeah bit crazy
anyway so if i plug this in so what
we've got here is an access control
system this is the reader this LED
lights up if I open the door
successfully so if i take the correct
door tag hopefully you'll see can you
see the LED okay so basically that would
be the door actuator that opens the door
if i take my door tag nothing's going to
happen okay because it's the wrong door
tag so what I'll do now is we try and
reprogram this to be that
how's that is that readable okay so but
I'm going to use is an off-the-shelf
compact flash format reader writer and
this is a little keyboard wedge reader
so basically these tags are sold under
the brand unique okay and you can buy a
unique reader and this is a keyboard
wedge which if you put one of these on
it it will just type it into the system
as if you typed the idea on the keyboard
so if I put that in
should get so basically just preventing
the tag to the reader gives me its ID
number okay so as this is branded unique
I've written a little program called
unique I tell it is unique tag that's
just ID and I want to write it I'll take
my blank tag and in theory that's now
done so that's been reprogrammed to be
that ID so if I got it right what should
happen if I hold it up I'm now in your
building so as you saw the kit to read
the CID is simply that so if I had that
in a little handheld and I walked past
you read the key out of your pocket
that's all it took a couple of seconds
to get that ID and I've now cloned your
door entry system so I'm sorry say again
did I use the same device to write it
now this this is a read-only device
they're they're pretty cheap it just
reads the ID number this was the one I
used to write it which is a compact
flash writer I'll talk about the
hardware towards the end but this stuff
is freely available and it's I mean it's
not cheap but it's not usually expensive
do ask questions as we go along by the
way okay so that's that's the ID systems
the other thing I was going to talk
about was cloning an animal tank so
normally I would bring my cow along but
she got detains of security something
something to do with fluids under 94 but
so i have i have with me my little mouse
friend
who actually if anyone's interested if
you want to get implanted this is the
needle that they're gonna stick in you
okay so he squeaked a bit when I put it
in him but not too much going to pass
that around oh sorry about that you're
now now permanently tagged but nevermind
okay so basically normally what I do is
I have a little webcam so I can show you
what's being shown on the display but i
cleverly did an update and broke my
drivers so it's not actually working
this morning so what I'll do is I'll
just pass this around and basically you
press the red button and it will start
scanning and then you when you hear a
beep its read the ID so it's read off
9680 470 double 897 so I'll just pass
this around and you can start having a
look at it so the idea is I'm going to
try and reprogram this tag so it's now
completely different standard the
original standard that I programmed it
to be as unique I'm now going to program
it to be an FTX be tagged and try and be
the same ideas for the mouse so first
thing I have to do is reset the tag back
to its original state when I first
started doing this this was the only tag
i had and i quickly broke it obviously
you know when you're experimenting and
you're messing around with head of
formats and so on it's very easy to send
it the wrong thing and the tag just
decided it's not going to play anymore
and I then found a manufacturer who sold
blanks so I bought a pile of blanks and
after a while I broke all of those two
so one day I was on a very long train
ride and I was going to a job and I had
like four hours to kill so I sat down
and thought I need to fix this so I
actually came up with a program
these tags are these are the q5 tags so
I came up with a program that fixes that
so that resets it back to a default
value and I can then program it so I
tell it's an animal tank I then give it
its local ID so whoever's got the reader
if you could shout out the number yeah
ok so again I tell it i want to write
the tag actually in the in the interest
of trying to follow the original form
factor what i'm going to do instead of
writing it to this i've got one of these
tags in my wrist so i'm going to program
my reprogram my tag to be the mount ok
so i will do that
never do live demos okay so in theory
that's now reprogrammed so whoever's got
the scanner ah yeah I'm not crazy enough
to have one of those needles stuck in me
it's actually found into my watch strap
so if you want to scan the mouse first
press the cut okay I'm read the ib ok so
now scan my wrist John a terre i am that
mouth thank you my wife will be
delighted so unique ID I don't think so
does it only work across the same chip
type of form factor the q5 device is
sold in dozens of different form factors
so you can get it from these kind of
cards credit card shaped cards key fobs
you know ones that look like this you
can get ones that are impervious to heat
little males that you can mail into
wooden planks all kinds of formats so
whatever it is you're trying to clone
there's a very good chance you will find
the physical format that matches the
original so some of the issues I thought
about you know why this this is a
problem obviously you can track
individuals you know i'm using a little
reader like this but if you've ever been
in a shop you know and you see their
security gates as you walk out those two
gates that catch you shoplifting
those are basically using the same
technology so you could position those
around the place and anyone who walks
through them you'll read their IDs or
you can wire rapid or anyone that walks
through the door frame you'll get them
hi them antenna under the floor whatever
so pretend the potential to track people
which means you can then obviously
target individuals if you're looking for
a certain person arriving on the scene
impersonate people to get access to
buildings but also the other way round
provide an alibi you know if we start
using these for compliance so say
somebody's on probation and they have a
tag implanted and they have to go to a
police station once a week or once a day
and prove that they are there if i
reprogram my tag to be them then I've
provided them with a perfect alibi I've
got the police saying yeah he was here
in the police station at eleven o'clock
when that Bank was being robbed so and
obviously the the sort of far end of the
scale you know we all like to talk about
the T word smart bombs to go off when a
certain person comes in range I've heard
that there's a South American military
for actually using these implanted tags
for their officers so the officers get
access to certain parts of the base and
the grunts don't so you see one of these
implants going by you know it's an
officer time to go bank so how do we fix
that don't rely on raw IDs okay so we're
now going to talk about the smart card
type RFID tags but actually you have a
conversation with the tag and the
example that I'm going to use is the UK
passport of the the e passports in
general now I quite often get asked how
do I know if my passport has a chip in
it this logo here
that's an international standard if
you've got a new passport and you have
that logo on it then you have a chip in
your passport if you don't then you
probably don't have a chip in your
passport but that's the clue if you come
from the UK the other clear is there's
this dirty great tip in the back of your
passport but I don't know why we do that
but most countries don't that the chip
is hidden so what they're actually doing
with this stuff is they're storing data
about you on the passport if you go and
look at the standard there's defined in
the standard 48 different fields of data
that they're going to store in these
passports and that includes stuff like
you know biometrics fingerprints your
facial image so the picture that's in
the past for the document you use to get
the passport in the first place so if
you produce the birth certificate that
will be scanned and stored on the
passport your home address your phone
number your profession all kinds of
stuff so really an ID thieves paradise
so it's got all this really secure stuff
on it or important data it's obviously
you want to protect it right so they use
encryption they use pseudo-random IDs so
unlike this tag when you present the
passport to a reader this tag gives off
unique ID with a passport it gives off a
pseudo-random ID so I can't just walk
past you and find out your passport
number is 1234 and I can now track you
because next time I scan your passport
is going to give out a completely
different number to read the data from
the passport I need to authenticate so
they've encrypted the communication
between the passport and the reader and
they've done that with three days and
that's a standard called basic access
control now the standard says you don't
have to protect it you can allow people
to just log in and read it without doing
any kind of authentication
but if you do then you have to use the
basic access control standard and that's
all laid out exactly how it works the
other thing potentially you can do is
encrypt the content but again that's
optional it's up to each country whether
they do the encryption or not and if
they do in this case it's also up to
them how they do it did you have a
question ok so the question was because
three days is a symmetric key algorithm
how do you you really got one key that's
shared by everyone or you've got some
massive key management problem ok all
you have to do some kind of key change
so you do what you do is actually you
you do some hashed challenge responses
so yes good point so what they've done
is they've standard those the way you
figure out the key it's different for
each passport but the way you find it is
the same ok so basically you read the
DMR Zed the machine-readable zone at the
bottom of the passport you take the
first field which is the passport number
you take the date of birth and you take
the expiry date of the passport and you
add those things together and that's
your key that's very secure so I'm
actually going to demonstrate doing this
so change reader again this is an
off-the-shelf reader this is the high
frequency stuff so quick change of kit I
also meet
okay so normally what would happen is
you would hand your you would hand your
passport to the Board of Control and
they would take it they'd run it through
a machine called the name as a breeder
and that would read the bottom line of
the mrz and derived the key from it
because i don't have an MRA reader we
have to type it in so here's one I
prepared earlier so if i put the
passport there so it's now read it's
logged in it's now reading the trials as
you can see it's read the the mrz data
so that's the actual name and the date
of birth and stuff stored in the
passport it's now reading another file
each item is stored as a discrete file
so there is what is actually stored so
as you can see I was much better looking
when I had this passport even with the
lights and all that this is actually my
son's passport and this is what stored
so none of this has taken off my artist
this is actually stored in the passport
so his image name date of birth expiry
date all of that stuff is directly
stored on the passport okay so if you
now wanted to make a duplicate at this
passport you've got not just a rough
idea of what should be on there but the
exact data that should be on the real
passport which I can't help feeling is
bad
plus whatever data they used to get the
passport actually at the moment this is
all that's stored on there I haven't
seen I've looked at probably six or
seven different countries passports and
so far the only thing I've seen stored
is this stuff the newer stuff like the
fingerprints and so on isn't yet stored
on any passports but in the UK by 2010
you'll have to actually to in order to
get a passport you will have to be
fingerprinted and rs scanned and a whole
bunch of other stuff you're going to
have to give up those 48 items of data
the other thing sorry gone ok how
difficult is it practically for somebody
to clone your passport because they have
to actually get hold of it thank you the
well there's two outs of to that one is
once you've got it the blanks are
available it has been done german
researcher whose name escapes me just at
the moment but i can find out if you're
interested afterwards has already proved
that you can just take this data and
copy it directly to a blank the blanks
are worth about a pound each maybe a
little bit more so it's definitely
doable the one of the defense's I mean
I've been having some discussions with
the UK Home Office about this stuff not
directly through the newspapers of
course
I do stuff they publish a story they
issue a rebuttal one song but one of the
things they said was ok so you've copied
the passport which you had in your hand
and you could have photocopied what's
the big deal and so I was challenged by
a UK newspaper called the Daily Mail to
say well would it be possible to read
the passport without actually having it
open in your hands and being able to
read the ml Zed and I believed it was
and so they challenged me to actually do
that so that the way it worked was I
went to their office and they had
someone apply for a new passport and it
arrived and in the sealed envelope they
gave me the sealed envelope and said
right now read that possible and I read
it in about four hours basically so I
brute forced yes there's no shielding in
the UK passport the only passport I've
seen so far that has any shielding in
the cover is the US passport so if that
had been a u.s. passport in a sealed
envelope I wouldn't have been able to
read it the UK passport when it's closed
you can read it but incidentally the US
passport if you just allow it to flop
open like this the shielding actually
acts as a kind of amplifier makes it
even easier to read but the reason that
was possible so if I try and read this
guy again say I didn't know the last
three digits of the passport number i
can just brute force it there's no
protection in the passport to stop me
just doing repeated access attempts and
failing and trying again yes sir
right so the question was now I did it
once would it take four hours to do the
next one no it would be considerably
faster because the keyspace I was having
to check included what i thought was
roughly the current passport number
because we issue the passport
sequentially I knew roughly where they
were what I was doing was checking about
10,000 numbers once I've done one on a
particular day I would have a much
better clue as to where we were in the
sequence so I probably only have to
check about a thousand so it would be
about 10 times faster and this is just
for new ones yes I mean it's not a
practical this is not a practical attack
against random passports you see in the
street but the point was that you know
the defense that it was impossible to
read a passport without having it
physically in your hands and open was
was failed was not true so any other
questions okay so question is so you can
copy one but can you forge one so can
you change the content of an existing
passport or create a completely
arbitrary one so when I was reading the
files as I said each one is stored in a
discrete file so each object each of the
48 items is in a file stored on the
passport so the image is in a file
called EF dg2 and I extract that to a
jpeg there is a device there is a file
called the security object the fso d and
e FS OD contains digital signatures for
each of the other files and the
signature for itself if we look at that
with a hex editor
you can see that with in there there's
the signing authorities public key okay
so you can check the signature against
the public key of the authority that
issued it which you read from the
passport anyone spot the deliberate
mistake okay so basically you're
checking the validity of an object
stored on this object against an object
stored on this object so i give you the
new key that matches the signed stuff
that I've given you and it's game over
I'm sorry at the border they yeah so
okay the defense against that is at the
border they would have the public keys
that they're going to check against
you've got something like 28 countries
signed up to this these keys are going
to expire monthly i believe so you're
going to have a massive key distribution
problem CR l's and so on which we know
anyone who does PK I will know that the
crl issue is one of the biggest issues
you have to deal with so again I brought
this up in the UK and said well it's not
secure because I could forge the key and
they said oh no there's there's a thing
called the PKB so the PKB is the public
key directory and it's an internet
accessible directory of all the public
keys and all the revocation lists for
all the countries signed up to this
project so I read the specs I'm sure
enough the spec says there is a PKD and
it will be publicly accessible over the
internet and here's how you talk to it
blah blah blah so I contact the UK
passport office and say how do I get
access to this no response I'd search
the internet for any clues as to how you
get access there aren't any so I found
the website of the working group they're
actually defining the standard for the
PKB they finally ratified their design i
think in june of last year
and they put it out to tender at that
point and i believe they appointed a
company to deliver this system in around
october of last year so if this system
is already deployed and working and
being used that will be the fastest
government IT project ever done I'm the
entire history of the world so I just
don't believe it exists at the moment
yes so the question is are they signed
by it's typical Authority this is the
public key of the certificate authority
so the way the PKB works is each country
sets up its own authority and they have
write access to the PKB so they can
update the public keys for their country
so it's up to you the person checking
the document to go and get the public
key and check that it matches the one on
the passport and that the signatures
match for the objects that are signed
with that key any other questions yeah
right okay okay so the question was have
I had any discussions with them about
disabling the chip or you know what
would be the response if I try and use a
device with the chip disabled the
standard specifically says having a
non-functional chip should not prevent
you from crossing a border ok so the
device isn't expected to necessarily
work and in fact in a recent audit
office review of the technology in the
UK like most countries our passports
last for 10 years the chips are
warranted by the manufacturer for two
years
so I think it's not a problem if it
doesn't work but if it didn't work the
second time they'd probably make you pay
so the first time they'd say you need a
new passport will replace it second time
it'd probably make you pay and the third
type may might detect some kind of
pattern forming here and decide to
prosecute you because you know this
isn't mine this belongs to well this
belongs to my son but mine belongs to
the government as well so I'm not
allowed to interfere with it right so
you don't bother replicating wrong with
a chip you just do a blank one which
doesn't have the logo on or whatever
that's not going to work because for
example in the US if I have a passport
as a UK citizen if I have a passport
issued after October of last year and it
doesn't have an RFID chip in it then I
cannot participate in the visa waiver
program so the US has actually forced
this technology on to the rest of the
community by imposing that restriction
so everybody had to adopt a passport by
October of last year otherwise their
citizens couldn't travel freely to the
US anymore well as I said if you have an
RFID passport and the chips not working
you'll get away with it the first time
yes you could and you'd get away with it
once so you can either disable your
existing chip or you can forge your own
and not have a chip in it at all but the
end result will be the same that they
will probably let you through the border
once and the second time they will start
to ask awkward questions
Terrace will get through once which is
all they need yes sir ok so the Creator
if from the point of view / identity
theft could you just walk past some when
I'm read their passport answer no
because you need to know the key details
so in order to log in I need to know
quite a lot about the passport to be
able to do the three days basically
authentication so it's not really a
threat as far as sort of drive-by
attacks go but the real issue I think
from my point of view is when they first
introduced these they said this is going
to increase your security I can't see
anything about having that chip in there
containing digital copies of my data
that does anything to enhance my
security this is not a better more
secure passport than the old one that
didn't have a chip in it you can't ok so
so the comment was you could read the
chip and then offline brute force the ID
know that the mechanism is it's a
challenge response so you say to the
passport here's a random number hash
with mikey and it says back go away
that's the wrong number yes so did you
see if you're sitting next to someone in
an airplane for ten hours you could
brute force it yes and in fact I've got
a little bluetooth reader that allows me
to plump the reader somewhere and sit
somewhere else doing the actual work so
just I think we're running out of time
so I'll just quickly flashed through my
final slides
so the obvious threat we can we prove
that we can get the key data from other
channels we don't physically need the
passport in our hand I've also found
like an profiled passports to a certain
degree so I can tell when I see a
passport even without logging into it or
trying to read the details so just
random person walking past I can figure
out to some degree which country you
come from for certain countries so i
reckon at the moment i can determine a
US passport i can determine an Italian
passport and I can determine an
Australian passport so the code that
i've been using here is all open source
you can download it it's currently
drives a couple of different
manufacturers devices ACG and frosh
there's an open source project called
open PCD which we're about to start work
on trying to get my code working with
their hardware so you can build your own
very low cost reader I actually have a
few bits of kit with me if anyone's
interested but I build these things ACG
don't normally sell to end users they
don't have any kind of finished products
that you can just buy from their site so
i buy the components and i solder them
together and I I sell them it's not
something I particularly want to do so
if anyone finds people who are shipping
ready-made readers that happen to be a
CG under the hood let me know and I'll
point to them on the website this was
the comment from a CG having been very
helpful at the beginning they suddenly
notice what I was doing which i think is
a kind of a shame because you know it's
in all of our interest that the
technology is secure but it's kind of
typical of commercial industries looking
at people pointing out mistakes and
that's pretty much it any other
questions
I think the reprogrammable cars will go
away now I really don't think so i think
that the problem is just the way they're
being used you know you shouldn't rely
an rfid tag is an authentic it's not an
authentication token it's an ID token so
you shouldn't rely on a unique number to
say not only is this what it says it is
but it's guaranteed to be you know being
operated by the person who's authorized
to use it you have to have some second
factor of authentication if I've
understood you could you could you block
people from being able to read your tag
by broadcasting another tag is that what
you're saying yes on on on the low
frequency stuff there tends to be no
collision detect so if you put two tags
in the field it's not going to work the
higher frequency stuff the ACG that the
1356 smart card stuff they do kind of
random back off some stuff to allow
multiple tags to speak at the same time
okay I definitely overrun now but before
we go I just wanted to quickly mention
there's as you probably seen there some
collections going on for the hacker
foundation and one of them is to pay to
see a grown man sacrifice his colon
I think here's a task that we would all
like to contribute to and I know some of
you may be worrying you know he's flying
home tomorrow and there'll be other
passengers on the plane and we maybe
have to think about them but in any good
cause there will always be some
collateral damage so I think that's a
risk that we should take so everyone
please reach in your pocket and put 10
bucks or 20 bucks into there and we will
see this man eat 40 what is it is it 40
a 40 patty in and out burger in one city
which is a really horrible sight for
anyway there you go okay thank you again
as well can you thank video man for
helping zach with his face the video man
where he's at work helping as a cow mmol
new jobs to provide samuel reinforced
eyelets right but it was seen but we're
gonna break for lunch there's 100 ryos
dozen and one night without animatics
and if we had neva didn't have the
promise that I would be fermented that
original speaker she's the purpose of
divine we have a bunch more fit and well
be a fever Henry we're done
you