and the past known attacks and like how
those attacks with like material
recanting and obviously about the puzzle
that I've worked on and finally the demo
of like one of the crashes okay and
obviously I won't be like discussing the
details about the crash that has taken
place because I were a tipping point I
probably want to make money out of it
and yeah i'll show you the demo to sit
so scared up so how many of you are like
familiar with skate around here well
beautiful like you lot more people than
I expected so scanner dick is defined as
a supervisory control data acquisition
and that is the acronym for it and it is
defined as the common process of
application and collects data from
sensors and shafts off or in the remote
locations and sends it to the central
computer for like what you got the
processing of that particular data so a
typical example would be like in a
manufacturing plant or something where
like you're like doing some kind of
manufacturing and you are having like
say like you're producing a thousand
computers a day and say some point of
the parts is like you just ran out and
so like you have like the first 800
which has been manufactured completely
and like the next 200 which just doesn't
have that particular part in it that
kind of thing so you want those sensors
to send out information through your
central server and there you basically
say okay fine like stop production right
now that kind of thing so and it is like
the most widely component of your cradle
infrastructure by critical
infrastructure I mean like all your
nuclear power plants your electricity
utilities the gas war all those places
everywhere I mean the manufacturing
plants are just like the smaller scale
of where the scalar networks is being
used right now so the basic components
of the scanner networks are like you
have like the operator the guy who looks
into the computer and things like he's
cool and then you have the human machine
interface which basically pulls out like
the software basically which puts out a
nice GUI of the
how the interpretation is there after
all the data that it collected from the
empty use what an mpu is basically it's
a master terminal unit which basically
aggregates all the data from all the
remote sensors and then pulls it up
together makes an analysis of it and
gives the this one like it if the MTU
basically does or if there's an any
query coming and likes it from the any
of the RT use it just says like okay
this is the response for it but there
are like some cases where the odd cases
where the empty use is not able to make
a decision for it that's when like it
comes to the operator to make the call
so one such cases like when lick your
manufacturing something and like you
don't have like some parts available
anymore so then that's when like you
want to like check up with this one the
empty empty makes a flag for that
canceling then there's the communication
channel they can write another scalar
network goes through all sorts of
possible channels like right from
Internet to your wireless cell phone
towers everything so and finally the RT
use which basically does the oldest
dirty work of collecting the data here's
a cool little thing that I do well as
you can see over here like the the
robotics is something some kind of like
manufacturing plants those are the RT
years and then we have like the routers
and the plz plz sub messing with program
logic controllers and those are used to
again like they can be working as an
intermediate three empty use so again
like this entire scatter architecture
you don't have to like make it less like
one master and slave it came like master
master and slave like I'm like the
intermediate guy acts as a slave to the
above the hierarchy that just like your
tree hierarchy I can't think and like
initially one like the scalar networks
were all developed they were all mainly
going through like the serial ports and
those kind of things and they were like
short distance that cannot think and so
it all started that way like using like
rs-232 and those kind of things and now
nowadays nowadays it's all going through
ethernet and then like the expected ones
is going to be like also like the
wireless in the caster so this is like
the basic diagram like how it could
possibly look and oh yeah obviously like
you can attack on like the into the HMI
itself we're like
the anti processing takes place you can
attack the empty you wear like you can
force that want to go down to and you
can attack the PLC's or the rtu it's
like the sensors it's of you can take
control of the sensors it's of in order
to buck they take an attack of thing why
do we need security in the scalar
networks firstly Emily simple question
when this product and when if i'm not
wrong like your Modbus was like created
in like 1970s so obviously they didn't
have security in mind in 1970s when they
created these stuffs for like
communication purposes and when they did
that and then like now it's still being
used by some of the not some like many
of the companies they still use Modbus
protocol and there was an extension to
it called Modbus plus and the marbles or
Internet in those kind of things but the
the basics of the protocol it still
remains the same but didn't think about
adding any of the security features to
it it's still one double select some of
your critical infrastructure is like we
use dnp3 in like all most of the gas in
the water industries and it's still not
so secure the UCR see but yeah right
that kind of thing so it's pretty easy
I'm like the next thing is like the
pretty one good example was like the
blackout emlak which took place in 2003
January yeah yeah 2003 January and it
was basically an overload and that kind
of thing but you can also likes it and
there was like the other case where like
you had like the nuclear power plant go
down for like five hours and I'll get
back to those examples coming Nick next
slides so that was just one example like
the blackout happened because of the
overload but there could be like
possibly like the government is like
probably hiding it from us or something
and in there we're like somebody
attacked into it it's like very easy I'm
like it's not like so very difficult yes
Jeff so I know I thought he had a
question sir until like the blackout
silica that was just one for you think
the
hey think about the case where like your
company in Company B and like what if
you're producing the same stuff unlike
one easy way one like take on the
company b will be like yeah they produce
so many stuffs during the Christmas time
that's when their sales is really high
let's take them down on Christmas that
kind of thing so simple ways you don't
even have to go and hack into like the
main servers or anything just take down
the cooling system of the company and
they let all the service blend down that
kind of thing so it's like one easy way
to like take control of the company and
make them into loss or something like
that thing now that I'm recommending you
guys should do it add button like I'm
just like saying that's simple way to do
it then like try to find real hard bunt
overseas and get into those computers
and then like obviously there's other
possibility to like where like if the
sensors are supposedly giving you like
some feeds the values so say something
to determine like the temperature of
this particular room and with this
server room if the temperature is
supposed to be maintained at 65 degrees
Fahrenheit unlike and sensor sends out
saying it's 65 degrees Fahrenheit even
though like we have taken control over
the sensor and that is sending out false
information to you where it's like the
real thing is like probably 85 or
something that kind of thing and the
other cool thing about these protocols
is that like not the cool thing I'm like
it's a sad thing actually so you don't
need authentication to like talk to the
servers I'm like you can just like go in
like send and like this is the
instruction that I want you to execute
as a server I like the solar just
executors and send it back to you so
that's how weak it is I'm like there's
like no check as to like this is the IP
address it's coming from this is the
thing that not even those kind of basic
tests so that you just go in like
sending like a data saying oh this is my
instruction why don't you do it and the
saw was just going to respond back to
you saying yeah this is the answer to
your query and like this is the thing I
hourly okay I'm going to go like you
asked me to shut down so i'll go shut
down that kind of thing so that's how
simple it is to do it so yeah the attack
scenarios will be like basically
providing false data like the way I
totally like in the case like of a
temperature sensor or like sensing like
the water pollutants so here's an
example like we're like you take out the
water from the lake or some
and process it and then sending it out
to all the houses all over the your part
of the county or lick your state that
kind of thing so what happens is like if
there is a pollutant in the water it's
supposed to go out but that has been
determined by the sensors inside the
water they can't say so if you can like
control over those sensors and say like
well the water is fine you can just send
it that kind of thing I'm like it's
going to go through and everybody who is
going to drink the water is going to
eventually die of false like that kind
of thing so that's one simpler case and
denial of service attack basically like
like I totally like sending out like a
reboot instruction to the service it's
like you need an authentication to do
that so if I keep on sending reboots
command to the server continuously it's
going to keep on rebooting every time
and like it's not going to be processing
any data so you're like totally taking
down the entire network there and
obviously they're the extremity protocol
anomalies and like most of the software
is when I looked into them I'm like it
was a pretty sad I'm like the first
thing that you see is like feel like
make the software like to just sell it
out as soon as possible if they don't
even care about like that the looks and
the feel of the software not even
examine like this just one like have
something which says okay this is the
instruction this is the output go for it
that kind of thing alchemia done it and
they don't even comply with any of the
rfcs or any of the standards basically
how these software's make how they're
supposed to be interacting for this
particular protocol that kind of thing
so that's really Emily every time I look
into once out try like ugh this is like
too simple to do it they can't think and
the previous attacks there was one
particular thing in California's of the
first one where apparently al-qaeda had
some connections over here and this was
portion i just googled up and i founded
in Washington Post in June 27 2002 where
they apparently had all the schematics
and everything of taking down like the
power utility over here and second one
is like the cut those this contractor
was working for this Russian thing yes
it was an Australian thing yeah so yeah
he was working over there he got laid
off and he knew how the scalar system
was over there like how those things
were managing the input and he just
threatened the company that like if they
don't pay him something of the kind of
thing and like he was
like basically introduced sewage water
into the drinking water and lake or make
everybody for second second thing and
because there was a slammer worm ever
lonely which they took down one of the
nuclear plants for like fires and the
other thing was like the hacker in this
one is in Russia where like he takes
control of the gas pipelines I know if
any we will just look 24 over here
anyway yeah I'm like i watch all five
seasons of it like and lick the
Christmas break so like I know which
season it was but in one of them like
they do think about like introducing the
nerve gas into it without being fresh
that was basically taking control of the
scalar system indirectly that's it so
you basically could do that do they take
control over there and like take control
of the sensors like not to like send out
the values the readings to you and once
you are done with your thing and then
like when the real thing is going
through like then release it back so
like the server is going to think mobile
the sensor just went down for a while or
something like counting and it's going
to like come back but am I going really
fast or something and like I got a
little bit carrier subject so these are
the scale of protocols that you can see
out there like these are just a few of
them for the feel like Modbus dnp3 mod
bacillus like probably one of the most
ancient one slick probably little few of
the first ones to be developed and it
still being used a lot all over the
places and Modbus was like mainly
develop for like all the utilities again
all the utility companies basically use
that one dnp3 is like mainly for water
and gas that's that's where like they
use dnp3 a lot and so this and I CCP is
like used and like all the pretty go
although probably like all the
electricity place and everything and you
see a is again like you see a and you
see a part of you see 82 architecture
which stick damn I forgot the name ah I
forgot an expansion for it so you see
again like it's an architecture
basically for like the communication
models I'm like what it does is like
again for like all the electricity and
like all those people they usually
different standards like all the ice
standard and like part of IEC standards
are used in even iccp too so these are
again like used for like the electricity
and like those generations places and of
course like all there are also many
other more protocols over there now
let's get on to like the Modbus protocol
so do the basic architecture like the
first two bikes is always a transaction
ID so each MTU is going to be like
talking to like lots of client IDs I'm
like actually theoretically they can
talk to like to 55 of them but so and
each one is going to have an transaction
ID with it so that you can be talking to
like the ID one with the transaction ID
2 or something and then like with the
client ID to with some hundred
transaction or that kind of thing so the
first two bites always determines the
transaction ID the next two bytes is the
protocol identifier which always has to
be zero is two nulls then the next two
White's is the length light and the
strange thing is like most of the
queries all have a length of six bytes
so if you want to like future in the
future you want to go build up your own
stuff so yeah yeah why should just
support these two I know yeah currently
they do that's like I was like pretty
shark like when I saw like oh wow this
is like awesome and these guys are like
crazy cool like I like I in fact like
the first where they actually starting
to write my pleasure I know if you guys
have heard about Auto def a uto da fé
that one is basically what it does is
like it takes out like the interpreters
from the Wireshark like those files and
then like it creates a test cases kind
of things like a generic thing it
doesn't like go through like that
details of it just like spills out like
what are all the things that you can
take in that kind of thing so that's how
I look into it first and then like I
thought like I'll write it out based on
that particular order def way then like
I thought like you know what that's not
going to give me like so much of
feasibility like so much of extensions
that I really want to do that won't be
possible in that kind of thing so I kind
of like ended up not to use that then
the next two bites of the length and
then that unit identify which is the
basically the client identifier so you
basically
you can say like client ID with
so-and-so is requesting for so-and-so
information that kind of thing and the
next byte is the most important one
which is the function bite we're like
the it seems like perform this
particular operation that kind of thing
and the last last one is like the data
or the sub function sum of the function
codes taken like some functions to like
like all the diagnostic ones they'll
take in like and sub function code to
and the data basically is being like
asking like supposing it's requesting
for particular register value so it's
going to like mention the register
number over the data portion just after
the sub function thing so basically this
particular picture is from why sure yeah
and if you see in there like the 0800
for that is basically the 08 is the
diagnostic bit which is being set and
then like the 04 is the force listen
mode so right now the instruction was
sent to force the client into listening
mode so what happens is like when you
make someone go in two like listening
mode no matter what the server says the
flavors not going to respond back to you
so when such a case happens like you
basically forces the client to go into
listen mode and then you carry out your
attack and then release this one to go
back and respond to it and by the time
all your attack is done and like the
server just doesn't even know about it
they're kind of thing and here's some of
the function codes which I took some
pain to like put it down to everybody
kid here is it so all the function codes
and everything and if you see like like
the first one to six they all take the
length x dash six and they all have like
sub function they don't have sub
function but then they have like the
four bytes of data bytes the seventh one
and hex value the lemon and there's one
more which is like a single byte
instruction so they don't take in like
any of the sub function codes and there
are some of them like the program for it
for poll for it but those are all like
the proprietary ones so those you won't
find in like a normal implementation
they're kind of things like darling only
appalling like certain implementations
and
yeah like the other things are again
basically explains what it is what each
function code does so this is again like
the sub function I mean like the the
diagnostic mode where what I was telling
you about like the previous the pcap
that I showed you so it is like all the
oh it's and like we're all the sub
function codes for that particular
diagnostic mode this can like tell you
like all this report slave IDs or like
what you want the sort but you declined
to do client all the server to do and by
the way all the Modbus Modbus protocol
can do either way transactions so like
you can force the client to do something
as well as the server can force the
either either way you can enforce things
to happen because like I told you like
it could be like in the intermediate
free level two is early which could be
acting as a server for some of the
protocols some of the artists might by
it self be acting us and our to you to
it another Mt and they kind of thing so
these are all the other sub function
codes and these are all two bytes
basically the oldest of function because
it should be 0 0 0 0 0 0 1 the kind of
thing going on to the next protocol
which is the dnp3 again like it always
starts up with like the first two bytes
which is like the sync byte which has to
be like Oh 564 and then like the length
right again the other thing is like even
though like in the Modbus if you would
have seen the length by just like two
bites law it's technically it can take
an only like 250 max character 255 minus
like the header length so but they do
have two bytes over there the RFC states
it has to have like dancing so and in DN
pity they made sure it just takes in
like one bite as a length right so the
david enforce a little bit much better
architecture into the dnp3 protocol
we're like introducing CRC's and like
the CRC's are used in the Modbus the
later versions we're only in the data
processing data transcription only there
the CRC's are yours and like the
querying processes it just nobody cares
about it apparently which is like the
most critical ones again over here look
the first byte is the length white so
again over here the length can be like
maximum of 250 and all the
minus the header stick anything and then
we have the link control which basically
says like this was like these are all
the instructions that you want to follow
that kind of thing and the next device
is the destination and then the source
address to two bytes each and the crc of
the entire header then comes the data
portion and the data portion is again
like split up into further things which
I'll explain it from coming slight and
this is the packet capture of the very
good dnp3 thing and if you see like the
command 15 which is like the command
basically in this one comes as the third
bite in the data portion before that
they're like two more bites which i'll
be explaining there so which says over
here is the disabled spontaneous
messages so if you're if you're going to
be like waiting for somebody that thinks
it's going to like not respond to you so
yeah the control bite is basically the
if you see the control bite over it'll
lose it now the link control so that one
is basically provides all the control
information of the function codes then
the next one is like the layer layer
transport so transport layer bike over
here like the first bit basically says
it's like the start of the first packet
of the n-type if you are having like
obviously going to have like huge chunks
of data so you want to explain it into
like smaller chunks and then extended
across and which sinister kids of the
first packet or like that if the second
better said then it's like the final
packet or both of them i said it's just
one packet transaction and then followed
by the next six bits like that sequence
ID then the application layer control
which is again like does all the first
in the final confirmation and sequence
and all the skin and things then the
interesting thing about the dnp3 is like
it can chunk the data so all your data
is going to be like see our seed first
and even though your max data is going
to be like to 50 bytes it has to be like
junk into like 16 bytes each and each 16
byte is going to be followed by two
bites of crc so this was the reason why
i couldn't use auto def and like the
other the chucking purposes for like the
first in the final but setting in that
kind of thing so and again like the crc
of the dnp3 is like completely different
from like the regular series that we
have so they have their own stuff and if
you want i can share that code too so
so then like we had like the CRC's being
created every 16 bytes so even though
like the length bite will be like just
one byte value and you'll say like if it
is like 2 15 or 2 55 that there it's the
actual packet is going to be like 292
probably 32 bytes of crc after every to
every 16 bytes of junk that kind of
thing these are all again like the
internal indication flags about like
those control bytes how it should be
kind of thing and attending ICCP is the
next protocol but like I'm not going to
go in much detail about this one and
because i thought i'll be running out of
time and so again like in icc p we
established it's like a really layered
highly layered architecture in icc p and
you can just keep on adding up more and
more layers to this one and it's a
really complicated one so first you
establish a connection the TP TP katie
establishes the connection then like the
next one is like connection-oriented
layer then you go on to like the next
the session layers and the presentation
layer and all this everything like they
have their own like seven layer
architecture over there after like the
regular architecture I did see what kid
over there probably at so the kid would
be interested this buzzer is basically
called Sully because the guy with whom I
worked bedroom and Cody so thirsteee you
guys are the one who developed the
framework for this one and they decided
to name its alley because they thought
this slowly from monster Inc was like
really fuzzy and like they wanted to be
like that so what a product the test
cases that I've made mainly made Earl
for like the protocol anomaly detection
then like all the unauthorized read and
write instructions and then determining
ups like fear the possible then I of
service attack and today i'll be just
showing you like the two cases for the
Modbus entity and p3 protocols the main
components of the puzzle are again like
the initialized one and then the blocks
which does the all the blocking of I'm
like putting it into like the entire the
Sally Pfizer is like based on like
blocks so that you create the test cases
of each block select
it up together and then extend it across
that kind of a thing so it's like much
more better than like the regular files
as well like you create the test cases
and then like send it out that kind of
thing so here it's like 1 probably a
hundred lines of codes like you'll have
like probably like 2,000 test cases for
this particular protocol i canít a ok
sorry here I shall explain a pfizer is
basically what it does is like you are
trying to find automated bugs and
software so you have application so you
want to extend you normally like I used
to sending like legitimate values to it
all the time supposing like you're like
checking out the web or something you
say like w google com and what it does
is it's going to put it and get / google
com and / HTTP 11 or whatever that this
one and it's going to set it up that's
like legitimate request so what happens
if I put in like a case where like get /
and probably like two thousand bytes of
a random data over there and then like /
HTTP da one and if there's in a proper
test case over there for checking for
values which is like greater than
certain number of bytes and what happens
is that we end up like all flowing that
particular buffer and then going into
some other portions and overwriting the
code and like taking control of the
mission basically yes please so this
puzzle like create the values which is
not supposed to be a legitimate value so
you can create like really weird stuff
like there was just one example of the
guests
make sure it's valid enough to hire
later so sorry not yeah so so here's the
thing like if you are implemented like a
Modbus protocol in your network so what
it's going to do is like it's going to
open up the port 502 because that's
where it is supposed to communicate and
you will be opening that particular port
up and like what my father is going to
do is like I'm going to send data at
with like that fight or to port right
now and try to get over it so I can do
lunch to it commenced to you mean to
select sending a legitimate commands to
that particular port
I will be getting to that kind of an
idea basically I'll the last slide of my
presentation will be probably well ok
does it work well I just weren't right
against the desert yes we do because I
they will let me come out and present
this stuff if we're not covering it
fresh in the person well yeah going on
to the next one the bed RPC is like the
one we're like it doesn't our pc
interface between like the fuzzing
furbearer lick the client target us and
to the place from very generating all
the test cases and like for all the GU
eyes and everything and the general
primitives are like what you want to
send like you want to send in a static
string or like you want to send in like
some random data as or like the bytes
that what were the things the looks way
too many of them to the list over there
and sessions is basically like the way
it maintains the session of every single
attack that we set up and like gets a
response but I can like Caesar which is
like legit or none taken and the last
the next one is like our own exception
handler for the Sally framework then the
agents are basically the network
monitoring agent which what it does is
like most of the cases like especially
people like us when we hadn't liked the
IPS sector we want packet capture we
want to see what is on the wire in order
to like make something sense out of it
so the cool thing about it like it's
going to like transact every single
packet and like put it up over there
according to the test cases and save it
up there and when something bad happens
when something crashes we just know
which put it up pick up to go check it
out rather than going through like a
huge dump of like probably thousand p
caption thank you so this will be
released out on june thirteenth I
suppose jun 13th or July thirteenth one
of these two days pedram is releasing
his book on
think so along with the book it will be
released and pedram amini param land
yeah the couple guys said so pedram p ed
I am I mean II am I n I so know that
author I am Not sure you got that the
framework was built by him so my test
cases will be released with it so sure i
can give me my sorry at dnp3 yeah and
probably like i'll be working on the
other protocols to in the meantime i
will be i'll be adding an icc p for sure
but i'm not sure if i'll be doing the
uca I was try to do that one to like ask
someone like you should probably
exchange check it out on open rce org so
that's probably where you will find the
search code for the Pfizer to most
probably so that's yeah that's his
website to so like he'll certainly be
along and the other plan is to basically
to integrate it with Jaime I don't know
if you have used by me for reverse
engineering so will be like integrating
this puzzle along with pie made to yeah
so yeah the network monitoring thing
will be basically taking out all the
peak at the process process monitor will
be a basic checking out all the
processes over there like if the process
got killed or like if there was
something it costs an exception that
kind of thing and the beam control is
like the cool one that we really thought
because it most of the time when you're
doing like the test cases it's like
gonna like do it in the vmware image and
then like do the crash and all these
kind of things there's one part of your
thing that happened that we did with
trend micro when you're like testing it
out and like it just blew it off bad and
like it just crashed it so bad we
couldn't
get the OS to reload again so it just
wouldn't load up so we had to go back to
the previous lap shot in order to get it
up and running and then go from the the
next test case almost not that one I can
think it was a major crush on that one
so just because of that party the recent
like he went on to like do this but I
moduli so badly can after every single
test cases just take a snapshot of this
one and then goes and deletes it that
kind of thing so if such a severe crash
happens we can just revert back to the
previous snapshot and then like load up
so all those things are done by the vm
control here's a small snippet of my
Modbus protocol this one test cases the
first one has to be always initialized
with a unique name the second one is
basically the 001 is like I'm just
keeping the transaction ideas static
over here I'm not facing that particular
value because I thought like that itself
is like running out to be like really
lot of test cases over there the next
two bytes has to be static with like I
said it has to be like to null bytes
which determines its a Modbus protocol
then like the sizer bite which basically
takes the entire size of the data that
is going to be following after that and
then like puts it up over there so the
size of block again like the cool thing
about it is like you can do all the
little Indian big Indian and like you
can do the fuzzing of that particular
thing itself and then like part of data
so this is a padding instruction to to
like right up to the data to then the
next one is like again like I kept it
static which is like the unit identifier
which mostly it doesn't matter like
which unity all right and trying to hack
into that kind of thing so the next one
is like the most important one where
like we are like fighting for every
single function bite over there like all
the unique cases and everything and the
last one the D word is basically like
the four bytes of the function sub
function code and the data so that
generates a huge and like if I were
alike by default it doesn't do like the
entire the four gigs of options because
it's gonna like run into like years and
years and years to finish so it just
does all the boundary condition sorry
so I trigger them you'll see you see the
devil I said so yeah that's right like
we because like if you're like doing a
2-byte thing it's like 65535 test cases
not like on an average say like we do
like 10 per second or something so it's
going to take 13 years I suppose to
finish up like the entire 65,000 kind of
thing so that's what I will just do the
boundary cases like really unless you
want that's what like the possible is
set to false over here if you really
want to do like the entire race then
like you can set it up to true and like
do it this is also barrel so so the
other thing that you can do instead of
having the D word over there for like
the four bytes because I feel like I've
tried out this one as well as the other
case wherein like I said it as like two
words short words so like it's like two
bites like first before since it's all I
told you it's all going to be like
blocks English so it's going to be like
the first two bites occur it's going to
like get first first with like all the
different possible sub function codes
and then like the the next two bites are
going to be like set as a default 0s or
whatever default values and then like
that one will be kept static and then I
think so I kept it as a deeper over here
cuz like it didn't matter to me much sir
and strangely but this is what i did i
just went in after i finished all this
coding I just went in google them for
like you know scalar software that can
see the first thing I click downloaded
the demo version than this one Darwin
crash I said like yeah that's good I
kind of thing here's the d mp3 protocol
again like I can I have the initial over
here like this but in a test case I'm
like just doing it as a static 1 i'm not
doing like the the fuzzing of the data
if you won't do the passing of the data
then just have to like include these two
ones in that small bubble over there so
again like the static ones are like the
first two bites of the sink bytes which
is like which says that this is the dnp3
protocol and by the way dnp3 works on
20,000 for 20,000 so you will have
open up that FML report with all the
firewalls and everything so then like
the bite folic control bites all those
things the if you see over here like the
after the S endoscope block start data
the first byte over there which is like
the transport layer chunk which
basically checks for like set set up
saying like this is the first packet or
the last packet or the middle packet
that kind of thing out the entire
transaction so that thing is implemented
in here so that's you won't be able to
have it in like regular Pfizer's or
anything because the only other people
who have a puzzle for dnp3 is like new
security or someone and they don't seem
to be telling much a boiler times like
then they like charging like super crazy
money for it too so I said like you know
what I can just build one myself and
give it to you for free and after that
this one transport layer is the
application layer chunks again like so
since it's also a again like a layered
architecture you have to go through that
kind of thing and next testing out like
the bites and all this and CRC checksum
for the dnp3 protocol has to be created
after every single 16 bytes and then
after the header value over there so
those things are being calculated I miss
something
so this is the thing somebody asked me
right here I want the fire world
application firewall and everything so
here's a simple case like if a client is
sending out an instruction to the server
saying reboot the system right now that
kind of thing so that's basically a
reboot cold reboot command which is the
OD over there in the second line
highlighted so which says it's like the
reboot command for the dnp3 protocol and
it's just going to reboot just always
going to reboot I you keep on sending
that one like so many times it's just
keep on I'm going to reboot and reboot
and reboot and you're just not going to
have any more data being processed
anywhere over there so sending it once
it's like kind of like acceptable like
you can like say yeah this is fine like
probably there was something wrong with
the server so let's reboot it but what
if like you're sitting in like a huge
bunch of them like Saturday I said
that's what like I was just thinking
about her like I just didn't know what
to do with this idea so I just thought
it is a slight over there if somebody is
going out there to build a new IPS
device or a new intrusion detection
thing you can just pull it up with this
kind of an idea will be cool so now what
I do is basically like say like you have
a reboot come and check out for that
particular set of bytes then let's see
if that is coming from that particular
these many counts within like this short
span of time that kind of thing you can
have like ten commands within like five
seconds or like something that kind of
thing and if it is coming from the same
IP then it's like really fishy over
there for yourself like anything I'll
show you the devil
okay the port fire 2 is not it opened I
just want to make sure this is a tcp
version of sorry this is a tcp version
of the Modbus protocol implemented by
this burrito software company so I'm
just opening up that particular port
over here so the transaction can take
place this is the Modbus test case that
I've written so that's how fast it was
and you basically have the the service
of it like send out like the responses
to and the crash were in danger you can
see the instructions right I'm sure it's
also clear it's fine that's good for me
so like that basically shows you like
where exactly right over there a switch
put in the command it got like screwed
over this i can't answer it's in the
vmware image where the application
actually crashed so i'm sending out the
attack from my machine
yeah other than like that this one just
crashing over there like you won't get
any more responses from the victim like
I think so
that's a bad answer no but like oh yeah
I'm like this the entire thing is going
to be like open source so that you can
just go in and create your wolf icing
test cases over there and put it up over
there for your own focus so like the
framework has been built already like
this is like just plugins that like
mascara is what like I volunteer to do
for bedroom and then like I'm like doing
all the scalar steps for him and we put
it up there and we have some for like
the RPC which has been developed already
so our pc is done like HTTP has been
done already and the basic stuffs like
we like already putting it out and when
the puzzle is going to be released it's
going to be all coming out but the other
than that like some proprietary
protocols or anything that you want to
do you can you're welcome to do it
yourself and everything is going to be
open to yourself so yours
finally some of my references that I've
used in the paper all the stuff and
digital bond is one of the really cool
websites where you can find a lot of
information previously they were giving
everything from free now they charge 100
bucks for it it's a bummer but it's
pretty good yeah I can push it up to me
to do I'll good or I can just give it as
a organizers or something and they can
put it up somewhere yeah yeah special
thanks to these two guys who have built
up framework and any questions this
point in time oh gosh
for Jimmy look for these protocols or
four so there's some protocols which do
have authentication like the ICC p1 you
have to make first establish a
connection over there and lick over did
the checks are all done but even there
like this yeah so but here's the thing
in those is one other I don't know if
you guys know what a guy called Matt
France he's pretty big in the scale I
world I'm like he's done some stuff so
they're so like I was like talking to
him and like really generally doing
stuff so that he was in Austin
previously before he moved out like
Chicago right now so the thing was when
you say like along the TP Katie command
and like the icc p that crashes that but
you're softer i'm like they're like
these softwares they just built it up
like you know like asking is possible
they can just leave the house that kind
of a thing you know so you'll find like
a lot of vulnerabilities out there so
yeah if you find somewhere over this
reporter tipping point will pay you so
yeah that's about it so any other
questions somebody else had a question
I to touch a fig probably you will have
to set up your own thing only it's like
not that easy but it's pretty expensive
too I'm like if you won like set up your
own skill and network and everything to
ditch okay well the thing is this right
away I'm talking over here was made my
talk or heroes mainly about the protocol
anomaly so if it's a protocol anomaly
then like it's like that putting a
software effort is being used by like
ten other vendors then it's I me like 10
other people who are implemented scared
then like they're all vulnerable to it
and like most I'm like I was like pretty
shocked I'm like first I didn't realize
this was the thing I generally talking
to one of the my friends on the key
works for Talon manufacturing plant like
I was just trying to telling him that
I'm working on scalar that kind of thing
he said Oh skate out we have a scalar
server nodes and thick Wow ok but then
lock me in there by any chance I just
want to test it down
had
yeah they hold it like tries in a year
or something through sands holds that
scare some it three times in a year yeah
so does it thank you