morning I want to thank everybody coming
out to layer 1 2007 put a lot of work
into this year's show we think you guys
will enjoy it in addition to some of the
speakers we got no one or the day
tomorrow we've also got some
entertainment tonight doesn't even live
here last year I got a CD burlesque show
we got them back with all-new ass that
really worth checking out hold on your
raffle tickets you got when you
registered with that comes a giveaway to
be given out all brought me again no
starch press why did miss a bunch of
books sony interactive gaming gave us a
bunch of stuff including a couple of
PlayStation tiles we're in some pretty
nifty looking jackets yeah potassium can
argue in favor cool plus you talk to the
hacker foundation they're talking about
making a really really cool donation for
going into a chaos computer camp in
Germany chair with a flight directly
back to DEFCON because it's the father
again so pretty slick um you guys can't
swing by the vendor room you probably
already been there you got a badge we're
going to go ahead the world at least
we're going to get rolling up first is
Michael Kent between fetus if Cynthia
responsible disclosure or at least his
interpretation of it with that I'm going
to go ahead and what things get started
and i'm going to draw the show
hey my name is what camp oakley can all
hear me and just about understand their
some as explained going to be talking
about responsible disclosure or kind of
responsible disclosure he says unable to
use a flipping computer here we go and
before I start my employment me put the
same looking today with an please don't
sue them and any ideas of mine you have
any bad here we go does that work back
yeah my help kill right I'd like to be
beginning of quote by AC Hobbes which i
think is probably relevant and as much
I'll come on to talk about a co-op
Slayer but it's might firmly held belief
and it's going to be like them to help
them throughout this presentation that
they can't actually beat Ernest Ernest
the herbs an acquaintance with real
facts fooling the envy about for all
parties vendors need to learn that I
would argue okay so to introduce what
I'm going to be talking about there's
the disclosure of vulnerability
information security flaws whether or
not it's responsible or otherwise is a
divisive subject area as I'm sure you're
all familiar there are multiple flavors
on the subject area and the vendor
researcher expectations of what
constitutes a responsible piece of
disclosure or full disclosure are
entirely different as are their
expectations regarding the results I am
one thing which is important to remember
is that with regards to our disclosure
and the disclosure of security
vulnerability information there are host
of legal implications for both
researchers and renders less so pro
vendors obviously because they've got
bigger legal teams developing an
understanding of what sort of
information to disclose when and more
importantly to whom is actually vital if
you actually double the risk getting
prosecuted getting separate jail or
basically pissing off Microsoft earn a
little bit of history and so it's good
to put things in perspective
human beings have always kept in she had
secrets really but regards to the
disclosure of vulnerability details that
usually is usually referred back to the
locksmith debate of the 19th century and
that's why I just went in with a quote
basically what happened was in London in
the 19th century the sky called AC
Hobbes wrote a locksmiths guide to
basically break him any lock now that
was presumably done and to assist
locksmiths in that crack unfortunately
the media its own and just a share that
they've always been dimwits and actually
said well you know up writing a book and
how to pick locks probably might help
burglars more than locksmiths and
unfortunately the boundary rates in
London didn't actually agree with them
but you know the meter have always been
Jeff gases is often drawn together
whether or not to disclose and indeed
what sort of information to disclose is
one of the oldest history one of the
oldest issues in moral history at the
end of the day to put another face on
that a Trojan horse r is at the end just
a crap model of a wooden model of the
horse we've actually without obviously
secrecy being in place okay so to put it
into a bit more specific perspective
with regards to computer security in
terms of when did it the debate started
and I'm about whether or not you should
do with responsible disclosure what you
should do full disclosure or if you
should disclose anything basically that
started approximately what over ten
years ago in the only night is in the
early part of the well the early part in
nighties people got increasingly
frustrated and pissed off with Sir
emergency response team basically
because up until that point and any
vulnerability information by and large
if you wanted to the legit about things
had to be pushed through them and start
being huge there are it's all cages and
because of people's levels of growing
frustration woody
weird and bully academic way of doing
things no you know III book trap was
cell which I've got my own feelings on
the book truck which I'll discuss later
and in terms of recently the conflict
and that there's a fad degree of
conflict out loud between responsible
and full disclosure is ongoing you know
examples 2000 world such a lame-o work
of exciting about vulnerabilities in the
system but eventually pissed off that
many people he got pounded by the FBI um
2003 mark and Dave Litchfield of MGS
Fame I got so fed up with Sir even ten
years of the book trap was set up that I
basically said we don't wanna play no
more which really isn't great if you've
got high high caliber security
researchers say look we're just not
working with you anymore because it's
kit form the pipette raising you know
you've done something wrong and again
2004 as levski over Poland wonderfully
although unveiled mangle made and in
2006 basically posted a host of and I
say msie books without soak into ms
burst and the press of cops aight that
will well but um NGS next-generation
security software based in the UK wrote
a lot of research on oracle books a
couple of bulk state races on butch
al-qaeda's own book Dave Litchfield
particularly is pretty much up there
with the top by of Oracle researchers in
the world okay so recently and I'm sure
you're all familiar with my cleanse
Black capped off with which was on cisco
iOS Cisco kicked off about that one and
plating that the information that was it
contained within that soft was illegally
obtained and violated their intellectual
property rights and as a result if the
dog was presented ISS who were limbs
employer home would price the legal
panel police link did what any good
researcher should do in that situation
reason
did it anyway earlier this year a
blackout DC Chris project was doing of
bioactive was due to be presenting on an
RFID floater the lovely people at head
again and pointed out there was an
infringement of their intellectual
property and if it went ahead I like to
earn Chris project in particular with
face legal action potentially and as a
result of toppers cancelled so basically
vendors are still putting pressure on
researchers and legitimize research
groups at around at the moment doing it
under the auspices of intellectual
property rights which sucks to be rough
okay and support things again into a bit
more perspective of regards bull
researchers moment 2003 OS organization
for Internet safety basically was formed
by coalescence of vendors response and
reaction to full disclosure practices
basically their their response was okay
people are posting books in our code
let's have people come to us and then
well post books on art obviously will
with regards to specific company
instances a case she memorably familiars
Oracle and Mary are Davidson Oracle has
been kicking off with researchers for a
number of years and basically wish them
to silent some anyway she marries town
and all those Oracle are one of the
companies are pretty publicly explicit
in their dislike of vulnerability
information shall we say all the vendors
probably agreed in a less visible form
shall we say another interesting recent
development is that you've now got
private companies and private groups
such as I defense to pinpoint rather bad
of our to actually pay for them to stay
secure upon release and from a research
perspective this is great and as much
that you know you get paid to do what
you did and bull the
the problem with that model is it may
actually lead to a situation where you
basically got security through obscurity
because unless people know down here is
pointless but come come on without a bit
legs up so currently there are about
four appalling main models in terms of
disclosure of the disclosure of one
durability information basically you've
got full full disclosure practice which
is you tell the world before you both
are actually inform the vendor and
you've got responsible which straight on
bending for the world that you've got
profit driven which is where you tell a
pain third party and hope that they turn
tell the vendor and then the world or
you've got numb disclosure which
obviously self-explanatory okay so um in
terms of a vulnerability life cycle of
the disclosure life cycle of a
vulnerability basically it's got
distinct life cycle depending on where
your legitimate social security
researcher or not obviously you've got
discovered the bowl then you've got to
exploit it which you know is look too
tied-in then you disclose it maybe and
then maybe there's a fix right then I'm
hopefully those two events a moveable
but that depends how you go about things
okay so what happens between the exploit
exploitation in this loader hold on your
ballot is where the disclosure process
comes in pretty obvious statement
depending on where research is set and
depending on where their molds and
ethics around and they make use to alert
a vendor prior to the publication of a
ball they might choose to false the
vendors home by public release of the
ball which you know if you've been
dealing with a vendor who's been
remarkably in community no communic as
it for the past six months and you may
well feel that's a good idea or
depending which side they settled
largely retaining vulnerability details
for potential later malicious used by
themselves or others and the choices
that made by researchers all rely on
what I prefer to as a color at home
which is
pretty self-explanatory stop and the
size of the eager eager obviously plays
a large part in security research and
you know if you've got somebody is an
egotistical idiot shall we say they're
going to publish anyway just for the
press ok so this statistical analysis of
how it breaks down these statistics
aren't accurate because I lost it a
statistician but there's accurate as I
can make them basically unsurprisingly
book track for many many years has been
moving towards a full just responsible
disclosure model as opposed to a full
disclosure model so um as I say overall
and this has been overall continuously
since bogtrotter set up in 93 and book
track has been the responderte has been
responsible disclosure model for wolves
a partial partial vulnerability
disclosure which we'll talk about a bit
little x role is not a popular phone
with disclosure for reasons i actually
don't get okay what the stats don't show
and this is just as important as what
they do show included in this statistics
for full disclosure practices are
vulnerabilities that make no mention
about contact with lenders or patches
and obviously there may have comes up to
the vendor but they have written it down
to write on it including the postings
for responsible disclosure are both
postings by vendors themselves you know
the others section of that graph that
just preceded this threat basically
includes proved false positives of which
there are legion of the book truck you
know and obviously the one statistic
that put down there and is the number of
0 des amis distance if I knew that I
wouldn't be giving this talk and another
thing that's important about those stats
is there isn't actually any differential
between those vulnerabilities that
practice surprise level solutions and
those in a friend of a friend software
package basically my mate Jeff's made
bolting barter and found precise ripped
a minute there's no differential between
the two even though the real world oh
really is so we've regards to what
perceived as per best practices
and I highlighted this perception and
basically the best industry practice for
disclosure of vulnerability details
arguably dates back there are RFP
disclosure policy which was done in two
thousand most corporate guidelines that
are out there and fire research groups
acknowledged this as basically the
source of their policies unfortunately I
fail to realize that the NC book truck
disclosure guidelines actually predated
by year although they say rules of the
same sort of thing okay so accountants
the RFP month which you may or may not
be familiar with I'm sure you probably
are basically breaks down into a number
of key steps reading the security
researcher concepts of endor by email
which becomes a Dave transact vendor has
got five days to respond from the
initial day of comes out if they don't
respond then vulnerability details are
published and a researcher has a duty to
help replicate vulnerability with the
vendor and potentially provide any
mitigation strategies they might use if
anything takes longer than five days in
the entire process so the RFP guidelines
based at this age to publish and be
damned and the goal is to wait until the
vulnerabilities I've been patched all
other ways otherwise mitigate against
and then do a joint release between
vendor and researcher unless of girls
that takes 15 days okay so there are a
number of potential issues with the rfp
disclosure policy as it stands basically
if you're a dinky vendor five days not a
problem you can respond to them if
you're a major enterprise level software
company five days know the partner at
the end of day company the size of
emerson although they should respond to
vulnerabilities within five days may
well lose email given the nature of
their company and then the size of their
company
depending on who you're dealing with
communications can ultimately breakdown
and the issue is that the five-day
window that's actually in built in terms
of that policy doesn't actually allow
any room for haggling you know the final
point which is perhaps most important
one is that depending on where you stand
ethically the disclosure process should
actually be one which is based around
collaboration working with the vendor to
basically increase the security of that
product and service their customer
better and the minute you start imposing
time limits an arbitrary time limit is a
tram you're actually basically setting
up an entirely unnecessarily
confrontational situation whereby as a
researcher you're instantly in
loggerheads with a company which you
know isn't it great style and with
regards to what's out there and in
corporal and there are there are lots of
security research groups out there
legitimately and by legitimately I mean
those companies are feel the exists to
do sec research as own income stream to
kick operating is SSX force basically
they've got the exactly the same model
see RFP guidelines absolutely no time
limitations there I've got a number of
caveats that are in built into their
disclosure policy which you would expect
bear in mind that they're a commercial
enterprise basically what they stipulate
is if the vendor becomes unresponsive or
is initially a responsive then they'll
dispose vulnerability date details I
also disclose details if the media
reports of illiteracy
or in their words if active exploitation
is observed rather go to observe it but
I will help that process is a defining
wall but their time scales are moving
all semantics again kind of sim with the
similar Tara trick but instead of a
five-day window they've got a seven-day
window and so basically if they don't
receive us a response within seven days
and if that communication isn't
maintained every seven days donut our
instruments if they'll publish their
where they thought weather where it
falls down is they actually have a
stipulation in their policy the lesson
issues resolved in 30 days or a good
faith effort is made by a vendor than
the published details what they don't
stipulate is what actually constitutes a
good faith effort you know that they
have ax if you find that matrix which
are which you know is quite bad because
already actually have metrics then you
can't actually measure anything a little
thing that they have which is for
unresponsive then does a grace period of
30 days may be granted now when you're
talking about legally binding documents
which is effectively what you're talking
about here using words like may is
probably not your best idea so is a
basically what corporate guidelines
shown with only chosen to but there how
sale there which old trying to fit in
the same sort of territory is that there
is a massive variety of photo/tom scales
the details are released by security
research group and process of releasing
those details there's no actual
consistency in research company policies
surprisingly enough and indeed
hellbenders should actually respond to
that are those policies the important
the most important thing to remember
about all this is that because of the
nature of what they do also cute
research companies are interested in
being first to market obviously if
they've got a juicy build in the latest
OS or latest the latest major tool has
been trumpeted trumpeted in
do they will probably actually go with
that unpublished details of that
regardless of what their policies say
because you know hindered a data to make
money not to actually improve security
and as a result the disclosure policies
seems to be a hugely moveable feast
which is all largely dependent on their
economic needs and demands all right
you're all probably bald and you're all
credibly incredibly they stopped because
that is incredibly dry I agree with you
but the reason why I've mentioned all
that framing information is as a member
of security industry or the security
community you've got to know about the
disclosure process and how it works
obviously security vulnerabilities
Earnhardt's are following just you know
so you can probably look a friend of a
friend PHP forum and find a shedload of
them you know enterprise level
vulnerabilities which are the important
ones are different math in a welt appeal
to the vendors and what you actually
need to define if you work within the
security research industry and secure
industry as a whole is what actually
occurs or what should occur if you're on
the client engagement and find a
high-risk enterprise level trouble for
durability what do you actually do right
basically what you do in such a scenario
is all dependent on what agreements are
in place in the first life in first
place between the researcher or the
research group and the end client at the
end of the day depending on who you work
for you as a config you as a
representative of your company or you as
an individual might have a disclosure
policy or you might not from an
individual perspective what you need to
define is who carries any legal legal
liabilities that are going to be
involved in the release of vulnerability
data you know um
obviously you first do a unengaging if
you discover a vulnerability el no
engagement is complete engagement unless
the vulnerability is so severe as God
widespread damage to enterprises the
entire situation now is all processing
agreement lead unfortunately you've
gotta know both unless you have
processes and agreements in place you
may well find yourself in a situation
where you pissed off a vendor and vendor
comes up to you as opposed to your
company for further it for further
details of that food reporter Michael
Lin so I'm dealing with a client in
terms of how you deal with the phone
when you've found a vulnerability is
part of an enterprise audit and you
first do you care in anything other than
the exceptional circumstances is
obviously to the claim what you need to
do following them which will be defined
before you even start an engagement is
to actually takes ownership of any
vulnerabilities are discovered unless
you you've actually contracted it in it
may well be the situation that the
vendor says you're doing work on that
home so does if you find the book the
company that you're working for actually
owns up over now if it's a significant
enough issue they were actually just
taken a huge chunk of cash in on that
sales because you were working for us
obviously and depending on the nature of
the book you're going to have to
sanitize vulnerability details so it's
not to expose the client so obviously if
you've discovered an issue with in
citibank software you don't put citibank
software although it would be funny and
how do you deal with a vendor when you
actually discover I'm security security
deficit well the end of the day is how
would you deal with anybody else you
know your first contact has to be a
non-confrontational as possible you've
also got me as technically specific as
possible so that weeks down the line
without that well we didn't understand
you
as a researcher is an individual
research you gotta follow any guidelines
are in place by company policies if
indeed they exist if they don't why
don't those X create the research dinner
another thing which you should
potentially do depending on what it's
about is offer any mitigation or
remediation of advice was obviously it's
kind of crappy if you go to a vendor and
say well i found an issue not Sonya I
fix it but good luck with that isn't but
at the end of the day the entire process
of disclosure and vulnerabilities and
dealing with vendors is about
collaboration is not about personal
glory glory at the end of the day
security can only be increased if people
collaborate and that includes
researchers and vendors you know and
vendors have to know that researchers
after knew it that's the nature of this
the beach stealer what's going to happen
wouldn't you talk to a bangalow and
depending on who the vendor is their
mail may or may not be a number of
situations that you find yourself in and
regardless of insolvency the vendor
probably isn't going to appreciate your
efforts effects of you've said your
piece of software which is a commercial
offering is shafted nobody likes to wear
that as a result the vendor may choose
to become unresponsive and the vendor
may also appear to be technically obtuse
you know what why would anybody want to
put in a thousand days into our
application what what why you know
depending on who depending on who the
vendor is the might actually not have
any experience of dealing with
vulnerabilities this might be at first
of them you know another interesting
point is that the vendor mean we still
communicate in securely obviously if
you're sending von d tails around by or
unencrypted email depending on all sort
of all the details they are not great
idea and another thing that might happen
is you might get sued which you know is
always a bit of a deficit and you might
also get a job which getting fed by
deficit um and again you might lose you
career to frame them in a bit more
detail and done an alpha minus you guys
are with done CFO wasp basically about
it was one or two years ago now guy
called dumb cop who had to London owasp
basically had a sniff around a website
for the disin army appeal basically did
about your genital URL manipulation if
you got to clean north he did that on
high-profile site on the first night of
launch so that's security guys were all
over in like a rash as you would expect
because obviously they're going to be
watching it on the first note to see
what happens please went around to his
house went to call and now he don't work
in security number didn't go to jail but
the point is although that was probably
benign research or be unsupported
research by the solutions provider he
basically did something which was benign
and splendid up losing his career so you
know it is an issue and it's becoming
more of an issue um historically there's
always been a substantial gap between
how researchers are perceived by vendors
and how they perceive themselves if
you're is that research who you think
you do a good job that's why you do the
job you do and if you're a vendor you
see secretary searchers depending on
whether or not they have a job or not as
a colossal pain in the ass because they
cost you money you know um depending on
what can sort of companies you end up
dealing with researchers can only be
seen as a minor consideration of
something to do with something to deal
with in the entire process of building
and deploying your code or worse
depending on what history the vendor has
as somebody is maliciously inspired now
if you're not politically inspired
that's colossal pain in the arse and
vendor attitudes and indeed researchers
attitudes to vendors aren't leech aging
but there are still with huge remains of
the old combativeness between vendors
and researchers this is especially true
if you're working as an independent
researcher and not working as part of a
security research group you know it's
easier to the little or otherwise
discard an individual as it is to
accompany in it so the problem is how do
you actually deal with compulsiveness or
silence that presents itself from a
vendor when you actually want to push up
full details and you could react
according to rfp and a host of other
guidelines and policies by forcing
response by aggressively just pushing it
out there by the full disclosure model
depending where you sit this maybe isn't
the best idea you could have ever had
because at the moment at least in the UK
and to my knowledge in over here in the
US they're increasing calls from eight
researchers legally responsible for
publish involved at urban mobility data
I mean specific example the UK have
recently updated computer misuse act and
as it sounds at the moment computer
misuse that basically says if you attack
a system maliciously you go to jail
burial in the updated version which was
obviously for or by somebody who'd never
worked in the security industry and any
capacity whatsoever basically it says if
you write exploit code you go to jail if
you write a tool which allows people to
attack systems you go to jail so
basically if you write a Perl scripts
you go to jail not great
I am the climate politically in both the
US and the UK and indeed across Europe
has altered substantially in the last
five or six years I'm really say why
because that will become a political
screed and but basically you've never
got a situation where hacking and as a
result a security research which
probably not be hacking depending on
which side of the ship you settled can
never be considered as an act of
terrorism you know it can't that would
be very in mind those circumstances it
can actually be that long before full
disclosure is actually perceived and
reacted to as a terrorist act as a
terrorist threat you know it another
important point is that although full
disclosure may force the vendor to
respond because they have to because the
details around there in the short term
and it may be the shorter long-term
depending on what sort of issue you
found it's definitely going to increase
enterprise-level risk you know now
that's not cool ethically that's not
cool security should be about increasing
security not detracting from it you know
so basically if you go unresponsive or
otherwise naive a vendor what the hell
do you do to actually combat their
resistance um model of developers you
know one but it's a good'n basically and
you're in first instance of our ability
details should be securely reported to
the vendor instead of sending them of
bloody plain text email send environment
but send it via encrypted email you know
these are already off to a good start
basically if there's a situation where
you concepts of ender and there are
all you are communication breaks down
for whatever reason a researchers to
make a legitimate second attempt
detailing their intention to publish was
obviously if you detail in intentions
publish that's forewarning so legally
they've had for warning they can't take
action or they Karen but you know it
makes things a bit more problematic and
depending on the responses you get back
and publish a non technical advisory
with a reasonable amount of time fill in
for vendor response and again attempts
of endicott aspect attempt contact with
the vendor which you've actually
published that non tech advisory
following the expiration of the time
period that you set within that non tech
advisory is they still not got back to
you publish the sacrificer but don't
employ included any exploit code
obviously that sounds incredibly lame
but the minute you start putting in a
cloud-based animal it potentially
malicious code base people can perceive
that as a malicious Act and the
malicious illegal act you know so break
it down and sir nice pretty crafts ten
days between first and second look on
sucks ten days between checking contacts
and non tech advisor e-bill the same
days between young sac and third contact
and then I put C mobs but it could be
any arbitrary length of time you decide
based upon the severity of the issue to
full release this this is different from
what's out there is much that unlike RP
guidelines and most evil top row
policies your first response is a
wonderful disclosure basically your
first response if the communication
process breaks down is to push out an
old tech advisory you know it can tell
you very generic details issue exists in
black yeah you don't follow that up with
a set advisory but with no exploit route
so that basically means that even though
you reported the issue it can't actually
be exploited which obviously reduces a
restoring the prize of RS good and
because there are multiple opportunities
for events to respond in no entire
circle
that obviously reduces Emily leave the
liability the may impact on you you know
and obviously one point of consideration
is the time scales you know three months
is a hell of a long time if it's only a
small issue but then three months is a
hell of a short amount of time if it's a
major issue so you know obviously cover
up to consider that as a as a blend you
know and there are a number of issues I
it is much that the legal
responsibilities and the legal liability
still sits with the researcher or indeed
the researchers company and the model
still creates combativeness between both
the researcher and vendor communities
you know because a sacrifice rate if you
want to call it that doesn't have any
area code although that prevents
malicious use of the vulnerability
discovered obviously impacts bone and
impairs legitimate continued research of
the issue or class of issues that you've
discovered and although you publish to
research your there is emergency patch
here and the entire point of this is to
find a property and get the problem
fixed so what the solutions well are the
solutions is a bit as a first questioner
vendors and researchers at the moment
operate according to their own rule sets
and their own perceptions of rule sets
in as much so you've got the IRS on one
hand and rfp guidelines on the other
vendors have that way of doing things
researchers have that way of doing
things it's still to count you know very
that in mind maybe this is just an idea
something like sir acting is like a
clearing body wasn't actually that bad
an idea especially seen as it reduces
legal responsibility liability and
basically if you have a mediating group
that is composed of representatives from
both researchers fenders companies and
both sets of communities then you know
Paul although the aims of researchers
and vendors differ yeah obviously the
goal in the end game in this is the same
which is vendors want to produce secure
software and it would be nice if they
did produce secure software you know so
for vendors a neural anelia sold off
quick process at least I don't think
there are security comes action music
funk in this day and age there shouldn't
be any situation where somebody's post
into book trucks angels anybody now
contact e you know it shall be clearly
and explicitly stated if you referring
to security issue report here using
encrypted email to this address yeah
they should have a security responsible
processing and policy in place depending
on who you deal with they may or may not
and again I keep coming back to this
point but you've got to communicate
between researchers and vendors securely
if they want to do things over plaintext
don't play in bowl with them until
people will report that information
potentially and if they do you're liable
from an intellectual perspective and
from a perception perspective then
descent you have to start treating with
our researchers would agree more kudos
and credit shall we say again referring
bucks the Oracle situation basically
what happened there Oracle down to the
researcher basically said no sorry you
found a book will be up there and
instead of doing that basically
appreciate a researchers efforts they've
saved you an inordinate amount I when
your code review process they're
effectively doing your job for you and
ever again if you get an issue reported
it to you as a vendor inform your
customers that an issue has been
discovered doing to be explicit but at
least let people know you know and if
you can provide a temporary workaround
and a timescale to eventual picture race
what happens at the moment is companies
wait until the fixed an issue to tell
their customers that an issue exists
that's not cool if an issue exists tell
your
customers so you should be looking for
licks it's simple stuff but it isn't
dull them from the researcher side of
the equation from the flip side of the
coin basically give the vendor the
benefit of the doubt although some
vendors can be incredibly obtuse and
combative and annoying and incredibly
epsilon into one of a bad race give him
the benefit now they might not know how
to deal with false then I hope not
actually have the mindset to deal with
that again communicates your room and
provide any tech details requested in a
Sony manner if they come to you and say
we don't know how to do this tournament
I'll do it and also inform the vendor of
any methodology of time scales that
you're actually following because then
they can say three or four moves down
the line or even in a short duration
than that we weren't about aware that
these timescales are being followed
therefore you've committed an illegal
act thank you we'll take you to jail you
know they know and again don't put your
ego before enterprise security is not
about getting press it's about
increasing security that's what it's
about so bearing in mind the situation
that it stands and bearing in mind and
the issues that present themselves it
might be argued up the days of full
disclosure disclosure in its glory days
and will it be behind us you know at the
moment born purchasing companies like
tipping point I defense etc can help to
separate the research for a vendor and
separation is good from a legal point of
view the point is that that isn't
actually multivator bowel tourism on
that part that's Mulder it motivated by
very clear well very well for our Matt
profit driven model it's not about
saving the research as a fast it's about
making cash
the process of report involves even if
you're legit researcher as opposed to
somebody who's just like other puppets
on that the process of reporting those
rooms is still a potentially risky and
damaging process you know recent history
shows that depending on what response
you get from a vendor you over up to
reduce and the levels of research that
you publish or otherwise risk a whole
heap of issues because of as I say
arguably non-malicious terms which is
what I'm talking about here it wasn't
motivated by malice it was motivated by
a genuine and vanilla interest in
increasing security and the moment
researchers have lost a career
credibility and indeed their careers and
although guys like lame-o attacked you
shouldn't be in jail you should never
have even been considered for
prosecution because you can't decide
what to report on when and the risks
that are presented by pissing off the
wrong people are potentially quite
severe why is a researcher of a report
in any way anything anyway why not just
sit on any volunteer tells at your point
because at the end of the day silence
and your silence as a researcher doesn't
increase securing no ethically this is
about increasing levels of security
that's what it's about you know as I
said earlier you've got third-party
commercial valen purchasing companies
and schemes out there at the moment they
don't use this to increase security I
know it sounds bizarre bearing in mind
what they actually do they actually
exist to make cash there are money
driven business yeah um any disclosure
you do um help string free security
levels unless of course you respond by
full disclosure in which case the
effects are obviously reversed you know
here is exploit pro please reason enjoy
dinner physical and ethically if you are
ethical if you are more Tamatave ated by
ethics and morals
as opposed to personal glory and sodding
ego non-disclosure isn't actually an
issue it's not an issue and it's not an
option you know disclosing born details
in any format early i would argue
without giving the vendor adequate
response times is also not I mean how
often have you seen a balm disclosure
Lou is basically the release the day
after somebody comes out from Saks a
vendor you know I comes up to the vendor
yesterday posted today that's not call
how's the vendor Mincey responses are
you know and because because the field
of sac research is at the moment so
brawl with potential legal ramifications
and implications and what you have to
decide as an individual is what your own
limits emotions have done and bake and
actually help some defined way of doing
things even in an individual methodology
and you can't just go around posting
blendy thousand or more because if
they're severe enough the possibility is
they might decide to have you for it
only write this this is an interesting
one and it's also an incredibly ass
enabled don't know how many of you went
a smooth con but basically the x MS
Bergman window Schneider and now chief
security something or other at Mozilla
basically claimed quite perversely an
alt oddly rather than the researcher at
the moment has got all the power no
actually they haven't and if you are a
bender you've got considerably more
power than an individual researcher you
have a legal team of specialists to go
after researchers I don't know about you
but I don't actually have a legal team
of specialists the size of Mozilla's so
I suspect she might have been pulled
over and the same cold Dave I tell
basically claimed that responsible
disclosure poll process was a vendor
ruse so basically prevent security
details being pushed out into the wild
and the
only real alternative available to
researcher was to actually sell your
wares to him now as I said earlier he
basically makes money if you sell your
wares to him so I wonder whether that
motivated by altruism don't think it is
at the moment the simple fact is that
vendors are getting more and more
twitching legally yeah it may be that
the license agreements for their
software aren't well defined after all
and this this is movable argued in at
all your your idea of acceptable use and
their idea of acceptable use might be
completely different as ain't never been
argued legally and if you try to argue
argue illegally I think it might be a
tricky sell and because of what's going
on vendors are actually using the stick
of intellectual property more and more
are basically saying if you find an
issue in our technology or in our crowd
you in some way imprinted upon our
intellectual proper now the problem of
using your thing tonight is judges and
juries and warriors understand IP they
get it they're used to it you know so
the minute vendors start coming back the
research is using the stick of IP you're
basically presented with a situation
where legally everybody knows what's
going on apart from the researcher I
don't know about you but I don't think
that finding an issue is an infringement
upon intellectual property it's not even
if you completely reverse engineer their
firmware so what that's him to the day
your bill there to find security
vulnerabilities not actually clone their
firmware for example um at the moment
the situation is it stands maybe this is
because of lack of legal understanding i
don't know but if it goes to call t with
the biggest legal staff wins from that
and frankly is axon i'm in as much that
obviously the researcher losses and if
the researcher loses then arguably
securities a whole loses out
you don't want to be taking people a
call it's as simple as you basically
should be working with people and not
against them so the end of the day what
I'm trying to get out with this is that
self-determination as an industry about
what to do with bond details doesn't
work you know arguably the security
industry and hyphens has evolved and
matured recently you know over the last
few years it's gone from two guys in a
bedroom to multinational companies you
know the days of bedroom enthusiast
Estelle weathers went Christ but we've
also never got huge corporate cartels
you know bearing in mind that there are
huge corporate cartels which sold you is
to push out security solutions or
security research maybe they should
start acting like huge cartels and
actually have a defined set of processes
why they won't do that is their goal is
to arguably turn a passbook get in get
out catch em and not actually improve
security I could join the nurse'll run
against why that doesn't work but I
won't but the disclosure processes as
they exist needs to be regulated both
from within the industry and from
without to ensure that vendors and their
Eagle legal teams can't actually target
individual researchers but again so that
in responsible researchers can touch the
impacts pull the perception of the
industry as a whole which is what
something at the moment when relatives
does no pull it's like at the end of the
day the type of the cisco tabata last
year cisco went after a researcher you
know they apply pressure to his boss and
went after that researcher basically
because his boss or his bosses didn't
actually have a defined an acceptable
way of doing things that was agreed with
everybody else okay so the point is and
maybe and this is just a maybe the
research community as a whole needs
regulation and agreed guidelines yeah
obviously because of the way it works
regulation current from from government
in army and it seemed well why not
because governments have their own
agendas at the end of the day the
government's goal other government is to
stay in power it's not to improve
security is sustained power that's why
it can't come from government what why
Carly come from the community yep 10 so
why don't my club me at least to talk
about those agendas air them and
actually come to some agreement instead
of all operating in our own of
individual vacuums and all risking our
own individual little prosecution's that
seems a really stupid model if you're
basically saying the one thing stopping
people actually working together is
their inability to communicate learn to
communicate
no that's not that's not a community in
the traditional sense of we have a nice
little regulated council and we have
aldermen and all the rest of it now
closed not know the put the point I'm
trying to make this isn't about
enforcement this is actually a foul
agreement at the end of the day this
isn't about regulated and enforced
guidelines while I'm actually suggesting
is that people should actually start
collaborating and agreeing a responsible
way of doing things whether or not they
sign up to that so what but if you do
sign up to that you what's the point the
poppy if you help their teeth how do you
get how do you get to yes but it's that
point my point my point is involve the
government involved vendors fine but
don't let the government's and the
vendors dictate policy yeah I'm not
saying they're not all I'm saying is
that the regulations can't come from one
single party that's my pulley
yeah but that the point is it's not
about protection at the moment not none
of the current state of the world is
about protecting the individual
researchers that's my point I've course
boards date also can play a partner I
completely agree with the only and
plastically agree with you they have to
play partner it's going to work but they
can't be in charge of enforcement the
same way that a software company cannot
be in charge of enforcement this is why
there should be a collaboration between
all parties and an actual agreement
reached between all pies because
otherwise you will get the government
coming in and saying this is how it
should work no no don't to jail because
we don't like the way you're doing
things and that's not cool you know and
why is it come you might be back you
might be back you might be better
protected than you are now i agree with
you but do you actually want the
government deciding what can and cannot
be published because if you did that
it's really an America mate you've got
an America you've got this you've got
this First Amendment thing which
basically says you have the right to
publish anything you want and you know
as an intellectual as an intellectual
theory that's not about Gary you know
the legal enshrining of the right to
communicate is dole done mate and the
minute that you say that governments
controlling what people can uncle say is
called and allowing people to say or not
say what they want then that's when you
start wandering into with this weird
dystopian hooked up vision in the world
we devote at younger hello lovely people
to change our say given it a stir at the
white chamber by changing the law always
heat is the First Amendment but
ultimately limited hot pillow is 220
against all of these people that matter
practice until you cum people with low
vision so you preparing yeah I've got
I'm not arguing I'm no argument being
your point of clarification
clarification and change of law what I'm
arguing are you with you about is the
enforcement of those clarifications and
changes they do government go ahead
leave his arm pretty related to the
total things we never more narrative
right at the end of it yeah the ender
exactly the point is we we have to style
thinking about less and the moment we're
all basing what we do career-wise on
shit that isn't find you know we need to
start working towards definitions you
know and I'm not standing here so no no
the answers I don't all I'm saying all
I'm saying is we need to start thinking
about this we need to start coming up
with them a foot methodology that's
acceptable to everybody not just
acceptable to a and repressive regime be
it in the US or in China or wherever not
not actually acceptable to large
software cartels but an agreement and a
methodology that's acceptable to
everyone from the guyanese bedroom
packing some firm bar soap firmware to
some asshole that's never know ever seen
a computer bits in charge of dictating
government policy you know we need to do
it
dodson appoint me need to start having
this conversation amongst ourselves and
most vendors and basically amongst the
pulled at large because at the moment
the researcher is basically responsible
for their own actions which vary looks
great from a personal libertarian point
of view but not so great if you start
going to jail yeah sounds expensive but
if you've got the likes of a matador at
all and the US government of the Chinese
government and God knows how many other
governments involved guess what
expensive an issue and that the point is
as a researcher yes but you know yeah so
the prom the problem with that model is
dangerously close to extortion that you
know which I think has got legal
ramifications
yeah but the tipping point model has
just described there and as just defined
by the cash equation is driven by cash
it isn't driven by a goal and altruistic
goal to protect the researcher in keeps
increase secure a is about making money
it's a little money driven business it's
not in there yeah depending on how
depending on who the actual vendor is
and how big their legal flowers I think
you're placing an enormous amount of
trust in a third party company which is
beyond your individual control no I
don't think it is I think if you start
actually the same that we will I as an
individual will trust this company to
laugh at look after me then guess what
you've just got rid of your individual
rights under the point is even if the
contract
yep that's it beats a b2b fabric to be
fine with you though multiple members
are contracted employee of ISS guess
what the minute about vendor with a big
enough legal muscle length on them they
said well we'll have words you know so
you're basically saying the tipping
point is bigger than software companies
financially and big enough to stand up
to their legal seems only know in you
know that if a vendor applies in look
precious as I'm legally or economically
don't give it up I you say you're
actually claiming the tipping point is
big enough to combat huge software
cartels I work for tipping point the
pages of when we are disclosing the
information to the vendors we don't like
ask them for money we just tell them
this is the 1 over G so you want to
fight it off I mean we are giving a free
information yep so I think we helped the
researcher art for this to be doing
friends or his presser so we have our
body here be very valued by the VR
basically we have an important to
prevent and box so we make money from
our box like we say like be protect our
clients isn't this one I in fact we have
a very erratic I with Microsoft that way
like when we just felt some things to
them and even they like what they tell
us say you may want to like patch this
kind of thing like this is the thing
about the new one will reduce out so
protect your customers even if they
don't yeah I got it
yeah for sure but just to come back to
the ship employing party and the end of
the day there you have to accept the
tipping point or a commercial company
exists to make money it's no it's not
trippin it's not driven by altruism and
that's my point you know what made it
fun official Keota research ya ali
modeling you have to go again one of the
videos because of the tax code isn't
everything but then they we don't really
feel like you're like telling the render
the food the guy as a vendor ever asked
what you know right what would you do it
ever under us so we didn't have what it
really is they're going to listen to
kind of thing happens we'll be late
serving people information for free for
expanding your system and there is like
I mean I kept by shouting like that the
researcher public and outside and the
show
oh no there isn't I never said the water
case of that as a ricotta why wouldn't
you want to go to a third PI because do
you actually do it do you actually do
you actually want to exist to serve a
third parties PR machine in the case of
tipping point and you actually want to
exist to actually increase security
without actually having to deal with the
culper end yes so is it is the goal to
actually make money on this ok why not
but is that the goal yeah yeah it's a
nice but I've gotta agree with you but
the minute it starts becoming an agenda
into an orbit cell yeah but i agree with
you at the moment is it stands very not
but the point is a minute it starts
becoming a profit-driven thing the
people only disclose to people that pay
them then guess what we're all kind of
screwed
but the plot the point is it as it
stands and this is why I'm talking about
what I'm talking about there isn't
actually any of them it's all that up in
the air in that ephemeral the there
isn't actually any levels of protection
other than what protections individuals
can build in for themselves web that by
selling stuff to tipping point or
whomever or by actually adjusting their
own methodologies to sue a particular
need bini been to avoid game sick you
know your way no yeah okay well thank
you very much and undoubtedly we can
continue this conversation later when
i'm drunk and probably a bit more lucid
as possible over
I wasn't having a go at sitting boy by
the way now I'm trying to say is that
needs to be defined almost dissolved oh
yes of course yantis that was my wave
signal terminals but he didn't work