you put this on something different you
don't have my audio oh I see you don't
have the mics and I'm talking into got
it yes I broke my no I didn't break the
mic I just clip off the mark just find
it okay it's like that so that all right
okay he's got reason sound good alright
um voice protocols aren't stable we're
still coming out with new products very
fast which means people will tend to
implement mistakes the vendors will take
shortcuts people will try to get to
market without bothering to do things
cleanly because they're trying to you
know everybody wants to come out with
their version of a white phone that also
plays music because Steve Jobs said he
might do that so you get that kind of no
race to market kind of thing and yet
it's telephones so it's already legacy
stuff gear that I mean the current
generation of cisco phones were built in
the late 90s and they think that's
perfectly reasonable because in the
phone world people take 10 min 10 years
to deploy a new phone system so whereas
you know you you walk into a shop and
found the running windows 98 we all go
ooh it I mean the vendor doesn't even
want you doing that and yet you can find
than those windows 98 vintage telephones
around with that level of technology and
security capability and that and all
that kind of stuff um new products that
keep coming out are coming out
vulnerable people are doing silly things
you know you hear stories about voice
phones being shipped with the debugging
turned on so if you bothered to rebuild
the canoe debugger gdv you could hook up
to the phone through the debug port you
know silly things like that so new
products are still coming out vulnerable
this is not like it's a solved problem
and I got to make up a buzzword when I
was doing the slides here so you know it
used to be that you know the cool hot
thing was to attack something that was
very popular like Windows XP you know
and as they get these things more and
more stable it's sort of it's not the
it's not the cool target these days so
you got you know like to cause celeb so
I think that tarjay celebrate
a new term which is you know the hot
target next week is going to be
something else because we're not going
to have XP to beat up anymore and of
course Vista is all much more secure
right so that's going to be boring so we
have to anyway they're new targets
coming out and what's a popular target
is something you have to think about the
other reason to think about it is
customers think they're buying secure
products you know Cisco is an example of
this just because they put up billboards
in Northern California that says they
sell secure networks doesn't mean they
sell secure networks you know if you pay
for an expensive billboard and pay a
lawyer to sue some guy who you know
tries to do a talk of black hat and then
you ship VPN concentrators that use FTP
and clear text passwords to update the
configuration files then you've got a
what do you say versus what do you do
kind of a thing going on here and the
customers assume they're buying
something secure nobody ever get fired
for buying a cisco network right that
kind of thing I'm pointing out these
issues in theory will make things more
secure going forward so this is you know
one of those we're trying to make
people's networks more safe and I'm not
trying to break things I'm not trying to
hope the bad guys you know destroy the
world or anything like that all right
architecture this is basic stuff how
many of you are in with the lights off I
can't actually how can I ask questions
who how would major have done this and
win is contest I mean I can't buy asked
questions you raised your hands I'm not
going to see them because I can't see
any of you anyway let's try this anyway
how many of you are managing a voice
over IP network now there's a few brave
souls how many of you are involved in
the evaluation or purchase or deployment
or somewhere at that phase anybody going
through that one you having a good time
20 over here some more how many of you
are actively attacking voice networks
yeah yeah see good yeah fish barrel
point to reload yeah it's really boring
yes so anyway okay so the little just
going through these remember when I'm
talking about components I'm thinking
like a bad guy at this point so I'm
thinking about targets you know one
man's product feature set is another
man's target list so these things are
what used to be private branch exchange
a--'s which means they're you know fully
featured phone systems and if you talk
to an enterprise environment they expect
the phones to have all sorts of no
doodads and gimcracks on them you are
supposed to be able to get
music on hold and follow me services and
conferencing and all sorts of cool
features they tend to have a thing a
call manager at that's a cisco product
name but that's also the generic term
there's this widget in the middle which
is doing call processing in other words
there's a target in the middle to go
after there's things that are doing
proxying because some of the protocols
were not designed to be nap friendly so
you have to have proxy capabilities so
there's you know stuff like sip Rockies
around doing that sipping session
initiation protocol there are gateways
there's the old-fashioned plain old
telephone system or pots you know so
there's gateways between the voice
systems and the pot system and gateways
between multiple voice systems so again
you've got things at the edge and
they're run by the phone department and
you know one would like to think these
things were safe they apparently aren't
are not trusted because when I go start
to do talks on or you know classes on
this and people you say what kind of
attacks do you expect to see and they
all assume some bad guys going to be
sitting in a coffee shop in Beirut and
you know connecting to their voice
network and read the CEOs email because
the voice to potts gateway was stupid
something like that so that people
assume this is an issue then is all the
backend fancy stuff you've got directory
servers so this is really cool you know
if you work for an 80,000 person
organization you can pull up people's
names and identify their phone number
and you can do it through the phone
that's all very cool that also means
that the right kind of bot can crawl
through and get your entire phone
directory and then you know what are you
keeping your phone directory and if
you're lucky it's just names you know if
it's got titles and things like that you
get targeting information if I can find
all your execs that travel and have
fancy things in their laptops or I can
find all the developers who you know how
many of you are developers for big
corporations have the source code of
your product sitting on your laptop that
you have with you you don't want to
admit that to you you kept that laptop
up in your room and you get your second
laptop down here you did do it that way
right and you're running cryptid disks
you know you should be doing this people
can do targeting you got to think that
way you got to think like they're gonna
be bad guys out there and then there's
voice mail servers you know how many
times you eat i saw this about two weeks
ago I keep collecting examples I'm
having a conversation with the person
who runs somebody's blackberry exchange
server in the bed server for all their
crackberries for the executives and she
proceeds to check her voicemail
with me talking to her and she picks up
her phone and goes bash bash bash bash
on the three-button and you know there's
there's a surfing over somebody else's
shoulder to pick up there you know
password by looking at their keyboard
you know if you're really good you can
run exploits to do this with ssh by
catching keystrokes and their timing but
you don't have to do any of that if they
have a four character password they're
all the same digit and they like will do
this with people watching so voicemail
is a really great place to find weak
passwords and of course nobody in
businesses or other other kinds of
environments would ever leave private
message is on voicemail you know think
about that so anyway that's another
target once you can get the phone system
and the you know all the data attack
models together it gets kind of
interesting of course then you've got
all the infrastructure stuff behind it
which the phone people don't think about
and the network people may not think
about so you get this the standard
things that you do in a directory in
what infrastructure environment but if
you think about them like targets about
the phone system they're they're more
interesting targets interesting in
different ways so you got like directory
servers like these things are tied to
Active Directory or something dhcp dns
all these kinds of servers because the
phones are dumb the typical voice over
IP phone if it's an actual dedicated
instrument is stupid and speaking of all
sorts of information from the
infrastructure hopefully as log servers
although phones are even worse than
computers in general about having
instrumentation and then there's all the
routers and switches and stuff if sort
of in a perfect world the phones would
be like the voice over IP telephones and
things doing that would just be standard
network devices and so that wouldn't be
an interesting comment but you get
various vendors like nortel and cisco
where there are special things and
switches to know about handling phones
and their special things in the routers
and so somehow we've managed to get
voice specific components and so now
you'll find products that are voice over
IP ready it's sort of like you know if
you I'm trying to keep track i haven't
found one yet i'm waiting for a voice
over IP ready power strip you know nice
dumb stupid power strip and say you know
because they're used to find SNMP
manageable power strips even if they had
no computer in them or windy windows
compatible power strips i mean you see
any strange things that would be
compatible because there were special
products alright so i've got oh that's
interesting
all right you can't see the edge of the
slide you're not going to miss too much
anyway this is a diagram I ripped off
from another presentation and apparently
there's copy protection in the diagram
no actually the pictures are
sufficiently exotic those black clouds
were just clouds that said switch
network in them so there's nothing big
their classic voice network kind of
saying I've got phones up here tying
into switches that know they have phones
on them going to some switch fabric and
then there's servers and desktops and
things tied into some network and that's
tighten some of the switch fabric and
they're all plugged together and there's
various and sundry infrastructure stuff
in the middle that was what was in this
box so now I've got my phones and my
computers tied together so the phones
are a good path to attack the computers
and the computers are a good path to
attack the phones and apparently the
voice vendors don't actually draw
pictures like this and go Luigi I can
attack all those things from the other
places so you know this isn't a network
diagram this is a targeting map you got
to think about it that way now protocol
elements so phones voice phones white
phones excuse me are doing a bunch of
voice protocols this is this stuff over
here and then they're doing all the
extra bits to make things work and this
is one of the places that the vendors
will get things wrong or be sloppy and
therefore there's places you can have
exploits happening so you get the usual
suspects for protocols for something
that's trying to run as a simple dumb
appliance the main ones kind of
interesting here is they'll tend to have
an HTTP server in them a web server in
the phone so you can configure it this
means i have a web server which means
you know go back through your copies of
the archives of every web server attack
talk given in the last 10 years and try
that on the phone because it's a little
stupid device and you know that might be
worth doing then the lower level stuff
it's all the usual kinds of protocols
with a few extra sort of modern fancy
features i actually forgot the typo in
this slide that's cool so it's UDP not
upd of course so you got TCP and UDP and
they might be running TLS if they're
doing encryption and that's running on
top of IP and these are all you know
boring protocol components right I mean
we've been building TCP implementations
for I don't know 15 years now something
like that same with IP some of these
things and yet phones can get these
things wrong these days because they're
products and they go through new
development cycles and then they're
adding in fancy extra features like
quality of service so they can do
control of how much bandwidth you get or
VLAN tags or power over ethernet or 80
to 1 X or some of these other extra
features because they're trying to sell
hot new products and every time you add
another protocol in is another chance
for the vendor to screw it up and for
them to shift the product with bad
defaults and for the people who deploy
it to configure it in securely or not
knowingly or unknowingly configure it in
securely so all these things are every
time they add another feature to these
kind of things it adds another
possibility for how you can attack it
and you could call it the attack surface
but you know there's actually some a
technical study area called attack
surface analysis which requires looking
at code and stuff like that and all I'm
saying is every time they add a new
protocol buzzword on the marketing slick
you can tell it that the product just
got a little dumber all right things
that have happened in the past if we're
trying to do exploits in the future it's
useful to look at what's gone on in the
past most environments slopes the
computer stuff we've done you know we
expect bugs in the past to have been
fixed and we assume that you know if
something gets talked about by cert and
on CNN and you know in the media and
Microsoft publishes patches against it
and blah blah blah that this would make
things visible enough that other vendors
would figure out to worry about this so
like ping of death finger death started
happening in the late 90s and you think
that anybody who built a test plan for
an IP protocol stack since then would
have said all well we make sure we have
a test for ping of death in there
because we would want to do that but
these things keep coming up stuff like
that in the voice world there's the
standard space stuff so you got sip than
RTP and all of ETF protocols and
unfortunately because voice systems last
a long time vendors have this penchant
for doing proprietary protocols and
they'll get away with it because it's a
closed environment in the old days you
bought 7,000 phones from nortel and you
bought all the nortel widgets to plug
into your phones and it all was just a
closed system so nobody cared about the
protocols so the net result of that is
you get some old things floating around
crusty old protocols that didn't
work well when they were brand new and
and yet get used today so like in the
ccitt standard space that was the x.25
and and all that stuff that was around
before the internet the stuff that was
popular in 80's they had a protocol co
h.323 which was for video conferencing
and it had a call setup protocol called
H to 28 now in case you hadn't noticed
we're all using tcp/ip in the internet
these days and part of the reason is
because the ccitt protocols were
terribly complicated hard to implement
hard to make them interoperate and had
all sorts of encoding formats that were
too complicated and it was just a pain
in the neck to get it running but the
phone vendors didn't notice this because
they were building things in their own
clothes little world and you then get
things like like attacks against the
asn.1 ber encoding format which is
something that happened in the SNMP
world and it's happened in the
certificate world and then you know a
bunch of grad students in finland
bothered to write a java program that
fuzzed h 2 28 and they suddenly can
start finding bugs like this in phones
this is an example of something that
happened and this is the classical cycle
of the the Avaya shipped phones they
thought they tested them I'm not sure
how much they did I assume they tested
for something they certainly didn't test
for edge cases they assume nobody would
ever send that they assume they were in
a benign Network apparently and nobody
work sent bad things to them so anyway
they found a bunch of bugs in that
that's an example of this sort of thing
a--they you pick an old protocol they
think it's okay to petit run with it and
NZ no some kid comes along about this
right buzzer in Java in five minutes and
it becomes famous support protocols
their phones therefore no think small
stupid computer with low budget you know
other think other negative thoughts if
you want people have attacked web
servers people have attacked the ldap
interfaces inside the phones and inside
the directories people attack the DNS
and the phones the DHCP capabilities so
they would tend to put these generic
protocols in you know a cisco phone
having a badly implemented dhcp client
so it's like I don't think Cisco
actually invented dhcp but I think they
had people around when it was invented
so you think they'd get this right I'm
sorry that's that's a naive way to look
at it but in reality what happens is you
know they've acquired some startup in
the last
five years which you know paid some
bunch of 55 programmers in India to
implement something really really fast
that they've never implemented before
and so you basically get fresh raw
implementations of things even out of
big big companies so you can get you can
get vulnerabilities in the in the most
boring places on the server side you get
the equivalent of kinds of things they
people are doing call management it was
this box in the middle of a call manager
and so you have to send it control
messages he's got more lights he's
putting on anyway well I see more it
because I can't see the clock I can't
see my keyboard anyway because it's
designed to record I know so the call
manager in the middle is accepting
messages from the phones and they again
think it's a benign environment so
little things like there's a message to
get sent when you pick up the phone and
pick up the handset and the phone goes
off-hook you know well what happens if
you get 10,000 those a second hitting
the callmanager they don't think things
like this and it's like a one packet UDP
message in some cases so it would be
simple to do that and again there's it's
a server in the middle so all the usual
kind of server attacks like ldap and dns
and DCP and stuff like that if this is a
you end up with some protocols which are
new new enough that other people haven't
bothered to attack them and they might
be looked at if you're trying to take
out the phones like if you can screw up
the quality of service processing you
can make it so the bandwidth management
for the phones is bad and then you get
the phone audio quality can be reduced
so in the voice world you can do denial
of service attacks much easier because
people are listening to the signal and
you know if you screw up the timing on
somebody's TCP connection and the pack
it has to do packet retry underneath
your browser you're not going to see
that as the human I'm unless you're one
of us and your run wireshark the same
time as your browser you know some of us
do that right and you know normal people
wouldn't mundanes would not do that but
they'll notice the phone quality go
glitching if you've got the audio stream
games screwed up because you've got the
quality service mix that stuff so you
had some of these newer protocols you
can get cases where it's a place to go
off and bother to attack that you know I
don't know I haven't I know I don't
think there's any buzzers against qos
values you know at the moment but that's
that's the kind of thing somebody would
go off and
then there's the infrastructure bits
remember I do all the switches and extra
networks there the the cisco example its
systems done a lot of these things up
early in terms of voice over IP and so
because they've done a lot of good stuff
there's a bunch of examples of little
mistakes they made here and there so
they have this thing called CDP which is
cisco discovery protocol so mistake
number one they have a proprietary
protocol they didn't do a standard space
one which is cool and hip and that's the
way cisco does things but that means
that cisco invented and only people who
drink the cisco purple kool-aid were
reviewing it and you know they don't sit
around thinking about trying to attack
it apparently so you'll get stunts like
they did the cisco discovery protocol
message that comes out of a phone that
says hi i'm a cisco phone and when you
turn on network access control speaking
of endpoint security here you turn on
network access control on your cisco
switches under some conditions if a
phone sends the CDP message says hi on
the phone it says oh well i'll let you
on the network anyway because you're not
a windows box so i can't ask you to run
all that network access control software
so we just have to let you in now this
is a low-level ethernet message no
authentication no signatures no
requirements that you can tell exactly
what port it came in on none of the kind
of limitations we've learned in the last
20 years to do with real protocols and
so you know I can generate a CDP packet
that says hi I'm a phone and you know
everybody can do that is just do a wire
sharp trace and take the packet replay
it it's like not hard so you get this
kind of a thing where the the
proprietary protocol which was trying to
wedge some features in past the you know
past the protocol stack can end up
causing flaws there are network access
control based issues other than CDP
there was a report about a week ago some
kid in some high school got expelled
because they turned on knack at his high
school and apparently if you report back
to the knack software that your
operating system is the null string it
assumes you're a phone or something like
that and it just lets you on the network
and this kid found this disgusting flaw
in their protocol and Exploited it and
so he got expelled which you know
it's a kid maybe he shouldn't have been
jacking the school's computers you know
you can have that whole philosophy good
boy bad boy debate but the vendor ships
something that was configured this way
and they put it in high school so that
says the requirements were screwed up it
says the implementation was screwed up
it says the deployment was screwed up
you know it says whoever did the
security review was like we're putting
it in high school so there's high school
kids out there you know as an everybody
bought a copy of hackers you know when
you freeze frame it at the point where
engine unusual Angelina Jolie looks the
cutest you know it open it's like what
high school kids haven't heard of
hackers hello Wow let's see you gotta do
an age check now so anybody here was in
high school no they're hiding no okay
fine well it's a weekend you never can
tell kind of scruffy characters show up
these conferences anyway um
infrastructure protocols IP layer things
you know we we've been finding you know
we do goofy little things just because
you're trying to get warmed up to do
some work so turns out if you send
different linköping messages to cisco
phones you can sense what model phone it
is now if they can get that kind of
protocol implementation wrong and it's
cisco you know they're presumably better
than you know some random vendor and
taiwan who's making cloned phones so you
know they can get it wrong other people
are going to get it wrong and IP is an
example of something they screwed up the
ping time the ping message format and
these things are written down and have
been for 20 years it's not like this is
an exotic old protocol exotic new
protocol it's hard to do arp things you
know once i've got phones hooked up the
switches now the switches are part of
the critical infrastructure for my
phones and it's even better to freak
people out by dropping all the phones in
a building than dropping all the
computers because it scares more people
and so things like arp storms screwing
on with our tables and switches trying
to make the thing and think that the
same phone is on seven different ports
plugged in you know all that kind of
icky things you used to do to to to
attack switches you're back in that back
in two thousand when much was giving
switch tak talks at black hat you know
all that old crusty stuff try it because
it might still work because you know the
phone system thinks it's a closed system
even though it's not and they assume
nobody would ever know the protocol is
running inside the boxes all right
vendor behavior again
back in the bashing here and I use
specific vendor names but the point is
you end up watching people do these
patterns and you end up wanting it's a
good thing to think about this because
you can see where they're going and
where they're not spending their energy
and so you can use that to identify
possible areas to attack things all
right so let me tell you who I'm talking
about / vendors just get calibrated here
you got the people who used to make
telephone hardware like avaya and nortel
know companies that used to make
telephone gear sort of pre ATT break up
the first time you know that kind of
stuff and they have started doing
networking stuff also in various ways
abaya you know can't figure out how to
spell switched and so they new deals
with extreme or various other people you
get people like nortel who bought Bay
networks so they actually have all the
gear themselves if they want to run it
that way and you get other combinations
then you get a network hardware vendors
like Cisco and 3.com but where you know
a cisco now grew into doing the phone
stuff from the from the the networking
side and 3.com I don't know I well as a
tipping point person the room so good
not say anything too snarky about 23
combi know it kind of looks like they
kind of slink out of town stop building
routers and switches and terminal
servers and ethernet cards and started
declaring themselves a phone company
that had an ids subdivision near as I
can tell that's what they did I've said
this in front of the 3com engineering VP
and he actually didn't like stop me but
anyway 3com used to be a network
hardware vendor and now they're doing
phones so that's curved why i put this
in the category you know three comments
no excuse for getting any protocol wrong
in any phone they ever ship ever since
they were around when the ethernet
standard was written so no excuses none
anyway then you get the network
operators who are also doing goofy
things so you got singular and Verizon
and orange and you know whoever else is
out there and they again think they're
in a closed environment they can just
control the entire thing and that gives
a really bad security attitude if they
have any security clue at all then you
get the instrument vendors you know
voice phones are cool so voice over IP
phones are cool so you're going to have
the you know you're going to have
iphones from 3.com i mean from the 3com
no that's not one of the iphone vendors
who from cisco or apple and then you
going to have you know you go to see bid
or some show like that and they'll be
55,000 taiwanese vendors of voice phones
you know with a big sign that says worse
we do 40 bit WEP on our wireless phones
or you know like stuff like that that
really happens so you get the you know
as it turns into more and more of a
commodity you'll get more and more
phones that are are vulnerable coming
out because they'll be the chief
products then you get the protocol stack
houses one of the ways that works when
you get a new protocol rolling through
the industry is you'll find there'll be
some bunch of guys in a corner somewhere
as we know how to build sip or RTP or
secure RTP or they figured out how to
reverse engineer at Cisco's voice
protocol when they have a piece of
software that runs on windows XP that
makes a soft phone something like that
so those days those folks who used to be
called Stackhouse's you know protocol
stack houses they'll sell a protocol
stack to a vendor like they'll sell it
to a Korean mobile phone vendor who's
having voice over IP that kind of thing
this is cool because you can you know as
a company trying to build a product you
don't actually have to hire engineers
you just find somebody who's already got
it in your write a check that's cool
that way it's not cool from the point of
view if you get no genetic diversity and
we have seen issues with this the SNMP
vulnerabilities that sort of ripped
through the internet about five years
ago we're partially because SNMP
research was the primary vendor of SNMP
implementations and they had the same
code in lots and lots of vendors
products and therefore they had the same
vulnerabilities and lots and lots of
vendors products so you really should
pay some kid in the back room to build
this protocol with their bare hands in
some cases because you know otherwise
you're going to be just as bad as your
competitors in terms of security issues
all right then their priorities now this
is obvious to some of us but I need to
remind you of this because I'm thinking
about why you would look at how where
would you look for potential
vulnerabilities so you know they're
going to think about stockholder value
it's like you know notice customers have
they're like I have to get down to
number six before the customers in so
there's stockholder value which means
they want to sell stuff it doesn't
actually have to work they just have to
sell it and then there's the image
because that's to look cool you know so
we have to have cisco phones being
getting a product placement on Eureka
watch that TV show it's like you ever
notice with all of the executives have
cisco voice phones so they're doing
product placement things so you know we
don't have to build real code we can
actually get our products and placed in
scenes in Hollywood
must be cool you know market share is
important so you want to have your
product out everywhere your market
position whether you know you know come
up with some statistic to cook to say
you've got more of something than
somebody else and then you get the
optional things like maybe it'd be nice
that the product was stable it doesn't
really have to be it has to get through
the sales process I mean the demo has to
not blow up and you have to stay a thing
has to stay alive long enough so the
check clears from the customer but after
that you know I'm not clear it can be
anything after that customer
satisfaction is optional you know
they're thinking about the suit they're
selling the phone systems to they don't
care about the geek way to keep it alive
so that's way down there and security is
very optional secure nobody would care
about security you know this is no
nobody really cares above this stuff
it's a Looby okay if the entire phone
system died right so there's that's way
down the list and so if you're trying to
think about where to look for weaknesses
in people's products you got to remember
this sort of priority kind of thing here
so a sexy phone that had you know a
voice over IP phone that had Dolby 5.1
surround sound and looked really cool if
you were running it on the Brit of the
command center and on Stargate Atlantis
when they were dialing the gate make it
push a button and it related to the gate
dialing protocol that would be so worth
putting that feature in there and I
don't care if it does clear text telnet
sending JavaScript that's
unauthenticated with local control it
would be fine that would be that would
be an acceptable product plan so you get
a who knows what they're going to think
like stupid vendor tricks vendors do
some dumb things that they don't realize
that look like this from the outside
because the you know developers you know
don't know developers don't stand up
here and talk to other people that you
know hide in the back room and drink
Jolt Cola and write code and you know
whatever and so this like there's some
disconnects that astounding that you see
in big and small companies they'll tend
to put things on a resource-poor
platform they'll make comments like I
can put Dolby 5.1 surround sound in and
i can add 506 different chips in there
to do enough crypto to the digital
rights management soleta can ship iTunes
because they signed a license with Apple
but God forbid I could digitally sign
anything in the protocols they'll say oh
I can't do that because we have no
resources well they do have the chips
they just don't spend the money in the
right place they'll do partial protocol
implementation
you keep going until it works good
enough and then you stopped you don't
actually build the whole protocol they
don't do testing this is sort of some
vendors you know seem boobs are develop
this habit over sort of the past 10
years that it's okay to not test things
very much just sort of ship them out
there you know the customers will test
them during beta test you know the the
the Microsoft example not not the
Microsoft anything wrong with this but
you look at some of the numbers that you
know auntie's betta run was seventy
thousand users or something like that so
they have 70,000 idiots out there doing
free QA it wasn't really freaky way but
that's a net result of these long beta
programs that people have so you end up
with free testing coming out of the
customers so why pay for Q wave if you
can get the customers to do it for free
after they've sent you a check they
don't seem to add security requirements
you know the idea that I might attack
the phone didn't seem to occur to these
people and a lot of these products are
going to design it certainly after the
industry started to become security
literate so you know the cisco phone
that was designed in 1998 and maybe it's
okay that had few security features you
know any cisco phone that shipped in the
past two years and a supposedly fresh
product and fresh code you know what's
your Excuse why do you think nobody's
been doing bad things to the internet in
the past two years you know they got
that kind of a in effect they wanted to
feature creep so you know this week I've
got a phone next week I'm going to phone
with the display then I want to display
with a web server in it then i'm going
to download images then i want to sound
then i want to play music then it's got
to play itunes then i have to do camera
phones and just keep going and going
going adding features into these things
and every time they add more features
you get more integration points where
they can potentially have flaws they
don't seem to understand modern networks
the phone telco types doing doing this
product review thing I did I talked to a
bi and I'm trying to configure their box
and I said so where do i plug in the
syslog server you know it's a machine
it's on the net I'm supposed to look at
the IP packets it's a server so I asked
how to plug in syslog I thought that was
a fair question what do you do for
logging and their response was what
logging I said you know what do you do
if you have like customers have an issue
and they want to see if there was a
glitch in the product and their response
though is oh there's an analog port in
the back and the think and phone home
and have the
air guy come out it's like we don't need
logging who would need logging of things
you know now that's getting a little
better now because you get things like
regulatory requirements which so you
have to be able to see the logs and show
the auditors so it's getting a little
better I'm finding that you should do
that it'll make it more secure nobody
pays attention to me if I say if you
don't do that you may fail the audit and
the CIO gets to explain it to the boss
that gets money sometimes you might fail
the audit is apparently a good pick up
line to get people to spend money on
security helps if you can prove it but
you know that's still it gets some
thinking it actually gets them thinking
so I don't think about security or role
based management or auditability or any
of these things we're trying to do in
the rest of the networking world of
trying to make things better and then
they do proprietary protocols now we
keep going through this people build a
proprietary protocol you know six guys
in the back room or maybe one guy in the
back room you know designs this thing
cooks it up thinks it up prototypes it
ships the code all the rest of the
developers they put this thing in the
product they assume you know they show
key way all the cool features and nobody
ever actually bothers to fuzzy or check
it for validity or see if there's any
edge cases or that kind of thing and
then it gets deployed to the field and
then some high school student in Germany
whose board sits around you know rights
of poor line perl script it fuzzes
something and things fall over you know
we've had this happen over and over
again maybe we offer you know maybe
there's Perl scripts longer than four
lines but not necessarily and so
basically if there's a proprietary
protocol on your product it's flawed you
know just day one it's flawed because
somebody's don't find something someday
because you that's why we have peer
review and standards protocols processes
and all that kind of stuff because this
is a bad idea and we know we all the
computer business learned this a long
time ago but the vendors keep doing that
because that's the cool way to you know
do the shared all about the shareholder
value kind of thing you know and
security being optional we don't care
about that so if it's got proprietary
protocols somebody's gonna screw up
something at some point and also by the
way they'll have like no documentation
or it'll barely be documented you find
scary things like I bet there's aren't
decent standards on the cisco SECP
protocol inside cisco I bet there's no
decent protocol spec written down on the
inside you'll find embarrassing things
like that you're supposed to read the
source or you know use the
implementations
already there so you know something will
be it'll be hard to bring in new people
to work on it and it'll be easy for new
people to do screw-ups so you get that
so you get this bad cycle if they do a
proprietary protocol you know the five
guys who built it bring build the first
version it works fine then they
outsource all the code to dr. Stan and
give them the protocol spec which wasn't
really very well written down and tell
him to build a new copy on the new phone
and they do what they think is the right
thing and they put a hole in the thing
because you've got this extra process
there and since it's a proprietary
protocol you know you can't buy to
validate validation suites on the street
you can't hire extra people to know the
protocol to look at it you can't find
people who are building that protocol
for years to help you find the bugs in
it you know like I got paid to fix a
ping of death bug in 94 I looked up
trying to look up the notes when we were
doing a cisco ping testing I think 93 94
and I'm sitting there in my lab trying
to build my course and go oh gee I
suppose we should try different ping
sizes just for the hell of it and we
start to find things so you know me
pulling ten-year-old 13 year old
vulnerabilities out of my hat to try on
modern phones that's embarrassing that
shouldn't work should be tote that yeah
we shouldn't be there people should
people who don't look at history are
doomed to repeat it you know it's one of
these things though delivery flaws um so
these things that vendors due to deliver
stuff which is just broken when they
ship it to you because of what they're
doing and it's about the vendor and
their attitude and their processes and
what they're spending money on and it's
actually not got to do with the code and
it's also probably not got to do with
the coders so I'm not saying people who
code things are stupid I'm saying the
managers who pay them and direct them
may or may not have reasonable marching
orders and stuff software development
lifecycle deficiencies you know how do
you eat you should be able to have if
they're really doing software
development in the modern style there
should be a life cycle process and they
should have specs and requirements
documents and test plans and all all
that stuff they teach you in school that
people do when they develop software
lots of vendors don't really follow any
of these processes and you can find
things where their deficiencies you can
see that as an outsider when you start
looking at products you know if they
ship you a product with spelling errors
in the text messages coming out of it
that's a signal if you see you know if
you go read the release notice you
discover that the qos implementation in
the phone you're looking at has been
revved four times in the last three
weeks because they keep getting it wrong
and obviously that codes brittle and
unstable so you can see things by
looking at the deficiencies and software
development lifecycle as an attacker on
the outside so they're generating signal
by screwing up that they can not to be
security literate they don't assume they
have to worry about this stuff until
after the fact if at all it's like oh we
didn't think about security when we
built that it's like well why would you
not think about security when you build
some mission critical infrastructure
component like the phone system testing
deficiencies they won't do enough QA
they went to the right kinds of QA they
won't do QA which tests for negative
things they went to edge case testing
you know stuff like that you know you
can tell this is going on because when
people sell things like like the new
security hardware fuzzer essentially
what it is it will send lots of
different kinds of packets at a target
to see if it's got flaws you know those
things sell well if they're if all the
vendors already had this working they
wouldn't need products like that so you
can tell that there's bears deficiencies
they're trying to do trying to do things
better because they weren't doing it at
all before you get vendors who will ship
things that they say well you know put a
firewall in front of that cisco routers
if you plug in the FX I fxo card which
is the thing that has the analog phone
interface on it if you plug one of those
in and you turn on the machine and you
bring up you enable the interface it
turns on h.323 which is the protocol
that you use to talk to that thing well
that's fine but it turns h.323 on with
no authentication at all which means if
you take your randoms windows but random
windows box running netmeeting because
windows XP ships with netmeeting and you
say the h.323 server is at this address
you can start talking to the router
directly so let me there's no
authentication that wouldn't stop you
from doing that and then you could make
phone calls that nobody could trace so
we found this we reported it their
answer was oh well that's just the way
it is you were supposed to do enough
switch AP a CL
between that you'd stop it so this is
like you know Don't Ask Don't Tell don't
don't attack you know kind of thing it's
like it's okay i can ship an insecure
product because you could put enough
layers of stuff in front of it so it
would be okay so those i'm calling us
prophylactic solutions and that is a
technical term not a rude comment but
you know it's a you'll put a firewall in
front of Mike my product because it's
too weak people think that's a
reasonable thing to say when they sell
products that's just silly in my opinion
um vendors day they want to do network
access control so you know cuz you know
endpoint security is hot you know
addison-wesley paid my buddy mark to
write this book and you know people are
care about endpoint security and you
pick up the news you know newspapers
that are cover these things and they're
all talking about network access control
and network knack and nap and all these
other you know it starts with and it's a
three-letter buzzword that's all fine
and good except then you discover they
normally men network access control
means control of my Windows desktops
which is nice windows desktops should be
running the right antivirus software and
all that crap i agree but what about the
printers and the phones and the access
points and all the other IP address of a
widget you have on your you know your
network the the monitoring cameras that
you put up outside every door that had a
you know a proximity card on it because
you went to the talk the other day you
know what all that stuff is on your
network and so they want to do network
access control and control everything
and know every user and yet there you
can't assume anymore that it's a
computer with a human next to it and you
can identify the user name you know
what's the username for the phone
outside the door to the garage that you
can you know pick up the call in you
know there's no user there so they kind
of their schizophrenic about whether
knack is in this picture or not and they
act like everything has a network access
control and it's all the world is now
safe well the world isn't now safe the
world is now safe if you have a really
simple network they you know they date
sheet on the the non voice protocols the
protocol stacks all that stuff they do
immature implementations of the voice
protocols that are there because printed
rush products to market so it's standard
kind of vendor flaws that happen he's
added another light obviously the
questioning is going to increase here
and then they have a flawed proprietary
protocol so they keep doing these kinds
of habits and you can watch the habits
happen and then you can
if they're doing that kind of stuff you
can use that to identify this memory
flaws in their product if you're trying
to look for vulnerabilities sir all
right so anyway so sort of you know
vendors are stupid you know and it takes
a lot of vendors to change the light
bulb and there's going to be flaws in
the stuff just assume that so anyway
that's kind of the attitude going into
this and yes that's negative and snarky
and all that and unfortunately true more
than it should be all right predictions
let me just back up another one thing
you know if you're going to write a
zero-day about you know because
something you saw because you're seeing
this you know don't put my name in the
comments of the code just you know have
a good time whatever use some
responsible disclosure procedure you
know enjoy yourself whatever you know
and yeah I might predict something I
mean I'm not like right all the time but
every once a while actually do get
things right so anyway some predictions
and the idea here is think about things
i'm predicting if you're trying to go
chasing vulnerability so you're trying
to look for if you're trying to go
hunting for things first thing is the
legacy telco stuff so before the
internet before the dot-com Internet
boom thing you know we have these
telephone networks that very fancy they
had ISDN a bunch of other actually
fairly sophisticated protocols built in
but they were all totally closed systems
and so they were often completely
unsecured they have no passwords or they
ran telnet or all those other kinds of
ugly things that people used to do in
the bad old days so they're pedasi
possibly completely unsecured targets
and if you're talking about a modern
infrastructure the box that did the
old-fashioned telco stuff may just be
across the aisle from the brand new box
that does voice over IP which means you
may have some internet accessible thing
sitting across the aisle you know
connecting to this old kind of gear and
so you may be allowing remote access
ability and these old protocols people
don't understand because you know
basically it was before the ipod it
can't be high-tech right away that's
sort of the boundary now you know if you
think if you think you're you're an
old-timer because you remember windows
98 you're real
old now you know and you'll god forbid
you like remember das or you know you
know BBS's dial-up BBS's that seems to
be the generic old-timer comment at
hacker conscious Darla PBS as i was
around in the late 80s or something so
well some of us writing code in like the
mid 70s so you know don't try that you
know i can do the old geek save you on
sorry we get these old legacy stuff and
it could potentially be connected in and
they assume nobody would ever find the
any details now and you see how you
can't see this but I'm going to I can't
move let's see no I can move the pointer
okay if you look down here we have a
username whap at cingular com this is
from the help screen for 80s set up if
you have a motorola v3 razr this is the
aunt from their website i got this image
okay and that's the URL you feel free to
go there so it says notice down here i
did the mouse to his thing again here so
as a user name laughter cingular com and
a password a hard-coded password listed
on the website and then it's describing
that it's ISDN mouse mouse mouse there
we go so it's an ISDN line so I'm sure
they think I sdn is some Greek term that
nobody remembers and some of us remember
these protocols and what happens if
they're doing stuff like this today what
happens if they have this kind of a box
tied into a voice over IP network and
somebody figures out they can jump
across some gap and telnet into
something with that username and
password and start setting the is the
end parameters inside the switch you
know they're assuming I'm sure they
assume that nobody you know on the
internet today can spell ISDN remembers
any of these things so they just think
this is some you know character string
you're supposed to type in when you're
you know configuring your mother's phone
because your butter renew your bought
one of those you know pink razors on you
know ebay and it gave it to your
girlfriend your liking so you have been
you program the phone so she can go to
use the browser you know that kind of
stuff your boyfriend or whatever so if
they're doing things like this now then
you know why should I assume these
people are going to build a secure
network tomorrow and by the way after
you finish going through this agony to
program your motorola v3 razr and the
singular network when you get to the
section where it says how do you do
email it says put in the hostname and it
will send on port 25 to that host
anybody so all singular
um internet limited literate phones are
capable of talking to port 25 anywhere
they don't block that going out so if
you want to build a really good spam
zombie network take the phones yeah and
I've given this you know the passwords
up there on the website talk about the
years worth yeah yeah and if you change
your service plan for singular they seem
to sometimes kind of reset your password
on your voicemail also so they have
other problems but they're part of AT&T
now so we're all safe yeah the new AT&T
the new insecure apt so anyway futures
areas they're going to be problems so
there's all kinds of new platforms
coming out you've got windows platforms
so you know it's windows and I mean I
gotta care is windows the thing is
interesting is if you talk to someone
who does work in the kind of embedded
space using windows and their various
Microsoft seems to keep evolving the
products and I can't keep track of what
they currently are I've heard windows ce
e windows mobile windows XP embedded
various and sundry names of things which
are in some way shape or form windows on
some platform and so windows mobile
happens to be one of the instances of it
now and if you start talking to
developers who live in this space you
ask some of the sort of the simple
questions like is there a Windows Update
and sometimes you get the answer is no
they don't even have a mechanism to ship
us updates never mind us putting them in
the phone into the platforms the target
platforms so you end up with questions
of okay so you pick this operating
system fine what if somebody finds them
exploit some dll you know how do i get
the dll's out on to all the phones how
do i do uptake in my phones so this is
kind of you know and if it's in fact the
same platform you can start to think
about potentially the same kinds of
exploits working and again I'm not
you're on those lots of operating
systems here not just picking on
Microsoft or anything so you know you
get is there a kind of an update
mechanism and think about what would we
do is that what would they do if we had
a zero-day against blackberries you know
while we tell the blackery do we tell
the people at rim to you know refresh
the network and update all the phones
well they seem to not be able to do that
these days they know they crash the
American network to we
go and they crash the European Network
last week and I'm sure the people in
Japan are totally freaked because you
know they're going to do that update
they are next right and I'm sure they'll
say we have it all worked out now you
know right until Japan goes offline for
six hours so and the poor people at
rhythm I'm sure they're not happy
they're doing that I'm sorry to bash on
them but you know it happens so that is
the sort of example of you know because
the simple thing is you know the event
if there's a flaw and the vendor knows
about it and you guys know whoever did
responsible disclosure and then they
build the update then you get a ship
ship the update out and that's that gets
more and more complicated with small
small devices iPods you know if ipods
turn into phones then we'll have all
sorts to interesting things you got
multimedia stuff going into your phone
now so like this is the company that
shipped quicktime with javascript with
local capability until somebody caught
them and then they patched it so that's
one of those somebody cut home yes they
are really well that's we can talk about
that yes you can patch quicktime I hey I
real early quicktime this laptop i had
actually built this up during the week
which is why i thought of putting that
background slide up there if you look
quick time it's really hard to tell them
that you didn't want itunes also so
their update mechanism is a little odd
it's good yeah well actually have to
keep unchecking the box they keep trying
to give you itunes and this is a what I
kind of try to politely call the Burning
Man protocol strategy which was no sir
the Apple strategy of you know some
naked girl at burning man who's just
standing there asking every way to come
up and kiss her you know kind of thing
about the protocols so like you know you
search on the wireless network here and
you recognize the apples because they're
sitting there screaming to do a reverse
dns lookup with your username and your
host name and your IP address and what
version of what was ten you're running
and you know presumably is going to tell
me where you bought gas last time if i
bothered to look at the right packet
about this whole i want to be sharing
things and it's designed to be an apple
and it's free and cool and the ads have
the cute guy in it as opposed to the
dweeb in the soup so that you know that
style of protocol it's the style thing
means that they're going to build
protocols into their products that are
likely to do that sort of thing and if
that assumes there's no malicious people
watching so you know
yes I take a push updates the phone um
there's something it's not the vendors
the operators and the FCC won't let you
update phones that fast so assuming
Microsoft Word Perfect and Apple were
perfect and Cisco were perfect all these
companies were perfect you still have
issues about getting updates in the
phones has a mechanism and it works
sometimes and well in mobile I actually
haven't tried windows mobile at the last
time I looked as X being embedded if you
can yeah okay and that's what it is now
and the phones are still moving targets
so who knows what phones are gonna have
a year in a year you know life cycle of
a phone is about three months you know
they pull up new devices you know the
motorola v3 razr came out and there was
the it was the cool hips thing to be
carrying your pocket when you went to a
nightclub cuz it was a nice thin foam
and then they came out with a v3r in the
v3s and turns out that they just keeps
throwing implementations over the wall
and so they don't pay attention the
issues they have in them because they're
their commodity devices they're like
fruit they go stale you don't you just
dump them and do another one then you
get the embedded products which are you
know something else some other operating
system or some custom thing and
generally those are going to be if once
we get into things me more and more
commoditized they're going to be is
under net engineering as you can get
away with doing it so they'll do as
little as possible to ship the product
and so that's going to be another
example of a place where people will do
the shortcuts and they'll assume nobody
would ever reverse-engineer things you
know nobody'll ever figure out how
Wiegand protocol works behind smart card
behind us you know proximity cars and
and nobody who ever figure out how to
look at the inside of iOS to figure out
what the decompression format is and so
there's a whole bunch of this oh it's a
embedded system you know nobody could
find out what's in it well I don't think
that's a good attitude attitude next
level up protocol stacks you know don't
assume the vendor can spell IP I don't
care who they are don't assume the
vendor can spell IP that you know they
seem to get these things wrong
frequently and all the protocols that
keep doing fresh versions of things and
so they're fresh and they're vulnerable
old because it's basically the 10
implementation all the time and then you
get the voice specific things so they're
trying to do fast-moving changes to
protocols and try to improv implement
products with them and so they're going
to have stability issues and they're
trying to rush things to market to you
know like these days everybody wants
their only look as cool as possible for
iPhones really ship because they're
going to compete with that and you know
they're going to you know people are
going to suddenly want to do music on
their phones and you know whatever other
features you can do when you're in your
iphone so you get these arms races back
and forth and they'll keep shipping
things fast which means you'll get
vulnerable things being shipped
vulnerable protocols because you'll end
up with all the vendors trying to chase
the same thing so you know they want to
do cameras or they want to do dolby 5.1
surround sound or something silly like
that oh they're all want to plug into a
BMW so you can have your phone sitting
in the docking station you're in your
car playing music while you're on
speakerphone downloading PowerPoint from
your enterprise so yeah well that's
where you do this in your car do you say
you need extra extra batteries you know
it'll suck power do this you know you
could build a tax and suck power out of
the batteries you know renting a no-op
loop for her costs power so maybe that's
a good enough exploit you get these
things called convergence phones they
have voice over IP and a tcp/ip stack
and it's a gsm phone or whatever phone
on the on the other side so you get
those things think you're going to know
the fantasy picture like like Nokia
describes it is you know you pick up
your phone on your desk you're talking
on the phone you're on a tour to 11 with
a tour to 1x and it's all authenticated
and cool and hip and secure and you walk
out the front door of your office you
walk down the street far enough you lose
signal from your office you connect to
the carrier's wireless you know gsm
network it Rihanna kate's magically
somehow you walk down the street you
walk into the starbucks you jump off the
GSM network under the t mobile wireless
network re authenticate yes again yet
again and all the time you're still in
the same you know conference call you
were listening to so this all sounds
wonderful as a feature capability
however you get things like you just
handed that off across three different
authentication systems which you have to
have wired together intimate
huh blindly yes you have to trust them
so yeah you have to trust t-mobile to
get their phone thing right inside their
water their authentication thing
rightness of their wireless then you get
the fact these are dual stack platforms
so you've got two protocol stacks wedged
in small device by people with too
little budget being rushed to do it too
fast so this is a good way to take a
bunch of really smart people and have
them build really buggy code sort of the
general effect you'd get out of that and
then you get all these edge cases due to
hand off protocols so you're changing
networks and you're you know you acquire
an address on a new network your dhcp
lease changes underneath other other you
know connections and stuff like that and
protocol edge cases are the kinds of
things that vendors tend to test for
badly and attackers tend to test for
well because you know you can sit around
you know in your house you're drinking
jolt cola you know writing Python
scripts that generate bizarre connect
messages and they all should be handled
if everything was done properly but
that's the kind of goofy stuff that
people will get wrong and then they
these are new paths to attack other
things so you can get into an enterprise
from the GSM network now or from
t-mobile if you actually can do this
convergence walk back and forth thing if
people do that enough things badly about
how they integrate these systems
together you can attack businesses
through the phone system now not just by
trying to you know go through their
firewall and you get new paths into sort
of research sharing resource sharing
kinds of environments so you get things
where you know you plug your phone into
the docking station at home and it's
also your iPod so of course you want to
have it hooked up so you can play your
you know itunes music on your high-end
stereo at home or connect it to your
TiVo or something like that so now all
those boxes are on the same network
wired together running who knows what
protocols back and forth and potentially
having a tax go back and forth so you
can you know you can attack your stereo
you know maybe somebody to build an
attack that you know goes into your
stereo and deletes all that music you
bought off of itunes did you know if you
sign up for itunes with paypal that it
pre charges if pre authorizes a
five-thousand-dollar charge and your
paypal account from wouldn't that be a
nice place to deploy a virus anyway did
i say that you can attack your BMW
I don't know about BMWs but I know that
daimler chrysler products have gear in
them so you can your plug your iPod in
and it connects in so hmm is windows CEO
that makes me feel really safe being cut
off by a z4 next time I you know dry as
i drive back up by five to the home so
they have been failures so there have
been failures of cars with software
software failures of cars Yeah Yeah
right and you know this is your mobile
device is going to be involved in all
this and so these are attack vectors you
know if you're trying to think like a
bad guy you know what would you try to
do with it what can I do with the phone
exploit well if I can start to attack
your car at school or you can attack
your you know if you download a bootleg
movie that you get off a bit torrent you
know because she thought you were cool
and it's got some sort of bizarre active
content in the movie and then you stuff
in your DVD player and then the you know
the exploit walks through the home
network into your phone and then you
take your phone and go to work and then
it can climb into your interpreter
employers network you know that sounds
like a bad calm Clancy novel proposal
but you know that's a target that could
happen somebody could do something silly
like that and you know depending on what
kind of environments out there that's
got all the right conditions for
somebody to go out and develop something
like that you know somebody pissed at
the Rara a who's trying to do bootleg
movies who's trying to you know exploit
other people who were downloading that
kind of stuff you know so you make the
bootleg movie be you know you know some
exotic you know girl doing yoga kind of
thing so everybody will download a copy
now we can't do Paris Hilton anymore
because she can't make any more movies
from jail we assume right so you know
you'll have to have some other kind of
boot like movie everybody has a copy of
ya behind bars yeah yeah Paris behind
bars the next movie yes anyway Oh anyway
crypto so I do crypto stuff a lot voice
vendors don't understand crypto first of
all they always say the hardware can't
handle it they saw as crypto is hard
because you have two lots of CPU cycles
and we have to have special trips and
things like that these are the same
people who have SIM cards that are due
RSA encryption already so the hardware
can handle it that's just an excuse
people will do things like have
authorization systems that you log in to
do something and your login never times
out so if it's your desktop computer and
you log in your gmail account and never
times out well yeah fine whatever but if
you log into something on your mobile
phone with your on your phone with voice
over IP that's your convergence phone
and then you leave the phone on the
subway and the authentication tokens are
still sitting on the phone or in the
cookies or whatever the jsessionid is
still there or whatever it is and that's
immortal then somebody can pick up the
phone clone the data out of it and
authenticate is you so that's a crypto
problem and it's not like the algorithms
broken it's that people are misusing
this stuff all irregular rules about
crypto don't use proprietary protocols
don't make up your own crypto algorithm
don't roll your own implementation with
your bare hands unless you really know
what you're doing make sure you do some
things to check it to make sure that it
does actually work properly you know all
that kind of stuff about crypto you know
and it means these being small devices
and new implementations we're always
getting sort of people showing up going
all we can do our own special
implementation because we're cool and
different we know this is okay to be
doing this it's a closed environment
will get away with it nobody would ever
look at our encryption algorithm so
anyway that the people are doing things
like that and the crypto should work the
RSA stuff should check the signatures
you know if you have a web browser doing
money kinds of things through your phone
or through your you know or your your
voice phone has a big fancy display to
show customer IDs and stuff you should
actually do all the proper crypto stuff
and people forget this they'll have
there have been phone shipped that
didn't check the SSL signatures there
have been phones checked ship that had
bad roots in the more don't let you load
new roots that's another thing about the
phones being different look at the roots
loaded into a blackberry and look at the
roots loaded into a windows mobile
device and you know look at the roots
loaded into a motorola razr and you'll
find different things it this is the
world where you can walk into a singular
store and hear some customer to next
counter yelling at the person behind the
counter because they're getting a root
certificate not loaded
actually heard that in a singular store
now I get those errors all the time
because I be crypto things but end users
hitting root errors anyway so you know
this is and and people want to use the
the phone for other things so the voice
over IP stuff is going to be sitting
there with browsers try and do other
kinds of authentication and stuff these
devices have to have keys stored in them
somehow so you need to make sure the
keys are you know stored safely and
securely and you can't read the things
out that kind of stuff see how am i
doing on I'm 10 minutes over right yep
there's no hook thing in the back room
you're not waving at me of course you
may be but I can't see you in the dark
anyway I'll go speed up data formats
people getting the implementations wrong
again stuff like that um targets cool
targets rich media things you know
multimedia stuff quick time and you're
in your phones you know being able to
send voicemail messages or animated
voicemail or something to your voice
phones we are having your system side
together you know aggressive active
content you know JavaScript's not
suppose to be doing things attacking the
phone stuff itself you know what if we
had weird signals coming in attacking
the Codex so you that's the proto
decodes taking the audio signal and or
generating the audio from the binary
from the the digital data we can have a
tax against that people are putting
games on phones so they start putting
games and things like games on boys
phones eventually web to bueno fad
services you know dodgeball every
anybody used dodge ball here it's like
they were you everybody was using that a
torque on last year and I'm thinking so
all the hackers in one city are
trackable by one service run by Google
and you're going to like you know I'm
going to send you an SMS and then we're
going to go to the ATM and I'm going to
get the three hundred dollars i'm going
to pay you 20 day that you gave me and
they're not going to be able to track
that we're all running dodgeball anyway
so you got these web two point O
services which assume you want to share
a lot and sharing a lot usually means
not very secure anyway enterprises you
can attack enterprises with VoIP phones
it's another target another patakha pass
this is a bad thing they're all running
exchange Microsoft Exchange which it's
not like exchange is a bad thing but
it's a sophisticated system and you've
now added a new path into it so you get
new corrupt potentially coming into your
email infrastructure plus you get things
like
cisco unity server i think is the
product name which is essentially an old
copy of exchange running on Windows 2000
that Microsoft that uh cisco refuses to
let you update this is a classic case of
you know assuming exchange is perfect
and Microsoft ships me perfect but uh
maintenance releases I still can't use
it because the way Cisco did things so
you get funny combinations because
you've got sophisticated email systems
voicemail and email going back and forth
you know blended attacks what if we have
spam causing you to hit a phishing site
which causes you to click download
something which would attack your voice
phone you know what if we have that
combination people put fancy things in
their phones and now you get more data
there so it's a better target so you get
the you get the sales guy who has the
fancy blackberry whatever phone and they
download a copy the business plan on to
the phone and then they're running
around doing things and they've got a
voice over IP clients so they can also
do vonage or skype or something like
that and now you've got all the
conditions where you've got a
interesting piece of data on a
vulnerable target that you know how to
attack so you can have you know reasons
to go after phone so even better and
then of course there's all the traffic
because i can see if i can identify your
voice traffic i can see your motions
where you going and what you're logging
into stuff like that anyway um voice
people in the when they deploy these
infrastructure things they they tend to
take the network types and make them
play with phones or take the phone types
make them play with networks so you get
up with competency gaps because they
don't overlap people would use through
phone stuff tend not to have been like
iOS wizards and people who do iOS you
know if you have a CCNA or ccie or
whatever you got you probably don't know
every single command in your nor
telephone switch so the same thing both
directions so you get combinations that
are issues and you get again places you
can look for exploits people will use
old copies of iOS because they think if
it was part of the phone system we're
going to leave it alone for ten years so
you want to be running 10 year old
copies of iOS know you know that Cisco
wouldn't say that was a good idea but
people might think about that because
that's the way they look at their their
phone system so you get attacks that way
is people will run really old here
you know we don't catch people running
Windows 2000 servers mostly these days
you know the vendor tells us not to you
know there's lots of reasons not to
whatever but there are people in voice
environments using things of that age or
older so anyway making things better
just quickly the real things the way to
make things better is it would convince
people to stop buying stuff that's not
secure so the real kind of exploit
that's really valuable is you know if I
get a phone call from some sales vp at
nortel it says somebody screwed up a
sale because the customer bothered to
ask questions about security and they
bothered go around nmap on the phones or
something so that's the way to make it
better is to make the sales be impacted
by the security problems you know
dropping O'Day and scaring how other
people is lots of fun but if we can
actually get the sales process to be
impacted by this this would be the way
that actually change this kind of stuff
and potentially nasty things you know we
talked about you know lawyers going
after us evil hackers who are looking at
things you know why aren't the customers
suing the vendors when they ship
screwed-up stuff want their class action
lawsuits you know if you could lose your
business if you had no phones for 24
hours lots of people their businesses
that can say that which means that's
target which means if that happened
because the vendor shipped in secure
product that they were negligent about
that's potential lawsuit so that means
that that's the other way to get this to
work betters you know sue people when
they should be when secure stuff I know
that suggests being litigious but that's
I mean if they're going to use the
lawyers to hit us we should use the
lawyers to hit them you run a real
network connect your phones to a decent
network anyway it's kind of obvious but
whatever vendors should not forget it's
an IP node they seem to not think about
that think about the security
requirements you know send people to
conferences who care about looking at
security anyway test the products please
test the products don't ship things that
aren't tested they look like they're not
tested I mean I'm sure they do some
testing of some sort but they look like
they're not tested and you should be
able to do security update paths you
know i can buy patch Lincoln on by s us
is that the right term for the update
server the corporate kind of update
server for windows update things like
that well yeah except if there's no such
thing as windows update for cisco 7940
phones
there's no easy way to you know I can't
I can't go to my customer and say get
whatever Microsoft told you run the
update mechanism follow their advice
faithfully just do what they say and
you'll be way better I mean that's true
right so I can't say you know go to
cisco and keep running me keep bashing
on the Windows Update button on your
cisco phone until it says it's
completely up to date you can't do that
they are naming mechanisms do this sort
of thing and don't go into denial about
outside security research vendors keep
doing this like oh there is anything
wrong with our phones you guys are all
just making mistakes so there's been
lots of that happening presumably that's
the level before they start suing people
they have no concept that you'd want to
maintain your phones I don't think it's
planned obsolescence I think that they
assume that you're going to keep the
phone for ten years and keep it the way
it was because I think I think that's
the way that people kept writing the
requirements and that sounds fine but
you know eventually we end up with a
phone which is in fact windows XP you
know inside the thing that happens to be
very small and look like a phone or
something like Windows XP and which case
it's a modern operating system with
modern sophisticated features and modern
maintenance requirements and so you
should do the modern thing to update
from the modern vendor and that's all
assuming that everything all the vendors
doing the right things cuz you know
software has bugs and you have to
maintain it that's the way it works you
can't know 10 year old code is you
cannot assume that's going to be good
forever and that that's kind of what the
attitude they used to have so anyway ah
ah let's see vendors dump phones and the
newbie developers I i think that the
phones tend to be the low-end thing and
so you uh you tend to put the new kid on
it it looks like that based on some of
the bugs spend some money on testing
implement Foles protocols don't give
priority to look at feel over secure
your look and feel is cute stable and
secure will be nice also if I can make
your phones unstable I can scare people
very much done so if I can ruin the
stability that that's an interesting
thing to do anyway all right
yeah security research anyway brit
phones are brittle basically phones are
brittle anyway that's it sorry to come
on thank you yes I can't see you I'm
sorry because the lights are like over
here question yeah yeah if you're going
to do access control in your switch make
it voice literate do enough things so
you can put some security capabilities
in that and don't just assume you can
have this massively active thing like
8021 like an 80 to 1 X client to to do
that they I mean they could do more
things in the switches that they wanted
to that I have not found any products
doing it right I have found products
that claim they can do it I've seen some
things that are that are have enough
horsepower some of the things which are
called secure switches they tend to be
firewall for port kind of devices
juniper make some stuff like that
juniper netscreen naevus networks
concentra there's a few other vendors
out there doing things like that which
basically do control per port and if
they did the right set of things they
could quite capably defend a phone that
way but they don't think about it
they're busy obsessing on you know you
run windows on this thing and they'll
tell you what user logged in
yes you'd have to write firewall rules
for phones well that would be the
architecture bug wouldn't know I haven't
found people dealt with that they don't
seem to actually think machines are
mobile like that yeah I mean there's
roaming stuff but that's that's another
set of problems and no I don't think
I've that there they've got that salt
really this is an example if I don't
think they thought up the security
requirements for that users have I
should help youth Mike