okay all right um thanks for coming
we're going to talk about a basically an
introduction to evolutionary algorithms
and we'll try to talk about some
applications of it unfortunately they
didn't put a clock back there so if i
run long or short then we'll blame noid
I'm rooster I used to give talks a long
time ago I don't know if anybody
remembers me I mostly focus on internet
security but on the side I dealt with
viruses and bacteria type simulations
and worms and now I'm in school for
mathematical biology so this is a this
is actually the very big interest to me
and I mine and basically coming learn
from this talk is not really so much
trying to say like this is how you write
an evolutionary algorithm write this how
you write genetic algorithm it's more to
put an interest in here about how they
work and what they can do most of the
work in this area is completely
theoretical it sometimes even hard to
find a problem that that can be solved
by some of these solutions but in the
end it will it should get you thinking
about possible uses or just you know
move in that direction so a quick
overview um evolutionary computing is
basically an optimization heuristic
algorithm and what heuristic algorithm
basically means is that it's a way of
solving a problem by learning and not
expecting to reach the absolute best
solution its goal is to get the closest
is humanly earned as computer ly
possible without actually being
necessarily having to reach the top and
we are doing this using biological
concepts somebody at some point said
that biology is nothing more than an
algorithm looking through a certain set
of space to determine a solution in the
our cases solution of survival so can we
use them can we emulate these kind of
things to be able to solve our own
problems so first we have the coast
things in computer science terms because
all of this in the end comes down to
computer science and computer scientists
basically when you're in you're in
school getting your CS degree the
biggest thing they teach you in these
classes is how to make your problems map
to something that you
can solve how to base how to create
these kind of solution space and so one
case we have what's called a search
space and a spur search space is really
a collection of all possible solutions
it's also includes a concept of piece of
crap also includes a concept of distance
between all the possible solutions so
you can kind of picture it as a big map
as an example when I brought up here was
a protein search so if you're trying to
find some kind of a protein let's say
you're trying to have one that will
develop an antibody or something like
that for a particular virus there are 20
different amino acids if anybody knows
that creating proteins so you have to be
able to combine all these amino acids in
such a way to try to create this this
protein well that's infinite obviously
there's it's an infinite search space
and it would be impossible to go through
so even restricting it down say to a
chain of 100 min glasses or less strict
that down even with such a search space
you're still looking at a vast a huge
amount of data try to go through and say
for instance we represent each amino
acid by a letter A through I guess would
be L or V or whatever you need to have
some kind of an algorithm to go through
that now traditional churches of
anybody's from with binary or
traditional search is not sort so
searches do all kinds of things where
they split the split solutions and look
either side of it or other kinds of ways
of mapping through it but there's no
learning involved today that it always
does the same thing over and over again
what we want to do is find a way that
when it makes sideration it figures out
maybe a little bit more information
about how to get that result and one
analogy the computer scientists use for
this is called fitness landscapes so in
our example a fitness landscape will
represent a presentation of all the
possible amino acid chains I can figure
it's like a big flat map and each step
in the map is an amino acid chain and
each amino acid chain is made up of a
string and we'll say that's a string
length it's a length of L the distance
between the string is they're having
their Hamming distance
and what all the Hamming distance is is
the it's a it's a term that implies what
it takes for this string to become this
string so for instance if you have a
string that's aad and another string
that's a AAA the Hamming distance is one
because it only takes one one thing to
make sure to change it strength to the
other so you solve for that hammock
stream and each amino acid chain you
give it out a fit amino acid you give it
a fitness as well so that graph becomes
just a flat graph which ends up being
with bumps because each amino acid has a
little bit more fitness or it might be a
little bit farther from another one so
you end up with a terrain if you will
and that's how a landscape a fitness
landscape is made so in our case we're
we're going to look at this as an actual
train and we're going to say that our
algorithm is a hiker traversing through
this terrain trying to find our solution
the first thing we can do we can try to
find our solutions we can have our hiker
walk it through every single point on
the entire terrain start on the east
side take each step all the way through
into the west side all over the place
and he will be guaranteed that they will
find the absolute best solution
guaranteed obviously doing this um it's
going to be slow I by the way feel free
to ask me questions are raised your hand
or something I say something confusing
he's guarantees guaranteed to reach the
highest point to find the best solution
there's no way around it in fact it is
the only certain way of finding the
correct solution of course this is
overwhelmingly time-consuming and it's
processor-intensive if you imagine doing
something you know basically 800 zillion
times another possible method of going
through these Fitness landscapes is
using something called hill climbing
hill climbing assumes that our pop our
search or fitness landscape looks more
like a mountain so that the bottom edges
are all very flat where our solutions
are less likely to be correct as it
moves up higher and higher up the
mountain to the very top we reach the
most optimal solution so what we do is
we basically start at the bottom and we
just move up
we don't move to the side we go straight
to the top until we reach the top and
that's our solution this is okay and
it's very useful but it can be
particularly problematic if we're
looking at a much more diverse type
landscape and we'll talk about hill
climbing in a minute there are other
types of searches as well we can make
more explorers and put them all over the
place we could make them more
intelligent about how they decide which
direction they're going to go in and
we'll look at genetic algorithms that do
that and then we can give them the
ability to climb down hill as well and
we'll see that simulated annealing does
that now the fitness landscape metaphor
isn't perfect it's uh it's a slightly
flawed like anything else when you're
trying to force every type of problem
into one type of solution in real-world
solutions large scale problems are never
solved this way if you're going to be
building a house you don't decide where
you're going to put the bricks and then
decide that where you're going to put
the plumbing into eventually where you
decide where you're going to put your
bed you start out by drawing a picture
of the house and then recursively coming
clothes and farther and farther until
you get to the point where you're ready
to lay the bricks out so if it is trying
to look at things as a fiddle ask a poor
at look at each individual bit it gets a
little hard for our mind to be able to
deal with that in our mind the landscape
has two dimensions or three dimensions
right x y&z axis we can't really picture
any more parameters in that so if our
Fitness landscape starts to get outside
the scope of what our mind can imagine
is hard to conceptually use it we assume
that the points of the landscape are
actually neighbors that we can actually
move freely from all over these points
that they're all available to us which
isn't necessarily true and we're also
assuming that all methods are all paths
are symmetric but if I'm at Point a and
I go to point B that going from point B
to Point back to point a is also
available which is not necessarily true
either so we're making all these
assumptions when inside our Fitness
landscape which basically means that if
we're trying to solve a problem that is
that fits outside the fitness landscape
then we just find another we find
another way of solving it
try to point out there are things that
aren't always easily solved this way um
hill-climbing algorithm we're going to
talk about this for a second it's
basically its main feature is for
maximizing or minimizing a function that
has a discrete state which means a
limited it has a finite amount of state
you can think you can look at as the
problems are represented as vertices on
the graph so you have the graph that's
all little crisscrosses an age solution
is basically just that intersection
point of vertex in the graph the
algorithm will follow the vertex looking
for a path up and as it follows that
finds that path up as we mentioned it
keeps going up to the top now there's a
couple of different ways that it can do
this we have simple hill climbing which
basically finds it finds the closest
path up and just jets up it and keeps
going up and up and up like this now the
problem with this is of course as you
can imagine as you're starting to move
up you're more likely to hit will be
called your local maxima which means
that if I've got say two mountains and I
climb up to the top of this one it's a
solution but it's not necessarily the
best the best would be at the top of
this other mountain one way around that
is using what's called steepest ascent
search where we kind of it looks around
the algorithm looking at all the
different possible gradients and it
chooses the one that's the most the
steepest and it takes that path up goes
to the next one looks around at the
which one of the steepest it takes that
path up and so it climbs all the way up
see this ascension see and then but that
isn't even perfect in itself right
because once again it is still possible
even with that to end up on the top of a
small mountain so the next solution was
the shot gun hill climbing and basically
what that means is as I'm taking the
algorithm to his steps and I take it to
the top of a mountain I then randomly
move to another place and I move up the
hill climbing algorithm and I do more
comparisons and I do this over and over
again at many different spots and then
in the end what should happen is they
should with all that randomization be
able to find my optimal solution anybody
have any questions about that all right
the first one we're going to talk about
is are the first real real one other
male timing is simulated annealing now
this one isn't really a biological
process but it's always gets thrown in
mostly because it's wave manages through
the search space and because it uses
populations now simulated so annealing
is basically the process of metal
heating up and cooling down and that's
in the annealing property is how what
the cooling property so when metal is
heated up to its absolute boil up to its
melting point there's a tremendous
amount of energy if anybody seeking
physics class they've seen this there's
tremendous amount of energy caught up in
this metal and how this looks is as the
molecules are shaking all over the place
now as the metal starts to cool and the
temperature comes down the molecules
have less space that they can move along
around in and to the point of when they
finally stopped moving and they do
develop a a crystal structure and that
is done now in will see that this
actually applies in our algorithm as
well if a an algorithm cools too fast
all right I'm sorry if a metal cools too
fast then the crystal structure starts
to become too brittle and is actually
the metal is pretty faulty you if you
control the way the tenth the cooling
happens it creates a much stronger metal
so what how do we then translate this
whole concept of this metal cooling into
an algorithm and how do we use it um now
let's see okay so the first thing we're
going to do is we're going to create a
random solution now one thing we'll see
here with simula nailing vs. will look
further than genetic algorithms we're
going to find one we're going to use one
solution so we're going to randomly come
up with a solution generate that and
that's going to be our current solution
we're going to assess the solution now
one thing you're gonna find is all these
algorithms and stuff are fairly simple
some of the implementations inside them
are more complex for instance assessing
the solution it's really easy to say
just look to see you to make sure that
it's the best how you do that is a
little complicated and depending on what
your problem is simpler problems are
obvious
much easier to assess the more complex
ones so in this point in our algorithm
we determine how close the optimal
solution is to the current solution of
course that's depend on the problem
being solved the energy in that solution
is then determined and its termined by
how well it solves a problem Yeah Yeah
right sure absolutely i mean this is
this a heuristics one right well in its
not necessarily NP complete right it
could be an np-hard problem its weight
okay well either way your optimal is a
little computing its best solution
you're right we're optimal solution it's
whatever we what we're choosing is being
our representation of what we think it
should be which satisfies a solution
right sup satisfied right what's up
status feiss right so so anyway the
energy term by how well satisfies to the
problem then we randomly change the
solution of course how we randomly
what's oh how we do that is just
dependent on the problem itself then we
use acceptance probability to determine
if we're basically going to accept this
solution or if we're going to move on
and basically it's dependent on how well
its fitness will determine if the
temperature of the current solution is
lower more accessible we then run this
or we just automatically accept it if if
the temperature the current solution is
higher is in pass to this algorithm
right here just basically just this
equation and all it says is that if the
temperature is higher we are more likely
to accept random crappy solutions if the
temperature is lower we're less likely
to and then then we basically then we
reduce the temperature and we keep
iterating through until the temperature
reduces so the point where our search
base gets smaller and smaller smaller
and then we have a I showed a cooling
schedule here to determine when the next
what the next temperature is going to be
and this is just a geometric cooling
schedule and then you just do that over
and over and over again until you come
up with a solution the different kind of
parameters that you can adjust inside
the simulated annealing is we can change
the initial profit initial temperature
the initial temperature is going to make
it either more effective or more fast or
more or more there's going to get
quicker obviously you want to make sure
that it's a high enough temperature that
you can do an expansive enough search
but at the same time you want to make
sure that it's something that can be
completed in a reasonable amount of time
we have to determine what our final
temperature is going to be we looked at
our last cooling schedule and that will
end in 0 but not all cooling schedules
are necessarily in 0 you might end up in
the negative number somewhere and that
you have to make sure you account for
that and then the temperature function
pretty much there's many different kinds
of these like i showed the geometric one
you just have to it's all a matter of
kind of figuring out what your problem
space is and using that to try to help
determine how you want the cooling rate
to be and then the number of iterations
at each temperature the next thing we'll
look at is swarm intelligence swarm
intelligence is I think the more fat is
kind of more fast anyone uses the idea
of collective behavior in decentralized
self-organized systems it's made up
basically you have individual little in
some cases they called agents in some
cases our card particle particle is it's
all basically what you want to call it
and it's made up of each one of these
individual ones and each individual
particles give it a set of rules to
follow they this these rules kind of
define the behavior of each individual
particle by itself and when in the end
this local behavior allows for images
emergence of global behavior so what
this means is um if you ever seen a
flock of birds or school of fish
basically they're all kind of grouping
together and the question is how do they
do that yeah you see flock of geese you
see the one at the front followed by all
the geeks behind them and you might be
tempted to think that basically that
geese is in charge but it's not sure
right ants colonies are the same kind of
thing if I shoot that geet that goose in
the front that flock of birds didn't
keep going they're not going to fall
apart so that no one bird is in charge
of this entire flock but in the end the
behavior acts as one entity and how this
does it is by using simple rules if say
well the bird is given herb in this
agent or this particle is given a rule
basically you're supposed to stay at
certain distance away from another same
agent as yourself and you have to not
hit things maybe a couple of the rules
as a as those rules are processed over
time things start to merge together and
they develop this behavior so we can do
something very similar in in computers
and the one I was going to look at is
called ant colony optimization and ant
colony optimization basically simulates
aunt food searches so the way ants move
let's say that we have a brick and we
have two pieces of food one is farther
from the other one and I didn't have a
slide for this unfortunately um and I
don't have a whiteboard which would help
but to Ansley from either direction
going to that going to that food source
the shorter aunt is going to reach the
food source first is going to turn
around and come back the one of the
longer paths going to take much longer
is going to come back around now they
use pheromones that they leave and they
develop they create a trail down or long
this of these pheromones what happens is
the shorter path has a stronger amount
of pheromones as the and goes along
comes back drops more pheromones the
other one has been exposed to the
environment more so there's less
pheromone as the next aunt comes along
he's going to they're going to look at
that pheromone trails and they're going
to make a decision on which path are
going to take they won't necessarily
pick the trail with the most pheromone
they may choose the other one so there's
a probability at that point of
determining which trail to take more
will take the
sure the shorter path so I'm take the
longer but as more and more start taking
the shorter path you'll have more the
ant trail becomes where there's the vast
majority of them are following the one
and very few ants are following the
other to the point where you see that
string of ants that you see every once
in a while where they're all following
the same path and it right so they fall
back so we end up creating somewhat of a
positive feedback loop um how do we do
this in how do we do this in it as an
algorithm and this is the the easiest
way to picture how this algorithm is
useful is where I've seen it uses in
graph trying to analyze graphs or in the
routing I don't know how people do
networks but I've read some papers on
how to use ant colony optimization for
advanced graph our advanced network
routing and the really complicated
networks so what we do is we create an
initial population began and we
distributed them all over the entire the
graph space and we have to distribute it
everywhere because we don't know the
proper path and that's remember in this
particular one we're looking at paths
each ant keeps a list what's called
tabulous which basically is a list of
all the places that they've been so the
one thing is important is that it
doesn't keep a cross over at same path
so in the beginning when the ants making
a determination of war the agent is
making the determination of which path
to take we have an algorithm that is
actually going to an equation that's
going to stay the same through the
entire process but at the very beginning
there are no there's no pheromones laid
down there's nothing so the probability
of either path is pretty open now so
they so this is going to be end up going
to be zero or whatever it is a general
probabilities for that and the algorithm
is pretty basic it's basically just a
function of the of the the heuristic
measurement times the the pheromone
level as a summation of all of the ants
for all the trails pheromone levels
so when the ant make it store so these
are some these equations we're going to
use the and makes it store it's going to
decide what the pheromone level of the
path is going to be and it determines
that by it's basically the change in
pheromone level is a is a sort of
looking for it's a given number a chosen
number and a end of this the pathway of
the the path of the end but the actual
pheromone level a constants are accused
of constant words you're leaving me
actual pheromone level is the is
calculated by taking that change and
multiplying it by the current path and
then multiplying it again by by o'connor
extras multiplying the change against
another constant which is usually
between zero and one just to give you a
little bit more randomness and then
adding that to the current path and then
you have what would be the current
pheromone level and at the same time the
current the the pheromone evaporation is
calculated basically by multiplying the
pheromone level by a number that's one
minus our of our constant probability
number oops so how does it work each ant
uses that initial probability of
cohesion like we looked at to determine
where to go in the beginning and of
course like I said it doesn't have
anything to do it doesn't the equation
doesn't have any numbers yet to fill in
with it as an passes to her note that no
one is entered first into his tableau
list and then the pheromone level is
calculated and I'm using those equations
that we showed the actual pheromone
deposit is then is calculated and then
when all the ants have actually finished
all their their their past they restart
the cycle at that point we have numbers
to stick in that probability so it
starts to change as different paths have
different weights based on that
pheromone level as more pass following
and less evaporation happens and has
said more and more tours happen the
number of paths becomes smaller and
smaller and eventually you have one path
determined
these are some of the uses I said I
really like I said really dynamic really
complicated routing systems people have
academically shown how that you can
solve some of those problems using ant
colony optimization I've actually even
seen papers written on how you are using
ant colony optimization for some
cryptographic analysis which is a little
out there okay so we're doing on time
okay so the next thing I'm going to talk
about is genetic algorithms but i'm
going to give i guess the high school
bio lesson again just to make sure that
we're all it the benefit of this is like
i said in the end what happened is
scientists said you know biology and
evolution provide us a method of
understanding how problems are solved in
in in real world they have taken a the
biologies had this do some of the same
things we've had can we learn from the
way that it does things and try to
emulate that so the first concept is
evolution which is a change in traits
within a population through inheritance
this change happens through multiple
generations over and over again we end
up with white bears in the north pole or
wherever bear the white bears are I'm
not a biologist random mutations can
create new genetic combinations and
really this it's very one of the very
important keys to this whole process as
we change to happen to become more
common oh yeah as these changes start to
become more common or even more rare we
have an evolution of process moving
forward happening another way of looking
at it could be called the spontaneous
generation of innovative functional
structures a kind of a more technical
term basically I can do more things from
evolving natural selection natural sexy
occurs when you takin is allows an
organism to be better fit in this
environment it survives as we all know
from Darwin Awards as these organisms
survive there is a higher probability
that its genetic controller we passed on
so the idea is that if i can live i can
have more children
and I can my children can have more
children as they start to mate with
people that also have a higher fitness
these traits are these traits are passed
to offspring have a higher problem
surviving these traits that are less
likely to survive meaning that if I'm
going to die before I have children
children then I'm then most likely those
traits are not going to be passed on and
then it continues so the fundamental the
fundamental building block this entire
thing is DNA and I'm not going to
pronounce that diox rub-on nucleic acid
like I said right and it contains all
the genetic code for all development
it's all those jeans it makes up the
fundamental pieces of the chromosomes
where the chromosomes are going to be
very important for how the genetic
algorithm works and only 1.5% the actual
DNA encodes protein anybody's interested
what the other 990 whatever percent 98.5
percent is is somewhat most much of his
of a mystery some of its for determining
how transmission rate happens many
people heard junk DNA that's they will
classify this as junk DNA lately they
found that more and more of it is
actually maybe a little more important
than we thought and then when cell
division happens each cell gets an exact
replica of the DNA and the genes are
people are as part of the DNA and
they're a part that actually encodes a
specific protein so as you know how what
color eyes are clear hairs are our hair
is how our eyes work all based on jeans
and the howard sequences these proteins
also contain some regulatory sequences
for adjusting rate of wind transcription
happens in our case proteins have our
working proteins um genes and
chromosomes working what's called
alleles and allows a pair of jeans each
appearing on the same chromosome and
that'll make sense here in a second
chromosomes are basically a collection
of hundreds of thousands of genes all
together inside the DNA structure or all
built out of DNA and they're a
collection of all the chromosomes is
called the genome so basically if you
you were to like create a number map of
all of your genes it's called genotype
and if you in your body or the
representation of those jeans is our
physical manifestation is called the
phenotype our chromosomes are what's
called mama magis and that means that we
have two pair of like jeans they're not
exactly the same they're like each other
and the idea is that we got one from
each of our parents and we have 46 total
jeans 22 of them homologous one pair is
not and that's the XY gene which is
determines our what our sex is what's
that chromosome sorry did I say the
wrong word oh yeah I said gene denied
it's 46 chromosomes 23 pairs 22 or
Malgus one is not or two or not now when
sexual reproduction happens each sexual
reproduction cell has 23 question is how
do we how did we go from 46 chromosomes
to 23 chromosomes and this is going to
be this concept is going to become very
important in in our algorithm and its
concept called meiosis and it's how
sexual reproduction cells called germ
cells are made this happens when the
cells destined to become reproduction
cells are created in each of the cells
those cells the number of chromosomes
that are passed on is reduced in half
and the question is how and really it's
done randomly so that when when the germ
cells created a completely random salute
a random algorithm is running your body
that says take this particular
chromosome from this one from this allel
and this one from this one and so you
develop the 23 chromosomes and that's
where and then when we're developing
those crossover those those chromosomes
we have a constant of crossover and this
is kind of where the whole and this is
how we is a sexually reproducing people
evolved crossover happens during the
meiosis period so we develop we get a
chromosome from our parents and we get
one from each of our parents or a mom
and dad and on each of those chromosomes
is a bunch of genes now we might have
genes that are considered wild genes
basically mean they're the original way
the gene was meant non mutated some
people might have mutated versions of
these jeans when crossover happens it
basically decides which gene we should
replace with another one so um we create
a new chromosome based on breaking apart
the two chromosomes and create the new
one that chromosome is then handed off
to this to the germ cell and that's
what's used for the reproduction so it
is random the frequency of this
recombination is determined by genetic
distance if two genes are are really far
apart from each other there is a good
chance that they might they might
recombine or crossover if they're really
close to each other that you have a
tendency to stay more stable another
important concept is mutation and
mutation is a change in the DNA through
some kind of outside influence it's
going to happen through ultraviolet
radiation viruses I put in here I think
it's kind of interesting that if you do
if you look at our DNA there's lots and
lots of samples of virus DNA in there so
we are in effect kind of descended in a
way if you look at it viruses make
mutations can affect the somatic cells
and somatic cells just basically a
non-sexual cell and that's where cancer
comes from and some of the things like
that the vast majority mutations are
either bad or neutral I give an example
here of one where it's beneficial it's
basically one example of a mutation
that's actually made people either more
resistant to the HIV or in some
situations where one parent had the gene
and one parent didn't that helps to
delay the onset of AIDS okay
so we'll talk about genetic algorithms
so what we're doing here is we're now
using those principles that we learned
simulate the evolutionary properties to
solve problems in this case we're going
to we're going to work over a population
of solutions rather than in simulated
annealing and hill climbing where we had
one solution we were working with we're
actually going to work with multiple
solutions each solution represented as a
chromosome and the candidate solution
that the we're looking through our coded
is they are called phenotypes but
they're basically in column chromosomes
typically solutions I say are coded as
binary strings and well I'll talk about
that in a second and here is basically
the steps that we go through for the
genetic algorithm we're going to create
the population where they am going to
select survivors based on a fitness
function we create offspring based on
these survivors and then we evaluate the
fitness function and determine at that
point we make a determination have I
have do we have still dramatic amount of
evolution if not then we probably reach
the end of our as much as we can do so
we end the algorithm also we can end it
based on how many generations we are
going to allow might say that we let
five hundred generations and that would
be call a run so what we're trying to
like max match the idea of biology and
their fitness idea in in biology the
fitness function of biology is really
easy survival in our case it's not so
simple inheritance it's basically the
way the genetic operators going to work
and I'm going to go into what several
different genetic operators but I want
to talk a second about the chromosomes
chromosomes because how you represent
your chromosomes your solutions are is
very important initially Jon horn is one
of the original adventures of the let's
see actually many we have myself so
these are random over time we find the
best solution
the design of the chromosome like
everything else is dependent on your son
the problem you're trying to solve and
we'll see this in a second when we're
looking at the different chromosomes
chromosomes binary encoding was
basically the first way that this was
done and that's because the inventor
John one of the inventors John Holland
use this to solve the problems at the
time and so we that's the one that's
considered the most well understood and
the most often used and basically that
means that the chromosome is listed as a
bit string they work really well with
fixed length and fixed order binary and
coatings the problem is that it it can
get more complicated we change the
length or change it change some of the
ordering one of those things that people
are researching but they don't
necessarily know the best way to use
this kind of thing another way of
encoding it is what they call many
character and real valued encoding what
that means is that each gene if you will
in the chromosome chromosome is either a
character a word or maybe a real number
it's not a bit too stout a binary number
and for instance this could be effective
in some like cut oh yeah so the one
thing to think about when you're
thinking about these kind of algorithms
is what's called no free lunch I don't
know people have heard no free lunch and
it basically means that no generic
algorithm is going to be better than a
specific one so the times when these
algorithms are most effective is when
you don't know what algorithm to use so
when you for instance if you're doing a
search or you're doing a sword over
finite file for instance you're never
going to use one of these things because
um you we have binary sorts and we can
use those much more effectively but
let's say we're trying to create a
grammar parser right we could create a
grammar parser using a ton of reg axis
but that would be really complicated and
if there's any changes over time it
wouldn't be able to would have to create
more and more reg X's to try to deal
with that now but this is where these
come in and they help basically as their
learning and then start adapting the
algorithm starts
can deal with those kind of changes and
that make sense they meaning it is an AI
Algrim that's what these are these are
we excited I algorithms right and it
right and you know I've seen things like
that and you know there's tons and tons
of research in the end you know we
talked about how these things work
there's even research done still trying
to understand how genetic algorithms
work because it's not really clear they
you know it's they develop some
mathematical models around it but at the
in the end you know they we've got us
some some theories but that's about it
but yeah so there's the encoding is one
of those things where you've got
researchers all around the world and
universities just trying to resolve how
to encode problems correctly another of
one way of people are doing coding is a
tree and coding and everybody knows what
a like a binary tree looks like not all
trees have to be binary but and this
works great because as you know it gives
you open end of this you can create you
can this tree can go on but of course
that's the double-edged sword because it
can go on forever and then of course you
start losing your ability to be able to
search this space because the tree goes
out of control and how do you choose the
best one like I said it's depending on
the problem you basically have two
enamel analyze the problem and kind of
decide from there you know what
direction you want to go in so cross
over so the genetic algorithm how to
consider it is considered one of the
primary features that makes a genetic
algorithm do what it's supposed to do
actually one thing I'd like to point out
that i should have point out earlier
there's actually even some contention
sometimes about what a genetic algorithm
is what I'm what I'm showing here is a
really a generic basis of what genetic
algorithms are and there are more
specific type descriptions and
explanations so it's kind
interesting that way like i said it's
very is still very academic so that's an
operator and a genetic operator used to
force diversity in the chromosomes so in
this case our genetic we don't work with
allows we don't work with pears we just
have the amount of chromosomes we have
as you might we have and we randomly
choose when we're choosing these things
like these cross over we're just going
to randomly choose a couple of
chromosomes but two chromosomes are
chosen and as an hour biology reference
and they are randomly broken and
attached the question is how do we
determine how we're going to randomly
break these things and reattach them one
the first solution and I have some
example code that I'll show you in a
little bit and I use this as the one
that ends up getting use is called a one
point crossover and what this basically
does is you track through two different
through the two different chromosomes
you pick a point where you want to do a
swap and then every all the data from
that point down get swapped between the
two chromosomes and you have now created
two new chromosomes the problem with
this is that it yeah when you if this is
too big you're starting to move large
amounts of data around and so your
randomization is actually kind of narrow
for one thing you cannot combine all
possibilities I give an example here of
11 dot star star star star 1 and star
star star 11 star star you're never
going to be able to make that convey
other combination so those are going to
be solutions you're never going to find
they can you can end up destroying large
chromosome sets is it as it's holding on
too tightly to certain data sets and it
has a tendency for hitchhikers if you
could imagine if I'm cutting a
chromosome in half there could be dating
in there that's not very useful but it's
always going to be moved around more
more likely than not because of how
large the section section we're picking
up we end up with the kind of a loci
preference the the endpoints end up
getting always together so so to solve
that problem they decided they use to
point crossover which basically means we
should we choose two points in the
algorithm or am starting the chromosome
and we swap in the
take the chunk out of the middle and we
swap that this helps a little bit
because we're working with smaller data
sets so anytime you work a smaller data
sets you're more likely to get a small s
information and less correct less
carryover from other solutions or less
carryover will will happen this method
it reduces the damage to large data sets
and and also resolves the endpoint
problem there's this one that's called
cutting splice which is another one of
those ones that's really theoretical
because in the end what happens with
this one is you're going to end up with
different sized chromosomes all over the
place which most problems most of the
time you're not really going to be able
to deal with that's going to make no
sense and you're gonna end up with all
kinds of faults but there are times i'm
i mean i i've seen it and I know how to
make the splice but I've never ever come
up with come across a scenario where
it's actually something you'd want to do
but you know it's always possible
there's something out there as things
got more advanced the they worked on
what's called uniform crossover
parameterised uniform crossover
basically means we're going to walk
through every single one of the genes of
the chromosome and we're going to run a
probability mouse over it news that's to
determine whether we're going to do the
crossover or not and we'll do that
through every one of them time-consuming
but a but obviously going to be very
ineffective in making sure that we're
truly we're truly going through all the
different possible solutions one that's
not quite as time consuming maybe not
quite as effective but more effective
than even the two point crossover is
what's called a half uniform cross over
and we basically take half the bits and
swap them and we have an algorithm we
take the Hamming distance and then
divide that by two and that's how many
different bits are crossed over not all
solutions can be swapped like this
however anything that requires a make
sure you have no there no duplicates
like the Traveling Salesman problem
wouldn't be very effective with this the
next genetic operator I was to look at
his mutation and basically this adds
just that extra layer diversity means
higher into our into our environment it
keeps offspring from being able being
too similar and slowing down the
evolutionary process and one one way to
determine how you're going to do this
mutation is basically after you pass
through your crossover algorithm you're
in another pass over of a mutation
algorithm and it has a probability do I
mutate or do I not mutate selection is
in and then the the next really
important part and basically we decide
which chromosomes are going to move on
and which don't which are the ones that
are surviving this word responsible for
deciding chromosomes will survive the
plan is to let the fittest specimens
survive and let the less fit die off
this has to be carefully balanced if you
may be right a couple run across a
couple of chromosomes that it seemed
really fit and start focusing on those
early on you're leaving off a whole lot
of a whole lot of solution sets behind
and you're more than likely going to hit
a local optimum or local local solution
that isn't necessarily the best one too
weak a selection process meaning that
you're letting too many things reproduce
and it could take a really long time so
the first way that they did this
selection was based on this was in fact
the first one was which the John Holland
made was the fitness proportionate
selection basically the selection is
proportional to how much what the
fitness is and they'd show the first one
is a roulette wheel selection and you
could picture a wheel and there's a
roulette wheel a little arrow that comes
into it and each chromosome has a slice
of that wheel dependent on how what its
fitness number is so the wheels spun as
many times as there are chromosomes and
where that word out where that needle
lands is those are the ones that move on
this doesn't it appears to according
does not work very well over a very
large data set or it doesn't work very
well across smaller data sets it would
be pretty effective over extremely large
data sets as the as Italy it starts
balancing out but if you're not doing
very many spins
it kind of loses its ability to be truly
random the next one was the stochastic
universal sampling and it was basically
like the roulette wheel but instead of
spinning the wheel it basically randomly
placed points around the wheel and said
those are the ones that are going to
those across those ones are moving on
the selection then at that point the
Sigma scaling is the next one that they
developed and that was developed
probably about 10 or 15 years ago and
basically what it does is it applies
pressure let's call it selection
pressure to each one to the fitness
function or I mean I'm sorry that's a
fistfight it applies selection pressure
in the selection process so what it
wants to do is it wants to make the
selection process constant through the
entire thing so that there is a chance
for crossover of maybe possibly less
desirable results that may not
eventually be more desirable and if you
look it's a pretty basic algorithm and
basically what it's saying is we have we
take the mean deviation we take the
results as it is so far we divided by
the main deviation of the fitness which
in the very beginning the deviation is
not going to be very great so this
number is not going to be very big and
then the we've got a more liberal
crossover route selection process as
that deviation gets stronger though it's
going to be less and less crossover
happens or less most likely that the
cost of that selection is going to
happen so I at the beginning the
deviation will be high deviation for
each individual not be drastically
higher than me this forces more diverse
reproduction the the diversity of the
reproduction is really the most
important part of the genetic algorithm
and for it to work next one look at the
Boltzmann selection and the idea is that
sometimes you don't want it to be even
or you don't want it to be even across
the entire product of the entire
selection process sometimes you want to
be able to apply more pressure sometimes
you want to apply less pressure so in
the beginning it's possible that you
want to have less pressure you want the
development process or the selection
process to be very weak to allow
more recombination to happen but then as
you get closer and closer to your
solution or you want to maybe want it to
be less reproduction happening more
focusing on the solutions you've got
kind of like in a simulated annealing
way in the cooling process the next one
the look at is called rank selection and
this one is it takes away the fitness
number out of the entire Islands entire
process so what it does is it basically
determines which ones are the fittest
and doesn't really necessary keep the
number it just says this one's the most
fittest the next one down the next it
ranks them based on that and then
there's a probability of which ones are
going to then be selected so what that
means is that the even if the the top
one is has a much higher number the
chance isn't actually any different for
the second one to be selected and this
allows for a much more even distribution
of these chromosomes to be selected it
can be good in the beginning when the
absolute fitness of each individual
allows for OC good at the beginning not
knowing the absolute fitness of each
individual allows for more diversity
sometimes though there are times you
might need to know this absolute fitness
one thing is this can actually be fairly
effective or has proven to be fairly
effective against noisy Fitness
functions where you might call into the
function and get different results at
different times even with the same input
well then there's tournament selection
and this was kind of meant to make
things to speed things up a little bit
as it mentions on all selection requires
two different passes one to actually
calculate the fitness or the deviation
depending on which one you're using and
calculating the expected value and it
can be somewhat time consuming what this
does it basically pulls out to random
chromosomes a random number are selected
and if R is less than a parameter then
it basically it either chooses the more
fit one of less fit one
and then both are returned back into the
population to be then show it possibly
selected again there's a concept of
steady-state selection which I don't
really know a whole lot about because
I've never really used anything like
this but basically the idea is that
we're not replacing very many
chromosomes and this is suppose is it
appears to be mostly effectively used
against when you're using multiple
chromosomes to solve a problem meaning
that they're the results is actually the
time together these chromosomes is the
actual solution it's not using each one
is its own solution and that's used in
rule based learning so um in evolution
again when different organisms start to
become very diverse they lose that
ability to be able to reproduce with
each other the genetic information is so
dissimilar that reproduction can't
happen so even if sometimes like usually
when that happens you you can't even
generate offspring there of course rare
exceptions like the liger which is my
favorite animal we can use this idea in
genetic algorithms as well to once again
force diversity once again diversity is
really the most important thing in a
genetic algorithm a function is use
determine how some of oso you can use so
one possibilities use a function to
determine how similar two chromosomes
are if you if you bring two chromosomes
together and you're attending to do a
crossover you can run a function over
them and determine if they're too
similar if they're too similar you can
they can be dumped right back into the
pool and two more chosen that way if
because the two chromosomes are too
similar any kind of crossover that
happens won't be all that effective
we're preventing incest which I hear is
taboo we're not trying to make species
we're just trying to make populations
might get more diverse another
possibility is creating i think john
holland father this one as well create a
mating tag which is we put a tag in the
chromosome which says I'm
you know I don't know blood type B or
I'm this kind of a mate and then when
you pass a function over it in that way
does not to actually calculate how
similar it is just looks for the mating
tag and says these two are are exactly
are too similar so once again this
doesn't happen I was time going oh and
my own was supposed to be almost done
all right I'll go faster uh well
actually ok so the tuna columns like I
said they're not really well understood
they're simple to describe in simple the
code but what the results you get end up
being pretty complicated schematic this
schematic three which i'm not really i
don't have time to get into at this
point is basically was the original kind
of model that was come up with with how
these work and it's a theory where each
schema is basically a building block and
the theories of genetic algorithms focus
on discovering and focusing and recom
binding good building blocks in the
highly paralyzed way and good solutions
are made up of building blocks of good
building blocks so i mean that's that's
basically the genetic algorithms and the
evolutionary algorithms is i'm going to
point them out I have some code that I
was going to show that was written I
wrote that's an example of genetic
programming which basically is an
implementation of genetic algorithms its
purpose is not to solve must make a
solution but to actually make a program
that is the best way to solve a problem
here does anybody have any questions
from that before i bring this up okay so
um basically what you see right here is
uh there's some initial variables things
like the crossover probability of the
mutation probability the maximum number
of generations the maximum chromosomes
we're going to have the maximum number
of programs because this is basically
building programs each chromosome is a
program made up of instructions now this
is simple this is a very simple example
because basically what we've got here is
a vm
that vm basically takes a show that real
quick that vm takes a very limited
amount of instructions as you can say
here it takes a dupe swap multiply add
and cross and over check to see if the
stacks over it just all those are the
only options that it takes so what we're
going to do is we're going to build a
program that this that uses this machine
right here to solve the problem and the
problem that we're going to solve or the
program the problem that we want to
solve is X cubed plus y squared plus Z
so very simple our fitness function is
going to be very simple as well that's
really meant to show you what we've got
so as you say we've got we've defined
our various variables I as you can see
here I've got what's called tier 1 tier
2 and tier 3 and Max fit and that's
basically going to be our fitness and
I'll show you the criteria that makes up
those there's those are not very
important so if you see main the first
thing that it's going to do is it's
going to do its Creed the setting up the
current population while we're before
while we're within our max generation
meaning where our number that we define
we're well we initialize the population
so take a quick look it's initialized
population basically we're saying we've
created a structure and we're creating
we're initializing each member of that
structure and right there and basically
it's just a part of a program is fitness
as length fairly simple ok so I'd
we initialize the population we perform
our fitness check for the first time and
then while we're during our generations
we perform selection do the fitness
check again a lot of printing of stuff
and that's pretty much it that's base
that's the fundamental of the of a
genetic algorithm now the important
things at this point are what are its
fitness is doing and how does it do its
selection first thing we'll look as the
fitness so the fitness check is
basically we create a random solution
for this X cubed Y squared plus one we
then take that we make an answer based
on that so we create a random solution
for it we just pop some numbers in there
we sent it to the virtual machine and we
get results back and our Fitness
basically says if we get nothing back
then this is not a very good fit if we
get one if we get a problem back but
it's um we get a problem back it's
possibly a pretty good to fit but if we
get the answer back that from this from
our random selected number of characters
then we know it's a good fit right and
then it again then it just goes through
revaluing the fitness and saving the
total fitness fairly simple once it once
it's finished function is as you can see
it's fairly simple because their promise
trailer simple but basically we defined
from telling it to run through this
machine how to make the solutions and
then the celexa selection criteria
here's the select process the select
parent let's say about this 222 it's all
pretty straightforward and then perform
reproduction we we have a cross point we
use a random
we use a random where the max is based
on the current population and the
program the program size add one then we
run through different types of the
different selection processes are
different selection points and then we
also have a mutate point where basically
we just run through it we do a random we
do a random number check again to make
sure we actually want to mutate if we do
then we do the mutation we increase
mutations and then the selection is
basically based as you can see right
there it just goes call it's like parrot
again and then form reproduction based
on up here again so what I don't
probably get it for you this is a
combination of mine in somebody else's
so I have to pull somebody else out of
it and put mine back in but I wasn't
fully done with it so um so uh did you
do plus I really wanted to be in Java
not see but I hate translating things
from c to java uh that's pretty much it
does anybody have any questions all
right well thank you very much oh yeah
good oh so you know I have to be honest
the biggest you know I've done secure in
my life but me learning genetic
algorithms had really nothing to his
security so when I thought about doing
this talk I talked with a couple of guys
as friends went from the ghetto hackers
and we were trying to figure out you
know what can we say was a good
application for security for this and
fried was very much like you don't have
to tell him any applications they can
figure on their own but I you know if
you do enough research you find one of
the big places this is being used is in
IDS's understanding IDs because
basically what one in ids is is I've got
a problem and I've got a whole lot of
rules I need to compare it to and how do
I do that do I just run through every
single one of them which would be an
exhaustive search basically or is there
a smarter way to go through these rules
and you know the calguns can tell
with that and there's or using
combination I've seen the music
accommodation was simulated annealing to
be able to do that so I don't have a I
was actually at one point thinking of
writing something that was a little more
security based but it was it was taking
too long but yeah that I mean that's
fundamentally IDS's I've seen it used in
crypt analysis a little bit when looking
through key spaces or something like
that anything else all right all right
well thank you very much thank you