last talk of the day before the free
booze the dancing girls zach is going to
talk about access control systems any
going to show you something very very
interesting about how they work and how
are all broken should I would like think
of it like land man for access control
yeah trust me it's it's broken okay so
what I'm going to do is I'm going to
give you a quick overview of access
control systems in general just so
you've got a bit of a backgrounder and
then I'm going to take you through some
credential technologies like protz cards
swipe cards some biometrics and there
are kind of basic workings so I'm not
going to go too deeply into how
fingerprint recognition algorithm
actually works but just an overview and
then we're going to actually start to
look it's a worked example of biometrics
how actually goes about doing it and
we'll take you through their rare common
floor okay so and by the way I do tend
to get ahead of it my mouth runs ahead
of my slides so you will probably see
this happening quite a lot okay so
here's a basic access control system
like you'd expect to see this reader
could be a swipe it could be prox it
could be a biometric reader like
fingerprint I traditionally in a basic
system like this you've got a single
access controller electric lock and
normally a push to exit button
occasionally you have other exit devices
such as passives mounted above the door
passive infrared sensor so that when you
walk up to the door it unlocks and that
could be a whole world of peeing in
itself because they're waving a bit of
underneath that will quite often just
pop the door slightly more sophisticated
systems actually have a local door
controller which talks to the access
control system quite often the access
control system simply pushes the
credentials ie the user IDs the card
number to the door controller which
remembers it in this situation we've got
what's mazzanti pass back so both sides
of the doors have readers so you acenta
Kate to get in and your scent Kate to
get out basically so you can't slide
your card back under the door and let
someone else in can be a problem because
occasionally it gets screwed up and you
get users that either can't get out or
can't get back in so not ideal ok so far
as physical tokens got we've got your
mag stripe card pretty common the white
gang card a little bit of data these
days but still used and going to places
like airports London Heath rooms ly gun
cart authenticated proc scarves which
we're all familiar with at bottom
ferrite card now this was the original
card key they're not really used that
much these days i concealed barcode card
which we'll get to in a minute smart
cards and we'll start with our concealed
barcode card it is as crappy as it
sounds
basically yeah you have a barcode and
then you have a ir translucent material
that just looks like a black stripe
along the bottom of the card hold it up
to any bright light and you will see the
barcode put a bright light above the
barcode on a scanner and you'll just be
able to image the barcode right off it
is fucking embarrassing so basically if
you find anyone that's ever implemented
one of these systems I suggest that do
you fire them and then shoot them so
they don't infect anyone else so Mike
stripes again we're all pretty familiar
with normally three tracks I two types
of cards so you've got high coercivity
cards and low coercivity cards so
basically how much magnetic energy it
takes to actually align the particles on
the card so credit cards typically our
local things like your cal state
driver's license is a high coercivity
card so you can't just pop it through a
regular reader writer and write that you
need a special high coercivity I card
writer I expose head in the reader which
means it's yeah possible quite easily
actually and there are certain high
security cards the hotel lot in this
hotel are considered by the manufacturer
to be high security now you'd be
surprised so basically that means that
in general a regular card reader writer
won't be able to duplicate them but that
can simply be as easy as just adjusting
the track offset so the tracks don't
line up where they would normally do on
an iso standard card and they also use
slightly different modulation techniques
so it by no means high
high security it's certainly
duplicatable but just not by your
standard card reader writer the max max
rights basically use a protocol called
clock and data which is pretty simple
you've got your your clock pulses along
the top your data pulses along the
bottom the presence of a a one or a zero
with a clock pulse indicates your data
stream this is actually a bit of my Visa
card actually they're only a small bit
here's a dad no significant digits there
but but you can clearly see there's your
your clock along the top and your
database along the bottom but in faerie
carbs not really used that much anymore
the where the original card key card so
it tends to be an insertion leader but
I've seen readers where you hold the
card up against a little metal plate I
and it has what you could only describe
as a fridge magnet inside which has
these discrete magnetic domains so
basically if you have a bit paper and
you pour iron filings over that's that's
what you're going to see and the
original car key as I mentioned why gun
cards a little bit more interesting
there is a special wire which is
actually coaxial on my special forging
and has this magical Wiegand effect
which everyone thought was really cool
at the time and non duplicatable of
course they never really thought you
could just take an existing wide young
card when we order the bits but a so
basically if you look at the card you'll
see little bits of wire embedded in it
and so that's pattern just remember it
because we're going to be seeing a lot
of it
and basically the top Brewers ones the
bottom row zeros or either way it
doesn't matter I that's what carb looks
like that's what it looks like when you
hold up to the light so you can clearly
see the wires embedded in the card and
basically what the why kind effect is is
when you wave your special bit of wire
and wire to past a magnet in it which is
polarized in a particular direction it
charges up with magnetic field and when
you wave it next to our oppositely
polarized magnet it dumps its charge and
if you happen to have a convenient
little coil nearby you can actually read
that pulse and that's all that's
happening when you swipe your card
through the reader there's two magnets
for each rule one charges the wire the
other discharges it next to a little
coil so once you swipe your card what
you actually get is that the wide and
electrical protocol there's basically
three wires a data one wire a data zero
wire and a ground wire and these tiny
little pulses are effectively what you'd
see as you swipe the card cool down
through the reader so you've got to your
binary one here it's 40 micro second dip
and there's a 2 milli second gap between
the the next pulse then your 40 micro
second dip and then a 2 milli second gap
and that's that's it's really quite
simple there is quite a lot of variance
in that the particular reader but i have
here happens to do this some i've seen
this be as high as a hundred
microseconds hear it it's a it's quite
flexible as a protocol so this is
actually what it looks like when you if
you hook it up to a logic analyzer and
you
run a card through it doesn't happen to
me this card but as you can see you know
it's identical pretty much this is
important so you need to remember
because this is what we're going to be
looking out later the next thing we've
got is the Y and format so generally if
you go out into a store and say oh I
want our a white guy and prox card it
will probably be 26 bits they'll ask you
oh what facility called would you like
and that's ranges from 0 to 255 and then
they'll give you a range of carbs which
you can specify quite often so it's
actually 24 bits because you've got a
parity bit at the beginning a parity bit
at the end and that's what makes up a
wide and ID they will manufacturers of
cards will quite often say right I'll
tell you what we've got this super
secure version which is actually 36 bits
and we don't sell the site codes to
everyone what will give you your own
site board and we won't sell it to
anyone else so just remember when you're
buying your 26 bit card quite often
there's a there's a chance your
next-door neighbor might have the same
facility good and therefore might have
duplicate cards prox card which we're
all aware of their passive so it takes
its energy from the reader and basically
pairs carved up and the carb bars back a
data stream and it does it this when you
hold our plots card up to the light it
looks exactly like that you think
there's a little strip of wire wire for
wire antenna in there and a chip
actually it's a coil of a bazillion
terms of the finest wire you will ever
see
so basically it pairs up it's
magnetically coupled and it bars back a
data stream it takes five hundred and
six bits across the ear interface to
hand over a single 26 bit ID so there's
a lot of redundancy in it okay don't get
prox cards on rfid cards people use the
term interchangeably they're not
proximity cards are magnetically coupled
they've got to be close to the reader
enabled from for them to work I and
basically when it's transmitting the
data back what it actually does is it
shorts its own coil it's got a tiny
capacitor in there to kind of keep it
alive it shorts its own coil load which
is effectively killing its own power
source but it causes a tiny volts drop
in the coil that's actually powering it
in the reader and that's how it actually
singles signals back so basically
through this magnetic coupling RFID
cards basically our true little radio
transmitters they take a radio signal
and typically they transmit the response
on a different frequency tends to be
half the frequency that's used to
energize it
okay see what I said about my mouse
running ahead of us late okay contact
with smart cards in my view the way to
go I there tend to have the tent of
decent crypto screens the authenticate
the reader so if you have a standard
prox card reader it will read pretty
much anyone prox card of that frequency
so you can you know stand behind them in
the street and you can read the data off
their car with contactless smart cards
is at least some authentication you
can't do that i will get into there's a
bit of a problem with someone we'll get
into that in a minute so i'm going to
give you a quick rundown of biometrics I
there's my favorite and this is by far
my favorite the retina scan hey iris
scans which are really popular than news
at the moment new one that's coming out
which is a venial hand map I hand
geometry another perennial favorite mine
and the old fingerprint so fingerprints
are simply a capture and compared to
technologies in general yes optical and
your semiconductor capacitive sensors
I'm not too keen on there but I'm not
too keen on either of them simply
because the semiconductor one can be
very easily damaged by static
electricity it is literally a single
semiconductor field and so you can zap
that one really easily easily defeated
as we all know gummy bears like
photocopies silicon fingerprints it's
they're not about hard the important
thing is that they're all images so
generally this is what our fingerprint
breakdown looks like and the technology
depending on which algorithm is using
will look for particular things so
it might map all the ridge endings in
your finger but it might look for
bifurcations or islands and everyone has
their own scheme there is no kind of
standard way for recognizing
fingerprints which means some vendors
technologies might be far more secure
than others and geometry scanners I
actually have a few of these simply
because they're they're quite easy to
use the not foolproof again it's just an
image capture this is actually quite a
nice image of thoughtless devices
actually capturing and the smart guys
added a 45 degree murder in its field of
view so no they can claim it's a 3d hand
hand geometry scanner because it it
takes a side profile I thought yeah well
I thought it was quite a nice hacked but
still the marketing department got hold
of it's like yeah yes no hanky 3d venial
hand scans which I hadn't actually had a
chance to play with I pretty cool it
takes an infrared image of your palm
I've seen seen them do it with hand
geometry scanners as well where it's
doing both a hand geometry and a venal
hand map and apparently someone's come
out with a finger venial map which I'm
not sure how many veins on the end of my
finger but here apparently enough
according to them we'll see but again
the important thing is it's just an
image capture and that's where all
biometric sent to end up with so your
iris scan again just an image but the
skinny thing is potential for what by
capture I I think that's this particular
unit you used to have to spend a lot
time aligning yourself which is a
problem with all biometrics as alignment
and they came up with this little
scanner that you don't actually have to
spend edges messing around with tulane
yourself so you just kind of glanced at
it it recognizes your pupils and takes
the scan from that my fave retina
scanner one of the more secure ones it's
quite hard to steal credential because
basically you have to get up close and
personal it's hard to use I mean
literally when I say you've got to be
trained how to use a retina scanner you
do it's easy to to screw up even if you
know what you're doing manufacturer went
bust bit of a bummer but I did snap up
to them for seventy six bucks on eBay
which was very nice okay so I'm going to
use this as a a good example of how
biometrics work in general so first of
all the user enters code on the reader
any biometric technology that says hey
my voice is my passport recognized me is
doomed to failure never ever ever
implement it basically what you want to
do is you want to match up a template a
known template that's been recorded by
your security administrator with you so
normally it starts off with you entering
a cord on the reader and on a retina
scanner it displays a target a visual
dot the older ones had an array of nice
little line of green dots that went into
infinity and you can have lined them up
so you could only see one the newer ones
I'd like the one picture there has a
little green dot which you superimpose
over an orange lot
here's a tip ever using your retina
scanner put your finger on the scan
button before you line up because you're
going to need to press it yourself so
you're looking to you write this you
sugar your header end to your you're
only saying you're seeing your is only
senior single door or your your little
green door is spot on over your orange
blob and you press the Scan button and
then you freeze because a retina scanner
actually takes a little bit of time to
capture under a second but it's like
don't move incidentally I got my first
retina scanner from abyss that was a
standalone access control system for a
Hanford which manufactures weapons-grade
plutonium so you'd scan who scan sorry
and when you step back to find out what
happened the booth would actually we you
and if you were heavier coming out than
you were going in the door stayed a lot
in fact both stores doors stayed a lot I
I did the boys with a gun scheme so not
that easy and they all have a variance
factor because everyone changes look a
little bit you know I have the staff
here gorge themselves on Krispy Kremes
this afternoon tomorrow there will be
slightly larger and that changes things
all of a sudden bits and pieces that the
biometric expects to be in one place
slightly further apart I if you load up
on water again things change if your
head is slightly oh you weren't quite
standing quite straight you're a slight
slightly angled again different so they
all have a fudge factor you never match
your biometric one hundred percent and
quite often when you look
these these readers if you've got
slightly more sophisticated device I
when you scan yourself it will give you
a score as to how closely you match your
ideal biometric that it recorded and the
systems administrators can tweak that so
you can see right well if you get within
thirty percent it's okay but you know 35
isn't sometimes there can be a lot of
villians because people don't know what
they're doing basically when they're
setting these systems up and again that
the stricter you make it the more
rejects you're going to get with people
trying to ascend to gate and feeling so
here's a retina and imagine that I just
looked into my retina scanner and I've
aligned my little dots press the red
button and what happens because it scans
up a circle round my retina which is
effectively what I retina scan actually
is what happens is it takes that image
it flattens it out and but as it parses
it it notices that here oh it got a
little bit darker here oh I'm here and
here and here and here and here and here
surprisingly enough on the original
retina scanners the credential was 360
bits long I did start hashing this on
later later models but it just just
shows you it's like how are we going to
do this these people you think are
really really smart aren't quite that
smart you think oh well if he's designed
a written identification system
got to be great but maybe not so my fave
I have to say if certain problems
alignment it's totally subjective so we
just skip back to that that spot that
sport may be optically just where I
dropped it on on this image I've said oh
it's going to be in the center but with
you it might not be the center of your
retina Center your retina just might be
here as far as you're concerned in your
in your view so when you see movies
where someone pops someone's eyeball out
and holds it up to the retina scanner
totally totally totally bogus because a
even if they could align it so that the
the target ends up spot-on in the center
of the retina it might not be the center
of the retina as that user perceives it
as they aligned it when they were
registering it with the system so almost
like having a brain print because
basically it's how your brain how that
the neurons whining the retina to your
brain actually decided it was going to
that was going to be the center again
you've got your fudge factor and ID's
end up as a hash which is not always a
good thing so false acceptance rate I
people that really care about this are
of the military ie they really don't
want they'd rather we had the false
rejection rate was high E someone didn't
match their valid scan than to have a
high false acceptance rate where someone
that shouldn't be allowed then suddenly
is and again they're all coupled with
the user ID so bit of a problem with
biometrics
how do you revolt your credentials which
is not nearly as bad as the red bit of a
problem it's like Oh someone's
duplicated my retina what am I going to
do I well you're screwed basically so
there is a bit of a catch and it's about
backwards compatibility really and also
market forces the great market force why
and why gang card the bollocks these are
the most secure things ever when they
came out you know back in the 60s 70s
and all the access control manufacturer
said right we warn your white guy and
came out they didn't make access control
systems they made the cards and the
readers so basically everyone wanted to
interface with white gang breeders and
they still do so everything we saw
everything we've just talked about from
the retina scanner down to your standard
proc swipe the all used Wiegand
electrical whine and electrical protocol
the wiegand data protocol to signal back
to the controller and that's a little
bit of a problem it's plain face pretty
much it's easily intercepted is even
easily more easily replayed you've got
your output from biometrics and includes
the output from your strong crypto
readers a lot of them have white guy at
bit on the bag some smarter
manufacturers are starting to move away
from this but it's a huge problem so the
goal of my little project was to record
widened IDs and to replay them and to be
small because basically it needs to
intersect the physical wiring guy in the
reader I'd be easily installable and to
be cheap would be nice
problems well once it's in there how do
I actually control it how do I get get
it to replay IDs how did I make sure
that the the idea i'm seeing is actually
good and if i want to get the data out
of the device how do i actually do it
again don't want the wires hanging about
so basically this is what a reader
standard reader would look like you've
got to your positive and negative which
is dead handy because it gives me / and
then you've got the data one and data 0
lines which are transmitting the actual
Wiegand data and quite often you've got
an LED which is driven by the access
control system that just basically makes
the school green when your load access
so this is gecko it's really small and
it's really cheap and it uses command
carbs so basically it has its own little
set that is its own tiny access control
systems on it's a little set of cards
that knows to look out for it uses the
access allowed led this one doesn't but
the v2 one does to to actually say oh I
just seen a wide an ID go past or and
the access allowed led went on so it's a
good good card and actually again this
coming in v2 it uses the access to load
it led to get the data out of the reader
because i'm using a pic chip for this
and they're quite handy so i can say in
five you're an output pin and you're
totally driving that led oh you're no
serial port 9600 bits per second it one
nor and here have this stuff to send so
basically I have a little optical
reader that you hold over to the LED you
swipe your dump card and it will just
read out its entire contents of memory
and it just places in like this it's
really small this has quick connects so
basically I video man if you're about
I'm going to pass these are these are
artists renditions but basically is it
physically they're identical to this so
I'm going to pass a few out and you just
pass them around so that people can
actually kind of see what we're actually
dealing with here I so I'm going to give
you a quick demo standard disclaimer
applies if locks is in the room please
leave no because he's been drinking my
demo all weekend so I'm seeing right now
it's not going to work but just in case
it does I'm going to take all the credit
for it
so here is oh nice thing is is here's
the actual device I'm talking about it
and this was my artist rendition before
I started and it's actually just a
little bit smaller so this is a tiny
tiny tiny little access control system
you got your reader and as I said this
particular one doesn't monitor the LEDs
I so that's what this yellow line is
this is simply to drive the LED on the
reader and here we have our power and
our data zero and data ones so it
recognizes to users oops you see that's
the lock effect so user Adam and users
AG and a bad user is denied so what
we're going to do is we'll just pop our
device in as you can see from the units
being passed around there quick connects
are open so literally is as easy as
cutting the wires and just crimping them
in all these readers tend to have
pigtails or rather than connectors so
it'd be easy to also the connectors are
the single largest thing here that the
pic chip in here is an 18 pin dil
picture in a socket so it's huge
compared to what it could be if I went
surface meant it would be a lot smaller
and it would be completely completely
dwarfed by the connectors
so users ack user Adam bad user just to
use a sack again here we parking yes and
now I have a card here which previously
wouldn't work this isolation i knew i
was missing something keep telling you I
run ahead of myself so I have three
other cards here which I didn't show you
if I will know and we'll just leave them
here the moment so bad user user Adam
and user Zach the cards on this side
nope so they're all not recognized for
this access control system
believe it or not quite a lot don't
actually bother monitoring and it's as
simple as holding lines high when you're
connecting it so bed of nails you just
hold the lines hi there's nothing
there's nothing smart happening here I
one of my favorite access control
systems is actually manufactured by
harsh it's a system I use and it uses
courts strong crypto to talk to it sir
it's its readers I it is likely to sport
things like that I because it's
constantly talking to the readers but
basically no one else does that you know
they're just sitting there lines are
down okay so bring it back up so we have
a bad user reviews or Adam we have user
Zach and then we have our previous card
which didn't work which is this one here
oh dear this card is the replay card now
there are none of the two cards here
this one here for example quite handy it
didn't work for a reason because here's
user Zach and user Adam
but use a replay so we'll use our magic
enable card let them back in so now use
of Zack so basically there's a whole
raft of of Handy other things you can do
this was a this was a pic so i have a
dump card which will dump stuff out to
the LED i have some program cards so i
have a program i have an end program and
i have a1 and a0 so you literally can go
program 1 0 1 0 0 0 0 1 and and get your
ID in there so it did work this is what
happens when you look at the protocol
analyzer and you can see that the this
is the ID of the card that was actually
swiped the last few bites are bits
should I say and you can see that the
card that's transmitted to the reader is
completely different I albeit not that
different because I happen to use all my
cards in the same batch but they're so
the scary thing is is it took 12 hours
to do it was literally that simple
included learning the IDE and how to
program pegs which isn't hard at all not
when you write it in six key a big basic
I it's got a very basic feature set and
you've seen their disabled vary from to
which I'm working on at the moment these
pictures
either have either there's a whole range
of them they've got different features
some have got built an eeprom most of
them have got built-in flash I they
check the validity of the card by
monitoring the the reader LED so there's
a slightly / one here which is our
another connector on the top which
intersects this led line I that's my fav
is serial port line 5 clock the data out
and it will load the data via the
command carbs version 3 i'm using a
bluetooth interface i just take the
larger positive i'm obviously have no
way to control it that's not a good way
of doing it and then they're from for
that little guy is stem fun so this is
the GSM antenna I this is a gps antenna
and it is fully programmable in Python I
and the cost about fifty bucks so so
yeah there's lots and lots and lots and
lots of fun to be had now as for these
readers I basically were you screwed by
two screws for plastic cover because
basically that's literally all it takes
two screws so that about wraps it up
hope you enjoyed it and you're rocking
so does anyone have any questions sorry
the fuck well I'm quite decided if I'm
going to release it or not because it
was so easy to do I mean it is
criminally you should learn how to do
this pic chips are fabulous I it's I
mean is it's not hard in any way shape
or form I this this little circuit here
has some supporting hardware like a
little crystal to give that the chip its
timing the only reason I did it on this
one is because I happen to have a pic
lying around that didn't have an
internal clock I mean literally
everything's their Hardware serial ports
built in there really really easy to use
shockingly so I mean if I can do this in
12 hours and I generally I'm not known
for my coding I anyone can
anything else well the problem is is
it's not there isn't a vendor that is
that's the same thing it's just couple
of pulses going down two wires so it's a
bit of a problem everyone I mean most of
these readers have no frame if you buy
an alarm device like a passive or I even
a little junction box it will have a
tamper switch built into it as you know
as part of the device not one of these
readers I've ever looked at has any form
of tamper switch at all some of the
biometric devices do but they're worth
stealing I I spoke to some locksmith and
they said oh well it's easy you just put
tamper-proof screws in so it'll be
really obvious when you destroy it
taking off the wall and I'm like okay so
I destroy taking off the wall they're
like 20 bucks on eBay I'll just put a
new one back in the other thing the only
thing it does raise is this particular
manufacturer who are born name I has has
its own command carbs so when you pair
one of these readers up for five minutes
it goes into you can program me Maude
and it has its own little set of command
cards surprisingly enough I so I've got
a card that will turn the beep on and
off I don't want my beep to beep boom we
have a card doesn't beep anymore so how
do you know that this feature isn't
already in your readers because hell if
I had access to to their microcode it
certainly would be so you know how much
do you actually hire actually much the
actually trust your access control
vendors you know with their I shouldn't
really mention this to some people with
rampant paranoia but it's like yeah it
could very very easily be compromised
already I some keypad readers use why
games some are really dumb and they just
have a contact closure on the back so
some some keypad readers are actually
kind of smart they talk Wiegand to
back-end access control system and some
are just literally locally programmed
and if you actually were able to get
behind the keypad you could just short
out there I the contacts that would
actually open the lock well if you had
to look at the ones I that are floating
about all you have to do is cut four
wires poke them in the end there crimp
poke them in the ends and crimp and
that's it pressive yeah plus I could
take you know how long does it take you
to take a light switch out of its socket
put it back in well now you what you
want to put it back but I mean that all
of these can have fits down dorje boxes
just when you walk around the place have
a look and see how many of these are
sitting guarding doors with you know no
camera back up there just you know
sitting in the back of an alley
yeah yeah art do it in the day just say
oh I'm here too I I told one of my mates
about you said hope he just put a
manufacturers label on it just call it
Tara filter or yeah all depends when and
where the readers are I mean the classic
place is the is is smokers corner right
in the back every building has one
especially in California it's like and
in the UK now as well so there's a yeah
there's going to be a door it's good
it's going to have a reader on it and
yeah it's going to be in some little
place because they don't really want
people to see all the smokers I yeah I
say it's a classic there's just have a
walk around and have a look and see how
many exposed readers there are
this is a pic and it's a 6 16 f 627 I
and it is just one pic and the
connectors yeah it is that embarrassing
so some of the this reader and most
readers will do from 5 to 12 volts if it
is a 12-volt system the signaling always
goes back certainly in my experience at
five so you may have to I add in a
little voltage regulator so you don't
fry your pic but they're the size you
know TOS package their size of a
transistor so hard way well incidentally
this this is timed down to the
nanosecond and my timings are actually
better they're more accurate than the
reader itself just a little bit but
they're more accurate and if I actually
made my device slightly larger that
included a little slot ceramic resonator
clocked it slightly faster I could make
even more deadly accurate still so I
mean I the only kind of hardware used to
develop this was it was a programmer
sorry hey you just use a u.s. use bed of
nails a halt to hold the voltage up the
signals signals each bit is it dropping
it drops for a bit so it so its standard
state is held high so you just hold it
high while you're doing the install I
and Norma's going to be an advisor I
mean pic programmer 50 bucks looks like
that and actually just a little logic
analyzer to get the timings perfect but
sir that is the same one you used and
this one was about 300 bucks but
basically you can get really really
really cheap only I mean this decides
like 34 ports you can get you know one
or two port logic analyzers are little
USB scopes really cheaply as well so if
no expensive at all yeah but the thing
is it's it's really really close to the
end and it's it's not it doesn't look
like a tat because it's actually
intercepting the signal and terminating
it effectively so I mean no doubt if you
are actually actively looking for this
stuff then it may be possible to detect
it but the bottom line is i 90 are
heavily MC ninety i'd say probably
ninety eight percent of access control
systems don't even bother this stuff
absolutely I mean obviously putting at
the G box I mean if you if you're
outside a building then I accessing that
door is kind of number one I once you're
in then I mean you could read it read
out the data I there are other devices
for calling cards so rather than trying
to find users it would be quite easy to
install one of these that the XR one of
the external readers just read a whole
bunch of carbide ease and then once
you've got them just emulate the carbs
well quad-core quite called quite often
sorry this this is generally mounted on
the outside so I'd be at the service
entrance it how long does it take to pop
the cover off two screws you cut crimp
primp so I i would say three minutes or
under yeah I mean I if you practice you
could probably do it really quickly
one of one of the problems with this is
people think that that the actual
security is in the card not in
what'swhat's going back and forth so
they made no attempt to really secure I
mean if it was me it would be you know
tamper switch to hell I would be talking
crypto from here or ideally from the
card back to the access control system
sadly no sorry I don't normally use just
shielded cat5 cat6 cable I yeah and and
some some places will do if it's
particularly exposed but again you know
two screws in a plastic color that's
that's what stopped you getting behind
the reader any more questions then I
commend you to the bar