we have emily hacker and she is going to
tell us about avoiding
murky waters uh clear threat
intelligence communications
and watercolor painting so i'm very
excited for both those topics
thank you for joining us today emily i
really appreciate you being here
thanks leslie my name is emily hacker
and today i'm going to talk to you about
how to avoid murky waters
both in threat intelligence
communications and in watercolor
painting
so to start let me tell you a little bit
about myself um
as i said my name is emily hacker and uh
yeah that is my real name
i'm a threat intelligence analyst at
microsoft and i've been in the industry
for about six years
i started out as a technical writer on
an intelligence team
and i did that for about a year and a
half before i formally transitioned into
threat intelligence analysis
so i have the perspective both from an
analysis background and a communications
background prior to microsoft i worked
um
for a security vendor as a security
researcher and before that
i worked as an intelligence analyst for
an oil and gas company
which is the same place where i got my
start as a tech writer
if anyone has any questions for me later
um you can find me on twitter as
at dreadphones
for my security focus topic today i want
to talk
about how to produce clear threat
intelligence communications
communication is a vital aspect of
intelligence
in fact intelligence cannot exist
without communication
but in the cyber threat intelligence
industry i have
found a lot of resources for people to
learn about the technical aspects of the
job
and the majority of people that i have
worked with have a technical background
but i've noticed there's far fewer
resources for people that have that tech
aspect of the job down
but want to learn more about the
communications aspect
some people refer to communication as a
soft skill
but i want to challenge that notion i'm
not really sure what the opposite of a
soft skill is
but i think we can all agree that
writing and communicating can be really
hard
um how many of us have ever opened up a
word document to write a report about
the latest malware strain that's
affecting our industry
only to kind of just stare at it blankly
not even sure where to start
or how many of us have ever read a blog
posted online about a new threat
only to finish it with more questions
than we started with
clearly communicating intelligence to
key stakeholders is important and it
shouldn't be written off as a soft skill
to start off let's define the difference
between a news report and an
intelligence report
and just to clarify i'm not knocking
news reports i actually have a degree in
journalism and i started my adult life
working at a small city newspaper
there is a hugely important role that
the news plays in our industry
but it's a different role than that of
intelligence
so what role does the news play
um to put it simply the role of news is
to inform
a lot of times this is done in a
somewhat purposefully generic way
um as the audience of a news report will
vary hugely in background
industry skill level interest level
some news reports can include some
generic mitigations uh for example a
news report about
patch tuesday might include the generic
recommendation of
patch but for the most part a news
article you will read
is just gonna let you know what is going
on
an intelligence report should take this
a step further an intelligence report is
still informing the audience about the
thing that's happening
but what sets an intelligence report
apart from a news report
is that it helps decision makers make
decisions and that's what intelligence
boils down to
to do this an intelligence report needs
to contain
actionable information and while we're
on the topic i will bring up a phrase
that many of us have likely heard which
is
actionable intelligence i bring this up
because i don't
want to hear this phrase again if
intelligence isn't actionable it is just
information
not intelligent secondly
intelligence reports need to include
tailored information
mitigations and next steps this is
critical for the
help decision makers make decision
aspects of intelligence
i can already predict some people maybe
maybe pushing back on the statement so
i'm going to pre-clarify
by tailored i don't necessarily mean
written for one specific company or one
specific recipient
i don't mean that every intelligence
vendor should write a different report
for each of their clients with
information about how
trick bot or whatever has affected them
what i do mean is that a report should
be as specific as is required for the
audience
if you're an embedded intelligence
analyst working with a sock
this likely does mean that you need to
tailor your report
um to just your company don't write
about emote
in general write about whether it's
affected your industry
or write about an incident that you saw
in your own telemetry
this also means that you need to include
tailored recommendations to help make
decisions
are there specific security controls
that your organization should enforce
to help stop this threat from affecting
you should incident responders put in
blocks for specific indicators that
you're seeing
if you are a vendor this probably does
look a little bit different but it
doesn't mean you aren't still writing
tailored
intelligence part of what sets a vendor
like crowdstrike or microsoft or
proofpoint or any of the myriad other
intelligence providers apart from a
security news blog
is our ability to tailor our reports
with internal data and telemetry
we can write specifically about how
we've seen threats used
what we've seen them lead to what the
consequences have been for other
companies and importantly what our own
customers should do to avoid the same
fate
whether you're an embedded analyst or a
vendor
after your intended audience reads your
report they should walk away
understanding both the threat to their
organization and what actions they need
to take
in order to make sure um that people
understand your report there's an easy
formula of questions that you should be
answering
what is the threat what is the potential
impact and what do they need to do about
it
for the first question you're answering
what is the threat and to do this you're
describing what is happening or you're
informing the user and this
aspect of your report is actually very
similar to a news report in a lot of
ways
which is why reading the news is
actually so helpful for intelligence
analysis
when you're describing the threat make
sure that you don't just
mention a malware family name for
example because malware by itself
isn't a threat because it doesn't have
you know intent or
opportunity really an example of an
answer to this question
could be something along the lines of
our organization has recently seen a
surge in incidents related to trickbot
trickbot was originally defined as a
banking trojan but has evolved over time
to become
a prolific modular malware that can be
modified to suit the attacker's specific
needs it is frequently delivered via
malicious emails or is dropped by other
malware variants especially emote that
was a pretty vague
answer to that question but depending on
the length of the report i might add
more for the audience but you get the
idea of how you would describe the
threat
the next question to answer is what is
the potential impact from this threat
and this can be a mix both of things
that you have seen in your own internal
telemetry
and stuff that's been reported from
other organizations
for example for trickbot using that
example again you may not have seen it
leading to
ryuk in your own organization but that's
still a potential impact so it would be
worth mentioning in your report
however if you have seen trickbot in
your own organization
leading to cobalt strike or hands-on
keyboard activity and data exfiltration
you would want to include that as well
and make it clear that that's already
impacting you
for example you could say while trickbot
can be used in a variety of ways
we have seen attackers leveraging their
foothold from trickbot in our
organization
to deploy cobalt strike beacons and
perform reconnaissance and it's likely
they will attempt exultation of data
in addition trickbot has been widely
reported to lead to ransomware
especially rio
the final question to answer in your
report
is what should the audience do about the
threat and the answer to the question
will vary depending on who the audience
of your report is
which i'll talk about in my next slide
but in general it's important for your
audience to walk away from the report
knowing what steps they need to take do
they need to block certain iocs
patch of vulnerability hunt in their own
environment for a certain type of
malware or certain threat
make large organizational changes such
as group policies to disallow
entire threat vectors even though the
length
and audience of a report may vary widely
answering at minimum these three
questions will help your audience
understand your intelligence report
a lot more than them trying to glean
those answers as they're
reading it buried amongst all the other
data in your report
in fact for longer reports i recommend
having an introductory section
or a summary section at the beginning
that answers these three questions
before you move on to a larger technical
analysis or more details
so this brings me to my next point which
is audience
if i am a vaccine scientist writing a
scholarly peer-reviewed
research article about my latest
findings i'm going to write
those findings a lot differently than if
i'm writing them for an article in the
new york times
the same logical is true for
intelligence communications different
audiences
need different types of information
amounts of data and levels of detail
let's say you're an embedded analyst who
has just heard about a new malware
threat to your industry
a report to your incident response team
may just include a brief summary of the
threat
and a list of iocs to block maybe
depending on how quickly they need to
react
a report to your ciso regarding the same
threat is likely going to look
a lot different than that a list of
hashes probably isn't
really helpful or interesting to them
what they want to understand
is the impact to the organization and
what next steps need to be taken by
the larger security organization
if you're a vendor you are probably
often writing reports that will go to a
wide variety of audiences
it might include other intelligence
analysts management threat hunters
incident responders
and you can't write a different report
for each one of these recipients
what you can do however is have
different reports sections
start each report with an executive
summary that is enough information for
management
which means you'll want to include some
recommendations in your
executive summary and then you can
include longer technical
analysis after that for recipients who
are maybe also
you know other intelligence analysts or
threat hunters and then
specific iocs or specific hunting
queries can be included
in a technical appendix for only the
audiences
that actually really need those for
their job
by organizing your report this way your
recipients can read only the sections
that pertain to them
without shuffling through your entire
report looking desperately for the part
that they actually care about
and last but definitely not least about
audience
i want to touch on responding to rfis
which are requests for intelligence
and getting feedback on your reports
since the purpose of intelligence is
communicating it to other teams
it's critically important that those
teams understand
and find value in your reports make sure
to develop relationships with the
audiences of your report
ask them to provide feedback for how
they'd like to see changes going forward
set up rfi processes with key
stakeholders
so you can ensure that you're going to
be writing about the subjects that they
actually need to learn about
intelligence is only valuable if your
audience understands it
so make sure that they do
so far i've talked a lot about reports
but i want to take a moment to define
all of the different ways that
intelligence reports
can take form any time that you're
communicating information about a threat
its impact and what how it can be dealt
with i'd argue that you're sharing
intelligence
in written form we do most commonly
think of this as an intelligence report
we probably have these get sent to us
from vendors or we see them posted
online
we might have to write these ourselves
and they take a lot of time and a lot of
research and they
probably involve several layers of
editing hence how i got my start in the
industry
but that's not the only form of written
intelligence how many of us have ever
pivoted on something in our
own environment that we found on twitter
i certainly use twitter for intelligence
i often will see tweets that are along
the lines of
hey i'm seeing a phishing campaign using
teams lures to get users to click on a
credential phishing link
the senders are using gmail accounts and
the subject lines all contain
new message for you and it'll probably
contain a screenshot of the email a lot
of times
and there you go that's intelligence
what's the threat
a fake team's phishing campaign what's
the potential impact loss of credentials
what are the next steps to take search
your environment for emails that match
those
details another type of written
intelligence of prop
um a lot of us probably do but don't
really think about as much
are incident write-ups anytime you're
documenting your investigation for an
incident
you're documenting intelligence keep
that in mind when you're doing write-ups
and consider how helpful you're being
for
yourself the next time you face the same
threat i have certainly been guilty of
feeling
rushed and writing my incident right ups
really fast thinking that nobody's ever
gonna see that nobody really cares but
me
and then two months later the similar
threat impacts my organization again and
i come back to thinking
wait a minute like how did i deal with
this last time how did i find all the
affected machines what did we do about
this
writing that information down the first
time will help your team and your own
future sanity intelligence
doesn't have to be written down though
in order to be
intelligence verbal intelligence is just
as important
and this could take the form of maybe a
vendor call to a customer letting them
know about a threat
that's impacting their industry this
could be kind of in the same way as a
report but
in verbal form or maybe it's a call with
other industry analysts
if you're on a call with those analysts
and you hear someone say
we've been seeing a lot of ice id lately
that's not
really all that helpful but if you hear
them say we've been seeing a lot of ice
id coming in through email leading to
hands-on keyboard beta exfiltration it's
a lot more helpful especially when they
follow it up with indicators
or ttps or something that you can
actually pivot on
even the dreaded management presentation
is an important form of intelligence
in one of my previous roles we had to
give a monthly intelligence presentation
to upper management
and while i dreaded it because it was
nerve-wracking it was admittedly
one of the most impactful methods we had
to enact change
these presentations didn't just include
information on what we were seeing
but recommendations on what actions
management should be taking to protect
the company
combined with data from multiple
incidents and how the change would
impact the organization
management was able to walk away
equipped to make a decision and
sometimes those decisions would cut off
entire entry vectors that had been
plaguing us for months
stuff like that really highlights the
value of intelligence
if you can tell your audience what the
threat is how it impacts your org
and what they should be doing about it
you can help defend against malicious
activity
so we just talked a lot about a bunch of
different forms of reports and you may
have
noticed that they would have varied a
lot and what kind of content you would
include in those
different forms of communication and
that makes sense because intelligence
isn't a one-size-fits-all
approach different intelligence teams do
different types of work
and therefore produce different reports
i've heard
different terms for these three types of
intelligence um and people might think
of these differently
but these are the ones that have
resonated with me that i've seen
reflected in my daily jobs
but it's the concept behind the terms
that are important so i'll talk about
them
the first type of intelligence report
that i want to talk about is one that
is a tactical report these reports are
oftentimes going to be related to an
ongoing incident or an investigation and
might be sent to your sock or your ir
team
to help them in their remediation
efforts
a lot of times these reports are going
to need to be sent out
pretty quickly so you aren't going to
have the luxury of spending weeks
doing research looking at evidence
crafting your message going through
editing
um they're usually just going to take
the form of a few sentences that answer
your three
critical questions what is the threat
what is the impact what do they need to
do about it
and then that's kind of it there might
include a list of iocs or something as
well
if you're an embedded analyst you might
find yourself needing to send out this
type of
report a lot so it's probably helpful to
have a quick report template
that just basically outlines those three
questions for you to answer
and get sent off as is
the next type of report is an
operational report
this is kind of actually where i live
currently in my current job so i can
talk about this one a lot
um and it's kind of the bridge between
tactical and strategic so
it's more than like a one-off incident
but you're not necessarily detailing an
entire actor's
activities this may look like a report
about how a specific malware variant was
observed during a few months period of
time
it prob it it probably will be
including a lot of information from
multiple incidents so not just one
and it would include the various
infection vectors and kill chain
from those incidents but it's not going
to go into detail
about every way that malware has been
used over the course of history
or necessarily who the operator of that
malware is
what is still important though are those
three questions that
i've talked about a little bit too much
probably now um those questions can
still be answered
but this report will probably be more
detailed in a tactical report and
include more research
and it'll probably take a little bit
longer to publish if it has to go
through
a editing process or a review process
strategic reports are the highest level
report and that they
cover a lot of information the
the now famous mandy and apt-1 report is
an example of a strategic report
it covered the actor who they were
working for
where they worked um what types of
threats they had been using what their
goals were so on
it didn't really detail a single
incident or necessarily a single
campaign it was a much higher overview
of the actor
now if you are an embedded analyst you
might be thinking that
an apt-1 report isn't really something
that is
in your purview given how much time and
dedicated research effort
is required to produce that and how
frequently you have to adjust to the
changing threat landscape
there are still opportunities for
strategic reports for you
too though to me i would imagine this
looking like a report detailing a number
of campaigns
that all used the same entry vector and
tactic
maybe word macros and a suggested
mitigation such as
disallowing macros that come in
documents from the internet
this report would probably be going
pretty high up your management chain
and would require a lot of research over
the course of several incidents
some external research hard work editing
and would be suggesting a whole new
strategy that the company could take to
defense
defend against attackers
so to recap the difference in these
three types of reports a tactical report
is one incident an operational report is
multiple incidents strung together into
a campaign
in a strategic report is multiple
campaigns strung together to show
a pattern or strategy
all three types of these different types
of intelligence
may have different reports that fall
into them and there may be some reports
that you
are producing that you don't really feel
like fall
nicely or neatly into any of these and
that's okay
what is important is to answer your
three questions
and get um audience feedback going
forward and you'll be good to go
so now that you know what to do i want
to talk a little bit about what to avoid
when you're creating an intelligence
report to start off
it's important to avoid jargon
um especially if you're writing a report
for a
varied audience such as customers or
management
you may know what you're talking about
but at the end of the day
it's more important for your audience to
understand your report
than it is for them to know how smart
you are
not to mention a lot of jargony reports
that i've read are using that technical
language to describe
how something is working and they never
really use
any time of the report to describe why i
should care about that thing
the second pitfall to consider is
timeliness versus completeness
is it more important to let your
audience know about something now
or to wait and to make sure they know
more details later
depending on the type of report you're
writing the
question this question is probably
pretty easy to answer for a tactical
report
timeliness is critical you can send an
update later if you learn something more
for a strategic report completeness is
key
for an operational report though it can
be a little bit more tricky
so knowing that is tricky can help you
work with your team your management your
editors ahead of time to
determine which reports are more timely
and
which ones need to be more complete and
finally don't overwork your report
i know that writing and communicating
can be very difficult
and it can be tempting to want to make
changes and to make little edits
forever or to suddenly question your own
analysis
as soon as it's about to be sent off to
the customer
or to think that you really just need to
wait for one more bizarre loader
incident before you're ready to talk
about that malware
but at some point you just have to ship
your report when it's ready it's ready
and if you keep adding to it you're
eventually going to be taking away more
than you're actually adding
which brings us to water coloring
similarly with a painting if you add to
it too much
you're eventually taking it away
[Music]
so for my non-technical hobby slide
today i want to
talk about water coloring and i actually
picked this up
um during the pandemic so it's a fairly
new hobby to me
i started learning it from youtube or
blogs online and stuff like that but a
lot of those were geared towards people
that already had some experience with
painting or art which i did not they
weren't really geared towards total
beginners
so today i wanted to talk as someone who
is a beginner for other people who may
be interested in picking up this as a
new hobby for the first time
i chose specifically to talk about this
versus one of the hobbies that i've been
doing much longer because i think it's a
fun way to help newcomers
into the hobby together so we can all
learn together plus
if you're new to a hobby such as
painting especially you know water
coloring
it can be a little demotivating if
you're talking to someone who has been
doing it for a long time
and you find that you cannot reproduce
their paintings or
anything close to what they're able to
produce um
so i have some examples in my slides uh
that are what
the paintings of someone who is brand
new to this hobby would actually look
like
in addition i i want to talk about water
coloring because i feel like it's a
hobby that's super
accessible as i was thinking about what
of the hobbies i have i might want to
talk about
um some of my hobbies felt less
accessible such as like running or
exercise
not great for a varied audience which we
talked about with intelligence
communications
so my other hobbies like hiking it kind
of depends on where you live
um so i didn't really want to talk about
that and then stuff like the piano i was
like okay well you have to own a piano
and so i found that water coloring is a
hobby that is super accessible
that a lot of different people can do
from you know it doesn't really matter
where you live it doesn't matter what
stage of your life you're in
it's something that you can kind of pick
up at any point for a lot of people
so out of all the different types of art
available
that i could have chosen to talk about
why am i talking about water coloring
i tried every type of art imaginable
during this pandemic trying to find
things to do so i tried acrylic painting
i tried pastels digital painting colored
pencils
you name it i probably tried it and
watercolors ended up being my personal
favorite
because i have felt less pressure to be
perfect maybe this is a perfectionism
thing
um but i don't have a lot of natural
drawing
talent and i found with certain art
mediums such as colored pencils
you kind of have to be able to draw in
order for your
art to look anything like what you
wanted it to look like
with water coloring and some other types
of painting as well i have found that
it's a lot easier because you kind of
just do a couple of like
brush strokes or like dabbles on the
page and it kind of ends up looking like
you know a flower which is mostly what i
end up painting
um or something along the lines of what
you wanted it to look like
additionally i have found that water
coloring is less commitment than some of
the other
types of painting that i tried so
something like oil painting or acrylic
i need a canvas or a board and i
feel the need to fill that whole thing
up with a background
and a full scene or like a landscape
with watercolor you're just doing it on
paper
and i feel like i can just kind of
doodle almost with water coloring and it
feels like
so much less of a commitment than
filling up a whole canvas
um it when i was doing some acrylic
painting it felt a little daunting to
have the whole canvas and be like
okay i'm gonna have to fill this whole
thing up but because water coloring is
just on paper it's not daunting at all
um thirdly i have found that for me it's
very calming
it's relaxing it's semi-mindless it's
something that i can do while i'm
listening to music or listening to
podcasts
it's something that you could do while
you are listening to a virtual
conference put on during a pandemic
um you can do it with others when we can
do anything with others or you can do it
by yourself
and that makes it a really nice hobby
for me to have
and then finally as i mentioned i picked
this up during the pandemic which was
nice but i've also found that i think
going forward
it'll be very good for me for winter
because most of my hobbies are outdoor
hobbies
and um they're not always feasible in
the winter
so to start out i wanted to talk about
the difference between acrylic and
watercolor because i know acrylic is
another kind of beginner
painting medium that people will pick up
so i wanted to use these two paintings
as an example
of what i was talking about it being
less of a commitment so the painting on
the left is one
um that i did using acrylic and i it is
my attempt at painting the crow that
lives outside of my apartment
and as you can see i used a canvas and i
felt the need to fill up
the entire thing so i painted the whole
sky and i had to paint around my bird
and everything
and that was a little stressful and then
also it required me to have
an understanding of perspective so like
actual art
talent that i don't really have so
the buildings in that painting look a
little wonky because one is supposed to
be across the street
and it just it it took a lot more
time and planning than maybe i was
willing to give to any hobby during the
pandemic or ever
especially something that i'm brand new
at one pro for acrylics is that you can
paint light on top of dark
so you can see my crow's beak and his
eyes are gray and i painted those over
the top of his black
um feathers and in addition the building
across the street
the windows and the lights on the roof
were painted on top of the darker brown
once it had already dried so that's
that's nice because i didn't have to
plan out space for those ahead of time
the picture on the right is a little
bird that i had painted when i was very
new to water coloring
um and you can see that
there's no background there's no scene
he's just a bird i painted you know a
couple of brush strokes just for a
branch for him to sit on
but i didn't feel the need to fill up an
entire scene additionally he's just
painted on
watercolor paper so i wasn't devoting an
entire
canvas or board to this painting that
didn't feel like i was wasting money or
something if i messed it up
um also one pro for water coloring is
that
it's really easy to mix the colors so my
bird has both
blue and purple feathers and they mix
together nicely versus my crow the white
detailing on his
wing it does it didn't blend very well
just looks like lines
one con for water coloring is that you
cannot paint light on top of dark
so um for my bird's beak on the right i
had left
space for the orange beak but you can
see where it touches his
like the blue paint it kind of melded
together and doesn't look great
and then also the budding leaves that i
had put on my tree branch
you can see the branch through them
because the light green is significantly
lighter
than the dark brown branch behind them
so if any of this sounds intriguing to
you and you're interested in getting
started with water coloring
there are some supplies that you're
going to need and you can buy the
majority of these
in a starter kit which is what i did i
bought a watercolor starter kit from
michaels and it was super affordable
and it had enough supplies for me to
determine if water coloring was
something that i was actually going to
be interested in
once i decided it was i did end up
switching out some of these items for
higher quality versions of them
but i'll talk about which ones i
switched out when i get to them
so the first supply that you're going to
need is paint
this um seems pretty obvious there are
two types of paint
in water coloring there's paint that
comes in a tube
that is like a gel consistency it looks
like a
what you might expect acrylic paint to
look like but it's watercolor and then
there's paint that is dry and it comes
in a palette like what you might
remember from like elementary school
when you had those crayola paints in the
palette that you could paint with
um i have only used the tube paint so
this is an example of the two types of
paint that i'm talking about
um i've only used the tube type paint on
the left there
i have not used a palette paint yet so
all of my recommendations here are based
specifically on the tube paint i don't
know if they would be different for the
palette paint
so just something to keep in mind i will
say
the paint that came in my starter kit
has proven to be good enough for me for
beginner
i am aware that nicer paints will make
nicer paintings
however as a beginner i'm really still
learning the techniques of how to
paint with watercolors and what i really
enjoy doing and
having nicer paints isn't going to make
me a better artist yet
and so i'm i have found that the starter
kit paint is
more than sufficient for someone who's
really just starting out
in this hobby
the next item that you're going to need
is thick paper
obviously regular paper like printer
paper won't do for water coloring
because
it's water so the painful paper will get
all
messed up and wrinkly and wet so you
have to buy specifically watercolor
paper
the paper that came in the starter kit
that i tried was good enough
but i will say it was a very small ream
and so once i decided that i liked
watercolor and wanted to get into it
more
i ended up going out and buying more
paper
like a bigger ream of paper and while i
was there i just bought thicker nicer
paper
additionally you're going to need one
nice brush
i have found that the starter kit came
with like five brushes
and i tried them all out and it was nice
to be able to try them
but um i didn't end up needing that many
brushes
and it the nicer the brush you have the
better it'll be able to hold on to
water and paint and so it actually does
kind of matter
to have a nicer brush so once i had
tested out all the brushes from the
starter kit
i went back to the store and bought a
upgraded much more quality version of
the one that i
actually ended up um
liking and using and it has helped
significantly
i will say though this does you know
kind of depend on the fact that
i have been doing very small paintings
i'm not doing like these huge scenes and
if i was
i would probably um need a bigger
brush as well to paint the background um
but because i'm just doing little
flowers and stuff um
i haven't needed that and the one brush
is good enough for like doing small
details with
the tip of the brush and i can push down
more to get like leaves or
bird feathers if you will just whatever
i'm looking for
the next thing that you will need is a
palette the palette that came in the
starter kit is the only thing that i
will say that i was not a huge fan of
from the starter kit
it was kind of small and flimsy and it
really only had room for like six colors
but not a lot of room to
mix them together so i did actually go
back to the store
and buy a better palette um
i actually have it right here and you
can see that it has it's a mess right
now but it has room for
five colors but what i like is that it
has this like
trough area um and i have
used that for mixing the paint colors
together usually with a white and so i
get a gradient of that color
in the trough area and then i can just
pick from the gradient for what i'm
looking for and i can do
something like what i attempted with
these attempted cherry blossoms in the
left of my slide there i just kind of
picked it's all just one
red that i mixed with white and then i
just picked different
pieces of paint off the gradient to make
which color flower i was looking for
the next thing you're going to need is
actually two jars or cups if you've done
painting in the past with like acrylics
or
oil painting you only need one but with
watercolor you actually need a clean
water horse as well so you will need two
just something to keep in mind and you
won't want to contaminate
um your clean water with dirty water so
that's all you're going to need
um but there are some optional items
that you
can add if you would like that
i have found have made my paintings more
professional looking
or in general just more fun and the
first one is washi tape so washi tape is
very inexpensive
and it can be purchased almost anywhere
i got mine at the art store
and what it does is it adds a nice crisp
border
there we go a nice crisp border to your
painting so you can see what i did here
was i had two scenes from kind of the
same
painting and i had taped around both of
them so it kind of gave it this like
comic book feel where there's like two
frames from the same scene
and in addition it gave it a nice crisp
line around the outside as well
because without that you wouldn't really
be able to achieve that with water
coloring since water is wet and it'll
just go all over your page otherwise
additionally it is very satisfying when
you have finished a painting
to peel off the tape and reveal that
very crisp
line below it's worth it just for that
additionally another thing you can add
to your painting is pins and
ink so i've heard about this on line
when i was researching watercolor
i saw a lot of people posting art that
they were saying was like watercolor
and ink and they were using the ink to
add a lot of details to their
painting so they were they were adding
like strands of hair
or um petals on a flower or what have
you
so i decided to try that out and
there's probably some kind of artists
ink that you may
use for something like this but as a
total beginner i wasn't going to
buy that so i just used pens that i had
in my house
and i tested out a couple of them to see
which one worked best or if any of them
worked
and i found that they did work at home
pins so this is not
the best painting obviously um but the
one on the left
is my attempt at using a bic pen to
use a rose the one on the right is a
paper mate gel pen and you can see that
the big pen worked just fine i feel like
for a starter
who's getting started in watercoloring
this works just fine
and i used it to draw the whole flower i
don't think it added much to the stem
or the leaves but i will say for the
petals of my rose
this would otherwise just be a red blob
and the pen gave it an outline um the
paper mate one i did the same thing but
it
mixed with the water and made all of my
colors this very
murky gray ugly color so
just watch out for that um another thing
i will say is that i haven't done this
very much
because it requires the ability to draw
which i
don't feel like i'm good at and again i
think this is maybe a perfectionism
thing but i
i don't like when i draw something and
it doesn't look perfect and so i
i prefer not painting with pens but it
is an option if you want to add more
details and you find that
you're struggling to draw certain you
know flowers or something that need more
detail because the water just mixes
together
so to talk about the actual painting
itself now um
there are two main methods by which uh
you can watercolor
and the first one is wet on wet this is
when you
get just clean plain water on your brush
and then you
brush that water directly onto the paper
um
first and then you get the watercolor
paint on your brush
and then paint on top of the water that
is on your page
and this can achieve a very like smooth
watery effect so you can see from my
example painting on the right there
the top blue paint area
was wet on wet and um you can see it's
fairly smooth
you don't see too many brush strokes
really it kind of like the edges are
very smooth
at the bottom edge where i didn't have
any tape and it looks pretty nice
and if i had used a lighter blue i used
a darker one just for the example but if
i had used a lighter one it would have
made a good
sky or background color however
wet on wet is not good for details so if
you see
the red smudges below
that was wet on wet um and i was trying
to make little dots and i did this just
to highlight that if you are going to be
using watercolors to paint something
specific you won't want to use the wet
on wet technique
wet on dry is when you skip the brushing
on of the clean water
and just paint your paint directly onto
the dry
page and so for my red dots on this
example you can see that they didn't
spread out at all so it's a really good
way of getting detailed paint or
sorry detailed drawings in your painting
but for the blue section at the bottom
you can see that it looks a bit scraggly
you can see some brush strokes
the top doesn't look very clean
so i would not recommend necessarily
using it for like a wide area if you're
painting a background or something
and these two techniques can be combined
so you can paint a background
um using wet on wet and then add your
detailing on top
using wet on dry and for that each
painting that i had shown a little while
ago that i have right here
so that's what i had done here the sand
and the sky were painted on
with wet on wet and then once they had
fully dried i
added the bushes and the water on using
or sorry painted the sand using wet on
wet then once they were dry
i painted the bushes on using wet on dry
so as with any hobby when you first get
started you're going to mess it up
and that's fine because that's how you
learn
but there are a few things that i have
done um
that you can learn from my mistakes and
hopefully not make the same ones
so the first mistake i made was being
left-handed
i have been left-handed my whole life
and yet somehow i always forget
um and really what this mistake was is
that
watercolor paint is wet and um
i'm not used to painting at all so when
i first got into it i've been used to
you know
using a computer or writing or doing
things that that won't transfer
and if you touch the paint it's going to
transfer all over your page so just
something to keep in mind if you're
brand new to painting
if you're really happy with what you're
doing and then you drag your hand
through it
it will make a mess and it will be
frustrating so just keep that in mind if
you're left-handed like me
you may actually want to start from the
right side of your page if you can
the second mistake i made was just using
way too much water this painting on the
right was supposed to be a flower
and it does not look obviously anything
like a flower because i used just an
inordinate amount of water
so for the three circular purple flower
heads i was trying to make flower buds
i had way too much water on my brush and
i didn't realize it
and i painted directly under the page
and then the second mistake i made
was touching the stem directly to the
flower
so then all the paint ran together
because water touched water
and it made this horrible murky brown
disgusting color
there's a lot of ways to combat this the
first is not to just get so much water
on your brush in the first place
but secondly i have found that it's very
helpful for me
to dab my brush off on a paper towel to
get some of the water off
and then third let it dry a little bit
before adding more details and then
fourth if you are adding those more
details
don't touch them to the other wet part
and then the last mistake i want to talk
about
is don't just dive right into it and try
and do a huge painting
i think this was the very second
painting i attempted when i was
watercoloring
and you can see it's just not very good
it was very frustrating for me
because i was like yeah i'm going to be
great at watercoloring and i tried this
huge painting
and it was bad um because you really
need to allow yourself the room to start
small
learn how to watercolor before you try
to do a huge painting
um so just give yourself room to learn
so just as a final note for watercolor
painting it's super
easy to learn the basics and to do this
i will show you my very first painting
which is
quite hideous and embarrassing um it was
supposed to be a bird
it is terrifying because it's not very
good the beak
just went into the feathers it looks
awful but you can see a mere two months
later
i was able to paint these flowers and
they look significantly better than the
bird there's still room for improvement
but you can see how far i was able to
come in just a short amount of time
i'm not going to say that it's easy to
be an amazing watercolor artist
but it's certainly beginner friendly for
doodling or having a mindless hobby
during you know winter it's also a
really nice way to make gifts or cards
for your friends or
your family if i painted some of these
flowers i could send those like a
birthday card
to a friend and that would be very nice
that being said whether you like water
coloring or not
i recommend giving art a try there's so
many different mediums of art out there
and different people will like different
ones i know my sister is a huge fan of
gel pens with coloring books um digital
art is really popular right now and
there's free software like krita or
whatever that you can use to try it out
um some people might want to go the bob
ross route and do oil paints
experiment with several types of art and
find one that works for you
because really at the end of the day
it's a very relaxing and fulfilling
hobby to have
um so with that i think i talked almost
up to the minute but if we have any
questions
and any time for them i'd be happy to
take them
yeah we're about out of time but there
are a few questions in chat if you could
hang out with folks for a little while
and answer some of them that'd be very
much appreciated
it was an amazing talk and your artist
beautiful uh thank you for sharing it
with us
thank you you're definitely more
talented than me so
thank you so much emily