up next we have hacking cars
and crops on a budget with griffin payne
so
thanks everybody for taking your time
out of a sunday afternoon to join us
and thank you to the pancakes con
organizers and volunteers for putting
this all together it's
good fun so today we're going to be
talking about hacking cars and crops
on a budget so let's begin
there you go so who am i i'm griffin
payne
and in my professional life i'm an
associate director
on productivity's attack and penetration
testing team and what that means is i
spend a lot of my time on the phone
and doing powerpoint presentations and
not so much hands-on hacking these days
but in a former life i was a pen tester
and previous to that
i've done ir blue team compliance and
everything in between
oddly enough i never wanted or intended
to be
in security or rit i wanted to be a
video editor when i was in school
but trying to get a job doing that in
cleveland was a bit hard so i got a job
doing help desk and kind of progressed
through the years into security and here
we are in my personal life i'm a husband
and father of two young boys
so i don't have much free time at all
anymore i like to collect art and scotch
so i'm pretty excited about nick
britton's
rare collectibles talk here in a little
bit i like growing plants which you will
see here
in a moment i'm an outdoor lover i'm
living in denver now so
lots to do out here big fan of animals i
have some dogs and cats and i'm not a
very serious person at all as you can
tell from this
picture of me in a hot dog suit at
defcon china a few years ago
and we'll talk more about that in a few
minutes
so before we start i'd like to throw out
a disclaimer so
what is presented in this content what
i'm going to be talking about
could be used for nefarious purposes and
you are solely responsible for what you
choose to do with this information
and it's all made for educational
purposes there's plenty of research
online that you can go find
that will help enable you to build these
things but it's entirely up to you what
you do with it
so with that a lot of the techniques and
tactics i'm going to talk about on the
automotive side
are dated so there's nothing
groundbreaking or zero day coming out
here
it's all things that have been out in
the wild for a long time
but the intent of this talk is to show
you what you can do with a very small
budget
and a little perseverance and dedication
and willingness to learn
so a lot of these techniques still work
on older models but some of the newer
models
have mitigated a lot of the things that
we're going to talk about or just scrap
technology
all together now that being said
so when i used to present to automotive
companies oems as they're called
original equipment manufacturers
to talk about testing and why testing is
important to them this was the pitch i
would use to start
so here we go imagine you're driving
down the street
nice summer day you got the windows down
you're just listening to some music
and all of a sudden the music cuts off
and
you get this weird error message on your
infotainment screen you're like what is
that
start tapping on it tapping on it boom
ransomware
my car how is that possible and when we
used to say this to the automotive
companies they're like yeah
right ransomware car but then it started
happening to refrigerators and
thermostats and things like that and
like okay maybe this does apply to us
maybe we should listen
now to give a little back story about
when i first got into automotive testing
i honestly didn't think i would ever be
able to do it i never thought i was a
good tester i'm still not a good tester
there's plenty of people that are way
better than me
and then coming from traditional i.t
systems into the automotive world
knowing how much time and money is spent
producing these vehicles and
you know airplanes and things in the
transportation industry
i assume it would just be like top of
the line technology and state-of-the-art
tools and software and in reality that's
not the case
so when there's a software vulnerability
people like microsoft or cisco push out
a security patch in 30 days 60 days 90
days whatever
and it fixes the vulnerability in
automotive or transportation or
you know gaming with slot machines and
things like that anything that's
built on hardware with software overlaid
isn't as easy to fix
so when a vulnerability is found in a
piece of hardware
you can't just push out a software patch
and fix it in a lot of cases
and once it's discovered it's out there
recalls are really expensive the
production life cycle on vehicles and
planes and trains and things like that
is really long it could be anywhere from
one to 15 years from
product inception to design requirements
definitions prototyping tests
prototyping again and then production so
when a vulnerability is found
it's a long time coming before you can
push out a
for it and then when you're building
these things
you don't anticipate with the attack
surface or the techniques you're going
to look like in 10 15 years
so when you i began testing automotives
i didn't think i'd be able to do it but
then you jump in and you see things like
telnet and clear text protocols
and linux operating system with sc linux
features turned off because
it makes infotainment units slower to
boot and it's a lot easier to test than
you might think
so get the preconception out of your
head that you won't be able to do
it because anybody can do it and we all
start somewhere
if you want to get more into automotive
testing i highly recommend popping into
the automotive
village the car hacking village those
guys are way smarter than me
they virtualized a lot of things so you
can get in there and play with stuff
and it's it's really good learning
experience you're not going to break
anything you're not going to hurt
anybody
so absolutely talk to those guys pop in
there and
ask questions now that we got that out
of the way
let's get into it so the
point of this talk is to show what you
can do on a very limited budget
on both growing crops and hacking cars
so our first example is going to be a
homemade
passive keyless entry start amplifier
slash relapse
now if you're not familiar with the
passive keyless entry start i'm sure
most of you are it's when you walk up to
a vehicle
the keys are in your hand or your pocket
and you touch the handle of the car and
it unlocks and you didn't do anything
with keys where you get in the car
and you don't put the keys in the
ignition you just push the start button
now the way this works is the car emits
a high frequency signal when you're in
close proximity
and the keys respond with a low
frequency signal so yeah we're right
here
you know open up now when this technique
was first hitting the scene you know 10
15 years ago whatever it was
police were dumbfounded when they saw
the home security footage of these
criminals going to houses
and holding something up to the side of
the house another guy would open the car
start it and drive off in less than two
minutes so when they found one of these
devices they figured out
that's what was happening and then we
were talking to oems about this and
everybody always downplayed it they're
like oh
it's not going to happen to us it's you
know it takes very sophisticated
equipment or it's really expensive
whatever the case we're like hold my
beard watch
so we built this using
really cheap components so what you see
here is a spool of copper wire
a breadboard holding all these
components together a microcontroller
with about
30 lines of c code and a battery and
it's all stuffed into a defibrillator
case because that's what we're laying
around
so all of this is done for less than 20
in less than a day
and this is what it can do so
in this video here the keys are inside
the house
this green thing in my right hand acts
as a receiver so it takes a signal from
the vehicle
and amplifies it through the box to the
keys in the house which then respond
with the low frequency signal which
travels further
and let me show you how this works
um
and that was all done in less than 30
seconds so
this is you know a serious problem for
car thieves and
newer cars have mitigated this in the
new key fobs but this is still a very
prevalent attack my wife's friend
out here in denver actually had her car
stolen a few weeks ago and this was the
suspected technique because
no signs of forced entry it was in and
out in less than two minutes
still a very real attack
um another point to mention there if you
heard the two beeps in the car i'm not
sure if you did
it's the car alerting me that the keys
aren't in it as a thief
i don't care i'm driving this to a
shipping container dropping it off
getting paid
i don't need the keys but it's an
audible alert
because you can't disable the vehicle
while it's in motion because
safety hazard so this isn't going to
stop anybody from stealing your car if
you're still inclined
now the next technique we're going to
talk about is using software-defined
radios
now this will be the most expensive tool
in the bag they range anywhere from
thirty to three hundred fifty dollars
the hack rf1 is probably my favorite and
one i see most often in the field
because it operates
at a really nice wide operating
frequency from one megahertz to six
gigahertz
the price differences you'll see in
these basically gives you more
operating frequency now with that you
get to communicate with more things on
those channels
some of the cheaper ones the twenty
dollar twenty five dollars still
operated a very specific frequency so if
there's not
something talking in that range you
won't be able to communicate it with
it but the hack rf1 for example has a
really wide range so you can talk to the
garage door openers cars
whatever in this example we are
targeting a tire pressure monitoring
sensor
and that is the little sensor that's in
your wheel
that will detect if it's beyond the
recommended tire pressure sense so if
it's
higher or lower you get a little alert
on your dashboard
now i was doing some research on this
particular
product or you know whatever for a
vehicle before this talk and i hadn't
seen anything new so i think they
scrapped it all together
but at the point in time when we were
testing this
it was a self-inflating tire system the
way it worked was there was four sensors
in the tires
a central control unit that received the
messages from the tires that then talked
to an automatic control unit would
inflate or deflate the tire based on
need
now this picture is just an example it's
not what we're actually testing
but the applications for this were
military commercial and heavy machinery
so imagine you're in a battlefield
situation you don't want to get out of
the car
and pump a tire or change tire if you
have a flat or if it's you know
over inflated so they had this
you know the system that would inflate a
deflate based on need
so we're testing it with the software
defined radio and we were able to
you know capture the communications from
the tire pressure sensors that were
going to the central control unit
we were able to spoof those and trick
the tire pressure
control unit into thinking the tires
were under inflated or over inflated
so think about the implications for that
in a battlefield or in some heavy
machinery so
we trick the tire into thinking it's
under inflated it just keeps getting
pumped up until it explodes so if you're
in a battlefield
it's the last thing you want which is
why they probably scrapped this
technology
because i hope they did or figured out a
better way to protect it
and all that was done with a
software-defined radio and a computer
so not a lot of specialized equipment
next we're going to talk about the can
bus can't talk about cars without
talking about the canvas
so in a traditional it network you're
thinking you know cat wiring and things
like that
in a vehicle everything is you know a
canvas the ecu's which are the
electronic control units are basically
little computers that control various
functions of the vehicle
the easy there's various networks in the
vehicle there's
besides the can there's land flex-ray
most the easiest to interface with at
least in my opinion is the can bus
because you could talk to it through the
onboard diagnostics port which i'll show
you that in a moment
but this is one of those things i
thought was just going to be super
expensive i'd never be able to do it
because when you take a car for an
emissions check or for maintenance they
plug it into this super
huge machine that's got to cost
thousands of dollars
when i first got into this i didn't
think it would be a realistic thing to
do in my
my own time and then i found things like
the canon tank for 75 dollars i
personally use
canalize for 60 dollars there's the
cannibal here that's 80
and what this does is connects into the
odb port in your car
which can be found above the footrest
and
it's always accessible because it's used
for diagnostics so it's not going to be
any screws or anything holding it in
place
it may not be as easy to see as this
picture here but it's always
going to be on the driver's side
somewhere on the dash
and this device will plug into that and
then it has a usb adapter that plugs
into a computer
now things like wireshark have native
can
you know support there's other tools
like can utils that have canned dump and
can send so you can send packets and
capture packets
if you want to play with this more again
pop into the auto village
those guys have various components in
there right now that will let you play
with cam messages you can replay them
spoof them and try to figure them out
now with cam messages they're not
straightforward
there's not a standard used across all
the oems so they're not going to be able
to find a cheat sheet to see what things
mean
when you first plug into it and start
capturing the data
it looks crazy it comes in super fast
nothing's very clear like the ids are
all over the place you don't really know
what the messages are saying
but if you want to play with it you know
you could do it in your own car
plug in and then do things like turn on
the the winch wipers or you know
do your turn signal or put the car you
know push the brake or push the
accelerator
and just keep doing that over and over
and you'll start to see the same frames
over and over again so then you capture
those
you can replay them you can put them
into a loop and just blast them in there
and then it'll start to do things to
your car and you can identify
which message is doing what now through
the can bus
and the odb port specifically you can do
a lot of things you can unlock and
change features so like in my car
for example i could change you know what
the key press does on the
on the keys in the picture before was
from an audi forum where a guy was
flashing an ecu to do
a turbo boost unlock you can do actions
such as triggering the airbags the
brakes for the acceleration and when we
were doing automotive pen tests that's
the type of stuff we were looking for
could you communicate with something
through the can bus to
trigger the air bags to pop because
ultimately safety is the most important
thing in a vehicle
and if you could impact safety through
something is
like the can bus then it's a major
problem
so one of the other disclaimers i'll
throw out here is
playing with your vehicle and ecu's
could lead to potential damage
long-term i've never done it personally
i've never broken anything in my car
playing around
but i have seen horror stories where
people have braked ecu's they've had to
like tow their car
with dealership to get it flashed and
that's cost money
so you know proceed with caution there
is a lot of techniques now and tools
where you can virtualize these
you could buy ecu's off of ebay for 40
50 there's a resource i reference
at the end of this talk that shows you
how to set that up throw some 12 volt
power on it so you can have it on your
test bench and
i actually playing with the car and then
there's other great places again like
the auto hacking village and
you know forums and groups like that
where you can play online and not
actually do any damage
next is the infotainment system
so when i guess the last few vehicles i
had didn't have an infotainment system
and when i finally got one i'm looking
at it i'm like well how do i interface
with this thing
it's seamlessly integrated into the
dashboard there's got no ports on it
like what am i supposed to do
to play with this you don't really need
anything besides a computer
and if you want to figure out how to get
it apart look up a youtube video or
google
how do i replace my infotainment unit
and you'll see things like
step-by-step guides so in this
particular vehicle we were testing
it just showed these two little yellow
clips that held this piece of plastic in
place
so you just put a little force and pull
it off and it came right off
nothing broke and now we have the
infotainment unit exposed to us and it's
held in by these two screws
on each side so what do you do when you
have this device
well you pull it out and it's basically
just like a little computer it's in a
chassis
it's got screws and everything else and
what do you do with the computer when
you want to play with it you take it
apart
so pro tip keep a jar or a little
magnetized pad there so you don't lose
the screws
every time i take something apart
there's always extra screws when i put
it back together
don't know where those come from but you
know
once you take it apart you'll start to
see things on there that you might
be familiar with such as an sd card
reader
and once we found that we pop the sd
card out
put it into a laptop and what did we
find is a linux file system that was
readable and writable
so once we mounted it and started
playing around we found all these
binaries
that had vulnerabilities or we could
decompile the code on and play with them
once we did that we just put it back in
the file system put it back in here put
this together
dropped it back into the vehicle boom we
owned all the applications on this thing
we had root access we could bypass
pay walls that the automotive
manufacturer had through the store
so we could abuse features do some
monetary impact we weren't able to
communicate on the can bus
because of whatever limitations we ran
into through the test
but you can do a lot without any
specialized tools when it comes to the
infotainment system
next we'll look at wireless so
anybody who's done a wireless test in
the past will
be familiar with these devices elf is
probably one of the most prevalent
there's also the tp link there which is
only 15
anything that does packet injection you
can do a wireless test with
so in this particular example we were
testing
a handful of vehicles so there were
simultaneous tests going on there's
destructive testing of a team tearing
down an
infotainment unit we were doing wireless
assessments
people were just looking over the whole
vehicle while we were testing
we observed that the infotainment unit
was beaconing
for this access point it wasn't ours so
we used the wireless
usb dongle use host apd to use that
access point name
and as soon as we set it up the vehicle
connected no username or password
once that happened we did a port scan we
observed 422 is there
we tried things like root route route
admin eventually guested on like the
fifth or sixth try
and we had root access to this device so
while we're doing that
the team doing the destructive testing
was checking out the data sheets
realized the chip used in the
infotainment unit ivi is in vehicle
infotainment
allowed for ad hoc mode and that was
disabled via software
so we got thinking let's enable that and
we did
use the same access point name that the
car initially connected to
and then the car was acting as an access
point now all the other vehicles that we
were testing connected to it
with that idea we decided to push some
out of the vehicle so we did and then it
propagated the other vehicles
so we actually created this wormable
exploit
that connected all the vehicles and if
you think about it
again this goes back to you know
thinking that you're not going to be
smart enough or
you know have enough skill to test the
vehicle all of these are
basic security best practices wipe the
infotainment unit before it leaves the
factory
use a strong root password all this
could have been prevented
but it wasn't and it's just basic
security missteps that allowed us to
take over this this fleet of vehicles
so to summarize none of that was very
expensive was it i think the most
expensive thing is the hack rf1 and it's
everything else can be had for less than
a hundred dollars
and you can do whatever you want with it
so
again pop into the auto hacking village
play around
don't ever feel like you're not smart
enough you don't know enough to do it
we all start somewhere i still don't
think i know anything about this stuff
but you just jump in and start poking
around that's how you learn you try new
things
so let's switch gears my other
passion of mine growing plants i love
plants
when the pandemic hit we would go to the
store to buy food
nothing was available so i was like okay
we're really gonna have to kick this
into gear
we're gonna need to learn how to make
bread everything in between
so this picture here you'll see a banana
tree and an orange tree
which aren't native to cleveland so i do
enjoy growing plants
but it was really tricky in cleveland i
don't know if you've ever been there
you're from there but the weather is
really unpredictable you could have
three months of no sunshine it could be
freezing in the middle of summer growing
outdoors wasn't really
tenable so i moved it all indoors as you
can see in this picture these are a
bunch of tomato plants and a banana tree
in my closet and they don't look like
they're doing very well do they
the tomato plants got really tall and
fell over i was like there's got to be
something easier than this
great enter aeroponics so aeroponics is
a version of hydroponics
in which there's a container that holds
plants
in these pots that allow the roots to be
exposed to a constantly spring mist
and in aeroponics there's two types
there's low pressure and high pressure
and what we're going to be talking about
is low pressure
where it's a 24 hour spray of mist for
these roots
now once i found out about this i was
like i gotta get one of these things
let's let's go buy one but for 940
like that's crazy look at this thing
like it can't possibly cost that much
right
right so let's show you how i put one of
these together
for pretty cheap so first you're going
to need some pvc pipes and connectors
you can go to any home improvement store
your lows home depots menards whatever
you have available
10 feet of half inch diameter pipe is
2.40 cents i used less than twenty feet
plus the the elbows the t connectors and
the ends
it all came to about less than ten
dollars
next you're gonna need sprayer nozzles
like i mentioned with aeroponics
you wanna create this fine mist so these
nozzles go into the pvc pipe and the
water pressure goes through and it's
forced through these nozzles and creates
this fine mist
so 40 of these is six dollars on amazon
and if you'll notice it says 360 degrees
so they make these
in 270 and 180 they do a really targeted
spray but
in the aeroponic system you want a full
360 degrees because
the roots get wild and you want to make
sure they're all being sprayed because
dry roots are bad
next you're going to need a submersible
water pump and it has to be submersible
because it's going to be
in this water solution all the time so
if you get a dry pump it's not going to
work
this is something else you can find at
your loans or home depots
you typically find it in like the
outdoor gardening you'll see in koi
ponds or waterfall features
you can get this one on amazon for 24
and it does
400 gallons per hour you may not know
how many gallons per hour you're going
to need
it depends on how much piping and how
far away your water tank is from the
plants
but 400 worked for me and it comes with
all the features and the connections
that you need
next you're going to need something to
hold the plants so you see here this one
is 18
and it'll work just fine but i opted for
this actual plant table for a hundred
dollars from botanicare
it's three feet by three feet it's a lot
sturdier than this flimsy black plastic
and it's got really good irrigation
channels as you can see here
now pro tip again i wouldn't use this
had i've done this again my initial
build
was a flood drain table so the plants
sit on the table
and the water would flood it for 10
minutes every hour and then it drains
now when i did this i didn't realize how
big of an impact
the light hitting the plants and the
medium holding the plants would be and
it turned into an lg nightmare
to the point where i couldn't even clean
i had to throw everything away but i
didn't want to buy anything else because
i'm cheap
and i made it work and the next slides
will show how i made that work
but if you're going to build this
something like this would work and you
just cut holes in that and drop the
plants in there
so the net pots so you know your typical
garden plant that you buy from the store
it has a little plastic container that
the
plant sits in it's got a couple holes in
the bottom for drainage
and an aeroponic system you want
something that's like this with lots of
slides and a bunch of holes
you can get 50 of these for 10 on amazon
and why you want it like this is so the
roots get exposed to the mist
and they can just grow through it freely
next you're going to need a medium for
the pots so i chose clay pebbles which
are basically just little clay rocks
this 10 liter bag is 15 and 10 liters
translates to like 40 pounds so this is
gonna last me the rest of my life
if you go this route use clay rocks
rinse them before you use them because
they're really dusty and that's bad for
water
so just you know get enough for the pots
as you can see here they just sit in
there
this is what the roots look like i'll
show you another picture that in a
moment
but rinse them off and then you're good
to go with that
next is something to hold the pots in
place and the black light from
you know the water solution everything
like that we're all familiar with
cardboard
they make corrugated plastic which is
essentially the same thing it's got the
little ribs between
it's waterproof it didn't grow mold and
it was easy to cut
and i also bought a little circle cutter
from the same you know home depot lowe's
whatever
it puts a little hole in the center with
the razor blade it spins around so i
could cut the circle for the net pots
so this thing's less than 25 bucks for
the cardboard or the corrugated plastic
this is a big sheet it's what four feet
by i don't even know
96 inches and six feet and i cut it down
to three by three and i had some
left over for whatever else i needed for
next you're going to need a container
for your water solution
one of the things that appealed to me
about hydroponics aeroponics
is that it's kind of low maintenance
and once you get this all set up this
thing will hold
20 gallons of water so you don't really
need to water it often you just come
down and check to make sure the water
level is higher than the pump
because you don't want it to burn out
and it's pretty much
set it and forget it from there and
finally you're going to need a light
so the pictures you saw earlier i was
using a high pressure sodium light
when i first got into this hobby led
lights weren't a thing
but now that they are this is absolutely
the way to go 500 watt
is 50 1000 watts 90 i think i paid like
400 dollars for high pressure sodium for
400 watt but it's a tank and it's lasted
20 years so when it finally dies
i'll replace it with this but this is
absolutely the way to go now
now let's put that all together remember
the pre-made system for 940 bucks
ridiculous this entire homemade system
with a light
is 250 and you're done
now the only thing that doesn't factor
in here is the time it takes to put it
all together
and i apologize i didn't realize i'd be
doing a talk on this or i would have
taken more pictures of the build process
but let's go through what we have here
so you take your
container that's going to hold the
plants that the sprayer will be in you
measure it
you get the pvc pipes and you cut them
and it's like playing leaky pipes on a
windows system back in the day
you put it together doesn't look right
pull it apart try it again
it's like oh this t goes here this end
cap goes here you figure it out
boom done next you're gonna need the
sprayer nozzles in so you just get a
little drill
drill a hole pop those in whoops
there we are there we go and then if you
can see around here
i use a pure silicone caulk and just to
keep you know seal the gaps so i don't
want any water leaking out of there i
want it all coming out of the nozzle
and then this is it all put together so
you see the corrugated plastic
the neck cups the rock cube or the rock
or clay pebbles
and i put little pvc pipes in here
to support it because i started to sag a
bit
and now you're basically done so sit
back
and watch your hard work come to life so
after a few days you start to get some
sprouts
you could start the seeds in you know
white paper towel or something like that
if you want to just drop seedlings in
or if you just want to put seeds into
the neck cups that works too
so feed and pollinate those are key
things to growing plants
so when you're doing this you don't need
plant food
but the difference between using plant
food and not is
night and day your plants will be
humongous
the more fruit bigger fruit if you use
plant food
now it's important to use a hydroponic
based
or a food made for hydroponics you don't
want to use something that's made for
soil because
it may not be as water soluble it'll
clog your sprayer and your pump
and that's just a nightmare you don't
want to deal with
now the other thing with aeroponics and
hydroponics is the soilless growing
system
so there's nothing absorbing any of the
nutrients it's all going straight to the
plants and you'll see that here in a
second
so this is you know week one i think i
think this is week two or three
and just see how big these things are
getting so if you see here
each one's next to each other and i
didn't plan
for how big they were going to get so in
the next picture
i had to you know weed out the ones that
weren't doing too well
and when you're growing plants you'll
notice that some are doing better than
others you just get rid of the ones that
aren't doing well
to make space for your healthy ones now
i don't know if anybody's ever grown
peppers before
but these things got massive in this
aeroponics solution so like a typical
pepper leaf
when you're growing on outside is like
as big as your hand these things were
like two dinner plates like i was
cutting them off and showing people
because it was just so impressive
now when you're growing these the canopy
will get really dense and the leaves
below will start to die off
it's important to cut back on those
because you don't want the plant to
focus any additional energy trying to
keep those alive
you want it to spend its energy on
growing the healthy leaves and foliage
and putting all the energy into fruiting
and the vegetables
and i'll show you a picture of that
later too
so you remember this picture the tomato
plants they got
five six feet tall i never saw a single
tomato and i couldn't figure out why
i didn't realize how important bees were
and i didn't want to bring a bunch of
bees into my house
so easy solution five dollar electric
toothbrush
once your plant starts to flower this is
a green pepper
it grows these little flowers with
little pollen sacks and
in nature bees birds all those creatures
take that pollen and spread it around in
your house you don't have that luxury
i didn't know that and an easy solution
was a five dollar electric toothbrush
once your plant starts to pollinate you
just take the electric toothbrush turn
it on
hold it next to the stem over here
shakes the polymers from these flowers
it pollinates the other ones and now you
have fruiting plants
this is what happy and healthy roots
look like in an aeroponic solution
so this is the underside of the
corrugated cardboard in that pots
the roots just won't run wild underneath
there like it looks like
a tangled mess it's insane but these all
hang
and the solution just sprays constantly
around there there's nothing stopping me
you know interfering with the absorption
of the nutrients and everything it's
just straight
roots and water nutrients
now that you've fed pollinated all that
you start to get your fruit so this i
don't remember exactly the timeline here
i
should have chronicled it better but i
think the life cycle on the green
peppers was
you know 60 to 90 days to maturation
another thing i didn't realize was green
peppers red peppers and yellow peppers
all come from the same pepper
so i was saving seeds from green peppers
and red peppers i was buying at the
store and planting them
and they're all green and i couldn't
figure out why yeah go figure
they just leave them on the plant longer
and they mature and sweeten and they
turn red and yellow
but you can see here they're starting to
grow and they're looking healthy
the plants will continue to flower all
the time so if you see here like there's
little trimmed roots
there are trim branches and stems and
like i mentioned
once the canopy gets really dense the
leaves start fighting for light and
they'll start crowding each other out
just want to trim those back so the
plant is focusing on the healthy
leaves and putting all this energy into
growing the vegetables
now after they look ripe and you're
happy with them
you can enjoy so you just pull them off
add them to your food
and you're off to the races so in
summary
back to this picture of me in a hot dog
costume in china
laying on top of the test vehicle in the
automotive hacking village
information security has taken me all
over the world i've been to china
england you know poland germany
everywhere in between
all because it's a highly in demand
field
and your skills are appreciated get out
of your own head if you don't think
you're good enough
i still don't think i'm good enough but
that doesn't stop me from getting in
there and trying
there's plenty of people that would love
to help it doesn't matter where you're
starting from or what your background is
all you have to do is put in a little
effort a little dedication
and try that's that's where we all
started you start poking around
and it'll take you places
finally some references and i'll leave
this slide up for a moment for anybody
who wants to uh take a screen cap
but car hacking for pory's charlie
miller and chris valesik they're
great they're the ones that did the
g-pack a few years ago
but car hiking for poury's teaches you
how to buy an ecu
for cheap set it up on a 12-volt power
supply on a workbench so you're not
testing an actual car
and you can poke around there's other
resource sources out there that will
show you how to virtualize it so you're
not messing with the actual car
you can virtualize infotainment units
now you can download
you know images for those things and
play with them in a
you know virtual box or something like
that the relay text on passive keyless
entry and start systems
i think that's what gave us the
blueprint for building our remote
keyless entry system
everything's out there already and like
with anything hardware based
it's kind of a test and discovery once
the initial vulnerability or technique
is found
and put online all the hard work's done
you just need to find it
and put it together you don't need to do
all the research yourself somebody else
has done it
and you just need to put it together as
for the crops
i didn't use any of these resources when
i built mine i'll admit i actually
purchased one of those solutions in the
past it was a little four by four once i
didn't spend a fortune
but it was still kind of expensive i
realized how it worked
and then i put a bigger one together but
i did a little research on these before
this talk
just to make sure that these would be
good to provide some guidance
and these all had really good you know
plans
and explanations as to what you're doing
and how to build it
now with that being said any questions
awesome presentation griffin there are a
couple so
first one was are bugs like fruit flies
and that's an issue with aeroponics
no they i did actually have some flies
there's some little fruit flies in the
basement but i wasn't sure if it was
from
you know the liquor collection down
there or what
it wasn't a big problem because they
would just land on top of the
plastic and drown so it wasn't
overwhelming i didn't really have any
issues ever with that though
okay great and do you have any best
practices for trimming or pruning plants
now just get some some spring-loaded
clippers because
you know the other ones are a little
hard to deal with but
if the doesn't look healthy or if the
leaf's starting to wilt or turn brown
you don't want the plant spending too
much time on that so just clip it off in
it
you know i feel bad doing it because i
don't want to hurt the plants i actually
spent a lot of time with these things
like
i say it's really low maintenance and
you can set it and forget it but i was
down there all the time and i was just
like sick because it's like
fake sunlight and you're talking to them
and you can actually
see progress like every few hours
they're bigger and bigger which is crazy
to me
so yeah you just you know care for them
you're doing the best for them so you
cut off the dead or dying
dying leaves and branches and they get
stronger
question about let's see
oh well someone commented and said you
need more bees in your presentation so
next time more
more bees next time i'll do them in the
house
i was like what can i do with this like
can i be classic that seems like a great
idea
um and where do the extra screws come
from
i think they're just hidden in the
chassis somewhere and they fall out once
you
you take it apart the manufacturer's
just messing with you
to encourage you not to play with their
stuff right right
yeah um and then lastly i had a question
for you and so
for anyone i guess who might be for the
younger
folk um how far back would you have to
go
to get a car that isn't susceptible to
the hacking that you showed today
i mean i have a 2018
and most of that stuff still works so
not too far and like
i i think i mentioned the my wife's
friend's car being stolen hers was like
a
2020 and that
relay technique still works so you know
more the higher end manufacturers
started to put like the rolling crypto
keys and things like that into it and
like time-based responses
but some of the other ones just still
don't care or it's too expensive to go
retrofit into all of these existing cars
do you have any recommendations for some
pee caps with canned
traffic for playing around i would talk
to the auto hacking guys
they probably have better answers for
that than me
most of mine came from just trial and
error i would connect my car
and start playing with things like i
pushed the gas pedal down and
like it would flood you know can traffic
when i did that with certain ids so i
knew that had something to do with it so
i'd get those you know trim out the ones
that weren't related to that and replay
them and see what it did so
it's kind of trial and error you know
you just play around and see what works
and what doesn't and
make sure your vehicle is in park right
okay and then have you made anything
delicious out of your own plants
yeah i use peppers all the time so
nothing super delicious it's just
saves me a trip to the grocery store and
it's it's nice being able to enjoy the
fruits of your labor
you know no pun intended vegetables yeah
it's awesome like the banana tree i've
i've been to five or six banana trees
i've never got them to the point where
a banana will grow because it's like a
five to seven year process
but i'm really looking forward to that
when it finally happens
and you mentioned um i don't know if you
started the aeroponic did you start the
aeroponics in cleveland or
in denver i did so i just moved to
denver november i've been doing
aeroponics for like 15 years now
so so in so my question is does the air
matter so now i know you're
you're fit you know 52 88 feet above the
ground
does the air matter that's a good
question i have no idea
okay let us know the arrow comes from
the aerosol
i would assume spraying of the mist
but i could be wrong i don't know right
does it matter at higher elevations
i've never tried on here yet like we're
still settling so i haven't got the
whole setup re
you know built back but soon i'll
everybody know next time
all right awesome well thank you so much
griffin
uh this was a wonderful day i'll be
honest if you have any other questions
and uh i hope you enjoy
thanks everyone