because it's here tales of both hacking
and climbing
from julian thank you um
first of all i'd like to thank everybody
who's joining uh this call
or this this talk anybody who's
participating in pancakes con
appreciate it um now the previous
thought was very very technical
and i'm a bit like um tom i i'm
not 100 sure of everything that he said
but
this is gonna be a lot less technical
we're gonna go through uh the pen
testing methodology so
um basically all the steps that i do
whenever i go onto a pen test engagement
uh just to make sure that the product
that pops out at the end is
more or less the same so that there's no
surprises or anything like that and that
we're following an actual process so
in that sense uh hacking in in my book
is
is science and art at the same time so
there is room to be creative but you
still need to follow a certain process
second part of my talk i'm going to be
talking about climbing um
so sorry
who am i my name is giuliani shaw as you
can
probably hear i'm a french native
speaker
i'm a pen tester i'm a cyber security
consultant
so my title changes depending on what
project i'm working on i'm a co-leader
of a monk
of a owasp chapter here locally in
atlantic canada
started that last year i got a few
search under my
name as a cyber security consultant uh
certs are king just because it it gets
you contracts
uh people are looking for certain
letters after your name whenever you
you get con whenever you respond to
proposals um an outdoor enthusiast as
you can imagine because i
i'm gonna talk about climbing so of
course i love being outdoor
i'm a volunteer ski troller i love
adventure racing
and i'm also a husband a father to two
humans two cats
and a dog so i'm always tired basically
um so like i said the agenda we're gonna
go through
the methodology that i use i typically
use the pentest standard
methodology i find that it fits really
well
with the way i think and the way i like
to approach things there are other
methodologies out there you don't have
to follow this
one but it's the one that works for me
and then
second part we're just going to talk
about climbing
first thing i'd like to talk about a
little bit about hacking we're all cyber
security professionals here that are
listening
most likely uh we we know that watching
csi and watching the matrix
you know we're not as we're hacking
we're not flying down tunnels of ones
and zeros right it's not
it's not really how it's done if you
watch somebody who's sitting at a
terminal and and doing quote unquote
hacking penetration testing
it's not very exciting to watch it's
a couple of screens a person is probably
scratching his head
um depending on on how you handle your
emotions you might be screaming or
laughing depending whether you were
successful or not
and the other part of that spectrum is
that
while it's not all that exciting and
it's not
all that techy in the sense of you know
ones and zeros flying through the screen
finding somebody signed into
facebook and posting as them that's not
hacking either you know it's just
to you know just plain jokes so anyways
i thought that was a
kind of a funny meme um so let's get
through to
the seven phases of penetration testing
as per the pen testing standard
i'm gonna go through these one by one
and some i'll spend more time on some i
spend less time on but this is a good
overview of the steps
that we're taking whenever we go on a
pen test engagement
i'm not going to read off the slides
here but
it gives you a good understanding so
let's just go to step one
pre-engagement interactions i like to
joke around
um this is the part that a malicious
actor
is never going to do even though they're
following more or less the same
methodology that we do
a malicious hacker is not going to sit
down with his
client to discuss you know the rules of
engagements and
who to contact if something goes wrong
it's just not going to happen but us
as people that come in and we're getting
paid to do an engagement
this is probably one of the most
important parts
is setting client expectations we want
to
you know make them understand what they
can expect from this engagement a lot of
times
uh depending on the client i'll go in
and they have no idea what a pen test is
they just know that they need to get one
done so it's
really important for us to sit down talk
to them
talk about the goals what what they want
to accomplish is this because of a
regulatory body that wants them to have
a pen test
is this because one of their clients is
asking to have one
and our approach might be different
depending on why
they need a pen test one of the most
important parts here
is rules of engagement what am i allowed
to do and what am i
not allowed to do i mean if if you
follow security news you'll remember
about a year and a half ago
some i mean there might be some people
from that company that's listening to
this talk right now there were a couple
of individuals that
went uh past the rules of engagement and
they ended up
in a situation where they got arrested
and
basically brought out to the local
police department everything at the end
turned out great but
just to show that if you don't follow
the rules and engagements there might be
some serious consequences
so very important to uh to take in mind
once we've sat down with our client and
i'm gonna sound like a broken record
here as i go through these steps i'm
just gonna reiterate them just to put
you into context
uh so bear with me uh so once we've sat
down with our clients and we've
gone through scoping time estimation
what they expect of us and everything
else we can start um
in our actual pen test and the first
step
that i typically do and that's a good
and a good
thing to do is to just to gather
intelligence
at this point we're not even touching
their systems
we're going online and we're looking for
information about the company
uh why are we doing this well some
companies most companies most people
will hang
a lot of really important information
out in the open
this is what we call open source
intelligence what am i looking for i
might be looking for
job postings um you might wonder why
what does a job posting give me well if
they're looking for
somebody with 10 years experience in
cisco gear
well there's a really good chance that
there's
cisco equipment in the environment if
you're looking for a senior php
developer
there might be some really good
indication that they have php in their
environment
so they can gather all that information
and start
painting a picture of what their
infrastructure looks like
to be honest most of the time when i go
in to do a pen test i know this already
because in the essence of time they'll
give me some network diagrams they'll
give me some information on their
infrastructure but this is just a show
in a pen test just to show what somebody
with no information whatsoever could
find
other things that you can think of
support forms
here's a snippet of our configuration on
our firewall
and it's not working can you help us
well as a pen tester if i have a
little bit of their config file that's
on their firewall that's really good
information for me
so once i've gathered that information
i'm going to do a little bit of threat
modeling
this is not something that i spend a
whole lot of time doing
i like to call it a mini risk assessment
mostly the way i use this is mostly to
understand where i could focus my time
i'm gonna
identify the assets that's in place so
if they have health information that
they're trying to protect
i'm going to spend most of my time or i
don't want to say most of my time but
i'm going to spend
a good majority of my time focusing on
getting to that information
simply because that's uh the information
that a
an actual malicious hacker is going to
try to get to
so i find that it's good it's a good way
of understanding where to focus your
effort
simply because as a as a pen tester and
as somebody who's on
getting paid on contract i only have a
limited amount of amount of time
to do my tests and um a malicious actor
might have
year to year to be attacking this
environment i really need to make the
most out of the time
that i'm given whether it's time or
money
so that's why we want to do a bit of
threat modeling
so we've sat down with the client we've
gathered all the intelligence that we
could online
one thing i didn't touch on is looking
through breach databases
you might be able to find passwords
hanging out in the open that's
good information i mean you can
actually imagine why you wouldn't want
to have a username and password
when you're doing a pen test but that's
another thing that can be found there
uh did a little bit of threat modeling
and now we're really getting into
the meat of the engagement we are
actually attacking their systems
so the way we the first step is we're
going to check the doors i like
i like using analogies in the
vulnerability and
analysis stage i'm actually testing
doors i'm looking for
places where there might be a way in
so i'm gonna check if the doors unlock
i'm gonna check
where the windows are and everything
else um in a more technical sense i'm
looking at
services ports software that's installed
things that are unpatched things that
are misconfigured
any type of any type of technology that
i can use to my advantage
or misuse to my advantage to gain access
to their systems
how do i do this i can do this with
automated tools or i can do this
manually
there's great tools out there such as
you know
nessus nexpose openvas if you're looking
at open source stuff that's going to
scan a network
it's going to be fingerprinting services
and technologies we're looking for names
and version numbers
once we have that in hand we might go
online look at
your cvss database to see what kind of
vulnerabilities
lies in i don't know ticket lord 1.2
uh their ticketing system and see if
there's anything
of use there any exploits that i could
use i'm not
using those exploits yet i'm just again
painting a picture of
where i could focus my attention to try
to get into the systems
common misconfigurations is important
too especially in an active directory
environment where you could be
completely patched but if it's
misconfigured
there might be ways in so we're testing
all of these things
now this can be active in the sense that
i'm actually sending packets i'm hitting
systems and they're responding back
or it could be passive i could be
sitting in an environment somewhere and
just sniffing the wire and seeing
uh what kind of protocols are are being
passed around
what kind of things can i see passively
so that i don't get caught
and that's an important point getting
caught i'm talking about pen testing i'm
not talking about red teaming
pen testing um you're not trying to be
silent here you're just trying to find
flaws you're trying to find
vulnerabilities you're not trying to
evade intrusion detection systems you're
not trying to evade their
web application firewall you're actually
trying to find if the web application
has a flaw so you're not trying to be
silent here this can be very very
loud it would be a lot different in a
red teaming environment where
you're trying to be silent and you're
trying not to get caught this step would
be
very very different but you would still
go through this step
next up um we've we've sat down with the
client
we've gathered intelligence we did a bit
of threat modeling we we have a good
understanding of where the flaws might
be in their systems we're gonna try to
exploit those flaws
um one of the ways that i like to
uh uh talk about exploitation is
you you know there's a door there now
we're trying to pick that lock
because we know the lock is easily
pickable uh we're gonna try to pick that
law open the door and stick our head in
try to see what's there this is mostly
all manual work and this is where the
creative part of the pen testing comes
in you have to think outside the box
uh you you're trying to make system
you're trying to make
have systems do things that they're not
designed to do
so you're trying to bypass security
mechanism and sometimes you have to
think outside the box you have to be
creative you have to you know try it a
certain way and if that doesn't work
you might want to try another way of
doing things so
there's a lot of creativity that can
come into this this
phase the exploit and the post exploit
phase
some exploit code might need to be
modified you might have to write some
exploit code that's more of an advanced
uh
pen testing thing to do you might not
have time most of the
i mean if if you're going to start
writing exploit code
and you have five days to pen test the
full environment you might just don't
have time so
this is something that uh security
researchers might do on the side
and then release to the public so that i
can go in
and i mean call me a script kitty if you
want uh scripts are easy and fun to use
up to a certain point
and proof of concept code is always
popping out
just grab it from reliable sources make
sure that
it's you know review you don't want to
send something into an environment that
might infect them or whatnot just make
sure that you
you review those exploits that you're
running against their systems
so what do we do once we've exploited a
system you know we we've found those
flaws
we've exploited the system we're in um
well i mean why not move in you see
buddy here in that uh
in that photo he's moving his boxes in
and and that's what we're doing
at this point exploit move um
we've gotten access to a system whether
it's low
a low privileged user or
it might not be a system that seems that
useful
to us right now but we just want to make
sure that we can
we can stay in and that we have access
to it for
a little bit of time i don't like to
read from slides but this second
sentence to me is very important
so we're talking about the value of the
machine it is determined by the
sensitivity of the data that's stored on
it but not only that
if you get into a system and there's no
you
you look around and there's nothing of
use here you don't want to back out
because this system
might be your pivot into further
compromising the network you might be
able it might be a dual home machine
that has
an internal ip that you couldn't see
from where you're sitting so you might
be able to use this machine
to look further into the network or to
move
laterally into other systems there might
be some scripts lying around
with passwords there might be all kinds
of stuff you can do with this machine
even though the machine itself doesn't
look very useful to you
doesn't mean it's not it means that it
might be used
to do other things um and that brings us
to
our next um it's not a phase i guess
it's more a question that we're going to
go back to our vulnerability analysis so
we we've looked at all the exploits or
we looked at all the vulnerabilities
inside of their systems
and um we've exploited one of them
at this point uh just for an example we
were able to
do a little bit of post post
exploitation
now we have two choices are we going to
take this new machine that we have
access to
and run vulnerability analysis from that
viewpoint
in further into their network or
do we want to step back look at our
vulnerability scans
and find another vulnerability that we
might exploit
so either way we're rinse and repeating
um do vulnerability analysis do
exploitation do
post exploitation we keep going round
and round and round
i don't know if i'm doing any copyright
infringement here
with this try harder but what you want
to do is try again and try harder
keep going until when well until you run
out of time right because
this is a paid engagement they only have
a certain budget
and you want to be able to hit
everything
and hit all the goals and do everything
that they want you to look at
but at some point you're just going to
run out of time and run out of budget
so that's when you're going to stop as
opposed to a malicious actor who's going
to stop when he gets bored or he gets
what he wants
we're just going to keep going and give
value to the customer
for as long as we've we've got time
and um last but not least
uh we need to give a report um
again this is self-explanatory but i
like to laugh a little bit
because it is a dreaded question
sometimes when can we expect the report
when i'm done a pen testing engagement
and i'm done to to writing the report
while writing the report can be a it's
fun by itself i'm a hands-on guy i just
want to go on to the next
engagement and do all the cool stuff
like uh you know not flying down tunnels
of ones and zeros but trying to exploit
vulnerabilities in systems
the report is not very
a technically challenging thing to do
though it is a very challenging thing to
do right
again you can be creative here and why
is the report important because
again reading from slides the report is
the tangible output of the testing
process
it's the only real evidence that a test
actually took place
if you've done your job right you're
leaving no trace
you're there's no indication that you
were even
ever there maybe a little bit in the
logs but the logs you know they'll get
flushed out eventually
but the report's always going to be
there and the report is going to show
that test was done uh and we're going to
be able to show it to
all kinds of people including auditors
including regulatory
uh bodies that need you to be pen-tested
clients
um we're going to give a letter saying
that this was done
and in the report what you want to do is
you need to assume that
there's three types of people that's
going to be digesting that report
we're going to have senior management
they want to have the executive summary
non-technical
are we good are we bad and most of the
time it's bad
how bad is it it management they want to
look at
what the system looks like and be able
to budget time and budget people to be
fixing those vulnerabilities
and then a really really technical
section where it shows you exactly how
to reproduce the results line by line
what scripts were run
what did you see what did you do for the
it staff that's going to fix the holes
they can go in
and really understand what's going on um
so i'm right in the middle of my
presentation here and
i'm basically done on the pen testing
methodology
um as we can see all the steps are laid
out in front of us
if we follow these steps there is room
for creativity inside of each of these
but we definitely do want to follow
these steps to make sure that the
product that comes out at the end
is repeatable and something of value
um so i'm gonna thank you for this part
of the
presentation you've got my linkedin here
twitter i just uh got a twitter um
i think a few days ago honestly and i'm
gonna start posting some content on
there
uh most of the content that i've posted
up to now is on linkedin
uh so let's um
please think of questions that you might
have and we might have time at the end
to do some questions if not we can take
them to slack
but i'd like to get to the other part of
my report here
give you a big warning here i go from
dark mode to light mode
the next slide is going to be very very
bright so you might want to put your
sunglasses on shield your eyes or
um just be careful one two three here we
go
climbing uh some of you might know why i
call this talk because it's there
um they've been because it's there has
been
called the um
the three most famous line in
mountaineering in the 1920s george
mallory
set out to climb mount everest uh he
went three or four times i forget
my history is not that great of climbing
but he went out to climb mount everest
and um at a press conference
uh it i mean there is some question
whether he actually said this or not or
if it was paraphrasing from the uh
from the report or whatnot but it came
out in the news later on that when he
was asked why do you want to climb mount
everest
he answered because it's there and i
feel the same way with hacking sometimes
i know that as
as i was a kid and i know a lot of
people that started out in the industry
by just looking around their desk
and looking around you know no internet
nothing just a few games
um it was there so we just wanted to try
and hack it and see what we could
do with a system see if we could push it
to its limit and see if we could bypass
certain things so
um why climb stuff because it's there
why hack stuff
because it's there so i thought it was a
good way to uh to call this
um this talk quick disclaimer
climbing is dangerous and i have no
credentials on the subject whatsoever i
used to have a
certification for it was called climbing
wall association lead assessor or
something like that internal
uh that's been a last a long time ago
but i just like to go out and climb
another thing i didn't write here is
that i haven't had the chance to climb
as much as i've
wanted to in the last i would say two
years
so if ever you do run into me at a cliff
somewhere at a climbing gym and i'm
barely making up the wall it doesn't
mean that i don't like climbing it just
means that i haven't had time to go out
and climb um most of the by the way most
of the photos here are photos that have
been taking on on trips that i've been
on
um so what's on the agenda
uh what are i'm gonna talk about the
types of climbing it's a little bit like
information technology or cybers the
cybers like
one of my podcasters that i love says
um climbing is a little bit like ikey
where
you might run into somebody that says
hey um my brother's a climber he's been
up mount rainier out west and you're a
boulder
um you don't really have the same skill
set
though they a lot of people that do
mountaineering will do bouldering too
but
uh same thing as as i.t or cyber
security or
anything like that you might run into
somebody and they'll say uh
oh yeah i know somebody who's in it uh
he's a developer and you're in tech
support well you know
you might not have the same skill set so
climbing is a bit like that
it's a catch-all term and there are a
bunch of different types of climbing
one thing i want to go through too is
why i call
climbing methodical and why i call them
a climbing creative same as pen testing
there is
science and there is art to
climbing one thing that i find fun about
climbing is the vocabulary like any
esoteric type
sports or or endeavors that you might do
there's some pretty funny vocabulary
sometimes
feel free to ask me about this on the
slack channel later on but there's one
here that
is probably screaming out to you
screaming obviously
it's called the screen bar fees it's a
it's an actual technical term
um it's a term used in ice climbing so
when you're ice climbing you've got
these
ice axes i actually i have a
show-and-tell here so you have these ice
axes
um and you're swaying this on top of
your head right all the time
it's cold your gloves are not that
insulated because you want to have a
good feel to your hands and everything
else so hands on top of your head
really cold blood drains out of your
hands
you get to the top of the climb um shake
out a little bit either you anchor up
there or you get lower down
and then all of a sudden that warm blood
goes back into your hands your hands are
freezing
no blood into them pins and needles warm
blood comes rushing in
it hurts well they call it the screaming
barfi because you want to scream and
barf at the same time
that's basically what the term is so
again
dino dirt bag is a good term just feel
free to reach out
and we can chat about these things
so let's go through the types of
climbing um
the types of climbing i've i've ordered
these in
in terms of complexity and commitment uh
commitment in the sense of um
being out in nature in being in a place
where
if you get hurt it might be hard to get
rescued and in
commitment in the sense of how much
money it takes to
get into it and how much knowledge you
need so
first off gym climbing gym climbing is
great it's a great way to get introduced
to the uh
to the sport um
safe way to do it there's always people
out there to help you can take courses
uh there's no not a whole lot of
objective
hazards such as falling rock uneven
uneven terrain and stuff like that it's
a great place to get started i
highly recommend anybody who's
interested in climbing to at least go
out
to the climbing gym and uh take a course
or
or just find somebody who's interested
in going
next up on our journey we're gonna talk
about bouldering bouldering is
well climbing a boulder right no ropes
no
safety equipment except for the mat here
you can see that
um as i'm climbing this rock there's a
mat at the bottom so if i do fall
or when i fall in my case i'm not going
to hit
the hard ground i'm actually going to
hit this uh pad
that's there and yes that thing does
fold up and you put on your bag just
like a backpack
and you walk up to the boulder and you
go up
and climb so you don't need a whole lot
of equipment you don't need a lot of
knowledge on how to set up systems
security systems you can just
go out and climb boulders i mean if
you're interested enough you don't even
need a mat
i mean the only problem with bouldering
is every fall you hit the ground
and at my age i don't boulder as much
because hitting the ground hurts
next up we've got top roping i'm going
to take the laser pointer here
just to show a little something so top
roping as you can imagine
jim climbing's in the gym bouldering is
in boulders on boulders
top roping the ropes on top of you so in
this case you can see that
as i'm belaying my daughter here when
she was younger
the rope goes all the way up to the top
of the cliff and back down to her
there's an anchor up there that was set
up so you need to know how to
build a bomber anchor you need to know
how to belay
using a device like this like a belay
device
um and you have to own a rope and
everything else but
if or when she falls
the rope is she's not falling basically
she's just leaning against the rope
there might be a little bit of slack in
the system and the rope
will stretch but in this sense it's
really safe because you're not you're
not falling you're just leaning against
the rope
and it's a great way to get really
comfortable outdoors you can top rope in
the gym
also so this would be your next step
next up we've got sport climbing i'm
going to keep my laser here i know it's
annoying when it's on the screen
but sport climbing is when
the rope you're bringing the rope up
with you as you climb the cliff
as you can see here the rope is not
going to the top of the cliff
my pretty my my lovely wife here is
actually bringing the rope up as she's
going and what she's doing is that
people that have developed these cliffs
these climbing areas they've actually
drilled bolts into the rock and as you
go up
you use a um a quick draw quick rod it
clip on onto the
the cliff and then you clip your rope
here
so this really protects you you could
i mean you could hang a semi truck on on
these things
uh so it's not a 110 pounds falling
woman that's gonna
rip this out of the cliff right um but
the reason i call this a bit more
committed is as you can see here where
she's
standing if she were to fall she would
fall and kind of swing
a little bit right because this is the
part that's gonna that's gonna secure
her
now if she keeps climbing here and she
gets to this part and she's already not
clipped to another piece of protection
the fall is gonna be a lot more
committing because she's gonna fall all
the way down to this piece of equipment
then all the way down that same
length all the way down here plus the
stretching the rope she might end up
down here
that's a serious fall and that is
extremely scary when you're you're on
top of your last piece of protection
and you're looking at a fall and you're
looking at a 10-foot fall
a lot of things can go wrong in that
type of fall
but it's still very very safe
one thing to keep in mind here all this
equipment
the rope the harness the carabiners the
the
bolts on the rock they're all there just
to protect you
you're not using those pieces of
equipment to
pull yourself up the cliff you're
actually using only your hands and feet
now we get into trad climbing if you get
into an area that has
lots of cracks you know there's a nice
little splitter crack here and you see
all these pieces of equipment well these
are pieces of equipment
that you put in yourself so you're
looking at a cam
that actually goes into the rock and as
you pull on it
the the boat the lobes kind of push out
so they really protect you
but that's a lot more committing you've
got nuts you're just going to slide into
ah here slide into the the crack like
this
and if you fall it's going to hold you
but you still really know how to
you still really need to know how to you
know put these pieces of equipment in so
that they're
they'll hold and that's why it's a lot
more commitment on the safety side
and these things cost a lot of money so
it's going to cost you a lot of money to
to get
into here but at this point if you're
lead trad climbing
um you've been climbing for a little
while already
so as you can see we started off in the
gym falling on mats
with people helping you out and
everything else and now we're out in
nature
probably by ourselves putting our own
pieces of gear on the rock
and uh it takes a lot of more
mental fortitude and and whatnot to be
able to do this type of climbing
it's a lot of fun though um
scream barfis look at that um let's take
my opponent off here
so ice climbing uh this is the type of
climbing that i refuse to bring my kids
climbing because basically you're
strapping
26 knives to your body and you're
crawling your way up the ice
so as we looked earlier this ice acts
pretty sharp at the end and then you've
got these things
in your feet um i don't want my son to
throw a tantrum and start kicking me
with these things so i'd rather not
bring him
ice climbing plus it's cold miserable um
for him it's a lot of fun it's a lot of
fun
um so yeah so that's ice climbing
uh other types of climbing alpine
climbing is out in the high mountains it
might take you a day or two to get
or maybe a full day but it's a full
committing
thing it's not parking your car walking
five minutes to the local cliff
this is actually going out in the high
mountains
and hitting a cliff wall whether it's
ice or rock or whatnot
mixed climbing is a it's a mix of ice
and rock
you're you still have those crampons and
those ice tools in your hand but you're
wedging them against the rock in the
rock sections and
hitting them into the um
hitting them into the ice uh in the
icing sections mountaineering
it's not as technical uh again in the
high mountains
uh you're roped up to other people
because you're on a
on a glacier you're doing glacier travel
most likely
and there are crevasses that you can
fall into hidden crevasses under the
the snow in the eyes that you might fall
into so you're you're strapped to other
people
and aid climbing um is
a very different type of climbing where
i
i was talking earlier about putting your
pieces of equipment
into the rock but only using that
equipment as
protection in case that you fall aid
climbing you're you will actually
put some weight on that equipment
pulling on that equipment
uh so instead of just using the rock and
just using your hand and feet you might
be putting
a piece of equipment and pulling on that
piece of equipment to bring yourself
up uh the cliff
um so basically those are the types of
climbing that are out there there are
other forms and other terms and other
ways to mix all of these
ones up but it should give you a good
understanding of why climbing is a very
wide sport and a boulder might not have
the same skill sets as a trad climber
which might not have the same skill sets
as a mountaineer
but something that's in common with all
of climbing is that we're building
systems to protect ourselves or in the
case of aid climbing to actually
go up the cliff so it can get pretty
complicated
one thing that i really really like
about climbing and
and it's also one of the things that i
like about it
is sitting down and talking to people
after a day of climbing we'll sit around
the campfire
and talk about the newest gear the
newest methods
why a knot like a knot
that we would use in a certain situation
they did some tests in the lab and that
knot
is not good for that situation anymore
because they've noticed that in certain
situations it's going to fail
so you should use another knot and it's
a very very technical
sport in that sense and i mean you saw
me
pushing gear up there's a lot of gear
and a lot of
gadgets right so in that sense it's very
methodical if i get to a cliff
first thing i want to do is make sure
that um
it's safe make sure that if i build an
anchor i build it the correct way with
the correct knots with the correct
uh forces and and it's all physics and
so it's very methodical in that sense
but at the same time
climbing can be very creative mostly
because
well you look at this climb here that's
a cool little climb here in atlantic
canada it's called gollum's cave
it hits all the nerd uh things
and um the this
this part as you can see i decided to
climb up
this i'm gonna take my pointer again
here my laser pointer so
i decided to go up here because for me
it fits somebody might have decided to
climb this crack here
uh somebody might have decided to you
know pop out and climb the
rat here there's multiple ways up and
you got to pick the one that works great
for you
another thing that i've noticed is you
know when you're working on a problem in
it and
you wake up in the middle of the night
and um
you you you wake up in the middle of
sorry i've got
chats i should have turned that off but
you wake up in the middle of the night
and you all of a sudden you go like
wow i solved the problem in my sleep you
you weren't even dreaming of it you just
woke up and go like i know the solution
i've been in situations when
um i've i was climbing uh trying to
solve a problem
you know there's a sequence of moves
that i can't do i can do all the moves
leading up to it
i somehow shimmy it around it or pulled
on gear and i can do all the second part
of the climb but that one move i just
can't figure it out
i've had multiple instances where i wake
up in the middle of the night
and i've solved it i know exactly why
i was using these two fingers and i
needed to use these two fingers instead
and my weight was completely changed and
everything else
next day i go to the gym or the climbing
area and lo and behold i've solved the
problem in my sleep
so in that sense it's also very creative
i think we have a few minutes left i see
here i did have a few questions
i'm just gonna first of all thank you
there's my socials again like i said my
twitter is pretty bare at the moment but
i'm gonna be using it a lot more
going forward and um any questions i saw
a couple come in yeah so here's what
we've got for questions
uh do you find oswe type of trainings to
be useful for your team now
and in the future uh oswe
uh definitely any hands-on training
um certs like i said is big in the
consulting world
but anything from uh that that actually
gets your hands on the keyboard
tests your technical skills like oscp
oswe
oscp all these certs that i have actual
real world lab work
definitely uh something to look into
all right and from the same person what
are your thoughts on free soloing
freestyle i knew that was going to be a
good question um don't do it
it's extremely dangerous if people don't
know free soloing is using just your
hands and feet
with no protection uh there's a movie
that come out came out called free solo
alex honold is the world's uh
crazy person in free solo um there is no
reason
unless you want to push your own
personal limits and i cannot
condone doing free soloing i've never
done it i
i like my life and something really if
if a minor thing goes wrong the
consequences are really bad so
i can't in any way uh say that you
should go out in free solo
all right i think that's all the
questions that we've got from the chat
if anyone else has any questions just
pop them into the slack channel
i did see your questions around the
types of fun uh do we still have a few
minutes
yeah we've got about six minutes uh take
your time perfect
so uh i saw here that um a friend of
mine just uh asked me to
talk about types of fun hi jeff um
types of fun there's a climber called
kelly cordes he's
uh he could be a comedian he's one of
the funniest person i've ever heard talk
first of all
uh alpine climbing to kelly cordes is
the reason you wake up early i'll give
you the real reason why you wake up
early to go alpine climbing
it's because there's a lot of hanging
ice and stuff that can fall down so you
wake up
really really early you start the
climbing in the middle of the night and
by the time the sun shines on the face
you should be off the face or
pretty safe kelly cordes says that the
reason you wake up early to go
alpine climbing is because by the time
you wake up you're halfway up the cliff
and you're it's too late for you to turn
around by the time you get to your
senses
it's too late and you can't turn around
anymore so that's why we
we take off early funny guy uh
he's got a theory on the types of fun uh
three types of fun
type one fun is fun while you're doing
it it's
drinking a good cup of coffee it's
drinking one of your favorite adult
beverages on a sunny patio it's fun
you wake up the next well maybe not wake
up the next morning and it's still fun
but
um it's always going to be fun as you're
doing it type 2 fun
is when you go out and it's not that
great
you know you're suffering um it's not
uh you know childbirth could be
considered type 2 fun because when you
wake up the next day or a week later you
think back
fondly on the experience while you were
having that experience it's not great
but um afterwards when you when you
reflect on it
it was fun and type 3 fun is just never
fun it's breaking your hand
it's like you look back on it you go
like yeah that sucked
but climbing and you know
sometimes hacking is a lot of type 2 fun
while you're doing it you're frustrated
you're hurting
you're suffering but then you look back
on it and it was worth it
so i i definitely like to live in the
type 2 fun
place awesome so final question have you
ever done any spelunking
splunking no i haven't had the chance to
go spelunking um
though it is very interesting to me
again the systems are interesting
uh the anchors setting up the systems
using the right nuts in the right
situation and using all the equipment
would be a lot of fun
i never had the chance to go spelunking
while i think people do it around here
uh for some reason it's not anything
that i've ever had the chance to do
awesome well again if anyone else has
any questions drop them into the chat
for now thanks for your talk i will not
attempt to butcher your name
because i cannot speak a word of french
despite growing up in new england you
can you can call me julian
uh julian richard everybody calls me
julian richard um
i've been called worst let's stick with
that then
all right we will uh we'll see you in
the chat