removing nudes with both the law and the
cyber
and wrap up with how to uh
look like you're djing so hand it off to
our first speakers
hello everybody internet
uh i am aaron
i'm farah and we are from the lebak
collective
um we are going to give this
presentation
um about removing nudes with law and
cyber
and then we will talk about uh
dj psyops and perception management
in the club scene um
before we get started um we want to
provide a content warning
we are talking about uh what's
collectively known as
revenge porn we also deal a lot with
cyber sexual abuse and harassment in
this space
um we are not going to be offended if
you need to
take a step away some of these topics
are very hard
but we take it upon ourselves to to talk
about it uh when we can't but
we bear in mind that everyone needs a
content warning for this
um a little bit about us
so i am a computer engineer
and i also specialize in cyber security
policy
uh i'm i've also founded
a organization called decrypted so what
we do
is provide accessible educational
resources
with regard to cyber security
and i'm erin pronounced them i
enjoy working as a security researcher
trusted safety researcher um i started
le bach with a cohort of mine a couple
years ago
and ever since then we've added more to
it so
uh what is labok um fun fact
it's cabal backwards we've never
actually publicly acknowledged that
um but it's uh mostly a hacker
collective
with a bunch of people from other groups
um what we wanted to do when we
initially started it was united
folks who were thinking about tech
criticism folks who were in the cyber
sexual abuse
space and just share resources
get people in the same like chats
so that we could talk about what we're
doing separately
and share resources that we may want to
deploy across
different segments so you may know some
of these groups like cyber decrypted
tech against fascism we are also members
of the new york cyber sexual abuse task
force
um hello to those watching um
that is a joint task force in new york
full of really awesome people uh who
work
in the cyber sexual abuse space um
fighting for survivors
uh we also are the curators of the
museum of modern malware at defcon
um i know it's been a while since the
last irl defcon but
it was cool and it was fun and i'm
excited to do it one day again
uh and um you can contact us at
labok.dev
at labok.dev on twitter you know we we
look forward to every message that we
get there
all right so i'm gonna tell you a little
bit about decrypted which is a new
organization
um so we provide accessible educational
security resources
completely free of charge um so this
is really targeted toward people who
don't feel
like they're included in conversations
regarding cyber security
um so in 2021
cyber security is really a basic
life skill at this point um it is
a key part of cyber self-defense
and there are a few just
hacks that everybody could use uh we're
also
a member organization of the bach and
with that we're also members of the new
york cyber sexual
abuse task force so our largest platform
at the moment
is instagram just to reach everybody so
if you are interested in what we do you
can reach us at decrypted.tech
or on instagram we're also
decrypted.tech
all right so now we're going to get into
something that is very uh
important but not always practice so
we're going to talk about sending needs
safely
so one of the basic things when you're
sending some
anything safely is to use an encrypted
channel
rather than uh just one side encryption
which is called encryption
and transit which is when you have your
message
from the sender going to the server
that processes something and at that
time it's jumbled up and encrypted
at the server level it's then decrypted
with a key
and then they are able to read it
and then it goes to the final recipient
so
what needs to happen when you're sending
sensitive information
is using end-to-end decryption so one
of the software's that we recommend
is protonmail and also
another one that we're going to get into
is signal you always want to use
open source software if you can that way
you know that the claims that are being
made are true
all right so signal this is a
great app that gained a lot of
popularity in 2020
um one of the huge benefits is the
default
end-to-end encryption so this is not
something that you see in a lot of apps
for example
telegram you need to take the steps to
make it end to end encrypted
also encryption is not available
for group chats whereas for signal it is
also with phone calls and
video chats so this also
minimizes the information associated
with your identity
the only thing that you need to sign up
for signal is a phone number
um you can use your own phone number or
you can mask it by using something like
google voice uh
as you can see in the little diagram we
have below
there's minimal information attached to
you with signal
and then with whatsapp you start getting
some more data that's linked to you
so location contacts
then you get into facebook facebook owns
everything
so that's where they get into your
biometric data health and fitness data
um
and then we have some other parts that
just make it easy to use like a built-in
blur tool
really what we're hammering in here is
if something's easy to use
people will use it um and you don't need
to have
a very complicated way
of sending something securely
all right so now another thing to keep
yourself safe is
some photo manipulation this can be
for anonymity or it can be for later
identification
so this is something that comes into
play when we're talking about sensitive
topics like revenge porn
so one of the first things that
unfortunately not a ton of people know
about
is eggs of data so when you take an
image
it's not just what meets the eye there
is an associated file
with over 50 tags on it
some of the things that are there are
extremely sensitive identifiers
so if you're able to open the exit data
you are often going to see a location if
the
if the photo was taken with a smartphone
so it gives exact coordinates along with
the date and time that
it was taken and then other things like
the camera information it also
allows the user to edit the copyright
information
um later we're gonna be talking about
dmca
and where copyright comes into play
so uh this is gonna sound really simple
because i know this is like a major part
of a lot of apps but
um a lot of people just don't turn
disappearing messages
on uh even though we all go to these
apps that have it as like a somewhat
standard feature
um so just your general reminder i don't
know who needs to hear it
but this is a feature that you need to
turn on yourself
um it doesn't need to be for 30 minutes
it could be for a week
um actually most of mine are for a week
because we are
talking about memes um but
you know there's there's actually a lot
of people i know who
who don't actually turn on the
disappearing messages in signal
um basically every app messenger has it
now
um and a lot of them even have
anti-screenshot protection as well
so these are all settings that
unfortunately not
on by default but they are there go and
find them they're very useful
um a little bit about water marking so
remember we aren't just scrubbing
exif data so that we could care about
privacy but
sometimes we actually want to add things
and that's for later identification a
big one is watermarking
uh watermarking your nudes great idea
um it helps us prove later that those
nudes are in fact yours
why would we want to do that well in a
copyright
scenario a watermark will actually help
us prove that you are the copyright
owner for
that material what's great about a
platform like only fans
which we are a member of um
you can actually upload anything to only
fans and it will put the watermark right
in the corner
a very simple way to prove that
it originated from your account um
by the way quick shout out on our only
fans um
we find that it's a great and easy way
to
get us on your case so if you're an only
fan user
you can essentially message us say
i give you the legal right to you know
go find my nudes on the internet
and that will actually be permissible
from
a dmca standpoint which is awesome which
is why we're there which is why we're
helping people out there
it's very simple way about doing it um
uh we have a quick demo of how
some of this might work uh fair yes okay
so
um we're just gonna put together a
situation where this might need to come
into play
um so very
intimate situation where two might
two people might be talking one thing
that always needs to be there
is consent and boundaries um regardless
of the platform this needs to be spoken
about
it doesn't need to be a long thing um
but it is important
so we don't want to be using something
like imessage
um because this will attach a lot of
things
to your identity um so we want to move
this to
an encrypted channel like signal so
before moving to signal we're going to
use something called exif
metadata so this allows us to scrub the
metadata
as you can see one of the things is you
can see the location that the photo was
taken
and you can just remove all of that with
a
key click
and then we're going to move to signal
and
here we have the encrypted channel
and one thing that we're going to turn
on is disappearing messages
um so let's say you want to leave it for
30 minutes
so before sending the picture this is a
matter of personal taste
if you would like to remove or blur your
face
signal has that built in and then you're
able to send it
and again safety does not have to be
a long drawn out process you can see
that this took
about a minute to do
we are going to wrap up with a little
bit about taking down content
um this next part
real quick i'm just going to say the
thing we talk about a lot
is are we giving tools and techniques to
the enemy and um a big part about what
labor
does is we see ourselves as having all
this cyber security knowledge hacking
knowledge whatever
um and we want to diffuse that give that
to people who
could use those skills but don't have
them because they don't work in cyber
so that's people like survivors of abuse
sex workers
but we talk a lot about in the security
community and we talk a lot about in the
cyber sexual abuse space
uh about whether we are giving tools to
abusers um and
i'll just say right now if we ever catch
you doing that you know
you you'll make a lot of enemies uh but
i know that
is not going to stop everybody finding
this content
is very useful if you're looking for
your nudes
it's also very useful if you're trying
to find them and i'm
going to be patently aware of that by
not
talking in detail
one thing about only fans and why
we're often requested by onlyfans users
to
go find their misused content
is because there's a lot of people who
don't want to pay for that content
one of the first places they go to are
reddit
followed by discord telegram twitter
it's not impossible to find these
in fact most reddit uh most
reddit content misuse cases we see on
the only fan slide
they will typically put the only fan's
username as the subreddit
um one thing that we essentially do when
asked is
we'll go to reddit act on behalf of the
only fans user
and say this subreddit is full of
misused content
here's the originals here's the uh the
uh infringing work
um and reddit will take it down no
problem guess what
um another thing for the other platforms
is
just doing a google door um double
quotations around the username you'll
find it eventually
um further research um this is
there's an awesome awesome article i
suggest everyone to put in their browser
and google it
but we're not going to talk it too much
you could take
image fingerprint hashes and essentially
create a database
um of wherever things are being posted
one long-term project that we are
working on is
essentially using forum scrapers that
we've used for the dark net
but use it on forums where they post
you know voluntary sexual imagery
we end up with a database full of image
hashes
and that's something that we can
reference later when someone wants to
know if any of their content's been
leaked there
um really really brief thing on the dmca
um it's a law that
does a lot of things um but for the most
part we're gonna use it as a tool to
uh make sure that copyright isn't being
infringed
um some websites have a very easy form
to use this otherwise you have to
actually
send it in to whatever email address or
contact info
that site might have if they are
operating in the us
and they have user gender generated
content being uploaded
then they have to have participation in
this there will be some sort of contact
info
um if you want the full story um you can
go to our website labok.dev
content we have links to all the major
social media platforms
content takedown sites as well as
a dmc eddy template that you are free to
use that works in the past
very very quickly first you draft the
letter
in the exact format that is required by
law
you send this to the websites either via
that contact form
or the dedicated emails that they have
set up
and you await any follow-ups sometimes
they won't even notify you if the
content's been removed so just be sure
to keep on checking
um but this is this is like our
our bread and butter um this wasn't
like a very commonly used tactic maybe
even like
a couple of years ago i'm very happy
that more people are using this
they're watermarking their nudes they
are copyrighting them in some cases
and going after all the content misuse
that
they find themselves it's very um simple
to do as long as you follow
everything to a t um unfortunately
because of the
you know the the kind of obtuse like
legal understanding
that is required that might be a little
intimidating
just contact us ask for help if you ever
need it
or contact anybody else in this space
and
we'll make sure that we could do the
best that we can
um okay all right we're gonna pivot to
the second part of the presentation
um this is about
being a fake dj uh this is based on
experience
uh i i know it may not work for
everybody but
let me let me begin by talking
a little bit about what psyops are
if you work in the cyber security space
especially in a very particular part of
the cyber security space
you may have run into this um the
idea is that people have perceptions
that can be played with manipulated
um and you you hear a lot about this in
the social engineering
part of the hacking community um
psyops are typically uh
outside of the military context they're
they're they're broadened
social engineering campaigns across a
wide variety of people
um so
a little bit about djing well so there's
a classic look of what a dj looks like
a lot of times they have a turntables
with vinyl records
that's a little old school but the
concept is the same
you have two musical inputs two input
sources
and you are managing between the two
the concept is the same regardless if
you're using a cdj which is the most
popular digital one today
or you're djing with vinyl records um
you're you're gonna basically have the
same setup this is what that setup looks
like today with a digital
interface but since we're learning how
to fake dj
this is a little uh irrelevant
but you can see how on the left we have
an audio source on the right we have an
audio source
you're queuing up a playlist below and
you're managing
what the audience is hearing between the
two
um this is going to be important when
uh we are spinning up perception not
disks
here's the plan we're going to design an
aesthetic and brand for your dj alter
ego
we're going to come up with a playlist
it doesn't need to be that crazy
and uh we're gonna book a gig at a
non-suspecting bar
club or party um here's how you're gonna
do that you're either gonna call ahead
and say you're your manager booking for
the last leg of a tour
sounds they aren't gonna question it um
or you're just gonna walk in on a random
night and claim to be the dj for that
night now this
relies on a unsuspecting or
apathetic staff we'll get into that
later
um four you actually need to do the gig
and then five profit
a lot of these gigs typically pay in
cash or in drinks
um so here are some five tips
on how this works um most important one
confident body movement you got to be
bopping you got to be dancing
the occasional fist bumping if you have
your homies there
you're going to want to like have them
like whisper in your ear
you know you you kind of yeah yeah you
talk
but you got to be smiling you got to be
like looking like you're having a blast
you gotta know what you're doing when it
comes to the
hand movements um like i said we don't
need to know how to dj but you need to
at least
look like you're doing something it
could
i've actually coded and done work while
djing
and it gets the job done programming has
a lot of tip taps
it's fine um
the next one is astroturfing
this is important remember we've
established a brand an aesthetic
um hopefully you have a dj name pharah
what's your dj name
[Laughter]
uh but hopefully hopefully you have your
instagram set up
that's important um instagram is
currency and
the number of followers that you have
will determine
the uh appreciation of that that
currency so
um you're just going to want to acquire
fake followers that's that's what you're
going to want to do
um you can get them for pretty cheap um
you can usually get
uh bulk packages of thousand five
thousand ten thousand
um another thing you need to think about
with this not like i'm some opsec
expert obviously but you are going to
want to buy likes as well
um the sus the suspecting
viewer of your instagram will be able to
see that you have a high follower
account
but not a high number of likes on your
posts
that's a red flag so you're going to
want to budget for
the number of likes and followers you're
going to need
you don't need a bunch i'd suggest 10
000 followers
and then you know a couple thousand
likes across
several posts um but remember everything
you post needs to be part of the
aesthetic
um another way you could hack that is if
you post stories you don't need to
necessarily buy likes on stories
um targeting all right very important
you're gonna want you're gonna want to
find a venue
with ideally these four things it's
known for djs or open mic sets um it's
in a low-key yet artsy area
um dj mail fraud's career was
all in bushwick brooklyn um
unassuming apathetic staff that's
they're your friends
um and they're the ones who are
essentially going to go along
with your grift and known for cheap
drinks
um booze is important um the more
alcohol is in circulation in the bar
the better you will sound and that is
not a you problem
that is a everybody else's problem
so yeah this is the venue
i'm not gonna state which one you could
see the defcon hat
that's how you know i was there um
aesthetic um so we talked a little bit
about this you need a dj name you need
an aesthetic
um you need a really cool poster you
need to dress cool
that's my attempt but you essentially
need to look cool
you need to look like what you think a
dj might look like and
that will go a long way no one's going
to question it when you're the coolest
person in the room
and you're carrying a computer and
saying you're the dj
um people will just go along with it
and lastly you're going to need a tiny
bit of musical know-how um
so i know that this is about being a
fake dj but you're gonna need
bare minimum these skills you're gonna
need to be able to put together a
playlist
i actually recommend putting together
like three playlists
um one sorted by ambient poppy hard
which will be anything from
like rock punk um to like hardcore
techno
and then uh latin i have an entire thing
of latin
um that's that's important
uh don't don't skip on the bad buddy um
you're also gonna want either cheap dj
software or literally just spotify um
spotify has a crossfade option
in the advanced settings you can go an
entire set
using that as long as you have the
playlist queued up exactly the order
that you want to
what they call in the industry selection
you can get pretty far with spotify's
automatic crossfade options so
so don't think that you need any sort of
like new software to do this you don't
you just need to be the selector and
to use the crossfade option um the most
important aspect for transitioning
between songs
whether you're doing it manually or
with relying on spotify's algorithm
you're going to want to
keep beat matching in mind even when
you're not doing this manually
so beat matching the concept is you want
to transition from song to song
where both songs have a similar tempo or
at least
they have a tempo close enough that when
you transition over
um whether it's sped up a little or sped
down a little um
it's gonna want to seem as seamless as
possible when it comes to the beat
you can't go from a slow song to a peppy
song without a little bit
of jarring from the audience perspective
um
so there are plenty of sites and
softwares that do this
um depending on the dj software again i
recommend dj pro it's free
right i think um they will actually do
it for you automatically
uh or you could go to a website like
songbp.com
just type in the song and it will give
you the key
it will give you the bpm and you can
start
planning your playlist accordingly based
off of
what the bpm is so again
a little bit of musical new how know-how
but you can
go a pretty long way faking it
uh and the outcomes are fun i mean you
get to be a dj
essentially um and you get to play a
a a gig which is hilarious
uh and really you get free drinks which
is
particularly half of why i did it
so yeah being a fake dj the secrets
of dj ing kind of spilled there
i mean uh they all look like they're
very busy they're not
they're they're not all right
well thank you um we'd be happy
to turn it over to our moderator i
actually don't know if we're going
are we doing a q a um yeah we've got
time for a q a if you guys want it
fantastic um how much how much time uh
we have
about 10. awesome cool um
well yeah let's do that um are
would we just take that from slack yeah
fantastic i don't see any questions in
there just yet but if anybody wants to
ask up then we can go from there we had
some minor
technical issues that we were working
through during your talk but everything
looks to be good now
so folks may be just catching up awesome
all right so our first question yeah
you can see that one uh what's up with
the gru flag
and where'd you get it oh what that
that's nothing um i got it from the
internet uh
where most people get loose things
nothing to see here
how do you find songs for your playlist
um well
i'm maybe i'm being a sumptuous but i
hope you have music taste um
and if you do have music taste then you
start thinking about
okay what are the songs i listen to when
i'm happy what are the songs i listen to
when it's sad
branch those out into different moods
vibes different playlists and you will
start
to uh you know get the ball rolling
thinking about other songs that you like
that are similar if you have something
like spotify again
the algorithm is everywhere they will
continue to recommend songs based off of
what you've added to a playlist
that's also good for selection um
but you know i get most of my music from
suggestions from friends
suggestions from algorithms like youtube
and spotify
it's it's it's easy once you have a
couple to get the momentum
from all that recommendation and and get
some more on there
um how do you delete exif data through
your phones native at photo apps
or do you need a third party to do that
um yeah um fair maybe you could talk a
little about that i think that was
i don't know which app that was i forget
off the top of my head sure
um so you can't do it on any phone's
native app you can only view the access
data however if you're using apple you
can use
exif metadata or if you're using android
you can use
exif editor so these are free apps
really easy to use
is that for android and ios so
exif metadata for ios and then
exif editor for android
oh and there will be a recording awesome
can you touch more on how
anti-screenshot tech works
um so it's fairly new um
both ios and android have native sdks in
the operating system
for developers to use so
it's not something that you can
implement on your phone
so that it works on every single app it
will vary from application to
application
perfect example is most of the banking
apps have this now
you can't take a screenshot of your
account if you're in the jpmorgan chase
app
for instance and that works on android
and ios
um so it will depend
from app to app to app the way that you
turn it on in something like signal is
you have to go to the advanced
settings and it will
stop screenshots it supposed that but
again it relies on the developers of the
app to
implement it it's not something that you
could turn on across the entire
uh phone operating system um
oh there's more above thank you leslie
um
so do you have a recommendation on how
many transitions you need
to have a tempo versus more down tempo
in a given time if i have an hour long
set should i
peek once or twice an hour more or less
um
yeah i i think you mean like peak like
in terms of tempo
and yeah i i mean i don't necessarily
have a suggestion there i think
um one thing about being a fake dj is
you have
more uh more capacity to monitor the
crowd
and read the room and frankly that's
more important than any sort of musical
skill
um if people are feeling the music then
great you should just continue on
whatever you're doing
um don't try and force cocktail twins
when everyone's
like bopping to uh jlo so
um you know there's you gotta be
cognizant you know
again you're a social engineer you are a
psychological operator you want to
read people read the room get a sense of
what the vibe is
and exploit that you could have 10 peaks
for all i care if everybody's loving it
so
so no recommendation there other than
be cognizant of your environment um
let me look a little i i think leslie
said that there are some talks
or some questions let me just see if i
missed any i think we've caught up on
all of them we've got one last one about
x-fifth data and the parlor hack
and then we'll uh wrap up from there
okay um we don't have to answer that
it's peter
[Laughter]
peter peter peter is our paid stooge
to to give us questions um in this chat
um but i i hear exif data helped with
the
uh uh it helped with
people analyzing people
um who were involved in the interaction
uh i've heard about that
but you know who knows
it's for a different talk all right well
thanks for coming by