we have randy parkman here to give us a
demonstration
on making pizza from scratch and give a
talk on hunting malware beacons it
appears that
in defiance of all the demo gods he's
going to do this live
absolutely thank you moonan um and good
evening to everybody
i have enjoyed this pancakes con
so much there have been so many great
videos and um
it's so hard that it's two tracks i'm
gonna have to go back and watch
a lot of these on the replay so i'm so
glad that they're recorded
my name is randy parkman i work at
binary defense
in threat hunting and
counterintelligence i've done that for
about a year and a half
and before that i worked at the fbi for
15 years
doing cyber crime investigations with a
great team of people
so if you have any questions about
threat hunting in general
or digital forensics incident response
or how to work with law enforcement
i'd love to talk to you about that
that's one of the passions that
i hold very dear um but another passion
is making pizza
so i wanted to do something that would
be kind of fun
and also a little bit different and i
put a poll out on twitter yesterday
and asked if we should you know kind of
play it safe and do some powerpoint
slides or
do everything live including
doing live things on azure sentinel um
while we're baking a pizza and
you know the votes for live definitely
were overwhelming
so that's the way that we're going to do
it um i want to give you a little bit of
my background just so that you know
um you know kind of where i've come from
and hopefully
this will be encouraging to people who
are getting started out as well
um when i was very young i got my start
in programming with my grandmother i
have a super cool grandma
who taught me atari 2600 basic
programming
from magazines that came with the basic
code and
we typed them in one line at a time and
see how it works
i'm also very fortunate to have had a
mom who homeschooled me
and got to learn by doing and sometimes
mess up our family computer
but i think you learn so much more
from making mistakes and then fixing
them than anything else
so that's how i want to approach this
presentation as well i'm going to show
you
uh live as we're kind of figuring out um
how to do these threat hunting queries
i'm going to assume you know nothing
about sysmon or sentinel and just sort
of introduce those
um and the other thing that we're going
to do to just make it a little bit more
interesting
i have here
a pizza that i've assembled and
as i'm starting the threat hunting part
i'm going to put this pizza into the
oven behind me
and then what i'd like you to do on the
track to chat
is let us know when you think the pizza
is ready
when we should check on the pizza i'm
going to kind of be watching it here
over my shoulder
and hopefully not smell it burning and
moon if you don't mind let me know if
pizza
people are saying it's pizza time when
the pizza comes out
that's my cue we're going to switch
topics and go
from threat hunting to how do you
actually make pizza
hopefully ending soon enough that we can
take a lot of questions but if not i'll
go back to threat hunting because
there's a lot
to talk about there so let's get this
got it
i i have to say this is the most guts
i've seen from any presenter to not only
have a a live pizza demo
but uh to have the audience dictate its
face
this will be fantastic there we go and
all right hopefully you can see that
baking and now i'm gonna share my screen
and uh you know because it's always fun
to just share the whole desktop that's
what we're gonna do too
tempting all of the demo gods all right
so there's the
poll definitely almost 80 percent said
live that's why we're doing it this way
so let me introduce first um cismond
and sentinel if you don't know anything
about it sysmon
records all of the things that are
interesting happening on a windows
machine
and soon there will be a linux version
as well sysmon is free software from
microsoft
it's not supported which means if it
blue screens your computer
don't play microsoft um it also takes a
little bit
of work to do some config but
there are some really great websites
like
olaf hartong's modular sysmon config
that will help
you get started but suffice it to say
that sisman is like
the black box flight recorder on an
airplane it records all the things that
you might need to go back
and investigate if something goes wrong
so that's what we're going to use
azure sentinel is not free it's also
from microsoft
but something that a lot of people don't
know
is that it's very inexpensive for a home
lab so
if you're watching the earlier talk
about putting together your own your own
home lab sentinel is a great affordable
way to go
you can put a lot of um
logs in and like uh with a small home
lab i'm paying less than five dollars a
month for all the log processing
and then if you're not sending logs to
it you don't pay anything at all
even though you can still query your
logs so let's get started and just see
kind of what we have so i'm just going
to type in
sysmon and i have a custom function here
it'll prompt me for a where clause to
filter this but let's just start with
looking for
all of the sysmon blogs in the last 24
hours and see what comes up
this is a great way to get started if
you don't know
what logs you have available you can
also go over here
and see there's a lot of custom logs
that i've got
put in here i'm going to collapse this
just we've got some more screen real
estate
you can see there's a whole bunch of
things like process create this is
obviously something that is important
that happens on a computer
when a program starts up and then
there's
process terminated events event id2 is
file time creation changed
but let's summarize this really quickly
just so that we can see
what sort of data we've got the
summarize operator is really important
in kql because it goes from having you
know we've got over 30
000 results here it's capped our results
to just looking at the things that we
want to look at
all summed up so let's do summarize
count
so we'll get the number of events by
event id and also render description
because if you don't know what all the
event ids mean it's kind of nice to see
what they're described as so then let's
let's just click here to sort it by the
count
and see which things are the most
popular and we can see that registry
object added or deleted
registry activity happens an awful lot
image load is like a dll registry value
set is also very popular
and then network connection detected
this is what we're going to focus on
we want to look at every single time
there's been a network connection
now i told you this is a small lab
there's just a handful of computers in
it and it's the weekend so not much is
happening
and still we have over 9 000 events in
the last 24 hours
so obviously we're going to need to do
something if we're going to find
interesting network connections and in
this case what we're going to be looking
for
are network connections that are
regularly repeating like a malware
beacon calling out back to its home
so let's select just the network traffic
now
i'm going to do where event id is equal
to
3 34 3 there we go
and then we should see just network
connections all right now if i expand
one of these things
i will see some details here like i've
got the process id
i've got the process path that might be
interesting
the source ip address and the
destination ip address and then this
host name is a little bit misleading
because it's not a dns host name
it's actually a reverse dns lookup of
that ip
so the next thing that i want to do is i
want to sort of summarize these
somehow right um let's start out by just
projecting the things
that we want so project we'll just take
some of these columns
let's project the computer because that
would be important
the destination ip address
that would be good oh and let's do the
process path too because we want to see
what
process is uh responsible for each one
of these connections right
all right and then how about the
destination port that makes sense too
okay so if we do that um
now we'll see a nice some uh
summarization here where we can see
um when oh you know what i didn't get
the time
created too that would be nice if we can
see what time that was
so let's do time generated
time generated and now
that will make a little bit more sense
all right so already we're getting
a feeling for something that we might
want to investigate
you can see that run dll is running very
often so this was at
1034 utc this is a 1035 1036
these are very frequent connections
right and they're all going out to the
same ip address on port 80.
so hopefully you're already seeing if
you were doing a real threat hunt you
would already
want to start investigating these ip
addresses and here's another one here's
another run dll
32 and it's reaching out to this other
ip address
um but let's say that what we really
want to do
is um if we're in a real live
environment we're going to have a lot of
these to go through we still want to
summarize these
a little bit right so um what i'd like
to do now
is i'm going to summarize
and let's do um just
the count first um
by let's say the computer
the process path the destination
ip
and destination port and you can see
intellisense helps out a whole lot this
is one of the things i like about
sentinel you don't have to type
everything
okay so this is interesting now we went
from 9000
down to just 92 unique items and we can
see
that there's some of these that are
recurring
very frequently right so let's sort it
by count it was
i think it was already kind of sorted
that way but we can see at the top of
the list here in the last 24 hours
or 8 457 um
events network events going to this ip
address from this run dll
and then slightly less to this ip
address
and then of course we see teams pops up
an awful lot
right and then we've got another kind of
suspicious
looking thing here too but not
nearly as many connections so what if we
want to see the timing between
those connections the first thing that
we'll want to do
is we want to sort by
so that we get everything together that
has to do with the same
computer i process and destination ip
so let's do sort by the first thing we
want to do is computer
the next thing is destination ip if
you've ever done a multi-column sort in
excel
you kind of understand what i'm doing
here so i'm putting together
all of the connections that are from
each computer
to the same ip and then
time generated
let's see
and we'll do it in ascending order oh i
see
um i need to
get rid of this summarize now because i
don't need that i'm going to
order this way all right now i've got
things ordered
now i want to do a special kql function
called serialize serialize tells it that
i want to be able to do some
computation between each field and the
next one in serial order if that makes
sense
now um we've already found something
really interesting just with that simple
query so if the rest of this gets
complex and you're like wow i don't even
know what he's doing at this point
you've already got some useful skills in
kql right
but let's take this a little bit further
and let's do some statistical
computations
that sentinel lets us do so let's do
the extend function this is going to
create a new column
so first let's extend the
next time and that's going to be
the time
def let's see
time
or maybe it's diff time date time diff
there we go i'm glad that intellisense
helped me there
we want to compute by seconds
uh between the uh
wait a minute here next time
i was getting a little bit ahead of
myself next time is just next
time generated there we go and now we'll
do
extend um
time diff extend i'm gonna call it delta
time
the change in time is equal to date time
def
seconds between the next
time and the time generated okay so now
we've computed
um seconds or second there we go second
is the right word uh we've computed the
time
um oh i forgot a closing paren
there we go we're computing the
difference in time
between each one of these connections
and the next one
right okay that sort of makes sense some
of these are really weird numbers
they're negative numbers and that's
because
we've got a difference between one
destination ip and the next
one so we also want to extend
the next computer is equal to
next computer there we go
and then let's do uh next
destination ip is equal to
next uh deskt ip
whoops i p not work there we go okay
so now we're going to have a record of
uh what was the next computer and the
next destination ip
and we can filter that so that we don't
get the really strange results we're
computing
a difference in time across things that
don't make any sense right
so i'm going to say another where clause
where
next computer is equal to
this computer and
um and next
destination ip is equal to
this destination ip
okay so if this works then we should
have the
uh time delta there we go the delta time
and they're always positive numbers
these always make sense
okay we're getting somewhere but still
we've got these 9 000 records right
so let's now do a summary
so i'm going to summarize um first
let's do make list
uh the last of
delta time and i want to
call that um how about just the
uh delta time list that makes sense to
me let's call it
delta time list
whoops list is equal to make list
s time and then
buy and i need to tell it how i want to
summarize
this up so i want to do it by again
computer
process panel and destination ip
all right so let's look at that and see
what we've got
now we've got for each one of these
processes that is talking to a
destination ip
all of the the list of delta times
between their connections
hopefully this is starting to look
useful to you
so some of these all right yes the
appearance that the chat is of the
opinion the pizza may be done
oh thank you i was hoping that you'd be
watching that all right
so let's take a look oh my goodness
as pizza chefs are fired i'm sorry this
is an
overdone pizza look at this i am still
going to eat this pizza
for sure but
this is uh this is very brown i think it
will be
okay and my wife is on the side laughing
because this is pretty funny but
that is exactly the kind of thing that
you can expect
when you do a live demo of baking pizza
right so what we're going to do now as
promised is switch
to the topic of how to create the pizza
and
especially when you burn your pizza you
might want another one
so um we'll get right to that and then
um as we take questions i'll see if
there's more interest of a pizza topic
or more interest in the threat hunting
and we'll get to the one that
makes the most sense okay can you see my
screen
uh my video here yeah it appears to be a
measuring cup
excellent all right so i'm going to play
the video and
talk through how to make the pizza but
first i want to introduce this topic
by saying i've seen many many pizza
making videos that were about how to
make the perfect pizza
right and of course that makes sense you
want to make the perfect pizza
but what i prefer is rather than chasing
after the perfect pizza that is too
difficult and you don't attempt
i'd much rather make the pizza that you
have time for that's simple enough that
you actually do um
over the course of the last 20 years or
so
i've calculated rough order of magnitude
my wife and i have probably made over 2
000 pizzas
and each time we do it we try to make it
a little bit simpler
and we've come to this um actually we
both make it a little bit differently
from each other but both are just fine
and we've come to the realization
that um pizza is very forgiving it's
really easy to make and you can actually
mess it up a lot and still get a very
good result so that's what i would like
to share with you the encouragement
that you can do this you can you can try
it yourself even if you've never baked
any bread before
so start with some water um the rule of
thumb
is that you use about three quarters of
a cup of water
per pizza so i'm normally making two
pizzas at a time to feed my family of
four
because we eat a lot of pizza and so i
use about a cup and a half
that should be the hottest water that
you can get out of the tap not scalding
that you could still uh put your finger
in and it's okay
um you also use about one teaspoon
of yeast per crust that you want to make
now if you have just a package of yeast
and you're making two pizzas just open
the packet throw it all
in it doesn't matter a whole lot and i
know real bakers will probably hate that
i'm saying something like that but
you know as long as the yeast hasn't
gone bad it's fine
now i'll tell you one good pizza
debugging tip
or troubleshooting tip if you find that
you your dough doesn't rise at all
it may have been that you put the yeast
in too hot of water
the water is like boiling hot you'll
kill the yeast
now here is a pizza hat i am putting in
a teaspoon of brown sugar
my wife never puts in brown sugar you
don't taste it
but i found that it makes the crust
brown up a little bit nicer
even if you don't have the oven
parameters quite right so i put in
a teaspoon of brown sugar now the trick
is
you don't really need to measure the
flour um and that's a good thing
because if i'm trying to measure flour
adding it slowly a bit at a time
i always forget where i'm at i always
forget how many
cups i've put in already and the the
pizza gets ruined
so um what i do is just add the flour
a little bit at a time and then once
i've got enough
flour in there that it's kind of looking
like this it's getting a little bit
thick
then i add the salt one teaspoon salt
again i try and keep things really
simple just a teaspoon for everything
the teaspoon of salt goes in at this
time also
to preserve the yeast so if you if you
put the salt in
too soon if you just mix the salt
directly with the yeast
that can cause the yeast to die and then
you won't get a good rise
but as long as you put in at least a
little bit of flour you can mix the
salt in at that point and you have no
trouble
now i just keep adding a little bit of
flour
um little bits at a time until the dough
gets to the right consistency
that's the trick rather than measuring
the flour out
you just add it a little bit at a time
now believe me
i have made mistakes with this many
times and just
i got lazy or i was in a hurry and i
dumped in a whole bunch at once and it
just made a mess
i also want to say you don't need a
mixer to do this but it makes it a whole
lot easier
um so once the dough is looking about
like that i want to show you another
pizza hat this is definitely a hack and
not something a real baker would do
and i also want to be clear i'm not
going to microwave this dough so don't
don't be too aghast what i'm doing here
is microwaving some water to get it hot
and then i'm using the microwave as kind
of a
proofing chamber or rising chamber that
water
will keep the inside of it humid and
warm and then i just put the dough
into the microwave but again don't turn
the microwave on this would be
disastrous especially with the metal
bowl
and just leave it in there for a while
until it's risen and it looks like this
now if you have plenty of time then
you don't need to use the microwave at
all if you've got
you know i usually four hours or so it's
about the time that i give for normal
rising at just room temperature
my house is warm enough i will usually
come out from my home office at around
lunchtime
eat my lunch make some dough it really
doesn't take that long
and i'll just leave it out to rise and
by the time it's dinner time the dough
has risen on its
own but i often forget and
i don't make the dough in time and
sometimes we've been at the point where
it's like
an hour and a half till dinner you all
want to have pizza and there's not
enough time to let it rise and that's
when i use that microwave
water and quick rising hat and it works
so once the dough looks about like that
um then you can take it out
and if you can sort of try to preserve
some of the bubbles in the dough that
helps the dough
to rise but really however you do it is
fine
this is my nine-year-old daughter
helping me with the demo because
at this point i couldn't both hold the
camera
and do the dough so um she's trying to
get out about half of the dough and
doing a marvelous job of it
um i really enjoy baking with my family
too it's an awful lot of fun
and then this is the part where it
starts getting kind of scary if you've
never done this before and it seems like
you're going to mess it up
it's going to work out just take a deep
breath it will be fine
um making pizza is a lot of fun and
the thing that can help you relax is to
know that when you're making it at home
it doesn't matter if it's perfectly
round it doesn't matter if it's smooth
it doesn't matter if it looks perfect
it's going to taste just fine
unless you leave it in the oven too long
and you burn it like i just did but
otherwise it's going to be fine
so we have a clean counter that we've
scrubbed down really well
and then we just add enough flour to
this so that it's not
too sticky and you can actually work it
with your hands um
you you could use a rolling pin and roll
it out and that's not disastrous but
the only thing that will happen if you
use the rolling pin is you'll kind of
remove
some of the air bubbles that have built
up as that dough was rising really
nicely
and so i mean your pizza will still
taste fine it'll just be a little bit
flatter it won't have those nice sort of
risen bubbles in it if you want to get
the most
bubbles try to stretch it rather than
roll it if that makes sense
and this is the part that can get really
scary
if you try to get fancy with it i have
tried
over and over and over again to throw
the pizza dough into the air twirl it
around
like some kind of expert and you know
what just about every time i've dropped
the pizza dough and nothing good has
ever come of it so i don't recommend it
unless you're just very talented at that
um just try to sort of stretch it out
here's another pizza hat
from all of the uh recipes that i've
ever seen
have said to put the pizza directly on a
pizza stone
but i have a really hard time with that
like i'm always messing up the pizza
when i do that
so instead i'll put it on a piece of
parchment paper which makes it a whole
lot easier to get in and out of the oven
now here's the thing that i was kind of
hoping would happen as we did this demo
the pizza dough tour that is because i
didn't
let it run in the mixer and knead it
long enough um the longer you need it
the more elastic it becomes and the less
that it'll tear
but what i wanted to show you is it's
fine even if the pizza dough tears you
can just fix it just sort of pinch it
back together again
and it'll be just fine now the most fun
about making
pizza at home is that everybody gets to
put whatever toppings they want on it
when you put it in the oven you want it
to be the hottest oven that you can
and a pizza stone works great heat up
the pizza stone in the oven ahead of
time
but i have also made this on all kinds
of metal pans and it's also worked out
just fine
this pizza or this oven i've heated up
to 500 degrees fahrenheit which is
260 celsius um and that's worked out
really well
real pizza ovens are like 900 degrees
and
um they're super hot so you really can't
get
the the oven too hot at home um this
pizza
is a special one it's half dairy free
and
half full dairy cheese so that everybody
can enjoy it whether um they can eat
dairy or not
so um i'd like to stop now and take
questions and see if there are any
questions about
pizza or about the threat hunting
queries
and then if we don't have any pizza
questions i'll get back to threat
hunting and round it out with that
already yeah uh your oven was perhaps a
little hotter than
people were anticipating by the look of
it
alrighty uh so we have one person asking
if you
add a semolina i guess flour at the end
to build the crust
oh excellent yes i've heard that the
semolina flour
will do a really good job um but i don't
i just keep it really simple
um i've used all-purpose flour sometimes
bread flour it comes
out a little bit differently depending
on what sort of flour you work you use
but any of those types of flours will
work just fine
all right uh can the dough be over
kneaded
oh that's an another really good
question so i actually
have an excellent book called the bread
baker's apprentice
and the author deals with that very
topic
and uh the author's opinion which i
trust quite a bit
is that you just cannot need it too much
um my own experience and
you know as a person who just tries
things out
um i have also experimentally just
tried to let the pizza knead for a
really long time like 30 minutes
in the mixer or when i've done it by
hand just
keep going until i can't knead it
anymore it's never
been messed up there's never been any
problem with that the only problem that
i've ever
had with pizza and kneading was not
needing it
enough so i'd say if you're not sure if
you've done it enough just keep going
until you're tired of needing and then
it'll be just fine
all right switching uh switching back
over to your other topic
we have a question as to whether you can
detect beacon with jitter
using kql or is that something that's
too difficult
oh excellent um i'm glad that that
question was raised because that's where
we're going to go
with building this kql query next
so if that's all right it'll take a
little while to answer that question
but uh but the short answer is yes we're
going to use statistics we're going to
use a standard deviation
and figure out even if there is some
jitter
in the beacon check-in we can find the
ones that
are most likely
repeating now i also want to point out
that
with the beacons that we're going to
find here we also just found them
because they
were the top of the list for computer
process and destination ip just the the
count
of the number of connections so it stood
out that way as well
just because they're so frequent but i'd
like to show you this
way to summarize um and
calculate the standard deviation because
i think that's really interesting as
well
all right and i'm really glad my wife
turned the oven off because i was
getting very warm sitting
with my back to a 500 degree oven
all right so we've got the make list
here
um let's do some other uh
summation summations too let's do uh
connection count i'm just giving it a
variable name here
it's equal to count and we'll run that
okay now we've got number of connections
that's going to be useful
and then let's also do the standard
deviation so i'll just call this
standard d is equal to
stdev and give it the
delta time right that's what i called it
delta time there we go
okay so now what we've computed
is not only um the number of connections
but the standard deviation between the
timing of those connections
and you can see that we're probably not
going to find anything
interesting any sort of malware
beaconing for anything other than
under uh 10 connections right so
let me filter that now and say where the
connection count is greater than
well just for sake of argument let's
just do five just so that we see a few
more results
right off the bat okay
now we're seeing for a connection count
with 10
there's a standard deviation of 9166
and you can see that's because these
delta times are all over the board like
there was a connection there's a pair of
connections that the time between them
was
6241 seconds there was another one that
it was just 481 seconds
that doesn't seem very regular so let's
sort that or
let's sort by standard deviation
and let's do it um
ascending so that we have the lowest
standard deviation
at the top of the list and if you're not
familiar with this this is just a
measure
of how regular the connections are so if
the standard deviation is very low
that means that there's not a whole lot
of deviation
between the values in the list if the
standard deviation is very high there's
a high degree of deviation between them
or a lot of variance
and you can see that just by sorting by
standard deviation and putting the low
numbers at the top
now we've got the most beacon like
connections the most regularly repeating
ones
right up at the top of the list so this
gives us a way that if we didn't even
want to look at the rest of these
like let's say that we wanted to set
this up as an alert
that would run every so often and send
us
um uh maybe a message on teams or
start a new ticket or something like
that um
let's just filter for the things that
are
very low on the standard deviation
measurement so this is where jitter
comes in
now if you're not familiar with it when
you create
a remote access tool like cobalt strike
beacon
and you're giving it configuration
you'll want to tell it how often to
check in
and you'll also want to tell it how how
much jitter to put into the check-in
times and that's the amount of
random variation between
check-in times and the reason for jitter
if you're a red team operator
is to avoid um a blue team doing
analysis just like we're doing here you
want to be able to fly under their radar
so
instead of having a check in like every
10 seconds you know 10
10 10 11 10 9
11. that type of check-in which is so
easy to
spot you want to do something that is um
you know maybe five seconds here and
then 15 seconds later on
i try to get the standard deviation up a
little bit
and maybe hide in the noise that's the
point now
the only way that you can really
hide in the noise using this sort of
regular repeating check-in
is to have a very long polling interval
you know like
you know maybe 15 minutes between
check-ins
and then have a high degree of jitter so
that one time you're checking in
one minute later the next time it might
be 15 minutes
and create a lot of variants in there
now the reason
that i think a lot of red team operators
and definitely
uh professional threat actors don't
do that um and let me just say i've
studied an awful lot of malware beacons
and i almost never see that kind of
jitter
the reason they don't want to do that in
my opinion is because it's really
annoying
as a red team operator to work with a
beacon
that you don't know when it's going to
check in again that means you're sitting
on the other end of the keyboard
typing some command and you don't know
if it's going to run in one minute
or 15 minutes or maybe an hour later
that makes your
work day go really really slowly and you
start to wonder if your beacon is
even working at all right so
let's first filter um let's do
where the standard deviation is
uh let's say less than and here's where
we
we as the threat hunter are going to
pick
a number that makes sense to us so just
looking at these numbers
i'm going to say how about standard
deviation is less than 200.
i think that's going to highlight just
the connections that we're interested in
that seems to be doing a pretty good job
now we can see these
standard deviations are really low but
i've seen an actual malware
beacon with i think it had 10 minute
pulling intervals and a really high
degree of jitter it ended up being about
an 87 on the standard deviation scale so
this should still
get us the values that we want now the
next thing that we want to do is maybe
expand
our time that we're searching and see if
we still get
reasonable results over a longer period
of time
now you can see we've got a few more
a few more things that are popping up on
our list this is over the last seven
days in this lab environment
and we can see okay run dll run dll this
be loader two that looks suspicious too
these other run dlls
these are all definitely suspicious um
not so sure about this one though
this is sort of weird the destination ip
is a ipv6 and it looks like there's a
whole
bunch of zero so these are a whole bunch
of connections that happen
at the same time now i don't really want
to see that result
so what i'm going to do is tune this
query a little bit more
and let's say for delta time
i don't really care about delta times
zero
so let's put another where clause here
and say
the delta time is greater than zero
or i could even expand it and say
greater than one i don't think i've ever
seen
a malware beacon that its check-in time
was one second that would be incredibly
noisy and we'll probably catch it
another way just by
most amount of traffic so i just did the
delta time is greater than one and now
you can see i filtered out some of those
things that i didn't care about
so much on the list i'm pretty happy
with this right now like
if i had over the last week uh my
sentinel sent me an automated alert to
say hey you might have a beacon you
should check out
for each one of these those would be
good results that i could actually do
something with
so let's see we've got a little bit of
time left i've got some more things that
i could do
adding in some dns data here or maybe
looking up some of these ip addresses in
threat feeds
but i'd like to go back and see if there
are any questions that i can take
before we run out of time the
one that showed up earlier is uh
admittedly somewhat controversial so
i'll go ahead and elide the
controversial part
but what are your favorite toppings uh
for pizza
oh my goodness so i am an adventurous
pizza hacker
and i like putting weird things on pizza
so my favorite thing to do is actually
ask other people
what they like on their pizza and then
try that um
somebody from germany told me a lot not
long ago that
tuna right out of a can was a good
topping and i have to admit
i was not so keen to try that because
tuna's okay on a sandwich but
i didn't think it was going to be good
on pizza i tried it
it was pretty good uh not one of my
favorites but it was definitely worth
trying i
enjoyed that um something else i've done
on pizza
that has come out really well i'm in the
pacific northwest and smoked salmon is
huge here
so i did some cream cheese and
and some fresh mozzarella and then put
the
smoked salmon on top and i actually put
the smoked salmon on
after it came out of the oven so that it
didn't dry it out too much and it was
still
just that perfect sort of moist
salmon with that good smoky flavor i
thought that was really good
i also like fresh toppings after the
pizza comes out of the oven i like to
put
fresh basil and some
uh oh what are some of the other fresh
things that we put on oh fresh tomatoes
that's really good um and i like them
when they're not all baked and dried
but really pizza toppings are personal
and i think whatever you like on your
pizza
is the right thing to put on your pizza
and unless you just like to be
adventurous like me you don't really
even need to worry about what other
people like on theirs
fantastic i i like the way that you
handled that particular
question there that's something that can
get a little fraught with some people
oh for sure
i don't see any everyone
is is now talking about how they really
want a pizza now
uh despite diets and other such
impediments
so i think that you've gone and nerd
sniped the entire channel at this point
excellent all right well i've got a
little bit more i wanted to
add on to this query and just because
we're running short on time
i want to sort of show you um what other
data i have added into this
so this is this is pretty much the same
query that we built before
but i've added on dns data because
i wanted to see has there been a dns
query that resulted in an answer of one
of these ip addresses before
so what i've done is a kql join
and if you've ever done sql database
queries
you should be familiar with joins
they're so valuable
and it works in kql as well so i've told
it that the kind of join i want is
left outer what that means is i want
all of the results from the left table
the left table is this
right it's this result that we're
looking at right now in other words
even if there is no dns query that
matches this ip address i still want to
see this result i just want to see that
there was no dns query
because i don't want pardon me adding in
extra data to cause me to miss some of
these really important
results so then i've joined it
to another custom data source that i've
got in this
environment i've got both ciracata and
zeek
both of those will read dns queries on
the wire
and then i've used another
really really handy kql function here
called parse json parse json
as one of the parsing functions along
with
parse csv or parse xml
that will take a field that's in your
results and make it so that you can
query inside of that so i'm going to
skip ahead where i figured out
that in ceracata the dns
is the question and or the answer is
put in a json format and i just care
about the first one
i want to extend the answer r data
which is the resource data coming back
into this new field called our data then
i want to summarize by
the resource record name that was the
query
and the r data so in in other words i'll
just take this query
out actually and you can see what this
results in all by itself i think that
will be really
instructive and helpful so you
understand where i'm going with this
query
here we go all right so let's just run
this for the last
um four hours so we don't get bombarded
with a lot of
results so what this is saying is that
these are the queries and
sorry these are the queries on the right
and on the left
these are the responses and so i can see
already there's one of my
ip addresses that the cobalt strike
beacon is calling out to
and the dns query that was made for that
is wellernaft.top
and i think we're just about done with
time so i will
close it there and thank you so much i'm
gonna be around in slack chat so i'd be
happy to
keep chatting with you and answering
questions fantastic thanks
for uh bringing your double live
demo to pancakes con randy we're very
glad to have had you here