uh shecky's been in it for over 20 years
and has been working as a security
engineer for the past
six uh he's a an organizer for chicago
burpsec and a volunteer for hacks for
kids
heck for kids i'm sorry good afternoon
everybody
today i'd like to talk to you guys a
little bit about something called
burnout
it's not going to be a highly technical
talk it's a subject that goes
very deep but is very important
especially for those of you just
starting your careers here as you get
older
you start to understand it a little bit
more but
it's not something that is you hear
people talk about it but you think
that can't happen to me and it can
happen to just about anybody
and it's one of the reasons why we have
some of the issues that we have in the
industry
in the field today so burnout is real or
why i love trains and yes we will get
into the train stuff
in a little bit
there we go so first off who am i uh i'm
shecky i'm also known as michael kafka
i'm a senior security engineer for a
futures trading company i have my cissp
and just recently got my gcih
you can reach me on twitter it's silicon
shecky and yes i do tweet about trains
occasionally
i've got my blog site um i help organize
one of the burbstocks here in chicago
which is the security meetup
and i'm a trained and model trained
model railroad aficionado
i'm not the best in the world i'm not
the worst in the world
so let's get into this topic itself
burnout
what is burnout the easiest way to
describe it is burnout is that feeling
of i don't want to do this
you wake up in the morning you don't
want to go to work you don't want to do
anything
it's a loss of interest it's an i don't
care type attitude
it can lead to depression it can lead to
anxiety
and it's something that you really need
to start looking at early on the anxiety
is usually about the first thing that
i've found that people wind up having
with
that anxiety of do i really want to do
this do i really want to go into work oh
god here we go again another job like
this
oh god i'm going to have to deal with my
boss again
it's not something that's fun to deal
with it all
and it's something that leads people out
of the infosec
or whatever other industry that they're
in but especially in the infosec because
we put so much pressure on ourselves
we think that we must have all the
answers
we feel that we are imposters imposter
syndrome fall
can lead to burnout just about anything
that makes it
non-fun or non-worthwhile to yourself
is a form of burnout in its own right
so overworking is probably one of the
biggest things that we've ever
heard of from burnout and you know
it's those 24-hour day shifts 12-hour
day shifts seven days a week
the large amount of time with no break
whatsoever
and that can be caused by poor
management not having enough staff on
hand managers don't know how to deal
with you
or with other people
that brings things down to a section of
what am what are they doing wrong who
can i talk to about it can you
if it's management talk to your manager
say hey listen
you're pushing me too hard you're
pushing me too far
the best managers out there aren't going
to want you to burn out they're going to
help you take that step back so that way
you can go ahead and do that
the other thing that i've noticed that
causes burnout is being over
passionate the word passion at another
con
was brought up and we had this huge
discussion there
about passion is it a good thing is it a
bad thing and it depends upon how you
define
passion passion can be as simple as
having a very big
interest in it passion can go into
an area of all you want to do is xyz
all you want to do is do your infosec
all you want to do is do your research
and you delve into everything on that
and that's
all that you have and you've got nothing
else around you
so what happens when you hit that wall a
frustration level
you lose all interest again
you get into a situation with burnout
where you need to fight it
the biggest mistake that people make in
our field
is paid time off we all get it
people do not use it and i don't mean
using pto to go to
a security conference i mean using paid
time off
as paid time off telling your manager
that yes i am taking this week off
and i am not answering emails i am not
answering my phone
i am out of service i need to
rest and recharge my batteries
you need to take the pto is there for
that reason what
period it's there to give you that
chance
to take that step back to step away from
the
grind to step away from the stress
now that's not to say that you won't
have other stresses on on another side
or from somewhere else but to step away
from that work stress
to get that off the mind
you run into another issue though and
this happens with all of us you're on
vacation and you start wondering
especially as it gets nearer the end
what am i going to walk back into
and that's just something that that
there's not a real good answer for
how to stop it the answer to that is you
stop it by stopping it
the real answer is and i found this is
talk to the people around you talk to
your family talk to your friends say
hey listen i'm starting to think about
this can you distract me from it
find something to distract you whether
it be a hobby whether it be going out
for a bike ride
hobbies are a big way overall even
without paid time off to go ahead
and de-stress and fight that burnout
and i'll be showing you one of my
hobbies in a few minutes here which is
trains and you'll
be noticing all the trains sitting in
these slides here
uh outside of the opening slide all the
trains are photos that i took
family and friends going out and doing a
walk
in nature with them which i get into in
the last bullet point there
going ahead and just spending time
sitting down playing board games not
computer games necessarily but board
games
going and sitting down and having a nice
dinner with someone
these sorts of things uh if you're into
going ahead and singing karaoke can be
fun
going to an amusement park can be fun
something that
again gets you away from that stressor
level of work
that constant oh my god i have to think
about this oh my god i have to solve
this problem
oh my god oh my god oh my god i don't
want to deal with this anymore
so you take that step back and you let
your body refresh you let your mind
refresh
meditation is a very good way to go
ahead and relieve the stress
if you want to start trying to do that
and that's just as simple as sitting
down for 10 minutes and counting breaths
it meditation can be that simple just
step away from it all don't try don't
force your mind not to think about
anything
just focus on one simple thing like
counting breaths
these are all basic ways of helping to
fight that stress and that stress is
what leads you to that burnout
in the movie real genius they have a
great scene there where they're talking
about laszlo down in the tunnels and if
you haven't seen the movie real genius i
highly recommend it it's a fun great 80s
movie
but they're talking about the genius
that came before him the top dog that
came before
val kilmer and mitch and mitch's
characters
and val goes val's carrot character
chris
knight goes ahead and says yeah he broke
in a major way
he thought he he loved solving problems
but he thought his answers were the
answers to everything
so one day somebody told laszlo that
what he was creating was hurting people
and it cracked him
severely and that's something that we
all have to
understand there is no answer for
everything
infosec itself is really nothing more or
less than risk mitigation
overall it is something that is
constantly changing
and there is no way that you're going to
be an expert in every single section of
it
you might know a lot about specific
areas but there's always going to be
somebody smarter than you and there's
always going to be a new question and a
new way that pops up out there
and the best way of going ahead and
being able to
take care of that stuff is being fresh
taking that step back relaxing your mind
out i find honestly
with to help me without with answering
questions is stepping away from
all of it for a bit because all of a
sudden out of nowhere an answer will pop
into my head
and that's something that should work
for you also take a step back
stop thinking about it you overthink it
you're going to come up with the
with the with the wrong answer or the
harder way of doing it
and you're going to start doubting
yourself and then you start doubting
yourself
and then you start stressing about it
and then you hit that burnout level
again
and it's not fair to yourself
the only way you're good for other
people is to take care of yourself in
the long run
physically mentally emotionally
you can go and see a professional for
help and i highly recommend that there's
nothing wrong with that
but you have to understand and if you
can't recognize the
the symptoms talk to somebody else that
you trust
and see if they see these symptoms in
you the depression the anxiety the lack
of wanting to do
stuff the losing interest in things that
interest you not just work wise but
overall
because it all starts integrating
together as you go down this path
so as i said there's a lot more to it
than that
and we're going to get into the trains
in just a moment here
but i want you to understand that i'm
i i sound preachy it's because i've seen
too many people burn out i've seen too
many people
just not lose it we've seen
in the industry too many people get to a
point
of no control anymore and not ask for
that help
and we want you to be good we want you
to be safe
we want you to be able to help others
it's not something that's going to be
easy and it's not something that
looking at oneself is always the hardest
thing to do
and it's not something to be ashamed of
to turn around and say i'm feeling
burned out takes a lot of credit to
somebody
to do that saying i need to take a step
back
i'm burning out i need that time away
but you have to do it
otherwise you're just going to drive
yourself into a ground
and into an early grave and that's not
something
anybody anybody wants to see it's
happened to too many people
so let's get away from that and start
talking about trains trains and model
trains
and what you're seeing here in this
background is this is my actual layout
right here
over on the uh left hand side that's my
son
running one part of the layout you've
got a
close-up of one of my newest engines
that i've got uh what's called a gg1 it
was an
electric engine uh it was used a lot in
pennsylvania
you've got sitting next to the right
there
is a shea engine it's a type of steam
engine
but instead of horizontal drivers
drive rods everything is vertical on it
they don't go fast but they're very
powerful they were built for
logging runs and then finally is just a
shot out the back of an old pullman car
that i took
now i'm gonna stop sharing my screen
here for a moment
and we're going to get right into this
why model trains why trains at all
well there's two different ways of
looking at it i do some rail fanning
which is going out and actually seeing
trains out on the rails i'm i'm lucky
i've got a
train museum not too far away my son
absolutely adores training got me
pulled me back into all of this and then
there's the model railroading aspect
that you can do
right in your own home and you say well
i've got a small apartment well that
doesn't matter
there are a few different scales of
trade of model trains out there
this is the next to smallest i don't
have the smallest one which is even
smaller
the next size down from here which is
called z scale and i'll go over the
scales in a moment
is small enough where you can actually
run it inside of a pelican briefcase
you can actually make a setup along
those lines
so you have your z scale which is the
smallest one out there
you have your n scale which you'll see a
lot of
you have your ho scale
so you can see the difference in size n
scales approximately half the size of
h o h o is approximately half the size
of the infamous
o scale
o scale the best known manufacturer of o
scale is lionel
lionel back in the day also made
something called standard scale yes this
is an original
1920s era standard scale engine
yes it still runs yes it's still the
original motor
inside of it the wheels have been
changed once or twice
um i've gone ahead and done a little bit
of work on it myself that was
actually my grandfather's engine right
there
there's so much different areas of model
trains
in model railroading you can get down to
building models
for your layouts you can make a simple
layout like what i've got
what i've got which is just some basic
loops
you can get into intricate layouts with
mountains and scenery
but in about in the end you get into
something like this
this is your basic engine and yes this
is a 1920s one also
but you've got your armatures it's basic
electronics
this is a switch for allowing the train
to go backwards and forwards
and it's so pretty easy to work on
itself i actually have
i'm in the process of finding a new uh
wheel for this so that way i can
get this one back up and running the
engine itself does run though
so you have your engines like that you
can learn
electronics not just from the engines
but from wiring up
attracts a track site simple tracks like
what i
showed you in my picture there is i
have one controller per track more
complicated tracks you have blocks and
everything along those lines
model building is actually from the
1970s here my dad and i built this one
but you get houses you can do building
you can do free building
the nmra which i had shown up on the
slide and i'll show it again when i
re-share the screen
is they've got all sorts of information
on their website
the basics of wiring track wiring the
basics of model building
but they go all the way up to master
level stuff and master
certifications in model railroading and
building
scenery and building track layouts
designing
don't know if a lot of you realize this
but the original hackers the original
infosec people back at mi i think it was
mit
were model railroaders
you take a look at a model railroad
track when you have switches and
everything
and it's like looking at a network in
its own right
so there's a tie in there so it actually
does makes logical sense as to why
but you still get that step back as far
as i'm concerned
there are different styles of trains out
there this here
if you look at the difference between
this right here which is my
one of my more recent trains which i'm
not running right at the moment and this
here
you go well one's a steam engine and
one's a uh
non-steam engine or diesel i go yes
but there's differences that you don't
see on the two of these also
this one here is what runs off of what's
called dcc
or dc dc and dc power is
your basic setup you plug everything in
you plug your controller in and it runs
around
dcc or digital command control
gives you a way of going ahead and
running multiple trains on the same
track
timing out the engines so that way they
don't hit each other
all the way down to actual sound effects
such as chugging sounds
and whistles and bells
and even the sounds of engineers on the
trains themselves
now you say okay so what do we get into
when we're dealing with this
it can be as simple starter sets start
off around 100
or so if you want to go wooden trains
with your kids that's even less
expensive to start off with a basic
set but you can go ahead and go through
all different sources
you make it as complicated or as simple
as you want
i sit down in front of my train set and
i kick back and i relax
and i'll sit there for hours on end just
watching the trains go around
maybe reading a little something just
letting the the white noise of the
engines
go at it my son will come in and say i
want to run this train i want to run
that train it gives me a chance to bond
with him even more
so you're dealing with stuff that again
for me i find
nice and relaxing
these trains come with and i don't have
a way of pulling this one apart let me
go grab
this one here
this right here
is actually an engine from when i was a
kid this was actually one of my two
favorites when i was a kid
and i'll show you what i'm talking about
squares
ease of working on them because top tops
right off
and then you get into just got a couple
basic wires going to a motor right in
the center
and really upkeep on this is cleaning
the wheels
putting a drop of oil in the bearings
every so often and lubricating the
rods and that's it that's your most
basic
dc engine
and different dc engines will run a
different
we'll run different ways you'll have
ones that can go ahead and
like this one here from back in the day
was made for kids
more so because it was made to be able
to run fast it doesn't
like running slow
you have other engines such as this one
here if i bring
this one up to full speed on the
throttle
it's going maybe half the speed of the
of this one
on full throttle so you get a difference
in types
you can get involved with model railroad
clubs in your area
and you can get involved with other with
other aspects of it
um your hobby shops
along those lines your driving shops
will always be willing to help out it's
a very
friendly hobby overall
and there's always something to learn
with it
now as far as the engine's going rail
fanning goes
now as far as this goes you've seen
my picture here you've seen
this here this is a
each type of each one of these engines
are different types this is an sd40 i do
believe
this is the world's largest steam engine
the big boy which did a lot of traveling
and was
back up and running for the first time
in 60 years back in 2019
but you have all these different types
of trains out there
you can go out and do photography of
them you can go out to your local
train yards a lot of times or the tracks
run close by your house and if you're
into ham radio
listen to the chatter on your ham radio
there's a specific set of bands
that you can use a scanner for that you
can listen to the traffic
to the chatter between the engines and
between the control towers
very very easily there's no
encryption on or anything they're wide
open
it's fun to listen to but it gets you
outside and
that but there's some safety rules when
you're doing the outdoor train stuff
number one you want to stay at least 25
feet away from the tracks
that's pure safety if you don't do
25 feet away from the tracks well number
one half
most of the time you'll be trespassing
and number two you're really risking
yourself getting hit by the train
or getting pulled it sucked in as the
train goes by by
any sort of vacuum from the speed of the
train going by
so enjoy the outdoor trains safely
now
as they said i threw this all together
really fast so
it seems like i'm running a little bit
short on everything
so i'm gonna open things up to uh
questions shortly
because i'm sure a lot of you might have
uh some questions on it all
and feel free to go ahead and
ask away do we have any questions for
starters
alrighty so i don't see any specific
ones uh just
yet but let me uh just ask a couple of
my own real quick
uh to see if we can emphasize a few
different points
uh going back to the burnout section uh
what kind of experiences with burnout
have you had
i've had a few different experiences
with burnout
and actually none of it has really been
i've had one experience in the i.t world
with it directly
and that was back when i was doing
network engineering and consulting
and i was the one-man crew and i just
there was no way i could take a break or
anything i was the last man standing in
the department
and it started to affect me and it
really started to affect not just me but
my relationships with the young lady i
was seeing it
the lady that i was seeing at the time
my significant other and i our
relationship started to break down
i was worried about everything i was
constantly thinking i was going to get
fired for the smallest mistake
and it was partially because i was
working so hard and it was partially
because
i saw everybody else jump ship
um but it's it's
it's along those lines now as far as
actual burnout goes i used to do wedding
photography
and that got to a point where it
stressed me out so much that i stepped
away from photography completely for a
couple of years
nowadays i enjoy it as a secondary hobby
but it just
got back any influence smart trains and
new technologies being used we'll get to
that in a minute
um but there's
it burnout to me is been something that
since i actually
found a couple of real good employers
i've worked for
they forced me to go ahead they
initially forced me to start taking time
off
and nowadays it's like okay yeah i need
to step back i'm going to take a step
back i need to take a mental health day
just a day so that was there so that's
something you'd recommend that
managers would do then is is to
encourage their employees to
take time uh for avoiding burnout
i think that they should encourage it i
think they should encourage it
where they are not getting in touch with
that employee
i think managers need to be taught what
warning signs to look for for potential
burnout
and a lot of that's because you're not
going to see it yourself
or you're going to be afraid to talk to
your manager about it
and you got to get over that fear but if
the manager sees it and says i want you
to take a day off
jump at the chance because they're
seeing something that you're probably
not
excellent thank you for uh expanding on
those points for us
you're welcome so it looks like we have
a question inside of slack here any info
on smart trains and new technologies
being
used um i haven't
thought too much about smart trains um
there's a positive traction system that
they use right now
and i like the idea of deposit
the ptc systems out there i do believe
is what they're called
are fantastic safety systems
um the new technologies that are coming
out
on the trains again i don't
dig as deep into some of this as some
people do
and i'm just catching up with some of
the technologies
but they're coming out with some nice
stuff the model railroad side stuff the
technologies are just
unbelievable the on the rails side of
stuff
the newer engines with some of their
controls in it are fantastic
the rules for safety out there are
fantastic the problem is is with all
these new technologies
there are now older trains that cannot
run on the rails
because or cannot run on specific types
of rails because they're
they don't have the new technologies and
can't be retrofitted easily
the ptc system is a great example the
big boy which i showed you
to does not have a ptc system in its cab
so behind it runs an actual uh
diesel engine with ptc in it that does
dynamic braking
and makes it safe for the a-class or the
major
railroad lines smaller railroad lines
local lines
don't have that ptc requirement at this
point in time
so they could run something like the
shea or
the uh silver streak type engine that i
showed you before
all right do i have any i hope that
answers your question a little bit as
far as
technologies on the model railroading
inside
probably the newest technology that
people are starting to use is raspberry
pi's and the arduinos to go ahead and
run their
layouts do you have any thoughts on
unlimited pto and how that plays out
unlimited pto has pluses and minuses and
yes i have
a big thought on that um
a lot of places that i've seen that have
unlimited pto it's like okay yeah take
the time off when you need it
and you never think that you need it
it doesn't force people what i what i
prefer to see is if somebody's going to
be doing unlimited pto that
that a place goes ahead and does a
mandatory week
of paid time off for an individual
quite honestly unlimited pto is a
fantastic thing in theory
but when you're a workaholic you're just
going to ignore it
if on the other hand you force an
employee to say okay there's a mandatory
week off
and we are shutting down your accounts
and you're not going to be able to see
your email or anything
i would much rather see if you're going
to have mandatory or
unlimited pto i think they need to add
that in
to the equation on it all so that way
people are forced to take that week
um yeah a lot of people that i know that
have
the unlimited pto it's unlimited pto
and they don't take advantage of it and
their
management don't doesn't do a lot with
them and they wind up not even really
taking pto it's
a working vacation so
um yeah
mandatory pto is used in bay it's used
in banks to check people aren't actively
deploying the system that's one of the
advantages of of it is that you can go
ahead and do a check on
a user account etc and stuff like that
but it's it really needs to be done also
to go ahead and let somebody
recharge and refresh if you don't have a
way of recharging and refreshing talk to
friends
start learning so i'm hoping that with
pancakes gone
you've gone ahead and turned around and
found
that you've got a new hobby
or something some new interest whether
it be trains or
mountain climbing or cooking or birding
or djing
so any other question whether on trains
or
on burnout
so i do have another just a
a little bit of curiosity uh you
mentioned the uh
the digitally controlled trains uh
do they signal through the rails or
something like that how does that work
ah yes uh digital command control it
signals through the
rails what it does is it sends a pulse
through the rails so basically
it's it's using the pulses as binary
code
which is why it works so well with
switching over to adreno
or raspberry pi for control systems even
nowadays
um so what there's a combat with it also
you can go ahead and run a dc
a non-digital controlled engine on a dcc
track but because of the way the dcc
signals go
if you let that engine idle that that
non-digital
engine idle it will burn up you will
burn
out the motor inside of that engine
because of that pulsing
now can you run a dcc engine on a dc
track you can do that very easily in
fact a lot of companies make it so that
way
certain basic sounds of the engine has
sounds
will automatically run such as whistles
or bells
while you're running it on a dc c trot
but yeah it's it's it's literally a
pulse
inside of the electricity that goes
ahead and sends the signal on
binaries
thank you that's actually really
fascinating
it's a neat system to go ahead and dig
into i've just started playing with gcc
and i don't have mine set up right at
the moment
but it's it's something that i really
started looking into and then
as i learn more about it i'm tempted to
take the pi or an adreno and start
working with that to see how much better
of a system i can come up with as
opposed to what's just out there right
now
so
if there's nothing else i want to thank
you all for
for listening i hope this came off very
well for everybody and you were able to
learn some stuff
and i'll see you on the rails
fantastic thank you shecky for your
presentation today and for stepping in
for us