so okay
at mining Stevenson I'm that president
preside
and is now I am a director and treasurer
a free site
so we read you
as quick as possible an explanation what
actors faces
because some you may not be familiar
with it at
reside is the one that we're interested
in in Atlanta but
akers bases in general are everywhere
and they're not necessarily affiliated
with our organization
they each have their own different style
I'll an actual universities are really
starting
you implement actors faces due to
Georgia Tech has won
mentions video other kind of all over
the place we wanted to talk to you a
little bit about cars
and sorta summer things we've learned
from
a guess and social engineering
standpoint although it's a little more
complicated
anyway at first will
show you what what we got going on here
so basically
I a hackerspace people teach classes
sometimes three sometimes they paid
their about any number different things
usually an introductory topic we have
much
tools people use so you can but projects
together and
you know we're gonna as that we host
events I
some free some up on paid but we have
many
manager conferences and stuff like that
at the space answer
during events we got some 3d printers &
rapid prototyping technology and stuff
like that
people can get into that there art
all over the place and and we make with
nine gina's
and young the very things I
so it's like it's like a university
basic separate you know
with beer if you're over on
so so free side is divided into zones
back tiffany's so you're staring into
our introduction zone
which welcomes people to space
and we have our 3d printers a as you see
we are poor
working well mostly working 30 better
something and sometimes and others in
their cages the context for like your
I am so this kinda hacking goes on in
this area because it's not all like
computer stuff we have a server room but
with you lot a difference to
we got our wallets pool their feeding
them we got
myself staring into 3d printer so
this is cool arm one thing that
have happens at a hackerspace is setting
expectations
so when people walk in the eighth
they're kinda overwhelmed by the
possibilities of things that they can
make
because we have something on the order
24 two dozen zones right
yet and so people sort of like look at
all the stuff but like I could do
anything I you know and that's true
by you know expectations need to match
reality so three burners need to be
maintained
people need to understand how they work
they need them know something a little
bit about the toolchain
cad slicer and other things like that so
you know we have the a capacity to help
people
along the way but differently we need to
set the
we said those expectations for lease so
that up
people don't feel like were
misrepresenting exactly how much they
can do with
you know a compatible level about per
right in order for it to be a free
enough space for people to
do anything they want week can't really
manage all the services
so a lot of times it's getting outta the
people that have the knowledge
building those relationships with them
and and then getting them to teach users
self-directed
and that's kinda you harder for a lot of
people so
and so it's a volunteer member
organizations and no one gets paid no
one's there we don't have a staff we
have a volunteer staff
so everything has to come from
the members themselves and the
communities so as we like to say the
only limit is your cell
and federal and state and local law
missile okay so
but we do have appointed different
reprint so we can show people this is
what goes right
is wrong how how these different
concepts word we do try but
scaling kinda in thing anyway I'm the a
electronics lab so we recently got a a
six thousand dollar grant a first grant
to you %uh rebuild this area and
make it less wooden and the more state
of the art and include some new
equipment new soldering irons and that
sort of thing
aren't we knows another consumables
years are on the blink is that
yes though we got oscilloscopes and
stuff like that
our hardware it's all member donated so
you know it varies
in like weather in workplace
I am yeah I okay and then we got to the
classroom
right with the Wayne their I'll and
so c16 like so we split their class fees
fifty 50 and
so if anybody wants to teach classes
they wanna make life money you get happy
what people pay to take it uses twenty
dollar class injured
reprinting entry had like anything arm
we found a counterintuitive thing that
people imagine they'd
a free class a/b attended much more than
class in small the and that's not at all
true arm
if somebody pays little bit obligates
the teacher to show up and then the
people have a commitment
they actually that was weird binding a
bars com
so now we just charge up to nose for you
know the
Plaza yes a two-income twenty dollars
per three-hour class yes
I'll regis aren't so what yen this user
this is our kitchen as you can see
things happened the area
arm so this is summoning those are the
guys there and
in the kitchen and as we all are there
and we have
a meeting space where we host
different talks and you know we did 3d
printing talkin
whose really super weird because the guy
is hosting a talk
headed on hangouts and so one or the
other speakers was just watching from
above
want the speakers in person harkin just
nodding and it was like that
communication there's a area Max
Headroom moment yet
so that was a real a9 accidentally a
16-foot
screens okay an this isn't the shared
project area so up
well the sons or like to share resources
on all this was member donated
and it has varying degrees utility by
typically the way this works is members
members are able to grab anything
from the shelves and do anything with
them art
actual functioning projects whatever we
we enable that
I'll this is a brain-computer interface
are set up that got Timberly a
set up a lot about work stations we have
like for work tables in the front where
people can
set things up like this them so no you
on the fly projects and put put it away
and get others involved
yes I wanted to play with brain computer
interfaces and I wanted people that knew
what they were doing
to show up to them so I started a
monthly meet up
call brainiacs and we I found the coast
and so we do a monthly thing where we
play with brain computer interfaces
night trackers in
are tweeners and so we have all those
things talking to each other in so we
made a
mind-controlled infinity portal that
I'll show you later on
presentation is part of it and and some
other weird stuff so
you can get super weird if you can
actually get people to imagine what they
can do with an environment so maybe it
starts with
little building blocks and putting them
together you crazy stuff
the Media Lab we have LED strips
all around the top oven and so
weak mind control that to on
or just do 1ba when things I wanna
point out is our environment is fully
hackable
by the members so most the times people
work
in top-down environments just provided
for you
by every side you provide your own
environment and it's sort of like
an amalgamation everyone's involvements
its to try to manifest what they want to
create
in this space sale you can get you can
just totally repurpose an area space if
you get people interested in
we had a craft room that nobody's really
using and so
on this guy who does editing for some
teen vampire drama
in his day job wanted to do a podcast
and arm
maybe diversify from team we also and a
fully functional ham radios yeah which I
think I've gotta
rate gathered here so we have to two
antennas and so we have
a fully functional ham radio station
which is also the podcasting studio
now former craft room and so we can I
just felt that out
in you know because there were people
that were interested in
member storage everybody gets a little
bit a storage
so people always try abuse storage in
the place and that's something we can
have to constantly work on but
you know we can accommodate everybody's
personal project
gonna be shared space at this the
workshop not a great picture
yeah that's a better so like we have
table saws
and chop saws and planers some things
like that and
while some scrap wood again this is just
member donated material that
is available for use feel free incoming
icon someone you know yeah.so I'm
you know a lot of people do woodworking
and that's their
you know happen entry into the space we
get a budget and that
that manual brake for bending sheet
metal and scrolls on a drill press
we have a laser cutter right which does
really cool prototyping stuff
I a laid back type 2 lays in a mill now
I am and so we have a lot of networking
stuff into a basin
a welder in a kiln
foundry Ford whenever on
and much other stuff sometimes people
take a cardboard there were like no
shame on you
and then there's this somewhere so that
I find you
yeah but I yes oh om
you know I its kinda it's a fun
environment like the reason why we have
so many different things going on there
is because
we want people to barter their skills
with each other so everybody comes in
and does something
am and the mat know what it is that they
have the advantage over you know
over the other people but the guy who
brought in the lathe and brought in the
mill and does all the metalworking
really wants to know about automation
controllers deadline designs on
fabrication and he can
make them do stuff and so that's what he
does is he teaches everybody male
working and then he learned how to make
our
are tweeners work wanted the when the
first things that we
did when we sorted took over the space
and got into a leadership role
was do several social engineering
tactics to slowly try to ship the
courtroom the space
so wanted the core values that we
emphasize with humility
so that you could actually show up to
the space
not know something about how I X a
copter works
and that is totally OK because
everybody's gonna figure it out together
we're all gonna back on this as a team
which is really cool because we have
people come in there like I'm the best
at what I do and
were like okay collect as a foot surgeon
up you know one up him
and I we'll see how that that were
temporary so like
because everybody has mic skills then
you have to come in with an open mind is
no idea how the castle arm so
I anyway at why the first project that
we did not show people
sorta 10 said get a win right
was a hex Cap term we built that and we
fluid
and crashed in I am the and
so we decide to do something easier I'm
so
I we we didn't learn to solder thing
where we basically milled out the
circuit boards
and made the actual circuits and then
talk budget
people how to solder at at Maker Faire
and I was fun on
to these are all projects that somebody
had the idea and they decided to get a
bunch other people interested in
as if you have an idea and you don't get
much other people interested in you end
up doing the whole thing
I so you know them at we built an
off-road wheelchair
for a friend of ours for Albany so we
took at
really horrible zero turn lawn mower and
we add
but blinking LED is on it painted like a
Mario Kart situation
and boom there you go so that was a lot
of fun
on at so we did a fundraiser for that
and get there are paid for
and is really cool we have a paranoia
board in space
that anybody can contribute to to unlock
the secrets of the
arm reptilian alien Billy Minardi that
her I
we know to be running our government and
everything around us
at all times ISO you can see Betty Page
up there
yet that anyway Wed is a
oh yeah I smile yeah my bad I get
estimate is that yeah
11 really um but yes 0
so that their Tom there is a dude in our
space that has launched several kick
starters and and runs a couple companies
and benefits from that environment
because he knows how to use it so it's
not exclusively like you only have to do
open source nonprofit stuff you can do
this kinda stuff
it's you it's a game like minimus know
with this %uh this is the box so
up yet but divides yes at
push the button at your own you know
right taking your life in your hands
anyway this does something and we're
very excited about it
a so I am anyway so that's a thing
and he's got his own setup at home so he
his setup is way better than are so he
comes there to talk to us
the maybe drink beer and not necessarily
to use all the equipment but he brings
on information with them in
sometime tires people to hang out
there's that's cool
I this is a you're going to be um this
was an interesting idea that we had
so we found out later on that class
series don't work really well
unless you actually do like an
interesting series so
the theory behind a series not the
reality
there behind it was that they would be a
six-part journey into constructing a
custom
3d printer so each of these parts were
printed out
and during the class on the instructor
showed how they would be put together
and this was the printer at the end of
the class
excellent yeah
money will send I hey actually on that
point
um the at the social engineering talk a
last night because made to that
he's talking about visualized story and
kinesthetic learners
I and so yeah it's it's cool to decode
you know what color somebody isn't
speaker money level but
what you can do if you're teaching
somebody and you want them didn't fully
understand what it is that you're
talking about is you can do something
called
you where you tell them what you're
gonna do you in the new show them
you doing in the new make them do it net
takes it through auditory
visual and kinesthetic you make sure
that they understand what it is you
talking about
I am just assign anyway akers
willie mention not I am yeah
so who worked hard margin yeah
oh okay so this is a full om
iight so mu you know
have one of our members basically did he
published
as a medical research where he 3d
printed a fight did not know anything
or much about 3d printing came into the
space and said hey
I'm for surgeon and I'm interested in 3d
printing and I think
the if I we look at a couple a bone
disorders where they present differently
in each patient you have to
make a custom a syriza
I guess it's an enclosure gonna put
behold the bones in place after the
surgery and all that stuff
what if we just 3d printed their foot
and then we did all the surgical
fixtures in all planning on that
and as he did that I think that took the
surgery time my eight hours the to
I am so cuz they were doing 3d images
I'll
doll dresses I thank you nom it is a
published papers
yeah we're the only and other under
space published in a medical journal
yet the name the the name is a total
nightmare I have it happen
I guess it didn't import the we don't
have any or home noted
does our gather our surgical photos on
our blog in San people like
other all know it then like so it's
really bad and people better
the computers but I am anyway so that
happened
this is so this is a project that at
that Nick and I
work done Nick a who's the surgeon is
the best person to hackerspace thing
ever
I am becas he's just excited the as
ideas and he
follows through on a min he gets people
involved in a min that's what he does
and so he and I have a paper on the way
to publishing I where we basically
did this horrible set up with books and
at looks horrible but basically what
this is
a a fixture to hold somebody's heads
table in front of this camera which is
doing I tracking and so it's looking at
where they're looking at on an image I
and
recording that into and analysis
environment that we can later go back in
scan over and so what we did was we
looked at that
gaze patterns across I series
have 30 x-ray images and had surgical
residents
and surgeons with over seven years
experience
scan across and then we took all that
data in
and made some conclusions across it says
that this is this is an expert you like
but a bike at this and this is a
resident is the call my god I hope I
don't fail
you know I have a look at the whole
thing in like major every
it so I had so they're like obvious
differences but also some
some experts have bad habits and on it's
hard to tell if they're using the
peripheral vision to take
in a bunch staffer there you know
whatever so there's a lot of stuff that
we're gonna do after this
at probably the next phase of this
project is we're gonna take a brain
computer interface and put it on
somebody's head while they're doing the
scan and so we can know their
levels of attention and focus is this
getting across the image gets super
weird
I am so we just try to make things as
weird as possible when we're there
and in that vein this is AI
infinity a mirror that we bill for
alchemy
I and so I have this is the design this
is the prototype on the laser cutter we
did a fundraiser around this
is Kevin Edward the tabloid wild crazy
guys
that helped us build a prototype which
we were like oh my god like that
and then as it is the final thing and us
so that it on and then we hooked it up
to bring computer database
mind-controlled
so it's way early rainbow tunnel to
forever date you can push on the acrylic
and it works the tunnel and then you can
control it with your mind in a bunch of
people
on acid at Albany were like oh my god
this is the truth in everything
and so so that your or they just worked
and
the other word there was some twerking
there is number reporting incidents that
we had an old
no we don't applaud for twerking well
sign a prenup thats
we made a note working sign so hum but
it was
we we fix that but I we have a
quadrocopter
in addition to the ex captors ways you
to fly play around with panda
so we have a member who's getting the my
own thing
I I guess hasn't released yet I don't
know II beta
little wristband that checks no reads
basically a
on electrical impulses the same way that
the brain computer interfaces dubin
with you know muscle and read all your
gestures and Stephanie wants to control
this
with one and I think he's got some kinda
can an idea worked out that he's gonna
control with the other to
on that can be awful arm I
sigh I told him to incorporate a
brain-computer interface now
by I am I think it needs one because be
loses focus knees like
you know controller thing is a call hey
and then it like goes and bombs a
a you know that would be bad yeah I want
one thing with a
when you're doing a custom AXA copter
make sure you read
all the documentation and make sure you
calibrate it because the
a common problem is if you do not put
the fail-safe in
and you just go for brought all it will
just keep on going
and it will not stop yeah it'll get
stuck in all product up it so that's the
thing
didn't happen ours but I'd like to chase
goats and turkeys reconcile
arm so we're we we do give a flying fuck
I am and and so this is a I
plane that you brought in he was like
this is a wreck
piece a crap and you guys can probably
pick secure the hackers which never
happens everybody brings broken stuff
like in
by I but dont ever bring a CRT to
hackerspace because
and 9 its not K and a way on the tables
on a couple
are pieces of equipment he made a phone
weighing out a bit and then flew in
is that crashed in is really
disappointed on
so this is this is what we wanna talk
about in terms like at
that social engineering political aspect
this is our charter membership over time
so we use this to understand were here
want you explain
what we in your not so we sorta came
into the space and gone and the
leadership
this point and
we did such an interesting cultural
change the lotto
funny things happen very quickly we had
fourteen members
and we just started really rallying
people to do
public demands and tell people about the
space and
at the same time set expectations don't
try to over hype something
and really bring on people a divers tell
you gonna make approachable rioted
intimidating to be in a place yet to be
so
raised so you Stephen and I have
different styles
arm so I'm kinda like the I guess
like the good cop I guess here the human
ear damage
yeah I'm and the shaman the space for
some reason people come to me with other
personal problems and
show the redemption hacking but a
basically a what I do is my approach is
I listened very carefully first and
foremost to
what a person does I'll
in terms of work yeah but really what
what they're passionate about like
kind of side projects to work on it home
I pay very close attention to you
or the interests of our and than what
they seek to do with the space
and sometimes we have people who are
really engaged at home and they just
come the space to have a beer
you know socialize and so that's cool
and i can spin them into different
it is that place that you can go to wear
like everybody else in your life is so
tired of hearing you talk about this
thing that you're into you
and then you know they're like oh my god
how you can talk about this again okay
yeah when you come here everybody's home
and it's weird okay I didn't even know
there are you
so I call these like get the badge I
moments so I you know a guy comes to me
and you'd like
you know he so sad because he has a
toaster that can talk to the internet
and you know I'm like well here's a
friend has written software that can
talk to your toaster and he's like
all and then they get married I'll you
but lay
is a yet exit there's two things going
on a star
the green is awesome because it's serve
a success story but the rat is
month-over-month so we have falling off
a little bit
here lately on so we we trying to figure
out where we're always trying new
different things because we have no idea
what we're doing arm
and I think that's the case for most
will be real engineering degree
anything sorta 3 plateaus right and yet
I i think is a good time to talk about
I'll
Rick fall up it's pop singer that higher
party guy wrote a book that free ebook
course call
us warm wise and he talks about three
critical numbers
7:30 in a 150 and 150 is Dunbar's number
refers to tribal organization arm
7:30 are sort of like smaller subset
seven is the number of people that
can come to consensus and then after a
all bets are off
saddam we have six people on board yes
so usually
you know we try to keep the core
leadership around six or seven
and then 30 is the number of people in a
group that all know each other very well
and so past that number as you can see
we were sorta plateauing on our way to
30 and we had to rebuild
relationships assorted divide the space
up a little bit so that we can get
another group
about 30 to come together and
organize a space that way and so that
that takes a lot of time and effort that
takes a lot
listening to everybody and making sure
that you can create those connections
between people that foster that growth
and then
foster that interesting projects and
that's what so
the the the social engineering talk last
night focused a lot on
pacing yourself with someone naturally
and basing their
their speedo at the way that they speak
in that kinda stuff
and that's good if you're if you're com
trying to gain you know gain trust to
gain access and I can I think but if
you're
building a long-term relationship that's
called leveling in that happens
naturally is you
get to know somebody in are just so stay
open minded to what they're doing
so you can try to learn and mechanically
do all those things and you're gonna
forget some other man then it's going to
look really weird because you're going
to be doing all the action
have another facial expressions or
whatever and they're gonna be at home I
got you can I
strange up so but leveling happens
naturally and and the reason why
those social engineering techniques are
all part of a body research is because
I'm it because it does happen naturally
and we understand it and we
are receptive to that and so you kinda
need to create an experience with
different people and anchor them
in the space or in the community because
this isn't gaining one time trust her
access I what you're trying to do is do
you
trying to create an area where you have
the opportunity to explore anything
yet so in the in the social engineering
talk the talk about tinkering
people two concepts and ideas so that
was part of the reason for creating that
sounds as we anchor people to the idea
of
oh this is an area of common activities
as the 3d printers &
you know if somebody comes to me arm
that doesn't quite get the humility
value yet
which is kinda awesome because they show
up in there like I'm the 3d printer
expert I'm like cool will you
repair all these machines for you know
now you are the leader
this zone and its awesome and some
people really do
like take to that yeah I am so mean it
you can go to play with different people
styles but anyway
we we wanted to show this concept you
guys in
add get you may be a little bit
interested in it because
I social engineering is really hard and
the dude that was talking last night had
several decades of experience
its really difficult to do and so he
environment where you can explore that
no risk
and that goes the same with skills and
different other things right you want to
expose yourself to an environment where
there are people who know what they're
doing
in specific areas and then there's no
risk failure and if you do something
doesn't work out you clean up your mess
from the space
and leave it the way the founder and
then you know trace amounts
them now the questions
16 yeah we haven't started mom
with when the number was lower we
started with zero
and then we increased om to 16 percent
and we have a female doctor now as well
that's something that's like barry
personal important to me that we
increased the diversity in the space
that way
I'll and you know that something that
you don't see very much often a lot of
different hackerspace is
and the approach you have to take with
it is a very careful one
and it has to be considerate and sincere
because
yet
well the the diversity message in
general
affects how the the community gets
together because one we didn't want to
specifically
say okay we want to make the place you
know nicer
for you know female specifically so we
do have
policies we create policies on sexual
harassment thing is that we do a
foursome
by the diversity message in general is
we want this to be a place where anybody
can become
anybody from any background it so it was
not specifically adding that
like inclusion and diversity that made
it more comfortable for everybody
it's just that we don't have a %uh yeah
value the hell even that you have to
start with the value
and it really after you start with the
value and you make that a Korean you
show people that it's a core and you
mean it
when you say that kinda behaviors and
tolerated here then
good behaviors follow more diversity
followers and it just kinda builds on
itself
and you know we do occasionally try to
trying to nudge people towards more
leadership so we can have diversity in
our leadership
I'll by you know I'd I mean we didn't
really have to it candor issues a
flagrant
director to undergo yes arm and so
yeah I its it's tough
and it's tough to help people understand
that but one way that you can make it
make sense to people is
we don't want diversity in space to be
politically correct or anything like
that
when you have diversity in an
organization or in a group of people you
get
robust ideas right you get people coming
from different angles different
perspectives and its smart
to have people like that around when
you're working on projects are working
on
marketing to broader demographic than
you
personally understand that kinda stuff
so it makes sense as an organization
do that anyway the same as it makes
sense to split up into different zones
and have different technologies
in questions good we didn't
nom the organization owns it it was
founded up four years ago
and or actually by almost 2009
yet by and so yeah I was it was founded
the space is just a rented
warehouse unit in the west and I'll
and yeah it's just 30 been like three
cycles leadership
generate that much reason anywhere else
alright
thank you