hi everyone welcome to my talk on
application testing methodology and
scope based record
my name is harsh bhutra and i will be
guiding you through my own application
testing methodology
and scope based recon approach which i
follow for my own pen testing and bug
boundary
it helped me a lot in the past to
quickly gain a pace into bug bounty
and get some good result out of it
before diving directly
into the topic i would first like to
thank omar graham conference and
red team village for inviting me to
present my views
to all of you a quick introduction about
me
i currently work as a cyber security
analyst at detox technologies
i am a cyanocrat teamer i am currently
into
top 115 buck crowd all-time leaderboard
mvp for q1 and q2
i have authored multiple books on
hacking recommended by aict and ni
tritty at chandigarh
i often blog about security findings
that i have
i speak at the conferences for various
topics like recon broken cryptography
and similar other topics sometimes i
write
poems and all and i am a lifelong
learner like you all are
the agender for today's talk would be to
talk about application testing
methodology
how i created my own methodology and how
i applied
further we will be looking at threat
mapping manual testing approach
recon 101 what is scope based recon
methodology
how you can utilize it what are the
various small medium and large copricon
at last some of the offensive recon
tactics that i use
and ultimately if you have any question
and answer you can bombard it
okay so first let's talk about
application testing methodology it is
really crucial to understand that
whenever you are performing a pen test
or doing bug boundaries
having an approach having a methodology
always
helps you out to stay ahead of your
target be organized
so these are few seven steps that i
usually
go about while doing any pen test or
participating into any background
program
the first thing is define the target
scope defining the target scope
always helps you to stay in a particular
scope and
reduces eliminates the chances of being
out of scope
and ultimately save you from unnecessary
hazards that you might do
secondly understand the applications
business logic this is the crucial step
a lot of people they directly jump
testing the application
now before performing an attack
always make sure that you know that your
weapon are
completely fine they are completely
ready you know your enemy well
so navigate an application like a normal
user understand the various workflows of
the application
if there is an uh e-commerce application
understand what all workflows it goes
through
from selecting a product to adding it to
the card from purchasing it to refunding
it or like that
try to create a threat map in the third
step based on the various
functionalities try to create a threat
map okay
there is a functionality of refund can i
abuse it
if yes then what are the possible
theoretical ways to abuse that
we will look at threat map in the next
section
further perform scope based recon which
will again we will look at the next
section in the brief
now once you know that you have a threat
map once you've started doing your recon
now it's time to perform manual pen test
while your automation happens in the
background
right in the manual pen test you will
fire your tools like burp suit
or any other proxy tool that you prefer
and then you will start testing every
single functionality for every single
test case like if there is a
authentication mechanism you might test
for sql injection you might test for
direct request you might test for eye
dots or
some other issues like oatmeal
configuration if applicable
now further you might need to perform
application specific attacks
now application specific attack might be
like the application is using
java so there might be a possibility of
java dc relation issues
application is built upon ruby so there
might be some rupee gadgets and d
simulation issues
you have to be specific as per the
application
apart from the generic wasp top 10 or
sense25
there can be any category of the bug
that might exist
further you can go based upon what is
the use case of the application
if it's an e-commerce application or if
it's a financial application
you might need to be specific according
to that test case
or that use case now
make sure that whenever you are doing
this you always
learn what you lack there is a lot of
times i i feel like i am less confident
in maybe sql injection
so i should go back spend some time on
learning sql injection
and again come back and hit on the
target now one thing that i would like
to mention
over here is never get into lab
mentality
because a lot of time beginners get into
lab mentality and they never feel
that much comfortable testing real
application and they get demotivated
easily because they are not finding
anything out there
labs are designed in such a way that
they will be
hackable and somewhere we have
like a mindset a mentality in our mind
running that okay this is something
hackable right
so just make sure that you don't get
into lab mentality
that it's easy that's that's what you
will see in the real life
real life is totally different from that
experience
now further threat mapping threat
mapping is something which a lot of
people
might not know or might miss basically
threat mapping is
totally a different process than the
regular pen testing but
why you should use it because it will
give you a better
approach a better view to look at your
target now uh let me tell you why
when you navigate the application you
know that what all the workflows
application has
what all the possible end points
functions components
or whatever application holes or
applications consist of
now suppose there is a function a what
if
you theoretically imagine the attack
scenario for that function a
so say an attacker can uh you know
delete for
the a function from user b's account or
an attacker can basically you know
pop up an xss or payload or something
else into the a functionality something
like that
right so having a mindset about each
functionality will give you a good idea
about possible test cases
right so threat mapping helps you to
understand
that what could be the possible test
cases for each applications
each functionalities and each component
now how you go about threat mapping
so threat mapping threat modeling
hunting they are like totally a
different process
but to again like make it a
very quickly easy to understand and
possible for everyone to implement
i have again divided into five steps
navigate the application while you are
navigating
list down all the components and the
functionalities
once you have all the components in the
write down theoretical attack scenarios
for each function
like so like i said like for a function
i can do this
i can do that i can perform xss i can go
from sql injection
okay you you will have to create some
theoretical attack scenarios
create possible impact scenarios based
upon what is the impact upon
confidentiality
integrity and availability and
can an attacker perform create operation
or read operation or update
operation or delete operation on a
particular function so for example there
is a
card functionality so what we can say
is it possible for an attacker to add
something
to another user's card now this is
something called create you are creating
a card
is it possible for an attacker to read
something from other users card
this is you are doing viewing read
functionality abuse
can you update somebody else card you
are abusing update
can you delete something from the other
person's card
it is abusing the d so basically if you
are looking at the current
impact scenario and ci impact scenario
you can again
you know narrow down those theoretical
attack scenario for
better test plan now you will have a
wide set of test cases to perform on
your pen testing or your bug boundary
assessment whatever you are doing
now make sure that you verify all those
test cases while you perform your
assessment
and it will be guaranteeing you that
there will be
a high chance that you won't miss
anything
anything obvious at least right now
once you move out of uh threat mapping
we have to move towards
manual pen testing approach again the
important thing is
understand the application workflow so
if it's an e-commerce application
what is the workflow of uh you know
purchasing some product so you might
need to go to login
to a particular panel then you have to
go to some particular product
add some quantity then you know add
address and everything every shipping
details and everything and then you have
to
check out and is it possible to you know
break the workflow somewhere and do some
malicious tasks so
understand the applications workflow
what are the normal usual workflows the
application offers
then like you know run your brain to do
some mischievous tasks that
hey is it possible to break the scenario
in any possible way
secondly figure out the various possible
flows of the same feature
now it might be possible that add to
cart functionality or purchasing
something might have
some you know different workflows like
you can go to a new product
you can add it to the card and you can
purchase it or maybe you can go to your
wish list and directly purchase a
product from there
so there might be multiple workflows for
a single function it is a purchase over
here
try to break those application flows
test every possible
test case for each individual
functionality like uh test like
accesses for every single input point or
every single end point where you
feel like data might be reflected or
data might be stored somewhere
do not miss any test case even if it's
complicated
try it go out of your comfort zone if
you feel like i'm not good with ecstasy
try it it's there is nothing bad in
trying you will learn a lot of things
along the way
rely less upon the tools proxy tools are
really good go in terms of manual pen
testing
again learn something new if you are
stuck at something and again start
hacking
i would again emphasize that don't make
a lab mentality instead
learn something apply in one or two laps
at max
and start hacking in the real life
applications because the more you will
hack on the labs the more comfortable
you will be with the labs only
instead of being into the real
environment
now let's jump to my favorite topic
recon 101 i have given a lot of talks
before on recon
so again i will be quickly going through
this particular phase
so recon is nothing but increasing your
attack surface discovering and creating
a better attack surface
so that you know you can find more and
more security issues you can
uncover more vulnerabilities looking at
the less travel road is going to give
you more success
so if you are able to you know widen
your scope to a great extent
there is a huge possibility that other
people might not have done that already
and there is a huge possibility that you
will get valid works
digging assets of your target to the
deepest point possible
is the ultimate aim of the recon again
recon
is not equal to security issues but it
will increase the probability of getting
security issues the valid ones instead
of duplicates
now busting some myths over here recon
equals to bugs no recon is not directly
equals to bugs
rather it's equals to asset discovery
and increasing your attack surface
which will enable you to find more and
more bugs
people say that rickon is all about
manual approach but
no the best way to perform recon is to
use hybrid approach
using both automation and manual so
uh there are a lot of things which you
can automate like subdomain enumeration
domain takeovers and other things
however there are things like
github recon google docking which still
like you are searching on showdown or
something they still need manual
intervention to you know
be better people again say that recon is
time consuming but if you perform it
properly and automate things in a right
way you can save a lot of times
what you can do is you can create your
own scripts
to automate say some domain enumeration
subdomain takeovers
some particular fuzzing and all and then
at the same time you can start
performing manual github recon manual
google docking or
if this github recon is not in scope you
can directly jump into performing manual
pen testing right so you are doing two
things in the parallel
saving a lot of time people think that
recon is all equals to subdomain
enumeration who is sport scanning
fuzzing etc
but this is not the case it's all about
how creative you could be like where all
you can go and possibly look for the
you know exposed credentials or maybe
anything which will
enable you to increase the attack
surface
yeah this is true that these abu methods
are some of the uh well-known methods
but
never limited security is a beautiful
field which is never limited to anything
every single day there's a lot of
research coming out there's a lot of new
tools and techniques coming out so yeah
it's it's never ending and never limited
now now again talking about one of the
uh my own approach the scope-based recon
which
simply is a methodology to divide how to
perform recon
when a specific scope is provided and
this is very much
important actually because if you are
blindly performing every single
reconnaissance thing on every kind of
scope
this is not going to give you a good
result you might go out of scope you
might waste a lot of time
but on the other hand if you know your
scope and if you know that
what you have to do in a specific set of
scope
you will be good to go you will be
knowing that okay what i have to look
for
where i have to look for and what i will
be finding after it
now there are basically three type of
scoops
when we talk about scope based recon the
small scope the medium scope and the
large scope
now why is scope based recon it saves a
lot of time
because you know that what specific
things you want to look for
you can easily automate your own recon
workflow you can just you know
okay in your small scope record you just
want to do subdomain enumeration and
subdomain
takeovers you can write a small script
using four or five tools
for subdomain enumeration and then you
can you know just simply probe them and
send it to
the subdomain takeover tools and try to
see
if it's working for you there are less
chance to submit out of scope issues
and just like other security
methodologies it enables you to perform
a better reconnaissance
now let's quickly look at the small
scope medium scope and the large scope
recon
so when we talk about small scope recon
we specifically
look for specific set of urls it may be
sandbox url queue or staging
environments like you will see a lot of
time
sendbox.target.com or
qastaging.target.com
medium scope we consider star.target.com
where we say that all the subdomain of
target.com are in scope
where in large scope we consider that
every single thing
the internet presents acquisitions
copyright everything
related to that organization will be in
school
now in small scope recall let's let's
look like
what we have to look for while
performing the recon so
these are the few common things that you
should look for like directory
enumeration and brute forcing
first the directories to the possible uh
end points do it recursively
uh a lot of time slash admin directory
might give you four zero three errors or
four or one errors or something like
that but if you're trying to do it
recursively
you might find a direct say slash admin
slash data or slash admin slash data
slash
usernames and which might not be
protected
perform service enumeration to see what
services are powering up your system and
you can further check if there is some
cvs for that or any public expert for
that
perform port scanning if it's in scope
to check for you know other quotes
uh perform broken link hijacking it's
again like subdomain takeover but here
like there might be some
social media links or some third party
links which can be taken over
look for js files for hard-coded api
secrets and credentials
perform parameter discovery and automate
for the xss and
other tools perform way back history way
back urls google
docking to you know look for the
potential
endpoints and urls to further see what
you can possibly do
you can use various gf patterns to end
and automation scripts to automate
accesses ssrf and other
tools now that last point totally
depends upon
how you want to automate things here
automation plays a really good role
now let's look at medium scope recon
in medium scope recon the most of the
things stay same
except for a few like here we look at
subdomain enumeration because
star.target.com is in scope so
subdominant animation is
really important further you can perform
subdomain takeovers you can check for
misconfigured third party services
you can check for misconfigured storage
options like s3 worked
you can go for github recon and a lot of
time we find a lot of good things on
itunes
and further you can perform google doc
for increasing the attack surface
finding more sub domains
you can perform internet search engine
discovery using
showdown sensors for binary agent spice
spice is
a new yet good tool i i use it
personally for a long time now
showdown and spice are the two tools
which i prefer to have in my arsenal
again potential url extraction for
vulnerability automation is the same
like we did before
and in the large scope recon this is the
favorite part that you know
there's a lot of things that you can
basically do and this is where
i did something uh for one of the
private program on the book crowd and i
i got from like say thousand rank to 200
in just a month time right so tracking
addressing every possible signature of
the target
application like trace trace and track
like okay
after 10 days there might be some new
subdomains coming there might be some
new acquisitions happening
there might be some new branding of that
particular target might be launched
there might be some companion websites
of that target might be launched
so when we say large scope record every
single thing would mean
perform enumeration on subsidiaries and
acquisitions
so go to the maximum depth so say you
are performing uh
subsidiary enumeration on target so
target might have a
substitute called target1.com which
again might have a substitute called
target2.com
so now you have to again go to
everything in target2.com target1.com
will also mean scope
you can go and check for dns and ssl
enumeration
asn and ipspace enumeration further like
you can
go for github recon and there you can
find a lot of things on github
because you know every single thing
every employees profile will also be in
scope and
if they are you know specifically uh
using some assets
which are related to again target you
can utilize internet search engines over
here
in a very beautiful way and there might
be uh
various methods not just limited to them
but these are some of the things that
you should
and must look for now this concludes the
most of the part of
uh small medium and large scope recon
now let's
look at some of the offensive come smart
recon tactics these are like again very
short tactics as i always tell people
whenever you're doing recall just choose
your scope and based on that
choose your scope based recon method
create a script for automating your
scope is recall
i have created a project called project
beam over github you can go to github
and
search for it and you can ultimately try
to see if it
it fulfills your need for scope based
recon in project beam we
introduce the scope based recon feature
so you have to just say that i want to
do small scope recon or medium or large
scope econ
so it will do the task accordingly which
are pretty defined
run your automation scripts over cloud
because it's fast it will save your
system's
processing powers so that while you are
performing burp suit
testing with burp suit and some other
tools you won't face any lags
manually perform bitcoin on github and
perform searching and docking manually
while your automation completes or
you can also uh you know perform manual
pen testing while your automation
completes
you can further create cron jobs or
schedulers to rerun the recon
task to identify new assets on a
specific time interval
and again compare those and see okay now
after one month there are 10 new sub
domains and i have 10 fresh targets to
look for
in a program implement alerts or push
for slack or preferred mode so that
every time you are finding some new
assets you will be notified
so doing all these things try to
implement those things by your own
i i highly recommend because project
game is also
not something very big it's just again a
bash script
with a collection of pre-existing tools
only so
try to write your own tools like that
way it will give you a really good
experience because when i wrote beam
i i got a really good experience about a
lot of things which i was not aware of
before
managing a lot of things and you know
how to put all the things together
so this basically concludes uh this
particular talk
and if you have any questions you can
always reach out to me on the following
channels i am most active on twitter
and once again i would like to thank
gray hat conference
red team village and omar for inviting
me and
allowing me to share words with the
people thank you so much and have a nice
day
thank you