[Music]
hey everyone this is propaganda panda
here
just here to tell you all about
something cool that's going to be coming
up
at gray hat later on this week starting
on the 29th and
going on to the 31st gray hat is the
premiere or at least one of the best
cyber security conferences here in texas
if not the world
and you can quote me on that maybe
uh i'm that jury's a little bit on that
but
one of the cool things i want to tell
you but that is coming up that is going
to be on the 30th
is the san antonio women in technology
track
now we have a couple of sessions here
that ends in a career fair as well as a
workplace
a panel but this is something you want
to check out
if you're looking for inclusivity if
you're looking for additional
information on how to support
women in technology as well as just to
be there and cheer them on
and learn a few things about the
challenges that women in technology do
face
as well as how they're overcoming them
which is always a very hopeful thing
now the three organizers are going to be
right down here on our website we have
ashley pearson
jennifer torres so these are three
people to definitely look out for
as well as you know if they you see them
on the discord please go ahead and tell
them hello
more information can be found at
grayhat.com and i will see you
at gray hat yeah
that was dumb i'd cut that out but
we'll see you at grey hat maybe with a
fedora maybe not
but it is a grey hat santorini women
technology
go check it out