I got the ear sorry for you guys
we'll keep it brief no and okay so your
widow they're in as well does it work
yeah yeah awesome okay and so we try to
sum up the day we talked a lot about the
IOT or embedded devices of all of the
kinds I guess and all our amazing
speakers sort of touched it in a few
days but you're you're the technical
whiz of us anyways you need to be here
as well and so I was thinking about it
let's talk about why do we see and IOT s
security concerns what's the concerns we
have with each day like when many
devices why what's the main reason they
go one of the things that I find a lot
of tend to be time-to-market issues for
a lot of the manufacturers yeah and
they're trying very hard to get their
widget or whatever their gadget is out
front of the customers and by and large
they tend to bypass security like with
the moran botnet we saw a 60-plus vendor
or sorry 60-plus sets of credentials
within the code that were default
usernames and passwords and this is a
problem that never should have been
there because programmatically there's
no reason why when you open up the box
and get out your coffeemaker whatever
Internet enabled device you have that it
doesn't prompt you for a new user or
sorry new password on initial log yeah
yeah time to market Jeff margin margin
yeah well margins and you know we have
these products where you know one sense
is one of the example and you have 20
cents for a TPM CK element type of
device but also they don't have anybody
as far as the ODM the original device
manufacturers the outsource contractors
who are building the software stack they
don't have any security on staff they're
small teams you know China Taiwan based
basically yeah
and I would say that culture is very
much the villain here yep and that for
the whole IP security you know it's it's
great for the security business to say
that hey security is really really hard
you should hire us and it's also great
for the general programmer because
they're like Security's really really
hard so
I'm getting excuse for up on
basic idea hygiene I think for smaller
IOT devices and vendors and
manufacturers time-to-market is
definitely you know priority number one
there's money dollars but I think more
established OMS and manufacturers that
say I don't know nest for example they
could push security down to like the OD
m and require them to reliable to any
type of security bugs that they
introduce or even fix those and patch
those and be on staff for however many
however many number of years and I've
noted my talk earlier when I was about
to link this is what we did for new
products so moving forward I think
that's probably you know one route to go
and one way to go without getting
regulation involved especially in
different industry verticals but that's
you know again one way that you can uh
you know push these small companies odm
vendors to at least have security either
in mine and staff and design as well
from the beginning what do you think of
I could one argue that we have like two
fields of this we have the consumer
appliance where culture and know-how
could potentially be a problem as well
we're talking about the Mirai botnets as
anyone here don't heard about the Mirai
botanist it doesn't know what it is no
everybody heard about it so it's
actually because more or less consumer
devices right it's like IP cameras and
yeah whatnot let's say my parents have
an IP camera and yeah we find the remote
code execution it's totally broken they
don't know that they don't have any idea
how to update your firmware I don't
think everyone in this room yeah okay
maybe everyone in this room updated
firmware on their routers but a lot of
people don't could up that's potentially
you could integrate with the culture
thing that we need to press maybe
educate our users so it's often a manual
process as well yeah to update your
firmware and be you know alerted or
recognize that there is an infirm or
update available and what the former
updates
Oh try self.window we're a budget update
automated updates on cue sweet I didn't
plan that it won't be effective I want
to cry now looks alright and yeah so and
then we have I agree with you guys but
you said time to market isn't that it's
a factor and what would like when we
look at the hardware can we see any like
do we use a lot of generic con wear as
well is that your opinion as well there
is a lot of standard based boxes no a
lot of a lot of the problems too is like
in that they have the times of market
issues they're trying to get fast cheap
at the door and we're seeing a lot of
problems that are being reintroduced
that we solved a long time ago for
example there's one brand of product
that is an IOT liberal aid the device
consumer grade thing that has heartbleed
built into it it comes pre-installed
because they're using deprecated
libraries and again this is where a
security review would have caught that
before it ever went out the door so
unfortunately a lot of these devices is
we got louder a lot of these devices
they have planned obsolescence built
into them so the consumer grade devices
they want you to buy the next widget the
next shiny thing but that doesn't
translate when you're looking at power
systems ICS and things for that effect
because these are systems that will be
in the field for 30 plus years yeah so
they have to be a much better way to do
it because you can't create any
affecting latency and things like that
when we're talking about embedded system
in general we actually have a lot of ICS
system or SCADA systems there where the
life cycle is super long and that's a
potential problem as well you have this
extreme machine and a hospital that
needs to run Windows XP because some
reasons well it's funny because there's
two ends of the spectrum you have the
ICS SCADA where they have you know
legacy embedded devices that are heavily
dependent on what can't be updated which
are really really expensive like
millions of dollars even if they wanted
to update so they accept the risk and
you know segregate or basically air-gap
whatever you want to call it into
a different size of network and then you
have the consumer side where you know
the margins are thin and there's no
incentives to building security from
from design pages with small newer
devices that is but yeah that's totally
different than the end of the spectrum
but they're still very relevant and
still contribute to what we have as far
as the impact and of IOT and how it
affects the Internet
Emma mentioned pacemakers and insulin
pumps and so forth that's another issue
as well cuz they're I don't know what I
what the life is expect expectancy is
for the the pacemaker engineers ten
years my grammar just gotta installers
who you need to change them that's the
thing about pacemakers also that okay
you you actually want your pacemaker to
be remotely accessible because it's much
better to have that risk than to have
the risk of opening up your body again
then again and again and again for every
patch that you need to do and the build
on that it also depends on what's your
risk level by the former US Vice
President Dick Cheney or Dick Cheney he
had all remote access to his disable yes
well he was such a lovely well I think
Barnaby Jack's gay when he was alive
actually had a proof of concept where he
could actually break the firmware in the
quite large of a distance I don't
remember how far it was but it was a lot
a long longer reach that was actually
supplied by the manufacturer that is not
super good if you're a vice president
edition no no would not have ended well
for no but basically also like if you
even though you would want to have
remote access it doesn't mean that you
should have bad most access and and
maybe it's not a good idea to like have
it Internet connected maybe you want
some air you know some kind of a I think
you want some kind of at least some kind
of personally
yeah I'm basic just looking at things so
what how am I really what can we
actually do about it as a community you
know
what can we do it's hard to it is doubt
I know of someone that might have
reported a huge cable modem incident
with one of the largest sized peas in
Sweden and they were not capable to
actually ship a firmware to their
clients because they couldn't they
didn't have the infrastructure so what
can we do as consumers and as a
community to make it better what do you
think yes god I think that the community
community is already doing what we need
to do it women just need to do it a bit
more basically you're talking and
talking about this we need to educate we
need to start with outreach we need to
start being nice to people and try to
understand why they're having issues I
mean like like the one a cry was already
patched but there are so many different
devices that didn't or the patch was out
there but no very many people didn't
download it and that's because it can't
and so we have to look at why is this a
problem we have to look at maybe stop
developing for other engineers and start
developing for people I'm not saying
that engineers aren't people your
candidate not is like I'm at some though
sorry yeah the build on a greater
experience yes does it build on exactly
what you're saying it really is about
greater level of education and I don't
mean necessarily within our own cadres
but beyond that talking to the figuring
out some way to push this information to
our parents that are at home that look
at the computer and say oh I can't find
the button for the Internet these folks
have absolutely no idea how to update
these devices and that's one of those
things is I understand why the planned
obsolescence I get it there's a revenue
model that we had there but on the same
token there has to be some level of
diligence as applied to people that just
don't know how to do it yeah and it has
to be made simpler and easier to manage
I mean fits it does a good job of
managing they
devices why can't that be applied to
other verticals sure sure I don't like I
know plenty of let's say I mentioned
like DVRs that were affected by Mariah
IP cameras but the other manufacturers
who weren't affected they now force
updates and force everyone to change
their password even as you install new
DVR force update force changer default
admin password DUI and that's just one
step and they recognize that really
quick that hey we got to make these
unique if even if it's up to the user if
they acute admin admin that's up to them
but they require them and they also have
a little like password strength I bought
a few of them just for for research and
I'm surprised right away I was like wow
I haven't seen that before I mean right
away they took some action so I'm
progressing it's just you know taking a
little bit of time but not too much than
I think well they will get there at some
point but there's always going to be
those bugs left behind by third-party
contractors and ODM the way I define
them as I think you said a really good
thing about admin admin I have people
don't know at what it's a secure
password also usually like we don't want
passwords like stopped using passwords
we need to go away from like that better
password is also kind of a way to blame
the user instead of blaming or instead
of making a system that is usable you
blame the user or you implement a system
not according to spec that's probably
good in these cases all right I mean I
assume general depends on the use case
and where it's been deployed and the
industry verticals well on regulation
not regulated there's definitely
different use cases just not you know
IOC has a whole you know these different
security controls applied to everything
I mean you know everything has its own
time and place so I think I think you
know yes do away with past the reason
symmetry verticals is doable but when
you have you know oddity in general
there's different attack services many
from from web to mobile to RF it's hard
to authenticate and do that securely
without know you
action at all but secure by default is
something that we can do as a tech
community you can push that from design
and then there are also some
implementations of passwords that are
usable and that are somewhat secure you
don't have to use md5 hashes so if we go
back to the OEM Jerry do you think that
today they're actually focusing on
security work from the Gecko or is it
something that sort of happens or what
do you think would you take a lot I
think that we're seeing a lot of
retroactive attempts to fix these sort
of things because a lot of cases they
already have an established code base
for whatever they built I agree and
they're really trying to go back and
wedge it back into place which is not
uncommon for any other vertical to look
at I mean I spent nine years in power
systems I still wake up screaming
because there was there you know there
was one ICS vendor who will remain
nameless had a default username password
that was hard-coded and we tried to get
that change and it was roughly a half a
million Canadian dollars in order to get
a change as a change request yeah did
you ask nicely we asked nicely the first
time second time wasn't so pretty yeah
so what do you think their readiness for
secure to reach it breaches as well for
all we have do you think there are they
good are they bad could it be better
what's your encounter is what you feel
what takes for om and let's say you
you're a big ice be and you buy like I'm
a couple of million devices and you find
terrible remote code execution
I see this a different situation and you
deployed smart home infrastructure isn't
people you know yeah and and yeah I'm
not sure about the ISP space but I mean
like the vehicle space you're getting it
real quick
medical space they're there they're
getting on board but as far as being
open to research and open to security
and open to building in security or
abiding by or working with the community
as a whole I think those industries are
going and some major OEMs for consumer
are ICS is a very closed system and I
know
workers people fourth i'ma Calvary and
we're trying some of the guys work for
ICS vendors and they're trying to get
these devices and more people's hands
again their major expensive their
millions of dollars so it's about
getting you know I mean I think we're
even having possibly a desk on the
working on for example the voting system
for us over I mean it's a more people
the more eyes the better and you see bug
bounties and bug body platforms have
these IOT products and vendors out there
and good PR and that's not only good PR
it's good for internet all in our
community and and consumers as well yeah
did you have some beer okay honestly I
think we're at a pivot point where
acceptance of the conversation is
starting to take place and unfortunately
they had to be born on the heels away
something catastrophic event like we saw
with Mariah that is a problem that never
had to happen yeah I agree but it's sort
of a good thing that it happened because
it needs to get I in my opinion I think
an easy and worse in order to get better
and I think the consumer asshole needs
to be affected more and then they will
actually be more aware I'm not sure if
that works
but I mean fully you can put it in the
perspective like the Sony hack yeah
influence the entertainment really huge
accident scene now that was a good thing
we got movies for free all right no look
every dock that was but I mean just this
their their their perspective on
security like they all start hiring
things and they're all like security
first and that they don't want to be in
that that Center I of hey we didn't do
diligence everything yeah and I think
that it's important that security risks
must become business risks yeah and as
soon as they become that we will have
that incentive to to actually do
something good yeah and accountability I
think is important as well somebody
actually always off to do risk alright
that's when you mean yeah exactly and
like when it comes to that first
paradigm of security that Bruce Schneier
was talking about that we documents it
has to document when you do a bridge you
have to like you checks and balances you
have to
checklist and lien and blah blah blah
and that didn't come from nowhere you
know there have been many people dying
from train accidents there have been
many people dying from bridges falling
down or from from buildings falling down
and earthquakes and stuff No
so we always learn from these terrible
terrible incidents so we need maybe we
need those incidents I agree and and
vexed at the same time because in
Montreal in Canada we had a bridge
collapse recently that had been standing
for about 40 years
luckily nobody died in that particular
incident but when my wife and I were on
our honeymoon we went over a bridge in
Spain on a bus and the bridge was held
together by pressure it was built by the
Romans 2,000 years ago using
interlocking stones it was able to
support a bus it if it standing for
2,000 years but nowadays for making
things like bridges that collapse in 40
years
but that's revival by it survival but
yes but it's sort of it when you lend
that over to the IOT side I'm worried
that we're worried so much about making
money that we're bypassing the
fundamentals I'm also note that the ASIS
and d-link except and half from the FCC
I mean that hasn't happened and that's
huge yeah thousands of dollars and only
that was not only getting fine but like
mandated to get ten tests yeah again
that's not usually you'll get fine by
like you know wpa2 W so like wet being
install like FCC is known to like mad
everybody to do this yeah WPA to save
will VPS and yeah yeah yeah well no not
WPS I mean if you're using web so you're
going to get in trouble are going to get
fined but I mean now it's like not only
you can you fine now you have to get pen
test not so that's you know that's new
but it's also similar to other industry
verticals like are there other big
companies you work with as a partner
like you want to work with Google you
have to have you know either abide by a
security framework as well as show you
know some sort of pen test report
similar in a way but and we're back
hahahaha and so well back on about the
ISPs I'm less concerned about the moment
is contained into the devices when you
see an isp and asia an example that
shipped out home routers to their users
with the control panel being publicly
accessible with the default credential
so yeah every one of their customers was
affected something that simple is
something that could have been caught on
the way out the door yeah
so what are the audience things do you
have any inputs to this discussion don't
be shy yeah we have a lot of them oh
yeah you want one so today there have
been a lot of talk about issues that the
industry have and some suggestions how
to solve them and but one thing that
I've been lacking is how to handle
handle education say if you're a company
that develop a light bulb for 40 dollars
or something consumers can expect that
to be supported for 15 years no one
would pay for it so like what are some
actual suggestions that you could give
vendors regarding deprecation or should
they should they like to brick the
device on purpose not a ten year period
or what what are the options available
except for building like solid software
so the options for people mommy jumping
I going the option for the consumer
unfortunately are somewhat limited until
you vote with your dollars on mass so
with those types of devices you I think
you said a phone that was what you were
talking about earlier yes nope a low-end
device okay so a low-end Android phone
or low-end device of some description
that's consumer grade again we go back
to the planned obsolescence problem the
vendor actually built this in that so
that after a certain amount of time is
no longer supported well so they can
sell you a new device as a consumer that
sucks I mean that's unfortunate but
that's the reality that we live
so if consumers are voting with their
dollars on mass that can actually change
that time do I have a good answer for
you
no I don't currently there are some
recommendations provided by FTC about
sun setting sun setting devices I mean I
think this past year we saw one of I
think a company I got I got acquired by
Google and it was the IOT hub and they
turned it down people relied on I'm
gonna look over ball or I think you're
actually ready was all revolving yeah it
was it almost instantly yeah but I mean
there's there's no like set in stone
you know rule or standard I think it's
if if you build a product and say you're
going to support it for seven eight
years or ten years maybe then you have
to do that but I mean think about these
case of the lock that's probably a big
deal right and you have to contact the
lock cloud whatever cloud infrastructure
it is and that cloud infrastructure is
free for us we just buy the product you
know however much money it is and they
support the whole cloud infrastructure
but I mean I guess one way like I said
would be to be upfront and transparent
and say this device will be supported
for X amount of years and I said there's
there's some recommendations on that but
again there's nothing set in stone not
many people are being transparent about
that in blatant like you know for their
products unfortunately cool dude that
answer the question yeah more or less
not really nice it's a hard case oh
there's not a right answer to it no I
think really it's a hard question and so
at some point that there will be a right
answer but right now there isn't until
we find the heavily reliance on let's
say a car that doesn't have it's not
going to be supported and you still have
to unlock your car and it's not going to
support after five years but that car
also cost twenty thousand euros or
30,000 or 50,000 yeah I'll flip it on
its head you miss a payment they lock
you out of your car yeah it could get
ugly fast so one more yeah you you
mentioned going off to the money yes
getting you to vote on that
um these have so a lot of democracy in
that regard they have a lot of say sorry
you said VCS and democracy in the same
power yes do you think it will be useful
to convince venture capitalist to
mandate security as essentially they're
looking for their balancing risk versus
the chance of an exit a profitable exit
completely here carry sagen if you could
convince them that this is something
that would increase the probability of
their exit wouldn't that be a force
multiplier honestly yes if you were able
to articulate in a way that they
understand that they're going to make
more money because it's a better secured
product then yeah there is the chance
that you'd be able to sell them on that
but they are really in it for profit and
that understandably that's their
business model but yeah if you can make
it in a business case like that
fantastic honestly that's the first time
I've actually heard somebody bring that
up so I don't know that anybody's
actually doing that yeah I think that's
a really interesting point but even
trying to advocate security or bring or
promote within an established company
working with marketing and trying to
work with marketing to get your point
across I've done that I've try to go
there well basically short answer is
what I got was like security doesn't
sell
unfortunately for consumers you'll
you'll get you'll get you know routed
you know get pop whatever maybe and
consumers will still buy that product
and this is proven with stores and
things like that that have been breached
cool one more yeah I mean just come and
as you say security doesn't sell but
there was also a usability doesn't sell
when we had the ten years ago like the
smartphone story is adding up functions
and no usability and then someone came
around and fixed that right so let's
hope that there will be a fixing
security IOT coming up right yeah oh
holy I'm I'm on the same boat as you
I hope ok where should we wrap it up I
didn't think we actually solve anything
we just just you want to dissolve so
yeah I don't know but so what
we have a party to do that yeah we have
a party to fix it that and everybody
look at them they're so they're so into
beer I can see it they're thirsty so
yeah without further ado let's end this
thank you so much for being here thank
you for being here Hey
[Applause]