hello yeah I took the train here from
malmö I was really nice for several
reasons but one of the reasons was that
I for the first time got to use my chip
implant that I have in my hand for an
actual useful use case namely as a
ticket on the train you can do this
since two weeks or something like that
unfortunately it didn't work out but it
could have worked out the second reason
why I really like taking trains is that
I hate flying and as a security analyst
I know that doesn't make sense at all
because I know that trains and and
planes are very very secure both of them
but there is something like with my
acceptance of this that has taken a long
while and to learn how to fly or how to
do it with life I had to learn a bit
about how the aviation regulation works
so I'm just thinking that I'm working at
a start-up and so let's make the startup
I am making a plane and I thought that
okay
this is an entirely new set kind of
plane so it's going to be super awesome
I have documentation somewhere on
Dropbox I don't know if it's the final
version or it was a long time ago that I
saw it and maybe yes we have probably
tweaked it a bit since that
documentation but there is some kind of
documentation on this plane that you're
going to get into and fly 10,000 meters
up in the air also it's made out of
Google+ and it's a really really nice
kind of
our plastic it's been used in the
Eastern German car industry for quite a
while and I'm thinking like okay it
cannot withstand lightning it's proven
not to withstand lightning but I put
that in the manual so it's okay and also
a pilot a skilled pilot will avoid
lightning so this is not an issue this
is basically how we in the IT coyote
wells are talking about security and it
looks ridiculous when we talk about it
where in terms of aviation and why is
that I'm thinking that's alternative
title for this might be death by
software bug bug and life-saving
persistent threats and and I'm the third
person out here to talk about a Internet
of Things no pressure
I'm going to use this super loose
definition because for my intents and
purposes like Internet of Things isn't
something new Under the Sun and every
part of this that has been used for a
long time so some time ago I started to
live in a in a test lab for IOT and so
every time that I went home my boyfriend
would get a push notification and every
time I left home my boyfriend would also
get a push notification and vice versa
so I knew for example every time that he
slept in and didn't leave the apartment
until 15 and they in the evening and I'm
like why didn't why is he doing
something useful with your life you know
but as in the beginning here I was very
much creeped out by this idea that a
boyfriend would get push notifications
and know everything about where I was if
I was home or not but his argument was
that well
it's a tool like domestic violence was
there before there were IOT devices and
yes you can make that argument guns
don't kill people people kill people and
and we can use a tool for good we can
use it for bad
so for example like nuclear physics has
given us chemotherapy it has given us
awesome new ways to look at materials it
has also given us Chernobyl Harrisburg
sellafield Hiroshima but it can't it's
not only used for good and for bad it's
also used for accidents and we also have
accidents and we also have negligence
and we have to ask yourself there are so
many powerful tools out there like
nuclear physics like the IT have we thus
far solve more problems than we have
cost
we've probably have but we don't really
really know that when it comes to
accidents like you know a typo in the
Amazon Web Services just broke
everything for a couple of hours and
someone months ago or something and as
you know like if someone like for
example mirai leaves their default
password is going to be a problem that
lets negligence and that's a problem for
everyone bruce schneier in
january/february started talking about
that we need to regulate the internet of
things and he argues that when we come
to the internet of things we have two
paradigms of security that are clashing
with each other so we have the highly
regulated
that we have and for example medicine or
in buildings you know it wasn't a
software team that has built this
building because in that case the
probability of the ceiling coming down
on us would be exponentially high sooner
or later you know and then we have the
second the second paradigm of security
that would be Agilent patchable and in
the IOT these clash because you have for
example a car that is regulated under
these highly regulated that works under
high regulation and we have the software
so that that is agile and super fast and
yeah who cares if is really is touchable
or not and sooner or later these
software bugs are going to kill us and
he says that the market can't fix this
because neither the buyer nor the seller
cares and this is an externality and
when we have externalities we need
regulation this is an
I used to my first education was in
environmental sciences and the first and
foremost thing that they said was in
environmental economics you need to
internalize the externalities and he
argues that we haven't been able to do
that so we need regulation but I see at
least three other ways to internalize
these externalities and that would be
some kind of soft regulations some kind
of voluntary certification and extortion
so we're starting to have these
persistent threats out there so you have
different kinds of ransomware that form
simply take control over your key
package systems or your hotel or
whatever and then they will extort you
now but then you can pay some money and
this is you know often a low fee and and
maybe this is incentive enough maybe it
isn't and then there is also these new
persistence denial of service malware
that will simply brick your device the
breaker box
it was richer device and they will not
have parens them but that's it and the
person who says that he has inven has
written this code says that I regard
this as a chemotherapy for the internet
and for the internet of things because
no one in the right mind would use
chemotherapy if you were healthy but
what we're seeing right now is something
that it's downright unhealthy and so and
I am in no way
encouraging malware but I'm seeing that
when we have this kind of threat that is
persistent the incentive to do something
good will right also from May of 2018
the GD P R is kind of going to come into
force and it's all
it's already out there but no one will
get these huge fines until May of 2018
so we won't know if this really works
and when it comes to electricity we have
these C regulations that you simply
certify before the fact and in the GDP
are it's the other way around that if
you up you will have to pay a fine
base case and which will also
incentivize more insecurity and what's
also so good about possibly good about
this general data protection regulation
is that you can't claim negligence if
your up you will have to pay and
that's it but then we never know what
actually will happen when it comes maybe
it's going to be just like any other
regulation that some lobbyists kind of
way through and the third option that I
see about internalizing these
externalities is that people want to buy
secure things but they don't know what a
secure thing is we can see this for
example when it comes to passwords to
that a recent study made by internet v
ism in there seventy-five percent of the
respondents claimed that they knew how
to make a good password and that's good
that they think that but the truth is
that very very few not know this they
know false fact about this eight
character bla bla bla missed a
recommendation from the 90s which
doesn't apply anymore and so we have to
educate customers about what to look for
in one way of educating and people about
this is to have some kind of trustworthy
certification that is voluntary to do
just like the organic field and I think
this would be a really really
justing idea if this would actually come
to to market so as you already heard
people talking about today IOT is
largely a tool without the use case we
are having so much out there in the
market and what to do with them I know I
got this chip before there was any use
case for it just because I thought it
was cool yeah so I'm going to go into
that now I always wanted to be a cyborg
and so in November - yeah two years ago
or something I went to this after work
and where you could install a chip and I
thought this is super interesting and no
one in the right mind would ever do that
I think of all the like a mobile phone
is invasive enough this isn't like you
have to have some kind of
self-preservation you know can't use
everything so when's this - this after
work seminar to see what it was all
about and 30 minutes later I craved this
chip I really really needed it and I
felt like this isn't healthy I just
swapped 180 degrees what just happened
and I started to analyze this I hope no
one's getting offended here what I
realized is that security people like me
are largely we're looking at things and
we say okay this answered our threat
vectors this is the first vector this is
a vector what you're doing is not going
to work because of this and this is this
and then that entrepreneur comes along
and they get offended by us being such
douchebags and we are standing on the
side and saying
that kind of work and so we get kind of
left out behind and when the hyper
adopters and the early adopters have
done their thing and all of a sudden
this is mature technology those threat
vectors are still in there but we as
security community we stand on the side
and we say and we want to be pure and
say like I would never do that I don't
do Facebook I don't do whatever so we
choose to opt out and stand on the side
or we simply do not communicate in the
nicest way also this entrepreneur who
really is excited and like driven by
this new idea that they have they also
don't have that much money and so you
have to cut corners and you know and so
is that also adds to the injury of first
and foremost they don't know what they
are what the fraction of the threat
vector was because they don't want to
listen and secondly they don't have the
money to do it anyway
more on sidewalks and tracking devices
because I thought this was a tracking
device and that's why I thought that
anyone who would do this would not be in
the right Knight and the reason for that
is simply that I watch a lot of sci-fi
so I for example at the same time I was
doing this this Ronin guy he has a
equivalent of a GPS tracker but it it's
going through the universe's basically
it so fast in the light in some way so
he has it back here and he's being
followed by life-sucking aliens
throughout the universe or the galaxies
and seven of nine here our favorite and
she the Borg they really like to do sail
over so so even though they try to I
conceal her and deactivates world
technology that she doesn't need the as
a plot device no and then there's a
tracker that goes off in their head and
they are getting followed by Borton of
course Janeway City and also what's
interesting here in in Star Trek is that
they in for example Deep Space nine are
in the next generation they didn't
conceptualize this idea that you would
actually have a tracking device that you
can't that you're not supposed to take
off so as a plot device we can always
like take your your tracker off you can
walk away and they do that all the time
for some strange reason
so cyborg original definition a human
being with bodily functions aided or
controlled by technological devices so
they're up we have the pacemaker led
with already me talking about there we
have an insulin pump that some
intrauterine device and that's some
dialysis and why is Malala here
she has a cochlear implant that will aid
her hearing because when she got shot in
her head she lost hearing on one side
and these cochlear implants they are
super interesting because they can give
us superhuman hearing but it's not
considered ethical to give superhuman
hearing to people who have these devices
yeah but yeah the dialysis and the
insulin pump they are not implanted and
so we can have a cyborg definition that
contains my chip there we still have a
picnic and the IUD I have a hot a hip
and Malala again
and of course there is a cyborg rights
organization in Germany Seibel default
and their definition of a cyborg is that
it's a human being with an electronical
device implanted or in or steadily
attached to the body with the purpose of
increasing individual senses or
abilities beyond the occasional use of
tool so when I got this chip implant one
of the reasons was that I wanted to
claim that I'm a cyborg but it turns out
after my research that I have been a
cyborg for a long time because we're had
wearing these tracking devices with us
all the time we have our we have the
little database of of accumulated one
hundred and thousand hundred thousand
years of accumulated human knowledge in
our pockets that's kind of cool but that
also means that we are cyborgs because
we are using these all the time and it's
a strange thing to turn them off so this
implant that I got I usually get this
these questions and that exactly what is
it
so it's an eye eye so 14443 compliance
chip and it's in biocompatible glass
it's right here it was actually
implanted here that it migrated which is
not very nice but it's at the moment
it's not dangerous and and it's totally
benevolent person who has like it's
benevolent to the body and the person
who makes this he accidentally once
jammed the hammer on it when he had it
implanted in his hand and the tissue
around it broke with the glass didn't
break and they used to these chips are
have a very very small antenna so the
ISO 14443 it calls for an antenna that
is the size of a credit card or passport
because this is the technology that we
have in our credit cards and in our
passport not treaty at all but this one
is really really small so it's very very
hard to read and that was the issue with
Swedish railroads they couldn't read my
chip because firstly the antenna is too
small
secondly the mobile phones that we use
for NFC reading usually getting give too
little patrick power to the reader in
the in the device so it's very hard to
activate it and on top of that we are
mostly water so there's a lot of
attenuation going on too so they are
very hard to read and then maybe one of
these cards can be read from a distance
of a centimeter or two but this can
barely be read if you're right but on
and this in this dangerous tracking
device you know of course it's very hard
to activate this but when the field that
you when you have activated this field
that field is readable or very from very
far away so these are susceptible to
remote attack they are especially as
susceptible to social engineering
attacks and well the security of this
and it is not negligible there are have
been a Kickstarter for a NFC hacking kit
that will break every every kind of NFC
[Music]
current we have and so like it was an
utterly flawed technology from the
beginning and it does not fit for for
example authentication so what I can use
this for
is public information so I've been I was
planning to use this with my mobile
phone but as I said it's really really
hard to read this and I have to take off
the shell of my my telephone to be able
to read it so it's not very useful and
so what I've been mostly using it for is
to store my LinkedIn profile which is
public information and that's good
because you don't want to keep secret
here yeah and so the thing is that this
is kind of strange and creepy and we
feel like it should be some kind of
tracker but we are already tracked all
the time I think this is an excellent
example of feature creep that we first
had these mobile phones that used teller
cellular triangulation to pinpoint our
exact position all the time and then you
started to use them for every personal
use that you would ever do and then you
put some unique identifiers on it so you
can track people between platforms you
can crank track them all the time
because you always have this on and you
always have it with you and of course
you can turn it off but then you will
take away the core functionality and we
have a problem that if you don't have a
cell phone you cannot be part of the
society so there is no meaningful
opt-out
um I want to talk about this whoa the
people that I came we came and met when
I got this tip they were apparently
called bio hackers which is a cool new
name for keeping healthy basically so
this is something that we've been doing
all the time we've been tracking like
people have been tracking what they are
eating for a long time people have been
tracking their periods for a long time
people have been tracking lots of things
in order to improve their health and to
know for example that I will get hangry
or I will get moody in this this time of
the month or whatever this is something
that it's nothing new Under the Sun and
in the biohacking umbrella there's also
these implants if you just have biology
like CRISPR and stuff DNA labs and
what's also very important where the bio
hackers is that they will never wait for
the FDA approval to do things because if
you have a body you're fundamentally
allowed to do what you want with that
body so these this chip is not FDA
approved every part of it would be FDA
approved after all the chip that I'm
using and we have been using it for
decades in our cats and our dogs and
whether the difference that veterinaries
are not very good at piercing so they
were designed to grow into the tissue
and this is designed not to grow into
the tissue but to be movable and easily
taken out
there is this security researcher in
Norway who is called Maria Noah and she
started she was working at nor set I
think and all of a sudden she passed out
and when she woke up again she had a
pacemaker and she says that's okay
without consent I all of a sudden had
this medical device but if she wouldn't
like if she wouldn't have consented she
would have died so it's it's a good
thing that she did get it but it also
turns out that this has wireless
interfaces okay so she would if she
would have loved to she wanted to
research it and it turned out that she
wasn't allowed to do it and so on with a
little bit of activism now since October
2016 it is allowed to do research on
medical devices under certain
circumstances but you should really
check out Marie Mallette work on this
she's it's really really really
interesting and what she thinks is that
like first thing that we would think is
oh my god this is remotely hackable but
that's not the biggest issue for her
like of course there's a possibility
that you can kill someone with a remote
hack but the higher probability is that
a simple software bug will kill her
she has doctors who is performing
Diagnostics on this medical device but
they are doctors they are not
programmers you get so many new
interesting problems to solve when it
comes to medical I Oh tea
so I when I met all these biohackers I
thought this is hey this is cool you
have to like put some kind of scientific
curiosity into the body and to into the
technology what can we do here you know
in the past 200 years we have expanded
the average lifespan of a person
ridiculously much so 200 years ago there
was no country on earth that had an
average life expectancy of over 40 years
and now there is not one country on
earth that has a life expectancy under
40 years and this is due to medication
and also technology so before I've been
doing triathlon so this is my my GPS
clock that I use for that it's also kind
of useless but because what I found out
when I started to track all the things
like all the metrics of my body is all
of a sudden I'm starting to get injured
because I get too much information and
when I say that okay I get I do feel
something in my knee but my watch is
saying that I'm starting to break and
break a record here and you have a goal
conflict so I started here like I would
never recommend anyone to use a
triathlon watch for example if you are
injured because you will forget what
your goal is your goal being for example
do you have and and you will look at the
stats instead also for that reason you
know most gyms have taken away the scale
because we have realized that if your
there is no meaning you can get no
meaningful data out of weighing yourself
every day but what you will get instead
it's an rekt yeah some I've had this
really really big problem with getting
angry all the time and like I had to eat
five six times a day and this is the
kind of issue that you can't go to your
doctor and say hey I'm I have to eat
five seven five six seven times a day
because they have other issues to solve
and also they don't have the methods to
solve it so I when a friend of mine got
this beautiful device which is an NFC
sticker and a rienne NFC reader and she
didn't need her old glucose meter that
is one of those that you prick yourself
in the in the finger and I thought hey I
I need to do this experiment it's going
to be really interesting and I found out
very very interesting things with this
one for example I I saw what really
happens when you eat sugar or when I eat
sugar the thing is that when it comes to
medication and a medicine how it used to
be before we kind of yeah you have to
take a hundred thousand people and an
epidemiologic survey and you have to
take an average of that and no single
person will match that average so it may
be that the ideal dose is for the
average person is here but my ideal dose
is here or here so for example I could
see that I am very susceptible to sugar
and I shouldn't eat it I also saw that
medication that I had been starting to
take had had a lot of effect on me and
so I started to realize that my
hungriness didn't have an
thing to do with my glucose levels they
were it was a psychosomatic symptom and
since I knew that I could actually say
okay I don't need to eat right now and
it turned out I was right so you can
learn very much when you're just
applying some kind of hacker mindset or
a scientific mindset to old tools and
I'm going to buy a kitchen soon it's one
of those things that you do when you
grow up
I guess and with this I'm also going to
buy new refrigerator and a new stove and
I was at another conference last week
and I asked one of the IAT experts there
and how can I be certain that that the
refrigerator i buy doesn't doesn't
communicate with the internet because of
the obvious problems that if you have a
badly secured internet interface and you
have a refrigerator that you kind of use
for 20 years that's a very very bad
combination so I don't I want to be
certain that my new refrigerator doesn't
communicate with the internet or that it
doesn't leave data and he said that I
cannot be sure about that and I should
probably guess that most of the new
devices that I do buy contain some kind
of Internet interface without telling me
I think that's kind of a douche move
sorry to say it I think that I I think
it's okay to do boxing but that doesn't
mean that I think it's okay to to hit
someone and out on the street so I don't
think that you should hit someone
without informed consent I don't think
that you should have sex with someone's
that
informed consent and I don't think that
you should collect data on people
without informed consent it's kind of
simple you know and I'm this informed
part I think it's very very important on
that very same in a conference people
were talking about the public acceptance
and this chip the reason it creeps
people out is that it's new there is no
public acceptance about of it yet and
but as it increases as it gets more
normal people will not feel like a safe
is it safe is it safe but they think oh
this is cool and the core issue has
still not been solved so there are two
ways of doing public acceptance
it's either by making it normal or by so
that people or make make it interesting
enough so that you don't care or you can
actually make it safe and I think that
when it comes to Internet of Things it's
a good thing to make it safe rather than
to make it normal
I also think it's very very very very
important to provide the possibility of
opt-in the end of opt-out so in this
case where the refrigerator is probably
impossible for me to opt out and that's
a little bit of an issue but there's an
even greater issue that in 10 years for
example and everybody's going to have a
smart meter at home or like everything
that we have will be be given kind of a
baseline of what her life looks like and
all of a sudden you turn that off and
opt-out will mean incrimination so the
reason that we are doing industry
anthoula
that you should you shouldn't judge
someone
without help me out here what's it
called the benefit of the doubt is that
we have had very little data but now
when we all of a sudden have a lot of
data and you know it you can have more
accuracy about what's happening around
ya I don't want my opt out to be
incriminating it's as simple as that
so I think that a positive a positive
way forward for the Internet of Things
would require open software it would
acquire open standards we need safe
processes and we need same business
models what do you think you can
thank you very much do we have any
questions in the crowd right here you
said your chip was migrating yeah if it
ever does become dangerous and you had
to have it taken out would you get it
done again and if so would you upgrade
like 30 mm model no this is a very
interesting so the next generation there
is right now on the I think it is in
beta right now a cryptographic
cryptographic platform as implants that
you can get and I was really interested
in that until I got to learn that it's
not 12 millimeters but it's this big and
you can't use piercings to like you
can't use a piercer you have to use like
you have to do a little bit of surgery
and that's a bit too hardcore for me
well piercings and you know that's also
something that's more or less everybody
except nowadays so I think that if
people will get implants they will have
to be insertable in that way or in some
kind of non-invasive way I don't think
that it's a way forward to have these
really really big one anyone else all
right
looks like that's it thank you so much
[Applause]