[Music]
good morning good afternoon good evening
depending which time zone you're in
i i'm ian tabor uh or internet and this
is my car hacking talk
from an ivy in a box to a car in a box
where i go into a car hack i did on one
of my vehicles previously
and how i then built a car in a box
first things first
who am i you could say i'm the ultimate
car hacker
i built this kit car 15 years ago now um
it's based on the mid 90's rear wheel
drive um
ford uh running gear and has
a 2004 ford focus engine up front
it's got quite a bit of power doesn't
need too much but not a lot of weight
goes pretty quick it's complete opposite
of the vehicle i hacked
um and it only has three ecu's
and two of those i built myself first
which is a mega square ecu
which does the ignition and spark
for the engine the second is the little
box as you can see in the top right hand
corner
it's a arduino mega based gps data
logger
which talks over the can bus to the mega
square
gets real-time data from the vehicle to
see what's happening so i can
play with the settings etcetera at a
later time
a little disclaimer um car hacking is
done at your own risk if you break your
car
and you will if you try too hard um
please don't blame me
um i've done it once i made my gearbox
disappear but managed to get it back by
turn
disconnecting the battery for a long
period of time however
did have to um take three and a half
weeks to learn how to change gear again
so on to my car hiking history
um in 2018 i did a talk at
um dc 4420 besides
rookie track and def con 26 car hanging
village
we're browsing from a car what's the
worst that can happen that went into
more details about this hack
the disclosure process the fun that i
had with manufacturer
um i will be touching it on it slightly
but not going into as much detail
um 2018
i was invited by buck crowd to a live
car hanging event
one of 12 researchers there i then
returned again in 2019 being one of 20
researchers
um that was interesting uh come on to
that
in a bit last year at defcon i was part
of a
car hiking panel with cybergibbons and
specters
um that's quite interesting general chat
about
um how we got into it what we've found
what things we've done um also in 2019
um i went to the auto isaac
event in texas for hacker one
as part of a car hacking vulnerability
disclosure policy
panel um to try and explain
that car hackers are actually good for
the automotive industry um
it's quite an interesting time meeting
manufacturers finding out what their
issues and things are for my sins now i
also run the car hacking village in the
uk
and help out with um the team at defcon
i will be bringing my
car in the box virtually to defcon this
year um
so last year i did 12 or 13 events i
think it was
um this year there was many more planned
but however corona rs has broken it and
i've done a couple of virtual ones
including this one um
i have been asked to go to almost every
continent in the world with my current
box
india australia brazil
defcon most of europe egypt
um logistically
i'd love to but um it's
absolute pain to try and get it anywhere
so
not going to be happening anytime soon
unless i can drive there
so onto the car in question in 2015
i purchased this ds5 1955 limited
edition
it had all the bells and whistles top of
the range all the toys
including a 7-inch touchscreen in the
middle of the dashboard
which you could surf the internet on if
you
tethered to your mobile phone using
either wi-fi or bluetooth
great idea wonderful why you'd want to
do it i don't know the ui was absolutely
useless
but you could tether through um to get
internet access
so at the time i was doing lots of long
journeys up down the country for work
but being bored one evening i decided to
have a
little sniff around run map while
connected to my phone
and managed to find four ports open
twenty three
one one one three three three three and
twenty thousand
um my day my day job at the time was
network architects
so uh everyone knows what 23 does so
telnet
straight into the head unit no
credentials requested
no nothing full access to the file
system
which included the usb socket in the
middle of the dashboard so you could
copy data off
um having a look around the file system
um
there are some folders with some sql
like databases
both system and user ones most of the
system ones contained
settings and things for the vehicle um
the user ones
however um those three interesting files
which contained your navigation history
your phone book
and your telephone history um
and you could also get out all of the
details of every phone that's ever been
connected to the head unit
so um at the time when i first found out
i didn't really do much with it because
um didn't really want to break my car
it's my daily driver
but in 2017 i decided to sell it so i
had a week to find
any major vulnerability any other
releases i could
so um reading up on the vx works command
reference guide
i found out you could map an ftp server
to a file
file path and extricate the data over
ftp
so you wouldn't even have to be inside
the vehicle to hack the vehicle
so at this point i wrote up my findings
contacted the manufacturer psa to which
their comment was well it's up to the
user to secure their wi-fi
which is not really right because
i'm not saying the wi-fi isn't secure
i'm saying the actual device is insecure
by having done it available
so little scenario posed to the people
at
citron um your mobile phone's dead
you have no internet access so you pull
into mcdonald's tether your car onto
mcdonald's wi-fi
um that then gives you internet access
however at the same time
someone on the same wi-fi can then run
nmap find out where
find that port 23 open
go through your file system find out
where you are and potentially rob you
and they're like ooh that's a bad idea
so i know what the fix will be it will
be disable the wi-fi
um problem with that is um the um
the actual exploit is also available
over the bluetooth stack
using the personal area network so that
didn't really work
but um not really a problem
so sold the vehicle but then
i was told by someone one of the
conferences i went to that
20 000 was actually direct access to the
can bus using dmp3 which is an
industrial control system
protocol still haven't found out how to
generate those packets correctly but i'm
working on it
slowly so what i did was
purchase the parts to try and get it
working off of the car
so i went to scrap yard purchased the
head unit
which definitely had the wi-fi chipset
because there's a little sticker on the
top that says wi-fi
um and this purchased the screen went to
the bloke in the
scrap yard and said can i have the wires
with it because um i don't have them in
the car i'm putting it in and they're
like well
if you're not putting it in the original
car i'll give you the wires but you've
not got no warranty
so um basically there you go
there's head unit for about 300 quid
um but however if you just plug a head
unit into 12 volts these days
most of them don't even have buttons on
to turn it on and you don't get anything
out of it
what you need to do is purchase most of
those things on the floor there
had to purchase the ignition key initial
barrel
body control module engine ecu because
they're all coated together
steering switches they can come off any
vehicle instrument crusts again can come
off any vehicle
and the wiring room and get myself a 12
volt-ish power supply
plug it all in managed to get the head
unit working outside of the car
however that's not really portable so
what i did was do a bit of reverse
engineering um using um
some can bus software can utils
on a raspberry pi kicked up the canvas
listened to the messages coming through
worked out there was five messages
required
to um
basically start the head unit up without
the rest of the car being there
so i made myself this in little bottom
left-hand corner there's a little blue
box um which has an arduino nano and a
can transceiver um that then generates
those five messages so you can run the
head unit outside the car
in the case that is shown there um
when i actually got the head unit
working even though it said wi-fi on the
outside of the head unit
somewhat uh the wi-fi had already been
disabled but the bluetooth
um personal error network's still
available um
i've recently managed to find a russian
website
that tells you how to re-enable your
wi-fi as you can see there there's a
bluetooth symbol for bluetooth terrain
wi-fi symbol for wi-fi covering that's
quite handy
it's much easier to actually do the
attack via wi-fi
that is via bluetooth because bluetooth
just takes so long to do enable
the only saving grace on the head unit
regarding the exploit
is that it isn't automatically enabled
every time you get in the vehicle
you have to manually go in and turn on
either bluetooth tethering or wi-fi
television
um so at this point i was probably in it
for about
500 pounds so the head unit and the
wiring loom and
the other other pitch you saw previously
i parked it for a bit uh because i had
defcon and things to go to
uh however i wanted to make a um karna
bench
the inspiration for my car on the bench
is here
this is grim cybers um 3po
which has all the ecu's from a 2012 ford
focus
in the us it's probably identical to the
2012 focus in the uk but the steering
wheel's on the wrong side
but whatever however this doesn't
actually think it's a fully working car
it has all these to use you can play
with the data going around
you can make it do things by injecting
data as as you wish
however um it doesn't actually think
it's a working car
so um at the time i then went off to the
bug bash
me and a couple of other people found a
major vulnerability in the vehicle we
were testing
um we then got a payout of a five
share of payout of a five figure some
between the three of us
um which gave me a bit of spare cash to
actually build the rest of my car on the
box
or in this case car on the floor so i
had to then purchase
all these other extra bits um
so on the left you've got steering rack
um with its associated ecu
throttle body main fuse box which also
has an ecu in it
engine ecu already had abs ecu for the
brakes
throttle pedal because it's an
electronic throttle plate all uh body
control model i already had
there were some other switches and
things that i need to purchase to get
the lights and stuff working
some of the lights um switch cluster
already had
instrument cluster yes already had i
also had to buy all the sensors
and all the electronic components that
are attached to the engine
apart from the big things like
alternator and
start motor because they're just motors
and they're triggered by three wires
don't really need to emulate one of them
um
but so at that point i then had a car on
the floor
which is a bit messy and yeah great it's
not the easiest thing to get out
set up and play around with so i then
had to
see if i could get rid of some of this
wiring
onto wiring looms um so this is the
wiring diagram for my kick guards ecu
it's a mega squirt 3.0 it has a db37
of which 26 wires are connected i
believe
six of those of which are ground it's
not the
most complex engine in the world it uses
batch injection
wasted spark ignition
single fuel pump
crank sensor throttle position sensor
heat single oxygen sensor
coolant temperature and intake
temperature and that's quite a bit of
uh wiring especially when you have to
build it from scratch
however on the peugeot 208 that i had
um there's the wire wiring diagram for
the
main engine ecu in the middle and the
associated parts are actually
needed to make that work um the main
engine ecu has two 53-way connectors one
goes off to the engine compartment
one goes off back to the body and
there's another 32-way connector which
also goes off the body
so that's 138 possible pins that could
actually be used
um quite a few of them are most of them
are actually
um this is because the engine in
question is a cylinder with sequential
injection
coil on plug dual o2 sensor dual
variable time
valve timing including dual cam sensors
it
also had um
air temperature whatever manifold air
pressure sensor electronic throttle
body and electronic pedal
this is just the single wiring diagram
for that one function every wiring
diagram for every function
is different there is no wiring diagram
that says
here is everything on that vehicle it's
an absolute pain
um when you're trying to build something
with all the bits of the wiring diagram
but
so we've got the engine ecu wired up but
we need to make the engine think it's
actually rotating
so what you need to do is you need to
spoof the crank and cam signals
um the way you do that
is the crank sensor on this
particular petrol engine um uses what
they call 60-1
pattern in which there's 59 holes
drilled in the back of the flywheel
there is a magnetic sensor pointing at
it and as as the 59 holes go around it
makes a waveform and the 60th hole is a
space that it knows where it is
and that can give its waveform for
the um crankshaft the camshafts
themselves
there are two camshafts in this vehicle
both have variable valve timing
um the cat one of the camp sensors is
here
the other cam center is over here and
there is a
profile on the end that also again has a
sensor pointed at it
and creates a waveform just so that the
engine knows where it is in the
um cycle depending on where it's put
the where it wants to put the variable
valve timing
so i had to find a bit of hardware and
or software that could do this
arduino comes to rescue a bit of
software called argustim
here is a trace from a
protocol analyzer top row
is the crank sensor first second row
is the inlet sensor and the third one is
the exhaust sensor
as you can see the crank sensor it
repeats twice for every one turn of the
cam
that's because it's a four-stroke engine
and you've got the suck squeeze pan
below
down in the bottom corner is a pcb i had
built
after i'd originally built it just so
that if anyone else wants to try and
build
a car in a box they can then generate
these signals quite easily
um there is space on that pcb for both
surface mount and through-hole versions
of the transistors
and resistors there's also a third spot
for one of the transistors to be a very
large one for slightly heavier
duty um slightly heavier duty
transistor load
so that was the cranking cam sensor
sorted
some of the other sensors on the vehicle
you can get away with just a
potentiometer
fuel gauge being one water temperature
being another
you can also use something to create a
vacuum on the manifold air pressure
sensor i tried to use a
syringe a large syringe attached to a
pipe it doesn't always work
but most of the time it gives you enough
of an it will
actually fall center enough to think
it's doing it
um there are some other things you need
to for when building a car in a box
um things like indicators you have to
have the correct load
for the indicators otherwise they'll
flash fast
onto the next sensor that was had to be
simulated in some way shape or form
um most cars nowadays have lambda
sensors
which are used to to check how the
fuel is burnt within the engine um
there's one pre
and post the catalytic converter they
basically create
a ac waveform on a dc offset
which basically says i'm going lean i'm
going rich i'm going to lean i'm going
rich
this is the circuit it uses a 555 timer
and those
values of um visitors and batteries as
shown
there are two of these inside my car in
the box one for the pre-cat one for the
post cap
the lambda sensor also has a separate
part that you also need
for in that there are heater circuits
within the sensors
they draw about an er one amp all the
time
so you need a um suitably sized and
high wattage resistor to be able to
fall the lambda heater sensor and the
sensor heater even
to think the vehicle is working
otherwise you'll throw an error message
the last of the sensors that was an
absolute pain to fool
i originally tried to do it
electronically by trying to monitor the
waveform
when spinning
the disc in front of a
sensor using a drill wasn't fast enough
and i couldn't work it out but what i
have done here is there is a motor in
the middle there
attached to a disc around that disc is
the reluctor wheel which would normally
be on your
um axle on the vehicle and there are
four sensors around that um
relaxed wheel one for each of the four
corners of the car
that then tells the abs ecu that your
wheels are rotating
what you need to then do is pulse using
that arduino nano
and here and the
rg stim with a larger transistor
you can then possibly modulate that
motor to speed up or slow down depending
on
where how fast or slow you want the
engine to think it's uh
this wheels to think it's going around
um that was a challenge but it's now
working
works quite well doesn't fail
too often sometimes it ends up going 170
odd mile an hour which is just a bit
weird but
oops whatever onto the car in the box
itself
um there are here is a map of the can
networks inside the car
and there are four canvases and the red
and orange one on the left hand side is
what you would call your main canvas
the one you can actually normally access
in the vehicle
there is your obd2 port on the bottom
left-hand corner
that bus then goes to the body control
module
the abs esp ecu power steering engine
ecu
and the main fuel fuse box that is a
high speed
bus at 500k there are two other low
speed buses at 125k
there's the yellow and green one which
goes from the body control module
which acts as a gateway to the steering
control ecu
so the one where all your switches for
your lights and the indicators and
things
the airbag ecu which i haven't put in
the car in a box because i really don't
want someone to try and set an airbag
off
at a conference and me having to fill a
form in
and then again there is an additional
obd2 port on that bus
so you can see what's going on on the
bus or inject messages if you want to
make it do something nefarious
the second blue and darker blue
low speed bus comes from the body
control module
and is for the instrument cluster and
the matrix within the instrument cluster
which gives you
gps commands on things and the ivi
again i've got an additional obd2 port
on this
bus too for reasons for
monitoring and or injecting data finally
there is a
fourth bus which is a high speed bus
between the ivi screen
and the head unit itself which i believe
is for the touch panel
so you can see what's going on
if it works might as well
so what does the car in the box look
like my current box is called
pdo p for peugeot d0 is 208
in hex which is what the vehicle has
come from
there is the main box at the bottom
there the box in the middle at the top
is a record box for 12 inch records
which is where the um
abs simulator is and then there is the
case for the iv in the box
um this all sort of fits in the back of
my car quite well
um i used to take up the whole boot and
all the back seat on my previous vehicle
not fun when going to a conference and
you have to try and stick around and
leave your car
exposed but yes
some of you are probably wondering how
much this has actually cost me to build
the ibi in a box was probably
a total of about 500 pound the rest of
the components probably cost me about
another 1500 pounds that's probably
about
2 grand in it um i could have probably
done it a bit cheaper by buying a whole
car
and then stripping everything out and
then selling the bits i didn't want
but that's just grief and don't really
have anywhere to store the other bits
um but yeah two thousand pounds that was
all paid for
thanks to the finding that we had on the
vehicle at the bug bash
so here again are the pictures of the
abs sensor simulator and the head unit
in a box
here is um a picture of my car in the
box
as you can see um the control
most of the control parts on the right
hand side so you've got the steering
switches
your dashboard switches your ignition
key instrument cluster
there's also the washer bottle attached
there
message me afterwards i'll tell you a
story about that one
on the left-hand side you've got all the
engine components so the engine ecu
audio stim on the left there you've got
um variable resistor for the water
water temperature the o2 simulator at
the top
pedals throttle body etc
there's also a board that allows you to
see what lights are going on
uh under that board are the very large
resistors for the um
indicators so you can they flash
correctly
so they don't flash fast um
so that is it in its um
exposed form so we think so
here here's a little video of my car in
the box
so that's argue stim burying the rev
counter
and it's currently doing about 2 000 rpm
and now i'm going to turn on the abs
simulator
and vary the speed you can hear the
motor going
it's currently doing 100
143 mile an hour
i'd like to like to see you do 143 mile
an hour and a purge of toy it probably
um shake itself to bits
there you go it's gone back down to
nothing
that is just an example of what you can
do you can also do
can injection and make those things do
itself
so um here is a little thing i produced
when i first started the car hiking
village in the uk
it's a nano can adapter i give out these
pcbs
as my business card this is last year's
one
so 2019 still got a load left anyone
wants one message me afterwards
i will send it to you if you cover the
postage
um what this allows you to do is build a
canvas adapter
for probably less than five dollars it
uses
a cheap arduino nano from china which is
a couple of dollars and a
mcp2515 can controller module
um again another couple of dollars from
china
it's easier if you buy the components
yourself
because getting one through customs is
quite easy
getting a box of 50 through customs
slightly harder i get them
charged for import tax etc
this in its default form if you load
them receive all sketch
shown here um you can use with the
arduino
ide on the serial console
and see all the messages going through
can bus
here is the same messages going through
putty
just use it as a 500k serial port
the github repository is there there are
some other ones for
other microcontrollers as well tnt the
sp32
but if anyone does want one give me a
shout
um here is another video of
what i call disco mode one of my little
um can adapters is programmed
to um randomly generate messages
for the light switch module um which
then basically calls it go
cause it to go into an epileptic fit and
do the flashy lights for you uh it's
quite interesting
um a friend of mine has a peugeot 208
and we were going to put it in his car
so when he got to a certain speed
um the lights would go mental and he'd
get worried but he wouldn't let us
so yeah swell sport um
so it's amazing what you can do by just
injecting messages
but don't play with your own car unless
you know what you're doing
that is why i have the car in the box
that is why i bring it to conferences
because if you it's if you break this
it's not going to kill someone i can
just replace one part might cost me
a small amount of money but not
excessive amount of money
um but that is me done i'd like to say
thank you
a to the grim cyber team for their
inspiration and their help in building
it
um b to the cartoon village team all
mentioned there
um for their support in building what is
now car hacking village uk
and the wider car hacking village brand
around the world
um also thank you to nohamsek for
inviting me here to this
activity con and haka one team for the
conference
and for the trip to the auto isaac last
year
if there are any questions please hit me
up on the discord channel
afterwards um that is me
done