all right well we've got people all over
the building
already but let's get started welcome to
besides Indy year number four when we
started this out we were at developer
town in the past couple years we were at
Ivy Tech and good times good memories
but you know we're growing a little bit
so this space I think makes a little
more sense for us so I'll just give you
some background on how I think today
hopefully will go we have obviously
snacks out in the atrium
coffee water donuts that sort of thing
the restrooms for here are on either
side out these doors
and then as you walk past the
registration there's a ballroom with the
villages area and that includes the
lockpick village the IOT village mr.
blinky blinky are doing their soldering
stuff we've got hacked for kids we've
got I use spices here with some cool
giveaways so a lot going on of course
the CTF with Lyn tile looks like it's a
lot of fun again this year always clever
puzzles in a good time there will be
we're fortunate enough this year to be
able to give away two Sands Network
passes for the CTF winners yeah
that's gonna be good we've got
certificates from the pen test academy
for training that we're gonna give away
we've got humble bundles which are books
that you can use to learn more to win
the CTF next year no I don't know but
yeah hopefully you got a raffle ticket
when you checked in and we'll have some
giveaways later I know rally security is
giving away a kit thank you Tim and
rally security if you haven't seen their
podcast check it out we have a question
the question is where the tickets in the
sands bags the answer is no so I guess
on the honor system we'll go back
through the line and pick up a raffle
ticket if we need to yay
very good but I want to thank for sure
our sponsors you know we could not have
done an event of this size in a venue
that's nice without their gracious and
generous support you can see some of
their logos up here some of them are
here some of them are recruiting
speaking of recruiting we have cybersex
jobs who's given wristbands and these
are if you're hiring or if you're
looking to hire someone you can wear
these wristbands hopefully make it
easier to identify and make that
connection but I know you know I work at
Salesforce I know Salesforce is hiring
like gangbusters if you're looking for
work if you're a student you know
heading in that direction definitely ask
because it's happening you know that
this is this is a great place to make
those sorts of connections uh well let's
see do we have this price mcdonald here
yep perfect we have a great first
speaker I'm gonna go ahead and call him
the keynote but he's going to tell us
his 15 years of experience in would be
information security basically and yeah
we're all very excited thank you so much
for coming most of all this event would
not be possible without you guys so
thank you for coming and I hope everyone
has a great day I'll talk to you again
at the end of the day price McDonald
[Applause]