good afternoon how is everyone
awesome have a good lunch everyone nice
and full and awake and caffeinated and
all that good stuff right awesome
alright well to my title of my talk is
the pillars of continuous incident
response we're gonna talk about Incident
Response kind of really how it's how
it's that ultimate team sport so of
course my talk a little bit about myself
high level of the IR process the pillars
of Incident Response that I like to call
it an actual walkthrough of the template
that we use on the Cisco IR team that we
use when we're drafting communications
indicators of copper eyes all that and
then in QA of course at the end it's a
little bit about myself of course like I
said team leader for the Cisco Security
ascent response services team my
background spans law enforcement
academia and then of course consulting
being a former cop I spent 10 years
which is really where I got my start
here in Indiana is involved in of course
Internet crimes against children is on
the Secret Service electronic Crimes
Task Forces spend a lot of my time and
going back to the old days when we were
you know our investigation started you
know just coming Ebates fraud right and
really how everything kind of evolved
really over that time then do an IR
digital forensics Incident Response now
for over eleven years and like I said
I'm an an Indiana resident when I'm not
of course
traveling or work you know married have
a family I also like to coach coach
youth football as well and that's kind
of what a lot we're you know this step
you know a lot more my my talk stemmed
from is you know things and pitfalls
that we see in organizations every day
from communication and a range of things
every day that organizations continue to
you know fail outright and how do we get
better because at some point depending
on your role and in security right
you've probably responded to an incident
at some point so a quick disclaimer
using my own of course not intend to be
legal advice
and of course always consult with a an
attorney for legal advice if you've done
incident response you're probably
familiar with the incident response
lifecycle right preparing that
identification of containment phase
right one of the worst things to do
during us that response is to underscore
pan incident you know maybe we shut off
the the C to channel that the attackers
were leveraging but we didn't realize
that you know me me cats and pop domain
credentials right on on our on our
domain controller so you know that
identification and containment piece are
really a circular process as security
professionals we understand that you
know I mean you know we really
understand that that containment and
then moving towards eradication recovery
and post it's an activity and this is
really the life cycle and you know that
we follow prepare train how you'll fight
because you'll fight how you train I
mean I think that's most important
depending on your organization building
that muscle memory so in the event an
incident does occur it's not really
something that you have to think about
right I mean it's just like hey we
practice this we rehearse this we know
what exactly what we need to do during
an its it often times you know I see
that you know we forget about the people
component well who's ordering lunch
right what about our network security
engineer that's working 80 hours that
week does anyone let Human Resources
know that hey he's probably having a lot
of overtime this week
so you know when you know they're not
calling questioning when you're trying
to you know kind of keep that incident
under wraps depending on what type of
incident it is maybe it was a third
party notification from the FBI
whatever it may be right so the people
component you know is really very
important during Incident Response so
the pillars prepare collaborate and
train so how does that really transcribe
having an incident response plan right
preparing having those discussions the
communication is huge and that's often
one that is constantly folks myths
organizations myths is that as
communication it's the most important
thing the example I used earlier a you
know an actual true notification where
forgot about letting the proper resource
another pepper folks know that hey we
you know our network security teams can
be working a lot of overtime this week
so it's the little things that are
important and of course tabletop
exercises and when done tabletop
exercises and
organization so having an incident
response plan right does your
organization have an incident response
plan I see this more and more
organizations are building a formal
incident response plan or maybe it's
just you know ad hoc right we downloaded
some things that we found you know on
the internet and this is our incident
response plan so really trying to grow
and and mature that process you know we
whereas InfoSec we wear many hats an
organization right
I'm sure if you know if you're a junior
you know an entry-level attorney honest
or whatever your role isn't you know
network security you probably wear a ton
of hats in your organization are really
every day so you're getting pulled a
million different ways so we all were
many hats and you know in our daily
roles in our organization now how do you
create an instant response plan there
there are many frameworks out there you
know having that computer security
incident response team and the important
piece is you know having a reporting
classification you know and response
will be built in as I mentioned there
are many frameworks the key thing is you
know really pick one and and follow it
right you know DHS cert has a good one
out there sands of course has has
published a lot as well than NIST a big
fan than this documentation because it
really you know not it just doesn't say
thread the needle but it took it really
walks you through how to thread that you
know how do you handle incidents how do
you respond instance how do you build
out plans then and then of course first
anyone familiar with first very good
order decision so the bottom line is
whatever that frameworks gonna be you
know the important piece is really just
kind of pick one and and stick to it and
and the biggest thing is you know
getting buy-in having a an executive or
ass is oh right that really signs off
that's the sponsor of that of that
instant response plan because you know
you could create an IR plan and unless
you have buy-in on the business side
it's really going to I mean it's it's
you know it's going to be just one of
these another another security thing
that we do and it's gonna fall over so
buy-in is extremely important
of course I talked about sands in the
NIST documentation
the 800 series documentation is
important anybody familiar with JP cert
Japan's computer emergency response team
they have a really great some really
great documentation so if you're wanting
to you know look for that attacker
you know hunt an attacker and event logs
or maybe PS exec writes any other ways
power system the other means that no
attackers are leveraging in our
environments JP sir actually put out a
very good how-to and some of the testing
that they've done so if you're a blue
team or our forensic or an IR person you
know being able to see a lot of those
artifacts the event logs a master file
table u.s. Journal forensics all that
type stuff very cool very cool stuff and
like I said they've actually published a
lot of good documentation as well so
when you're building out your c-13 right
I mean it comes in many different
flavors one of the key components is get
legal and communications involved Human
Resources IT and often overlooked is
business continuity and disaster
recovery those folks bring a very great
perspective and knowledge to building
out an incident response program and
plan because the end of the day I mean
what are our jobs as security
professionals right to support the
business you know in the event of a
disaster whether it's a a you know a
cyber security disaster IT disaster
wherever maybe our job is to is to real
is to support that business function at
the end of the day the technical
capabilities you know they're I'm a very
big advocate of training like I said
earlier you know train how you fight
because you'll fight how you train right
understanding what your capabilities are
from a technical perspective right and
then if you need to leverage a an
outside firm or you know a consultancy
to bring in that knowledge that's also
very important you know getting your
your C cert team to you know meet on a
on a monthly I'm on a monthly basis have
like you know you know you know instant
response happy hour or something like
that on you know on a Friday so but
identifying those core team members it
doesn't mean you'll notice it's not
necessarily all a security right I mean
it's really made up of a
you know a cross-section of really
however organization is laid out right
maybe we just have one person that does
security maybe we don't have any you
know internal legal counsel maybe we
don't have a human resource person you
know our IT person is very a very
skeletal crew so again going back to my
I was saying earlier having you know
leveraging the talent and and
capabilities that we have in-house is
very important building out that
incident classification and incident
severity right I mean I've seen some
incident response plans that you know
when we're doing interviews with folks
they came to get the own terminology
right you don't have to have some fancy
type of terminology right minor severe
catastrophic simplicity is critical
communication and developing whenever
we're building out an incident response
plan and building out playbooks
simplicity is a good thing building that
muscle memory because any event of an
incident stress is high livelihoods are
on the line it's really important to be
able to not even think about it just it
just happens as well but also important
to is you know as it relates to
classification not every event you know
is necessarily an incident right if you
work in a sock I'm sure you probably are
often fatigued by the number of alerts
that you probably get on a daily
business which is a huge from a a talent
pool perspective analyst fatigue in a
sock you know if you've you know
depending on the maturity of your sock I
mean that's you know as security
professionals we want to do interesting
things we don't want to be fatigued by
you know a level one alert every time
you know something comes in we want to
find the badness we want to find the
needle in the haystack you know within
our environments establishing
relationships you know outside of an
organization it's very important
especially if it's a we'll just say a
three-letter agency notification having
a partnership with your local FBI office
Secret Service if you're active and
InfraGard
EMS ISEC all these different
organizations that will allow sharing of
information I think some of the best and
when I start talking about Intel here in
a little while some of the best Intel is
just you know networking you know like
we hear it besides India right talking
to folks sharing sharing war stories I
mean that really does it really does pay
off
in the long run our DNA you know as
humans as security professionals we want
we want to connect with folks right
we're here for gaining knowledge for
learning for networking grow our career
maybe we're new to you know InfoSec and
we're wanting to you know really you
know get into security right you know
it's it's our DNA as humans we want to
communicate we want to interact
maybe it's an IRC maybe it's slack right
Twitter or whatever we want to connect
with folks and bedding that
communication into your IR program in
your process is critical
that's why communication I have is one
of the critical pillars to Incident
Response right talking to folks over
communicating things you would be
surprised in the in the heat of the
battle I can think of various incidents
that you know my team that we've been
involved with right I mean someone finds
an awesome indicator maybe they it's not
communicated and then we overlook it we
document it right take a note to a
document one that maybe you go back and
revisit it or someone else looks at it
it's like wow that learners are smoking
gun so that communication piece you know
I say embedding communication into our
DNA talking about it sharing sharing
things I think sometimes that's one of
our Achilles heels and InfoSec because
we don't like to share we like to to
keep things really tight instead of
trying to extract ideas and share
coordination of internal communications
I mean that that's really important if
an organization is breached the last
thing I wanted you know if I'm an
employee and I my informations
compromised I don't want to hear about
it on the news I want my company to tell
me about that incident so you know
coordinate the hoarding a coordination
of those you know internal
communications is very important just
like you know kind of really beyond the
scope of our audience here but you know
the external communications right when
we need to let customers clients when
when brand and reputation you know are
on the line having a playbook for
communications you know is very
important some of the best from a info
64 what some of the best play books I
you know I when I had a chance to create
some review are the ones that you know
if I bring if I'm a Jew
your analyst this is my first day on the
job right I've been here for a day I
should be able to take some type of
playbook maybe it is you know
investigating a phishing email whatever
it may be right or investigating window
or Windows Event log looking for you
know the event ID successful logins what
does that mean creating a playbook
so anyone doesn't matter if your junior
or mid everyone understands exactly how
we approach that problem creating some
type of a playbook and communication a
document is very important anyone read
Clifford's stoles the Cuckoo's egg
classic right what was the difference in
what Clifford Stoll did and I remember
this passage in the book documented what
cliff you took notes you documented the
attacker right he took copious notes
document really you know everything you
know everything that you do something to
be mindful of and I'll get to this here
shortly as it relates to attorney-client
communications I'll go back to that one
I actually texted my next slide case
study I told myself it wasn't gonna beat
up on target but it there's many lessons
to be learned from this so the National
Law Review magazine and going back to
remember I was just talk about
communications right attorney-client
privilege for target so when all these
lawsuits start you know being tossed
targets way it's kind of there's a
little irony in that statement isn't
there so when all these love lawsuits
started right I'm the the trial court
agreed that information sought by
plaintiffs was protected from discovery
so what is discovery you know in the
event of civil litigation you know it's
that exchange of information requesting
documents processes documentation all
that I mean you know notes and all that
stuff that could be summoned nor the
later time however one thing that was
critical that actually helped them as
far as shield them from a more liability
according to this this article on this
attorney that wrote this article or net
for National Law Review magazine
investigatory materials were clearly
marked as privileged
prepared and directed and delivered
directly to Council the incident
response team understood that so there
was that the rules of engagement that
understanding the ir team knew exactly
okay you know the difference between you
know investigatory material and
remediation reports indicators of
compromise you know hash values IP
addresses signatures anything associated
segregating that material really helped
really help them as far as their overall
scope I don't never what they end up
paying out I mean it was obviously in
the millions of dollars but one key
aspect here email+ lawyer plus request
for advice equals privilege that was
actually one thing that the that the
court actually found out when you're
doing and I'll talk about tables
remember tabletop exercises as being
that other pillar right for instant
response any time you know I work with
organizations where you have the legal
team involved it's always interesting to
see depending on the scenario within
minute they invoke privilege how that
changes the communication you know we're
not gonna use slack anymore to talk
about we're going pins and paper and
phone calls so obviously you know that
varies but that's always very
interesting to see you know during an
incident I'm really how that kind of
changes things so I'm gonna dive in here
to the communications template that we
use it's actually available on blogs at
Cisco comm so free to download if you
want there's lots of templates out there
I don't know if you're familiar with
Winnie zeltser of the sands fame he
teaches that believe he still teaches
the reverse engineering course but he
has a diamond model and some other
things and some of the tip let's the
kill chain and different things and
templates that you can download as well
it's on his on his website so I
mentioned that but I also want like I
said I want to do a dive here into to
our document like I said this is
available for download all right so this
is one of those diets kind of been
tweaked and you know kind of over time
right you know understanding who the
audience is I mean most executives most
folks want to be able to quickly access
you know the doctor they want the lay of
the land
tell me what the summary is include all
that you know the you know the
indicators are compromised do a deep
dive I want that in there but oftentimes
that first section they're not they're
not going to read past you know that
first section right so the latest update
you know providing the most recent
information to leadership so they can
make stand form and make key business
decisions latest update current impact
you know that's really important like I
said earlier one of the worst things to
do during incident response is to
underscore you know what incident
thinking you you know killed the C Tube
channel but you know forgetting about
the backdoors and you know the attackers
already have domain admin is still into
the environment so you know being it's
always critical is being able to really
tie that tie that to the incident you
know if it's something like a motet you
know quiet about something a lot of
banking Trojans that are out there you
know SMB vulnerabilities right I mean is
there still the you know as far as the
organization getting you know moving
back to business as usual what is that
you know what is that current impact we
have credentials that are compromised so
we've had credentials that are
compromised let's talk about quack file
I use that for example that's a popular
ranking Trojan you know Ted
quack bout right key logging
capabilities I mean that kind of changes
notification right and kind of how I
respond if you know we've had X number
of employees or users on our endpoints
right that you know had all had
credentials that were compromised so
that that changes things including that
type of information within a a template
or a document it's very important you
know areas of concern right anything
that that may be involved like said you
know this is free to download take it
you know tweak it do whatever you want
to if you don't want to use it that's
that's fine too but there's some some
good information in here of course if
you have a way or our template that that
you use if you're doing any type of
instant response you know please share
please share that as well action items
and this is what's great I mean it's so
easy as you know security professionals
right to go down a rabbit hole we want
to go down a rabbit hole what's a
necessary but we don't want to waste
spare you know brain or CPU cycles right
going down you know maybe chasing
something down
we don't need to so document you know
those action items right what's the
status who owns that you know is it
Kanye West Jimmy Joe who is it
when was that requested and we like to
color coordinate things within our
document so you can quickly visually say
okay well that's new that's great that's
complete you know that was just
completed so you know like right here
you know patient zero one seven lab I
our memory forensic analysis you know so
I can quickly look at that and kind of
see where the action items are what
needs to be done and kind of you know to
own that I mean when when the buildings
on fire are people's hair's on fire
being able to take all of that stuff and
and look at it it's very important right
to to kind of as your continued to you
know you know work to containment
post-incident activity being able to to
see exactly you know what those action
items are alright so including all that
stuff you know
you know posted syntactic tipping mate
you know analyze disk images possibly
depending on where we're at and really
what does what the scope is and the
caterers have compromised and all that
you know ongoing intelligence summary
and I just included this here from me
just from a recent blog post that I
pushed out last week so figure one below
and this is like the intelligent summary
this is where you're going to put
indicator this is going to be the the
meat of your report this is where you're
going to put indicators of compromise
really any intelligence maybe it's a
threat actor group right when we're
engaged in emergency response we work
very closely with Talos so there's a lot
of things that we will include from an
Intel perspective in this section of the
report so sis Mon and when using system
on on their endpoints system on for the
win right it's free and be noisy it does
require tuning but if you think about
you know me me cats in this example here
and this you know I pulled down and ran
the PowerShell invoke mimikatz
and right here in our system on event
logs again I'm just using this to kind
of demonstrate kind of maybe something
that you would include here and your
findings or intelligent summary section
right the system log then ID one process
create right invoke me me cats you know
being pulled down you know that invokes
at full strength you know being pulled
down here as well now depending on
logging right I mean you know it you
know I'm gonna include any analysis in
this section as well so here for example
using volatility the RS can plug in out
during memory forensic analysis using
volatilities your skit yaris can plug in
and the Mimi the Mimi catch er role
which of course is download ray and
available right there on github you know
running this command you know the local
security authority DEP module right
identifying Mimi cats being ran so
including that intelligence summering
right the raw you know the raw output
but in the current impact being able to
explain that to that business side okay
this is bad right you had Mimi cats in
your environment what does that mean you
know to the business side right you know
enterprise wide password resets that's
painful for aces o or an executive deep
to have to hear and have to you mean we
got to worry about changing 50,000
credentials or whatever the number may
be right so including that but then in
that current impact really explaining
why we're concerned that we have Mimi
cats running in the environment just the
output here so current recommendations
any recommendations you know that we may
have any recent discoveries any
recommendations you know you've made
from a tactical perspective problem more
than likely if you're an enterprise
defender you're probably gonna be you
know maybe put in just some tactical
stuff in here right you know you know
password changes you know logging right
whatever it may be we're gonna put that
in our recommendation section previous
incident summary so when we're engaged
with a client for emergency response
what we're depending on what the cadence
is you know we're going to it's a daily
cadence where we're meeting and kind of
reviewing kind of the lay of the land
the scope kind of where we're at you
know with the with the incident response
we're gonna clewd previous updates in
this and the bottom of this I mean these
updates can grow to tins and sometimes
I'm using some hundreds of pages
depending on the type of incident it is
a
the type of analysis required but the
bottom line is you know on this document
your most recent information including
here at the top that way you know
depending on who the audience is you
know still a lot of executives like to
read things on email right so having
something in a in a Word format that
they can read as well as you can see no
really identifying information trying to
keep anything to identify the
organization out there come up with a
code name or whatever right so find a
cool code name
you know Marvel or DC depending on you
know superhero right come up with a code
name to use for for this for this
document so that's like I said this
document is available for download and
so feel free to use it
tweak it whatever but it's definitely
it's good I mean it's it's been battle
tested and kind of refined and work
we're constantly we use it on our team
and we're constantly changing it to
update it and really make it better we
tried it simple right
update so your your executives whoever
your audiences they see what we're doing
on it we have our action items now who
owns it right and that way we you know
we can make sure we're still progressing
and working our way towards containment
eradication all right very important um
you know it's so easy you know in the
heat of a battle to you know kind of get
caught up on kinda you know what if it's
a that's let's just say it's a
third-party notification really that
they you know the impact and you know
day zero right from right where that
incident happens I always tell relations
let's yeah let's we'll get through today
we'll get through the next week but
let's also be thinking about 30 60 90
days out right I mean that's important I
mean everyone wants to get back to
business as usual you know during an
incident if it's a counter strike of a
catastrophic event yeah I mean people's
livelihoods jobs are on the line right I
mean we see that when you know these
major you know when these breaches
happen
you know folks livelihoods are on the
line so it's it's very important to kind
of be that calm reassuring voice I mean
that will pay pay dividends in the long
run and and really focusing on you know
using some type of formal document to
you know focus on tactical goals within
strategic as well right what a better
time to get sex security budget if you
have an incident right that would be a
strategic goal what can we do to
continue to to move the needle to evolve
and get better
crisp concise communication right if
your audience is you know maybe it's
your your security leader whoever you
know leave the leave the text speak in
there that's fine but if your audience
is depending on you know I work I have
some scissors that you know have more of
a business background others you know
write Python scripts so it really having
that walk you know that wide range
understanding what exactly they're gonna
understand because you want to make sure
that you're clear and concise and the
information that you're relaying one
thing that's cool you know working
Fransisco you know having a lot of the
collaboration and communication tools
that we have in place come up with
something that you use to for
communication I talked about slack we
use spark other tools to communicate but
think of a out-of-band way that you
could communicate okay you don't if
you're using service if your IT
ticketing portal is service now whatever
it may be
would it for your security your incident
you want to keep that entirely separate
last thing you want to do is be using
the same ticketing portal right tip off
the attacker so that's something come up
with some type of out-of-band
communication you know the security team
is using to communicate during an
incident that's that's that's very
important catastrophic major minor so
what type of you know these are examples
of critical communication I can tell you
I've seen updates and briefings how many
times have you know it seems like one of
the biggest productivity learners what
meetings right getting getting pulled
into meetings you know you look at your
counters I've got all these meetings
I've got to go to it's very important I
can tell you from being in the trenches
in firsthand when you start pulling you
know our security folks are people off
the handle hands off keyboard to jump in
a meeting that can be counterproductive
right
but having that incident commander that
understands what everyone is working on
right that's kind of managing that
entire incident right from beginning to
end the entire lifecycle sometimes you
know when we're involved that's a hat
that we wear because they're not mature
and they need someone kind of being the
tip of the spear to drive the incident
let's get it done let's make it happen
right take care of our people Drive that
incident to success but I can tell you
I've seen when it comes to containment
and think about work you know and even
like say do work stationary imaging
right trying to rebuild workstations
from a gold bill where we pull you know
why is it why can we only rebuild 75
workstations an hour well if we're
pulling 15 folks off that are doing that
task that's part of our containment
remediation to jump on a bridge that's
you could book a 30 hour 30-minute
meeting but how often they usually go 45
minutes an hour a lot of folks like to
hear themselves talk right so that
meeting carries on and you're forgetting
about what's critical to - you know
regarding the incident you know - doing
this so it's good you know depending on
the incident having that incident
commander whoever that's going to be
that coordinator that incident
coordinator that can talk everything
that's going on
if we've got third party vendors in it
right you know what I've worked some
incidents where we're working you know
with you know a global organization
there's probably dozens of us different
firms that are involved trying to help
this customer respond I can think of one
a cry net you those those type of events
last year that they kept us busy but
being able to have someone that's
driving that knows what's going on
that's important because like I said the
last thing you want to do Paul's start
pulling folks away from the keyboard
when it takes the brain want 15 minutes
to refocus so if you're doing you know
maybe maybe you're you know doing some
log analysis right or doing something
with pcaps
all right well every time my phone rings
you're just we're just we're delaying
these action items that need to get done
so I know I've really kind of hit home
on that point but that really that
that's so that's so important so
depending on the type of event you know
it you know I if it's been a
catastrophic event oftentimes you know
will you know we'll do like a morning
and then and then an evening but maybe
and only one of those will actually have
bring in our folks from all the
different teams
that afternoon briefing because then
again you don't want to inundate people
with with meetings because it oftentimes
it can be it can be counterproductive
can I have to during an incident you
have to pick your battles right you have
to say okay what's what is it party what
has to get done
what can I you know what can I you know
what can I go with here so tabletop
exercise love doing tabletops right you
know testing that I our plan how our
folks going to respond depending on who
you know if it's a technical tabletop
those are fun right you know we're
building out a scenario I can tell you
some of the ones some of the best ones
that I've been involved with you know
sometimes that business side you know as
well did one where we wanted to part of
it was to see if we can get domain admin
over the phone we created a custom
executable dropped it on 2530
workstations well part of it the the
client wanted to test their helpdesk
how can our helpdesk respond to the
incident so they give it influx of calls
right folks are calling in myself and
two other my colleagues other responders
our job was to be the social engineer
see if we could call in and get you know
we we work the only thing we were
probably with a name so what we do went
out to LinkedIn did a little research to
find out about this person called in to
the help desk
hey this is such-and-such I just slant
the airport I'm aware of the isn't it's
going on I can't access my machine right
now I need you to reset my password but
because I can't access it on my mobile
device because mDM's down right active
sinks down I need you to give me the
password on the phone okay yeah I mean
you know and then you know three four
three to get you know password reset
over the phone so tabletop exercises are
great but the important thing yet yes
there's free there's documents FEMA has
it's a little dated going back to 2012
FEMA has some good information and
templates out there my director at just
Sean Mason actually has kind of
conglomerated a lot and extra released
it as well we have it up here that zip
file that actually is on his there's a
blog post about it on his side so
templates and everything that are really
out there to start creating your own
tabletop exercise I wish I would have
bookmarked it mice on Twitter someone
recently posted about you know the
dungeons and
dungeon and Dragons themed tabletop you
know
you know rolling dice to see okay as
mice is available it's my security team
kind of letting the chips fall how they
were they are right because you could
plan out a very well scripted tabletop
exercise okay bring all these folks in
the room I'm doing one next week right
we're flying all these folks into one
location you know okay it's lunchtime
let's break for lunch we're not breaking
for lunch why we got to break for lunch
during an incident are you just as
everyone gonna stop what they're doing
and take lunch right business has to
kind of carry on as much as as much as
it can you know during the tabletop so
tabletops are fun I would really
encourage you you know maybe you're
you're the lone ranger you're the only
security person at your organization you
would be surprised how I open it during
at doing a a tabletop exercise can be
specified that for the business folks
I've had somewhere you know public
relations and legal we're like wow we
had no idea that the security team had
all this stuff they had to do and then
for the security was like wow I didn't
know that once we got to this point I
needed to make sure that I put a little
watermark on my documents instead
attorney-client privilege
so tabletop exercises are usually very
eye-opening for organizations so I would
encourage you to do that and do a
tabletop exercise a technical so like
for like a technical needs these are fun
and I love utilizing some of our cloud
technology to build out a actual hands
on a tabletop exercise you know and take
a technical audience that woman you're
gonna be focused on what the IR
lifecycle identification containment
eradication reporting now the chain of
command you know doing lessons learned
we still do lessons learn and
recommendations you know and we're in
the trenches every day it's so important
again you know going back to building
that muscle memory so I you know I don't
have to think about responding I know
exactly what I need to do I don't have
to think about it right it's just you
know that muscle memory is is so
important and building tribal knowledge
you know building tribal knowledge so
you know we bring a group of folks in to
do a tabletop exercise you know everyone
kind understands you know what
everyone's strengths our weaknesses
sharing that so we can all learn and
grow
from that but building that tribal
knowledge so we're not wasting spare
cycles spinning our wheels more like
alright we need to escalate this or or
reach out to someone else because that's
that's really important I always like to
say we have that magic hour right if you
can't figure it out with an hour it's
time to escalate someone else on the
team so we so we can figure it out
the more the merrier and the better it
is a typical agenda you know and that's
also important right I mean we're busy
you know our calendars are full it's
very important to stick to an agenda if
you're gonna facilitate an exercise
stick to it stick to that tabletop
exercise if you only I mean I have some
of the ones I've done have been short as
two hours because that's all we can get
folks together and the other ones we've
done over a day and a half or done
multiple scenarios maybe we've spent
that first session right hey let's use
the tabletop to also review our ir plan
that's a perfect time for it to be first
everyone's mind we've got this newly
created incident response plan let's
spend 30 minutes before we do the table
top to make sure we're acclimated with
it right because you want you've got
turnover you got people getting promoted
people over that are being moved around
right so it's it's important you know to
really capitalize on that time you can
bring folks together to do a to do a
tabletop exercise okay you know really
the the Incident Response you know
evolution right you know maybe if you've
been doing security for a long time
then what's your organization well maybe
you help that build their security
capabilities that currently exists today
right so how did that start out probably
started out over an incident right and
huh right to where oh crap this happened
we need to respond you know this is what
we need to do right that's how a lot of
organizations evolve over time is from
some type from some type of you know
incident you know following the
capability maturity model right starting
out ad hoc where we have that initial
you know it's very you know very ad hoc
its kind of chaotic driven right during
an incident right it's you just focused
on the now really no strategy to it
everyone's going this way right
one's kind of going every which way
right no formality or anything like that
to where it becomes repeatable right you
know you have a sin maybe you're doing
some Sam boxing you've build out some
repeatable process remember we talked
about playbooks earlier so hire a new
person you know that junior analyst
understands how they investigate respond
to various types of large doesn't
necessarily have to be an incident right
how do I do a windows-based collection
what are what do I need to pull about
Linux you know we're about Mac OS right
how do we respond on what type of data
you know do we need to do that becomes
repeatable right as we start moving to
define continuous monitoring Vino do
endpoint forensics tactical intelligence
right over here to manage and optimize
very few organizations get over here
right where you've got strategy and key
here you've got Hut teams all right you
got your red team your blue team
security team continuous monitoring
right folks are sharing you know
strategic in tell us but also we're all
Intel I mean it's great lessons learned
afterwards right some of the assessments
you know that I've done and been
involved with that's always great when
you start talking to different teams and
you find out that the the hunt team is
right their office is right off the sock
you know they're I mean literally
there's a window that's separating them
right you've got all their together
maybe in one part of the building right
there two building together every you
know they do lunch and large once a week
right they're just they're sharing war
stories they're talking that
collaboration piece is ongoing I'm so
like I said very few and that's what we
all strive to get right we can get over
here to that strategic level very you
know that's kind of think what we all
strive for but the bottom line is no
matter what your existing capabilities
are having some type of plan to do that
is what's most important right have
those conversations now in a stress-free
environment versus right in the middle
of an incident one of the worst times to
do it and that's one thing really that
we do well right
my group up here at the top or the
instant response services team we
collaborate with tallow
and then our ata folks which is our MDR
MSSP flyer I mean we've got again when I
were engaged with in emergency response
activities were we're working with our
Intel folks working with working with
Talos to really bring you know
unparalleled security service to to our
clients as well build a robust IR
capabilities so if you think about the
IR Revolution model that just kind of
showed you you know tactical
intelligence right the best form of
Intel is those raw IR reports right your
the threats that your organization are
facing are probably different from
others there's a lot of similarities but
sharing that raw Intel is very important
you know moving tornado detection
hunting prevention triage right and you
know and move it here getting back to
lessons learn and then you know starting
the process you know all over again so
very important but that's you know
that's kind of I guess in a diagram or
in a Visio kind of which what you kind
of want to shoot for and evolve with
over time so how do we measure incident
response
you know how fast did we find it how
fast did we respond to it and how fast
did we fix it I could tell you some of
the ones I've been involved with where
it's been a third party notification
safe from law enforcement you know that
often day zero hour zero panic mode
do-it-yourself sets in it's it's like
what oh crap you know we just got we
just got notified you know maybe it was
an IP address a start signature or
whatever it was to show you know
something happened so maybe that was six
months right Sarge well time how long
did the attacker have access to it and
here's what this is a we want to get
better to drive that down right dwell
time but time to contain our containment
time and business impact time we own
that as responders as organizations we
own that the actions we take once we
find out how quick can we were mediate
it right how fast do we respond to it
you know if we're stuck up here on dwell
time I've had some where dwell time
we'll just go though in good faith
effort
you know the organization will respond
to it what they think but then they're
you know they're they're wiping forensic
evidence they're destroying evidence
artifacts they have no log where all the
things that we we've been talking about
security for a while those things happen
but we really own that piece right
containment time and business impact
time all right
resources of course are our blog sides
it's out there belongs at cisco.com I
have a few blog posts are out there I
just pushed that one last week on me me
cats logging PowerShell logging and all
that twitter or cisco security tell the
security of course there's my twitter
handle you can reach RI our team instant
response at Cisco comm I will I'm
actually on that so if anything that
goes to that distro yeah we get and I
would I mean I guess I really the
takeaway here's debrief and and tell a
story we all have a story to tell every
day in our and our jobs and our roles
right if you're just if you're a student
just getting into security right be a
sponge soak up as much as you can but
but always you know tell a story
invest in Intel and Incident Response
you know you IR is going to evolve over
time and your and mature but definitely
simplify it for your organization any
questions yes sir familiar with what yes
yes
I would say I'm so like ICS that was
derived from DHS that yeah okay
I remember cuz when I was still in LA we
had I had to go is it nine hundred
series I don't remember that the
training I remember going yes absolutely
yeah I mean I look at my background look
at the background of folks I mean on the
team I mean some of the most important
skill set is that emergence that
incident management skills are so
important there's huge takeaways to that
in the in the information security field
right I mean because it's that we're
tying that date and we're tying that
information back the organization so
yeah I mean there's I there's many
similarities to that yeah yeah yeah no
yeah I see yeah I mean the bottom line
is you need to have some there's a lot
of frameworks out there but having that
framework whatever works best for the
organization is the most important cuz a
lot of them are you know steal an idea
here there and kind of mold it I mean
when you especially when you look at
like the 800 series in this
documentation so yeah good question
anyone else have a question I thought
it's on hand okay all right
if you've never died with the security
team if you've never done one usually
usually it's the security folks having
to drive that to do it and when I've
worked with some hospitals that have
just started building out a IR or you
know the security capability the risk
managers and emergency managers that
actually cuz the hospital if there's a
bad crash out here on you know 465 right
how that the local hospitals know how to
mass triage pace patients right if we
had 50 patients that came into our
emergency room how do we respond
hospitals test that often but yeah I
mean from what I've seen in my
experience yeah usually if they've never
done a tabletop before usually the the
security folks I mean we're that tip of
that sphere right driving it trying to
trying to make that happen but after you
do your first one like I said it's
usually now you've got buy-in from the
organization yes sir cool yeah no no
that's okay I did say I've got snore DS
I've got pins if anyone wants I got swag
webcam covers if anyone well I've got
plenty of things up here so happy to to
share that with folks so thank you thank
you
[Applause]
right