hey everyone how are you you guys still
wake yeah okay well I'm gonna put you to
sleep how many people like looking at
hex yeah that's right that was more
hands-on inspecting that's good okay so
my talk is really long and I can't say
at all because I buffer overflow or
something I don't know I I don't know
what I was thinking when I submitted
this talk because I thought I could go
from like beginning to end you know
in 60 minutes and we'll see what it
happens I'm paying two tracks let's see
there we go Who am I I'm paying tracks
I'm a lead security engineer at a big
company somewhere around here and I like
I like trying to figure out how things
work and I like breaking things you know
I didn't put that in the slide but I do
you like breaking things and we're gonna
learn how to break some stuff today I
mean this is not my profession at all I
do this for fun even though people have
told me that I probably should look for
work in this field what I do actually do
is I I do
malware reversing for a career this is
kind of similar so I wanted to talk
about like how to get started in this
field I think that a lot of people don't
get started because they think man
there's hacks involved it's hard or
there's assembly language right it's
really hard it's not really that hard I
think it's kind of like you know you
just have to get your feet wet and then
you realize you know what the water is
actually pretty warm you know I'll get
into it a little bit more there's a
lotta there's a lot of literature out
there and I I think that one of the
problems that I've seen with the
literature is it dives in real deep
right really fast and then it just
scares you off like my brain would hurt
after reading a couple of pages and I'd
have to walk away and then like a year
later I'd be like wait I remember
I wanted to learn about that so today I
hope that I can like give you that push
into the water and hopefully it's not
too deep and you know you guys can start
you know breaking some stuff too and be
like if you guys have questions
afterwards and you're interested in
you're reaching out to me with questions
and stuff
I'm always open open to like you know
sharing what I know and hey if you know
something more than me please let me
know because I am all about learning I
would love to you know share information
so when you get started what you need
it's really makes it a lot easier if you
have some type of virtualization
software VMware is great you really
probably want to have something that can
take snapshots right because it's a real
bummer when you have to go and like
start everything over again over and
over and over again if you can take a
snapshot and go back to the snapshot
quick it makes life a lot easier
you need a victim right today a
Microsoft apt is gonna be a victim
because just it's just so easy right now
because on Microsoft right Microsoft is
great but it's because this particular
piece of software is just like I think
it was raining just to be like you know
pwned
I don't know so and you needed to bugger
right and some other tools I'm going to
show you that there's some of the tools
that we're gonna use some really really
cool tools so I am NOT very good with
slides and we're not gonna be doing a
slideshow here I did pray to the demo
gods this morning and I'm hoping that
they heard my calls because this is an
entire demo for 60 minutes with some
slides thrown in so what do we have here
we have a Python script I hope everybody
can see it wait in the back if not
please move forward there's lots of
space down here and it I'm using Python
if you were a ruby person use a ruby you
know if you are a sea
sharp person some more power to you man
I use Python just because I don't know I
used to be a Perl guy and then one day I
woke up and realized that everybody's
saying that Python was easier it was
really right and I decided to change my
ways so I have a script this is how you
want to start out with a buffer overflow
what do we have we're gonna we're gonna
like create a hundred eight thousand
days sorry I was missing a zero just uh
a thousand days right
why is capitalized why I have no idea
that it seems to be the convention right
like I was telling the client the class
I was teaching yesterday I would have
chosen capital B's for those that were
not in my class why would I choose
capital B's for the thing I want to put
in there any one capital B's okay
capital B in hacks is 42 it's the
answers the life of it use it the
universe and everything right but I know
right yeah yeah that's true so I'm using
a it's just because it's convention you
can use whatever you want if capital B
is 42 what's capital a anybody 41 right
exactly so we're gonna we're going to
just create a file this particular piece
of software is a movie player right and
the movie player needs a playlist we're
creating a playlist obviously with a
bunch of A's in it right and that's
right okay so I'm gonna just go and run
that script I called it exploit
underscore AIP and it created a file
it's it's my playlist let's check it out
look at that all those moves are those
songs in that playlist right looks looks
good to me or movies I'm sorry it's a
movie player and I'm gonna go over so I
have two boxes right you need two boxes
or
two boxes if you can do run Python or
whatever script scripting language that
you use on a Windows box you can
probably get away with just using one
box if your victim is you know the same
platform is what you're developing your
code in right but I'm using Kali as one
box I'm using my Windows box obviously
from our victim I'm using a shared
folder between the two so that I can
just create the file on one side and
then you know execute the exploit on the
other so this is my exploit this is very
complicated right this is what I'm
talking about let's get our feet wet
let's dip our toe in right it's just a
bunch of Bay's well come to find out
with this piece of software let's fire
this piece of software up I'll pay later
okay I'm gonna open it up okay here's
the file okay and I'm gonna open it up
in a debugger immunity debugger okay
immunity debugger is a debugger based on
ollie debug lots of people know about
Holley do bug right because we use it
for malware reversing immunity to
debugger is an awesome debugger as well
it's based a lot like I said on all you
do bug the nice thing the reason why I'm
using it is because it supports Python
right and there is this great gentleman
Nate whose name is Peter and I cannot
say his last name but he goes by the
name cor LAN and Hiro Mona and Mona is a
great tool to help you figure out you
know how to write these exploits so I'm
going to go in attach my debugger to the
app the application and see what happens
right so I'm gonna start it up go and
the application crashed first what I
need to do is I need to go and accept
some exceptions that I have nothing to
do with the
overflow that I just did to this but you
will see right now that there's a couple
things that have happened right
do we see something that might be
noticeable on the screen at the moment
yes we see some forty-ones there's lots
of forty-ones
there's about a thousand of them
actually there's probably multiple
thousands of them right in memory right
now the other thing that I've done is
I've overwritten ie IP e IP is the
instruction pointer that tells the
application what it's supposed to do
next guess what there is no instruction
at memory address for one for one for
one for one yeah so what what just
happened I just crashed the crash that
just by sending your days all right
that's it I'm done hey how'd you guys
like my talk okay okay thanks thanks
okay let's let's let's develop this into
something more meaningful meaningful
right okay so we're gonna go and you
know what I'm just gonna fix my screen
here yeah I made it smaller yeah for
some reason it's not it's not really
you're doing what I wanted okay so I'm
so what I need to do now is I need to
figure out how far into my payload I
have to go before I over righty IP right
because I really want to control a IP
because if I can control a IP I can tell
it the application what to do right it
becomes mine
so what I'm gonna do is I'm gonna use a
tool that lots of you know how many to
red teamers are in here
raise your hand high be proud that's
right okay I'm now red teamer bye I
aspired to be one Metasploit is a great
tool and what we're going to do is we're
going to utilize a function of
Metasploit called
pattern create man my sorry about this
having it plugged into this this
projector is messing with my okay here
we go and if you go and use it what it
does is it creates a cyclical pattern
actually you know what before I do that
let's but say how big I want it because
that's going to be really bad okay yeah
sorry guys
there so you can see it oh you gotta be
kidding me Oh Kenya oh good okay I'm
glad you can see it I can't I can't see
anything
okay there we go I can see it now okay
I'm gonna do this again with 1,000
characters there we go okay so what it's
done is its created a cyclical pattern
right there's no repeating pattern in
this right I think there is probably
limit as to how big the sort of pattern
you can create but for our purposes here
we only need a pattern that's thousands
bytes long so what I'm gonna do is I'm
gonna throw that into my script real
quick okay
and I'm going to replace my thousand
days with my pattern
so
okay so here we are we've got our
pattern I'm gonna run it again this this
went better in my head okay okay so now
if you look at the the file right we've
just got this pattern okay so I'm gonna
go back over to my Windows machine and
now I'm gonna try to figure out how far
off or how big the office offset is
before I'm hitting yucky
opening it up okay I've attached I'm
gonna crash it again
and crashed it again right this has cost
the crash now look at it and see what's
an EIP we have a different we don't have
four ones anymore right because I didn't
send all A's to it capitalized but I do
want to know what the this represents
how big of an offset it is I can go back
and take this hacks that is in the IP
right now and ask Metasploit what the
offset is by using pattern off offset so
pattern offset is the partner to pattern
pattern create but I'm going to say even
save some time and I'm going to use Mona
right - to figure it out so within the
immunity to bugger I can just go down to
the bottom and say hey Mona
I want the pattern offset of three seven
six nine four one three six okay an
offset of 260 bytes that's all and then
I have control of yucky so I'm gonna go
back I'm gonna change my script again
I'm gonna get rid of this pattern and
what did I say two hundred sixty five
sixty bytes
all right so pre e IP equals 260 bytes
so this time I'm going to change this to
Priya a IP right but hey you know what I
also want to make sure that I am
overwriting the IP so I'm gonna put B's
for B's in because that will fill out B
IP right because I need four bytes for
this register and then I'm going to fill
the rest of it with what sees ya see
sounds good so I'm gonna say tail size
equals total -
the payload size right let's see the
length of the payload and then I'm gonna
say pretty much just this up here same
thing and I'm gonna put season here and
change this tail size so what we're
gonna have this file oh yeah what did I
do
yep that's right thank you did I miss
another one oh yeah nice thanks guys
okay this is the reason why and you
always have to pray to the demo gods
okay perfect
right so hopefully the bees will show up
in an EIP okay go back over and start it
up again so there's a lot of repetition
to this right you're going to be going
back and forth back and forth until you
get what you want
oh yeah set they're happy about
yeah there you go awesome it's very hard
with this screen the way it is okay okay
so now what have we done we verified
that indeed we have 42 s in VIP okay the
other thing that to know is I want to
look at the SAC down here where this
blue line is is the stack right and you
can see how I have A's above the bees
the bees at memory address 0 0 1 8 F 2 0
4 is apparently where a IP is being
pulled off with stack right more than
likely there's a red that occurred that
caused this to happen right there's a
saved EIP that's supposed to be at that
particular memory address the function
is finishing going back to the calling
function and instead of going back to
where it's supposed to I told it to go
to BBB B right hex address 42 answer to
life the universe and everything right
but then also on the stack you also see
C's going down further right I have
control of a lot of the stack right now
right so I can do a lot of stuff here so
the next thing I want to do is I want to
do something with this man what can I do
what can I do from here I can I can go
if if that that was a ret that told the
application to go someplace else
well don't I go and try to figure out
where I wanted to go hey let's see where
where we can tell it to go right ok so
Mona has this great tool called jump and
you can say Mona I want to know where
all the addresses in this memory spaces
that includes a jump in I'm very
interested in a jump ESP why a jump ESP
because ESP is highlighted in blue right
now right I have control of that memory
address right
I can I can tell it to go someplace as
long as I put that memory address in
that spot where that blue line is
because that's where ESP is pointing so
I'm gonna go and ask Mona for that I'd
say Mona jump - are because it's
register yes
ESP right well I've done this by the
miracles of television I've gone and
done that already
sometimes whenever you run application
commands and Mona they come back really
quick sometimes they come back really
slow so if you're doing a presentation
like this and you'd say Mona jump it'll
come back pretty quick and you know
people won't be staring at you for a
long time if you go and say Mona rap
right and that's where we're trying to
get to you might as well tell everybody
to go get some coffee come back in an
hour you know so yeah you you definitely
want to think about that whenever you're
doing this type of work so I did some of
this beforehand and what I want is I
want to know about the jumps so in my
files I have a jump text file that had
motor create and if you go down you'll
find that there's all of these jumps
here right
all of these jumps now the interesting
thing about the way Mona goes and looks
for things is it goes and says hey if
this library had or this delouse has any
type of exploit mitigation properties I
don't really want to look in them right
if a deal has a SLR turned on and the
the memory addresses are always changing
that's no good to me I need to have
addresses that are reliable
right now all the OSD loz in Windows 7
are all a SLR they're changing all the
time so I can't use those
very interesting this application has
multiple libraries that got shipped with
the application and they are all for the
most part safe for me to use because
there's no memory or exploit mitigation
properties compiled into them makes it
very easy to do this type of work with
this application
so there's actually this one file that
your library you see come up over and
over and over again its configuration
DOL there is no mitigation and on at all
no rebase no safe seh if you keep
looking across the screen no aslr so
we're gonna just take this jump ESB this
memory address and we're gonna throw it
into our script right here now what I
need to do is I need to pack it because
the x86 architecture is little onion
which means it flips all the bits
backwards so I can either go through the
painstaking task of flipping my back
bits and making a mistake while you guys
are watching or I can just use pack and
have it do it the work for me right okay
so now I should get my my application to
go and execute that jump now did I put
the jump in there I didn't inject any
type of code so far alright this is
really important as far as rap is
concerned what rhop is is the art of not
injecting code into the application but
it's still having and troll of the
application itself so what I've done is
I've found an instruction that already
exists something I can use all the time
and I'm going to tell it to go and
execute this code what I'm also going to
do let's just look go back and look at
the application again we have a series
of C's
right and I need to oh yeah I have a
series of C's and I need to figure out
how many see how much of a distance
there is between where that command is
where the memory addresses where I'm
controlling EIP and where ESP is
pointing at the moment right because
what I'm gonna do is I'm gonna want to
put some code in there to to execute now
I'm kind of stepping away from Rob for a
minute with this extra this this
demonstration just so that you can see
how that you know this one rap
instruction in a way this one gadget is
going to help me out okay so I'm gonna
what do I have I have one two three four
I have sixteen C's in between so I'm
gonna put that in my script so that we
know we can also put some instruction
that instructions in there so I just say
say D for the sake of argument because
I'm on a roll now and I'm gonna also
throw in to the payload I'm gonna throw
in hex see see anybody know what hex CC
does to a debugger it pauses it right
yep okay and I'm gonna just throw
forward those in write the one is good
enough right but I'm gonna throw it for
in because it will look pretty okay oh
yeah thank you
good job okay
okay let's check it out and see what
happens
start it up attach the debugger again
right and now we're gonna actually you
know what before I load it what I'm
gonna do is I'm going to halt the ex-ceo
actually you know I would hope the CCS I
was thinking ahead and didn't even think
about it okay so I'm gonna accept these
exceptions that have nothing to do with
my okay so what just happened do you
guys see what is on the in the
instruction panel we have CCS how did
that happen
I told us to go there right what
happened is something that should never
really happen in an application I just
told the application to jump in execute
code on my stack right what you're
seeing up here there was those CCS and
then the 43's
the int ie B X that's the stuff I'd put
on the stack right that's those aren't
instructions that's my my my playlist
right so now I have control I can do
whatever I want I can execute because I
can I got that in three they interrupt
three to execute so what am I gonna do
I'm gonna go back and I'm gonna add
shellcode to this particular sport
exploit because it's pretty easy right
where did I get this show code anybody
now yeah I have no I have no idea where
I got it yeah I have no idea so I don't
know what it's gonna do right okay
so I need to get rid of these C's first
right yeah
the reason is because I am trying to see
what's happening on in the I'm trying to
see what is happening in the memory
space while I'm doing this research
right because whenever whenever you are
affecting things in the application you
need to know how you're affecting it and
you don't know before it happens how the
memory set up you when you start out you
just know there's a there's a
vulnerability you know you see it on an
exploit DP you see an SES CBE right it
says there's a vulnerability and then
you do some more research and it says oh
yeah if you throw so-and-so into this
it's gonna crash it and then you're like
oh it crashes it yeah you know how can I
kick take control of it right I'm about
to take control of it right really
really well okay oh I'll get to that
yeah yeah yep yep yep yeah the
interrupts 3 is is telling the the
debugger to that is this a way of yeah
that is a breakpoint but I think it's
not the breakpoint that you were
thinking of but I will show you that in
a minute so a minute ago when I like
hesitated I said oh you know what I
don't even need this when I hesitated I
said oh wait I need to do something else
I was thinking oh I need to go and you
know sent my breakpoint all right
did anybody just see what happened I
popped my shell right that's easy that's
it all right
did I use rock so okay yeah you guys are
kind okay so I popped it right that was
easy
now my foots wet right you guys can do
that anybody can do it
if you got the right application to do
it five times make sure that you can get
comfortable doing it right it's really
easy okay so now let's let's like dive
in a little bit deeper right so if I go
back to my slides real quick so we found
an EIP
right I talked about pattern create so
there there's this interesting thing
called structured exception handling and
what it is is whenever you know a good
developer writes code they will write it
so that they know that there's going to
be this particular thing that happens
right in the code and they know that
sometimes it might not successfully do
whatever it's supposed to do right
so they create an exception for it cool
right so I'm gonna try something and if
that do something doesn't work out we're
gonna try to catch that exception and
then we're gonna do something else if
everything's fine with the first do
something then it just keeps on going it
totally ignores the you know the catch
but if something bad happens like you
know VIP gets shoved with for one for
one for one then we probably should do
something about that right well
interestingly enough with this
particular application when I did that
when I threw the four ones into EIP an
exception occurred let's check it out so
I'm gonna go back and you know I love
the color of the command shell I just
have to say that's it that's a beautiful
thing all right that's not supposed to
happen but hey whatever that's cool okay
so I'm gonna start it up again and I'll
pay later and I really have to try to
figure out how to get rid of that so I'm
gonna attach to it and I'm just gonna go
through this again right and actually
you know what let's create a different
totally different file
pop back over and this time I'm going to
have a different script and it's called
exploit underscore Sh right yeah does it
look familiar
yeah it looks a lot a lot familiar right
it's the same script that we started out
with this time they difference is
there's 700 bytes instead of a thousand
bytes why well in this case it really
doesn't matter right in some cases it
might really matter because what will
happen is sometimes you can do certain
things with you know certain size
payload but let's say you know you want
to throw an exception right and take
over the exception handler and for some
reason if the payload is too big the
exception never occurs because maybe
something else handled the fact that
your payload is too big so I'm just
going to pretend you know that I have to
have a payload of 700 instead of a
thousand to you know initiate the
vulnerability in this application and
what I'm gonna do is I'm going to create
this file right so we've got a file of a
is 700 of them go back this time what
we're gonna do is we're gonna pass the
exception pass the point of E is
open it up we crashed okay we're gonna
get to the point where the IP is over in
with four ones again right we just saw
this this has just happened but the
thing I didn't do before is I didn't
look at the exception handlers right I
over wrote the exception handlers for
this so this application is good right
in a way kind of it knows something bad
happened right
so in this case something bad happens so
the exception should be go do something
to fix it right but here's the bad thing
i over wrote that too with less letters
like really come on so now what do we do
we're gonna do this exact same thing as
we did before we're gonna do the pattern
create everybody and keeping up with me
that's excellent awesome I love it so
this time I'm just gonna say user share
Metasploit tools exploit pattern crate
right our friend pattern crate from
Metasploit i'm 700 and we're gonna throw
it into the script wow that's pretty
trippy here let's just do that again
because i have no idea what just
happened
okay
so now my file should have
oh this isn't just not going along I
apologize guys this is the reason why
you don't do live demos ok parent right
he apparently okay and that is okay I
did prepare for this I had an original
yeah right okay so this is the other
thing that's bad about this is the fact
that you know you try to do something
cool like this in under an hour and that
never does there we go okay so now we
should have our pattern I'm going to
throw that in in my payload
while I'm doing this do you guys have
any questions while I'm trying to
recover okay
okay here we go so here we we have a new
file right and it should have our
pattern in it now we can go and open
this up again and we're going to find
out what the offset is for for this
exception handler okay okay so here's
the point where we we were at before we
over Oei P with that a memory address
should be the same right because it's
the same point 260 characters into the
payload as we had before right now we're
gonna actually look at the exception
handlers and now the 40 ones are
different right
we've changed what's in the for the
exception handlers the nice thing about
the way the exception handler works on
Windows is that you can use a gadget
called pop pop ret to be able to take
control of that particular data
structure which is the exception handler
so what we're gonna do is we're gonna go
back to Mona and we're gonna say Mona I
want to know what the offset is of this
lower address so the way that the
exception handler is actually work is
there's two parts of each record the
first part is a pointer to the next
record so if you think about it think
about this whenever you have an
exception there's the the part where you
know if the exception occurs there's the
catch part and it goes off and you know
there's it's supposed to go do something
that is the exception handler itself and
there's a pointer on the stack that
points to that code to go and do that
right and then below that arab right
above that there's a pointer to the next
exception handler so if the way it
should work is it for some reason if
that handler fails what do we want to
do we want to go to the next panel geez
maybe the next Handler and have that you
know take care of what's going on and if
that fails let's go to the next thing
and the nice thing about Windows is the
fact that there's an exception handler
for the OS right and if you hit that
your application just crashed it just
disappears right so that is the reason
why you know applications crash a lot of
the time is because the exception
handler process you know try to deal
with whatever's going on and then it got
down to the bottom and you know
naturally occurring not what we're doing
here of course and you know the
operating system says oh you just hit my
exception handler I'm shutting you down
right you're going down now so we are
going to take advantage of this this you
know functionality and redirect
execution flow because of it so I'm
gonna go and take on the offset of this
lower address which is actually the
pointer to the next record in the chain
this this one up here the four one three
four seven five four one that is
actually the pointer to the exception
handler itself so what I need to do is I
need to remember the point the pointer
to the next record which is the lower
one right for something I'm going to do
in a minute but also this upper one is
interesting to me because that I can use
that to do kind of what I did before I
can go find a memory address that has a
pop-up right in it and redirect the flow
of the execution of this application so
I'm gonna go and ask Mona for the
pattern offset and I'm going say 3 3 7 5
4 1 3 2 and the offset is 608 bytes so
I'm gonna go back and this time I'm
gonna go and say 608 bytes into it right
free
seh equals 698 bytes right and what I
want is this to be pretty Sh and then
I'm going to write my age or my B's to
overwrite the the pointer to the next
record right and then I'm going to put
season 2 right overwrite the pointer to
the exception handler itself and then
I'm gonna just finish it out tail size
equals total minus the length of the
payload yes thank you so do you guys
under no why I'm saying doing this last
bit why why do I keep doing this here
the tail size that's right yes I want to
make sure that my payload stays the same
size so I'm going to exactly because if
I make the payload too small I not might
not overwrite something that should
trigger the vulnerability yeah sometimes
you can't yep
it depends on the application this is
all dependent on applications right
every application that you look at is
going to be completely different this
one you know I think that you could
probably write a couple thousand
thousands of bites into it and it
doesn't care okay
yeah it's called fuzzing trial-and-error
yeah good question
you know there's another application
that I gave to the class for an exercise
yesterday and you know I didn't tell
them how big of a buffer they needed
right how big of a payload they needed
and I said hey start with ten thousand
bytes and just keep on going until you
crash it right because the application
is just gonna say oh yeah that's cool
I'm gonna ignore you and then you're
gonna send it yeah more bytes and it's
gonna say yeah yeah I ignore you I'm
ignoring you again right and then you're
gonna get to this one point it's going
to like just right just crash out now
all the place okay so now let's see if
we overrode the exception handler here
okay here we are we over Oh the EIP you
with 41's and here we see that we indeed
have 42s in the pointer to the next
record and 43's in the the exception
pointer to the exception handler so we
now we we've won control again right
we're back in the same situation what
can I do here well the thing with the
exception handler on Windows is to take
it advantage of this we want to be able
to sort of pivot like we did before we
before we kind of pivoted from you know
running instructions normally from to
running instructions off the stack so
this what I'm gonna do now is I'm gonna
use a pop up Brett and that's going to
allow me to kind of pivot execution back
to the stack right and a gadget when
you're doing it dealing with rap is
normally some type of series of
instructions followed by a ret so a pop
pop ret is a gadget you know as far as
Roth is concerned so we're you know with
this we're definitely getting into rock
territory and it's a simple one but
we're still doing it
so let me just go and back and look for
a Rob all right pop hot rap so in moaña
I mean in the immunity debugger I could
go in and ask Mona Mona I want to know
where pop-up practices are and there is
a command called seh right because we're
dealing with seh at the moment makes it
pretty easy when you run it you will get
a file called SCH text and in there if
we go down we will find all of these
pop-up rights look at them all I mean
there's tons of them let's see how long
this thing is right seh you know
thousands of pop-up rights that we can
use so we can pretty much you know grab
want any one of them that we want
oh man I am way out of time Jared sorry
man
okay so this first one should I use it
no I can't use this first one why
because this application doesn't allow
me to use hex zero zero right in mic
payload if I try to use it it would it
would just mess me up so I'm gonna use
the next one I'm gonna use this one go
back was that somebody asked why yeah
okay why okay that's a great question
there are bad characters for some
applications some applications don't
like is your hex zero zero does anybody
know why an application wouldn't like
hex zero zero it's a no bite it's a
string terminator right right so with
this application guess what it does it
reads in the playlist is a string right
and it terminates so if my payload has a
null byte in it then it stops reading at
that point my playlist is that much
shorter right so I have to pick this
next instruction because there's no no
voice in it okay so what I'm gonna do is
I'm just gonna go in and do the same
thing as I did before and why am I using
struck pack does anybody remember that's
right this is a little endian so we need
to deal with it accordingly okay so the
other thing I'm going to do for times
sake is I'm also going so i over wrote
that i put the pack in the spot where
the pointer to the handler exception
exception handler is so that i can
execute my popup read the other thing
that i'm going to do if that is going to
that caused the behavior of a seh to
actually move ESP
I mean allow me to jump to the point
where the pointer to the next record is
which is the four bytes before that
where my bees were and what I'm gonna
put in here is I'm gonna put a jump six
bytes because what I'm gonna do is I'm
going to pop up Brett kind of pivot it
onto execution onto the stack execute my
jump six which will allow me to jump
over the gadget that I have here my pop
out Brett and then I'll execute my show
code so what I'm going to do here is I'm
going to put EB 0 6 which is in heck
machine code a jump 6 so remember that
there's going to be a test later and
then I'm going to also put two nulls and
the reason why I now know is I'm just
going to put two knobs in there and I'm
putting those knobs in there because I
just need to fill some space right
because there's 4 bytes that I have to
fill for that particular record and then
what I'm also going to do is that since
I know this is going to work I'm just
gonna go and grab my shellcode again all
right and I'm going to put it into my
script
okay and if I put it right here I'm
actually going to put some knots in here
as well just so it gives it a little bit
of nice landing not the reason you put
knops in is to make it so that you can
allow the cpu to kind of slide down the
stack right sometimes you don't know
exactly where the CPU is going to land
right now we know because I'm jumping
six bytes but if we don't know exactly
where we're in the land
putting an OP slide in there actually
gives us a bigger land landing to to
land in so I'm gonna put that in there
and then after that I'm just gonna put a
payload plus equals my shellcode right
okay and I'm gonna execute that and if
oh I must have done something wrong um
oh yeah yeah no maybe my shell code is
longer than let's say hex it looks fine
let's see what just happens and go from
there okay so we're gonna go back and
start it up again and see if it crashes
yep okay so do what just happened is we
got two shows for the price of one right
very cool and what's really nice about
this particular exploit is it cleans up
the application right I don't even have
to close it out I mean that's really
nice okay and I got to yeah and they're
persistent too this is actually
something that's particular to this one
application so what is Rob Rob is it is
where
you go and find a series of instructions
they have a return at the end and the
reason for doing that is so that you can
put like I did with the pop-up bread I
go find up the pop-up right get that
memory address and put it onto the stack
right and then what I do from there is I
continually add you know different
gadgets to create a program that I want
to do right the interesting thing about
wrapping is it has been proving proven
that is nearly Turing complete meaning
that you can pretty much do anything
that you want as long as your gadgets
you know are plentiful enough to do it
now the interesting thing about this
application is when you ask Mona to Rob
it goes and finds all the ROPS in the
space and when you're looking for
gadgets
I mean gadgets in the memory space of
the app application and when you are
looking for gadgets you're not looking
for gadgets in the normal way that you
think about it your what it does is it
goes and looks for the machine code for
Rhett and then works backwards to see if
there's the possibility of creating a
series of instructions that would help
out in wrapping the reason for doing
that is because the x86 architecture has
a multi variable length instructions
right it's kind of like taking a long
paragraph right and taking out all the
way whitespace mashing those words
together right you can still tell kind
of what the the paragraph said or the
sentence said originally right but if
you go and look at specific spots of the
paragraph without reading through it
you'll find other words in there right
in between the real words that were
there before can you visualize that
right the rock when you look for gadget
you're doing the exact same thing so
sometimes it's funny when you're in the
debugger you know you're picking a
memory address that's not really a you
know the right memory address for the
application code but it starts a gadget
with a return at the end right and the
double bugger goes crazy because then
you see a bunch of other like
instruction past that gadget that make
no sense like there would be no way
there'd be instructions like that but
it's just because that gadget actually
falls in between the real instructions
right so that's what wrapping is like I
said wrapping the gadgets are normally
find in returns but that's not always
true you can have gadgets that have any
instruction at the end that will get you
back to you know it executing the next
address I'm just like a rat so if you
had to jump ESP that would be at work as
well yes sir when you're wrapping you're
going to find a bunch of memory
addresses that do different things and
those memory addresses are in you know
either dll's more than likely right I
like configuration DLL right that's a
goldmine for this application and what
you do is you say you know what I need
to do a certain thing I'm gonna find the
memory address for a series of
instructions that do that for me and
I'll have an example in a minute
and then you just put those on the stack
so you're not putting instructions on
the stack it like the difference between
the pop up Brett in the jump 6 they had
the first one is a gadget that would be
a Rob alright part of a Rob the the jump
6 that was an instruction I put in
my payload I want with when I rob I want
to not put any instructions in and I
only put memory addresses on there okay
so the here's my here's my first exam or
my my only example I took my other
example out actually so what did we say
we said that no bites break this
application right so I can't use a
nobody
what if I have to push a something that
has a no bite on to the stack
for instance this 201 and I need to move
it into EB acts what do I do
all right that's Rob right so I found
that memory a memory address 6 404 C 2 6
8 more than likely being in
configuration that DLL a pop EAX and a
return is that a gadget yeah it is
because it's an instruction with a
return at the end right so what should I
do with that I'm going to take F F F F F
D F F and put put it right under it so
right in my payload right I have my age
my age my age my age and then I have
this value first value 6 404 C 2 6 8 and
then after that I have FF FF FF FF d FF
right and then I need to negate it why
because if I need to negate that value
it becomes my 201 did I have to put any
no bytes into my payload no I didn't did
I put any instructions on in my payload
yet
no I didn't right
yeah as long as there's if you find a
gadget that's an ad in your then you can
use it definitely yeah man definitely go
ahead Oh
actually whenever you ask Mona to rob
you can say Mona robbed and I want to
only use characters that are good for me
so I can tell it what bad characters are
and then it will only find gadgets or
make suggestions of gadgets that do not
have those characters great question
thank you I appreciate that and then the
last instruction right yeah memory
address six one six four one c70 there's
an exchange EAX EBX what does that do
for me that puts my 2:01 into the EBX
into the EBX
register right I've accomplished my goal
I have not put any code into my payload
I've only put memory addresses in there
right the neat thing about this is if I
know that there's multiple memory
addresses with each of these types of
instructions right I could make it so
that it changes my payload every single
time so why would I want to do something
like this well there's something called
Det
right DEP is kind of a pain right
because what does that do that makes it
so that you can't execute code off the
stack yeah that sucks
all right well Microsoft gave you a
solution for that it's called virtual
protect and a bunch of other OS
functions virtual protect allows you to
turn know execute off on certain pages
of memory well do we want to do with
that
I don't know maybe turn off the you know
make the stack no execute I mean make it
execute right executable we can use
virtual protect to do that why did I
have this example here that 201 well for
virtual will protect maybe Mike my shell
code is 201 bytes long so what I do is
it with virtual protect you needed a
couple of things whenever you call it
you have the return address is the
location as to where virtual protect is
going to return to that's going to be
where my shell code lives right and then
there's the LP address that is where I
want to change my address permissions to
execute right that's gonna be the same
spot the show code and then there's a
couple other things that we need to do
right we need to define execute read
write which is the 40 it's the same
thing as before and then there's this
weird thing at the end I don't really
know why that function needs it and then
to do it my originally if I have had
time I was going to show you how to use
push ID to put all of the information
for to execute virtual protect onto the
stack by using push ad that would be an
exercise for you guys at home is there
any questions as far as rap is concerned
and getting your feet like wet and
hopefully a little bit of what I've
shown you gets you to want to you know
try this out for for the pop hop Bret
allows you to pivot the execution from
the normal area of memory to the area on
the stack
only when you were trying to exploit
seh because what it does is it changes
it moves execution points execution to
that pointer to the next s eh record
which you have control over yep yeah no
that's cool yeah if you have questions
please come and ask me yep yep thank you
very much yes thanks a lot