eyes are having a great talk great
conference so I would like to start by
thanking my family for all the support I
have I wouldn't be here without them so
my talk is titled perfidious make be
back during great again for phidias is
the name of library I developed while I
was at Sai pretty interning at Sai
pretty and make P back doing great again
is basically a technique that I found
while working and researching there so
I'll be discussing that technique but I
would like you to make sure that you
keep an eye out for the bigger picture
which is the library itself alright so a
little bit about me my name is Charles
de Ventura Doshi I am a cyber security
graduate student at University of
Maryland I also work as a teaching
assistant there and I have previously
worked as I'm always research enter
honest I believe those are my twitter
handles and my github handle so I'll
start by giving some context about how
this project got started so when I first
started at cyber II the initial project
idea that my mentors presented me with
was developing a machine learning model
that could ingest large amounts of
baldra source code and basically create
a modular sample that could evade the
current endpoint detection techniques
now I had two questions regarding that
project first whether it was legal for
me to work on the project because I am
an international student in the United
States so I didn't want to get arrested
the second question was even if I was
able to develop all the parcels needed
for all the various languages in which
in which these malware source code is
being written in how would we find the
quantity of source code needed to train
a machine learning model and has it
figured well as fate would have it the
mentor that I had for the project
basically moved on to another company
and the project was left with me to do
it whatever I wanted to do with so I had
two options I could idle away my three
months at Highbury or I could basically
figure out a way to work a reasonable
amount of project that could be taken
forward so what I figured was we don't
have malware source code but what we do
have is a large amount of malicious PE
files right so I had to find a way in
which these PE files could be broken up
into in
that could be faded into a machine
learning model so in order to do that
the first step was to develop or find
basically a parsing library that could
split these PE files into small chunks
of blocks that could be used as inputs
to machine learning models and although
the PE file package that is available in
Python developed by aro is a really
great package it is not meant to do that
those kind of thing it is meant to parse
PE files and present that information as
is it is not really developed in a way
that all those various fields inside the
complex B file can be edited right so
what I decided was to develop perfidious
which is soon to be released a Python
package that can be used to pass edit
and assemble PE files from ground up
basically it creates such it creates an
environment in which PE files could be
split into individual Lego blocks and
they can be like used as and when you
require basically you could add and
switch sections and stuff like that
right so before we switch in to P back
during techniques it would be a good
idea to have a refresher on what a PE
file format looks like right so this is
an overview of what the PE file looks
like it has a dass header it has a door
stub which contains this program cannot
be run in DOS mode message or a complete
dos program it has or may not have a
rich header which was until 2017 and
undisclosed windows header it has the PE
signature it has the anti header which
is composed of the file header and the
optional header the optional header also
contains the data directory stable which
points to all the various data
directories and then it has the section
header which points to all the sections
that are actually contained in the PE
file right so this is what a das header
looks like it contains a lot of
different fields but the importance is
what important ones are highlighted in
yellow
ematic is the MZ signature that we see
at the beginning of a PE file this helps
the windows row know that ok this is a
PE file right the next is the CSUN field
which is the checksum so the checksum
basically gives you the check sum of the
file this there are several different
check sums present inside a PE file so
whenever you alter a PE file it's not
just sufficient to change one checksum
you need to change each and every
checksum accordingly so checksum
basically helps you to know whether a PE
file has been altered in some way or not
the e.l.f nu is basically the pointer to
the extended P head ER this basically
marks the starting of the optional
header so the next the next component
that we have is the da stub now the DA
stub can either contain the daus message
which can be a variable and string
terminated by a dollar sign or it can
have a complete daus program embedded
within it as if some of you have solved
Flair challenges you know there was a
challenge which contained a DOS program
and the message in the DOS header was
this program cannot not be run in DOS
mode so basically you had to run that
challenge and DOS mode so the next field
that we have is the rich header now rich
header is a really interesting header
because this was historically used by
windows to nail a couple of really
prominent malware authors because rich
header contains information about the
compiler version and the compiler IDs
that are used in order to compile that
particular software right so this can be
used in to create a sort of a signature
that a particular malware author can
have right so if you before this header
was discovered it was pretty much
impossible for anyone to know that this
existed right so this could be used as a
signature to deter detect them the next
is the PE signature which is PE followed
by two nulls this this basically marks
the starting of the NT header so NT
header itself is composed of file header
and the optional header and the optional
header points through the data directory
stable now file header is a really
important header because it provides you
the information about the entire PE file
it's the metadata about the PE file so
it specifies what type of machine this
file can be run on the number of
sections that are contained in this
particular PE file the time date stamp
which specifies when this particular PE
file
was compiled the pointer to the symbol
table number of symbols present in that
particular symbol table the size of the
optional header that for that is
followed by the file header for the
characteristics of the PE file which
specifies what kind of guard CF table or
what kind of basically security
provisions are enabled on this PE file
the next section that we have is
optional header it contains a lot of
fields but the most important ones are
the address of the entry point which
specifies at what address at what offset
inside the PE file the actual code
execution begins so this is where the
code execution begins in the text
section the image base specifies what
virtual address inside the memory would
this particular be if I'll be loaded
from the base of the code gives you the
basically base of the text section so
the offset to the text section weighs of
the data gives you the offset to the
data section the first data section so
once the optional optional header also
contains data directly stable like it
contains a list of data directories the
that data directories format is
basically virtual the r-va to the data
data directly followed by the size of
the data directory it's basically a four
byte by four byte list right so what
happens is this enables you to actually
find these data directories inside the
PE file now data directory is basically
contain metadata about various things so
export data directory contains data
about the export table so export table
contains all the exported functions that
have been exported by this PE file now P
files can be either a X's or dll's so if
it's a dll it contains a lot of
functions that are exported to other p5
right so export table contains all of
those functions then there's import
table importable contains all the
imports that are being done by this
particular PE file resource table
contains all the resources that are used
by this PE file that are icons all the
various windows that we have inside PE
files all that scans it contained inside
the resource data directory the
they're a bunch of different data
Droopys the security one contains the
certificate security certificate that
was used to sign this particular PE file
now this can be used to identify whether
a particular PE file was signed by a
particular company or not so this is
this is basically used by the Windows
loader when it tries to run any PE files
this is this this is what causes the
pop-up that you see this particular
software has not been signed by
Microsoft so this is what causes that
particular pop-up toaster come up the
copyright one contains all the copyright
information import a dress table
contains all the information about
various the various import addresses now
code injection code by P backdooring
basically means injecting malicious code
inside benign PE files to make it
perform malicious tasks
there are various code injection
techniques that are currently available
and currently being used the first one
and the easiest one is custom custom
section edition custom section edition
basically means you add a custom section
at the end of the PE file once all the
original sections are completed and then
change the address of the entry point
inside the optional header to point to
that particular section so instead of
the execution occurring inside the
normal text section the execution would
take place inside your custom section
now this while while it's really easy to
implement this technique it's really
easy to detect it as well because there
are like custom sections are really easy
to find people like endpoint detection
systems would could just search for the
section names and find out okay which
sections have inappropriate names or
which sections or whether they have
inappropriate permissions because a
section cannot just execute code because
code exists inside that section and the
fab and the address of the entry point
has been changed to that section we need
to also make sure that the section has
execute permissions as well right so
it's the ratio of the strength stealth
gained by this particular technique and
the time required for a correct
implementation of this technique is way
too way too low right so it's basically
very difficult to implement P code
caving so P code caving is a technique
we try to find out the code caves that
exists inside a P file now what our code
caves code caves are basically set of
nulls and unused values that are present
inside the PE file PE file while even
small PE files have large amount of data
that is contained in it and not all of
that particular space is being used
right so they have they might have sets
of nulls that are not being used by any
else by the windows loaded to do
anything specifically
so those nulls could be used to store
our malicious code but we cannot just
find these code caves and inject code
into it we need to make sure that the
code caves exist inside a section that
has execute permissions so that is a
task that is really difficult because it
varies from binary to binary right
because a binary binary one may have
code say like code caves and present
inside the text section that can fit our
malicious code violate two may not so
this technique is not really like it
does not work every time right
also the dis like I said the
disadvantages are finding code caves
inside the P files is really difficult
and finding a code cave that has execute
permissions is even more difficult that
can fit your malicious code so I had a
question why not just edit the text
section instead like just edit the text
section make it larger fit your code
inside it and make it run right so what
perfidious is trying to do is perfidious
tries to fingerprint the entire PE file
break it down into individual blocks
that can be increased or decreased in
size use the function to directly input
malicious code inside that text section
of a PE file it extracts the track a
text section combines the code that is
present inside the text section with the
malicious code using jumps and then uses
the noob like then assembles the PE file
from ground up right this is a technique
that is now advantages of the of this
approaches it's really difficult to
detect if done right because there is no
clear indication of a code injection
occurring right you are not adding a new
section you are not adding code caves
you are not you'll basically be Rica
creating all the checksums so there be
physical actually no way to detect
whether P injection has occurred or not
right the problem with this approach is
it's really difficult to implement
if you cannot really control all the
fields inside every single structure
inside a PE file this cannot really be
done because you need to make sure that
once DP once the malicious code is
injected within the text section you
need to recalculate all the different
calls that are being made to addresses
inside the benign text section because
the dot data section and each and every
section beneath the text exit section
will move move downwards because you
have basically you have added a it's
like it's like you are replacing a
smaller block with a bigger block right
so the calculations will vary you need
to make those calculations again apart
from changing all the data fields inside
the optional section in the file header
section and increasing the size of the
PE file as well right so this is really
difficult to do unless you have complete
control over your PE file that is what
perfidious aims to do
perfidious aims to make sure that you
have complete control over your PE file
you can edit each and every section and
structure that is present inside the PE
file right so how would you detect such
an injection that occurred inside your
PE file right if this P if if an
injected PE file using perfidious was
presented to you how would you try to
detect it if your system has only
allowed for white little white listed
software as in you have software that
you know I can run on your system and
you verify the checksum values of that
particular whitelisted software you can
detect injection because the checksums
will vary because the checksums will
have recalculated to accommodate the
changes in the PE file you can perform
graph hash analysis if any of you
attended the talk that was given
yesterday on graph analysis you know
that graph analysis basically tries to
create a hash value of the graph call
graph of the entire structure so what
this does is this basically takes the
dot text section into account when it's
creating the hash it's not blindly
creating the hash based on the values
that are present inside the PE file
right so this would easily catch the
changes that are made in the
dissection because the call graph would
vary because of the jumps that are
inserted inside the PE file right so
I'll give you the demo of the library
itself I tried to run the demo one of
the code injection occurring but I it
did not work so I'll give you the demo
of the library itself
so what I first show you what this thing
is doing this is basically an overview
of how perfidious will work so you can
just import a p object that is pointing
towards the dot exe file or dot dll file
that you have on your file directory
structure and then you can basically say
p okay i want to print the optional
header of inside the PE file right so i
want to extract the optional header it
basically went like the first time
perfidious runs like the first call to
the class PE what it does is it it
automatically passes the entire PE file
and makes all the necessary class
structures that are needed in order to
perform any operations that you want
after that you can just call the
particular object that is present inside
the PE file to print that so when I say
P object dot optional header what it
will do is it will print the optional
header that is present inside that
particular PE file so this is basically
the structure that it creates so as you
can see it gives you all the DLL
characteristics that are present inside
the P file it basically it's not just
giving you the hexadecimal values and
the byte values that are present inside
it it actually gives you the
corresponding meaning to that particular
structure it gives you all all these
subsystem types and each and every field
that is present inside optional had a
header along with all the various
checksums that you might need for doing
malware fingerprinting so this is just
one example of what perfidious can do my
aim with this project is it should be
able to edit each and every structure
that is present inside the P file and it
should be able to it can be used to
develop malware signatures that are not
simply based on bite values right they
are based on the actual values that are
present inside the PE file this are
basically rich header the optional
header the hashes that are used inside
that we file this gives you complete
control over your PE file so this can be
employed in side your endpoint detection
systems to develop better malware
detection rules that is what I am aiming
to do
so that that is basically your future of
the project thank you for your time and
if you have any questions warm round of
applause please for sure I'm sorry sorry
for speaking too loudly okay so we're
going to have question time now and as
we did yesterday we're going to have
prizes for the best questions okay oh
and you have swag awesome all right so
first I'm going to throw the throw it
open to the floor and then I'll go to
slider questions anyone from in the
audience would like to ask a question
please no all shy yes sir why do you
think that does Heather in the P Heather
is not removed by the Microsoft it's not
removed by Microsoft yeah it's not yet
it's not yet remove backward
compatibility that that's that's the
only answer they have for everything
that they do like but it's not just that
this is not being used anymore yeah
exactly
yeah it's for backward compatibility
they are trying to ensure that the PE
files basically run on each and every
possible system that exists from that is
one of the reasons why they did not
change the CMD the horridest CMD to
something better they had to develop
Windows terminal from ground up for that
particular reason because they couldn't
keep up with the backward compatibility
and couldn't make CMD better anymore yes
this gentleman here huh okay like
Windows Vista onwards you have
applications emit audio that could be
run in compatibility modes right I mean
it could as as back as Windows XP like
in window even in Windows 10 when you
enable an executable to run like that
does that in any way modify the headers
and if yes you know what section is
modified I'm just trying to see that if
that could be exploited in any way so my
understanding of that is basically the
headers will change depending on the
layer like the exe you so I'm trying to
understand your question
what modifies the header like what part
are you trying to ask modifies the
higher like if you so if an app that's
been made to natively run on let's say
Windows 10 or Windows 7 right and you
try to make a backward compatible okay
to run on say Windows 2000 okay sorry
let's go to 2000 Windows XP or or let's
say Windows 8 so as soon as you apply
that app compatibility shim okay as we
call it right so it makes registry
entries so I'm not aware what part of
header I mean what does it modify and
and does that actually I mean in any way
I mean yeah I've decided to understand
that that is that a technique that could
also be exploited that's a great
question
my understanding of this is basically
Windows loader
basically ignores the fields that are
newer into the PE file structure and
basically only uses the fields that it
needs where depending on the Microsoft
version that basically the Windows
version that it's running on it will
basically use the fields that are
relevant to that particular version it
will just ignore the fields the other
fields that are present so if you look
inside the PE structure like in depth
you will see resolved fields that are
present inside the structure
now these reserved fields are not being
used right now but they are made they
are being present they are present
inside the P structure to ensure that
the future versions where these fields
may be used and that will not break
compatibility with the current versions
so that is my understanding of how this
works
all right thanks there was one more
question on this side right behind you
with the gentleman with the green shirt
hi good morning um you were saying a
while ago that we will also be
rebuilding on calculating the addresses
of the the calls for example if you're
going to inject some code in the the p5
but what if it has a relocation section
the
would you be able to also recalculate
and rebuild the real log section yeah so
that is where the question is will this
be compatible for both 64-bit and 32-bit
Windows so about 32 and 64-bit it can
currently pass both parts both types of
files so it's compatible with both those
types of files 64 and 32-bit exe s and
dll's about the relocations
so the realidad data is stored inside
the data directories that is like I'm
working on how to parse those things but
I am pretty sure that once I am able to
pass data tech trees that are present
I'll be able to calculate all those
relocations as well so basically what I
am trying to do is I am trying to get as
close to Windows loader emulation as
possible that is what I'm trying to do
so it will have all the functionality
like all the parsing and the
implementation functionality that is
present inside of Windows loader it will
be able to do all those calculations
that are in those loader does but it can
do it as a Python library I hope that
answers your question
any more from the audience
if not then science will go to the
question on slide or will you take the
the most up voted ones so far from
Anthony how will this to behave when
most end point systems have behavioral
based detection systems in place such as
Windows Defender yes so it fails there
because what it is trying to do is
inside those behavioral based detection
systems they are trying to do dynamic
analysis it will be caught based on what
your shell code does right so if your
shell code does something outwardly
malicious like uses PowerShell or opens
connections outbound opens outbound
connections or something like that it
will be detected very easily right so
maybe we can answer one more question
and then you can vote you can choose
your favorite question and will also
give a prize to Anthony for the most
uploaded question so you can answer all
three I think we have okay we have a
couple minutes left here in the current
threat landscape more common modes of
attack
powershell are being more commonplace is
there a good reason to fall back on p
executable based injection payloads
again so if you see the current
scenarios
basically most end point detection
systems can easily catch powershell
based payloads right because they have
they have system in place to easily
detect whether a particular powershell
command is being around so powershell
based malware can run on systems that
don't have those endpoint detection
systems and have not disabled powershell
but otherwise they like it's it's not
the future according to me
okay so anthony are you here
no oh you asked for questions yesterday
you almost missed them uploading prize
yesterday three times Oh too bad okay so
she ends which one's your favorite
question the one that Jill didn't ask
about the windows okay you get a prize
yeah like I can give it to everyone who
asked questions so okay go ahead alright
so I'll let you I'll let you give them
the prizes later and then we'll have the
next speaker come up on stage to get
ready thank you another round of
applause please for shreya
[Applause]