surprise so you probably weren't
expecting this talk neither was i but
we're gonna do our best how much time do
I have by the way is this is this timer
accurate you have until 4:00 I don't
know what that means in terms of this
clock so 55 minutes all right
perhaps I'd suggest leave a little bit
time for Q&A right okay right on so I
had told Dylan that I would be happy to
come to this conference and I joked with
him that in case the speaker doesn't
show up I have one in my bag this is the
one in my bag okay
so if you haven't met me before either
coincidentally or online this is kind of
a word cloud of my most popular things I
tweet about so things I find very
important including tonight's karaoke I
hope there will be people who join me
but I am the founder and CEO of luta
security we do work with governments
large organizations in helping them
prepare for vulnerability disclosure
processes and sometimes bug bounties but
that's typically not our main focus we
really focus on getting people ready in
terms of how are they going to decide
which bugs are the most important how
are they going to eliminate as much
low-hanging fruit themselves as possible
and how are they going to if they do
choose to do a bounty avoid common
pitfalls perverse incentives and all
kinds of bad things that can happen to
you so how do we get here this is on the
on that side with all the military folks
that's probably my favorite picture of
myself at work it's how I explain to my
family what I do for a living I don't
know if you can see me in that one yeah
anyway the one on the right was me
testifying before US Congress last year
on the uber data breach does anybody
remember 57 million records were
downloaded and then they got paid an
extortion fee through their bug bounty
platform and I testified as an expert on
bug bounties on what they are what they
are not and on the marketplace that we
are creating by creating more and more
of these incentives so how did we get
here in general I've been hacking since
I was a teenager in the late 80s yep do
that math in your heads okay we're here
together now this is uh this is what I
call my midlife crisis hair so just
enjoy this when I started hacking in the
late 80s early 90s there were very few
new anti hacking laws we got to grow up
in a period where we could experiment
and not get into very much trouble the
same is not true today but what has
become true is that over the last twenty
years where I've been professionally in
the security industry we've created a
huge amount of marketing yeah we've
created a lot of marketing a lot of
solutions and a multibillion-dollar
security industry and yet why does this
stuff keep happening right we still
cannot seem to nail the basics a lot of
the worms that we see go out the patches
were already available so when it comes
to vulnerability disclosure
vulnerability management everybody has
the same vulnerability management
problem which is they have to apply the
patches for the bugs that are well-known
that are already out there that people
have exploits for and then there are a
few people a few organizations that
actually write code and have to create
those patches but everybody is in that
first boat of we have to apply the
patches for the technology that we've
deployed and if we don't do that in a
timely manner there we are
right so silver bullets are often sold
in the security industry is if you do X
then we'll protect you from breaches I
have not noticed any werewolves out in
the world that we live in that that
would be susceptible to these silver
bullets so what does it really break
down to when I think about how these
terms are used so interchangeably these
days terms like bug bounties
vulnerability disclosure and pen testing
I have to take a pause and take
everybody a step back and just get back
to the basic definition so one of the
things you might have noticed on my bio
slide is that I was the co-author and
co-editor of the ISO standards on
vulnerability disclosure and
vulnerability handling processes that's
ISO 29 147 ISO 3 0 1 1 1
and really all that is is the process of
receiving vulnerability reports doing
something with it such as creating
resolution and then putting something
out in terms of maybe a patch or an
advisory or both
sometimes it's taking in a vulnerability
report doing something with it maybe on
your actual cloud infrastructure and not
issuing any kind of alert because you
took care of it on your end it's all of
those things and that describes that
process bug bounties have become
synonymous with vulnerability disclosure
this makes no sense considering bug
bounties are simply the cash reward that
you may or may not offer to someone who
reports something to you
and they're also bug bounties are being
conflated with penetration tests you'll
actually hear people call them
crowdsource penetration testing now that
sounds like a harmless enough
equivocation of the two terms but what
are you really paying for when you get a
good pen test and I caveat that with
good because there's a lot of variety
and pen testing but ideally you're
seeking an organization who has vetted
technical security resources that are
under NDA not just with that
organization but then by signing a
contract with you are under NDA with you
what does that NDA do well it makes it
so that you can fix the bugs in a pen
test at your own timeline right and you
don't have to deal with the norms of
vulnerability disclosure which have
typical deadlines and you know
expectations from a finder that you will
fix things in a reasonable timeframe but
the other thing you can do with
penetration testing companies is that
they already vet each vulnerability
you're paying for only real bugs in a
pen test now what's strange is when the
marketing of bug bounties say pay only
for the real bugs
well they miss the fact that there's a
whole lot of noise associated with bug
bounty programs and so they seek to
manage it for you right the seams all
fine you manage it you know they can
deal with the signal-to-noise for you
and you get allegedly thousands if not
hundreds of thousands of eyeballs on
your code continuously scanning not
exactly the case but let's just pretend
for a minute that it's just that easy
and you know if you want to start a vole
disclosure program or maybe a small bug
program you just open up the front door
see what happens so most people are
expecting something like this
it's like mostly you know friendly
researchers some white hats a couple of
gray hats maybe but and it might be a
little bit of a flood but it's
manageable when in actuality it looks a
lot more like this and you kind of have
no idea exactly who is knocking on that
front door and often your incident
response team has to pay the price and
do the investigation right so how do you
distinguish friend from foe
when all probing activity looks about
the same especially when it comes to
data privacy now remember pentesting
they're under contract under NDA they
are acting as an arm of your
organization what that means is that
even if they uncover the entirety of
your databases and all of your customer
data it's not considered a data breach
why because they were under contract
authorized acting as an extension of
your organization bug bounties and vole
disclosure programs do not operate that
way now you might have heard the term
safe harbor kicked around for Volm
disclosure programs and bug bounty
programs and it's one of the worst
misnomers that I've heard applied in the
space in a few years the reason is that
no one can actually grant diplomatic
immunity to hackers funny not even the
Department of Defense in the United
States so when I worked on their
vulnerability disclosure policy there's
legal disclaimer there that says if you
follow these rules we won't take legal
action against you but it also goes on
to say that if a third party brings
legal action against you will kind of
stick up for you and say that you were
following these things but if you notice
it says that a third party could still
bring legal action
remember the uber data breach
fifty-seven million records they signed
an NDA they presumably deleted all the
data in exchange for their hundred
thousand dollars but what about all that
victims how is that data stored how is
it transmitted you know all kinds of
data breach laws could have still been
broken and those hackers are still
liable so using the term safe harbor I
would definitely stay away from that
because it's a misnomer for you and for
the researchers who might come forward
to you and let's see what about
automation how many of you heard of the
DARPA cyber grand challenge right where
it was all AI and the teams basically
created these AI systems to hunt for
bugs and to also dynamically patch bugs
well what's gonna happen if you can't
handle the bugs you already know about
from human sources when AI and other
enhanced vulnerability and exploitation
technology becomes more commonplace it's
like going to eat at a buffet when you
have no digestive system good luck with
that okay so this story we already know
the outcome of this story this person
was found not guilty by reason of
insanity but what happened was this
person who had participated in some CTFs
been a security researcher went a little
off his rocker and stole an armored
vehicle from a military base where he
was stationed and luckily nobody was
hurt he was tased on his way out let's
see what happened do we have sound
that's okay it sounds like a siren in
the US it's sounds different than here
so just imagine your local siren sounds
and also people swearing because there's
also swearing in the background this
chase started in daylight you can see
this thing doesn't move very fast you
can also see all of the incident
responders okay this is a part where it
had the people swearing in it so just
imagine your favorites where's what you
would swear if you saw this driving down
the street
very slowly going by right so people
were lucky one that that thing didn't
have any weapons it was an armored
personnel carrier it didn't it was
basically a tank without the guns this
went on for a couple of hours it ended
peacefully in the middle of downtown
Richmond in Virginia okay so they tased
him but this is what he said he said he
had authorization and he was just
running a test now clearly he had
problems and luckily he's gonna get the
help he needs because you know sometimes
the justice system works out and he was
found not guilty by reason of insanity
but how many hackers can be going forth
using the authorizations that you've put
in the scope of your Volm disclosure or
bounty programs causing major disruption
to your organization using up tons of
your incident response resources chasing
after what inevitably ended up being
harmless weird but harmless you know so
all right back to the bug bounding
platforms they're supposed to manage all
this for you right manage that flood
give you only validated bugs but there's
a fundamental assumption here the triage
labor is magical unending and we'll
always want to work for you not so so
when I worked at Microsoft for seven
years I feel like I should have like
seven like little windows tattoos on my
face you know for all the years hard
time I did on the inside but um
Microsoft even to this day receives over
a hundred fifty thousand to two hundred
thousand non-spam email messages a year
to secure at Microsoft pretty sure no
other vendor where government comes even
close to that number at the top of the
funnel so a human being does the initial
triage for each of these no spam filter
manually sorts the spam from the real
messages and then performs further
triage and when I joined Microsoft in
2007 popular science made a list of the
top ten worst jobs in science and they
said the Microsoft security grunt as in
the people who were on the other end of
secure at Microsoft had among the worst
jobs in science somewhere between
elephant vasectomized and whale feces
researchers like right there in the
middle
this was accurate and we made t-shirts
so the fact of the matter was you could
not keep triage personnel and these were
full-time six-figure paid Microsoft
security program managers you could not
keep them in their jobs for the
mandatory 12 months that it would take
for them to be allowed to apply for a
different job inside of Microsoft that's
how painful this job is so back to the
outsourcing who is
hang at your books it's not a bunch of
full-time engineers getting six-figure
salaries at these startups no no it's
mostly contractors mostly bug hunters oh
nothing nothing possibly could go wrong
with that all right so let's pretend
everything's going great and there is
such a thing as too much chocolate right
you could be getting the purest cleanest
feed of only validated bugs and yet
you're still overwhelmed why because you
didn't do the due diligence that this
type of program requires for you to not
hurt yourself I do an entire talk about
a vulnerability coordination maturity
model it's not just engineering that you
have to think about in terms of your
readiness to deal with vulnerabilities
communication analytics your
organizational priorities and yes
incentives but not all money some of the
best incentives that we ever created at
Microsoft were things that only
Microsoft could do so for example
certain bugs that came in before the bug
bounties were open we didn't want to
retroactively lipe them because boy that
would get expensive but we wanted to say
thank you to some prolific you know
security researchers so we'd reach out
to them and ask do you have an Xbox and
if they said no we would ask them do you
have a favorite graphic and what handle
would you like skinned on your personal
Xbox and they went crazy this cost us
$15 internally to do 1/5 write another
one a one-time cost to a graphic
designer
who is a vendor to Microsoft Xbox that
created one-time use like download code
so we only had to pay this this graphic
designer once to create a black hat a
blue hat a black t-shirt that said
hacker and you know a couple of other
clothing items that we would hand out
one-time download codes to researchers
who like did us a solid people went
insane and I believe they're still
handing these out you know so there's
one time 3,000 dollars spent certain
things that only you can do
no yes
oh that's the laser that's the right one
okay so not all bugs are created equal
this comes from a different presentation
based on some work that I had done with
MIT Sloan School in Harvard Kennedy
School in modeling the vulnerability
economy and exploit market if you think
that all bugs are the same level of
sophistication to find or to fix or have
the same value across all markets well
then I've got a cross-site scripting bug
to sell you for a hell of a lot of money
so a lot of the work that I do with
organizations is pointing out that there
is such a thing as low-hanging fruit
with known classes of vulnerabilities
with well understood cheap or free tools
that all you need to do is run them and
you will find these bugs yourself
whereas the majority of bug bounty
programs are still paying out for
cross-site scripting no that's really
the one okay so a lot of organizations
think they're just going to set up a bug
bounty program set up a volna Scotia
program ask for certain things ask for
certain types of bugs and really all
they get are bugs that are very very
uninteresting to them right it's not the
bugs you're looking for if we think
about it a lot of the breaches that have
made the headlines are due to basic
misconfigurations
basic security errors creating things
that have improper or no authentication
in front of them these are not
groundbreaking new classes of
vulnerabilities that you should be
spending tons of money to fix even if
you did hire pen testers as opposed to
using bug bounty crowdsourcing you still
can't start there as your first step to
true risk management right I can't
believe I've been professionally in this
industry for twenty years and I'm still
saying this but it's true
yeah and I call that bug bounty Botox if
you missed it so let's go through some
myths of this marketplace and some
motivations
we hear a lot that bug bounties are the
logical end goal of all vulnerability
disclosure programs that if you're
mature that you have you know you have
reached the pinnacle if you're doing a
bug bounty a lot of organizations are
using that as shorthand for maturity
when in fact they've missed all the
low-hanging fruit themselves and they're
looking real busy and paying out a lot
of money but actually it's for stuff
that I have literally taught Hollywood
screenwriters how to find in less than
an hour okay if that's if that's the
class of vulnerability you're paying for
definitely bug bounties are not the
logical conclusion and indicate maturity
there's a myth that hackers will only
look for bugs with in exchange for cash
not only is that provably not true
because Microsoft until 2013 when I
offered their first bug bounties did not
offer cash and was still getting over
150,000 or 200,000 non-spam email
messages a year for free but I have a
different story about that in a minute
and the third myth is that you have to
outbid the offense or the black market
it's not really a black market if it's
not illegal and how many of you think
the offense market is evil and immoral
well okay all right a little bit all
right well I was expecting everyone to
just you know kind of go along with like
offense that sounds bad but really what
the offense market describes our bugs
that are bought not for fixing but for
using for exploitation now that is not
inherently evil if you think about it
organizations like governments who use
it to target terrorists use it to target
child predators those are all uses that
we can all agree with they are legally
sanctioned by a judge etc I much prefer
that use of exploits with governments
than governments mandating that software
backdoors and crypto backdoors be you
know built into common applications so
anyway all right let's
oh that's the laser again all right so
one of the things in terms of this myth
that hackers will only do it for money
this was a great exchange that happened
on Twitter there was a hacker security
researcher who got a six-figure payday
$119,000 from one program when we broke
it down and I said look you know even
the Google project zero guys aren't
making $29,000 an hour and they're
finding very very unique bugs that you
know I browsed this list of bugs and
they're not exciting new classes of bugs
they were imminently discoverable yes
you would need some skill to discover
them so it's not skill lists that I'm
talking about but it was any pen tester
could find them if they're a decent pen
tester so then someone you know came in
and and and said oh well why would he
ever accept a position inside of an
organization when he could make you know
119 thousand dollars in four hours do
you did four hours of work to find those
and actually he replied back he himself
he said I was trying to join their team
it fell through the cracks through you
know paper work and an acquisition
happened but I've been wanting to join
their team forever
he left his full-time job to be a book
bounty hunter but he doesn't want to do
that even though it's super lucrative
and then this other person said well why
is that and what it came down to in
terms of motivation was he wanted
stability for his daughter so even
though he could Bank you know a bunch of
cash tons of cash in doing bug bounty
hunting the instability was something
that he didn't really want to live with
especially when it came to dealing with
his daughter and supporting his daughter
so completely different from what a lot
of organizations think when they think
bug bounty hunter we have seen so many
bug bounty hunters turned down bug
bounties because they wanted to see the
issue resolved and fixed that's another
huge motivation for security researchers
right when I was a professional pen
tester my specialty was robbing banks
you know this is like the early 2000s
and frankly you know bank security was
non-existent of a point online banking
and there were ways that I knew how to
mint money such that I wasn't stealing
from a person and I wasn't stealing from
the bank now I still drive a used car so
obviously money isn't the only thing
that motivates all of us who are capable
of finding bugs so this is another
excerpt from that system dynamics
research that I done with MIT Sloan
School Harvard Kennedy School there is
more to this ecosystem than money when I
look at the claims from bug bounty
companies that promise continuous
coverage let's just break it down by the
numbers so part of what we did in that
study was we did a labor market study of
the bug bounty hunters at the time and
we took data from Facebook and from
hacker 1 and we basically found that
most of the people registered on these
platforms or even reporting directly to
Facebook it was a lot of noise versus
signal so and in Kakkar one got upset
that those numbers were recirculating
and then published their own this is
from January doesn't look so good over
300,000 people registered only one in 10
has ever reported a bug on that platform
out of those a thousand have made $5,000
and that's lifetime it's not a lot right
so who's making all this money well a
hundred hackers have made over a hundred
thousand that's about pentester salary
it's in that range and only two of them
at the time I think it might be up to
three or four now but only two of them
had made a million in the entirety of
their time on the platform now one of
them who had made a million was a 19
year old argentinian hacker who had just
started doing bug bounties about three
years ago so in other words didn't play
fortnight did bug bounties that was what
he was doing and if you actually look at
his breakdown of the severity of his
cases in the number of his cases it took
him over 1,600 vulnerability valid
vulnerability reports with only a
hundred twenty eight of them rated as
critical is that a million dollars worth
of value from that bug hunter probably
not but the whole thing is that it's
based on this predicated idea that
there's an endless supply of
high-quality motivated eyeballs who are
going to look at your stuff all the time
and it's just not the case these hundred
individuals are pretty much bouncing
around between the major bug bounty
platforms so even getting their eyeballs
to look at your stuff is a challenge and
guess what the bug mounting companies do
they say raise the bug bounty how long
is this going to last
well the truth is bug bounties cannot
replace traditional penetration testing
nor do they indicate on their own that
your organization is mature all human
beings which includes hackers because
we're not machines yet have a mix matrix
of motivations and frankly finding bugs
is not a forever game not even for you
know those of us who want to stay active
doing hacking when we did the labor
market study we looked at some publicly
available data for critical level
vulnerability is submitted to Microsoft
because that was publicly verifiable as
well like with the bulletins and the
names and all that stuff it's about
seven years that people are
participating at peek game when it comes
to being able to find vulnerabilities
and reliably exploit them in the latest
versions of top software so this is
software that's had a ton of investment
in security so we're talking Google
Chrome we're talking talking Apple iOS
we're talking the latest version of
Windows and way back when Windows had a
phone that too right so right so it's a
seven year peak activity window for most
security researchers at that level and
then finally the last truth here is that
the defense market can only go so high
before it creates perverse incentives
what are perverse incentives and what
are some ways to avoid them so one of my
favorite cartoons is from 1995 and it
was Dilbert cartoon it'll come up a
little bit later but our friends at
Apple recently decided that a million
dollars was a good defensive amount for
a bounty
so they were saying you know hey we're
doing it because it's harder now to
break into our operating system and what
we're looking for is so very rare that
we want to be able to scare this out of
the woodwork and we want to be able to
quote-unquote compete with the black
market compete with the offense market
now offense market is nation-states and
organized crime what on earth makes
anyone think that a million dollars from
Apple won't just drive up offense market
prices right they were going up on their
own without the intervention of the
defense market so there's no competition
that's actually gonna happen it's just
going to drive up offense market prices
now why is this a problem
well offense market won't feel it and
they won't feel it in a very particular
way that the defense market will the
offense market was already outsourcing
finding these vulnerabilities at this
top level they do not have the mission
that the defense market has of trying to
prevent these bugs in the first place
how do you continue to supply your
internal engineering defensive labor
market if it's cool to just stay out and
not go work for Apple and make a million
dollars right the risk of collusion
dramatically increases at these prices
and if we think about it
I mean when I offered Microsoft's first
bug bounties in 2013 there were three of
them and one of them was $100,000 and at
the time it was the highest ongoing
vendor supplied bug bounty ongoing
meaning it wasn't a once a year contest
because we didn't want people to hold on
to the bugs and some people you know
when I started speaking out against this
million-dollar bounty we're saying well
but didn't you offer the highest bounty
said yes but it was matched to the
defensive prices at the time the pone to
own contest top price was $100,000 so we
weren't introducing a new price point to
the market what we were doing was we
were offering it 365 days a year and for
something that we wanted
so yeah Dilbert Dilbert figured this out
in 1995 right the potential for
collusion increases and if you look at
the United States healthcare system it
really takes one medical emergency to
increase your chances of needing a lot
of money really fast so let's talk about
the Microsoft bug bounties for a second
so what you're looking at here this is
the actual graph that was used to
convince the head of ie to pay for his
own bugs missus after Microsoft in 2008
had sworn they would never pay for
vulnerabilities because they were
receiving so many bugs already for free
but what we did was I looked at the data
the white line is actually how many bugs
we receive during the ie 10 public beta
period
not that many and then the white spike
was how many bug reports received
immediately after the beta period was
over kind of the worst time ever for
Microsoft to hear about a bug right and
these were all these friendly hackers
who were willing to turn these bugs over
for free why were they finding them
clearly during beta and holding on to
them what perverse incentive had we
created for them unwittingly well the
only thing we were offering them was
their chance for their name and 12-point
arial font in a bulletin if the bug only
affected the beta version and no other
versions we had created an incentive to
cause them to hold on to it until after
it was out of beta because that was the
only chance for them to get their name
in a bulletin oops so I told them I told
ie that we could move the spike to the
beginning of the beta period if we
offered small amount of compensation but
really it was recognition and so we
offered the ie11 beta bug bounty in the
first 30 days of ie11 guess what we got
18 serious vulnerabilities in that first
30 days so we were right we did the
traffic shaping exercise and we were
right anyone want to guess how many or
how much I spent for all of those 18
total
guess guess guess guess a hundred
thousand all right anyone else lower
higher how many think higher okay how
many think lower ten thousand okay so
somewhere in them in between yes it was
about $28,000 total and why was that
well one it was just a token of our
appreciation really we had this web page
where we'd feature them we had blog post
we had media that we were doing around
these folks who are helping us and in
reality a lot of the people who I knew
were capable of finding these bugs there
were very few individuals we already
knew who they were couple of a more on
parental leave I had to send onesies -
like seriously - babies to get them to
work on this thing because it was a
fixed time period and somebody had given
birth in their household so yeah there
was a lot that we did to round up the
right sets of eyes to prove this point
that we could do something with bounties
that nobody else had done and that was
take the eyeballs the friendly people we
already knew about understand the market
dynamics of who was buying our bugs for
how much and when and understand that
the incentives were very much around
behavioral economics absolutely not
about price
so this hundred thousand dollar check
that's not my real signature by the way
stop it cut it out
that hundred thousand dollar check was
written to James for Shaw who at the
time was working for contacts now he
works at project zero but that hundred
thousand dollars again this was for
something it wasn't just an exploit
nothing that was going to win at pone to
own could win this hundred thousand
dollars why because we were looking for
an exploitation technique now let's talk
about the offense market does the
offense market by bugs at six figures or
a million dollars a pop for beta
products probably not maybe for Apple
products because people line up you know
out the door and pre-order that stuff
but I have never seen a line for people
waiting to install IE it's not that's
not a thing so understanding your
products and understanding your user
behavior important
and understanding your market dynamics
the other thing the hundred thousand
dollars right so clearly the offense
market will by working exploits that can
defeat the latest mitigations but do
they need new exploitation techniques no
because the old exploitation techniques
work just fine right who needs the new
techniques it's the people building the
operating system because you need to
plan out several generations ahead to
fully incorporate the architectural
changes it takes to fix exploitation
techniques so not only were we offering
it year round don't make people wait
until poned own but we were offering it
for something that was not just an
exploit but so suitably rare is a brand
new exploitation technique ok hack the
Pentagon I want you to pay attention to
a few numbers ok so we were hoping that
a few hundred people would join you had
to pre-register you to give your actual
name your social security number I
remember a few friends freaking out on
Twitter being like I am NOT giving the
government my social security number and
I was like the government gave you that
number they also know your name and they
were like what they don't know I'm a
hacker I'm like you're tweeting about it
you know so that was cool I sent some
friends some tinfoil for the Hat but we
got an overwhelming response which led
to the worst signal-to-noise you can
imagine oh my god look at that it was
terrible over a thousand bug submissions
and 138 were real and not duplicate
right what is your duplicate rate tell
you your duplicate rate tells you how
many people could find that same
vulnerability how common and how
low-hanging fruit and discoverable is it
it's funny the bug bounty companies do
not track that number for you they
remove duplicates but they don't tell
you which of your bugs were super
discoverable low-hanging fruit because
that might actually get you to fix those
or prevent those or something hmm
anyway also don't start a bug bounty at
mid
do not don't do that this was us after
we had launched hack the army actually
I'll go back one so see this you can see
a little binary around there this was
one of those non-monetary gifts that
only you can give specially designed
challenge coin that went out to
everybody who successfully participated
in hack the Pentagon and submitted at
least a valid bug even if it didn't get
paid out because it wasn't the first
submission the binary round there said I
hacked the Pentagon this was the
Secretary of the army at the time when
we launched hack the army and he said
can our binary say I hacked the army
beat Navy it did and actually their
their football team did beat the Navy
for the first time in 50 years so I'm
pretty sure it was the hackers just
gonna say right there but look at the
numbers first the registration number a
lot smaller that was deliberate we
capped the registration in order to
handle what we knew was gonna be a
little bit of a signal-to-noise melee
right because the DoD wanted to start
with bug bounties as opposed to starting
with a Valdez closure program why
because bug bounties are sexy and money
is sexy and they wanted some headlines
this sounds familiar
million dollars anyway also starting it
at noon was much nicer right so how do
we deal with this as a whole I have been
one of the biggest proponents of good
bug bounty programs well thought out
carefully planned deliberately executed
bug bounty programs and yet I'm up here
telling you that they're not all that
what is the proposed solution well when
I testified before Congress about the
uber data breach one of the things I
pointed out is that frankly the top 10
computer science programs in
universities in the United States lacked
any kind of requirement for security so
even the university educated computer
scientists out of top universities in
the u.s. we're receiving zero security
education three of those top
universities had no security
electives whatsoever so we were not
we're not cranking out code writers were
cranking out bug writers it's pretty bad
also the fact that bug bounty hunting is
being celebrated by some of these
companies at outpacing the median
salaries in their countries especially
India where a lot of the bug bounty
hunters come from because there's a lot
of low-hanging fruit and a lot of like
easy money to be made India it's
something like 16 or 17 times 40 times
that in Argentina that's because of that
million dollar bug bug bounty hunter by
the way that's that data point that
drove that number up but talk about
perverse incentives where do we
outsource a whole lot of code writing to
a lot of the countries with a lot of
these bug bounty hunters so a tiny
fraction of talent majority generate
noise so what can you do
bug bounties for that works out well for
you finding bugs you missed after you
did your due diligence and there are a
lot of ways to discover or whether or
not you did your due diligence right
known classes of bugs the rate of
duplicates all kinds of stuff recruiting
for talent that maybe you wouldn't have
found and focusing eyes that you know
are capable of finding bugs and your
stuff on the areas that you need more
help with or focusing them at a time
that is mutually advantageous to you to
them and to your users like the
beginning of a beta period
what are they bad for your first time
ever receiving a bug that causes a lot
of bug indigestion let me tell you it's
really bad for employee morale if you
haven't thought through your recruiting
and pipeline capabilities when I was a
young twentysomething hacker working as
an independent penetration tester the
only thing that got me to join my
friends at at stake was because I
respected my NDA's and I didn't have
anyone to talk to you about the cool
bugs I was finding bouncing ideas off of
in terms of pen testing techniques
and really nobody to share knowledge
with where we would enhance each other's
knowledge so I took a huge personal pay
cut to join at stake back in 2003 when I
had been independent and happily humming
along since about 2000 as an independent
pen tester
why would young Katie have ever joined
Microsoft and ever joined any mega
corporation whatsoever if I had had
better economic opportunities and
freedom remaining an independent bug
bounty hunter forever so you'll never
know who or what you may miss if you
price your incentives for bug bounty is
way too high this is the problem that I
worry about with my friends at Apple I
hope they find some of those
million-dollar exploits but then what
what's the next generation going to look
like for them how will they attract new
players and invest in them and how will
they retain the people that they have
there will be career limitations for
folks inside of Apple I mean not
everybody is gonna end up taking Tim
Cook's job right you know especially not
from the technical engineering side of
the house so what happens to those folks
when they could just sit out the waiting
period and then come back in and start
making millions and then finally this is
not good but bounties are not good for
data privacy unless you've really
thought through how are you gonna scope
these issues how are you gonna handle
intentional or accidental breaches of
your terms if you are vulnerable to
heartbleed technically that requires a
small exfiltration of data in order to
determine your vulnerability if your
terms say thou shalt not exfiltrate data
that doesn't belong to you under any
circumstances then guess what you may
have some hackers who will never come
forward because they know that even
testing for heartbleed is a technical
violation of your terms or you'll have
people coming forward and then you have
a choice about what you do about it
so often I tell organizations they have
to prepare for when people deliberately
or accidentally breach their data
protection terms so what are you gonna
do go hack yourself seriously No
get out of here and go hack yourself
right now but really what you need to do
is understand where are you actually
missing personnel where are you missing
processes what tools could you be
running yourself to prevent phoner
abilities in the first place - if you
are one of those organizations that does
write code what kind of secure
development lifecycle stuff are you
actually doing what are you learning
from every single bug every bug is an
opportunity right
beware of perverse incentives and don't
just automatically assume that hackers
that we all do it just for money we
absolutely don't yeah bug Danny Botox
not a good look you actually have to be
pretty on the inside - turns out in
terms of your processes there's a ton of
cultures that have this idea of balance
between creation maintenance and
destruction and I think right now we are
over romanticizing destruction right
finding flaws constantly finding and not
having enough people personnel knowledge
passed down practices passed down that
helped us nail the basics I never
thought that there would still be were
mobile bugs in 2019 and yet here we are
so there's a lot of references I will
make the slides available so you don't
have to photograph that but I will leave
you with one thought in order to hack
our labor market our labor market has to
change the last 20 years in my
professional career I have looked at
rooms that look a lot like this one
right and how are we gonna change it
well we need to borrow from other
disciplines this is a nurse who became
interested in cybersecurity when her
patients could be killed by remote
attacks and embedded medical devices
she's now one of the best advocates for
cybersecurity and building secure
medical devices making them updatable
helping Institute vulnerability
disclosure programs in those medical
devices borrowed from another discipline
this person
we had just won a CTF and when she was
pregnant with this little person she was
in a homeless shelter so when we look
across our socioeconomic backgrounds and
what we normally see in rooms like this
we need to take a broader approach
because we are not going to keep getting
by with mostly male mostly white bug
hunters around the world that is not
actually going to solve our labor market
crisis this is one of the most obvious
areas for us to expand now I will say
one thing about this I've given you a
ton of information in this talk I would
love for you guys to ask me questions
about the stuff in this talk not about
diversity inclusion even though I'm
ending with it because guess what I
don't do diversity inclusion for a
living hire professionals who do and the
last thing I will say is that we're
running a bug bounty buffet coming up in
October
so hack in the box is doing a what's
called driven to pone competition and it
is a lot like pone to own in that there
are a selection of targets but what's
different about it is that vendors are
invited and they can follow their own
vendor disclosure rules
hackers can choose there's the driven to
pone set of rules which are the 90 plus
90 plus 90 rules which is basically you
give the vendor 90 days to fix it you do
a courtesy pause of 90 days for everyone
to deploy the patch and then you do a
courtesy pause and then you release
everything open-source why because we're
trying to train up the next generation
of people who can find and exploit these
vulnerabilities ideally so that they
come to work for organizations to
prevent them so with that I will take
any questions thank you wow thank you so
much doesn't she deserve an awesome big
round of applause
I think we're so lucky this is really a
great a bonus surprise and and they were
lucky to be able to hear you today speak
on
bounty programs Katie so thank you so
much really appreciate you stepping in
at the eleventh hour and for your
informative talk so now we have about
five minutes left for questions before
we go for coffee break we have two
prizes to give away ones for the most up
loaded question and one is for your
favorite question so first I'll throw it
open to the floor and then I'll go to
Toledo
so anyone any questions from the floor
for Katie yes sir at the back with the
red shirt hi do you prefer to open
bounty program to the public or to
private if it's public what's the issue
that could be faced when open to public
I believe that bug bounties should only
be embarked upon with mature
organizations who are already used to
receiving vulnerability reports
I believe that private bug bounties are
mostly used as a tool to get people on
to bug bounty platforms right and it
mimics this sense of safety that you
have with a traditional pen test but you
typically will not get a lot of
attention from the researchers
especially if you're offering sort of
lower amounts of money in the private
program then a lot of public programs
will offer right and it's lower amounts
of money for low-hanging fruit and it's
a lot of duplicates and everything like
that so they know that they'll probably
put in the work but not get paid so the
answer to your first question is you
know private versus public in terms of
bug bounty I believe public is better
because I believe that organizations
should be mature enough to handle
regular vulnerability reports and what
was your second question can you ask an
sorry
was the issue or challenge that could be
faced if open to publics
ah okay issues and challenges open to
the public well volume right dealing
with your major bottleneck labor force
which is not bug hunters but triage
finding trusted triage partners if you
don't have triage personnel yourself
that you're willing to constantly train
and maintain is going to be a challenge
but yeah it's usually signal-to-noise
now if you've done your due diligence
you cut down on that signal-to-noise
problem quite a bit because there aren't
a lot of duplicates there isn't a lot of
spam okay next question okay great so
we'll come to the questions on slide oh
we have two questions which have equal
number of votes the highest number of
votes so that they're right behind you
oh they're three now oh goodness
okay all of them with six votes all of
them anonymous so you're not going to
get your prize why don't you pick one
Katie okay Oh shall I read it out to you
I'm gonna stage I'm not I'm not very
coordinated okay so let me just see um
maybe we can take two if you keep no not
really because I didn't have a bathroom
break before it okay so that's done now
we're doing okay I tell you what make
the second one because it's got seven
votes okay okay all right is it now the
top one be nice it's and back doors both
are inherently bad in the wrong hands
why would the government having a
private exploit be better than them
implementing backdoors and common
software implementing backdoors hurts
everyone for a very very long time
having one exploit that may or may not
get killed in the next version of
software is a much smaller problem and
it doesn't inherently make that software
insecure for everyone what's that answer
that question I hope it did no crypto
backdoors anyway
okay one more quick question and then
everything will have to happen after the
coffee / bathroom break yes sir this
gentleman here I'm then right here and
then Katy you get to pick which gets the
price oh okay all right
hi yeah so my question is how is the
buck bunty balanced on the other end of
the rope with regards to racing the
development teams competence like a lot
of companies spend a lot with regards to
back bug bounty programs but what are
they doing on the other end like
internally with their dev teams that is
a great question and that actually is
dependent vendor to vendor so not all
vendors take those bugs as the learning
opportunity that they really are the
most the lot of the advice that I give
to vendors is when they say I'll look at
this bug it came into our bug bounty
program thank goodness we paid that
person a thousand dollars and I said but
it's you know missing authentication
what why did you need to pay a stranger
to tell you that right so anyway with
that I'm gonna call it done yes unless
somebody wants to like film a very
unfortunate accident on stage no no
we're done I think we're done it's okay
I'm supposed to pick something yes so
out of the two gentlemen who picked who
asked you questions which one deserves
the price or both of who they boast is
reprisal okay well then why how you both
get pride Thank You sama thank you a big
round of applause for Katie
[Applause]