hi everyone and sell for coming to hotel
when you shall fear your mundane office
equipment where we're going to presenter
or enterprise printer research and since
also to hugging the wall for doing that
is great opportunity yeah first of all
is a brief introduction about who you
are this is Mario Rivas and I'm Daniel
Romero both water security consultants
and resented at and Citigroup in the
Madrid office here you are four examples
of interest or do telecoms emails etc
but you want to know what better we
always have for a beer so just let us
know one who can take a beer
well this is an agenda of our talk these
are really classical agenda where we'll
start with a brief introduction and the
textual phase that we have we have
covered when during all research the
mario will presented testimony and some
facts that we have developed during the
we already set and a way across the
different modalities that we have found
at this after that we will show you some
exploit and the difficulty that we came
across
okay finally is a brief conclusions okay
let's go with the introduction okay the
main goal of the research was testing
isn't enterprise devices okay I'm
figuring out the current state of
security of them so we thought that
printers will be a good target so we
select six medium sized enterprise
printers and we decided to focus this
result on our red teaming approach so we
the outcomes of the ERISA could be used
during already mean engagement for
example so with Ebola with your research
exploitation and process predation okay
keep in mind that is not an assessment
so we don't need to find all the world
is a printer half so we know if we only
need to find one more data providers
remote code execution
okay but why printers these are really
good questions printers has been well
extended in company says many years ago
and usually they are connected to the
two different networks two different
villains and for example you can use the
amine aura to it to pivoting so
different Department attacks different
Department obviously the information
which is managed by a printer are really
sensitive we have for example corporate
personal financials
later etc but don't forget information
included within the configuration for
example we can find the mine account
password credential setter so really
sensitive information usually mm
printers are also consider a lottery
static so probably they are not
configure it securely or properly by the
IDT department so then we have and
control devices magic really since his
information and connected to the most of
the printers company networks or
companies in Elko sorry so this is an
example of some weeks ago were Microsoft
catcher right sinister hackers using
printers in order to attack different
companies okay why not
some vendors decided to make a statement
like this one so it seems like a
challenge for us let's go with the
texture face
well first comment that we identify two
different operating systems within our
printers the first one is our real-time
operation system and the next one is a
line okay obviously they have many
attack surfaces like web applications
and web servers mobile application file
parsers update some frameworks bring the
languages external services like for
example Google Cloud Print or apron
management services another like 10 and
SFP exampie etc
approximate attacks like Wi-Fi use we
NFC etcetera okay and we also decided to
include two other tasks for this
architecture face like hardware analysis
post exploitation okay but obviously we
didn't have enough time to cover all
these attacks or face because it's
really huge finally we decide to cover
the following words okay those bite
eating rays because we didn't include
this test in all the printers this is
another picture about the texture phase
more data like picture where you can see
the different elements that we include
within each part of the attack surface
where for example within the printer
language in five format we decide to
include the PDL
the PCL and PS languages okay let's go
with the technology I'm passing
okay so this is the main mythology that
we follow during the research we started
with the state of the art on setting up
our printers then we chose some scope of
the attack surface that we just saw and
then in a second process we started
searching for vulnerabilities passing
different protocols and findings on
crashes then analyzing them and then
trying to supply them in order to
compromise the device or gain additional
knowledge all these while also analyzing
the film were in the cases we have it
and also analyzing the hardware to get
some useful information as we will see
later talking about passing we started
with dumb professors which are really
quick to launch and we continued with
the smarter ones which were one more
time but give better results actually
botanists give out great results but
also we felt that it was harder and more
time-consuming that it should be so we
decided to make another faster while
looking at the state of the art we found
two amazing tools very well known Sally
and Buffa's but with great
functionalities and a lot of the things
that we needed but we were changing a
lot of the code so we decided to for
Buffa's and we ended up creating a
different monster and after Sally Ambu
mike wazowski will be the next one so we
call this fascist key we wrote it in
Python 3 and we improved some modules
like the string passing libraries and we
made faster modules to keep all our
protocol fasteners and there a single
program with a similar behavior between
the rest of the changes we wanted to
solve the different difficulties that we
were having while passing the first one
will be that different implementations
of the same protocol behave different
when otherwise crashes sometimes it can
go totally down or maybe a service
stopped answering or maybe just print
and stuck in a stack trace in some debug
interface so for that we wanted to give
flexibility and we made the main program
with a lot of arguments to control the
passing session and we made monitor
modules to constantly check that
then who and otherwise crushes sometimes
we were we needed to reboot in Manali so
for that we made restarting modules
which to do for example to turn off and
on and a smartlock and then to give
instability to the tour tour faster we
made a nice console where we can pause
and control the fuzzing session and do
some things like retest any test case or
do some other things like print in human
readable format and the test cases that
we are sending and save standalone
scripts that we can send later to the
manufacturers maybe or just use it while
developing developing and Sprite so
let's see a very quick demo its haven't
cut I think ok perfect
I will detect away so we have below a
pink short-circuit and you can see there
a lot of the options that we have we
have also or faster modules that we that
we have developed the restarted modules
and the monitored modules and other
options and we are now going to launch
or faster to our target the printer one
in the six three one part using the
internet printing protocol faster IPP
and they get printer attributes part of
that protocol and you're going to use a
restart a module that turns off unknown
and a smart plug that we have connected
to a printer we have here the console or
cool logo and some of the commands that
we have implemented we are now going to
test the connection to a target sending
a non fast packet and after receiving
the some information from that request
we can go to a different test case and
continue the execution from from there
for variety so now we are continuing and
you can see some of the of the test
cases like in a very similar way to move
us and after sending a pair of them you
will see below that
we will stop receiving ICMP s there it
is and now we have detected that in the
faster and we are going to restart the
target using the the smart black model
and after that we will wait for the
target to recover and it will continue
the execution automatically getting more
crashes and saving some suspects but we
don't want to that we can control C and
go to the console check the suspect we
have defi following one in this case and
we can print it in a human readable
format where you can see in the longest
line that we are sending 10,000 seats in
this case instead of default value in
that was a mutant on the packet we can
also print this like with a
proof-of-concept code but we can copy
and paste into a script and send it to a
manufacturer as a proof of concept or
yes you see you see later while
developing exploit now we are going to
wait for it to recover and we are going
to retest if this test case was crashing
the device or it was class by any other
thing that we didn't know so for that we
can use the foot on the first command
with the 5 on and one test case in this
case and as you will see we stopped
receiving ICMP second we have a crash
sebat in this case was a key buffer flow
and we can save this this proof of
concept into a file for later use and we
can also disable the element as we may
not want to continue testing this
because it's already one hour and we
already know it so why do I same time in
that so that was the this demo ok
all the code is already by level in our
external github and check it out and
before we because there are a lot of
changes coming soon
and let's go for just a bit of hardware
we took a very basic approach mainly
searching for things that will allow us
with the exploitation of the printer
for example the bank interfaces like
UART or take tack or some other things
that may allow us to down the field
where or get some useful information and
while doing that we will all see also
having too much fun and we did some
things that we shouldn't and now one of
the printers is not going to print
anymore
let's just say kill a printer save a
tree so one of the first thing we did
was looking for expose memories like in
this example we passed period 2 to the
SPI protocol download the film were from
one of the devices and we also found
some serial ports in three of the six
printers tested and we also found some
dated ports that seemed to be disabled
the serial ports were extremely useful
as they gave us a lot of information
like the back errors and stack traces
and we're really useful to exploit one
of some of the vulnerabilities that we
found also one of them was basically
interesting as it gave us an interactive
shell that we could use to to greet
write and execute things in the memory
of a right so we use this for a harbor
backdoor which could be impacted by
someone with physical access to a
printer in two or three minutes and for
this we use our Raspberry Pi that you
can see in the picture which was
connected to the serial port and was
also powered by it so whenever the
printer is on the Raspberry Pi will be
on and the Raspberry Pi will be
connected to a with VX and Wi-Fi access
point and from the we cool have had all
these capabilities so let's see second
demo very quick also
your own you know on or PC where the
Raspberry Pi is connected and we can
associate to it and from here we have a
direct access to or to our serial port
of the printer so we can just go into
the console we are now in the console
and we can for example bring the shell
where there are a lot of comments to
read write and execute things and we can
do something for example to dump some
memory as you can see somebody this is
not a very nice format so we are now
going to show do this with a little
script that we did to them some of the
secrets we can use the screen with
specifying the serial port and the port
right and after launching it you can see
some of the secrets like for Sutton's
for example the administrator password
which was Lala in this case then an old
byte and then something that is the part
of the previous password was that was
not all written while setting a shorter
one and of course all the secrets in the
printer are in clear tests because we
are like in the year 2000 yet or
something
so that was a quick demo we execute
things here but we have an exploit where
we will show you that with the remote
code execution okay so after this quick
hardware we are going to see some of the
como flaws found just a quick overview
we have a lot of well you can see the
red means higher critical risk yellow
means medium response and the scale
means that we use some vulnerabilities
to execute code in the device so
stopping with the applications we found
really with the four configurations
exposing almost all services available
also supposing well actually more than
20 in some cases also supposing the
monitoring panel with the folder without
credentials and basically reminding
the security controls of 20 years ago
and we found all the typical application
issues like cross-site request forgery
lack of access controls in different
functionalities for example to delay the
full backup of the configuration of
device and some cross-site scripting
issues like 1 2 3 & 4 and also path
reversal in one of the line of sprinters
that unfortunately allowed us only to
obtain some specific intentions and we
were not able to further exploit this to
get closer to our objective which was to
that full control device so all these
issues are not bad but we were looking
for something that may allow us to get
full control device so looking at
different words we found a slightly few
more interesting functionalities like
this one where you can see we got a lot
of information including appreciation
and security locks including session
cookies Active Directory loves her virus
locks more information like the full
list of processes
or other information about the
underlying operating system in this
second one was very similar to the first
one with different functionalities under
different URLs and this was using one of
the supplies that we will explain in a
few minutes and this third one was even
better because it just allowed us to
lower the full memory of the device why
not and get all the secrets and anything
that was in the memory at that time like
passwords documents whatever so all of
this was accessible without any kind of
authentication because his hidden
features and going to the memory
corruption issues we found a lot too
many more than we could handle or
investigate so in a lot of the services
that that the printers are like not only
our application but also in printer
services like
IPP or LPD or the Google problem the
implantation SNMP
basically we stopped searching these
kind of vulnerabilities because we had a
lot massively at vulnerabilities
everywhere which lead up to crashes
everywhere and some very useful stack
traces this one in one of the serial
ports where we are written the PC and
this is from another exploit that we
won't see today but don't worry now then
is going to explain you two other ones
okay let's go with a couple of examples
developers during all research this is
the first one this is a easy case and
this was these macros for my one or web
application process as you can see
within the image as send the HTTP
request a custody request with a really
long cookie value the printer will
cursor provides is a basic astatically
stack buffer overflow okay
look into the framework we identify the
developers for example for go to include
boundary checks in the code so probably
the stack is a string copy which is
copying the cookie value into a stack
awry Kulik buffer overflow okay an
important important point here is the
comfortable the comfortable is the the
cookie size including the cookie name
the equal symbol and the cookie value
okay and it is used for example within
the string copy size argument were faced
in my graduated from this there in this
column by level okay and question here
will be do you really think that there
is only one back here or obviously no
imagine that we replace the equal symbol
by a semicolon symbol okay the count
variable GU result importing bytes
14-15 is a negative number so we are
copying a really huge space in memory
into a stack awry so we have two
varieties in the same line these are
super have conflict the Ferger just send
in a really long cookie value and the
second one just replace in the equal
symbol by the semicolon okay and think
reverse petition blue
like we are going back to the 90s
printer so which is really scarce let's
go wait to check the difficulties qui in
defiance Allah within this heap and the
stack we were within 1/2 so 1/2 at the
back and keep in mind that we are trying
to attack our till our Toa so we don't
have a shell here ok we need to reverse
in the end FA 1 or e 25 some potential
function of functionalities that we then
use within our shellcode for example ok
helpers only we have the epistle written
we have potential read write and execute
table memory in the whole memory
probably so we have executed and we have
the status equal table ok and this Mario
comma T before we also identify a useful
really useful ability in this printer
that allow us to print the net print no
sorry dick get them and their printers
memory so we can use this variety in
order to bypass the SLR for example okay
so the exploitation change goobie we are
going to send a shellcode to the printer
just between patterns we are going to
done we using the memo elephant tonight
the hiding fuchsia lighting there ram we
are going to try to in the fight in
different indian diffic in the fight
sorry all shall go is in the memory we
are going to try to tickle the back and
figure the buffer I'm going to find out
we are going to jump into the shellcode
ok but for our redeeming tools we went
we wanting something more and question
here is will be what is one of the most
important data managed by a printer of
the dead oak humans okay so why don't
create a shellcode that brings the who's
a brain functionality I steal all data
or documents into the printer I'll send
them to throw other words connection for
example okay so let's go with the demo
for this demo we're going to have two
different machines the first one is the
target machine that we will execute
exploit and an exploit handle like we
will receive all the information from
the printer
and the second machine will be the
victim machine that will send this
document to their to their to the
printer in the right side you can also
see the rocket printer okay let me when
the squad
the demo okay
this is the demo here you have the
attacker machine which this is the IP
other for the attacker machine below you
can see the exploit for this for this
printer okay we need three different
document the target IP the target port
under the recipe we're going to attack
the printer one in the port 18 and we
over here include the attacker machine
which is the the reverse IP that we want
to receive the the connection but before
that we are going to execute or exploit
challah that we will receive all date
including sending to the from the
printer okay in this is listening the
poor 157 below we are going to execute
or explode as you can see an exploit in
the third line while using or memory
leak in order to define or shellcode in
the memory and I said that we were able
to receive a connection from our printer
with a sentient hack the planet frame
which was included within the initial
call for example this is a the victim
machine with a different IP address what
we are going to do now is just sending
sending this document this document to
the printer
ok we are going to select this sadly
same printer which is the printer one
after sending the document you can see
how the exploit handler will receive its
own data this is the data that'll print
the same today all 200 who are now
converting this data into a PDF okay
so at this one second after that here
you go this document that we were able
to steal from the printer ok and the
printer still continuing speedy you
normally and or exploit shall also
implement a new french elated that
forward this document to another
printing country by the attacker okay
this was the demo let's go with the yeah
sorry oh sorry this goes the the first
it was a easy case and let's go with a
tricky case ok for this exploit we
didn't have so well and hardware the
back and we came across I know
difficulties and protection that we will
see now
so it is not going to be easy to explain
by Google Drive too so be patient place
okay this is a polarity we identified
the molarity in the same place as
previous one but for this case we have
two different paths within the cookie
okay the first path is something like a
hash and separated by a column we have
something like a base64 string okay and
reverse engineering the finger going to
fight some potential functionalities
that goo contained the polarity but the
most important function here was the
function that they call the basic seek
or the basic code string okay we started
analyzing this dysfunction the VCC for
function the second function and we
identified that extract was pasted as
argument to this function okay and this
fire struck has different elements for
example this source pointer which is the
basis T for a cookie string okay the
destination point that will be filled
within this function with the result of
the basic C for cooking and for example
the soft lane and the destination lab
but this function the basis of all
foreign bases for function was called by
the whole PI D code in the highlighted
area you can see here we are calling the
code base is for the call function and
we are passing cookie Astrid cooking as
argument okay
and the buffer flow occurs because the
destination pointer the struct
destination points are worth diddly
associated to do a stat all right so if
we send a really long cookie value
basically for the code you are smashing
the stack well delay overflow overflow
in the this that arrived so but the
progress that was analyzed localist
we need we need to corroborate this then
lovely okay so we decided to use a
Unicom framework with allowed used to
emulate some piece of code see the
result for example like the registers
and we can create and excrete that
emulate different function for example
the function that get and check the
second part the cookie the string LAN
the basis of Oregon and
functions okay and GUI create an X and a
scrip and we passed 100 a base basis
basis apart in cold okay
and after execute or explode or a script
sorry we were able here we can see here
how we were able to override the PC to
register for example we can also control
all data within the stack pointer and we
were able also to override the r4 and r5
resisted this is because the last
instruction executed before drinking the
the power flow is a population which is
popping the r4 r5 and PC register okay
so we have now what we need in order to
create or exploit but when we started to
do this we everything become inside here
so with for example we detect that the
stack was not executable we to use many
many fingers dresses in order to create
or a chainsaw or shellcode but none of
them were probably because probably
because they win the reason something
like SLR or they can is the RTL who is
written using something like like a
cellar and we also identified that they
they were using a modified version okay
so the most important point here is it
is a nominal innovation system and
different tasks could be executed at the
same time so probably what the camera is
doing is just taking so code from the
from the finger and execute this code in
the memory in a different address so
this is the reason because we weren't
able to use finger addresses in order to
create or shellcode for example probably
they they were elena and offset or
something like that okay therefore we
didn't know where and how our shell code
can be executed because we have
something SLR on an annex and we were
able to find valid addresses to crypt or
rob change but we need a gadget
regattas in order to create or origin so
we need to find a way in order to find
it or Gladius okay thinking about this
we identify some incentive protection
and an approach is sorry for example
reverse engineering they take
the chicken a structure but obviously
within half and half time to the D
because it could take weeks or months
reverse-engineering table ladder in
order to find some potential static
addresses which is a good option
identify a static memory like
configurations okay within the printers
but all the we don't we don't know what
permission is hidden taken to that part
of code okay no memory but for same
random addresses that we will see now
looking for code helpers okay call
helpers I think what this one these are
infinite loop that we found within the
bozo other okay so when we came across
with this this piece of code we saw that
a good option will be create a blind
exploitation okay let me explain you
imagine that we have a code that we all
know if this code was executed properly
or not in use in the memory code who can
do is acid that code we are going to try
to jump into or infinite loop
it's a printed remind job that means
that the code was executed properly in
the printed clashes that means that the
the printer what the record sorry was
not executed properly because the
infinite loop was not executed so we can
do something like a blind SQL injection
but with memory corruption okay okay we
finally decided to mix the called helper
with the approach of brute force in the
PC register and figure out what X
solution wars
executed in memory the main goal with
this approach is helping us with the
infinite loop we are going to try to
guess exactly
God's instruction was executed in memory
okay let's go back example remember that
we can control the PC register and all
date including with a stud pointer okay
so for this example we're going to
include three set of face and after that
the infinite loop address okay and we
are going to start the broforce in the
the printers memory with some addresses
okay finally we jump into the address 14
which is a pop instruction but we don't
know whether this is appropriate pop
instruction we are going to try to guess
that this is a public instruction okay
and after the security Papa struction we
can see how our our zero register was
over with him at the first set of phase
with this one and the PC register was
overwritten by the second set of phase
so the painting will cross the painting
will be down okay in order to solve this
problem exactly
guess what extraction was executing
memory what we can do is change in
information including with this type
pointer okay we are going to change this
information and we are going to include
all the ones interface and not that the
infinite loop for example any way
execute this exactly same address or our
dealer resistor will be overwritten by
the first interface but the PCs resistor
will be all within by the infinite loop
others so the printer will remains up so
just changing the information clear was
in support we can see we were able to
guess that the exertion that was
executed moment was a publication which
is popping one resistor we don't know
which one and as it has a PC register
okay so using this methodology or
approach we were able to in define three
different factions in memory the first
one in the others 12 which is an add
instruction the next one is in the
others 14 which is a puppy session and
in the distance in the distance of 500
bytes we identify another pub
instruction so we have now a pattern
keep in mind that these goes in memory
okay so we have now a pattern exactly a
pattern a mummy with three we were able
to defy three puppies three extractions
okay the goal here was try 25 exactly
sympathy that we found my memory in our
framework address okay if in were data
and we were able to in defined exactly
pattern but in in other others good that
means is that the current ladies
applying an offset when the chemist
taking this code and execute this code
in memory the canneries apply in an
upset but going now now what exactly
option was applying by the kernel so
this provides useful drug ideas and
potential helpers you go in order to
continue with the execution clock
sorry for these but this is the way that
we fall in order to create or exploit
but this was not enough we need
mortgages in order to create or exploit
okay
and at this moment we remembered that we
identify another interesting issue or
gravity within this this sprinter that
provide us were exactly
images and gives good allocated memory
so we can use this this memory link
velocity in order to bypass for example
the a solar and why not we can also use
the images and gifts in order to create
or Rob gadgets okay or rope chains so
what we're going to do now is something
like exploitation with images so what we
can do here this for example don't lot
all the web portal images and give from
to our laptop we can use for example the
rocket a Python script in order to find
some interesting instructions within the
images and gifs overly imitation gave
has an hour no code so we are not going
to find coherent instruction within the
with damage but they are by so but
probably you can find some interesting
if I squeeze until we do that and we
finally were able to identify some
useful instruction and group guide is in
order to create a shellcode okay but we
came across with another problem the
catch is this is the last problem I
promise you
but do always agree show flash the
caches so we have some options here for
example call the RM instruction
to different function like sleep and
protect and others all continue with the
execution flow which probably the most
heart by the most professional option
it was just quickly in order to continue
with the situation flow we need that all
shellcode implement three different
parts the first one is auric payload we
should do something with or exploit
something like within the previous
display for example just hook in the
printf function ID and steal all data
sent to the printers or robots correct
the second part should change the
address that we were able to over going
with exploit so with a valid address at
the angry one we want to continue with
the conclusion flow so we need to jump
to a valid function for example okay and
the third part show an end accept
pointer we have execute or payload we
change the address so probably change it
or a stack pointer so we need to align
the stack pointer to a previous state
and just finally just trigger the
velocity as many times as you want okay
let's go there the demo for this exploit
let me open this demo for this keep in
mind that we for the previous plague we
attack the documents well for this
display we are going to attack exactly
the printers memory okay so for this
exploit we implement four different
functionalities the first one is a graph
theoretic which allows you to write
bytes into the printers memory and jump
into it for example we want to write a
shellcode the next one is what write a
file which is the same but we can for
example use a local fighter you have in
your laptop in order to overwrite a file
in the in the printer like an image for
example the next one is the great
functionality this allows you to read
intensive data from the from the from
the printer memory ok
the next is a search from today which is
really useful and it can allow you to
for example find sensitive information
with the printers memory ok but in order
to write read a data set that we need to
copy all data we want to read for
example in a known place in order to
read them so we can do what we did here
is just copy the data that we want to
read in a known place for example the
images so these are images that we we
are going to to use to replace them for
the two copied information these are
classical PNG with a normal header what
we're going to do now is write sentences
to a painter memory ok
we can write as a cello but for this
example is Jesus enters hi everyone
and we're not going to jump into this
code because notice a code we can see
how we write in the information in no
place and with a lotta image again you
can see how the first line contains all
hi everyone centers and these printers
okay we we can do the same but with a
great file for example the functionality
in order to write a logo in to in order
to overwrite web portal image for
example okay with this
this is a mat for the printer that we
and as you can see here this is the
image of the path we're going to copy
this path in all for exploit okay let's
go with the cop in this method that
we're going to do is just read their
logo and we are going to write this
information into the printer memory okay
it takes a bit so let me this forward I
don't know where is it
exactly it takes a bit okay and a second
it will if we will finish this finish
we're going to check the image again
this is the enmity we wanted to alright
and it will refresh this image we were
able to avoid this image with the hug in
the Box logo okay
this was for right information but no
literacy is great information from the
printer okay so we we will also
implement another functionality with
itself in writing you need to find
interesting formation within this so
looking into the printer we identify
that this was configured with a sorry
with a domain account in this case
identity grow the an inducer but the
power is not is not here in clean clear
test so we are going to try to find
these these power within the printer
memory and all what is okay so we're
going to use the search functionality in
order to search there integral text into
the printer memory and after secret this
you can see how we write in the circle
that will the work
where the load images as you can see the
entity group text was phone at the
address this one these the other the the
entity group text should be okay
we are going to now use they read
functionality in order to dump these
this information from these others okay
this is a reflection I think we are
going to copy and paste the same address
and we're going to read 500 bytes as you
can see here we're reading the
information from these address and
copying the same information into the
image others that we are going to
download okay and after finishing it
takes a bit agree the load the gain the
image you can see for example below the
bottom you can see develops or how the
SD group I mean we use a wart phone and
we can also see how a little bit below
how the super password was the package
that was included with the printer
member opening Claire takes also so with
this this block we were able to write
and great in sensitive information into
their printed member a controller in
whole printers
okay this was the demo for this exploit
and let's go with the conclusions okay
so before that I hope you are all still
alive after Danny trying to explain this
last sprite we knew it was hard so going
to the responsible disclosure process we
started in February and we got a very
mixed response from the different
manufacturers so had a very mature
process for this and we're really quick
a helpful helpful and releasing patches
and everything don't do the hunt we can
just say that sometimes it was easier to
find the vulnerabilities than the than
the security department so I guess they
should do some work in that area most of
them have already published patches for
most of issues
we have already published advisories for
all of them going to the CV party we got
a lot of them 50 in this case 14 were
medium risk ones another 14 were high
response and the rest 22 were critical
raise ones within the report and yellow
ones just take the the number per
manufacturer you shouldn't take it as an
indicative of their state of security
because some of the the vendors grouped
different vulnerabilities under the same
CV entries just for reference the full
list and going for the main conclusion
this research and to show how the state
of security in common office devices
such as printers which are present in
most in not if not all organizations is
still very mature and are dealing north
we found a large number of high and
critical risk issues in all the printers
tested and we wrote functional exploits
to achieve remote code in four of them
we shall here to and to retreat
documents and want to retrieve other
secrets from the memory and we run out
of time so so we were we weren't able to
develop more as place for the other
printers but they have been LEDs that
cooled probably to do that and we stop
searching for vulnerabilities after
finding a few of them as we said so we
think that probably there are a lot more
to to be found and we only checked a few
services as you saw in the attack
surface so there is a lot more to
research in this area and by what we saw
the first one looking at the services
will probably find some logs in there
and we do not expect the same
manufacturer having different
implementations for some of the
protocols like IPP or LDV so probably
the number of modalities
this different abilities effects a huge
number of devices
sometimes larger than than the number
made by the manufacturers we could also
say less marketing and more security and
join for the main gun question the
recommendation sorry for manufacturers
it will be to start investing in
security it is necessary in all the
phases of development lifecycle then for
organizations they should start by
considering considering these devices
which are connected to their corporate
networks as the threads they are because
they have a lot of vulnerabilities and
for hackers this is a very mature field
if you start researching whether devices
starting from the very basics you are
going to find a lot of issues and you
will learn a lot and you will have a lot
of fun so you should give it a try and I
suspected that which sensors showed us a
lot of these devices connected to
internet and we even saw that some
different manufacturers seem to be using
the same code for them for their
interest you can see in these two images
that are quite similar so probably we
tested more vendors than we thought
and the knowledge when finally thanks to
the material FISMA lewis and filling mas
for all their support also special
thanks to Mary Ellen Chris for suffering
us the most and also thank you to Alvaro
Felipe who was part of the research
during the first days but and also heard
that with great ideas during the
exploitation phases so it was difficult
to put a lot of months of research into
just 45 minutes but thank you for
suffering us a talking regression
no take one off the slide we can see the
top question is could these
vulnerabilities be effectively leveraged
to establish control on a local network
what yes basically uh yeah this you can
you can totally do that if you can
execute called you could sometimes
modify the femur or the file system to
get persistence and depending of the
operating system and you could totally
do that based totally feasible yeah we
have a demo that we were able to show in
this in this talk but we have exactly we
are doing exactly just executed a
command control with the printer.i
control just be boarding so our internal
language in order to attack today also
that's exactly the question thank you
[Applause]