[Applause]
thank you very much
can everybody hear me maybe how about
now there we go
shut up Mike nobody likes you neither is
Mike if you met Mike alright so I'm
gonna be talking a bit today about I'm
gonna try to get this higher because I
feel like I'm ducking it doesn't really
go higher okay I'm gonna be talking
about managing large assessments so I'm
a senior pen tester with AB set
consulting for some odd reason the last
year or two I've been doing very large
assessments like Louis is 800 top is
like 27,000 posts on an assessment so
kinda leads to some issues so why am I
talking about it most people learn
hacking on very small networks of like 1
to 20 hosts they don't realize that
there's a difference in attack
methodology until they're into it and
they've lost too much time and they lose
that engagement and that's a bad thing
in the consulting world you don't want
that and really little discussion is
done about pen test methodology and if
there's any pen test here that say the
pen testers here to say I'm an idiot
totally talk to me because I love
changing my methodology because I feel
like nobody talks about it unless you're
at lunch with Mike that's Mike alright
so scanning the thing that annoys me the
most scanning is not netflix time so if
you're on a large engagement and you're
waiting and doing nothing while you're
scanning is happening you've just lost
your engagement so a big blob of text
scanning tips scoping if your scope to
500 to a thousand IP is you're not gonna
be given 500,000 IP is you're gonna be
given a bunch of 16s right and you've
got to scan through that to find your
host so doing large engagements you've
got a couple options and the thing that
somebody's gonna yell at me for us they
use mass scan which I absolutely will
not use because I have crashed a
client's router before I filled up the
table and blew their network up not
gonna do it again
they told me to because I said no and
they told me to and they were wrong but
more on that story so when you're doing
a large scan do a ping only scan find
all your hosts they're payable out there
right throw those into necess and one
other comment because I was talking to
other pentest earlier today in pen
testing we always do
Nessus scans as part of our owner
ability assessment as well as the pen
test so you'll see with here I am always
doing a nessus scan on everything so I'm
doing a ping scan throwing that into
necess for what host or phone I'm doing
an nmap scan for just certain ports like
22 23 80 88 or 88 443 so on and so forth
just a couple ports doing a scan to find
more hosts but I'm excluding those hosts
that were pinging Abel because I'm
looking for hosts that are not payable
to have services up right so I take
those then I throw those in the necess
that's where I'm finding my targets and
I'm trying to do that as fast as I can
because the faster you find things the
faster you can actually have fun right I
hate waiting for scans to stop so
additional scanning can be done using a
script so I have a script that when it
detects that I'm on the Box actually
doing something
it's backgrounds all of my scans so it's
just like hitting control Z in Linux and
it backgrounds all the scans when it
detects that I'm gone it foregrounds the
scans and restarts them because when I'm
running necess scans or nmap scans or
anything else while I'm on the box if
I'm running something like D sniff I'm
gonna be capturing the credentials and
map is sending across
it's not gonna be capturing credentials
the client is sending to me by accident
right through multicast so when your
scans are running you don't really want
to be doing too much pen testing because
they conflict a lot so I push that off
to when I'm sleeping and I try to sleep
a lot so that that happens right so
don't do full port scams with nmap
because necess if you're using an SS
with it you don't want to duplicate that
effort right and map scan plus a necess
can if they're both doing a port scan
why do it and you might say why aren't
you using the great necess functionality
where you can import a port scan and
that's because it hasn't been working
about since March so it just does a full
scan again anyway and waste all that
time and a large assessment again you
just lost your assessment
so scanning tips continued break your
segments and illogical groups generally
slash twenty fours and do both your nmap
scanning and your necess scanning on
those segments doing a slash eight you
can actually run your entire engagement
waiting for your slash eight scan to
complete and you've never gotten
anything back so you're just sitting
there also if you're and I actually just
noticed I made a mistake so necessary
PDF reports are often too large to open
if more than 700 hosts are in there and
a lot of customers want their PDF
reports for various things PCI or just
to review or whatever so if you're going
to be handing those out make sure to do
your slash 24 scans are smaller so they
can actually open their reports because
otherwise they get banned and there's no
real good way to break those up after
the scans been done and actually neces
itself will crash I think if you have
more than I don't know if you noticed
3000 or so hosts on a scan that show up
it likes the toast itself so all right
things to do all the scans are running
if you're externally doing a test
importing showed and results into
Metasploit is great really fast
convenient and you can get pen testing
immediately if your internal running
responder which I know there was pretty
much a whole talk and responder
yesterday so I won't go into too much of
that but it's a great tool I've had two
customers in the last two years that
have not been vulnerable to it so it's
just the easiest win on the planet
capture cred domain admin you take over
the network and you've done then you
have more fun but still so check public
password breaches for possible password
cred reuse this is depressingly common
and OS int acting like google hacking
and all that kind of stuff right normal
pen testing so vulnerability reuse is
most of what I'm going to be talking
about today so when you find something
on a network you know it's probably
going to show up multiple times on the
network if you're doing 50 hosts you can
probably do this manually and see you
know hey this host looks similar and I
can I can find it again and check that
vulnerability 1 when you're on a larger
network that doesn't really work so if
you find the vulnerability once you
basically want to script it so that you
find it again repeated
and kind of how to do that scripting and
here's a short backstory so I was going
to start writing Metasploit auxilary
modules which I'm still working on some
but I found out that's a real time sink
so I started prototyping and doing some
other types of writing for vulnerability
checks and trying to figure out how to
do this with large number of hosts and
the great thing that I've discovered and
I thought everybody knew this and that I
was late to the game and I'm finding out
a lot of people in the pen testing world
don't use it is the Metasploit host
tracking database they use it but they
don't use it to its full extent so we're
gonna talk about it a bit today and if
you've never seen it before so you can
import data in and you just type
services - you and it pulls up every
host and port that your scans have found
and then you can easily sort through
that and say I just want port 80 and
then pull up all port 80 is or if I want
anything that has like a WW so it's
running HTTP you can throw in a service
scan 4ww and it pulls up everything that
is running a www port so it's really
kind of nice I'm getting pictures taken
all right so importing get scan data
into Metasploit if you've never used
this before which I hope you have I hope
I'm boring you right now so you can
directly import and map XML files and
necess dot necess files the export of
the nessus which again that's your
scanned data they're gonna be using
right and you can also as I said before
you showed on to directly pull data out
and start hacking right away so how to
write these scripts that kind of wire
outside of the box so and again this is
because Metasploit aux modules take way
too much time to write so I wrote a LDAP
check script and it took me 15 minutes
I've been trying to get the thing
written in an aux module that they would
actually accept into Metasploit and it's
taken me to many hours to that I want to
admit it's just not cool so if you're on
my engagement you don't want to be
burning time writing scripts you want to
write the script get it out there and
start checking yourself right so speed
is the key so using the Metasploit
database outside of metal
it the lazy way cuz there is a harder
way where you you know hook into the
actual Postgres database I'm not getting
into that that takes away too much
effort so you created Metasploit RC file
and which is just a dot RC file and when
you execute it with Metasploit it it
runs any commands in there as if you had
just logged into Metasploit and type in
some commands so what we can do here is
so here's my my LDAP audit 1 and it's
just looking up services that are port
389 and outputting a file of every 3 and
9 hosts on there and then we're gonna be
using that data and here's my gratuitous
script viewing slide let's see how that
actually works so when you try to pull
this into a bash script or you can use
Python or whatever you want but
basically it's just dumped out a flat
file with a bunch of info in it so all
that I'm doing is I parse that data out
so I just want my host import data and
I'm gonna put it into variables and also
since I'm working with LDAP and this is
the reason that it's costing so much
time with Metasploit is they don't like
you adding protocols although they do
but they don't so it gets a little
difficult to add a new protocol into
Metasploit to work with it so all that I
have to do here is throw in a check too
to allow LDAP s but as you go through
your script all you're doing is you're
pulling out that host data and using you
know just like you would on a command
line right so I'm using LDAP search it's
pretty easy and straightforward if
anybody wants to look at it I'm gonna
have all this done that github later but
so you have a nice little script it does
its thing but it's pulling that data up
in the Metasploit database so when it's
got 27,000 hosts sitting in your
database you can pull up every LDAP port
do the scan on it really quick and it's
super simple so seeing an action because
nobody likes to see code on a screen so
I execute my script it checks to make
sure my machine is configured starts the
framework and I'm scanning every LDAP
host on the Internet automatically so
it's just going down and trying to see
what data is there
which I'm gonna skip on to that because
we are short on time today so next and
the only reason that a lot of people
fight me on doing this method because
I'm wiring outside the box again is
multi-threading which if you're a bash
developer you know you can multi thread
so RC file for nikto my nikto audit
script so you're pulling 84 43 80 80 and
84 for 3 right
pretty pretty easy RC file for
Metasploit and then fat threading into a
bash script is very simple so you just
set up a max procs there so that's I
want four processes to run and then when
you're actually inside I guess this is
probably easier so you can just count
your PID and see how many children PID
are running on it and when you execute
your subscripts in here you just throw
an ampersand at the end and they become
a sub process of that process and so
once you get four threads going your
master PID is saying oh there's four and
as you keep running when when it goes
down to three it'll start the next one
and you've got multi-threading right so
pretty easy so long story short on this
you you do a bunch of scanning you find
a vulnerability you write your your
batch script right you throw your bash
script into a folder and you can run it
singly but once you've done a couple of
engagements you can combine all this so
you put all of your Metasploit RC files
into one you make a master shell script
that executes all of your other shell
scripts and you set up your threading so
that your master shell scripts starts
say five checks and then inside of your
scripts you have all those threads so
they're doing three to five sub
processes at a time and at this point
you've built your own vulnerability
scanner so you just execute that master
shell script once your data is in necess
we're in a sorry Metasploit and it
starts running through all of your
checks that you've done because you know
Nessus catches some stuff but hopefully
you're finding other things as a pen
tester that it's not because that's the
point right
so this is building a vulnerability
scanner outside of your vulnerability
scanner to automate all of that so you
more manual stuff to find more things to
throw in so I've got about a hundred and
eighty give or take of these files right
now so I've quite a ways on my way to
finding and building my own
vulnerability scanner but it makes it
nice quick and easy so that's pretty
much it it was a very quick talk and
again I thought it was very basic I'm
apologizing if you're bored but a lot of
people were asking me how I do this so I
wrote it up but contact info you ever
want to get a hold of me
I've got email eople sniper at gmail.com
Twitter is the impulse nyberg github is
e apple snail you're kind of finding a
pattern here huh oh sorry
maybe
there we go
I work in IT yeah QA so HTTP screenshot
is my number one go-to and I love
dumping them all into a directory and
then going through I actually have some
scripts that do identification now on
the HGTV screenshots and throw things
into boring less boring and I've never
seen before so it does all that nice
sorting and that really wasn't that hard
so it it just does some basic some basic
checking I can actually put all that up
online I'm sure to give me a few days
and I can throw that up on my github but
yeah it does some nice identification
then so you're not dealing with a bunch
of 404 pages or something like that or
just you know if they have 1,000 of the
exact same webpage they don't care about
it's it's really easy to say okay look
look at the image and look is this is
this similar to all the others and a lot
of times I'm really lazy so I do it
based on size so I get right down to the
bite size and and see what it looks like
and throw away a bunch of stuff which is
not the best way to do it but I've got
other ways but they take a lot more
programming to pull the image data or
the text data out of an image and
usually I don't spend that much time on
it but sometimes they have is I've got a
couple that I did because it was way too
much effort otherwise so any other
questions sure I've worked with it a
little bit and I've got to say I'm old
enough that they I've been doing Bosch
long enough that I found out about those
way later than my current process this
one is really really easy to build in
and it's been very effective for me so I
that there's better out there I just
have never done it because when I tried
it wasn't I got weird errors sometimes
and I just skipped over it because this
is like the world's laziest so I've
basically got my template that I build
into and it just works so yeah pretty
much any other questions comments
anybody think I'm an idiot I'm totally
up for those so anything sure I have had
very little luck with that have you this
is actually work so I had actually used
a different different method at one
point where you could actually import
your your end map XML files then and so
you added a plug-in to do that and that
was working great and that's basically
what I was using and I've tried doing
the ping method and it just hasn't
worked for me but and I'm probably doing
it way wrong so send me instructions I
love it but yeah I used to do the import
of the XML and that worked great
up until again like February or March
and now I imported it sees all the hosts
so it pulls that in but then it starts a
full port scan and all of them again
which completely takes out the point of
importing it right so it was supposed to
it used to take the host and the ports
and then do its checks on those just
those and now it just it sees the host
and it pulls those in and starts to full
scan again but depending on how your
scan was set up it could pull in a bunch
of data that you don't want so I just do
it manually and then bring that in and
it seems to work just fine so any other
questions comments anybody want to ask a
pen test or something I don't have too
much time left but that's a good
question so the question was why do I
live in Fargo
I'm sure you get this up here and
Winnipeg a lot as well and the answer is
hell no the the answer is I get I work
for a San Jose California company and
they pay me what is probably peanuts to
a San Jose company and what is probably
within the top 2% of Fargo it's a really
good mix I've actually thought about
moving it further into the middle of
nowhere where a house cost like 40 grand
because then I can just buy one every
couple of months right I just burned my
house down and get a new one so anything
else I'm done oh sorry the quickest way
is doing a quick demo and again I'm
gonna go back to responder on that so
running responder and watching the
password hashes fly by in gold really
works well if you just say that's bad
and they see bad fly repeatedly across
the screen they are not going to be
happy campers the other thing that I
used to do which is totally like not OK
in a way but so you show somebody that
you got a Metasploit shell on their
laptop right at a corporation they're
like oh that's not so bad and then you
say does your daughter ever use your
laptop at home and it's like well yeah
it's like I'm watching her on your
webcam like this is possible this is
doable and the second that it's like oh
they can watch me at home immediately
there they're jumping on it and going we
need to fix this now because now it
affected me it doesn't affect the
company and if you can do that it works
perfectly so yeah is responder cheating
me and my coworker got in a very large
argument on this yes and the same
question comes with ARP spoofing and
with ARP spoofing I would say it is
actually
not as feasible as it used to be
especially on an assessment
mainly because denial-of-service testing
is usually out of scope and you have a
chance of taking down the network that's
bad responder does not take down the
network and it sends you creds right
away and if I'm an attacker the first
thing I'm gonna do is one domain admin
and the fastest way to get domain admin
is responder so it's the first thing I'm
gonna use and if the black hat is gonna
use it I want to be using it right and
what black hat wouldn't take something
that hands you the creds can forward the
creds on and automatically use them and
usually get domain admin literally
within five minutes or less of being on
a network so so long story short no I
don't find it cheating I find it
hilarious and fun but not cheating
so I also am one of the pen testers that
don't stop so if I get domain admin I
don't stop and I just I keep hearing
that these people exist out there
somewhere if your pen tester does that
like bring them all back and shoot them
so if I haven't gotten like responder
they might get the main admin within
five minutes I'm gonna pull out I'm
gonna try my next method my next method
my next method if I don't have three to
five ways of getting into your network
and gating domain admin when I've been
doing it for two weeks or more I'm
really feeling bad like you need three
to five methods yes
responder actually only has about four
things you care about number one is you
want to enable SMB signing that depends
you against SMB relay attacks a lot and
especially I am blanking on it
there's a tool inside a responder that
basically relays creds automatically to
a box and it just waits for an admin and
then it it once you get admin it's done
and you've logged into the box you get a
shell you can dump creds and it's over
right so that's one and then you want to
turn off a couple different protocols
most of them can be done GPO there is
one that you have to actually write a
script because it's pulling out of the
registry you have to pull a a gooood for
each interface and then you need to Bey
we set a flag on that goooood so you've
got a ready script that pulls that
gooood and then sets the flag after that
good but it's really not that hard and
again I've got a script that does that
too I can push up to github as well but
yeah it's only a few things the problem
is they keep rolling it back so I keep
having customers that they've we find it
they fix it we do remediation testing
it's fixed we come back the next year
they're vulnerable again to like half of
it because for some reason they either
rolled it back or that script that I
talked about they don't push it to the
new boxes they only pushed it once and
now you've got other you know new hosts
up there that are vulnerable again so
they get pwned again and they get
annoyed because they got pwned again and
now we're remediation testing and
they're gonna screw it up all over again
so long story short you need to make it
that it keeps running and keeps fixing
exactly all right and we're out so you
have any other questions I'll be in the
back
[Applause]