so this presentation is about
searching for votes on the internet
scored points away visa payment on the
internet
uh... because
usually i hayes isn't going to write the
already on the internet network
and i hope that this to spotted white
acerbic
by introducing myself
and from what mocha
at wristwatch abound
and then probably the only occasion dot
and security researcher
uh... hotel sleep issues surrounding for
back which is a commission settled
the best
for voice over at the security issues
work scanner which is not
software-as-a-service
on
basically give it the idea address off
your pbx which
might be public facing
on the internet
and sends you back have a report
my research is not just the boat was so
correctly but sometimes uh...
i do a lot of research when it comes to
weather occasion security
whether the cation fire was
and the web browser security and very
his defense topics
and that's any of the security byron
any dispute
so we were talking about salute i'd be
introducing some basic propose for those
who are not familiar with sit
and
which show
how the internet explorer
went to wreck the devices
i've been talking about some ideas when
it comes to fingerprinting these devices
because the whole devices
that tell you what
uh... what they are running
some book about some strange behavior
handbooks
to monitor what others are doing
and will talk about briefly about what
the cybercrime
seems to be doing when it comes to
weren't elected
so that no uh... michael with sars
supporting
fares to propose
and to do next
as they say is work some programs
according to both soon
here contact
and set
face some some people tell you district
looks exactly like the g_o_p_
and and it actually does effect if you
have to use a lied to me
which places and she
messages it's with the governor makes
sense
of six messages as well
because it has the same for my pc
uh...
and they're so i guess the controlling
indeed message for a month for it which
we use for remain so you have
from and to have this is about
uh... but it's quite different from it
should be initiative you have to
client-server motive uh...
it's almost like that
baat and said
you might have a request which is being
sent to bind the sick registrar said
that
and
so so woods
magicians seven different
usually the insists on sports are all
over
port
fifty sixty
you could be
but that's not necessarily the case of
course they convened s
and its supporters of the cv
and you might have support for thier
lessons learned
frontier this would be on
d_c_ people worked
fifty sixty one
you have
that basically contracts of
entities
and two points which i don't usually
the phones supports
and you might have said
format that they're so you would have to
copy or normal medical
to wear to decide that and it would get
back to presence on the bundy inaccurate
and then you have centers
uh... i've been talking about
registration proxies
registrar solo
uh... record restrictions set there
where and wednesday register with us
they usually use a vindication of course
so it's not necessarily the case
and
if they're not going to just exchange
extension one hundred
than any quotes and it won't work for
one should be sent to
yet the internet's and and or not
associated with
uh...
deccan dept
extension
and then you have proxies
and parties and no and
wants to
speech scheider uh... sirf entities
and maybe there
it yet
when you have a uh... and i'd be pbx it
usually does the job of
bolstered registrar
and proxy server
is just an introduction
for those who are not coming in with the
protocol
then i suppose i said
and you know it's not it's
just like it should be an engineer had
followed debts
maybe had options
you have
invite
invite gets foam streamed
done correctly of course
uh... you have registered but i just
mentioned i just mentioned
the registered surveyor
packages that several support
diverges dramatically
and you have ruptures these are not the
only three of course but
they are the ones that i did not care
about
options gives you anis dot support at
options so we'll keep you wanna check
uh... within six to nine point
supports
certain that methods or certain
defendants
he would send in options
message
and these host usually looks like desire
an invite message
you can see looks richmond too
issue could be
you have to put the indication of an
invite you have we'd had uh... porting
in exp
for what
which would describe what codecs are
supported
on which forced the arctic deportees
and so on
um...
you have to do when from and best
but because i don't know about
about you can see that
and the from address
there except that
and i'd be mentioning that there there
are
and you have a certain tests if you are
right
india instead of the pot invitation for
you and have approx
in this case you had said you are right
the basic idea
when when it comes to scanning for sip
friends
you to be devices
is to get a response back
but traditionally
we were accepted
for doing board scanning going you could
be worse than the
dot blank beckett's that and two
packages
and skipping tonight's he uh... eric
accident the response
but in this case this is is more
retirement
because what we do is
we send affected it was and that's it
message
we get something back then you know that
there's a sick
tax and it makes sense
you know that there's a certain departs
and it's relatively efficient i guess
you don't need to use my purpose of kids
who don't use to use
brought up it's necessary
uh... lengthen my cruise i will use one
subject
and gentle scanning done like that
and is the basic idea and the most basic
scad
type of scam
using options you you would get there
at two hundred ok work for a formal form
some sort of response which
makes sense when you interpret it
uh... s
as it
abuses
one message that night
came across the uh... it's not
microsomes generate
message
it's something that someone else
created
and to the costs and to a
transferable
so this is the basic idea uh...
is that they're going to start
what it does is it creates a and options
message and sends it
and if you get something back then you
know
it works
um...
and is what i'm talking about peace and
lots of six messages to different idea
texas bebu you determined by say shit
and maybe you do it on different sports
club
in my case i only used fifty sixty
and when you get something back then you
know
that didn't they resisted mess that sick
entity
so
which has been met
we can do phrase different reaches
pending on your
uh... preference
and began randomized dispense as well
so
you might want to render my services and
so that you don't six dcn
network for the time
and you might want to granddad random
brendan scanners lurches different
uh... what it does is
it's face
or like the excesses except
the ones that are prided or
uh...
got a note on the internet
on the internet
and discuss
their own internet
uh...
this is an idea that you tried to get
that sound good
of what's what's out there
so we can do and then skies we can do
scanned by idea just class
weekend
standby provide that who wants to go
there and i want
but we don't want to do that decided to
go for conference
return used
shall i be databases for that
and my case i was a bit lazy and i
decided to
to find a website which
doesn't vote for me
uh... one i have to do what's best for
the country of my choice argentina and
its case
pretty right
but that's fine
changed the format so that the pecan
rangers appoint beatrice
are used to following
help shoots randomized random the other
hand scan
and what's that
uh...
twinkled from about four
from about five
and as you can see
you immediately starts getting results
no argentina is actually not one of the
most busy
sitcoms arm
what some other countries actually give
you one
much much better zones
so i decided to check out what
my own country dot
which is a tiny country uh... there's
more people living
on the island and there are not the
addressee s
and i thought about that
their system there in eleven point
thirty seven percent problem replying to
my sister
messages
which horse quite strange because when i
checked the other countries
what's you chew
uh...
have some people and it seems that
whenever we're giving didn't give in and
i'd be address changed and you i'd be
interested in june
they make sure that we actually use it
sellout
so that's that's why it's such a high
percentage
uh...
and by looking at these results
i noticed that
one particular provider
one of the major ones
was actually the exposing
dvd where at
pep boys over at the surface
and to all of these are exposed on the
internet abated
that force kind of course
these are different depressed once
actually
the first three are for sure from this
provider
and their cable modem
devices which has a
and you can plug in your normal form
to dampen
here tonight
also looked at the unpopular once
because sometimes you find some
interesting place
uh...
however in this case i notice that
there's a lot of bridges so
i decided that i want to versions from
my statistics
and this gives so much more coming
overview off what's out there
arstan skits not unspoken sometime
would have imagined
and my country at least
uh... bombs
you and you find the prints three
mansour
and for example grad student that one of
the peace and
from school never get rage
rarity
also looked at than other countries
which seemed a bit mysterious to me
uh...
the numbers are quite different
unique user agents
is much lower
by scans the first one million packages
embryogenesis
and
most of them did not have
uh... main did not have a user id
because of what i was doing this i was
looking at the user-agent string in
which is a
one of the heather's just like it should
be had this user-agent
or server
if any of these exist
i mean dump it stuart database
and in this case most of them don't have
don't seem to have user-agent
also interesting news uncw dot which
i'll be talking on paper
and the others are i'm not sure what
they are if
someone from the audience
notes uh...
the statement on it or not but i think
that
it's some sort of internet provider dot
so what about the norm
twelve percent still messages
i know it is that's
deal options message is not
is not being allowed to method not
allowed
and disease
quite strange because safari ptc clearly
states
issues
uh... support options to elicit
devices
and when you start scanning you find all
these different
uh...
na na received complaint or
different behavior
between different devices
but in this case it does us what
what that supports
and supports a very breezy
form on functionality invites
economics which is courted by invites
precedent by and
separate basic
soprano
what kinds of dozens expenses are ending
form
accents hangs up the call
whether multi jto
well i just thought you might
i don't fret
you guys are
uh... familiar with the italian ice
cream company
it really doesn't have anything to do
with that
uh...
it's just my user-agent
uh... my happens to be looking at and at
first when i took my user-agent
and accepted that spongy bone
uh... the reason why it changed
my user agent is because
some returned from smart
and different intrusion detection
systems are actually looking for
street st
secretions
friendly scanner which was my would use
images
i didn't want to get any nasty email
it's during my research so
i kind of changed east make sure that it
doesn't get caught by stuart
that's fine prime
i don't think i didn't get a nasty
mister stein
previously i did
then i decided to look at
somewhere near
and speeding
that's a very small echoing to my best
and i'd understand
twice
using different idea gets is of course
using randomization
there's a small number of some devices
being fixed post but there's a high
number of
better to be two hundred
different user-agent
uh... almost eighty
then there's
sony's
projectiles what what these
links is seems to be relatively popular
but that's still a small number
uh... upstairs
seems to be
more popular than the other countries
that had checked
gone you have the usually is
usually use a region standard-bearer
since you did great
service providers
some interesting once some thursday
user-agent stuff from student loans
um...
but over the world so we have to return
to the world
uh... clerks
particularly friendly
templeton purple was actually putting
and user-agent string
was extra or surveyor
was actually putting difference mains of
different cities looks
quite interesting
but it's not just the both ports fifty
sixty
uh... you guys can either course of
course
especially six fifty sixty-one
uh... for example i have a small in
texas didn't read that for that and it
has to
different ports
in one forty penpal crop one form which
would be listening on
fifty sixty
the other one is on fifty sixty watt
dismal
uh... which is a skype a particular
and that supports it
gossip
and it's up to two cents on six four oh
six four
of course
you won't find too many gizmo uh...
photographs it
suppose
book on the internet because they would
usually be behind them eighty bucks
they're such big cases where you have
any t devices
that when you do and open connection
when you open up a connection
peep abuse and be polite
and the port plans on
an eighty devices
would be open before but over the import
of our own internet that goods are sold
it would be interested in that
for debates the nation at the entrance
but that would
except bands
they seem to be the cheaper ones
uh... and and this this could be quite
an issue i guess
because all these other methods are
there certain markets and
started talking about producer david or
and invites which i don't
your comment
and you might have to start the records
but it's not so popular
at least not knock on the internet
recruiter ex post p_p_ axis
mccarthy and its records which points to
your
and the idea is that when it didn't
someone wants to protect your pbx
it with the first checked the set the
record except for one more the pbx
it exports of pbx with justice pass at
the airport and demo quick to point that
when of course this information is
appeared before after one
not for trust legitimate users
so what weightlessness
interesting and of course market
research
some people might be more interested in
that stand out there is
but what we're interested in exactly the
opposite
and
it's depicts a groups
it gives you a good idea when someone's
comes out then sa's
paid eight do you think there might be a
the police told her i'd be wearing or
something like that
it can give you an idea of how to assess
how bad the situation is
and it's kind of this
um... there's a lot of
cable modems out there
that are supporting sick
if you want to look at uh... by their
abilities and pbx is
you'll notice that there's too much less
pbx is being kicked exposed
chris morris there's gonna be
competition
at least when it comes to sit
and for example one article
vulnerability
uh... to digest the pitch i will be
describing expect much
over here about
basically this affects a lot of seven at
five point six
it seems to be a vulnerability and the
to proceed towards it
built-in bypassed by design
security issue
and according to my tests uh...
dinner that government of course
effects
around sixty percent
of the super bowls
and if you want to fight the later on we
can discuss
the security issue
and reports and once so we can get an
idea of how widespread dis whenever it
is
there despite the few use every god
there's quite a few such devices that
donuts value who they are
they tried to keep
keep it secret when one solution would
be fingerprinting
uh... the other solution would be
defended by force of course
but charts to go to the fingerprinting
technical solutions
uh... in this case
you can notice that
uh...
you notice a lot of
asterisk servers which had
user-agent which
would have been modified studing
combination or something like that
so
if you modify that there's ordinal peace
you've only
the fuel tank
is what when you say that span options
message
you get a response back
and didn't do ted into had that
and set by d
responded
and everyone seems to be generating base
in a different manner
so that's no standard way of
generating
this and everyone is including their own
uh... fingerprint x
so deep
indicates how much they risk but only
starts with a s and it's followed by
five or six hexadecimal numbers
and status decides some of the
fingerprints if you don't simply choose
to find morning databases
and two fishes of open-source
and
that's lots necessary even though i have
here is some devices don't creates
i think that sometimes
they should but they don't
so i decided to tickets for that and
look at other markets the order of
creditors is particularly interesting
in this case you noticed that
these two messages
have to see more debt
both are asterisk
messages
so if i put them percentage of their did
notice that fits
olympic unsupported are swept but the
rest at the same order
uh... in this case
because i decided to see sec
are infected
uh...
so it's
two seconds message is not an asterisk
messages
is something else
and that's one way to tell
between
once said one said entity and another
and it
sush movie shows you
dec except
crowded and the device name of course
so you might have to sink ships that
on different devices different products
and you also have
uh... you can look at the case
so in this case
uh... the case of because i'd be in the
first place it's uppercase the i_d_ into
second place it's not
and you have all these differences
which are quite
uh... usually when he was trying to
fingerprint
uh...
so them i think about this inspectors
pretty passive
you can do expensively or you can just
use one beckett's to elicit a response
and aunt
then look at these soon get back it
when you tried to do fingerprinting once
you have to call the database and will
be working on
and
yes it's the shits discourse introduced
them and they shouldn't sleep issues
minded their way to solve that
people can submit there
their fingerprints
and it does
automatic
uh... regular expression generation
it's not uh... the best
are a few moments
but if that works
however errands issues two point go
which
the unity
uh... i hope to approved the sun awt
because the fingerprinting is quite
what's old reliable right now so
it's a vicious that won't go away and
actually wrote that part said
bart said which that actually works on
nyc
the version zero point whatever from
and that's that's just about
fingerprinting
tell us talk about some
strange stuff
um...
saying same here added just ask and you
would send slots ups register messages
some reply
they would usually ask for
authentication or sell you hey you're
not going to race to get
and to get this information back
they could get registered
uh... you might get uh... for affordable
followed or something like that
but when you get that until k
it usually means that it's not ok
by two hundred ok what
it's means that you've got into stage
excuse that your scanner
was logistics to d_p_p_ x
and
or sip-it at the time
uh...
and uh... what happened in this case
account of what the lord
devices which went blank what's behind
it ok and say they're on during the week
bites that i was
second ohio sniffing my connection
and that was not a single subject ic
coming days
uh... which was not supposed to be
destined to my
i_t_n_ chips
uh... what what's happening was i was
getting
all this canning
going going on the internet from certain
i'd be addresses switch hazard actually
registered with my skynet
this meant that
for for me this meant that i got that
at handbook
uh... i could get more
surpluses it's
but of course um
i wonder what happens to be
to the people trying to use their
there and what's the point
it's
it's gonna create problems for sure
so i want to do that again
what about invites comes web
i'm not going to invite spencer for
uh... invite
that's false three
uh... in the case of deepak pbx
it might struggle proxy the implied
so it might strike to terminate d
for what
however many put most of the times
uh... when you try to review
accidentally deleted
antibodies it's just questioning it on
the specifics if you are right
seeing if it's usually registered to
extension
one two three
on the pbx
if you don't call it on one of the three
of you send a day
and invites message which doesn't
include step extension
that we've been trained talks new for a
four or some other message
but the problem is that
samples with experience when an
extension
just reading going at specific extension
it's not even that
security precautions really about
anyone any extension is quite a problem
but arnold is that
a lot of software based
set for weeks
do with this
uh...
span of apartheid were basic forms
abt this behavior but some do
so if you're doing these kind of scarce
you might end up
uh... calling at all
provider and you might end up with lots
of complaints
don't do it
uh... in the case of the pbx the
behavior somewhat different
at bb excluding
tried to
findpage de extension exists on the nice
work
if that's going into sunday not
technically quality
sometimes
not necessarily the case is that there
are many times right
it asked for pretentious for vindication
however into texas
extension does not exist and if it
matches for safety and uh...
with certain
patterns if it looks like a phone number
it's might strike to did
and it's my tried to or dad phone number
wronged in normal phone system
which might give you reform quotes
and that's what's
someone's rights to do but more than
someone
uh... quite a few minutes seem to be
trying to do this
one guy actually uh...
wrote the paper dot there
one particular experiment which was on
the
gemini provide that
lots of people who were getting each the
squares funny-looking looks
in various cd-r in there
quantic or cohen reports
so this time decided to investigate
uses the shipments vij
that they were sending it's not accept
the aristide complained but that sees
that it still works
um... who was faking user-agent of
course
tenant everyone forgets exciting
well known
support for
but this something someone was extreme
searching for votes and
uh... trying to uh... finds
waste of getting free fall most
so after reading this
this paper which was talking about what
at justice dot over here
i decided to write some basic very basic
quote
f_h_p_ d_x_
uh...
just a few lines of code
uh... and i don't think it went on
sold i put it on the internet and
started looking for database whatever i
was going to get paid
it's been a textile
you can look at the
accord
configuration is still part of the cold
but right
be shifting back to an advisory group
uh... the first extension doesn't have
any password
it's some article
uh... second extension response we're
gonna wonder except there's extension
www
and so on
yang you numbers hollow
it works for tax cuts with an army
so horrible
on the first case we don't have any
prosperous alot
just gives you an awfully
and
so prevalent
thinks it's registered to really pbx
second place
i'd give it their own prospered
so did you learn for for awhile
contingent quiet
um...
some people notes that
the bad
because of that buster keaton with
password
which i did
it's registers
and finally
i gave it uh... non-existent extension
and it's replaced with a four oh four
with us here
so that i
obviously wanted to make sure that it
works with but recently she's
i don't have any of the other two words
which are not
released and that there are some
two weeks
uh... which aren't being used by the
underground
cost them two weeks for scanning
so i put make sure that the president's
appreciates
the sip
that the extension and you may reach you
technique is implemented an arms dealer
so what it does is
it's
uh... checks
and uh... an extension of lives
it shows that its
it exists on the pbx or not
and then finally said as be correct
which dusty
using proved fortuitous
on that works
okay so i put this
this on the internet
and started getting adventures such as
getting some
interesting messages
i needed to do a lot of things very
in my data because uh... uh...
some people were standing because the
war which interests and that's the which
generates a lot of
traffic
but once i got to prevent vote of the
way
assassin noticing
one of the first messages that i've
served notice and was this message
an invite
uh... destined to uh...
itself america number
and premixed will come from mailed your
solutions
i didn't know about this company before
uh...
and more messages
different numbers
trying to get uh...
some some forms during the baby's trying
to get that line
tramped through their cause uh...
you'll notice that
they start changing the prefix
so that they had zero zero for example
as an adult of p_b_s_'s
you just that deal to get an outside
nine
so it should not
who are these misha solutions and they
seem to be
sometimes what
who are interested in voice over at the
security guard
uh...
and who are doing some testing critical
support over at the bottom
they have a complains
and there are actually saying hey
there's someone who is
so i think the use of agents and the
year
the colony b
at the corner and the has made it so you
should see it's not us
and sent them an email last week
to see what they say
including a and others like
didn't have anything from them
uh...
isn't there some that someone is
exporting data trim company
what us this message i started getting
this message
between one like this is very similar
to the same message that that that was
describing that's bigger about cops
the paper that i described before
i think this was not one month later
so with these guys
which this coming weekend and it didn't
really change their
software unlike
electing
uh...
even after i think there was a
reasonable doubt
and they started changing the prefix
elsewhere
with things you know stand working nine
zero one one so the
they try to undo married
the prefix arts and lots of invites
messages
check to get them outside
so what's the purpose behind as well
obviously does desperate for divorced
uh...
invoice will break the fraud
form front has been done
for quite a while you have the phone
preach and so on what's up mines stores
some of them in the movies
uh...
mobile home was supposed to cost money
battling for you
quote a relation
cost a lot of money
so while scheme
seems to be
uh... side agreements try to find some
pbx systems you don't be prosperous or
excuse all
trekking sindhu there
uh... phone calls
uh... try to find a way through their
phone books
on what they do is the the woods
configure their pbx test that's ever
uh... to use these different reach bunny
rabbit
pbx is on the internet
and
d_-day with said
access to the asterisk said that
tutors party still point providers
fortifying there said uh... these
services cheaper of course
and there were some people who work
what's doing this previously so it's not
just
my idea
uh...
there's a lot
of guys who are not quote or
their just keeping good or were
relatively low
uh... right
there though
million dollars of what's this
not only on the news but also from
talking to be good
one particular bank
was claiming that they lost
a lot of money
and because of for fraud because of
uh... primero b
ups on the internet
the program is that sometimes you have
to put your pbx on the internet to
communicate that news it's easier
well it's not necessary
an inspector to pt
put it behind the ppm
or something like that of course
uh...
apart from that
you might have premium number front
uh... which
continues in the two words
for selecting
and denial of service
might be a huge problem
uh... in the case of their close and
therefore accept it
it means that
although the all the employees can go to
home
the pbx doesn't work anymore
so if you have to call center triangles
to expose your
pbx on the internet at least
different stuff
uh...
i've noticed that for example microsoft
their solution
at which supports it
all pretty unless
uses the windows pretentious so
when you got to do when you do what
indication if you do a good for set that
you might have had a post one seat
so you cannot vote
hold
active directory domain digest
i never actually tried this
youth
so we are for for the stock car into the
sky
copycats officious to support my
statistics scanning
first
din it's is and you option scans the
first x_ number of
type the address is
import tax
it's very handy
because
sometimes you don't want to thank all
the advantages
anti-bill don't explode this
develop was
handy that and i didn't have my
to bear on
uh... bisbee reports acts which gives
you people
doctors tns dot
thirty unpopular devices as well and and
dot something very important script
before
public television on such issues
just has been updated
some reference s
that's all and i'd like to thank the
secti team
for the invitation
absolutely good for coming out
obviously got a few questions i mean
first of all the last thing with a high
price
uh...
to delight capture walk across
appear preferred that i
use managers are being in the other
thing
make one of those calls uh... cereals
uh...
i mean i'm going to read that featured
you know i i don't have
or nine seven features breast implants
uh... opening
these are curious to see was a lawyer i
needs by media a need to start
listening to n_p_r_ at these three men
the media
stocks according to packwood and make it
make you a bit of his list of all the
numbers that are being trend of their
current right now but i can't attended
uh... mildest
south american wants but you don't
really needs to tell me the phone call
in the sense that you don't meet
will be used
as estimate you don't need to be that
the other hand
because
once you start getting that you don't
normally be
over the phone
start sending enacted yet to be st
and yet that that would know
that came in half
three phone calls
then it would to decide
on its own number
track races but
how did that
ivan and there are also when you're
doing those jobs that he wouldn't be fun
products and all that was probably
thinks the main for
people to submit
what they find
i mean i want to have it at all it is
the difficult more the nub you know more
than a million ideas as of the country
it's it's quite pleased to have your own
combined altogether the senate
hong
did you say something about the digest
leakage thing i mean not how it works
but maybe how it's useful what would it
be used for using exploited ok okay
so that they just need to check on their
ability
uh...
what it does is
you have it's like sunset endpoints
against his old support
uh...
yuko recipe for
sometimes you have to guess what
expansionist dot
that's not necessarily a problematic
it's a targeted etc etc
if you put a sip phone
it concepts and analysis except the
phone for
maybe you have to put them into
sportsman or something
went beyond sets doesn't here and i
think something and up
from bantam
was the handoff
they sent you wrap
and the challenge that bought it's out
of hate you not authorize to send me a
bike if you are your possessions
doesn't interest force i think and we're
not trying to protect that which is
quite possible
it's just that just
authentication sort stepped into
inventions indication it's and it's like
treatments and are
extent the five and it's quite fast
to before such
treasures
those funds via overwork dialer again
suspects accused of the cfo
uh... osco books
so-and-so you rewriting the surpluses
nothing
so you're putting in more fun features
uh... more progress
so
apply it to
and which is already part of flight back
and being convened it's unlikely might
open-source passive smoke
uh... i hope the public siskel that
because siskel on the other ones using
fiscal
at least in their internet
uh... but so that the structures
apart from the propose
uh...
i'd probably the best thing for
these buddies similar to what swiss all
in the skies
i'd be exploring that they are more soul
employer invite stuff
but i have to be the the uh...
title of ireland
includes dozens of vicious
cause a problem with starting your own
resorts to women's
uh... everyone uses threats of people
that ended that acts
and
fire dept
quite a few moments do you do
as people are being quite pretty
sold it
anti-tank include something which is not
easy
i want to make sure that it's
not as easy to use
it's not just plug and play in
that's officious tends to be quite
consistent
but you're getting elected smells
yeah from time to time
but no not that much
but whenever i do an update
admittedly turks easy to set your own
usery's man
picked up by that
but there's that independent labs the
fingerprint