1 I'd like to introduce Greg city-states
he's going to discuss an experiment he
did how to use Evernote an informational
threats intelligent management platform
so what's the word up for a great look
right testing is this on anybody hear me
right
yeah so this is just a little experiment
that I did been working on it for about
a year now but basically trying to you
you some of the stuff that I learned at
work but try to use it for my own
purposes at home so first my typical
disclaimer so I have about 20 years in
the industry about sixteen of those have
been focused specifically in information
security in the past five years I've
been more in an operational environment
in a say in a security operation center
either helping them move to the next
level or or or at least did initially
working as an an analyst in so I in in
his part of that I also do the training
currently with instant response but as
you can see I you know done a lot of
security engineering stuff if you're
from the USS there's there's
which is a government compliance worked
proposals did trade studies you know all
the way up to what are you doing now so
I've done a lot so the things that I
want to focus on tuesday was just a
background of why why why I did this why
am I trying to use Evernote to generate
threat intelligence right so kind of the
contributing factors to that is a little
bit of dash boarding the secret weapon
does anybody here know what I'm talking
about when I say the secret weapon
ok that's good so we'll learn a little
bit about that and then also silos of
threat excellence so you know really
just taking a quick look at what threat
Intel is and is an emerging those three
things into using Evernote so to manage
all that data so that you can generate
threat intelligence to help you defend
your network in the example that I'm
going to be using its more of a focus on
you know you run a website so it's
fairly simple simple be an obvious
obviously you're gonna have scaling
issues with Evernote once you reach a
certain size but in one of the things
that i'm gonna talk about is that the
lessons learned the lessons that you
learn you trying to create something
through Evernote you can you know use
either open source or commercial
solutions to be able to scale that so
the background at least in the sector
that I work we have a huge tendency to
over complicate things we will take a
simple idea and we will try to build it
and they will go through like a whole
system development life cycle to build
this idea so you start out with
requirements and then from that you go
to go through the whole development
process in finally delivering it usually
in the end what's created isn't what
helps me it doesn't help the people that
we built this solution or the product
for in primarily that's because it's
built on requirements that were
developed like the year year and a half
back so whenever the solution finally
gets out there there there re-
quirements essentially have changed so
obviously we've
least some of the smaller groups have
transition to doing more than a job
development process but I'm more of you
know keep it simple stupid
so the whole kiss prynne printable don't
try to over complicate things you know
try to use the tools that you already
have in in in different ways so that you
can meet those specific needs to the
example that I give is is is there was a
workflow system that someone was
building for hiring new people what
happen you know they develop the
requirements for it to build this whole
thing
year and a half later you know i i went
back to the manager III had since left
but he went back to the manager and I
asked them you know how that hiring
workflow system going in in she said
that basically they know is using it you
know because they built this whole
system and it wasn't usable by the time
the system was built another principle
in kind of related to that is no build
at least try to before you buy in or you
n then bye bye that could be also
setting up a hope for a whole
development project as well use the
resources that you have in-house you
know the quick and dirty so illusions
because a lot of times you already have
the tools in in the capabilities in the
resources available but if you just
using in a slightly different way maybe
maybe focus more on Tues may not have
the exact capability that you want but
maybe set up processes to help control
that people use the tools in the right
way in the whole thing here is that
usually if you do a quick and dirty
solution it it's going to be maybe sixty
percent of what you need and that's
something that you can use now and the
best part of this is at the end of that
period
you understand what you really need so
whenever you build it first you
determine what is true
requirements are maybe that eventual
solution that quick and dirty solution
will meet your needs and you're happy
with that if it doesn't at least you
know what you really need so that you
can partner with with commercial
entities to look at solutions that are
out there or maybe develop a a whole
entire or bring in a whole development
team to to build like a fully lifecycle
solution I think the emphasis here and
in this is something that Dave Kennedy
mentioned in the keynote this morning
all
was to focus on the people I i
augmenting that somewhere you focus on
the people and end the process first to
determine what you really need because
you may not need that expenses solution
using the resources you already have
that may be good enough that quick and
dirty solution but if it doesn't then
you can go to building an entire product
worse alternative solution or partnering
with some of the different software
solutions that are out there but at
least you'll know what your gaps are
into you can pick the product that did
feel that fills those specific niches
the keys in in point was threatened tell
services and if anybody saw Chris
Nicholas instruct yesterday morning
you know one of the points that he
emphasized was was among a bunch of
other sayings was to you know bring your
threat Intel services in-house a nominee
explain why here so getting back to the
problem that I was trying to solve this
I was working as an analyst I was
looking to take advantage of this open
source in
Intel but it was very difficult because
I would have to go to like 10 sites and
search on this ip mean you could google
it and you could get some of that stuff
stuff back but what I was really looking
for was you know a repository of where
all that information is so that I can
searched in trended over over time said
the restrictions that I had this was
just sort of a solo projects so I wanted
to take all this open-source Intel and I
wanted to put it in a bucket and it had
to be you know the organization wasn't
gonna supply this for me BB because that
would be like a year-long process just
by like a server and set it up with
something so that organization wasn't
gonna provide it for me in in in like
obviously there would be no option to
build something internally so I wanted
to build my own obviously hosted
externally but I wanted something that I
could access from the inside so their
specific requirements I was looking for
was just a big bucket of that I could
just dump all this data into so things
like blog feeds or other type seeds data
driven feed so if you think of like the
shadows servers feeds that push out
indicators or Nikes on a regular basis
data files so these are those black list
that are out there so that you can you
know the black list of sites that you
shouldn't go to war
blacklisted IP zora domains than
anything else you know maybe I'm you
know some vendor put out a great threat
Intel report on on the next apt right
well you know I want to grab that and
just thrown into the system to you and
having everything into this one system
where I can do one certainly can find
everything out about that
so obviously I wanted it to be
searchable I wanted to have a way to
categorize things and I think one of the
most important things is I wanted a
tagging capability which serves as an
alternative to table of contents or
categorical as you so that you can view
data in different ways basically
creating higher keys of tags for what
you want to see anyone is something that
was cloud may speak because I'm lazy in
I didn't want to have to Lake speed up
the server and patches in nineteen it in
one thing to point out here because I've
given this presentation one other time
in in i think im I'm looking at this
from an analyst pointed years so I
worked pops up and then I want to go to
my threat until my open source thing and
I want to search for me that I P or that
string so I can find stuff out about it
which which is different from taking a
bunch of these threat Intel feeds in
Denver merging them through sticks and
taxi and stuff like that and
automatically deploying them to your
ideas
IPS is our firewalls so he was more
focused on in getting back to a Dave
said this morning it was more focused on
helping the people do their job so just
a little bit of background the dashboard
and stuff so this is basically we're
kinda wanted the seeds that started this
project up I was a sign of security
engineer several years back and I was
assigned to develop a dashboard for
executives so the method that it did I
use was I just use risk in in in in in
in the two components was vulnerability
and threat until I basically created
like a few tabs on this dashboard so
there is like an overall tab there's a
vulnerability tab and in there in there
was a
tap into I came up with some generic
data sources so that you know the
executives could get a feel for hey
what's going on out there on the
internet so there were some you know
other sources that are used there so
it's no secret but then we we also had
internal tools which I can't talk about
here
deadwood scan and give us data Lake and
Lake Lake what what patch level we were
at so combined that are two gether just
to create a nice dashboard but the one
thing that I learned from that are some
great resources these in in in this was
about five six years ago so so whenever
I left that job I really liked being
able to keep up to date so when I lest I
was able to create something better
because I was recently started using
SharePoint
so I basically took all those seeds that
I learned about and I use Google Reader
rest in peace and I with Google Reader
you could group seeds in then those
groups you could build gadgets which
would show up on your iGoogle page so
it's sort of look like that but
unfortunately he know Google Reader went
away
few months later I Google went away so I
get in there were a lot of other
solutions that we're trying to fill that
need so I went to feed liane so I kinda
used used that and that was nice but it
didn't give me that dashboard that I was
looking for
so the eventual solution that I'm
currently using today is Netvibes in in
their the paid version in a free version
and of course I'm using three version
I'm so I basically took a lot of those
lessons learned and added the feeds to
kind of create this cyber Intel
dashboard but one of the things that I
learned about dashboards was that
they're nice for you know blog post
feeds so if somebody comes out with it
with an awesome blog post and you try to
keep up with stuff so is or if its
vulnerability database that year's
subscribe to there is a lot of you know
just as long as there is a few postings
per day or a few items that appear in
ninety feet it generally works nice and
you can go and check your dashboard and
you can stay up to date with what's
going on but the data driven seeds to
these are the fields where you just get
tons of IP's coming out or I peas or
beans or whatever
in Qatar you want to use those are
changing too fast so it wasn't really
that useful in into it dawned on me like
why need something to store all that
information into I can later do analysis
on it if I wanted to now feedly in in
Netvibes both have a solution that you
can pay for that helps you you can come
to use them as a bucket service to check
that out but in the other thing is it
didn't work for periodically a plea
updated data files so if you're thinking
some some of those blacklist that it is
a single text file that you downloaded
on a regular basis Outen work well on
storing that deed but like I said one of
the you know the takeaways here is that
I identified many great resources of
information to collect ok so the secret
weapon so does everybody know getting
things done his duty does anybody use
out so its task management trust me it
it it's you know just in advance to do
there's a whole methodology behind it so
the secret weapon is essentially using
Evernote
to implement getting things done but the
key takeaways that I got from
experimenting with this and I never
really thought about it because if you
use Evernote you just think if I go to
see increased notebooks I can put notes
there Bubba Bubba but if you step back
and take a look at it
think I've ever known as a database you
know where a notebook is a table and in
note is a free-form record essentially
so following the GTD method they
basically they have the nope they have a
specific you know getting things done
notebook sort of segmented lawsuits that
it didn't you can nest notebooks so
there are you GTG stuff would disappear
in one part and not interfere with the
rest of them in a really use this
hierarchical tagging so they really when
who what when where and you could define
things Lake you know what would be
specific projects when would be the
importance from you know hey I have to
do this now for daily to stuff I have to
do now to stuff I have to do you know
maybe next week and then where do you
get home where you can also who that
task really relates to men what you can
do is you can create searches in you can
save the is so that you can look for hey
give me all the stuff I have to do today
at work and then that would just pop up
kinda into this is way this is from
their website into this is there you
know what when where who said they have
their methodology methodologies little
different but daily now next for sure
when and where then who it really late
still in then what are your projects so
when do the things with GTD is it's more
of just a framework and you can
customize it to you what what your needs
are so you know this is my method where
I you know I used 04 dealey
you know 14 stuff I gotta focus on now
to next etc and then I usually have a
separation of there's like community
things that I do things like you come to
Brookline there's stuff they do for work
and obviously and then there's a
personal stuff hey I gotta mow the grass
right in then we're so there's a similar
grouping there in then who focuses on if
if that task is something that I have to
partner with someone else on in I was
talking about how you could create
shortcuts in this is what my shortcut so
I don't have to like a fine wine and
find out what am I do what I have to do
today at home like I don't necessarily
have to build this complex worry I can
easily create this query once and I can
say save it so I can be Lake I can
select this and it'll show me all the
stuff that I have to do right now at
work
a centrist who once you set it up it's
free easy to use to you this is the
third part is the the the the third
input that led to using Evernote as a
threat intelligent management system so
over the past few years obviously we we
all know that threaten Intel market has
been growing so I started investigating
you know what is threat Intel and so
i've seen a little bit of it remained
open source perspectives and and I
worked with some of the defenders to see
what data they provide but I talked to
experts in in other folks just to get
their perspectives as well and my basic
takeaways are is that it's a very
interesting area where you're taking a
single piece of data
and you're doing a lot of math medical
transforms in all this fancy stuff rate
in just you know it's very interesting
but the but the big question is you know
how much value is it you know in in one
of my friends he basically I don't know
if I should say his name but if he
defined as he ever tweeted it then I can
just lists his street there but what he
basically said was that if during
intermission soon security and you
follow the rate people on Twitter that
you know there's really not much value
add for commercial then come commercial
threat Intel services now that's his
spurs purse perspective so I
investigation of what threat Intel was a
guy was trying to figure out why is it
not useful to us so is everyone familiar
with this sort of seen this the Pyramid
of teen by David Bianco so he basically
said you know these are all your
different indicators types in in
obviously like hash values I P domain
names now network and host artifacts
those are fairly easy to get you know
but are they like high are they
high-value medium value whatever so what
I really came to the conclusion is that
you know what Intel vendors are selling
isn't threat Intel its its threat data
in you know in in there is a good
article that probably put together a few
years back called an introduction to
savor intelligence but he references
some us' government document where they
talked about this is the Intel
intelligence lifecycle see you would do
this planning indirection collection
processing and exploitation acceptor
eg etc theoretically you take all this
day
data would suck it in and go through
this whole process and in need maybe
you'd get this this trickle of real
threat intelligence which maps to
traditional adversary TTP is so how is
this relevant anybody just a little
analogy
so I this circle represents a bottle of
the scope of the body of threat data /
Intel whatever you want to call a this
is your organization so maybe there's a
smidgen of overlap there so you're
buying this massive amount of data but
most of it is irrelevant
most of it is setting off your ideas
answers your IPS is your firewalls your
proxies for stuff that isn't even
relevant to you
ideally you would want something like
this right you you want him in a bye
this threat Intel in in its going to be
mostly relevant to us into this is where
Chris nigger since yesterday morning was
that you know when you're dealing with
threat Intel it's definitely to take it
in-house first so just quickly defining
what threat Intel is over the different
buckets so we just have open source
Intel think we all know what that is so
there is information sharing so its data
is your your join mailing lists or
bulletin boards or whatever and you can
share in meeting their blog collection
is huge so you know most people are
familiar with the log are you being able
to have this data available so that you
can search retro actively having a sim
of some some sort to both you make sense
of that lagdi as well as pulling all
your
alerts and be able to correlate them
together for stuff CFD investigate then
lastly you know something that people
don't focus too much on his case
tracking you know coming up with a case
management system so that you can have a
history of all the cases that you've
worked on in city you can go back and
look through that so this is where ever
know finally comes in so I basically you
know came in a look at the experiences
that I did dash boarding I mean look at
what I learned from implementing the
secret weapon thing right then i'ma take
what I learned about three intel and I
just want to push that all in in in use
Evernote as as my threat intelligence
management system to you can define
notebooks and hire key tags you can this
is perfect is it open and flexible rate
too if you want to change it almost
anybody can just go and change it you
could have the manager in team that you
don't have a you don't need a whole team
to manage your remedy solution and it's
easy to use over the heavy database /
workflow management systems and it's
really simple you just like take all the
stuff that you have any set up some
automation and you start dumping stuff
into it like you don't really really
don't don't care the most important
thing is to the dump it into one place
so that as an analyst I can go in search
it later so it's just where I focused
most of my time was on trying to pull in
open source Intel so just in archive
that in organization could search so
like I said earlier earlier
alert pops you get something off at like
an IP domain whatever you can search
through this repository that you have
the benefits is you know you can search
this and you can pivot around and you
can also do in adhesion so although
maybe these notes got created
automatically you can really going in
right stuff like oh this is this is not
a good entry door this you kind of have
a history and you can document what your
whole the value of that particular in
indicator so you can do you can dump get
your day
data in through fields in a little bit
of automation and the other thing too is
if you come across some some the cool on
the web I can just there's browser
plug-ins or I can just click that and
ban because Austin I ever knew
threat Intel database and then lastly
you need a recommended tagging structure
so I don't want to go to like you're
taking structure to be to pursue
scripted but just kind of the framework
essentially too far to follow and that's
what the secret weapon gave me so from
OS from an OS in person perspective
these these are some of the things that
I started out so I'm still using that
same trying to evaluate what my risk is
through you know having certain threats
seeds invulnerability feeds and also see
situational awareness feeds so these
could be just you know this particular
threat precede or the ISE blog or or
just like a new site related to security
so this you find something and it
happened like two months back you can
actually go back and say well what was
in a news wise what was going on around
that time so we can give you better
context so this is essentially what it
look look like
so I have as you can tell so using the
the hue so these are the sources in then
some of these sources have multiple
feeds in in in the fields are
essentially here so but the question is
how do I get all this data into ever
knew so first of all Evernote gives you
an email that you can look like a
randomized thing and so you could sign
up for whatever just using that email
although I wouldn't recommend it because
that email service we kept secret to
tell you wouldn't do that I think a
better method is used if this then that
great is every familiar with that i mean
just awesome tour it's easy to implement
from an RSS perspective you are limited
because usually you know news articles
or whatever you're only gonna get part
of it so you could you know teen tied up
in red a little scraper or there's a
tool in inexpensive tool called five
filter that that I found that you could
set up and it basically turns your
partial feeds into full content feeds
obviously so if then using this with
Twitter so there's a lot of Twitter
bites out there that are connected to
honey pots and you can just watch them
tweetIn suck that data in creating a new
note for every tweet and email
immigration especially like in my case I
use Gmail so I basically put a rule
there saying hey if anybody if I get an
email where the subject is this or from
this person or whatever you know store
copy of that Internet ever knew there is
a storm stack which is having used it
personally but has been recommended to
me is sort of an open source clone of if
this then that but lastly there's going
to have to be some scripts cuz every if
then if this then that only takes you so
far so you're gonna maybe have some
scripts especially for
those black list files that I was
talking about there's there doesn't seem
to be a good way to bring those in yet
so so for those that haven't had never
seen if if this then that but it's
basically you come up with the recipe
title in here I was importing the SSH
brute which is a Twitter guy that
Twitter bot that collects brute force
attempts against SSH
so I basically say hey a new tweet by
this user in then you can use these
reasons reserve tags like username and
text you know put it in the title in the
end the body you can put whatever I say
the notebook that I want to put in and
then these tags in India's little
symbols before the tags and essentially
those are that's something that the
secret weapon recommend so you don't
have to use those tags that they're
essentially like preserved like Special
Reserve tags and their related to the
who what when where things in this was a
little script that I'm on the new
hackers email list if anybody does so I
i live radio in the in the Dec
area in one of the groups there are the
Nova hackers which have been part of for
the past several years so I try what I
was trying to do was pull a one it is
black list files in an email to myself
so this is just a simple script that I
wrote a mere route a little script as
I'm not have included in like 15 years
but it but then I knew enough or I wind
coming clean it up some in in gaudy to
do what I wanted it so it essentially
goes it goes out there in this case it's
looking at for the malware domains in it
checks it has its cease if the house has
changed since the previous time that he
downloaded it if it's if it's changed
then it sends it often ever knew
and saves the new house if if it hasn't
changed then then it just logged in news
on just just set up with a simple
current script but one of the big things
is you know why did the research for a
lot of the focus has been on open source
data in Intel but some other aspects
that I talked about so we talked about
information sharing this could be
something as simple as just shared
notebook so in Evernote I can create a
notebook and I can just share it out
with my partners and then whenever we
come across something interesting we
just posted a new note it's just a note
so they you can go in there and had to
add comments about it so it's very
simple system so there is logged
collection although you know it
definitely wouldn't work on huge huge
enterprise at least for my cases I just
had my web server logs and I'm like Oh
heyy wanna go through a web server logs
and so I basically said all right I'll
go through and I wrote a little script
that disperses out the web server server
logs for that particular day and it runs
each night and it sends it off to
Evernote so now I have that log
information available using it as a sim
so not true sim by more last there are
specific things and i'm looking for like
hey are people trying to brute-force log
into my wordpress site where are the has
have any files teen star on within the
CMS
director insiders' if you kind of custom
things that I root for that and before I
would get emails about it but it
wouldn't necessarily do anything with it
but what I what I did was I changed it
to push it to a sim notebook so that at
least I had kind of one place where I
could see all the alert and do more
training and then from there I could go
back to my logs rain in in see what was
going on to a nice little quick way to
to do analysis in the other thing is I
guess so there is four inputs that a
focus on but there's also some analysis
aspects of that to you so really case
tracking rate so this could just be a
notebook rate its case tracking notebook
and then you could have tags for open
working closed into it and you could
create custom searches for a show me are
the cases the working cases the closer
you know in it and if you don't like
these three categories you just come up
with a new one
hey there is there is in review rate in
me not something that's fairly easy that
anyone could just add so some other
ideas is you could create a notebook for
your indicator database so the true
things that you find that are focused on
me like if you're focusing on advanced
tax rate in in in in in basically from
that maybe you could drive like a
campaign database Navy from that you
could drive an adversary database
essentially which is a collection of
everything associated with a certain
adversary which essentially are the
teepees which is that top tier in the
pyramid so how do you find all this so
we talked about it we have tags there is
a basic search so you can go in and just
search on certain key words there is
advancers so I can say really go in I
can specify certain notebooks tags terms
in that as well as dates and move in
most of these searches are by default
they do and Boolean search so example is
i search for like I get an alert in my
sim it says hey this my keys turn to log
in in in we locked in now
so then maybe I go into my log my a
larger file and I i can look for some
some stuff there but in doing this
search maybe I find a note about this IP
from OS into that need maybe from like a
month ago so then I can search like RA
that was a month ago between estate in
that date will let me see you know what
it what else was going on during that
time so I can use this search date
ranges to go in industry specify those
date ranges and see what new indicators
popped up from the open source
intelligence sources or or just
situational awareness tough news and
stuff that was going on you know did new
vulnerabilities come out
exploits come out things like that so
then what this has evolved into
essentially is obviously this isn't
gonna scales her in enterprise but it
was really like what I was talking about
initially we're doing the quick and
dirty first to find out what your needs
are into basically came up in in in I
guess these could be your requirements
where you could come up with like it
a metadata framework hey these are the
tags that I want to use to using the the
the secret weapon categories of you know
when what when where he and then you
have your different notebooks here and
then you basically come come up with a
tagging hierarchy of how you want to use
that in in you can see like define you
know when is maybe like priority
confidence word is your data types
where's your workflow worse or state and
then lastly it in this is some of the
other ideas that I threw into where
you're talking about doing the same
thing except for you know case tracking
indicator database adversary database
whatever
in one of the things to you is only like
you don't wanna spend a horrendous amana
time just like all that automatic data
that is that in like you don't want to
really spend an enormous amount of time
going back in time taking things that's
all you would we do but the whole
philosophy is only target if it's
irrelevant meaning most other cases
you're just gonna do this search and
you'd find stuff that way in the new
thing here is these
announces change you can use like a
these this what column here to cross
reference so you could cross reference
like an adversary to specific indicators
two cases to open source in Intel you
know maybe you got it from Intel sharing
say maybe it's related to a specific
words eg exit row so you can you come up
you know basically search do a search on
one tag and come up with everything you
know about that particular person now
these last you I haven't I don't have
any need for that but just from what
I've seen people do around industry
that's how you could use it but the
thing is you could use this medicine
structure to you know do you like may be
implemented in spunk do help stack that
that that seems like the big thing now
you could start this data into seems you
could use wikis meaning you can use
WordPress where categories like a
notebook but but in a blog post is is a
note you could use SharePoint or or even
something as like just a shared filed
posit Tory with lake with newt died
documents just anything because a lot of
people are doing nothing right in at
least if you can start out doing
something to determine what you need and
you can use that to those statistics and
those trends to
ask for what you need from executive
management but essentially we did we
just need a bucket that can suck in day
Dr supports tagging in allows me to
search their it and I got a simple Intel
management system so distant future
ideas that I'm having most of this is
really focused on you know trying to do
more interesting things with some of the
OS in stuff through scripting and stuff
to automate it some interesting ideas
are just doing some API automations you
could create an app that basically goes
into Evernote and does maybe it looks
for IP's in then it would not attack
those as an example she do cool stuff
like that where there's a lot of
third-party apps lake there's a diary
operate in the diary app is it basically
uses ever needed as its back in database
so you could come up with maybe like a
third party app they would look like
maybe like an incident response to all
but it would just be using every
afternoon as the back in so in the
conclusion you know when that one of the
things is you know there's lots of clean
solutions that are out there but one of
the big things I see is that there's no
central place like me to get on that day
data into one central place and then you
also need to figure out how to organize
it so really you know starting out with
ever ever known as your quick and dirty
you know maybe it will meet your needs
if you're a small group you know like 10
folks maybe that will meet your your
needs or maybe you're a huge
enter enterprise at least it gives you a
starting point to determine what you can
do internally first find where your gaps
are in then thats whenever you go out
and maybe try to partner with year
threat intelligence provider so you use
that information to fill those gaps in
getting back to that that that example
that I gave where they went out and
built this is hiring system in nobody
used it so I went back like a year later
and I'm talking to me
manager now I'm like hey whats how the
house the hiring system going into
basically said I treated it into this is
like a senior manager per person can
make you created it so then she showed
me and she basically just there was a
shared drive
she basically just created a hiring full
folder and had a folder for each one of
her workflow steps in as a candidate
would proves he threw she would just
move it on so I just want to give a huge
thanks to brew kind of had an awesome
time here so thanks for having me guys
you can reach me on twitter
graphics my personal blog is Nova
intersect dot com in there there's a
Twitter for that to you if you wanna
contact me this is that form but if you
really want to contact me directly it's
just cracks at Nova InfoSec dot com so
easily upload these slides to the side
chair or whatever and I don't know whose
screen scraping those but it but that's
all they don't have any questions
just struck me along the way of course
we started out with quicken the DEA and
keeping it simple
yeah yeah but this is gonna cost you an
awful lot of time this year looks you've
built an awesome tool set and it's
getting pretty complex yet can you
really say it is quick and dirty or
simple anymore I think yeah I mean
that's a good good question I mean ed is
a fairly complex system but you know
it's it's really just me doing it where
if you were implementing like a real
solution or if you were to purchase a
product to do this you would be talking
huge amounts of resources so it's all
relative in the nice thing is you know
I've created this for you take it do it
you don't have to recreate the wheel so
you know take my lessons learned in
create your own thing and it does not to
be an Evernote to be in your local Elks
tack in spelunker whatever you know so
any other questions and you know
their first of all I love the talk when
I was previously working for a well
known as inventor I tried to drive a
project almost exactly like this so I
like it thinks your data formats like
like your stick stuff I saw as a site
yeah yeah how do you integrate those
data points
well that's a future that's an area that
I would incorporate having really
investigated that too deep yet
like there's tools Lake see if I've
looked at and there's another one
blanking on the name right now but it's
for managing indicators but it's what's
there's another tool out there that has
about a hundred open-source Intel feeds
in its by the folks that do bro can't
remember the name it but I played around
with that i mean that's like you you
could definitely sucked out in in in in
in at least conceptually I know I know
that I could suck it in and do that I
guess I have to figure out you know is
that can help me because a lot of this
the XML structured data as an analyst at
me help me help me it may not use it it
doesn't all that data doesn't give give
me context as an analyst that's
investigating in Internet I think this
sticks in the taxi in there is another
acronym I think it's great for you know
you have this threat Intel feed-in you
can merge everything together and
automatically put it out to your ideas
for your IPS systems the only problem
that I like if I was running the network
I would have an issue with that because
I would like I don't just want to take
this deed and is dumped stocks out there
but i guess im looking at it is more
like it we we couldn't incorporate that
in there at least it could be done but I
I don't necessarily see a reason for it
but like I said it is something that i'm
looking at using the tools like six in
in in a few other other ones that I
mentioned the other thing that you can
incorporate which I didn't even mention
rate so once you go through this whole
process he needs figure out where your
Intel gaps are that's when you bring in
the commercial lenders in in you say hey
these are my gaps can can you fill those
gaps in then you can be using Evernote
but then you can take their threat Intel
feeds company into Evernote hours longer
whatever to fill those gaps
following question I'm sorry for holding
the mic it seems like you've built a
really critical business function around
and ask president yeah yeah you know
never know just like guilt would kill a
450 positions last week I see the value
proposition but I would feel much better
with an on-trend I agree rate this gets
back to the quick and dirty rate hey I'm
gonna figure out what I need you know
develop this whole structure so they're
now when I want to build when it when it
when I go to a certain size that I want
to build my internal system I I already
have a framework that i'm gonna build it
from in a can help me choose the raid
product that is going to help me because
I know the type of data that I need and
then I'm gonna put into the system but
yeah I totally agree for huge enterprise
don't use Evernote used you use
SharePoint and questioned over there
just a quick question so you put in a
lot of data we have not touched on the
kind of quality of dating called in
Alice's you have any tips tricks
whatever lessons learned about you know
managing quality of your throat until
like some of that is degrading
instructor is probably more important
you know how do you manage quality you
have a good lessons I think I mean my
philosophy is at least initially I don't
care about quality just give me the data
right on lemme store it right eye candy
determine if it's good or not
later when I'm investigating an incident
and i can see you like overlook this
this piece of this indicator that I got
from this feed is relevant in this is
great so then I can go back and use
theirs Italian structure for quality
there so I can say oh this is high
quality medium quality low but by
default it's just assumed low but in the
end you could trend that over time in in
see well on the cases that were
investigating you know we tend to be
using this feed more and it's relevant
to us so you could train that over time
and use that to maybe wait you know this
feed more than more than that feed ya
quality is hard
the best quality personally I think is
going to be like if you have is going to
be internally generated data so if
you're like many parts or whatever I
mean that's gonna be really relevant but
the thing is is this gets you started so
that you can stop and eventually get
towards building an indicator dade
database that that's really row relevant
to view your specific organization that
he answers your question but yeah so
it's there is no its work is is what it
is right there's no there there is no
easy solution for it you you gotta put
in hours and I mean that's what Dave
Kennedy was talking about this morning
where it comes back to appeal to people
like you can buy all these tools and you
can set them up you know no one is using
them no one's monitoring them you know
it comes back to the people that are
using those tools to do their job so any
other questions so all these feeds the
problem is you're not really getting a
lot of good contacts from these seats so
I'm gonna give you ideas to gonna give
me stuff but if you look at like the
permanent stain on the top of that is
your DVDs
exactly where the teepees that they use
if you have in your environment you see
particular things happening that you
associate with a particular threat actor
ya already have intelligence not just
like difference here scattered over the
place but if you see this along with
this then you can combine it into say
okay we need to look at this moment and
where that comes into effect is with the
analysis of that threat intelligence
which is like the best ways that I've
seen it on is basically it's like
everyone has value in this arena
you're looking at you have a bunch of
intelligence from incidents were you
seen this type of actors build a true
data base which links indicators
together and intelligent way to say ok
this IP strongly associated with this
actor of this is exactly like the
adversity that your dog made basically
in that what building that you never
know what I think could be a little bit
tricky I so I just wanted to make it
clear to people that say this is good
for open source intelligence and get you
so far but if you really wanna know
what's happening in your environment eg
only with like a serious threat since
you could have difficulties building
they correct intelligence on it
yeah yeah I mean I agree I think part of
it is I don't know if I kept this ride
but like there's a lot of stuff in your
organization that's going on in the big
problem like open source in 2009 it take
you so so far but you know there's like
your case tracking system there's your
internal logs ideally you would be like
year you have to do the work and put in
the analysis time using the information
that is at least at this point is
centralized so that you can go up to the
top of the stack in bill does TDP so it
could be done I think you know this is
only ever know I'm not suggesting if if
you don't have nothing ever know it's a
great place to start wearing what you
need right eventually you're going
through this process you're going to
determine where your true requirements
are and that can help you buy the rate
enterprise solutions but this is just a
way to start out for people that are
doing nothing right to still so they to
give that you know this whole this whole
thing started with me as an analyst
trying to understand lake in alert pops
and I basically have nothing nowhere to
go
rate at least you know using something
like this can can help me at least give
me some data points that maybe I can get
off can bring me back but
you know currently if you don't have
anything I think this is great great way
to get started so I think amount of time
so anyway thank you thanks once again