I like to welcome the next year's
figures in russia they have a combined
experience for more than 10 years in
ninety security and they're going to
talk about invisibility and how to
handle that I like to give a warm
welcome to and I should be done
address has a society that lets me be
more confusion that there was a MAC
address see MAC address there was no
society to idealize there wasn't a
society for other devices are
approaching so I have been attacked yes
but and this is the current state of
WiFi open wifi nowadays we we are here
to propose an approach proposed fee
approaches that could reveal the
communication that I actually experience
today let's get into some technical
details on this party is interaction
some details that have already good
communication the approaches that we are
presenting and euphoria in this approach
we are actually doing some dinner
trafficking into some frames actually
sending on to some data which are
actually expect that did I will be
sitting as we all nodded I sitting in
the payload but there are other ways
some very can certainly does the next
episode with the patch peloton approach
will be using there are many things that
we have known during this experience and
during this discussion I would say and
we are still learning and we will be
still working on some potential
approaches there are few other
approaches as well but they are not
considered that intrusions and
acknowledgement that right I mean people
they might be like light infantry or I
mean you might not be able to stand for
this was a couple of years back we
started this explosion and but later on
we got to lose you got things sorted out
things are falling in place and then we
were able to say yes so now we are like
what we just don't trust me loads the
data reflecting using some of the
freemen because we'll be discussing be
able to that the story behind
the story behind all of this is like
there are few and enjoy pieces in the
book that is ideally 80 do not levin
which is a good book
gradebook 6,000 pages book read it but
they they have closed everything in that
they have suggested of any legitimate
and very but they are unwittingly helped
you entered disclosing few things they
have to disclosing who feels like that
that can be otherwise used and less
access access points are used as a drug
dealer and they can be connected to
people whose for sending out and can be
used when connected access point to
access point and from the internet and
by that would not sufficient I know
the basics
my father very famous either side of my
reaction was like even open my files are
more prone to attacks on rebel and yes
they are like nowadays we need to do we
need approved to call me maybe may not
be so there's a hole in the network
parameter wub
this is two thousand and right now we
need a couple of minutes now most of the
industry's don't use this past bad
connotations admin admin admin password
password password so this is finds
eavesdropping and social identity
and connectivity myself the these are
all things that are adding to my device
these are a few more victims like mobile
phones cameras printers gaming consoles
laptops desktops are denied and the data
right now today I see us that is also
more prone to be a meeting its rotation
that can be used like managed management
interface card access station and I
don't think also a form of managed mode
can be used and that is a valid question
master mode that I feel relations in
this case that will come back to this
point leader on this morning monitor
mode choose everything seen my radio
me and 400 the communication guide you
through this information in their career
of information security of say that like
what actually occasion is in competition
greedy ordinarily the type of computer
security attack that cleared the ability
to transfer information objects between
processes that not supposed to be
allowed to communicate by the computer
security policy making it more simple
ways to smoke later on to any chance we
can see also markets really basically
deals with candles which are poured into
wireless so using various less
individuals in this particular dog will
be dealing more with battling clear yeah
I mean if we go through the application
layer of different types of registry can
implement in order to reach in order to
achieve greatness as communication is
concerned i mean basically be concerned
brought before giving me some
understanding on the 11th green slick
Wireless trains and the types so there
are basically management dreams Controls
Engineer defense so management firms and
the state few of them here like
Association requests and responses
Association be questioned response probe
request and response beacon frames so on
and so forth there are actually blood or
officers friendship but our interest
thing that we tried experiment that was
upon request and response and beacons
going for ya this is just a formality as
you mentioned like management control
and disseminating them here so it is
like dreams ideas thanks for the
question saying that for clear loser is
he gave his fall so on and so very
differently I don't know this is not so
let's go to the question approach that
was proposed to achieve a rather to
smuggle a doubt over alleged emailed
wireless channel the name of their
double period as alcohol and there's
actually have brought this time from
escaping terminology available use a
particular field or other particular
caste record or 11 be sure that actually
enforce to informational email to
confirm is essential element in the
wireless networks yes be confirmed
popular with the rate of around 100
milliseconds around permanent we receive
680 confirms number available to local
radio para free to their broadcast yeah
that is I don't want ages with us and
they do not require any other indication
or association that access point to
listen to them so basic structure of the
country music here we can see out of
there as of now we will be focusing more
on to this parameter stands for traffic
conditions rail companies
Wikipedia this actually does like how
access point is advertising beacon frame
so when 2011 began frame is injected
into the local paper rewarding does it
actually is a broadcast receiver address
its gonna be on FB and they will be in a
society which would be a big impression
that all of us know about me confirm
right there are certain parameters as
well which can be used in order to
traffic data within a society broken so
here we have connected to their device
so and some cash for overlap this
particular society is so tomorrow I
figured maybe another hotel let's call
it is in the hotel and then I just
started my wireless feature finds that
is like just to see like in past I was
gonna do go on as a network is that
network available into this is a global
video predatory
check that it went into exile and
friends of friends and nothing but prob
requests and if these requests received
legitimate response then there is the
difference between beacon frame and
request response as far as farmers is
concerned it's only couple of
fields are actually some type of 0
exercise in Castle Rock requested is a
real difference i think thats elaborate
about robert Winston response so how do
these friends and in the fields which
have been a lens in order to ship data
so going further like certain people
certain piece of information that's hard
when somebody some different properties
of that particular wireless network
interface cards concern into that
context so interesting elements like
this particular information element has
255 256 different variants according to
the IWW
been released in late 2006 possibilities
of information as of now there are a
hundred and twenty-one information
elements practice out of them we have a
couple of them for experimentation so
some other interesting elements we have
israeli areas and societies Transport
Service said identifier NBS said kind of
against use BR em strong indication
rates
again different parameter recently we
found some juicy about this as well and
country yes again this particularly
important for Public leadership over
legitimate chance so we began our
programs these dreams they do not
require authentication or association
himself being broadcast so no need 20
post-election like we need new york
pinpoint one particular host in order to
run and how did you know that would have
been a test case we have to take in
consideration
just busting our presence of these range
in my local monastery very common and
escaped the specialized in the issue
there would be some reading devices
there would be some monitoring devices
so instead of 600 there might be some
6,000 begin french President per second
but activity will be logged in case of
reading devices for that matter again so
they are pretty much
just to mention what we will be taking
into consideration that is why I am
indication so if we bring down to
business again we will see that there is
a particular field called partial
fortune but my this is the field which
allows you should data between 12 51
bytes which otherwise is used when your
card is in sleep mode Saudi I am
relieved with easy to fabricate the
freemen's AP but this information so I
just have repaired one probe request was
basically because I like three min
escapee
freedom was getting prepared on my
machine was getting into preterm icon
but it was not as keeping my machine
somehow I was unable to broadcast that
particular reason I have taken another
request and experimented same thing if
you see here
this right which otherwise is not
drafted or automatically using your
drivers who may be using it and if we
see the translation of particular we can
see some meaningful texts so I have
actually died right some script which
was very well walking four blocks this
is a new book I'm sorry this is a bad
idea right so I have actually important
everything from skipping ordered to
undergo a pipeline and why I put my
network interface cards my country and
destination MAC address yeah I kept it
publicly broadcast because it is a
problem question it has to be released
every network interface card every
intelligent wireless network device
presented to the local radio then
society I have certain parameters here
for a society that is not eleven idea is
a society and information this is
nothing but the name of a society is so
far I have again prepared
another construct and I dislike
available so here we have put in ideas 8
p.m. there is nothing but the name of
information in for a just and then I
have these particular construction over
each other in order to get out of here
this is the frame I cried when I try to
run this I don't know it is giving me
some including just have come across so
I could not rectifier but earlier with
some certain pics maybe if we can make
it run properly in order to ship this
particular date as far as I know I am
using certain by John actually Russian
Court here are intended over there would
be requiring some some workaround for
that let you know how this particular
rushing toward will be greeted by with
them like I actually will be lining or
maybe we need to find the wireless
driver for the quarter can produce some
good output and maybe she'll so this is
what we've been trying to achieve but
this is why we have made it work so the
reason we can see this screen capture
issues with this approach yeah
if somebody's going to deep packet
inspection firewall there will be
suspicious alarm generated for this
because we are shipping a lot of data
into some element which otherwise is not
supposed to send such a huge chunk of
data regarding the data is not taken
care of before showing in the data I
have to like he is very well but if my
decides is beyond Boothby by the issue
we have
just because it's supposed to be sent
for a particular Communication which is
already been initiated so this will not
actually helping case of broadcasting
attacks against it to act responsibly
ames significance to reply to Chardon
communication initiated by the remote
host earlier so we are in some comfort
zone we know there is some communication
initiated there is already some
information exchange happened so now can
we ride certainly over these extremely
responsive aims to the press is already
in place between two hosts responses by
unsolicited user will receive legal low
priority of inspection as it as it has
assumed that such responses about the
gun from a legend shows on peripheral
devices I think this approach with the
euphoria will give solution to the
sequencing issue why just because
already there is some sort of activity
done so to have this particular activity
there is some sequential mechanism
already in place so we need not reach in
Wendover he relied airborne logic in
order to generate that quenching
mechanism response to africa is always
made more intelligent as there are
capable of as they are capable of
designing segments
undisciplined traffic as I have just
explained you could come handy are more
more fragments sequence numbers
basically is an essential source address
so what actually really is like we have
included in the data and should be over
trip to Dover and ECG response against
it before doing that and coordinate W
certain logic and lodging and murdered
and pre shared with the user in the
parameter so you will use the idea
parameter thing and then we have shipped
over this secret was already pre shared
with other party and then we have a
special acknowledgment this may actually
we are actually going into the call
stack we are changing certain things so
this may not always abide by the rules
which are produced when do I W dot 11
standards there might be some diversion
and yes we did so resulting in more
organ immune more control over their yes
that is possible just because we are
ordering almost everything that is
needed to make a conduit issues yes we
still may be facing issues from animal
detection based firewalls can see the
last friends are still an issue again
this year but as far as lost limbs are
concerned there is actually no clue that
there is something which means sent from
those people whose be so how do how do
make it to husband have no mechanism to
gather this intelligence hands all began
with actually they'll host a key I'm
getting this award because I did not
receive the stream so this thing is
still missing
so the Proteas
upon them
there are certain more fields we have
been considering hiring show is the
things he had not occurred in fact what
we are doing yet we are doing that
initially what we are trying to patch
drivers so what we found your visibility
in there this approach fairly medicare's
the issues we have confronted in the
previous approaches having this it is
truly covered conduits are doubtful
securing the communication of the year
before we proceed further this
particular don't approach is actually
inspired by the work of art and beauty
he's researcher in 2006 black hard BC he
have actually produce research on seem
covert channel and covert communication
we have used rubber backing itself with
the battery does he use for driver
budging read different and the back but
does that very using for everybody here
are different
truly speaking July just having I just
am having is mentioned in the stock
because I actually my inspiration
basically in this so the best guess we
should we have the highest and best when
this is done we have prepared to host to
one post is having a rather these two
horse having bashed drivers we have used
Unix machines because these things were
more on Unix machines having known and
things like that
Windows machines also we have used in
order to check whether to go for
drafting the group trying to do
using this fashion drivers with their
dad is predictable and badge machines as
well or scanning stuff so what we've
done is likely have raised an access
point on one Linux machine bar dining on
March two more with having the patch
drivers and apple on it
the machines with and bash brothers will
not be able to see the engineer traffic
the machines with bad drivers will be
able to communicate reader devices
having somebody having symbol of
cardstock so for the detailing do this
work we actually tried to patch it was
like for for allegedly might reconsider
that is one reason like analogously
India so I figured if we see like it and
I'll be back in there are you wouldn't I
mean who had enjoyed since he'll be
considered it is either 406
same time if we consider into the
wireless so far back what we try to do
is likely have changed that hand crafted
with Virgin feelers been otherwise will
be dropped by those all posts which are
not actually having a patch driver
wedding kids of each driver this
particular frame may be interpreted by
colonel and will be friends for the
appropriate process so the deductions
from abroad are engineered by country
access points with passion for the call
stack and ordered by the devices having
a bash protocols either
probes conducted by devices with
back-to-back on stacks whereby the
devices with unpatched version of
protocol stacks the first gave little
variation in there we have received from
Benjamin sometimes we have experienced a
lot of driver we have experienced a lot
of crashes when we are still facing that
thing actually as right now we are
running majority of Linux
so this experimentation on basically
done on gonna do point six
the Starbucks postcard that
implementations feeling somehow so I
could not produce the good thing is
pretty much what are we really don't so
we can see in some cases devices with
unprofor the call stack were not able to
staff engineer trafficker dog and
sometimes give it to your advantage here
in in-house solutions or maybe getting
majority of attacks in wireless
infrastructure partial occurrence of
event horizon in wireless networks is
very much achievable using this approach
yeah because we are sending certainly
damage is only viewable by certain
candles or rather incredible by certain
drivers which abolished so sometimes I
feel like I'm training data from me to
see if she's trying to bridge back from
Wednesday's eliminated this would be
because most be so you will always
receive certain I see me back to who's
this actually if we will bring back this
business actually require a lot of
credit we just need to run the patch on
to our driver when she moves mood so
requires no great deal of changes in
operating moments of the past
drivers no cost low effort solution
would say is this thing working with
Kleenex boxes northern the windows we
are yet to do these things when Windows
boxes so what we're learning all the
time relying upon skippy for injection
poppers for graphing purpose but it's
been some like building streams in
skimpy use mirrors
do certain output which are like totally
absurd and that will actually language
just takes a lot of input from various
social and casual 4.6 retardant certain
resources from operating system as well
so it's not it's not your driver you
supposed to bad we need to take care of
certain resources from operating system
as well so that is actually from
compiling the shooting properly 24 point
X yeah so far as I know like there are
several different requests and responses
agencies including commission element
we've come across regional game capable
of data to identify that PPC request and
response are capable of more than 200
bytes again we have testing PCB BBC the
responses but we do not request properly
yesterday only I was able to find the
country the name of this particular
information element I D is country this
again is capable of Sebring to physics
by two so this can again be explored in
a proper way in order 20 or other
smuggled a dog over alleged change so as
early as well agree have explored only
watching really
diverging there are many movies yeah
there was a question why specifically
version feel we have picked up it was
just because that was the constant for
you we have used but apart from that
there are many of the field as well like
there are certain fields which are lying
around the park management sergeant
enjoying the rain controls against
doctors its he is so these field also
will actually help us coming of it some
different type of general yes an
interesting area so far my ps3 ps4
boyfriend because eventually like we are
born in particular device would actually
inheriting certain before date and then
chipping it over again so instead I'm
waiting for the device to wake up and
ended up over as my board beta I can
really will orbit organized better
border with my desired in the morning we
are doing this BS
framework we are so conclusion wireless
networks have a different way of
securing as well by Meena streaming
coverage any approaches we have proposed
I still in development so far which with
the help of my new
outcomes as a gift idea like in that
particular topic indication my eye I put
her down and make it readable by my
country so then I'm actually running
kind of a book on to various devices and
then just a matter of that age internal
mechanism or an algorithm in order to
have the mall operator dinner probably
yes
approaches we have proposed are still in
development or repeating this
acknowledgements I have been following
closely the league ledger given by Rick
Ramachandran he has actually is called
wireless security makeup primer so basic
understanding I have gained from his
prime as far as reams and packages
concern Josh right for his blog will
hack for sushi helping a large regarding
Skibbe scripts are new Google in 2004
hosting situation nice
bad allowing me to present rather
allowing us to present over here thank
you very much for your patience and
listening to my daughter if you have any
question I'll be glad to answer them