hi everyone so it's really great to be a
book on our talk to these about the
research we've been doing into DNS from
both sides below the recursive been
above the recursive and how we developed
a unified view of the units traffic to
track Internet threats so I'm the
technical leader senior security
researcher at OpenDNS so my focus is on
graph algorithms and how to apply them
in our kind of massive amount of data to
extract patterns and detect threats my
name is Thomas Matthew I'm a security
researcher at OpenDNS my background is
in machine learning and kinda time
series analysis and the outline in a
nutshell would be something like this so
we'll start with an overview of OpenDNS
is kind of global view and the type of
traffic we will deal with and then we'll
kind of cover the threat landscape that
we are focusing on are focusing on and
then we'll talk about the actual methods
of traffic analysis and then we'll
discuss some very interesting results
that I hope you will like and then we'll
also look at another major part of the
this research which is studying the
hosting infrastructures of these kind of
malicious domains that we catch with
traffic analysis methods and then we'll
have a conclusion and will open it up
for questions so this is kind of the
worldwide map of our resolver so we have
25 data centers with a hundred-plus
recursive resolvers on five continents
and that allows us to see a lot of
traffic and it's very useful to kind of
see have a good perspective into what's
happening on the internet and the DNS
traffic with the away there's actually
off two types so opened both recursive
as well as authoritative DNS traffic and
dennis is the protocol that helps us map
a domain name to tonight
p and authority to traffic is kind of
the global repository of all the
official mappings between a domain name
and IP and then the recursive traffic
refers to an individual clients DNS
query and then a recursive resolver in
this case opened in years then goes to
the authoritative server and fetches
back the record so these are two
distinct types of data traffic there
were dealing with when it comes to DNS
traffic in both these are extremely
valuable so having said that let's take
a look at the threat landscape that we
are trying to cover here so if we're
talking about cybercrime were kind of
malware that is trying to with which the
bad guys are trying to kind of make
money
financially motivated cyber crime so
usually are you trying to infect as many
machines as possible with a variety of
malware kind of kind of pieces so could
be equipped or an somewhere a banking
Trojan all kinds of about $40 at fraud
or like something software to force you
to kind of call a hotline and you know
they money to fix your computer so all
of these attacks or all of these malware
to get in planning on your box I usually
the they are delivered via what we call
that exploit kids and to end up on the
exploit kit and drop the malware you'll
have to go through another earlier stage
which is visiting like a popular
compromise site for like an advertising
campaign and sometimes you will be sent
like a phishing spam email where they
ask you to open up an attachment
like some of the Walmart or UPS alerts
and if you click on it and open it up
then you get the malware dropped on your
on your machine so our focus in this
research is to kind of the TechEd the
patterns that are typical of exploit kit
lens intimates and will show how if you
analyze DNS you can be very successful
in kind of point zero in on on those
type of types of attacks so before we
talk about some of the methods it's
useful though
talk about the scale of data that we're
working with because I'll put the
methods into perspective so we see about
seventy billion DNS queries per day and
so that translates in about half a
terabyte of data per hour that needs to
be processed furthermore if you just
took the sample of our authoritative
data and Canada transformed into a
relational graph would have around 46
million nodes as well as a hundred and
seventy four million edges between those
notes and the net and the nodes
represent a domain IP peering and edges
represent some sort of relationship
between nodes so with this amount but
this many kind of nodes it's really an
example of a needle in a haystack type
problem because it's just far too many
notes for an individual or even a group
of analysts to quickly identify a
potential malicious domain and that's
what we do develop some automated
techniques exactly so the challenge here
is to have automated methods that can be
scalable and efficient at the same time
so let's take a look at some of these
DNS traffic analysis techniques so the
classic
Dina stated that people are familiar
with working with is called
authoritative data and I'm sure some of
you have heard of passive DNS data bases
in a passive DNS data bases use
authoritative data authoritative DNS
data is a historical kind of mapping of
a domain to IP pairing so for example I
could see all of the IP's at google.com
has mapped to but the last one year if
I'm keeping track of all my
authoritative data so it's really useful
for a historical view of domains kind of
IP history as a result this is this type
of data is extremely helpful in catching
three types of domain we have some
badness the first is what's called a
fast flux two main fast flux domain is a
domain that continually changes its IP
mapping in a matter of seconds this is
used by a lot of botnets and Trojans so
they can evade
captured by the authorities also many
researchers enjoyed using authoritative
data to help them create domain
reputation mapping so they can kind of
see that have a certain IP ranges
considered bad and a domain maps to it
that domain is probably also a bad
domain and discontent to expand into the
idea of prefix reputation essentially
authoritative data is helpful to kind of
see how and I P relationship with a
domain can be somehow associated with
some measure of badness so the most
popular method is domain reputation was
talked about and it's kind of a matter
thats been used for the last ten fifteen
year by 10 15 years by security
companies rather some sort of
complicated formula involved identifying
whether a domain is good or bad so they
look at the reputation of the IP the
Registrar the registrant email and some
other crazy terms and then they come up
with the score and then if the scores
over some threshold the added to the
blacklist so the problem is this was a
matter that was developed around ten
fifteen years ago when the Internet in
hosting was considerably different and
as a result while domain reputation has
its place their new category of threats
that are able to easily evade classic
domain reputation for example many times
DJs or a domain generated algorithms are
able to create a slew of new demands
really quickly and authoritative DNS is
unable to properly handle them
secondly there's also a class of domains
that maliciousness can only really be
inferred by by looking at the client
behavior as they interact with the
website so
as a result we've noticed an exploit
kits have used compromise domains which
many times are associated with that have
a good reputation yet will then fly
under the radar of that domain
repudiation algorithm because the domain
that they're kind of compromise
everybody thinks is good and finally the
price of domains and subdomains have
gone cheaper so it's easier to flood the
market with a ton of domains that have
no reputation so you can even make a
prediction so we decided that there
could be a couple of techniques to help
us identify potentially malicious
domains that didn't rely on
authoritative DNS and we want to look at
the DNS query patterns and particular we
thought that Dennis Quaid patterns are
single that are harder for the attacker
to control so more particularly want to
see whether we could use DNA scraped
patterns to identify exploit kit domains
because they believe that there is a
very specific signal between exploit kit
domain and dirtiness gray pattern from
the client from the user and the user
and in the idea here is that the signals
of these exploit kit domains or other
types of attacks they have inherent vs
acquired or assigned features so if
you're talking about certain malicious
domains the lexical makeup is kind of
sometimes used as a feature to detect
them are you talking about the GaAs
you'll have like a CD also have a time
granularity whether it's like the minute
the hour or the day that will be used
internally to generate the domain name
there's also like the hosting with its
IP prefix ASN and also the registration
like what type of registrars are you
using
so those are all the features that the
attacker will try to kind of change so
he can evade detection and kind of being
caught the thing is those he can control
however there are certain patterns that
developed or emerging globally from the
infected machines or the kind of would
be infected machines that he cannot
control he cannot escape for example
certain time elements are certain
geographical kind of features of the
clients that are looking up these
malicious domains so our objective here
or like the premise is that we went to
defeat our campaigns by looking at these
features that are very hard for them to
defeat or invade and that's kind of the
the novelty somewhat off of this
research so the general ideas out there
can be significant changes in query
patterns that could be correlated with
militias term domains and we're able to
gather this data by looking at DNS
traffic from below the recursive later
and this type of data contains six
pieces of valuable information there's a
times down our client IP the domain
queried by the client the resolver
queried which gives us a geographical
location as well as the query type or
acute type and this then leads us to
building so the kind of the the system
we are developing here is goes like this
so the block diagram looks like a a
spike detection algorithm in the
beginning so you'll get like an input of
hourly logs that you run the spike
detection algorithm and then you get
like a large set of domains as the
output but then you'll have to clean up
that set further so what we apply is a
domain history filter that I'll explain
later and then from that you'll have
like a couple more filters that are kind
of worked at the same time when is based
on cue type that we receive enquiries
and the other one is some sort of an
active probing whether you check whether
the domain has specific records and the
combination of those two will allow us
to kind of the side whether this domain
is an exploit the potential exploit kit
its effects software
browser like fishing DGA spam etcetera
now having obtained that final set which
is quite refined we still need to kind
of expand the intelligence graph so what
do we do with pivot around the AP's the
Rangers the a sense the smaller hosters
the registrant emails any kind of
indicator that you can extract from that
set that will help you can identify
other things and enrich your kind of
graph so in the process can keep going
like in different hops as much as you
want as I mentioned earlier the traffic
pattern that we're looking for is a
spike in traffic and we define a spike
as a particular jump in traffic over a
two hour window however we also
calculated a threshold score that the
spike needs across in order for it to be
considered like a valid spike and this
helps us filter out high traffic demands
like Google Facebook the New York Times
or to means that might naturally because
they're popular websites and a post
something that attracts a lot of
followers so as a result are only
looking for domains that haven't
received a lot of traffic in the past
and then suddenly such exhibit
bikes in their traffic pattern behavior
this entire day job is done by using a
MapReduce job which helps us calculate
the domains that have spiked the problem
is we still end up at around fifty to a
hundred K domains to inspect so we're
not yet fully done so this is an example
of Philip to exploit kit domains and
their traffic patterns as well as an
example of the types of spikes that
we're hoping to extract from the DNS
query logs so because the majority of
the 5200 k domains are not militias we
need to add some more features in fact
when we started to look through the
domains we noticed that many domains
belong two mail servers or random blogs
and also included what we called
victimized domains and so this is an
example of a victimized domain that
participated in a DNS amplification
attack essentially people's spoofed of
series of DNS any requests to this
domain and this domain then responded
with a much larger package response and
the spoofed people receive them these
very large DNS packets that overloaded
their network capacity so that's as an
example of a domain that it's not
necessarily it shouldn't be blocked but
it's just being victimized by miscreants
so as we mentioned there's to be just
can't rely on the spike alone to help us
filter out demand so we need ok look at
the spike as being more than one
dimension so we want to add extra
dimensions into modeling the spike
better so
one type of feature that helps us get a
better idea of the the type of spike is
looking at the genus cleary type and so
every time you send a DNS query there is
a query type that is associated with
that DNS requests so for example let's
say that you're interested in knowing
the mail server IP address at google.com
you would send a DNS query type 15 which
refers to an MX record there's also then
34 other DNS query types of you look at
16 which is a tax record 99 region which
is an SPF record which deals with mail
application and then a 255 which is in
any record so the idea that we had
wasn't why don't we look at all of the
spikes that have been generated and then
partitioned into various pairings genus
clearly types so in this case the total
number of partitions that could exist is
31 because we just sum up over the
number of possible combinations in this
case being and choose five where n
ranges from one to five and we can then
see all the various combinations that
can exist so for example a certain
domain that spiked receive DNS query
types of one in fifteen what does it
really received in discrete types of
only one what's interesting is that
there's some very specific distributions
that are associated with the partition
for example 75% of all the spike demands
only received a queries and many times
we don't even see DNS queries of the
particular type for example the Q type
99 never existed and we've been running
this study for about the last eight
months and we have yet to see a single
denis leary of just type 99 occur in his
bike domain so what this kind of give us
hope is that this type of partitioning
can help us associate
partitions of it the behavior of the
spike so I'm gonna walk through some of
the examples that we found so for
example acute type of one in 15 that
means a domain that spiked received two
types of both won in 15 belong to
basically one classic family which was
legitimate mail servers and even within
this legitimate class there were two
types of distributions so for example
you could have a domain dad spiked to
say a hundred and then 50% would be of
type genus to Taiwan in 50 percent would
be a penis type 15 and then there is
also the 90 91 split where 99 was a few
type 1 and then one was cute I 15 and
this just accounted for 4% of all spike
demands but what was interesting was
when we started to look at the larger
time series for this partition there
began to these domains began to exhibit
a periodic pattern in their past clear
history so they realize that domains
that had some nature of periodic
patterns the past would most likely be
benign demands and this was something
that you would then use when creating a
time series filter later on one of the
more interesting partition types was the
Q type group that contained all the cute
I partition that contained all the Q
types and this partition was many times
associated with spam demands and will be
identified was that domains that had a
jump from said 1222 although sign a
couple thousand what many times
associated with spam demand so for
example dem dudes XYZ was a domain that
we found out to be participating in a
larger spam campaign however the
challenge with relying on two types for
straight black labels is you can always
blindly label things as spam so for
example here's Eurovision need I T which
also received the same which also lay in
the same cute I partition but it was a
completely completely legitimate domain
finally there was the cute I partition
of 169 99 which all belong to families
of mail servers so in this case all the
domains atlantis partition or somehow
related by there to Aldi in this case
you can see the VPM . mad dog BR had two
mail servers that are pretty much
spiking at exactly the same time and if
we looked at the previous history of
these demands we can see that they're
almost identical this was another
interesting part is you know having said
that remember in the block diagram we
showed that we have the spike algorithm
that looks at surges in traffic between
two hours so when we extract those
domains before we do the Q type filter
we apply what we call a domain history
filter this one is kind of trying to
separate benign versus domains that are
kind of involved in malware distribution
and what we first do is eliminate
anything that has more than X
consecutive 90 hours of traffic that's
kind of eliminating all of the domains
that had past history and then we have
been observing like exploit kit domains
for a while and we saw that they
featured this behavior were the spike
will last no more than why consecutive
90 hours of traffic and its specific to
the attacks so what we do in the next
stages limit only keep the domains that
have the most recent why consecutive 90
hours as an example of this domain here
it had a spike when we caught it but
then when we checked the past 30 days
will see that it had earlier bump a
couple weeks ago and that will kind of
eliminated from the specific types of
attacks were trying to catch however if
we look at the nuclear exploit kit
Landon domain we see that it has a spike
but then when we checked like the last
30 days
the history was kind of all flat so
that's kind of an indication of what its
kind of repurposed for now the other
filter that goes in association with
acute type filter is the active probing
or domains records filter this one is
basically asked in the domains we
obtained from the previous stage do they
have specific Guinness records so we'll
ask if it has an A record MX txt see
name or name server and each one of
these will tell us something like a
story about this domain so for example
for certain types of compromise domains
of you see that they are having a
specific name server you would know that
they are being compromised and
repurposed for certain attacks same
thing if they are using certain name
servers you will know that they are are
kind of used for delivering malware and
all of these
records will actually contribute to the
decision at the end so the ultimate goal
is to categorize a domain based on its
partition and some of the information
regarding its pike and then put into
various groups whether it's an exploit
kit domain
ed garsten belonging to the product
family so and so on so we decided to do
was to then can I write up a classifier
that could automatically kind of detect
whether what what family despite domain
belong to so this could have brought up
a larger than a philosophical point
which is what's the ground truth that
we're working with and so in this case
the end of the known bad that we had
been collected over the span of five or
six months and so in the future as we
can move forward
domains that we were to catch but only
kinda belong to this said it would be
difficult for us to identify say newly
emerging demands because they have never
seen any sort of you may like that in
the past and there was something just
for us to Canon know as we built this
system so we decided to use probably the
most basic of classifiers which is a
decision tree and so the idea behind a
decision tree is to have a set of
questions that we can have all combined
together to provide a former
classifications and once we go through
the process of training the classifier
over a training set of data each of
these questions are given a certain
level away and so when a domain kinda
passes through a decision tree as it
kinda is asked each of these questions
its output responds helps it cannot
follow down the tree and an end up in a
certain classification bucket so what is
meant was we were passing a list of
filter domains and then
once again I went through the decision
tree it would be kind of spat out into a
nice little buckets depending on whether
it's a spam demand or explain it to me
so the types of features that the
decision tree looked at when asking its
question involved the partition class
despite the main belong to the height of
the site and the number of unique IP's
and so what we found out was passing
through this list of domains of the
decision trees and then spitting it out
into the various pockets made it far
more manageable task so we're able to
reduce the list of $100,000 means to
actually only fifty or sixty domains and
that was something that our hands could
easily you look through and define true
positives so after kind of giving an
overview of the architecture and design
of the system I know you like to see
results so there's a kind of the part
that I find kind of exciting so these
are some of the types of attacks we
catch so like I said exploit kits the
current ones like engler nuclear
industry know a lot of DA's also lot to
fix software Chrome extensions and a
bunch of other plugin extensions that
you receive and also a bunch of a lot of
spyware scareware
kind of executables and then we also
have the class of browser-based friends
somewhere and finally we caught a lot of
phishing campaigns with the system now
having said that there is another piece
in the study which is recording or
documenting the hosting patterns of
these malicious domain so Thomas
mentioned earlier the kind of the
problem of ground truth based on past
history however if you also follow the
trail of the way kind of the bad guys
establish their infrastructures that
also give you some more intelligence on
how they are operating so you can
combine traffic analysis with hosting
infrastructure monitoring and it gives
you like a much better perspective it's
kind of the title of unified view to
catch baden's so there are some of the
documented patterns we have a lot more
about we kind of shows a few to share
with you so you have like what we call
compromise domains or what has been
called in the past few months domain
shadowing is basically a compromise to
Aldi's and they are injected with sub
domains and subdomains they are pointing
to appease that are not those of the two
LEDs and the ideas usually kind of our
hosting exploit kit lens and kind of
domains or proxies to the actual exploit
and also used for Melbourne teasing the
other pattern we saw is that in addition
to the domain shadowing you'll see them
resolving to several IP's so it's kind
of awesome fault tolerance here if when
I think it's shut down then they can use
the second one and usually they are kind
of spread and different prefixes and
sometimes different ASN hosters the
third pattern is we saw a lot of the
exploited domains and now we're kind of
domains being hosted on bullet-proof
hosting providers and is usually are
registered offshore
you know like an Caribbean island
Southeast Asia sometimes and some
Eastern European countries were kind of
the legislation or regulations are kind
of lacks or they can evade you know
abuse responding to abuse reports or
they can take longer to respond to those
kind of abuse reports and then they also
try to diversify their IP space so if
its registered its in the Seychelles
then they will try to have a presence in
datacenters in Aaron and and ripe IP
space and again it's kind of fault
tolerance so they should get shut down
in one country that can always use
another country and the country's will
have different kind of legislation so
one will be like more strict and the
other one will be lacks and they can
play that game the other one and I'm
sure a lot of you are familiar with this
you have a lot of these big providers
that are heavily abused over and over
again in Germany Lease weapon in the
Netherlands in digital motion in both
like North America and Europe and then
finally we love we saw a few examples of
shady hosters like smaller scale hosting
providers that are created within larger
ones and they are catering to mostly
criminals so I'll take the example of
vulture in a second so as the first
example the compromise domains or
dementia doing like I explained earlier
it's kind of the two will D injected
with subdomains for delivering attacks
in as a side note Go Daddy has been the
most abused in the past I guess couple
of years and what do you see try to
check is if the domain the suspicious
one that you can to the spike model has
a name server as
brody's name servers you will assume
it's kind of compromise and repurposed
for attacks especially if it has a
sub-domain on an IP that the suspicious
however we can find some false positive
so you can find these cases where it's
actually a Chinese luxury where casino
site or some spam and this is kind of a
not on the same level of madness you
cannot just like block it and see and do
it like Iran global however when you
look at more features in terms of Q type
or in terms of the IP of the clients the
AP's of the clients then you can make a
better decision so this is an example of
spam domain and explained to me that
both bikes and the decision she was able
to correctly classify these two examples
because it was looking at the number of
unique IP's which in this case is 40 and
compare that to the ratio of DNS queries
it saw that it became closer to a
one-to-one ratio than in the case of the
spam domain which is you can see only
had one unique IP and that one unique IP
generated 26 queries that was pretty far
away from a one-to-one ratio so the
decision tree then realized that there
is that difference and then classified
both of these groups directly on the
other hand in terms of hosting
perspective this the exploit good domain
is hosted on this ip that belongs to
this website is sent in more
specifically under this smaller hosting
provider called your about that are you
and this one has been kind of used for a
while for malicious purposes whether
it's abused or kind of complicity of the
criminals that's kind of the way the
spike looks for this exploit kit domain
and that's kind of the Europe by that
are you
hoster now taking a look at the next
pattern in terms of hosting
infrastructure and as we associated with
the spiky domain so this one is still
using the domain shadowing technique so
you have the domain MIT . Academy with a
sub domain they both actually the domain
results to a couple IP's
but they still belong so they belong to
different prefixes but they are still
under the same percent and more
specifically that IP belongs to a VPS
their servers that are you this kind of
a small hosting provider in russia now
it's interesting how we as as we said
earlier how we can follow the trail so
looking at the range of the 160 the
neighboring IP's are also hosting
similar domains and among those aP's one
of them was hosting this other domain
using domain shadowing which was also
resolving to another IP IP was living on
host life dotnet and other Russian
hosting provider which is actually under
lease web so this is kind of the case of
the big provider haven't smaller
entities selling kind of EPs and
dedicated service and then when you
check the range of that other LeaseWeb I
P you'll see that actually the range the
neighboring ones are also hosting
similar domains to this kind of an
example of at least three or two hops of
exploration to the intelligence graph
where you can catch things that you
haven't hasn't caught with the initial
model and we are kind of developing a
lot of these kind of micro models that
help you have seeds to kind of probe the
big date of tnx or IP space now this is
another example and other exploit kit
domain XYZ and it resolves to the IP so
it lives on this year saying it's
actually part of Q hoster this is a
hosting provider that have has been also
heavily abused or I would say may become
complicit with the criminals now the
range of that I P
all of the the APR 14 neighboring India
/ 24 they were delivering similar
exploited domains and the domains on
those IP's the usually had less than a
day of lifetime actually a couple hours
now another kind of technique will use
we look at the fingerprint of the idea
that we discover and
those ideas that had the same
fingerprint like they had a web server
engine X and then necesitas port open
and then the same operating system now
when you check the / 24 you'll see that
you have some other IP is having the
same fingerprint and then I flag those
and they said well in a couple days or
maybe a few hours they will also start
resolving they were start posting these
bad domains and efficient and actually
that happened in kind of the next day
where they started hosting similar kind
of exploded domains delivering the same
attack so again this is kind of the way
you try to predict what's happening and
it kind of worked out well on a larger
scale now another way to pivot around
the domain we caught the registrant
email actually now I believe it's
protected by privacy protect but then
before that it had this email for the
registrant that's BC project at that our
audit are you that was used to register
a lot of these XYZ exploited domains the
thing is it's also registering a
vtext.com and a lot of you are familiar
with those kind of virus total for
criminals
services like scan for you is famous
this one AV check is the one we caught
here I believe it existed before but
they changed their interface and they
posted it on a different IP and this is
typically kind of interface where you
can submit create an account and then
you can submit your samples and check
whether like fun do not make sure
they're under the radar of the AV
vendors of the industry you can also
submit your URLs for your exploit kit
lyndon domains or your sample and you'll
get alerts telling you hey you're kind
of getting caught now starting to become
scene so try to change or group you're
you're malware now the poster of this
specific case like I said it's kind of
shady hosting provider when we checked
its
what's what's around it we saw that the
host was registering the business in
billy's like the Central American kind
of exotic country and then when we
checked their IP space we saw that they
have been doing it for a while
terms of hosting ek domains fishing in
addition to kind of mundane content and
then the IP space was diversified across
Aaron and right and like we said they
try to have a presence in multiple data
centers across the globe and they will
kind of tell you here if you want to
store this content of this tape you
should choose service in this country
and if you wanna do something else you
have to choose another country so for
example if you ignore the NCAA in a
country where you're kind of okay or you
have up to 24 hours to kind of shut down
your content and 24 hours you like it is
it is usually more than enough time to
kind of clean up your servers and move
somewhere else so they always try to
play on this kind of loopholes in the
jurisdiction or like the way ISPs
operate now this is another case of
nuclear exploit kit lens and domain so
it resolves to the IP this is still
fresh as of today and is hosted on
digital ocean again digital ocean is
like a big provider we cannot say it's
like a bad one because its catering to
all kinds of customers and the specific
IP had more than four hundred domains
hosted for like a spender in a span of
15 days in the domains usually have like
a lifetime of again a few hours and less
than a day now the interesting thing is
that the previous patent we observed
with nuclear from a hosting
infrastructure is that at some point
early in february there was like a
massive amount of domains that were
registered from the free nom registrar
and they were all three domains using
like CCT lead like GTA TK and a few
other kind of African countries but they
had nothing to do with Africa they were
all like purpose for exploit kit domains
the interesting thing is that the name
servers were registered using a
compromise to email job @ gmail.com and
the name servers are hosted on digital
ocean and a super / vulture I'll explain
what that is super walter is in that
case the lenin domains themselves like
the ones delivering the attack the worst
hosted on a variety of a sense but most
notably a stripper vulture now the new
pattern that we caught like recently is
that they switched from having dedicated
nameservers to using free noms name
servers again it was easier for us to
kind of pivot around the name servers
because they were exclusively for the
exploited domains but now they are using
the free nom name servers which can be
used for any kind of domain because
again you can go a hundred domains and
the like some exotic city all these and
use the name servers of the Registrar in
there is no way to say everything under
these dennis is bad that's kind of you
know your carpet bombing the a lot of
things and you'll have a lot of
collateral damage so it's kind of a
loophole where they try to use and can
adapt at the same time the lenin domains
are still hosted on vulture individual
ocean however the other interesting
thing is that they are not abusing the
main ASN of digital ocean because when
you check digital ocean it's again
hosting provider with a large IP space
and they have at least 98 cents and the
ones that were abused there were like
the small ones in Singapore Netherlands
and a couple other countries so what's
the story of this Volturi here so voters
actually a child company of a stripper
that's kind of the number this is a
hosting company in North America and
they created vulture as the kind of a
small company to compete with digital
ocean on the affordable VPS market so
they have like actually a large space
like 65,000 IP's
spread across their own right and ethnic
and the fact that they were like very
cost effective made them very attractive
for both legit and criminal kind of
campaign so we found that they were
being used for the past would say since
like the earlier this year for exploit
kids fishing and other great content we
actually wrote a blog last month
explaining how we can we're monitoring
this infrastructure for a while so I
invited to check it out something else
that we've been able to catch RDA's
using this model and the concept behind
a DGA is you are in fact but the piece
of malware and this piece of malware has
a domain generation algorithm encoded in
it and uses the date as a seed and then
on a pre-specified day it generates like
a list of a couple thousand domains and
it then tries to connect to one of one
of these couple thousand domains and
that domain host some sort of key
information or transmit information
regarding some of your banking
information the DJs are a popular method
used by a lot of banking Trojans and
other cybercriminals and in this case we
were able to kind of see the initial
spike on the DGA
and catching quite quickly and
unfortunately found out that are
watching the news networks it already
caught it and it seemed cold it but we
also noticed was that this traffic
pattern for DJs last law a lot longer
around 24 hours while an exploit kit is
actual only five or six hours but what's
interesting is if we look at the query
patterns for a teaches what we notice is
that they're actually almost all
identical in their format so you have
almost the same number of resolvers
being used client IP's and also the
distribution of resolvers so then we
create clusters of sorry we create
clusters of domains and they're kind of
patterns are known as a DJ's definitely
former very tight group because the idea
behind it DJs that you have a state of
infected machines are all calling out at
the same time to the same set of domains
and so that pattern then becomes
repeatable across the state of domains
and it becomes very clear signature as a
result DJs are pretty easy now to be
identified with this method
other type of scene are fake software
and so this is the type of software when
you gonna watch maybe a free video or
something something pops up on your
screen and then something becomes
download it usually an executable
industry in this case we found that it
was downloading Windows executable and
there were nine
IP's in this vicinity overall hosting
the same type of fake software and then
that's when we decided to look at the
executable beset notice that virustotal
quite a bit of information regarding
previous AV vendors that it marked that
executable as militias the other kind of
thing we noticed about this one is that
all of those IP's in the range they are
not all of them had domains hosted on
them but they all had the executable so
they were set up in advance and you
could basically grab the the payload
from the IP's without any domain on them
so just luck W get the IP with the path
and we we saw this actually since 2000
13 or 14 were you have a lot of IP space
haven't been loads without any domains
and they just wait there and all domains
are registered and then purposed
repurposed for specific campaign this is
another interesting example of domain
shadowing so again like they used those
to oldies rejected with subdomains the
IP hear words hosted is like under this
is a test case in its kind of shady in
the thinks its hosting so when we check
the IP belongs to the smaller range
registered by a fellow called Valentin
Coolio most likely like a fake name but
then when you check valentins other eye
peas you'll see that he has a few other
eye peas from 16 to 23 interest-only
again like this for a kind of the
amusement park all those IP's they were
hosting a lot of domains by the
spherical Giovanni couple are so here's
what they call it the Italian goal of
offshore so he's offering a lot of kind
of advice on how to make business in
fiscal paradise countries and kind of
make money in offshore banks and this
guy is like the Italian kind of
police is after him but he's having fun
in South America delivering all of these
blogs and books and he actually has a
large number of electronic books for
people to immigrate to countries and
make a lot of money without paying any
taxes so that's interesting side thing
here we also then ran across a wider
view prologue to me is when you are
visiting a website that all of a sudden
something pops up blocks your browser
says you need to either pay up some
money or the police are going to be
contacted it's kind of like a baby
crypto locker in this case we noticed
that there were brought to mean that
were all spiky at the same time
unfortunately the overall hiding behind
CloudFlare so we couldn't identify their
actual IP address in these specific ones
they were all like russian police force
seem like MVD NFS be kind of alerts the
other kind of the final set of malicious
domains when I cannot discuss here is
fishing so this one we caught a couple
weeks ago it's an Amex fishing campaign
and we called like the initial spike as
it happened in our lives and this is
kind of the distribution of
IP's and resolve or so you had like
around 13,000 1300 queries from 400 +
ID's and they were asking 16 of our
resolvers so it was quite kind of
widespread and the entire world here and
I when we checked the IDs were these
domains were hosted there were again all
over the place and the thing is we try
to pivot around the eighties and also
the registrant emails used for
registering these domains and you would
expect to find some other badness in
this case we found like some Nova Scotia
Nova Scotia Bank fishes and also Royal
Bank of Canada fishes and also a bunch
of other card incites registered on with
the email like private zone
doctor ceci and mr Benn daddy W
unfortunately we also run into false
positives so these are two examples of
false positives that we run into and
this is an example of Chinese SEO sites
in both these cases we were able to
identify them as balls positives for two
reasons first was actually a lexical
reason these domains contain a little
bit opinion and pinion is the
romanization of Mandarin so certain kind
of character strings in like who you are
detected actually you have Mandarin
meanings and the second was if you look
at the IP distribution we could see that
the domain type is participating in
visiting these demands were also
visiting other Chinese SEO demands are
also spiking within the same our alright
so as a conclusion we can try to share
with you this unified view of into a DNS
to catch threats the ideas that we try
to use the DNS traffic we try to use
like a lot of things so one of them
which is the purpose of the stock was
using stuff below the record select all
the traffic patterns you can catch below
the recursive in then
combined that with looking at the
hosting of the structures and that gives
you like a better perspective of what's
going on on the threat landscape and
like we said earlier a lot of these
models that use below the recursive or
above the recursive since we have a lot
of DAT elected DNS kind of platform we
have is quite massive and the idea you
have to develop a lot of micro models to
kind of help you detect these little
seeds that then you can expand with the
graph approach to catch more badness on
the internet so our approach is kind of
a we use content but it's much less than
the patterns that emerge so what kind of
your Allen content agnostic here that
gives us a lot of advantages but you
also need sometimes to verify with URLs
and content analysis and this kind of
the philosophy here that we kind of
advocate you can go and check some of
our other references so we had the blog
about the IP infrastructure and domain
shadowing we had a couple tax at black
hat and DEFCON virus bought in and then
the spike model was discussed at bside
so this year and we had a blog
discussing the combination of different
models so not trying to advertise
anything but if you like this kind of
research we're hiring so talk to us you
can join our team will be very happy to
tell you what we are doing and that's it
so thanks again for your attention and
feel free to ask questions
you mean how they switch from so we
haven't done a specific kind of research
Brotherton that but every once in a
while when we run into domains are
seeing called we try to see like expand
from the IPO the name server and see
what else is kind of been like for
example for a new bus networks the
sinkhole on a variety of things you
cannot just say the sinkhole is used
forcing calling a specific attack so you
like a big company and you know they try
to target they try to kind of take down
a variety of malicious campaigns and was
that your question
the only thing is I was wondering if you
find a way to group I think the
double-digit for example to me explode
key to whatever to group them by your
specific group in to see all only take
to reach you call and if you can
basically use this as a classification
scheme for any case I we haven't seen
any single decays cause usually they're
very short lived in I feel like it
doesn't make it doesn't help much too
kind to sing call them
sinkholes are usually in my opinion used
for domains that you know you don't
expect them from the malware or you know
them from the Geograph them so you can
go and just practically kind of try to
sniff the back at the traffic from
infected machines but as for UK's don't
think it would help much