thank you good morning I'm um from
Princeton today I'm going to talk about
Morpheus this is a research project with
Janice M Rama porous and my advisor
Jennifer expert and the reason I'm here
is to get some feedback from the
operators about how useful or how would
you like to use this new mechanism to
actually capitalize your path diversity
to create a win-win situation two on one
hand you can hopefully get more revenue
out of your current appearing with your
neighbors and on the other hand you know
you offer better service to customers ok
we all know that large ice piece have
breached path diversity and hopefully
there will be more peering sessions set
up after it's not because you're all
wearing the green dots so first from
some measurement study we know that you
know top two percent of the large ice P
usually have TMO I SAS path for certain
destination and on the router level that
past diversity is even further is even
bigger for example I do some survey on
nanogram analyst almost a year ago and
you know a lot of some some bleep I said
you know it's very common to see five to
ten rather have a path and the different
paths actually have different qualities
just 22 example one security you know
there's almost up more than 10 years ago
the AAS 707 instance you know some your
prefix can be hijacked and in some other
cases you just you are your customer
just want to avoid some downstream s
because of their lousy performance for
example and in terms of performance
also it's okay sometime every customer
may want low latency path but some of
them in a want high bandwidth you know
different different paths really differ
in terms of performance and given the
kind of have diversity available in your
eyes peace in your network probably you
can think about how to actually
capitalize them in a better way today
it's we know that your customers may
want different paths so for example
financial companies they heavily
emphasize the security and the VoIP
companies the one low latency content
content providers they want high
bandwidth nearly one go closer to the
eyeballs and many others you know they
are perfect happy with the default
routes so there's no like one size fits
all solution but today unfortunately
this is the case you prefer you choose
the one quote unquote best route and
give it to everybody so what we propose
here is a routing control platform that
enables ISPs to act alone meaning that
they don't need to collaborate anybody
else they don't need to change their
existing routers but to capitalize their
path diversity so in the form of the
talk i'm going to cover two aspects of
this idea one is the kind of supports we
we need to make this work it's all
backward compatible and the second is
the design of the more of your server
it's sustained on standalone server a
set of stand-alone servers that actually
computes the route and push them to the
routers okay this is sort of a high
level view of the architecture you have
a set of morpheus servers they have ebgp
session with your neighbors and they
each of them only take have a subset of
your neighbors but because they transfer
the state and they
communicate with each other so each
single more fear server will have the
complete view of your BGP routes so that
they can select the best out of all the
routes for your edge routers and for
your customers it's worth mentioning
that it is not the case today so if you
take a look you will find different
you're different edge routers in your
network we have different set of routes
to choose from so it's it's clean it's
very very possible none of your routers
have the full picture of all the routes
you learn of your neighbors and this
argument then you know after choosing
the best routes the Mafia service can
push down the routes to your edge router
through cigi bgp sessions and we propose
to use IP or mpls tunnels between every
pair of edge routers so that you don't
you don't need to worry the hot potato
kind of stuff because that can cause
undesirable shift of traffic load once
some route changes okay so this is a
kind of situation will happen if you use
Morpheus so even if your customer c1 and
c2 are connected to the same edge router
they can actually reach the same
destination through a different path so
that it gives you more flexibility to
providing you know customized service to
our customers and the support are
already there you know the vrf from
cisco and virtual router from june
credit are readily available for to
realize this kind of customization and
now i'm going to switch gear to talk
about the design of the Morpheus server
to understand why we take the following
approach I'd like to point three
limitations of the BGP design the first
is an overloading of BGP
tributes we all know that there are not
a lot of knobs to tweak but actually
they are not enough because you're
overloading it okay you tweak the local
preference to support both bgp
relationship and the traffic engineering
you know you may get used to it because
you did every day but actually it's
quite messy and it's difficult to add
new policies because of that for example
if you want add security as a new policy
objective to the whole route selection
process you're going to think about
which nap should i use the second
limitation is the difficulty in
incorporating SATA information let's
take one step back and think about what
would be an ideal way to select routes
you want to go you know a lot of site
information to help you with that
process for example externally you won't
get some measurement data to tell you
which path is actually better it's
closer to my customer or is it has
doesn't have high bandwidth for example
and you won't have you no business
relationship registry for previous
ownership all these kind of things you
know it will help you to understand
certain property of the path either
performance or security or so and so
forth so today it's quite hard to
incorporate those information to your
the resurrection process okay so given
that to limitations what we propose is a
different approach before the actual
route selection process we introduce a
set of modules called classifiers each
classifier does only one job so one
classifier will take a look at the
royalton see okay i'm going to tag this
route learned from my customer with the
numerical number and four routes learn
from my peer or provided i'm going to
tag with different numbers and another
to classify who is taking care of
performances will look at all the routes
and say oh
this routes according to my measurement
infrastructure it it's has it has the
lowest latency so I'm going to tag it
with a number so each classifier will
only look at one property of the routes
and tag it ok it doesn't make any
judgment and doesn't make any rejection
in terms of filtering it will only take
the route and propagate all the routes
to the decision process and it's
desirable because it because of the
modular design it's very easy to add new
classifiers if you ever want to
introduce a new policy objective in your
decision process and we also envision
you know something it's very likely
different teams even different vendors
can come up with good modules so that
actually they can evolve independently
in fact there are a lot of nice
algorithm coming up in the research
community that can detect say previous
hijacking in a very efficient way so
they can just contribute their code in
some way you know and put it wrap them
into a module sorry wrap them into a
module then you know everybody can
benefit from that the third limitation
BGP is it strictly ranked one attribute
over another so there's no way you can
make trade-offs between policy
objectives here's example you know if
our paths are somewhat unstable then
pick the most stable path of any length
it could be from up here but otherwise
pick the shortest path through a
customer it's very reasonable trade-off
between a business relationship and a
stability but it's kind of hard to do it
today so what we propose to address this
problem is to use a different way to
pick the best best routes instead of
using the step-by-step ranking we use a
weighted sum so don't be confused by
this notations basically the idea is now
after this set of classifiers each route
we
have a set of some metadata right hey
they will have attacked for each policy
objective so you just specify a weight
for each objective then you compute
weighted sum which however had the
highest score will be the preferred
route and because you're different
customers may have different preference
over the routes so that translates into
a different sets of weights for the
policy objectives so in Morpheus we
support multiple decision processes
there's no reason you can't you give you
especially given the advances of the
multi-core you know there's no reason
you can't run multiple decision process
in parallel ok so here decision process
a may you know be set such that it
always pick the shortest latency path
but decision process be they may prefer
the most secure path for example and you
just said the diff weights differently
and then and then you're you can export
the different routes to different
customers according to their preferences
for example we have a product prototype
implementation based on zorp and in that
we we implement several classifiers in a
pipeline because that's sort of how job
implement its information flow and we
support multiple decision processes we
do some evaluation and we found the
classifier actually can work very
efficiently the most complicated one in
which we implement a research proposal
of identifying previous hijacking it
takes only about one-tenth of a
millisecond to classify route and then
we look at the total decision time which
is you know in Morpheus it's just the
computation time for a weighted sum so
it's very quick you know when
there were 20 routes / prefix it's
actually faster than a standard BGP a
decision process because in that at
least in the implementation absorb what
it does is it will take look at this
prefix and go back to all the peers to
see whether they have this the route to
the same prefix and achieve that route
and that compare through the
step-by-step process that's actually
much slower and we did we set up a
environment and you've got its
throughput in this setup we have 40 pops
and each more one more fish server in
each pop and each morpheus server
maintain this many ebgp high bgp
sessions and the sessions between the
morpheus service and we inject 20 routes
prefix what we found is very promising
because the x-axis is the number of
decision processes run in parallel the
y-axis is the throughput of updates
processed per second so as we can see
the decrease is very slow so that even
if we are running 40 decision process in
parallel we only get one one-eighth of
loss of the throughput pisode it's
pretty good and I'm not saying you know
you actually want to run 40 different
decision process but the performance is
there and finally other one to mention
that there's no threat to stability
because for large as peace most of your
customers are stops so even if you give
them non-coding quote non-default routes
they are not going to propagate this
route to anybody else they are just
using them their selves so there's no
stability concerns and actually that's
I'm not going to cover details here but
actually we also have a way for transit
ases to provide customer routes to their
customers and without causing stability
problems if you want to know more about
that we can't
offline okay in summary morpheus provide
a simple practical way to for a species
to capitalize their path diversity it's
significantly more flexible than what we
have now introduced no impact on
stability it's efficient and scalable
enough for even large ice piece and it's
backward compatible so actually as I
mentioned I have questions for you guys
what are your top policy objectives and
you know I over the last two days
actually i chat with some of you and got
very nice feedback about your practical
concerns I like to learn more about that
and because the way the way you need you
need to set the weights for the
different policy objectives you can
actually give some of control to your
customers if you want so what how much
control you are willing to give your
customers or you are only willing to say
I have several choices for you to choose
from but anyway I'm not gonna let you
touch my router I'm gonna just pick the
routes for you but I will let you choose
which type of rats you want and any
other practical concerns so very
interesting feedbacks and collaborations
and here's the link to the technical
report thank
hi can you go back to the graph you had
at the beginning showing the multiple
routes the explanation for how you're
choosing your rots is very well done
I'll is it the question I have is how
does our three make a decision to route
traffic from c1 or c2 differently
because choosing your destination is one
thing but this seems to imply that
you're choosing a path based on a source
and if you're using stock routers how
are you doing that without you know
redirection lists or some other
technology okay so your question is how
does our three know how to for the
tractor from c1 to c2 differently using
existing technologies right exactly okay
so this is a good question because we
use tunnels so that we can tunnel we can
use tunnels different tunnels for
traffic from c1 c2 and that the other
end of the tunnel could be the outgoing
interface of our three instead of the
income interface of our three so that
Utah no actually I forgot the exact term
but you can in mpls you can tunnel to
the outgoing interface in fact you can't
unknow to the interface of art r 6 and r
7 right then you can right before the
traffic leaves the outgoing interface
from r3 to our six you strip off the
header then you know it's going that way
ready
Randy Bush IJ e after some decades of
getting resilience through distribution
of the routing function on over-the-top
illogic space I wonder what happens when
the central server fails to the routers
recover and go back to normal okay so
Rani's question is what if one of the
Morpheus server fails is that quite know
it was when not what if when when it
fails yes they will fail okay it's a
good question and it's not a new
question because it's just a new
question it's an old question asking a
new scenario so I'm going to use it Oh
answer for that it's a typical
distribution system so conceptually each
Morpheus server will have a centralized
complete view of your routes it's a
desirable thing what we want it but to
avoid single point of failure what we
use is first we use multiple more few
servers and second although not it's too
messy to show here what actually are
going to happen is you know each edge
router will appear with two more few
servers okay and that that creates kind
of redundancy already in place today you
know your backbone router will appear
each of you are say access router will
appear with 12 of your back by others
yeah you're telling me why it won't fail
everything we know that it won't fail
has failed yeah so what's going to
happen when it failed okay so even if
one of them fails it you can still get
routes updates sooner or later more than
one is going to fail that's Randy's
everything fails eventually usually it
awkward times okay then you know we are
here the previous talk and can use the
course for restart you know we want to
remember what happened when AT&T put in
one bad bite and all the e5 ESS which is
you know and all the switches went out
on the East Coast the control plane
fails you know the brilliant engineers
will try to bring them back as soon as
possible what meanwhile you know that
the data plane cans the meanwhile the
data plane has do keep forwarding and
that the part that the I mean the point
of you know multiple sessions is just
you know the probability of two of them
fail at the same time will be much much
lower than one of them fail so even if
one of them fails you know it's not like
life-threatening you can still get the
route updates from another server
on the same slide you mentioned about
morphus connections between Morfa
servers to share the information is that
proprietary or how do you implement that
is it like some sort of a BGP session
between them it's definitely not
proprietary you know what we have in
mind is it something like at path okay
so you can send between Morpheus servers
multiple routes for the same prefix you
know the most backward compatible way we
are way of doing that is you know using
something like PHP add path the
extension
alright thanks for your attention and
I'm happy to chat with you offline thank
you