regional internet registry as we
recognize today ap Nick was the second
one and then we have the other our IRS
coming in after that so off this
combined really to try and put a bit of
brakes on the ipv4 address consumption
so organizations tend to get address
space that they needed rather than the
address space that they actually wanted
and there was quite a bit of difference
in that and I still remember even even
in the late nineties are still seeing
organizations especially in Asia where
where I was working of Sigma you know
we're a very big organization we should
be getting ok rather than trying to do
any proper justification as to what they
actually needed the thing is with v4 the
32-bit the 32-bit address space that
gives you four billion hosts
theoretically but there's this thing the
HD ratio and described in RFC 31 94
which realistically tries to describe
what realistic how many hosts you can
get on or within a 32-bit address space
so realistically it's probably more like
250 million hosts would you think about
it it's not really a lot world
population is over 6 billion 250 million
hosts is not really a great deal so then
we had the boom years and so this is
probably Wow
96 through to 2001 before the dot-com
bust so ipv6 development noticed
development was in full swing because
although the v6 folks were excited all
these things were going to do in AD and
and so on and so forth there's a huge
amount of v4 consumption the registries
were handing out address space at high
speed
many of the v6 specifications were being
sorted out and there's a huge number of
different transition mechanisms were
being developed because in that type of
thing people at that time people were
thinking right we're going to be going
to be six roundabouts 2000 2001 or so
various people were predicting running
out in 2004-2005 and others weren't so
there was a huge amount of men
is being developed to try and encourage
people are sure people how easy was to
just move over to v6 there was a six
point which was the experimental v6
backbone sitting on top of the Internet
I mean that disappeared or was shut down
in June 2006 but at the at its in its
heyday there were participants from over
100 countries involved in that and the
six bone literally was a tunneled
Internet infrastructure on top of the
real v4 Internet I know many are the
adopters so Japan Germany France UK many
of these countries were jumping in and
giving big incentives to use v6 and so
forth then we had to bust years after
the dot-com crash while some people call
it well that's when the internet became
boring as far as investors were
concerned it was no longer the big new
wonder technology it was pretty much
what everybody used and you know a lot
of people lost a lot of money business
lost their jobs and so forth but the
internet still was there it became
mainstream and it's just what we used
along with that the v4 consumption
slowed there was the if you look at the
registry stats you find that the amount
of allocations that were making this
period reduced quite significantly they
were still getting new members but they
were losing a lot of old members as well
so things cooled off there's a lot of
indifference as well there early
adopters of v6 just surged on forwards
yep you know v6 is going to happen
tomorrow
and while the skeptics became more
skeptical because quite literally they'd
seen all that ipv6 talk from 94 95 and
then when they were sitting in 2001 2002
and still nothing had happened still
things weren't working properly and so
you got this fairly significant division
of really skeptical people and really
enthusiastic people and the rest of us
sitting in the middle were like yeah
well whatever and so the reaction was
you saw even more transition mechanisms
being developed and that probably wasn't
too useful in the longer run from 2004
to today why l've got resurgence in
demand for v4 addresses those 19 1/2
percent of the address space still
unallocated at the rate it's being
handed out by the registries we're going
to run out sometime August September
October 2010 yeah I think all the
predictions have converged
somewhere around about that time at
least that's when the IANA pool will run
out whereas a registry pool will
probably early 2011 so the various on
the issues surrounding with that I'm not
going to go into the whole address
policy discussion and so forth but if
you join any of the registry policy
mailing lists you see there's a huge
amount of discussion about how we're
going to run out of v4 addresses and
what's going to happen after that and so
on so if you've got lots of spare time
have a look if you're interested in how
this is going you should have a look as
well but I don't say especially from
technology strategy within your company
I mean one question I asked many CTOs in
my travels is what are you going to do
what's your business plan after August
2010 and they always say well what do
you mean what you mean well you can't go
to Aaron to get more v4 address space
what you're going to do and nobody's
thought about that yet I mean I'm not
saying oh you should be running off
doing v6 it's more a case of what what
do you need to do people have talked
about the market for address space I
mean I suppose the radius a market for
addresses which is probably fine in an
affluent society but if you look around
the world how much of it is affluent
you look at some countries where well
that the monthly income is probably $100
for a person right compare that in how
these people I'm going to spend a
million dollars to get a / 20 for the
count so it kind of excludes those from
getting real for v4 addresses and so
they have to use something else now the
main thing with v6 is it offers huge
address space so the v6 that's the main
motivation today that's left is v6
offers huge address space and that's
kind of what I'm going to walk through
next so current perception really is
that v6 hasn't taken hold yet which is
well it's true mean not many of us are
using v6 the v4 address run out is not
headline news I mean you don't switch on
CNN or BBC world and see
it's like not the top news story doesn't
even feature in there
it doesn't even feature in the tech
section of any of the these media but
it's at least started to make some kind
of impact in the in the registry policy
thing and you know we've talked about it
enough at nano I'll go over the few
years I suppose at least we're aware of
it but yes the plenty of discussions and
run out plans and so forth all being
proposed with them within the registry
system and you know they're all weird
and wonderful and those of us from the
Operations community who also play in
the registry policy arena
I suppose well we don't not so much
frustration as well we have to sit there
and try and explain to a lot of the
policy folks why some of the suggestions
about run out don't really make a great
deal of sense private sector of course
needs a business case to do anything
I mean it's if you can't just sort of
walk into Company C right we're going to
switch over to v6 and well it's going to
be wonderful they need a business case
to do anything I mean I work for a
vendor vendor needs a business case to
do anything they don't just do stuff
because hey somebody said so and of
course any private sector business going
to say right what's my return on
investment at the moment it's like well
you get bigger address space and that's
no obvious retirement investment in
there so reality is something has to be
done if we want the Internet to grow as
it has been growing really beyond 2010
we need to do something so whether it's
some SuperDuper amazing net for ipv4 or
using ipv6 or doing something completely
different that we haven't even thought
about but something does need to be done
and people need to focus on that just
some more numbers to look at mean
internet population 630 million users
the end of 2002 is doubled by the end of
last year and that's 20 percent of the
world population that and we're looking
at places like South Asia especially
India and China becoming more more
internet literate and so forth and and
really piling onto the Internet at high
speed so where where's it going to be in
two three years time we jumped forward
the end of 2010 how many Internet users
are they
to be how they're going to connect when
the US was one of the early countries to
be part of Internet so I've got a lot of
the early address space so if you look
at average --is for almost 4 ipv4
addresses per person we repeat this the
world over 6 billion population
twenty-three point four billion v4
addresses well around that many so if
you want to do the same kind of density
how we're going to achieve that China
today uses five and a half / eights okay
and that's pretty significant amount if
you especially be start looking at some
other economies around the world RFC
1918 is only so big and we already see
several organizations saying well look
you know we've used up the entire RFC
1918 space what do we do next mean Alan
Durham from Comcast did the presentation
Nanog 37 explaining what the particular
issues were there and I can repeat this
from many other providers around the
world who face the same issues they've
used up the entire private address space
for managing their they're just for
management within their own network so
what do they do next because having
overlapping private address space
doesn't scale or doesn't doesn't work
for them the policy development process
of the registries turned down a request
to increase private address space I mean
that was a couple of years ago although
interesting enough a policy proposals
being put up at a clinic meeting which
is next week to try the whole thing yet
again and so people don't realize what's
happened in the past so we're gonna try
and do it again and where's this address
space going to come from
well the existing v4 pool which means
that there's then last usable v4 pool
for everybody else 240 / 4 has been
proposed as a new private address space
but then the issue is how do you back
fitter to all the IP systems that out
there in the world already
I mean writers can forward these packets
but can they actually set up interfaces
with them can you configure it on your
Windows PC you can't
so from operational small operations and
operating system support application
support mean pretty much everything is
there to some extent I'm not claiming
that everything is complete but at least
extent you see that you know the macros
are my Apple here a lot bsd linux is the
various commercial operating systems
they all have ipv6 support to some
extent not saying it's perfect but at
least it's there to some extent
applications more and more applications
seem to be coming what protocol agnostic
when we saw in the v6 re pretty much you
can start up your web browser and it
will use either v4 v6 transport whatever
whatever's there but we certainly should
not be trying to expect the end user in
can you could you explain to your mother
or your father that okay if you want to
use the v6 internet you've got to click
on this button and the v4 internet
you've got to click on that button you
couldn't do that to somebody they just
want to switch it on and they want to
get their email and and and browse the
web they don't want to have to figure
out which protocol they're going to
choose so the quite a few websites that
are tracking what the state of the
different applications are and I mean
I've put one up there that seems to have
a list of fair number and what's
happening with them if you look in the
ISPs as well
well the several different market
segments the internet exchanges the
regular carriers got the regional ISPs
wireless providers and so forth is PS
have to go to the registry to get the v6
prefixes so the URL have put up there's
it's one example of what the registries
do each registry has their own v6
allocation policy large carriers tend to
do things depending what the customers
ask for so some of them are running
trial networks and others are running
full commercial services I mean some may
be full services but they don't tell the
customers about it others are proper
full services that you can pay real
money for regionalize piece tend to
focus on the specific markets so again
if their particular market doesn't
demand v6 then they've all they don't do
anything about it
there's been a lot of discussion by
operators and so on about transition so
I mean I've put up the URL there that
the cluster five one that we talked
about in the the v6 our earlier today
and one of the many presentations
looking at sexual some of the
operational reality and more people who
focus on some of these things hopefully
the more time we can spend looking at
how v6 could be deployed then the
endless question of course why not just
use net you know the the many service
providers were quite experienced at
using single double even triple net
their issues with that as well I mean
what obvious one of breaking the
end-to-end model which is very important
to some people layering of NAT devices
causes problems how do you scale net
performance for a huge network because a
net has to basically remember the state
for every single connection running
through it so how do you did build a
super duper massive net box so it makes
it kind of hard to try and offer proper
services simply sitting behind Nats and
I've listed some of the things here I'm
sure the Lords of other implications as
well I mean this network security issue
that worries people I mean how do you
properly do IPSec and so forth through
net devices when an application isn't
net friendly you've got to go and
upgrade your Nats that can be
problematic as well I certainly remember
issues with that in the earlier years of
seeing new applications like sip and so
forth or protocols like sip having to
upgrade Nats just to be sip friendly
application layer gateways what about
doing mergers and so forth mergers
between different organizations using
this same NAT at address space how did
you join these networks together maybe
you can double NAT and have something
else sitting in between how would you do
multihoming when I've seen NAT being
used to help with multihoming awesome
alternatively using bgp by doing this on
a huge scale nobody's really looked at
any of that so there's a big worry about
some of the scalability unless there was
an old RFC mean it's been around for a
few years now RFC 29 93 that looks at
some of the architectural in
occasions of using that so I don't know
Matt my personal feeling is that is
there's a need for a larger address
space the solution that we've got the
only solution we've got at the moment is
really to use v6 to do that when we
could try and use that to do nap to do
this that is going to be around for a
long time
the many parts of the world we'll look
at see parts of South Asia and Africa
they're already very very experienced at
using that devices and layered not
devices within their own networks so now
it is going to be with us with a well
some ISPs are going to choose to use net
rather than go down the v6 road and of
course there's going to be the market
for v4 addresses like it or not I have a
real big feeling that this is what's
going to be coming towards us and there
are a lot of challenges ahead of course
so we'll look at the protocols and
standards now really - what has changed
what do people say oh well the address
the address space in v6 has increased
over v4 by 4 times it hasn't it's the
length of the address has increased by 4
times ok so the length has increased by
4 times from 4 bytes to 16 bytes so it's
many many many orders of magnitudes
bigger than the existing v4 address
space the header format has been
simplified and I think this mostly came
from the equipment vendors so the head
of headers now a fixed length rather
than being variable length check
something's been removed from the IP
network layer there's no help to help
segmentation anymore we've got to use
path MTU discovery so those folks who
love filtering all ICMP out of the
network will probably have to rethink
that particular issue 64 bits alignment
was exciting in 1996-97 because 64-bit
processors were new and amazing things
but nowadays 64 bits like yeah well
everything 64 bit processor so it's not
so much of a thing authentication and
privacy capabilities mean that was one
of the big things
for v6i early on and that IPSec is
mandated but of course I'd be before us
carried up so I caught up with a lot of
this now so how much of a big win that
is it is no longer clear and of course
there's no more broadcast in v6 either
that was one of the bigger things with
v4 early on enough I've put up a graphic
here that just tries to show what's
changed what's stayed the same and
what's new so everything and okay it's
appeared the right color everything in
orange basically has stayed this more or
less the same so the source address
destination address is the same the
version number the same field in the
header obviously fashion numbers
different but it's the same field a lot
of the v4 fields have now disappeared
like the IP header length identification
various Flags fragment off sectors you
don't get those now had a check sums all
gone various options they have all gone
and of course there's no need for
padding anymore what's new and v6 is
this floor label talking about that in a
little bit and otherwise I cut some of
the fields have basically had their name
change in the position chains but they
do roughly the same thing so traffic
class isn't the new name for type of
servers payload length is now as is the
new version of a total length time to
live and protocol really replaced by hop
limit on the next header and so on so
things have been simplified
hopefully it probably helps the the
equipment manufacturers or the protocol
manufacturers probably more than you and
me sitting here trying to configure it
on on your network so larger address
space so just over four billion possible
devices for v4 for v6 Wow 3.4 times 10
to the 38th I wrote the number right
very very big but it's it's completely
silly numbers if you look at it like
this 5 times 10 to the 28 addresses per
person on the planet I mean it's just
it's just stupid numbers but it I put
them up there just to show
what what the size really is and you'll
see later that the size is not really as
amazing as you see the way that the v6
spaces then be chopped up for different
categorizations as I'll show you in a
bit how was the size chosen may my
probably this is probably
oversimplifying it but general
impression was that some people want
fixed length 64-bit addresses because at
the time 64-bit was vastly bigger than
32-bit it'd be more than enough for
anything and for anybody and would be
efficient for software processing and so
forth some people wanted variable
lengths so he had a variable length
address size so it could be 32-bit but
we started adding on pieces it would all
just be fine possibly up to 160 bits and
that would be compatible with the OSI
and sup addressing plans it would allow
us to do out of configuration with the I
Triple E 802 addresses and so we could
start with say something nice and short
and then grow it it's bit like the for
numbering system once you run out of
numbers in your current addressing plan
well you just insert a digit somewhere
and life goes on but the result was now
take a happy compromise or one thing
compromised probably the best word happy
compromise 128-bit fixed length
representation well this is the other
new thing some is for some people who
are new to this it's a bit of a surprise
rather than the good old decimal
notation we've been using for v4 it's
hexadecimal color notation for v6 so if
you haven't done any hexadecimal in your
life before you probably should start go
learning it it's not too bad really I
mean it's just
apart from 0 to 9 you carry on ABCDEF to
represent 10 through 15 so think about
it that way it's probably not so bad and
the dresses end up being pretty huge so
you get typical addresses something like
this filled out with zeros and so forth
to try and fill up the space toufool 128
bits leading zeros between the colons
leading zeros can be dropped so I
can actually reduce this to 0-3 and all
these zeros down to 2 0 3 1 : 0 by
itself so that's handy it helps to
reduce the amount of typing folks have
to do successive fields of 0 can be
represented as a double colon so you can
just simply drop a 0 sitting there by
itself but you can only do it once if
you do it twice then the router doesn't
know although the device doesn't know
where the padding the zeros padding
needs to go in so something like 2 0 3 1
: 0 this one is perfectly okay but this
one here I'm having two sets of double
colons this is not okay another other
thing you can get is something like
address which is all zeros cool and one
can just be represented as double colon
1 which is a loopback address in v6 and
unspecified address all zeros is
basically a double colon so from a
typing point of view you can get some
kind of shortcut like that but generally
we're dealing with large colon separated
hexadecimal addressing folks used to use
v4 compatible address and it doesn't
seem to be used anymore I haven't found
anything that says this shouldn't be
used anymore but everybody tells me it
seems to be deprecated and I haven't
actually found the document that says
that it is but nobody seems to be using
it it's just the addressing was
compatible it didn't mean that you could
use this address on a on a v6 horse to
speak to the v4 world some people
thought that it doesn't it's purely an
addressing that's compatible with v4
which is well I'm not quite sure what
the intention really was there the other
thing that came up early on was well how
do we type in v6 addresses for URLs so
I've just thrown this in here you
actually have to put the URL inside
square brackets because of course colon
is used to represent what the port
number is for connecting to your website
so putting the v6 address inside
brackets was the way of suppose escaping
the colons inside their addresses so
this going to be pretty cumbersome for
you
I can't really imagine that too many
people are going to try and do this so
it sort of means that the DNS really has
to work for v6 maybe we could get to buy
with it in v4 because typing in a v4
address wasn't so bad but a v6 address
especially the bigger longer ones
the chances of miss typing or getting
something wrong and that is fairly high
so using proper names is is really going
to have to be available for everybody
the prefix actual prefix representation
is unchanged so for v4 address with
something like 1 9 8 1000 / 16 for v6
we're again it's the v6 address and /
the mask so it's exactly the same
representation as in v4 cider so at
least that's familiar that haven't gone
into some completely different notation
altogether
the v6 addressing rules are covered by
multiple RFC's I mean RFC 42 91
basically describes the architecture
itself so we've got three different
address types we've got the unicast
address which are familiar with in v4
and we've draw anycast addresses which
is basically one two nearest and that
all comes from the unicast address space
and we've got multicast which is the one
to many
so again it's the similar advert address
types as to what we have in v4 one
difference are--for is that a single
interface can now be assigned multiple
v6 addresses we don't have the case
where in v4 where and interface can only
have one address although again since we
six was first started on you can now
have multiple v4 addresses on C UNIX
systems on routers and so forth but in
the early days of v4 that just wasn't
really feasible what else
there's no broadcast address anymore so
broadcast has been replaced by multicast
sudden addressing so we've got
unspecified addresses all of zeros
so let's just double : / 128 loopback
address rather than one two seven zero
zero one it's now just double : 1 / 128
global unicast address space so far all
the assignments and allocations made by
the registries are coming out of the two
thousand double : / 3 address block so
that's about one eighth of the entire v6
address space is being used for existing
allocations from the registries
we've got link local unicast addresses
something called unique local unicast
which again I'll talk about in a while
and of course the multicast address
space is really last / 8 at the top of
the the range so if we look at the v6
global unicast address space you can
already see that the the massive number
of 128 bits that we had has been chopped
down quite substantially the final 64
bits we've got basically intended to be
used for the host ok and then the next
16 bits are our for the site so called
subnet ID and then the first 48 bits are
being used by the provider so I'm going
to go into these in a bit more detail in
the next slide but we've got this kind
of hierarchy between provider site and
the actual host Stroke lab so what we
had was 128 bits is actually fairly
significantly reduced this hierarchical
and structure was intended to simplify
aggregation as I say intended to
simplify aggregation I think in real
life as we look at the v6 routing table
today that hasn't really happened if we
look at the actual allocation process so
as I was saying mm / mm / 3 is the
global unicast block that's being used
for allocations at the moment out of
that each regional internet registry
gets a / 12 okay so each RIR
is getting a / 12 each registry will
then assign a / 32 out of this / 12 so
you as the ISP will come along to the
registry and say I need v6 address space
you will get a slash 32 okay and it
pretty much works like that you don't
really have to jump through the major
hoops that you have to do for v4 you can
pretty much turn up and say I'm going to
deploy v6 in my network give it to my
customers and the registers respond with
them
here have a slash 32 okay and that's
what you get mean it's not a case of
boom your small ISP maybe you should
only get a slash 48 or something it's
not you get a slash 32 end of story if
you if you if you can use more than a
slash 32 as your initial allocation you
get a bigger one and there'll be many
recent cases where ISPs been the ones I
know are in Europe and and Asia I've got
a lot more than a single slash 32 and
then the current policy generally
summarizing is that an RSP will allocate
a slash 48 prefix to each end customer
so each end customer gets a slash 48 and
if you think how big that is
that's such a huge chunk of address
space because within a slash 48 you've
got 65,000 subnets so it can have a good
number a fairly sizable customer site so
you don't have to do the sort of Spanish
Inquisition into your customers networks
anymore you don't have to say okay how
many slash ninety two's as in V 4/30
twos do you need how many hosts do you
have how many hosts we have in six
months time or a year's time don't do
that anymore it's simply a case of here
mr. customer have a slash 48 go play
okay so it's intended to be greatly
simplified like that so I've written it
I wrote in the next few slides just to
explain how big it is relative to v4 now
64 bits are reserved for the interface
ID so 64 bits are used for the local lab
so I would see realistically with half
the size of the v6 address space already
so really the only 64 bits to play with
in the networking field okay for the
local line you've got 64 bits and yes
that means you could potentially have 2
to the power 64 hosts on one network LAN
I have never seen a line that is
approaching any size like that at all
but that's what the size is I mean the
arrangement is to accommodate the MAC
address that was the whole idea okay so
you could do this automatic
configuration based on
MAC address and you'd no longer have to
use DHCP and horrible things like that
we'll come to this in a bit later 16
bits were reserved for the end site so
that's a possibility of to the power 16
networks at each end site so 2 to power
16 subnets 65,000 subnets so me at my
house I could probably go to my ISP and
say hey mr. ISP I want to slash 48
because I'm your customer and they say
appear have a slash 48 and I could
number all 65,000 subnets I have at my
house I don't quite see this one
particularly happening at the moment but
that's this that's the scale of the the
current v6 setup I mean I've tried to
put it into equivalent of v4 I mean I
don't how realistic these numbers are
but I would say this is equivalent to
give me a customer slash 12 an ipv4 okay
assuming 16 subnets it's a 16 horse
Purvi for subnet which is I suppose sort
of a reasonable average okay you never
imagine giving any of your customers
anything this massive 16 bits reserved
for the service provider so that means
possibilities of 2 to the power 16 and
sites per service providers so each
service provider can have up to 65,000
customers so you see now why some big
ISPs have already got more than a slash
32 because they have gone to the
registry and said hey we've got a
million customers so they've got a
sufficient address space for those
million customers and getting multiple
slash thirty twos if we try and convert
it into v4 money kind of it's about the
same as giving each of your each service
provider a slash eight in ipv4
which surprise surprise was sort of
happening in the late 80s so were kinda
back to that kind of generously handing
out address space 32 bits reserved for
service providers which gives us four
billion possible service providers I
don't know if the planet is ever going
to see that many ISPs given we've got 6
billion as of a population but you know
us in 50 years time maybe when we have a
hundred billion population it could be
quite a reasonable number although
interesting aside I'll say heroes
four billion discreet service providers
they're also 32-bit s numbers have been
extended to basically BOM s numbers on a
32-bit so we have potentially four
billion 32-bit s numbers as well so that
is an interesting mapping I think some
kind of my private thing is well how
about just every ISP that gets a slash
32 just give them a nice number as well
because it's it's it's the same it's the
same equivalent size so yeah they're
coming from the origin is do you think
you think the BGP tables are big enough
absolutely yeah
so here what I've been titled the
aggregation hope so this was sort of the
naive kind of okay if we give slash 42
customer the nice piece could aggregate
into 32 and the v6 Internet's only gonna
be full of 32 and what life is going to
be wonderful
well any of you who have played with the
v6 internet I mean I've been involved in
it for what 12 years now well you know
full well that you don't see just slash
thirty twos and of course is the big
question right with these thirty twos
how does multihoming work for some folks
who rigidly adhere to okay we should
only see slash 32 and I will filter on
that boundary
how does multihoming work okay and one
of the early promises of v6 was yes
we're going to deliver your multihoming
solution that's much better than a v4
one and that's kind of just got
forgotten about so that's why I've seen
saying there the current internet
multihoming solution breaks this rigid
aggregation model so what we're going to
see realistically for any v6 internet v6
writing-table as exactly as we see in v4
people are going to take the allocation
slice and dice to get the traffic
engineering and multihoming that they
need and if you look in the v6 routing
table today yes you see loads of slash
48 you even see smaller stuff get during
dozen I sort of v6 writing table summary
at the right meetings it's sometimes
been reported whether it's here at the
Nano meeting or when nano ganaron will
the joint meeting but I remembered it's
being reported here as well and you can
see
of the interesting stuff that appears in
there anyway let's get back to the the
v6 things so the lore 64-bits field of
the unicast address can be assigned in
many different ways
remember I said it was made so big so
that you can fit the MAC address in
there so this is this GUI 64 thing that
I've talked about on the slide we
basically take your 48-bit MAC address
insert another 16 bits and voila you
have your 64 bit or final 64 bit of your
v6 address so that's what how a lot of
us have got our v6 address here and the
in the conference Network and during the
v6 hour the other way is have it auto
generated using a pseudo-random number
mean that was to try and address privacy
concerns I'll come to that one I've got
one slide that explains that in a second
or assigned by DHCP yep DHCP is also
available there for v6 which in fact
most organizations seem to want to use
or you can manually configure the
address which is what most ISPs seem to
want to use so how is the eui-64 thing
work
well you just simply take your MAC
address it's six fields there you pull
them apart insert an fffe in the middle
and then you have your 64 bit version if
you know that your MAC address is unique
then you set this this bit in here as
one if you don't know if your MAC
address is unique you leave it to zero I
mean the chances of getting non unique
MAC addresses I think what I almost used
to say it was recently rare and plus saw
was a few conferences ago all the NIC
cards on PCs all had the same MAC
addresses which I thought was quite
interesting obviously some cloning
factory forgot to change the numbers but
they're all the same so that made it so
I'm no longer claiming that MAC
addresses are unique so anyway so the
64-bit address is now in there so this
is our final version so these are the
final 64 bits of your v6 address where
do you get the rest of your dress from
while you get the first 64 bits you hear
it from the router which I'll I'll show
you a little bit
Terron so the first 64-bits comes from
the router you've you worked these out
yourself on your own pc your pc does it
itself and that way you get your
complete v6 address RFC 30:41 probably
fair to say this was mostly motivated by
Microsoft and regarding privacy concerns
you know there they were worried that
their users if they go browsing into
places they probably shouldn't go
browsing into I want to remain anonymous
and so forth people could work out who
they are based on the v6 address because
you could figure out the MAC address and
then track back to where they are you
can do this with v4 already so I don't
see what the big worry is but anyway so
we've got this pseudo-random I suppose
final 64 bits of the of the v6 address
as far as I know this only on Windows XP
and it's probably on Vista as well I
have not seen it on anything else at all
so this is this RFC 30:41 address
privacy thing the v6 auto configuration
so a couple ways of doing it there's a
stateless or two configuration where the
host basically figures out its its own
address router solicitation is sent by
any of these PCs clients whatever they
are saying hey any router out there
please tell me what the first 64 bits
are and then if there is a router out
there it responds saying hey my first 64
bits are these so this is probably all
fine and good in a well controlled
network but when you have a network with
lots of routers in it or spare either
net ports hanging on the wall and you
don't know who could plug what in it
could be potentially dangerous so that
was a stateless sort of configuration
which is a useful phone network like
here probably useful for we can control
who can plug what into it but probably
not wonderfully useful for say a
corporate network or university network
and so forth so this is why we also have
stateful object configurable stateful
configuration where you have DHCP v6 as
we have DHCP v4 where a DHCP server in
the
your case will basically hand out
addresses to you so there's no stateless
auto-configuration available on the line
at all you have to get your dress mode
from a v6 DHCP server
there's also horse tree numbering as
well basically what you do is you
configure the new address on the router
you put a lifetime on to the old address
and then the router goes out onto the
line with the RA announcement saying hey
new prefix is this this is the lifetime
of the old prefix and in theory the
client will then migrate to the new
address applic any new applications
started on the client will use the new
address and when the applications using
the old address have finished the old
address then hopefully will expire and
disappear there was also this router
remembering protocol RFC 2898 sort of
interesting sitting here in the vendor
size side and people say Oh have you got
support for 2094 but when you look at it
and you think about the possibilities
it's completely scary so our nice thing
in theory but if you imagine your
network today do you want something that
just sort of comes in and magically we
numbers everything in the backbone just
like that I don't know many service
providers who'd be very comfortable that
kind of thing so you find that the
router re numbering just hasn't been
implemented and it's it's just too much
of a scary thing to do
sure it's easy changing IP addresses and
interfaces but what about your access
list your policy is you've got
particular customer filters particular
backbone filters what about interior
routing load balancing and all this type
of thing all that will probably be
dependent on your addressing so having
this just automagically renumber isn't
very appealing so let's look at Auto
configuration a little bit more detail
so what happens is a client basically
sends this router solicitation message
in other words hey any router out there
please tell me what your what what's
happening more or less the router
responds with the router advertisement
so it just says well the prefix is this
and this is the default right
notice no DNS servers included in this
ok this was one of the things that we
saw with the nano v6 and the Nano XP v6
on the handout that you got
it said the DNS server for nano v6 is
this address because the auto
configuration doesn't hand out a DNS DNS
resolver address and without a DNS
resolver as far as us and end-users are
concerned there is no internet even
though you can probably still reach
everywhere by address so a client
configures its v6 address by
concatenating the prefix it gets on the
router with the eui-64 address that it
won't works out from the MAC address so
that's pretty straightforward so if you
if you have a v6 capable router on the
network you plug into you get
connectivity just like that you don't
need to involve anybody or anything else
renumber aren't just described here
router will send a router advertisement
basically saying what the new prefix is
what the new default router is and any
remaining lifetime of the old address
and then the client will basically move
over to the new address
what configure the new address and then
expire the old address within the
lifetime there's a unique local
addresses now they've got an interesting
history and I think those of you have
heard me a different policy meetings
ranting about some of this I mean there
are a few others who rant about it as
well
unique local was intended for local
communications within the local network
only and there was things like
inter-site VPNs basically anything that
doesn't need to be routed over the
Internet
that was the big thing about unique
local kind of a little bit like private
address space but no NAT Phyllis
okay Steve a lot of people using private
address space for devices to communicate
with each other within a say an
enterprise network and those devices
don't need any internet access at all
right so people do that so so we've got
unique local a newly weekly local
replace something called site local I
mean those site local was the original
one that was intended to do this we've
now got unique local which to me as a
solid fairly innocent end user it looks
the same and there's a whole big
discussion about unique local and
various policy things and people trying
to do fancy stuff with it and so forth
make unique local globally unique and
and things like that which is why I've
said in the last bullet there the future
flea unique local as far as I can see is
unclear I mean certainly for using it in
local networks for devices that do not
need any internet connectivity it makes
perfect sense but then again there's so
much routable v6 address space why not
do we even want to go down this path
link local address that's mandatory for
v6 you find that any device that's going
to use v6 will have a link local address
link local get set up basically header
with Fe 80 remaining 54 bits gen here
are generally just set to zero and then
you've got the interface ID built up the
same way with the eui-64 that's used for
communication on links okay so if your
PC is connected to a router you find the
link local addresses use that for that
communication if you have a serial
connection joining two routers together
see over the one you have a link local
address used for communication across
the serial and then the global unicast
address is piggybacked on top of that
multicast has more significant use in v6
than it has in v4 you stop we have
broadcast and v4 those of you have been
around long enough we'll remember the
broadcast storms that we saw on well
different networks especially with
vendor defaults being inappropriate like
broadcast being enabled and interfaces
well that's all been fixed but at the
same time v6 is basically thrown away
the whole broadcast concept and so this
multicast is used instead which
hopefully is more efficient than than
they were sort of splatter cast that you
got with with broadcast the v6 multicast
address FF 0 0 slash 8 I'm not going to
go through this in detail because I
really know nothing about term a v6
multicast at all the first 8 bits are
all set to 1 the next 4 bits is the
lifetime of the of the address who can
buy the temporary or permanent the next
4 bits of the scope
the final 112 bits so the the group ID
and the scope of the multicast address
where you got those options whether it's
Nord Lynx site organization or global
some examples of where multicast
addressing is used well rip ng uses
multicast so rip ng is the v6 version of
RIP I'll mention these again a bit later
on it uses ffo to cool on double call
online so that's a specific address that
rip ng uses so we decide to go filtering
multicast on your v6 network and you're
using rip ng make sure you allow FF 0 to
: : 9 3 same goes for OSPF e 3 and if
you're using Cisco's ERP the same goes
for EIG R P when I've seen many cases
even in v4 land where people decide
you've got these v4 multicast packets on
my network this should be happening
filter and the OSPF falls over ok so be
aware that v6 if you're going to use the
v6 I GPS allow these multicast addresses
through any filters v6 anycast is
interesting
RFC 42 91 describes the v6 and it cast
more detail I haven't actually seen
anybody who actually uses it the way
that the RFC intends in fact most high
speeds or most operators are using
anycast in the way that v4 anycast is
used ok they're not they're not actually
saying this is a v6 and your cast
address they're just simply saying okay
we've got this address popping up in
lots of places and they're treating at
the same way as as v4 anycast and just
in case you don't know how in your casts
works in the internet well what it is
we've got a global address and they
serve our servers recognized by a
particular global address it could be
say a root name server
it's recognized by that one address but
that one address pops up in 20 30 40
different places around the world and
it's basically up to BGP to figure out
the closest
address for for the end user and that's
how the v6 anycast is being used as far
as I can see so if you look at say the
root name service I mentioned those some
of those operators now have a v6 address
for the root as well and the
cast those v6 addresses in the same way
that the vendor casted the the v4
addresses
anyway typical uses of v4 anycast today
and I should probably fix this are the
root DNS ccTLD gTLD name servers quite a
few rsps use them for smtp rail is
within their own backbones as well so
that's typical use of any cast today
whether it's before or v6 empty you
while the minimum link empty you for v6
is 1280 octet that's a wee bit bigger
than the 68 octet so had for v4 but you
think back to when v4 was being used I
mean we all had 175 bought modems 1200
baud modems that kind of thing we're
trying to run IP over that so six to
eight byte MTU kinda made sense these
days were all dealing with fiber and
wireless you know big fast media so 1200
byte octet seems to make an awful lot
more sense I mean Tom stall earlier was
talking about making MTU and then
turning even bigger than it currently is
so there could be some argument that
even the v6 one of 1280 octet is on the
small side
if Flinx can't handle empty use of this
size then you have to do specific
fragmentation and reassembly there's no
kind of just the disassembly reassembly
that you got in v4 v6 assumes you have
to be able to push 1280 by MT use
through the network a minimum
implementation of v6 can miss out path
MTU discovery if it wants as long as it
can transmit packets greater than equal
to 1280 octet you can also get this hop
by hop thing that supports jumbo grams
with up to 2 to the power 32 octet of
payload again on the real Internet I've
never seen this I realize this is of
great interest to the academic and
research community where this seems to
be more of an issue for them they were
discovery well that's built on top of
icmpv6
so it's a little bit like ICMP or the
art ICMP IGMP that we had in v4
basic let you find out the neighbors
that exist on on a
the v6 networks the various icmpv6
packet types we've seen the router
solicitation router advertisements
before this neighbor solicitation
neighbor advertisements redirects and so
forth so that's kind of a little bit
like ICMP but a bit more enhanced so I
would say as far as we're concerned as
the end user nothing is different v6 and
the DNS well not a great deal of
amazement here in infor v4 we basically
had a records so we populate your DNS
you had WWE BC test a record something
well for v6 well because a v6 address is
four times longer than a v4 address they
just made it quality records rather be
records or something else
it was simply quite a and that's what
it's called so you see a quad a record
you put the name and quality and then
the v6 address goes in there the reverse
DNS in my humble opinion is plain scary
I mean for v4 it was bad enough trying
to encourage operators to populate the
reverse DNS I mean in this part of the
world say Europe North America is no
problem trying to encourage operators in
Asia and so forth to populate the
reverse DNS because they seem to think
that no reverse DNS means that your
networks secure it's hard work because
oh it's really complicated to do the
reverse DNS because they've got to deal
with this whole in andra our point of
things and how'd you do it for a slash
27 and all this kind of stuff well if
you look at it for v6 I don't think this
is doing anything to try and encourage
people to use the reverse DNS ila I mean
yes there's a tool which of a name I
forgot to put onto the slide here and a
neighborhood I've forgotten standing up
here there's a tool that will build all
these reverse files for you and forward
files to make it easier but when you
actually look at the zone phone to try
and handle the IP 6 to opera verse it's
it's intimidating what to say but that's
what the reverse DNS looks like there's
basically a dot between every single
number that appears in the v6 address
and even the zeros that get dropped when
you write the address normally have to
be
included in the reverse and you can't
miss the zeros out otherwise the reverse
resolution doesn't work so the v6 D&S
you're going to have to start looking at
tools hand cranking this it's not really
going to be an option going forwards as
for the technology scope one of the
things I always end up doing and much of
my travels is participating in v6 forums
and v6 marketing meetings and so forth
where all the v6 marketing people are
standing up and saying oh yeah v6 does
this it makes your laptop battery last
longer and it guarantees quality of
service and guarantees round-trip times
on it
security is guaranteed and all this
other kind of stuff and it's quite
literally is stuff because what's
happened is v4 has been developed
continuously at the same time pretty
much everything and everything you see
with v6 offers today v4 can do - so the
difference is addressing range v6 is
128-bit rather than 32-bit okay look at
Auto configuration sure DHCP for v4 DHCP
for v6 yes we've got service and
reconfiguration as well IPSec v4 v6 okay
there's no difference I mean if you try
and find an implementation of v6 today
that's using IPSec by default it doesn't
exist okay
Mobile IP while you get direct routing
with v6 but you know that's still doing
a lot of work trying to figure out how
to make this work properly and reliably
and safely disarmed your quality of
service is one of the big things for v6
but you know it's no difference from
what you can do in v4 right so there's
no such thing as guaranteed round-trip
times I mean a v6 a guarantee round-trip
time say 50 milliseconds between here in
Australia be wonderful
we will probably break the laws of
physics completely doing that okay
Einstein would be wrong and that's what
seemed to be some of the marketing
people are saying they should stop and
think before they start making these
claims that simply aren't realistic
enough for IP multicast there isn't
really a great deal for me standing here
as a kind of and use
viewer yes some of the things are
slightly different but in principle it
works the same way
what does v6 do for security nothing
okay
IPSec runs on both if you do security in
v4 you will have to do the same security
in v6 I mean the only thing is we've got
less experience running v6 in a real
world in a real network so it probably
holds that we haven't even thought about
now I should mention what was the ipv6
source routing thing from last year we
would discover that in v4 years ago but
it was only just discovered for v6 last
year and things like that you know we we
haven't got the sufficient experience
really to look into it what about
quality of service okay there's nothing
you and v6 so we don't need to worry on
on that side as for the standards may
have put up a load of RFC s here that
there's a lot of stuff here a lot of
people support a lot of what's on here
as well ipv6 will run over most types of
infrastructure so as PPP fiddy nvm a
frame really I Triple E 1394 if you
really want to do that anybody remember
arcnet
I mean I'm sure somebody's still running
arc net somewhere you can run v6 in our
neck because hey there's an RFC that
describes it and so on so you can run v6
on pretty much anything so there's no
big issue there so I'm where I'm at with
time not a lot left let's have a look at
addressing so where'd you get v6 address
space from I'm probably going to upset
registries and registry people with some
of the things I'm going to say but
trying to help people get through what
could be a morass of I suppose policy
documents and so forth about how to get
addresses it's not as hard as can be
made out let us say first thing you can
become a member of your own registry
regional internet registry get your own
allocation so for most of you this will
be Erin I know some of you from Asia
packs that will be a panic all you need
is a plan for a year ahead where this
Mason discussion a panic policy list a
plan is not a commitment to do something
that if you don't do it the registry
will come and smack you all right a plan
is simply that okay I have a plan to
whatever I have planned to go to the
moon tomorrow that's a plan okay I may
not be able to do it I know I can't do
it but it's a plan that's all they're
looking for a plan for what you're going
to do in the next year so if you've got
some customers and you say yep I'm
planning to give my customers v6 address
over the next two years actually in some
cases that's all you need but look at
the registry website each of the
registry has their own specific policies
you can take part of your upstreams
firm / 32 address blocks you can get a /
48 from them I mean if you go into multi
home between different up streams you
get a bit of a challenge but if you
simply connected to your own upstream
get a / 48 from them and you don't have
to worry about dealing with the
registries use 6 - 4 ok I'm going to
talk about 64 and a little bit 64 is not
a way of getting v6 networks to talk to
v4 but 64 is a way of you getting onto
the v6 internet without having to bother
your upstream ISP or go to the registry
and the final point is there is plenty
of v6 address space all the registries
as they do with v4 they just want some
documentation so then they can point to
whoever wants to count the beans where
the beans have gone so from the registry
you get / 32 or more if you've got more
than 65,000 customers from your upstream
ISP you'll get a / 48 if you've got more
than 65,000 subnets you get more than a
/ 48 or you can use this 6 to 4 thing
where you take the single IP before /
study to address and give yourself a
whole / 48 out of that basically 2002
call on newer v4 address / 48 becomes
your v6 address block now it gives you
65,000 subnets and it's fully routable
across the whole internet I've been
using 64 at home for the last 7 years at
my home network so I'm all reachable by
through 64 and all my v6 networking just
works like that so I haven't gone to a
panic I haven't gone to my upstream ISP
the last time I asked him they said
what's ipv6 do we need it so they're
that far away from things so I've been
using it quite
I'll come over come to 64 in a bit so
Flyers be infrastructure so ISPs should
get a slash 32 from the registry how we
do the numbering I think is quite
important this comes more from
experience of trying to do workshops and
trying to help
ISPs do initialled upon deployment plans
trying to address the block for the
router loopback interfaces if you do
that number them all out of a single
slash 64 write a loopback only needs to
be a slash 128 and that's all fine so
you've got to to power 64 possible
routers in your backbone that's probably
enough for most people for a while
set aside one address block your
infrastructure
okay slash 48 gives you 65,000 subnets
me if your infrastructure needs more
than 65,000 subnets then set aside two
or three or more okay so some people
just do a whole slash 48 for the entire
backbone some do a slash 48 per pop or
poor region it's really up to you it
depends on the size of the network when
I've seen people go to registries and
say oh how should I do the slash 48
should it be this should it be that
registry doesn't care they're the ones
when you're the ones who know how to run
your own network so if you see your
network scaling to an extent that you
outgrow and a single slash 48 for the
whole backbone then do it per point of
presence basis and that is probably a
more sensible thing to do
what about lands easy / 64 per LAN so
when you were growing up and you learned
about putting class C's onto lat
Ethernet LANs yep
you need to relearn all those bad habits
to clear em right / 64 for LAN
nothing else if you do anything else
Auto configuration doesn't work what
about point-to-point links well the
expectation for those is / 64 should be
used as well but people have you slashed
126s but mobile ipv6 formation then
won't work okay so slash 23 success
seemed to work for most cases you don't
care about mobile IP than fine some
people use slash 1:12
then mobile ipv6 home agent discovery
does work ok so some operators are
converging on to slash 112 of
are still using slash 64's others are
using slash 126s okay
RFC 36:27 has got some discussion about
each of these but is that a
recommendation from the industry is
there an industry best practice I would
probably argue that there isn't really
one and you really need to try and pay
attention to what folks in the industry
are doing what I do in my own workshops
I just use slash 64 for all the
point-to-point links which is scaring
Lee wasteful when you look at the amount
of address space that's involved with a
slash 64 but then you're understand the
issue who slashed 126 is slashed 112
some people looking at slash 96's so
whatever you try and feel comfortable I
think take a look at what the industry
is doing and make your own decision
based on that
customers get 1/48 okay they get 1/48
you don't need to sort of do the Spanish
Inquisition as I said earlier just a
single slash 48 and then hopefully it's
fit and forget
I mean if they've got more than 65,000
subnets thank you for my second one or
third one but again and I encourage you
to take part in the registry policy
process there's big discussion going on
in all the registry regions about slash
40 is a bit too much yeah it's stupid me
getting a slash 48 for my mobile four or
my example earlier stupid for me to get
slash 48 for my house I don't have
65,000 subnets there so there's this
discussion but well maybe small
customers should get a slash 56 and
maybe single line and site should only
get a slash 64 which is you know it's
it's a it's it's a good discussion but
then you've got to think as an operator
what you're going to see in your in your
BGP table if you good start giving slash
64 out to your customers you could see
the internet routing table have lots of
slash 64's in them
anybody seen a router they can carry two
to the power 64 prefixes on it big
number but I'm not trying to be scaring
or anything like that but it's a it's a
number to think about other
recommendations try not to reserve
address allocations on a pop or anything
basis because you're using ibgp
that can carry big prefix
and so forth so it's not really
necessary just emphasizing my other
hobby horse you know aggregation with an
ibgp you don't need to do aggregation
for ebgp is very very necessary leaking
your ibgp out into the Internet is
generally not a wonderful idea so I've
tried to sort of explain how some of
this might work and that's not a funny
diagram I've used the documentation
address and this is not routed on the
internet so you get set aside a 64 for
your loot bags and then you've got
they've got a slash 48 here for your
infrastructure and then you've got the
remaining 65535 sub 35 subnets for your
customer assignments and then when you
run out of address space you go back to
the registry way they do this sparse
allocation for all the membership in
theory or hopefully you should get the
neighboring or adjacent slash 32 and if
you do you can aggregate it into slash
31 and then you just do your numbering
plan with that so to say the registries
will usually all they'll try and
allocate the next block I mean the way
they do the allocation at the moment is
to get the slash 12 from Ayana and they
do a kind of binary search type
allocation out of it so it's it's a
sparse allocation and they fill in the
gaps as more members require v6 address
space so if you go back asking for more
it's highly likely you get an adjacent
slash 32 or whatever let's look at the
routing protocols I should just have
time static routing in v6
hey it's unchanged from v4 ok all that
has changed are the numbers so default
drive is now colon colon slash 0 it's a
lot less to type than 0 0 2 0 0 ok so
lot less the type so that's a saving in
v6 and in fact if you look at most
router platforms the CLI is different I
mean is unchanged all you have to do is
just look for v6 rather than v4 so
example in iOS rather than IP route
something we do ipv6 write something and
you see all the same parameters so the
network you're trying to reach the next
hop address and any protocol our
administrative distance
after that so that's it's very very
simple
what about dynamic routing protocols
well they're unchanged - okay we've got
internal routing protocols the iGPS
we've got exterior routing protocols the
GPS we still use longest prefix match
routing algorithm that hasn't changed so
if you understand how v4 routing
protocols work all you have to do to
understand how v6 routing protocols work
quite literally is to learn the CLI okay
so learn how hexadecimal addressing
works people who come to the v6 writing
workshops end up being really
disappointed in some way because they
expected they're good to learn something
completely new then don't expect that
they're going to come to hear me give
them a lesson in hexadecimal addressing
which is basically all the chairs so for
interior routing protocols we've got rip
ng rip next generation we've got Cisco's
eigrp OSPF b3 and we've got eius eius v6
BGP now has been extended to be
multi-protocol so it'll handle the v6
address family as well as a familiar v4
this is probably platform dependent it
depends on your router vendor and what
they do by defaults dynamic routing
protocols January require a router ID
which is a 32-bit integer if you're
doing v6 and the complete absence of v4
you have to configure a router ID by
hand because a lot of v4 routers setting
up v4 routing protocols they'll conjure
up a unique number from the router
configuration normally from the loopback
interface address or me both maybe from
a real live lion address or something by
the way most iris peers are going to
deploy what's called dual stack you're
gonna run v4 and v6 at the same time so
if you're running v4 getting around
ready for v6 there's no problem but I
don't know I had it's a few years ago at
some early adopters who determined to
run their own v6 networks with no v4 at
all and they got stuck with this they
forgot to put in the router ID
configuration so the writer just said
well I'd love to run the writing
protocol but have no writer ID so not
not playing
so rep ng RSP industry just don't go
here the early six born use drip ng and
that was a major encouragement to
develop bgp supporting hyper v6 let us
say okay just don't go here don't touch
this is for people who don't want to
learn writing OSPF v3 the two IGP is
that are widely used in inter industry
or SPF for eius eius for using OSPF v2
now or SPF v3 is probably a sensible
strategy for you if you're using eius
eius just now then adding in the v6
address family support for ir size is
probably more sensible for you the thing
with OSPF v3 is it's based on OSPF v2
but actually has no interaction with it
at all so-called ships in the night okay
so OSPF v2 plays with its topology or
SPF v3 plays with its own topology
there's no interaction between the two
whatsoever so if you want to deploy v6
over little piece of your network you
can use OSPF v3 for that of all the
proper reach ability and it doesn't
matter what the OSPF v2 looking network
looks like okay so that's pretty nice
differences well OSPF v3 runs over a
link rather than a subnet although I've
seen most implementations these days or
SPF v2 can also run over a link as well
topologies not v6 specific it got
standard authentication mechanisms so
while certainly looking at iOS it uses
IB second of authentication rather than
its own built in thing link local
addresses are used rather than the
global unicast addresses and the two new
Alice 8 types I'm not going to go into
the detail the v6 writing tutorial if
you look at the last nanog mostly yeah
last was it last night I think it was
the Albuquerque meeting I did the v6
writing tutorial there so have a look
for the greater detail but OSPF a tire
size in that fire sires for a bit of
history of it it started off being a
routing protocol for CNS traffic so TLV
was added basically to enhance the
protocols so then we could add IP
support in there for v4 RFC 1195 to find
that
and then v6 address family support was
added it's been lingering there's an
internet draft for I don't know four
years now I don't know why it's got
stuck or or so forth
but anyway most of the major vendors I
know have implemented is is v6 based on
that particular draft multi topology has
also been added for eius eius and the
reason for this is the standard i/o size
the v4 and v6 topologies have to be the
same and that was a problem for some of
the early adopters of v6 because they
wanted to send up eius eius bought v6 in
a little corner of the network they
didn't want to deploy it over the entire
backbone but the way that i Esaias had
the address family support and it was it
had to be exactly the same topology so
this is where the multi topologies
support came in which lets you have
different v4 and v6 topologies a bit
like you can have with OSPF v3 and again
you just have to look at what your
vendor default is means Cisco IOS
default is non multi topology so you've
got switched on whereas juniper default
is multi two policies on and you've got
to go and switch it off if you don't
want that so the various bits have been
added for is ours v6 or two new tlvs the
four new tlvs for the multi topology and
so forth I won't spend time on this as
for BGP many of you have probably paid
with VPNs and BGP so v6 is simply
another address family so we've got the
v4 address family were got or v4 unicast
before multicast we've got v6 address
family and the two sub address families
unicast and multicast as well so that
was a very very simple addition so for
your router CLI is probably you've got
CLI that says address family v4 address
family v6 and you just simply set it up
in parallel to the existing v4 so again
it's a case of simply learning how to
handle the v6 addresses because it's all
the same as v4 so just the final piece
of the integration introduced in peace
which are probably not gonna have time
to go all the way through but I'll try
and skate through as much of it as I can
coexistent transition so many people
have talked about migration to v6 which
basically means
well seems to me to mean is like
switching off v4 and using just v6 I
don't think that's going to happen and
while my working lifetime anyway we're
going to be running with something
that's called dual stack for quite a
long time deuce type basically means
we've got v4 and v6 sitting on the same
device and on the same network so a lot
of networks around the world that
they're ready dual stack the running
they've got the existing v4 internet
infrastructure and they basically dual
stack all the routers to run v6 as well
you're also going to find that we'll be
tunneling techniques which tunnels are
quite useful for getting round bits of
the network that are simply too old to
be upgraded to handle these six you may
have some really old devices or so forth
that can't do v6 to use a tunnel to get
past those and will be various
translation techniques as well to allow
v6 only devices to communicate with v4
on their devices again you saw in the
net in the v6 how we're trying to get
NAT PT sort of work and it's sort of
worked for most of most folks so that
would be an example of a translation
technique so pretty picture with dual
stack this is pretty much what's going
to happen
we'll use v6 if possible if there's no
v6 destination for the client then we
try and use the v4 destination so how it
all was actually going to work dual
stack with DNS well the way the weight
will function is basically you have you
have the system here trying to reach a
destination so what it does say is
wwe.com so they'll go and ask the DNS
server hey give me an give me a v6
address for this particular website
that's the first thing it happens so if
your device has got a v6 address as well
as a v4 address the first thing it
should do is ask for a v6 address for
the remote site if the dns server says
not then it says oh okay give me a v4
address and then if it gets a v4 address
you get connected the DNS server
responds with a v6 address then you get
connected through to the v6 site okay so
it's really how it works all based
around the DNS and this was again the
the thing that we had set up with an @p
t at the v6 our we're a DNS server which
basically would give you a real v6
address if the site of the v6 address
otherwise it gave you a fake v6 address
which then would let you tunnel through
the NAT PT to get to the v4 site sampled
use stack configuration mean I've got an
iOS snippet that's probably a waste of
time showing this but it's basically you
got your v4 address in here and then the
line underneath you've got your v6
address you don't need to do anything
more there's no other magic needed to
configure anything something on the
writers using tunnels there's a whole
variety of things that people get
excited about all the different
techniques to establish tunnels quite
frankly only a few of them are
interesting manual tunnel mean we've got
a manual tunnel for the v6 connection
from the conference network back to
merit that's a manually configure tunnel
over the existing infrastructure so
whether so the manual tunnel could be an
ipv6 tunnel running over IP or it could
be a GRE tunnel you need to use a GRE
tunnel for example if you want to run
eius eius over the link people have
heard of tunnel brokers you can go to a
website and you can click on it and they
give you an ipv6 address and you can do
you can then set up a tunnel to this
tunnel broker site so some people use
that or you can use automatic tunnels
mean the 6to4 isatap and Teredo isatap
in Teredo are only really interesting
for enterprises in my humble opinion I
don't see them having much use for
service provider networks at all however
64 is interesting for a service provider
network and I would say it's pretty
interesting for the enterprise also
let's have a quick look at them so the
manual tunnel so we've got the v4
internet here and so we simply build a
v6 tunnel over the v4 Internet or under
the v4 Internet whatever terminology you
want to use that's a simple example of
how you could configure that the 6to4
tunnel is a little bit more interesting
because you can basically set up a timer
without really caring what the other
other end is doing it's got special
address space basically this to 0 0 to
signifies a 6to4 address range so that
sixty-four address ranges the slash
16200 to you take one routable ipv4
address a single slash 32 and drop it in
to the next 32 bits and that makes up
your 48 bits for your v6 address space
alright so you got your v6 network here
it's made up it's slash 48 so how do you
get to the remote network
well the remote network you also know is
using 2 0 0 2 : something-or-other so
what happens is this 64 gateway router
will realize that the destinations are
64 address and knows that the next 32
bits of the v4 address and it will send
the but will capsulate the v6 packet
with a v4 header send it to the v4
destination this router 2 over here sees
that it's a bar v4 encapsulated v6
packet strips off the v4 capsulation
there you have the v6 address and it
carries on inside the v6 Network so
that's pretty neat so it means that
sites that are using just 6to4 can use
just 6 to 4 to communicate with each
other without the core internet actually
have any idea that this is going on at
all 64 relay is more interesting because
it means that a remote v6 network can
basically take a single v4 address and
get full v6 connectivity without anybody
else anywhere else having to do anything
about it
because they rely on this 6 to 4 relay a
64 really is basically a gateway between
the v6 internet and the main v4 network
ok so what the really does the really
well basically announced to the v6
internet that it's a relay so it
announces the 2 0 0 2 : / 16 address
block so when packets come in with an
address space it knows to uh Nancarrow
pre 'it and pop them onto the v4 network
or the other way around 192 88 99 / 24
is announce to the world again as a bomb
basically as a means of converting
back into the v6 space from the v4
internet so if you announce one and two
88 99 / 24 to the v4 internet you
advertising a 64 really capability and
so basically any encapsulated packet
will head towards this address here and
get popped back into the v6 Internet
so this v6 this v4 address isn't any
castle dressed I mean the last time I
looked I think it's 6xs net list how
many 64 relays they think there are
there but about half a dozen or just
over half a dozen of these and various
spots around Internet quite a few
service providers advertised these I'll
set up these devices and I try and
courage eyes peas we've got like a spare
router lying in a corner just to set up
something like this if you notice the
2-0 2/16 in the 192 88 99 1/24 network
out to the internet then you provide the
64 relay service which is actually
really really handy and all you need to
do is just find a static default route
on the relay router - sorriness is not
the real a router but towards a really
router and you end up in any any of the
64 relay writers around the world
I mean I've used that quite a lot I mean
that's how I get my v6 access at home
and it's quite surprising that our TTS
almost match the v4 RT T's we don't
really get any of the wacky or weird
writing that you normally associate with
the early v6 Internet okay so 64 I think
is pretty neat so that's basically
summarizing what I said about about all
that so the the next piece of want to
look at just for time is the tunnel
broker you go to the website HTTP before
you pick up your tunnel address and then
you basically build the tunnel to the v4
device that they're specified and that
gives you access to the v6 internet so
several organizations around the world
to offer these this tunnel broker
service and it's a way of giving end
users access to the v6 network NAT PT 4
v6
well old RFC is 2766 and 3596 well 27 60
describes an @pt 3596 has just added a
bit more detail to it basically this is
the one that does translation so it lets
v6 only sites see the v4 only internet
and it says they're in a final bullet
easy to use transition and coexistence
solution I'm not sure if I even agree
with my own slide after my ever trying
to get the iOS one working earlier today
but it should be easy to use and and so
forth basically what you do is you set
aside a 96 bit prefix to basically be
your sort of dummy v6 address that going
to be used in your v6 world so that
dummy address is basically then used to
map onto v4 destinations so it's a bit
like v4 gnat in itself you've got a kind
of pool of addresses or arranger
addresses that can be used for the
father translation so the way that PT
works is a little bit like this so we've
got our v6 host out here with this nice
big address sitting there we've got the
v4 horse sitting over here I mean I've
used private addresses as examples
meaning in real life you'd use public of
course so it's basically you've got this
packet coming here source is well that
address the destination is whatever
you've chosen to be the the this dummy
prefix I mean the way we did in the v6 r
was basically the name seller gave back
this dummy address you saw the dress was
something rather and then it had this
double e e sitting in the middle okay
the NAT PT device recognized this as
this special translation prefix and then
what it does it translated it they're
translated into whatever the v4 address
is really meant to be okay and then the
then the v4 host responds so it's source
is coming from what once up to sixteen
one one destination one time to do
seventeen one one so you've got a v4
address pool the basically maps back
into the v6 and then the NAT PT device
basically Maps it back in into the v6
world so this is how it all should work
in theory and
that PT working well is pretty much
mostly transparent to the end-user
and I think at least I was amazed how
many people put up their hands at the
end of the v6 our singing actually could
do stuff during the v6 hours I was
expecting to be two or three people to
say yeah it worked but it was probably
but I don't know half the room which is
extraordinary and this is how the DNS
application layer gateway works so
basically you do you send out your host
will send out a request for host
whatever the domain is and the NAT PT
device basically will intercept this and
track see no it's not a quad it's
actually just an a request for this
particular destination response comes
back their address is this the NAT PT
basically gets involved as this is an e
record we can do a records in v6 Network
let's convert it into the quad a and the
give us the translation or v6 address
were using so it uses this translation
address that I've picked to zero ten
double : 45 so as far as the v6 the cost
is concerned that remote site host or
NAT PT comm is actually sitting on
Tuesday or 10 : 45 whereas it's actually
sitting in the v4 world okay and then
you do the same request for the pointers
so he asks for the reverse IP 6 2 r /
address and the nat PT translates it
into an in a draw ARPA the response
comes back and the because the pointer
record just gets translated straight
through so you that's certainly how the
DNS application there gate we work and
it's how the the top D application layer
gateway was working during the Box still
working now but during the v6 hour for
those of you who are using the the NAT
PT that so summary of all this you can
application their gateway per
application we certainly DNS is the way
that things are done by things like FTP
and so forth aren't really handled yet
but it's work in progress and for some
reason NAT PT was deprecated with an ITF
although that seems to be changing now
so that PT is going to be pretty
important going forward I think
as more people want to develop or deploy
v6 in the network and we're going to see
more of this coming from your vendors
and different sources problems will not
be tea of course as there's new anti n
security but then hey you know we don't
really vent n security for a lot of what
we do I'm v4 anyway no DNS SEC well sure
if somebody can try and figure out how
to do any DNS SEC through an application
layer gateway but so far there isn't any
and of course there's no IP set because
you're in different address la realms
but it is a pretty easy v6v for
coexistence mechanism that's pretty much
all it plan to do what I've done in the
last few slides was just put in it's
just for information but how to
configure v6 for various servers so if
you haven't figured this out I can't
find the documentation it's like how to
set up their patchy server to handle v6
how to set up by 9 to do v6 how to do
send me off of you know get your send
mail thing to support v6 not that many
people use sand mail anymore but this is
just how to do it various UNIX
applications and so forth we've we've
collected a lot of this on the cluster 5
wiki and so forth and the URL I
mentioned earlier about what different
applications need to have done to them
to make v6 support work we look at the
different operating systems main Mac
users always say ho-ho we've always had
had v6 and all just works but as well
certainly Chris Mauro and I have found
out in the last day or so that it's not
quite as straightforward as the Hat like
not being able to paste capital letters
of a v6 address is just positively weird
and you know various linux's have had v6
running there for quite a long time
XP simple enough to install i've played
with the windows 2000 version the early
development stack and that's kind of
just work too Vista has is enabled by
default not going to go into much of
that and most applications will probably
use v6 transport if there's a v6 address
offered and that really high speed which
I apologize for that is all that the
introduc
to v6 tutorial I mean as I said at the
start if you want to see some of the
detail of the router configurations
certainly on Cisco IOS that iOS XR and
on Juno's have a look at the tutorial I
did the last nog which goes through in
some detail about how to configure all
of that but hope this has been a useful
introduction and giving you a little bit
of a background as to what we did for
the network here today well especially
in the v6 hour today do you see how some
of the bits actually ended up working
main thing I want to summarize with this
at v6 should not be a big scary thing
for anybody because it more or less
works the same way as v4 does you really
just have to get a handle on the big
addressing the hexadecimal addressing
the double colons the different ways of
representing defaults and so forth and
otherwise take confidence in that and
try and move forwards and when you go
back from this I think what to do issue
the challenge to your CTO and so forth
what's your business plan after August
2010 what you're going to do when Aaron
is no longer able to give you v4 address
space do you want to go into the market
or do you want to do something different
that's all I have to say thank you very
much for listening for any questions so
if any questions please ask I won't be
around much longer because I've got to
rush off to apricot and Taipei which is
clashing with nanoka unfortunately but
you can try and grab me this evening and
first thing tomorrow morning before I
head off quick question you said early
on you were going to say a little bit
about the floor record field and then
you skipped it I don't then time is it
really irrelevant was my my curiosity is
does it have anything to do with
netfloor it just nothing to do with
netfloor s floor anything like that nope
and I haven't really seen any serious
doing anything with the floor record yet
at all I mean there's been some talk
that I've looked at I could be
completely wrong
I mean people who are probably involved
playing with that I probably look
this happening but if I look on routers
and what service providers are talking
about I've seen no implementation but no
it's nothing to do with net flow or s
flow or IP fix or anything else okay
well for no questions we now welcome
feedback how to make this better things
to add things to delete things that were
wrong please let me know otherwise thank
you very much