government examine this is a job every
day is exploiting software running on
three million devices
they together with I desire your honor
to be speaking at a GD on the track at
this year's %uh black and
however you enjoy it is said to have a
job as a tack surface and walk away with
a greater understanding and appreciation
for the vulnerabilities exist
in the framework you know we can use
this information to find your next year
and a half
the
I so
first thing I do is register with a
solution this solution was provided to
us by US Senator
unless it's absolutely unless it is
absolutely necessary to run Java in a
web browser
the same weight as described below the
even after updating to the latest
version of the software
this will help mitigate other Java
vulnerabilities that may be discovered
in the future and
know its a bad year for PC software when
the US government is saying he don't use
and Stephen what's the latest version of
the software
I'm so there has been a rough year
earlier this year them
we know that nobody in this room
actually his intention was going to
follow the US government has to say
so where forcing you this reason tation
so we hope you enjoy it
there
starting with the agenda we're gonna
take a tour in jobs attack surface and
describe the type someone abilities that
exist in the framework
around look at it as a set of five case
studies for the top donor body types
and and provide you with a senate
crucial concepts and it never published
muscle which have never been publicly
shown before the moment action
mind and then there are many publicly
released we're gonna talk about what
type 1 earlier action being
leveraged in the landscape and then
we're taking independent look at how
40 is handling the Securities and issues
exist in the job training or
there for suicide quick introduction for
days on myself
a if you don't know who I my name is
Brian going so I worked for Hewlett
Packard
and I worked on the manager Ron Emily
research in HP security research
organization
my primary responsibility is running the
zero day initiative which is aimed
the world's largest vendor agnostic but
bounty program
am also responsible for organizing the
countdown competitions
they happen and now twice a year I also
knew root cause analysis on the CS
emissions
from there are researcher may say come
in every day and verify excellent
ability though in my free time
I'm a family man I have two kids and a
wife and it when I'm not spending time
with them
i'm looking for Cody are looking for my
own abilities in code and
closest close source software I'm
you can find me on twitter I militias in
front where and now surrounds me a hand
on
day I'm just gonna most part he is your
name is your team and i actually were to
brand I'm when the guys that analyzes
cases submitted to you our program
as a result I spent a lot of time and i
dont hands
as a rule or that I often incurs an idea
I actually submitted
one survivor reports just three than two
weeks ago and have another marksmen
among you reach me on Twitter are see as
wondering which animals in mind he the
CDI a Twitter account
like so I really want to take a look at
Java
well who want to get a more granular
insight into the attack surface and US
Surgeon submissions
I had to zero day initiative in May 2012
in early 2013
and the things we really want to
understand was what the most common
vulnerability types
in the framework we want to also
understand which hardly architecture
produces the most owner release night
because this would be a good target for
auditing
we also wanted to understand which part
of the architecture
produces the most severe gonna release a
the and how those were actually being
leveraged in the landscape
and again looking at have an independent
look at how work was handling these
I'm the the industry had been
higher in early 2012 focus on the
sandbox bypass issue
which will talk about where in the
presentation and it was also model
zero-day vulnerabilities
they were being demonstrated how known
and then used against
major suffer mentors like Facebook and
Apple kinda Peter interest to make
do further analysis lie so let's talk
about the sample said that we used
we scoped our sample said to the modern
day but we can see our modern-day
vulnerabilities in Java and this coveted
2011 through 2013
in our sample set was a over 120 you
need to Java bugs
and this is probably the moon the
largest collection of Java
vulnerabilities
in one place outside a moral or outside
the NSA
or some other nations day I'm so we we
had a large collection a look and
we have the entire zero day initiative
database we had numerous on in relief
used to look at
penetration testing tools actually cares
and we included in this analysis 60 they
want to believe that have yet to be
matched by Oracle
I which should hopefully be coming out
in the next patch release
did you leave threat landscape
statistics special see you later and in
the size
we worked with reversing labs and got a
sample a 52,000 unique
Mauer samples analyzed and look at and
draw conclusions from
when we take a look at Javas footprint
it has a huge installation Mason that's
what makes it such an interesting target
for attackers
Courtney okay the Nanaimo so this
installation base during translation
have process with in a safe three
million devices run Java
it according to Oracle 1.1 million yes
options Allah and His 1.4 million job
cards produced every year have no idea
what a job with heart is
but it runs Java and I'm sure runs a
subset I don't know how to get updated
so if there's a chance to somebody's
house may be useful in that case
the other interesting thing is that and
mostly users in Java
are running outdated software there was
a there's a report released earlier this
year from Websense
it said ninety-three percent a job for
users are not running the latest patch a
month after its release
and sometimes up to a year the other
interesting thing about Joe is that
schools
are using it as a base language for
teaching computer science this
to students I know that you know geez I
went to University of Texas daytime
drama there's a baseline which
I went to Texas A&M University and they
also use that as a sign to show every
year there's
hundreds of snow there were thousands of
students coming out
who that is their primary language in
and so as a result has been a widespread
adoption have
job in the marketplace including in the
financial services sector
and now into the mobile device space
like
if we look at the software architecture
stuff is on the screen here
there's over 50 subcomponents they're
responsible for specific tasks
in the framework itself and you see this
if we look at them and that's where our
initial research focused on was
trying to understand the subcomponents
and $100 million affecting some
components and we'll talk about a couple
in real quick
the deployment is somehow knits a
consist in the Java Web Start
capabilities and the job applicator
abilities and there's
you'll see a couple seconds a large
there's a Larson a buzz in a component
the job FX component apply the same
API's for delivery in creating rich
internet applications
the Java 2d components as a set of APIs
for drying two-dimensional graphics
and the library some components provides
a basic functionality that is used by
most applications
really does provide a wide range of
capabilities and that's why it is so
popular with the developers
there's the ability to you consumed on a
Web Services work with databases
is the reason why people actually like
to use the software itself
so let's start looking at the actual
gonna really trans and the attack
surface
a job so we're looking at here is
patch statistics from 2011 2003-2013
and we see if you look at the match
statistics there's increase catching
which
you know as we all know is a due to the
increased my really have
research going on there 50 issues were
matched
50 remotely exploitable issues were
passed in 2011
and just in the first half for 2013 130
remotely exploitable issues were matched
to the increase in the in research in
Marion increase in patching
or black she provides a lot of meta-data
when they release a patch
and the release along with the patch
itself ASE
risk matrix which is shown on the screen
and it provides you additional
information about the vulnerability that
is
that is being fixed and needs and we use
this as for initial analysis
and you can see this is CV 2013 23
83 is a boner million into the
components
and it is remotely exploitable without
authentication
it's it's CBS s forces hand so it's a
very severe gonna really and truly
component
according to the risk matrix but the
interesting thing about how job backers
are York black shoe stores the CBS %uh
stories they actually assume
that the user is running the app with or
the Webster application as and using
administrative privileges
but really is probably the best way to
go for judging
CSS course I'm but in reality most
vendors are not going to do that and as
a result for QoS giving themselves a
more senior harsh penalty
on the vulnerabilities are there better
being fixed dammit I just depends on
your perspective if you like
he and the fact that they're using that
approach for judging CSS force
if we just look at the information that
oracle provides
with their patches we can see the
component rankings there on on the slide
those components listed on the screen
account for for the remotely exploitable
vulnerabilities
in job itself according to their
according to the match information
with unemployment being the number one
most vulnerable components
followed by the to you component a
libraries Jonah Hex nawt
some interesting statistics they came
from this analysis is that there's
actually two subcomponents in the
architecture
their work have had bugs in them every
single patch release
and that was the deployment and truly
components have been fixed in every
single release
there's actually a point in time where
there was a to some components in the
architecture that had
double digit CVV counts in a single
action that will happen to those in
February 3rd 2013 which i think was the
largest Java patch ever
I the deployment and John affects other
components had 10 and 12 respectively
on average the CSS course 7.6
7 have been if you look at the table
itself you to make an argument that the
to the component
is actually the worst company in the
architecture base of those
its ranking an average season average
CSS for
but these are looking at the zero day
initiative submission trends over the
years
I'm here in the ZF program we're getting
about five jobs 0 days every quarter
when you can see there the huge like I
was talking about in the fourth quarter
and the first quarter 2013 with a high
of 33
0 days coming into our program in one
corner and that's how the reason for the
name for the talk is a basically felt
like every day we're getting a new job
zero-day into the system which we had a
quick return it or called
I if you look at the components that are
researchers are actually focusing on
they're focusing on the to the component
the library component Java FX and the
deployment
component and sound and if you look at
it
the overall stats for how many the
bugsy after I was actually responsible
for damage the actual account for 36
percent in Java vulnerabilities
but the CSS for 9.20 or higher
that's a lot of bugs now with an average
score 9.28
I'm so when you look at it into a scene
in the senior researchers are focusing
on companies to produce the most loans
court components and end up on the most
vulnerable list when his EI researchers
are looking at them
it just depends on your perspective
so we did agree to let a 100 to 120 plus
his own abilities and we had in our
dataset
and we we categorize them by
vulnerability class RCW even
million for started off with the blue
boxes with privileges and what issues
buffer overflows improper restriction on
my for operations
122 untrusted for your fans is integer
overflows in a couple other bugs
I'm always size you-know-who ensure that
the previous Mr tissue had the most
number vulnerabilities
in the city and in Java and but column
by buffer overflows
followed by the caravans rights the
what we wanted to take a more granular
look at the 1i really classism cells and
so he said categorized
the underbelly classes even sure they're
we labeled and
gonna believe that have used the
reflection API's
in Java to recharge the code they were
restricted I and II
sense to allow them to return I'm
disable the same box
as unsafe reflections on a release the
Musa I'm
a job as deep religious blocs we labeled
as the reason for alleged violations
and then and vulnerabilities in that ad
I'm used to
more goals type system and going to be
using techniques like the serialization
interesting data
when they will this type confusion we
also some categorize the buffer
overflows into the classic even sadder
face variance
and how to bounce right now to boundary
for buffer operations
I'm so and with the key takeaway here
for job is
its it's a classic case study in almost
every single major my class
that exists that we have enough we've
known about for a long time
so a its though if you look even deeper
at
specifically the sandbox bypass issues
itself seems silly 62 a 265
account for over half a boner billy's in
our datasets
I'm if you look at the pie chart there
you can see that's
the unsafe reflection has match 50
percent over fifty percent of those and
I we scrimmage violations work order
and followed by the type confusion bags
ABC there there's a charge on the screen
and
shows zeeye submissions and then CEC
he's in the wild they are actively being
exploited so we can really say that
or who has known about this issue for a
long time and
as early as early 2011 2010 and these
are actually quite popular will talk
about this in the leveraging section
a with a with exporters saddam because
you know how to bypass OS level
medications like Devin Sr
they just work every time well if we
look a memory
corruption issues go see the movie 787
out around rates in 122 he may suffer
flows is really to root causes for this
is gonna release
in question the first is an integer
overflow that houses an allocation
smaller than the intended by for an
issue right past and then also incorrect
arithmetic operations
but if you look at the those two classes
major classes a-1 ability tax
we see that one-third of those issues
are resulted in order overflow which
will actually go over an example
menninger overflow
in a in the case study section I so that
it's an interesting 26
interesting look at the one abilities
themselves
and the fact that they are two different
types I
intricately rhythmic operations is a
majority of those a memory corruptions
be
to taking that information MMA ring with
CZ I information in all the data sources
that we had
we can determine the top seven
dollar-million classes for Java
number one being behind safe reflections
Stylophone about us
sandbox bypass and their most popular
actually in the library some components
the next easily scrimmage violation
again most popular in the library
subcomponents
followed by two classic memory
corruption issues we have the
he may see for overflow and the outer
bound right
followed by and trusted clearly
referencing a image on the FX company
which is actually my favorite some bug
in Java
I don't know why they exist but they do
and then there's any future overflow
bugs
in here their resulting he basically for
flows and type confusion
interesting thing to note here is that
the and safer functionally scrimmage
violations are the most popular him but
Russia
type confusion as number seven in the
West Mercia switch in that way around
when we talk about leveraging so the
next thing we did was
we said okay we know what the most
notable subcomponents are
we have a set of 120 you need jobs on
abilities
let's create a roadmap I'm the type who
gonna releasing each component and which
packages those vulnerabilities actually
existed in
so if we look at here and this is only
the one the first time this is this
mapping out the attack surface is
actually existed
I'm so if we look outside your home I'm
if we look at the 2d Judy components we
can see which packages
gonna really is actually existed in the
title own abilities which have any
memory corruption issues that exist in
their
if we look at the deployment
subcomponent
they suffered from a set and injection
and process control issues
the the hand and the rest in the
components in this list are actually
sandbox related issues
this is the and other celebs comparison
with you now son
you can see their job FX suffered from a
lot of interesting
under the reference style gonna release
I the library said that subcomponent
I'm mercy well pretty much excludes we
had sandbox issues
made money interesting component is
actually the sound company has had the
same box
and memory corruption issues in it the
interesting thing here in NY this
mapping is valuable as as a bug hunter
who wants to responsibly disclosed to
our program Vali was 32
I'm pinpoint which subcomponents to look
at and how to give your road map for
what to look for
especially when you do in one day
hashing you can take a subcomponent you
getting my stuff about the risk a major
dork provides
you look at this mapping and determined
went on a really tight Cinco changes you
should be looking for
now we're going to I take a look at
except que se the most popular on a
really tight
in the most popular components we're
gonna go over Essendon
to sandbox issues in the library
subcomponent to memory corruption issues
in this unique components
an untrusted pointer dereference 200
million the job at six components
something like I said before so many
spots and never been seen before
publicly here
and so but the moment hash like
aren't so the first leg is in the
library is a component and as a hatter
would say much as you do to you and say
for flexion
first what is unsafe reflection and
imagine you have AAA are actually in for
sports reflection
medea dispatch method that takes a
string and the summit's ring you then
execute method amply
in so you have to say they the string
had a and
it all and I am we look up and invoke
the admin
unsafe reflection would be where you do
not have proper validation on that
string8 and you allow a malicious user
German
run need to leave everything that
they've as CV joint 1325
436 is an example above unsafe
reflection as reported to us by Ben
Murphy on March 23rd 2013
it starts off by using security
explorations issue 54
which or or did decided is not a boner
million
I'm issue 54 makes use of the invoke
dynamic GM of good
to you get access to protected methods
so
in this particular case we can get
access to define class project into the
class letters last
and we we end up with him at the panel
to it
with on the also mentioned that they had
another way
a actually turning into a force play in
the corner issue 55
and bass on issue 55 and the same CV
as I'm with Ben Murphy is a minute to us
we can only assume that they're the same
phone
a in Murphy is found that you can use
method hand was buying two method
to bind the class to bind a.m. at that
handle
where a classloader to aim at the handle
and it will allow the class interviews
as a
valid argument so once you've done that
you can actually invoke it and
continue on once you've done that all
you have to do is create a permission to
mean that contains all permission and
then lose it
a class using that permission to manage
once you've done that you can execute
method from the lowly class to you all
invoke a system that security manager
know and you know if I the security
manager
or you could have a static initializer
within the load in class do the same
and he really is a sample the park and
we start off with
as de uso a custom class so
prevention I'm see make use of the no
dynamic opcode to you
get access to a protected class you have
to handcraft the classes you can I use
the Java compiler
you can do it with rocks fights but an
easier way is to use a framework such as
a SMT framework
so you invoke yearly class and
and recommended that you defined within
it in the whole point that is to invoke
this method here said define class
and/or and when are you in the past year
it is a method hanoi
and we use that method hand which will
be about the panel to you our
glasser define class protection method
and we just save it to a static variable
so we can access it later on
went to even vote our custom class with
an krier Commission object and encrypt
create a protection to maintain
using that permission object we can get
access to our class later
and create a minute handle and bind the
class order to that meant to handle and
then we invoke a class at this point all
we have to do is
notify the prison recommended within the
lower class to notify the security
manager
for as I said before make use as a
sacrificial wiser
so the way or decided to pass this way
is by modifying the
I'm where the methods that implicitly
called the
the convert methane with ensign invoke
you till rapper
and it was patched in JDK 7 update 21
and they did that by adding this a
search and this is Jack where
if the prior to class is not an
interface well cast are
object to the gym in class here we can
see the original version where you can
clearly see that there is no its check
I'm as a result to the hatchery if you
were to try to run the affirmation Park
you end up in a your will result in a
class cast exception
Arts in the next Mon ability is also a
libraries about
some component and as a pro in sandbox
issue due to his privilege violation
Java provides a way to you execute code
in a higher context in your
Creek given as an actress a nap with and
this is done through access controllers
do privilege block do for Lynch method
takes
two arguments one that's required when
that's optional the required argument is
a class anonymous or otherwise
that has a run method and this run
method will get Ryan
when more within the bloc in the higher
lower context
the second argument is an access control
contacts object and that's basically
assays see how the security context that
existed when the access control contacts
with is created
so if you created with a I'm interested
applicant and
when library code runs in with your
access control context it on trial
bill basically dropped religious for
executing your code if you're into it
with naam
within library code any would have a
higher context and you go to you do
wall more powerful things I'm on
November 17th 2012 in review found that
proxy doubt proxy proxy instance
does not see the callers access control
context unfortunately it requires an
indication hammer that they would
execute our retreat statements so
prior to GT his own this was not all
that useful
but he found that middle name method
handle proxies as a method as interface
and since
that allows creation of an invocation
handler incense
and you can use this to get access to a
protected methods such as chrysler is
defined class Nathan
the only issue with this is once you've
created the bound method and we even
have to find a way to execute without
putting your frames on the stack
and here's a will several pockets even
start off with some class that
you control and has an instance method
you want to execute at a higher context
me just instantiated you then I'm
describe the method type
oh the instance method you want to
execute and this is
just the the return value the diverter
class and then primer classes
you then look up the method using the
fine virtual method
and passage the desired class the
instance methods name and the met the
type instance
now you find it to your desired class
and sense
dry and run dry arguments drop arguments
as the name implies this drops arguments
before invocation of the method and also
in this particular instance because
the offset is your way on dropped the
first three arguments and object
argument a method are you in an object
array argument
once we done that we can create our
invitation here using that the panel
prices as interface
instance and at this point we so have to
invoke proxy new proxy instance
we have to do it on an interface that so
once we found into it we will be able to
execute code without suffering user
frames on stack
and this was passed in three different
places first in the method handles
function using I'm modifying the
fine virtual function which was modified
to make you something new
fine balance caller class method and the
main takeaway from this is that the
class return here will be it could
potentially be no and as a result when
we call access virtual here we could
potentially be sending mail to it
method handle proxies was modified in
the azeris instance method
and specifically the may be mine caller
a
call was added and within their the main
takeaway is that
if the prior a class is no or the prior
to class has a no class letter which
means it was
is like basically my break loaded pair
its my Rico that was loaded
then we will just return the meant that
handle without
any modification whatsoever and we'll
never make it to the spine caller
or you're buying caller function a
meant that handle implementation was
also modified and its fine caller
method just in case you make it this far
as the preferred
classes known then we will just throw an
internal error
I prior to this you would try to carry
on using a C trampoline and now it will
end up with a I'm no corner exception
art so the next vulnerability is in the
2d subcomponent and it's a he base
buffer overflow due to injure overflow
is reported to us by aids txt on
September 13th 2012
and exists in native code using I'm into
you have to access it using Java his
native interface
exists and sign a treaty media live it
and leave the image created
and the overflow occurs based on the
values for high
with and channels times for so
it takes four arguments the first which
is a type
that specifies full what a good daddy
you're looking at
if you specify the type is and wouldn't
then you'll be ordered
achiever the integer overflow I'm mins
32 which is the type four channels
with and hides is just a typedef around
the signed 32-bit integer
there are some restrictions placed on
the values here in that within height
both have to be greater than 0 and
channels has to be a greater than one in
less than four
but after that there are no checks
restrictions place whatsoever
so here we can see that if the type is
in with and because we're in the switch
statement
I am were multiplying within channels by
four
for modelling all those and then saying
it to WB and then later on where most
playing time you be in height
and using that to allocate memory so if
the value
Heights times with times channels times
for is greater than two 30-second power
it over Afghan war and the balloting a
buffer that is much smaller than we
actually require so when we write to it
all
overflow it was passed in JDK 7 update
17 through the use
the safe to Malta macro and this was
actually interesting because this was
patched
heard if you're looking at the open GK
source code
you can see this patch prior to you dad
that
JDK 7 update 17 been released
and here's a update is have been and we
can see that
there using the system of macro and only
fit sexy is will they said the levy to
the value
with an channels and then once again
they're using safety
mort on WB in four and only if it
succeeds will they said the BB
to you Davey times for and then once
again
to the before the call malek there and
multiplying WB in height before passing
it to my work
from ne the last 37.0 weaknesses in
outer bounds rate due to integer
overflow
as reported to us five tell it or both
on December 2nd
2012 c 2013 2420 was
the exists in been a decoded well
and its in San advt image
amet image rather is accessible via sign
a treaty image image representation
and the more normal function is set i cm
pixels
the issue lies and integer component
raster which is alas object
an intercompany a raster has a scanline
straight field
which is used without any validation
whatsoever
so here we can see a sniff it out there
said ICN pixels function and we can see
that the last
are you into it is a.j object in this
case it's definitely a major component
raster
I we then see a scan lines right field
being said
I'm as an offset from the good image
combining raster
and then here we see does nation's worst
players being said and you can see the
destination corner is
said base of some man to using the scan
lines right fielder and
that X&Y coordinates here we have the
outer loop where
both the source corner and as an Asian
porner are incremented without any sort
of validation
to prevents integer overflow and here
we're just updating the
destinations responders and in the inner
loop where once again
incrementing the destination for without
any validation
finally we're making our rights and
incoming source partner at the same time
so this was passin JDK 7 update 21
through the use of three new members
checks tragic source in check test and
in addition Oracle fully patched this
fire
I'm checking all in but are arguments
and not just the ones that were specific
to this vulnerability
so here's the check stray function and
we can see that they're doing division
to make sure that
if integer overflow occurs will return
false
same goes for check stores and check
test and then here is the updated
version is set I see in pixels
where we can see that and now they're
rallying accident
WNN here there validating XY H
you can see here that the rallying that
the de dos its array within the rafters
object is actually
valid and then here we can see the user
the
makers and they just introduced
arts the last war really is in the Java
FX subcomponent and
it's an interesting point the reference
the c 2013 24 train was reported to us
by italians or both
on December 9th 2012 it exists and calm
sign with pain platform to web page
and the issue is when page has punch in
a to functions in a call using jeanine
some 1 a.m. with allocate a buffer in C
Landon returns a pointer which then gets
sorted
and shovel and as an instance variable
and known as PPH
there's also an accessor method for
P page variable called get page and some
the instance methods within the function
will directly use P page
whereas others will make you so the get
page accessor method
since web page is public and the
get page classes also public were able
to it and it's our final were able to
use a placid
and modified and if and as a result were
rewarded to you
craft memory so here we can see a
snippet the webpage class and you can
see here that the
class itself is public we can see that
the get page class is definitely
following
and here's one in the native functions
Truk said Edenwald
and although it's private we can see
above it that says your boy is public
and here's the call to GW case edible
and within it you can see the get
the call to get page the way the hash
this was interesting in that we had a
slew of these come in all the same time
and I think that may be why its brands
favorite ever bug in Java and in JDK 7
update 13 as kind as a
make the hurting stop reaction or or
just banned
the a large number patches in this case
the con son with pain baggage such that
any attempt to access it
JDK 13 or up war zones and a package
access
exception there's also a package
definition research in less and for
every JK we looked at the exact same
but all that means is that you can't
strands I
tree the JVM by defining a package of
your own with in
con someone paid comes and with him %uh
he was also properly patch in JDK 7 UPI
by making the get page mended package
private
and fine also the net you can no longer
subclasses and
cool Carter me this parameter back over
drains so that he can go over
undertone and how these weaknesses are
utilizing the thread Wednesday
and so the first place around look like
to a jail cell was at
that calm down this year this at this
year's hunt down we decided to broaden
the scope from the competition itself
beyond just the browser but to actual
browser plug-ins
and the reason we do that is because
they the brother plans are actually
targeted by Mauer and used in targeted
attacks in 2001 the crash highlights
their own abilities eg
met existed in those plugins themselves
to include a flash rear and a forced
Java into the mix
at this year's countdown and and some
other people in the area in the industry
thought they were making it too in this
it too easy NEC coast is clear there's
my favorite quotes from when we launched
the rules
busy I was giving away 20,000 dollars
for free
which it actually feel like an idiot
time because there was so many 0 days
they were being discovered and the
mammoths emissions we were getting when
we launched the rules
a made me feel like we were giving away
20,000 hours for free
but that we did in any way we put that
twenty thousand dollar bounty on our job
and our expectation was that the same
box issue
due to unsafe reflection was going to be
we're just going to basically get a
bunch of those types of bugs because
that's when everybody was looking at a
CG expirations Enrique
release their paper in a lot of people
are looking at those have a bug since
our expectation was just to get a slew
of them
but in reality what we got from our
researchers who pre-register dish over
the competition
I was actually a top-four vulnerability
types that affect the Java
and I was kinda kinda interesting that
you know we would get it every type that
was
the biggest problem in Java James
four-shot brought in at least privilege
violation vulnerability
that he actually wrote up in a blog post
that's quite get if you leave your
search for it on the web
Joshua Drake run in a outta bounds right
now demands reminder million
they've been secure identity-based
buffer overflow issue and then murphy
brown and unsafe reflection lime
Leah and 40 for Java
it was the most targeted application at
this year's countdown
I'm because we decided to purchase
everybody that for pre-registered
contestants if they work
and so it ended up having 40 days disco
I'm demonstrated nm
from it was interesting theory to see
the different types of bugs that are
researchers would bring in
and I think our favorite photos when we
asked to move in if they had brought an
unsafe reflection by
job he said we have unsafe reflection
bugs
but we want to bring you something
interesting and so he brought a few
baseball for a flood
if they actually look at the limit the
landscape is off base after their racing
when I was there that we had
we've seen a huge week you see a huge
increase in Java in malware that is
actually leverage in Java
every day and actually interestingly
enough amir's the
Mona million discoveries that were going
on you see 'em at a huge uptake
in the unique in our samples out on the
gate in the sample said that we had
around the same time that there was a
large number of the issues being
discovered
we have up you know if you look at the
exploit your market and all the
different acts like if they're out there
on average you know and exploited to be
competitive in the market space has to
have to close job earn a release
in it just to be a viable for for
purchase
I say who you lookin like South
something to do. did
this shows visitors expected to have six
or seven Java vulnerabilities in them
a the other interesting thing is if you
look at the chart and the CD's that are
under active exploitation
you see an own abilities are still being
mona is they were discovered in 2011 are
still actively being used
in the landscape and that's due to the
fact that the install base for job is
not routinely updated
we have no we talked about the Websense
report were 93 percent of it Java
installations were being patched
after month in the release in the patch
and there's also the man I'm reports
show that
you know when you install Java it's not
on is selling the all major versions
that leaves them
you know users vulnerable to you
exploitation of these older bugs in
service still
you know gonna release from 2011
actively being targeted
in our sample said the peach was four
thousand examples in one month
attorney just nine gonna release and you
know them
the attackers are upping their game in
trying to get more Java vulnerabilities
into their
exploit kit in your tool sets because
they and innovation and give them a more
machines
but we want to look at is what what type
is on our bodies are available for
ex-players
out there so we we took them samples
with me took a look at it
penetration testing tools an exploit
kits they were out there
and came up with this table on on the
screen the GC right now
and and look at the type who own
abilities that they were actually
including
in the toolkits for use by people and
you see that the unsafe reflection
vulnerability is the most popular type a
boner billion the tool sets
available to exporters are and
penetration testers
a but an interesting tournaments is that
the Saturday
least privilege violation is actually
the bottom in less than anti diffusion
is moved up to rank number two
and available vulnerability types in 20
kids there is memory corruption
in the toolkit said he based buffer
overflows a being the most popular in
the talk at some cells
but but what what's really important is
what is actually being leveraged in the
landscape
and in surprisingly tight confusion in
our sample set was the most troubling
issue under active exploitation with all
with over two-thirds in the actual
a uni samples taking a manager type if
you can follow and safe reflection
followed by the the scrimmage violations
but if you look at it as Sam box bypass
issue may 7 ninety percent
about 90 percent and that under the
bonnet actually being used in a
landscape
I'm and another interesting thing is a
memory corruption issue I'm really
visible on the map
they are being used but they're just not
as popular and the reason for that is
the the same much bypass again the OS me
to have to bypass OS level medications
like deficit
in a so are they just work so that was
being included in the kids for use in
actually being used
a pass it on to jail now he's gonna go
over some exploitation techniques
art so I'm going over some at some the
angles for Juve exploitation and then
onto a useful technique for
memory corruption wonderfully is and
then all finally over
the server an hour that shows a sandbox
bypass
so essentially there to maintain its on
there is a must buy passes where you
essentially just need a ride and sis and
I
said security manager know I know find
security manager means once
you can run anything you wanted down
where you want to ever
the prom with that is any higher context
in your giving using a huntress a nap
with and you also
have to have no use a sec I know users
Akram's for memory corruption
you have your usual techniques so when
which could be a writer
function plan the problem with that is
then you have to deal with death and
esler if you have a an inbounds rate and
you also have an outer boundary then you
may be okay
in that you can't use that computer all
said & potentially do something
interesting with that
something that guys sometimes easier is
the you so the JavaBeans state in class
which was given to us by our tally turbo
so
John mean cement represents a single
dollar same into the form instance very
broad
instance method and then arguments so
what you can do is
allocate your buffer whatever where on a
really you control
and Emily after Chris statement I'm and
replace
the statements implicitly created access
control contacts with one that's far
more powerful
I'm you do that just by creating a
permission object to adding all
permission to it
cream protection domainhire a base of
that and then creating an ex access
control context using that once you've
done that all you have to do is use are
gonna really to you
basically swapper replace the as create
statements access control context with
your controlled one
and executed and you execute at a higher
context
so on our over a I'm case study over is
an hour that was given to us and it was
me more as he be- 2012 17:23
which is a vulnerability and the hot
spots like a verifier that leads to type
infusion
como characters except are that you have
to have a hundred
at least a hundred instance variables a
some class class
a and you have a static variable have
another class class B
you then have to have a method within
the class the takes classes these type
and returns class is tight and other
characters ago this is that you'll see
repeated calls to this function with no
as the sole argument
when we took a bar we saw six class
files three of which were completely
useless and that her unused in that's
they had no side initializer
and in reference and anything not even
themselves three from
were very very weird clearly a useful in
that where the extended Apple it and had
it and it meant that
admit method I'm so that was definitely
our entry point
another had a.m. and implementation of
projects such an action and made users
is not set security managers that's
clearly useful
and then another one way is referenced
by a and I think the
one that extended ap lit and had three
sacks methods that work all
that use for in and of themselves but
because they were used be sought
including
but we saw that their new
characteristics as CVD 2012 17:23
so we had to do. he skated to find the
actual CPE
interesting thing about this is that we
were told that Allah Tories Jul obvious
care issues
but they did not make use the advance
options such as code for office cation
as a result we were a wedge issues there
commonly available jodie compared to you
get the source code
I'm once we did that we were already off
the skate by just using basic compiler
optimizations
such as constant propagation to cut
elimination function inlining
and constant function evaluation so
here's a snippet love
the the the Dr he's getting the compound
version
and not just walk you through what it's
doing the first thing it does is checked
to see the shower running
Java version that's being run and if
it's not one point seven so it's on JDK
it will bail out and do nothing if it is
though it'll continue on and it all
taken the
class that X implements the privilege
exception action
turn into an array of bytes
here we we see the user the generic
constructor class to instantiate the
anonymous classloader and then we use
manage object major factory to get
access
low class protected method with NC
the method being in votes so that we
lower our privilege accepting
action class and then we invoke have met
in within that class and we send it to
pray owners are
the last parameter is the class we just
loaded and the first priority is a
strain that served
that's given a base of the aging of our
there was serving the star file
within the EU action classism the one
that extends pillager implements village
exception action
we start off in the trigger do prove
walk and the names are clearly not where
he was originally named by
just read named to make it easier to
understand
we take this ring that we've been given
and split it by letters HJ
and turn it into a URL
we then take the class were given and
get access to its constructor
and instantiate the object using the
euro we were
give her the string we were given so now
we re end up in the constructor in the
first thing we do is run axis controller
do privilege on herself since this
implements
privilege exception action this as the
result of executing the are run method
I'm the run method consists solely of
person that sits can you imagine also at
this point we know if I the security
manager
the bar really is already taken place in
everything that happens after here is
stage two
all happens hours/week going runner sage
tonight that from within this we
over your old to the string we were
given and we create a file in our apt
data directory
and it's called JobsOhio tempter
we then read from the euro and write to
the file and once that's done we then
trade executed feeling that we will try
to load as a DLL
so now we can see that this now the idea
of his gay we can see that
its actually very different from the
series I was actually see the 2012
thirty-sevens fifties only six and we
use generic unstructured to instantiate
a restricted class in this case in arms
classloader
with NU's manjaca commander factory to
get access to low class
protection method and we den use that to
load a
much a subclass a privilege exception
action what we've done that we know if I
these three major
and grammar siege to an executed
and that's when i turn it back over to
Brian's they can go over how or who has
been dealing with all the malware and
your abilities in Java
alright so we have a unique perspective
inside a busier day initiative because
we deal with a lot of vendors
time we deal with disclosing a lot of
own abilities aroma said 200
bedbugs patch just this year I'm so we
get a Julia Gillard an interesting look
at how
vendors are actually responding to the
disclosures that were actually sending
to them
so if we look at work or the recently
made it very public customer commitments
about how fast they're gonna turn around
zero their days are actually under
attack
they are give up their releases 24
releases a year though this is not
you know Mike Microsoft's Patch Tuesday
how they have helped him
I'm the other interesting thing that's
something that's not really known
and not report it very often is that
they're actually improving their own
ability time I'm
a year-over-year I so on average ZS
emission every cent or or or
in a in Java takes about three months to
pass rate this puts him right in the
middle of the pack
for for vendors caching software that we
work with
I'm but the interesting thing is that
they Maxime decrease that I mind over
the last three years
while donor release emissions have been
going up in their product
so it's actually quite a feat you know
the it from an external perspective it
looks like they're
a trevino working to a decrease the time
I'm
staffing up their response organization
to
I'm to deal with the incoming gonna
really disclosures as they've increased
over the years
a the other interesting thing is not
commonly reported is how aggressively
they are adjusting the attack surface um
jammer
at to deal with the vulnerability
disclosures are going on he saw this
jail mission you know we had a whole
slew a pointer dereference cases they
came in and they patched our
damn the by Justin putting the package
in the restriction list
I'm but over the last ten to fifteen
hear it sorry i three years we've been
actually killed 15 zero day initiative
cases
I do to patching and in this perspective
kill means
we've got the Queen's we purchased the
vulnerability from a researcher
the I'm we've done who has announced
this we know to be exploitable but a
patch comes out
and it fixes the bug that we just
purchased
rights over the Maxi killed several as
cases they had no idea that those cases
exist in Wheaton they may have been
the but they did actually pass them out
and and
by did by the techniques that they were
using to every detail
reduce the attack surface if you look in
detail using the u13
her seven you thirteen they chose three
fun trust upon any reference case is
that we had
and a new 15 they killed two these
privilege violation cases that we had
they're doing this like I said my by
increasing the after package
restrictions which will go over next
and also tightening up in an looks like
auditing the least privilege violations
what you see on the screen here he is
the package restriction this
modifications
over the last several nieces we may sign
this n u-9
with a bow and at that point there was
twelve packages there have been
restricted
tablets and u10 2011 they didn't make
any changes made in New 13
they added another dozen packages to
that restriction lest
and you see you know you're in the
example the interest appointed a
reference as com sign
when pain at the bottom there they added
that in there effectively am
million in their own ability in in the
in the jam affects component if you look
in you fifty know it's interesting
because they actually remove a setup
packages
and add another centre-back it is the
weather actually doing is they're
removing a lower level package
and a adding a higher level packaging to
further reduce the
attack surface on the application in u21
they made a lot of modifications
and in and you twenty-five add a couple
more
so you can see in in u21 we on the ad
the remove GlassFish to external and
added the GlassFish package so further
reducing the attack surface
on the air interesting thing about
watching the modifications to the
restriction lists
is dead as as a person you doing one and
a passion houses
you know that there was a problem there
are probably gonna release in their
seizure you look at those as a bee
as they're at it I'm you can also use
the mapping that we showed earlier to
come to get an idea of the type governor
bill you're gonna find
in those specific packages that are
being restricted
a.m. so you can see here in this is the
JDK 7 you twenty-five there there was
forty-three packages that have been
added to this restriction list
and a new nine there was tosses been
quite a bit movement
in the restriction miss the see a lot of
com son or your patchy
packages sold it's almost an expectation
that in a future release the hold up for
a higher happened in there and for their
reduce the attack surface same
conclusion
four goals whether quite a storm over
the last three years especially within
the last year
they've seen a large number gonna
release closures occur fifty-plus
nuvid DDS emissions have happened the
last reporter that have been submitted
to them
to adversaries are leveraging the
zero-day vulnerabilities
increasing the largest patches from
Oracle for Java
there is a focus in the research
community on the sandbox bypass issue
with and safe reflection being the most
prolific but I to Division being the
most
utilized in landscape band
the chief component being the one that
produces the most severe motor abilities
according to the CSS but he is not
utilized very often in the landscape so
whether that is a how you wanna
correctly scoring the CSS i think is
gonna talk to this conference about how
cs4 ng is used by the it's just
interesting observation
process improvements by or will they
have made quite a few process
improvements they're making commitments
and changing their attack surface in
Java
face tougher the restriction less that
you just saw and and we hope to see more
on that
we like to thank you for company's
presentation we like to think is easier
researchers who summit in Java
vulnerabilities every last three years
we can add on this presentation without
you guys if you have a job
0 day that you're sitting on an you want
to give maybe extra legal money
a WHOIS you can submit it to the zero
day initiative
we will pay you handsomely and and all
the response was voted for you
zero day initiative dot com we also want
to thank you ever sing labs
and as securely expirations for helping
us with their supporting material about
this validates so many assumptions we
had
in the product I early in their research
to pass thanks in your mind hunting