is good morning my name's the Toby
that's mickey
we're going to talk to you about York
could chill hands how many have you are
here because there is no space in just
four stalls talk about Android
when you're lying
I'll how many you have any experience
with you are
orgy a tag be booking systems exe
okay so this is intended to be a general
overview and introduction to you are
us those stuff that is repetitious for
you
our apologies and if there's something
new or this something I should like this
talk about
let us know first
most important legal disclaimer this has
nothing to do with our employers
this is in no way they work their
opinions this is all our own stuff
we take full responsibility for
everything and anything said here
anything goodies are brilliant and
everything bad is our fault
mickey wanna be that no
law I'll
a wehmeyer miners mickey a
what I do for a living is rate hardware
firmware I am but that
we but I his three
last year we did talk about Windows
Sidebar Gadget and that that
used to be a web developer and turning
to the dark side and got involved in
real security
much about it describing myself my name
is totally
I do enterprise security the I
break applications no hardware and
unfortunately after six as well
a.m. they've been doing it while I guess
so
today we're going to run through a bunch
of different areas releasing background
on what you are it is
rather talk about what you can do with
it all that sort of stuff that
it's fun for we're going to talk a
little bit about embedded systems and
why this is interesting
we're going to see examples tools were
and talk about how you would get
involved in you are why it's fun easy to
play with
I'm never gonna give you some examples
away places where you succeeded in other
places where we haven't found anything
interesting in finally
we're going to talk about if you're
developing embedded systems
how you can do a better job than some of
these companies have
love protecting their a systems from
explores so
general injure I this is really just
about sharing our experience this is not
going to be follows your days and
exciting new attacks your has been
around for a really long time
so there are people who have explored
this that this is something where when
we looked
it was normal to us and it was something
that we saw in not many people talking a
lot of people talk about Jade had lotsa
people talk about other sorts is
reversing we're seeing
people talking about %uh stripping chips
these days
we hadn't seen this discussed so
overlooking here to do is to give you a
little more about
how to use it and how to explore with
how you go about doing so your
background
technically you art stands for universal
a synchronous received Jones
receiver transmitter what is it were
we're not really sure if we think it
came from heaven or maybe it's gnomes
I they're pretty good sized actually
obviously do I
it's been around for a long time I a
very long time their references to it in
the old I'll
AT&T systems their references to seeing
it being developed
by Gordon Bell for PDP systems Johansson
is what a PDP is
call okay I'll
that's been around for a long time it's
a fairly fundamental concept
the kids build out the number different
ways the thing that matters about it
really rather than
where it came from or or who first
designed it is
what it's used for and what goes through
it you get a desperate
what some data all sorts of interesting
data sometimes you can get raw data and
format it straight
no control anything going through it
it's very interesting
the other pieces how embedded systems
actually use it
and the reason that's interesting is
that it's frequently used as a consul
acquit
so on a device that has no KVM
has no expectation up having a display
of having any sort incurred mechanism
use this as a way to actually get access
to the console
on or at least a one other TD wise one
other channels that they can use to
specifically do debugging or update or
modification of the system when it's
running
what's it for
well officially it doesn't really basic
things that just translates from
parallel to serial for months you can
see it you doing
okay good in practice where you really
end up with is a
interconnected that's feeding between
different parts the a
system which means that you can use this
show as a consul
and we'll talk about that you'll see
that and that's probably going to be
more interesting place but you can also
use it
when you connect to it to see me
information passing between
different components on PCB you can
actually get different data streams
going back and forth which means that if
you need to debug something fairly
subtle
between your storage in your amor some
your CPU in your store do you can
actually start doing that here you can
see interesting things moving back and
forth
the big 10 like I said in is that it's
going to be a given consul
and it's going to be used by most
embedded systems for that purpose
when I used a tag well jJ is cool but
it's more expensive in terms of the
hardware it also takes
a much have you left in terms of
building your skill set frankly
you can give you are too anyone who's
got a i
systems background estate got in your
face you're going to give me an ex
consul
and as long as they can play with that
they're going to be good in contrast
is using J tag you're gonna be doing a
kernel debugging gonna be dealing with
memory dumps you need to be on the
reassembly and understand what's going
on in terms of the system
it's a heavier left they're both useful
that they do so for different sorts of
things
so we talk about your soul how do we
recognize it
physically allies this is what it looks
like
or pins usually more most cases are or
been sticking out BC the a sometimes
they're not
there's no header soldered just or and
brawls in a row
a sometimes its stack
makes it easy simple all you need
or you are orbin one for voltage
1 per drop a reference and one for
receiving one Richard
so who what system
so an interesting way to
verified and you are using your is did
you are finding you are
is to okay everything and had on the PCB
the for per what it's worth actually
most the time when we looked
you'll just see at row for vince or in
the majority the case is resolved
wrote for Vince it's really common but
there were some where r
look at it and I didn't see anything me
he would grab it and say I'll
yeah let's try that and so we want to
bring out exactly how you do that
so this is the the flow I'm the rock
below are you doing you find interesting
in the bat in any configuration on the
PCB
I could be or buyers in a major s
for instance or arm
a role and Rovero all as
nothing to do with anything you see on
the board or are you follow lines
going from the CPU onto something
once you met those out need to find
round
to the I'll talk about it later
this is a written in blood so just to
make sure that you don't prior to all
sometimes live there buy votes and your
203 votes and that they don't be
like each other you think that the
ground your device
you would be embedded system the mean by
that to all would be embedded system
while it's booting if you are is used on
the amended system it will transmit
so the easiest way would be just
take receive lineup you to all and just
spoken all the pins and so you see
something
its gibberish on the screen could be its
just brought it up or a your in the
different bothering
the Prince the and you're just too tall
it's not garbage if you see English you
ever
we'll talk about the actual individual
tools reach these steps will mention
going to bust fire or talk about how to
check for voltage everything else in
just a little bit
somatic systems at a fundamental level
the really very simple things and to
make an embedded system you just mean
three basic components in need some
a RAM you need a little bit a storage
any deceive you you some simple examples
a different you components that you
might find
but there are literally thousands of
vendors and
tens or hundreds of thousands love
components that you could combine in any
safe
are in any combination to give you what
you need to be an embedded system
they're really very simple and as a
result there being played everywhere
this is the cliche with he say isn't
gonna
have to pay for it later Internet of
Things
all but this is where you're getting the
effect that you put in logic and
everything
generally where you're gonna see as a
result of this because they're
being used everywhere is that there's
actually fairly consistent
layouts the UC for different PCB's
and the it makes it much easier to start
recognizing things that's why
when we start looking at different
boards are looking for York
the majority of them it was actually
pretty easy to find the actually or
up pinouts even when things went really
different
it would be pretty predictable in the
recently in quotes around interesting is
how do you know what interesting as well
as it turns out
you look at a couple these new start
noticing I'll
that looks like those are the right 4
pins those look like an interesting
combination
love I'll tag points I
I should go get something there
interesting actually comes pretty clear
because this layouts are fairly standard
just to be clear this is not up I don't
consider this hardware hack a
this is a the low-tech way over
finding interesting stuff you don't need
to be a hardware hacker to do this
all you need is a couple basically all
very basic knowledge
your mission like
before we move on operating systems %uh
you may run into some art also
real time operating systems there are a
couple different bar
vendors out there but more and more what
you're likely to see is going to be
either
BST or latex and really almost
I'll or what eighty
personal time why any personal time it's
probably going to be Linux
it's not going to be in the next like
you're used to if you run it is a
desktop or for server
it's gonna be stripped down to the point
where
most your favorite was amazing and then
sometimes a really odd things are there
so we've seen cases where
X I'll start is in there even though
it's not necessary
or II GV
on the compilers a short sometimes
but it's not consistently they all the
debug tools the CD DUP
telnet met that it's still there
snow you at the same time useful stuff
like
in the I may not be there you may
literally be doing chatting
%uh texter echoing a text into a file in
some cases
we have seen one with the iiNet yet was
are useful
it was really anybody with it was an
anomaly was the time we can see one with
the Senators
up I don't think we ever had to resort
to add
by up a it was simplistic in many cases
most tools will be missing at least the
system level will have a very limited
file system in general
so the everyone things are others when
we talked about this is when people ask
what we're talking about
iran says okay so rather is right well
short routers are the obvious ones but
there's so much more but the child
stuff that we had sitting here are some
examples:
be did this on our own budget we did
this on our own time so we can get some
of the bigger and more interesting
devices but
you're gonna see this in well for
instance you'll see this
in enterprise-class routers airport
priced past
firewalls anything with embedded
hardware systems you're going to see you
are 10
anything doesn't expect to have had you
see your in
I you're gonna see this in things like
home power control systems I extend
this is a amo are you'll see it in
HDTV stringers show your arm Hulu
I are your Roku box will have it all
these sorts of things are likely to have
your
up we didn't you take apart are
refrigerators
up both because well we got really old
church leaders but also because
we didn't have to play social treaties
but you're likely to see if something's
got invited logic you it's very likely
to have your tennis
I found myself on a treadmill one day
looking and thinking
I bet this thing has your their bet it
does
by and certainly it in the
I actually what I'd be willing to bet
money that there's actually order
face you're gonna find this almost
everywhere including call
yet
with tools from
okay so the most easy
wait to start find what would be using
the FCC database
open on the Internet you can just look
up in SCCA being
find interesting stuff so
to make things interesting
to connect to the network and will do
our
live example if you have any questions
please feel free to ask
no
over
yeah
between model York's so the question was
sometimes in devices you'll see
multiple York interfaces available and
there's going to be some
logic that's used in some code is used
to control which one
%uh is going to be that send or receive
data from
at different points in the platform I
as far as I know the
when we've seen that it's been in the
kernel for the system as it starts
booting
I'll he been stranger
represent ice cream but my computer
doesn't like I'll
BIII I generally be looking at the
system configuration for
a which a a device it's actually
configured to a read out to in reading
from
at but I haven't seen many others would
be interested afterwards to look who
you need to know which ones you see in
there
it's intentional
course unfortunately didn't make
sufficient sacrifices morning to the
demigod so we are playing with fire a
little bit
but I'll no
those the Mac decided to go on strike
okay I don't like the slides so up
you have to trust us I or you could be
on your own device right now
pull up to the FCC ID database and we
can give you an example
love what an FCC ID looks like you can
find them on the bottom other device
on so you see something
under the list goes on
certification stamps you'll see
literally something that says FCC ID
miss when it's P Y 30 9400 124
as an example its always going to be
there are anything that's a legitimate
device is going to have an FCC ID
you just go to the database and search
for it
and your goal and you'll get back an
entire Saturday you'll get
on datasheets for you'll get images all
the PCs
for a couple different views are as well
as having the
covers stripped of other components and
general information it becomes really
useful it's the really easy way to go
and look for
I things that are likely to have your
dinner faces and to try and figure out
where they are
the next one on this is a bust are
a anyone here does not know what a bus
part is you had
somebody okay so this is a buscarte
stunning alright then
are sitting down used to it this study
the right thing
is mmm what's commonly called the Swiss
Army knife over hardware hacker
arm we we're using this because
it's more convenient to use it doesn't
mean that we can use anything else
other out we gonna talk about the print
or just like eight bucks on ebay this
one is 30 bucks
not not a very expensive
20 you all up things all love
a backers control sabes
it allows you to interface with a huge
number hardware interfaces that allows
you to control water rate and
reset the device into a number of other
cable things its
you can spend many many hours just
talking about the Aspire
and its actually I a something that's
been built out of the
of the packing in this or the builder
community
other major community it so that the and
they seem to support the companies that
actually make them
they're just really any things to do
really handy things to have
next on the list on the list as a
multi-meter
so we're talking about how you make sure
that your
voltages in too high for whatever your
tools or this is how you want to do it
there and that's an awesome ground by
Mintel
she can also do without battery in
Andheri the
other tools like this eight bucks on
eBay USB UART
able the may if you can
buy from China in the under a dollar the
by the mall a soldering iron
very important here find I'm hands on
the PCB in 10
connector bus art to it you need to make
the
comfortable a magnifying glass
is where old I'm and see very well and
sometimes it as a really really small
some these embedded systems are tienen
arm
the we move for instance is the you
have a credit card or the entire PCB
arm the there is there a TV
a beaming devices that are mobile mobile
rather the imply that 3G much but to
them and they connect to act as an
access point
those are really find me PCB that that's
what they're really small
can do it with a magnifying glass and a
bright light
so the the reason you would want both
the USB UART cable as well as something
like the bus pirate
and you really you probably want both as
well as the other in pieces the
soldering irons other ish
if you have the pins actually set for
you if you actually have pins on the
test points I then you can easily just
plug into one of the
I test points and plug it into your USB
port with the USB to UART interface and
it's very easy
if its editing the yield just get a
whatever's coming out of the ordinary
face
I that's really handy to have at the
same time
a lot of the times you're searching for
what the pins actually mean and what
they're for and having something like
the
aspiring which allows you to be very
polite very
the configuration very assortment of AC
working with
becomes much more useful so that you can
experiment and look around a little bit
finally we have something to show you
back to the FCC ID so I'm going to go
Google
FCCA the first was all
no web page redirects is the new one it
needs the FCC ID so let's take the
if the that this area this one
the third the first three characters
and then the rest is that
with the one are
ensuring then she an update and inside
this thing
use the wings is internal photos binge
of photos
other device its easier to
find compatible devices without buying
them just fine arts CA the
and looking in journals and you don't
have to spend money
this is a a great example
as you can see undermined
get this large
as you can see here have or
and sticking out no sometimes the FCC ID
pictures will not
represent reality because the these
companies that make these photos to the
FCC for approval
but it won't be the final piece is the
most the time so
the production products my not have
those and sticking out over
but are as you can see for peres
can only mean one thing well
its most likely only going to mean one
thing: thank you for that
and so we have a CPU
we have a last year and
your side to this is the the Rio's
sometimes the resume and
in you can Google the chip and get more
data off it
there
and
so a simple example of how you would use
the
FCC ID interface on the
it seems like a really simple and
obvious thing player
really is just tremendously helpful it
in ends up being the default thing
go to on every single case yet
you know it's for the
its military at it was our driver
and it is it is a valuable service
provided by the government
who was a I'll so
yet okay bottled up so
a eureka moment is when you plug in the
your and then you get the the next show
up which is awesome
we all love the next shows and most
though these just the show
and as ru and no authentication
no authentication whatsoever it's only
get a shell
it's really funny it would show that
didn't require you to login
and once you're here in the show in just
browse it
and you you see interesting stuff for
instance you can go into the
web directory up your device and see
all the while going to the numerator
going to force them just
a bless the a
see the permissions everyone
some so these are named very funny like
info
sorry this is dealing with an embedded
device so this is something where
if you didn't have this interface you
have no other method
%uh getting to this information it would
be a pure black box experiment
you'd be talking Raub bird forcing you
be fussing EB
asking whether people had seen all the
sudden with this
you have the doors wide open
everything's just exposed their
beans
so why would it matter
so the question is would right so
so the question was why would this
matter if you need physical access to do
it
and I swear we didn't his he's not a
friend of ours we don't know when we can
set him up to ask that question
up so when we give you the answer in
like three minutes
up it wasn't that he got paid to do that
thank you there
up the answer
will win the next slide others I show
you it will show you the answer that
question
awesome questions a so
what else can you do you looking a
from the device from the inside out
you you have an insider look what's
going on inside so if you if you
tester attack so you wanna check
something against the vice
it's not just the black box anymore you
get the CD processes
sale if you do something wrong get to
see %uh crashes from the kernel you get
that
yet more information you get to interact
with it like it's a real computer
like it's a real system in this is some
%uh the
d the wonder in the value tranny gets
lost because everyone's used to looking
at
debug information in seeing this stuff
from every computer that you interact
with
instead of thinking about the only get
this from a laptop or Unix System or
whatever I'll see you use to that has
SSH or has some other interface that is
friendly to you
and is intended to deliver this
information to you imagine the plugin
because its next to me this still all
and you want to know something about
what's on it and you decide that you're
gonna try and figure out how it works
all you're doing is throwing stuff up
against a blank
unresponsive wall in till you have
something like this as an interface into
all the sudden
for the value be able to explore or
research or chilling learn about
this becomes this takes you back to the
point where you have mail system to
interact with
see other stuff that you seen here none
of this should be surprising or unusual
to anyone whose blog into a system we're
done debugging any sort
what you need to recognize is that it's
cool because otherwise
you be guessing at a blank wall you just
not have any sort of information coming
back and it makes it much easier to find
things
that make actually it may actually be
useful
and interest and to answer your question
there
all
that's one aspect certainly one way you
can do it
absolute that that's that's mean it said
his answer was yeah
you use this as a way to do for your
body research against devices
and then what you've now got is the
specific knowledge about an entire class
in the device
so um for instance as anyone who
read the a scanning internet 2012 report
that was published on
a pastebin in which is yes so the
compromised many many many many
embedded devices and replace the
firmware with custom firmware
and they had to find one abilities in
all these devices that they could use to
do this
well the way you do something like that
would be the you something like the UART
interface
standing very like the UGA tagay on
by thats guess
but that's exactly what you would use
this for the kids you got additional
information
it also in some cases gives you other
like for instance the certificates
a sometimes not just the public
certificate
sometimes also the private key is well
for signing you'll see the
passwords stored in there that are going
to be you know a universal across all
the systems in the entire
a space I you can you a number different
things you can
easily use this for giving yourself
debug access for you or
earth for fussing investing is difficult
if you don't have any
suzie is difficult but it's more
difficult if you don't have access to
debug information at all
all the sudden the device stopped
responding and you have no clue why you
don't know whether it was dis-
a fuzz tester the previous one to
fifteen back it's much easier to do this
sort of stuff
when you actually have the information
yet I'll
by the way the docking we know was that
as responsibly dispose everything they
were actually going to talk about to be
clear we did
responsible disclosure on vendors were
engaged in sex has been released
firmware updates have been released its
up to date in the vendors would work
with
that would like to thank them and
soul
why else would this be interesting I'll
you asked about you can you connect easy
for users to find all your abilities
you could connecting remotely with the
interesting thing is in this is
something that
up someone I K think tremendously highly
oven and just
is really an inspiration %uh pleaded
I'll a
couple years ago and some work that he
did Barnaby Jack did an ATM hack
a couple years ago everyone knew
everyone saw it one other things the
clean it out though is that
the cheat the vault in the ATM really
hard to get and it's really hard to
crack
however there's about four keys that
allow you access all the logic systems
and having the sport you can unlock that
pop it open
plugin the USB stick a close it turned
back on
reboots with your firmware game over so
even if you walking up to a system
having access to this interface
its external exposure you understand
some other pieces because in some cases
they are
are accessible even without cracking the
full case you can do some interesting
things
so
forensics on embedded systems what once
you do chain went to make changes
who you are a after the system reboots
at all disappears it's all about I'll
the way at them in a bad system works
is needs its all operating system from a
flash loaded into RAM
and boot it is I'll every time boots in
both from the same image
so every change you make after it boots
as well
so what can we do with it
a we we thing ever on way to show you
guys
up prank your friends
basically we did what we did was we take
we took a
the very or cheap robber
that the battery back in the back which
make the mobile
innocuous your video on a second and
reprogram
reprogram that with a with this
is that
alcee no value
a second
wall sound does not sound we have
the tiger
between our our
the battery back in the back
default settings with the American
Society I think that be at the pawn box
toward we know that
specifically designed to scare people
it's not the same as carrots and
designed to encourage you to put push
the happy red shiny button
there we do with this connects to the
router after the roots
the other day the voices to transfer
files to the device
this is the your interface again this is
the
more or other device
as you can see the lights are blinking
on the router
doing something and you never you
network showing up
it's really blurry tho you can see the
second
yep yeah
most things a connect no automatically
Datz wifi and
I most people connect automatically tatt
wifi
the border I paste the link to a Google
and a new network and I and I had go
can y'all read that
its yeah
so by plugging this into the router
the router was wiped a reflashed well
but I believe are not reflect
reconfigured
was in the Flash which is actually in
benefit here I'll
and now become something that will
automatically compromise anything that
connects to it
the beauty is when it rebooted is make
pointed out way
slow boil
that no forensics want to get the power
all resets the normal all
yep pretty much you can do this you can
do that you can do this and it would
take some work
you can do something for the questioner
bigger
the say that again
what we need be these in a jackal
know you mean the unit %uh the Jordan
reno's on the
in this box one is and internet are you
know she'll
which we use the servile so taxes
as a web client and three what we
telling the embedded systems a
W get worse are the files from that line
and we just get whatever we wanna as at
first he wanted to put
rick rolled by the was to make Bieber
the medicine
and I refuse to do that to people I
think it's obscene crore
all so the beauty is the you just
pull the power and the configurations on
it flashes back to where it started
there's no evidence there's no
information and at some point someone's
going to have to pull a powerful waste
yet and I think this level solar panel
on this thing
and one for a long time unless you live
in the pacific northwest
be so
arm the message to the end so we can
make a
once again your show you how
back to a router and for a
when the system so
we can do this its buries its a fifteen
dollar router
super it's not like a hundred-dollar
hundred-dollar
I'll a
I'll and distinct all it's certainly not
as powerful as a
on blogger something or or pineapple but
for some cases you don't need to be
and at fifteen dollars I'm much more
willing to throw a fifteen dollar device
then I am to throw away under $200 or
$500 dollar device
a much more willing to throw a fifteen
college a place
sheesh so we work with the
a we mow at taking the Belkin
and they specifically upgrading the
firmware to actually just require a
login
and if I'm in a little this is this is
that the first step
in terms of actually doing this the we
don't recommend getting rid of the
your interface that doesn't make sense
anyone who's worked with hardware or
build hardware understand you need some
way to do this work
but there are some simple things you can
do that just make it more secure
who first one being just simply
require login have a user and password
in even if its generic even if that
changes just with your
different version is the firmware you
raised the bar just that little bit
or a backup all
I'll the other dates are two things you
can do you can disable logging this is
probably
this is actually a really important one
%uh because even if you can't log in
even if you just got a blank screen if
you're dealing with
a consul output for anyone who knows the
existing you're gonna get on the console
you're going to get just a dumb but this
is lots continues to hear the alert for
this is too many things going
I as and party admin login is gonna
still out there
you can disable it easily enough it's a
simple thing it's worth doing and
prevent it
real-life example would be: an embedded
system
have had a USB port on
you are to the with credentials cannot
be and you just see that
the logging assistant counsel once you
plug into USB
a storage device that looks for a
specific file a specific bad and outputs
it to the logging industry
so that will allow you to basically all
back different the two older versions of
the firmware because thats
the the way with supposed to be a a
backup
other waited the the only other way to
update the firmware on otherwise would
be to go online
so I you can remove the ordinary face
if it's possible if you don't need it
got a cousin to the device it's really
the
the most effective choice but like I
said as as people
you deal with hardware it's going to be
hard to justify and doing that
this is what we've recommended in
general and yet
this is so easy to you the is this on
the streets or in pretty obvious to you
are
we met our goals we wanted this to sound
like something you could pick up in an
afternoon and it really is
it's just that simple so the question
why are people doing this go play
going complete doing all
so yet we wanted to make this all the
fun so we get this thing
arm the device ago rip lost
open were here we will try and
accommodate requests from the audience
you know and was the buzzing or other
sorts of stuff
by the way I before we get distracted by
doing that
realized he didn't mention it at the
beginning the first
embedded talk I ever saw in the first
thing I ever saw that made me think this
artist of the school was Barnaby Jack in
a talking about debugging and rewriting
firmware on a home robbery
did he manage to make the home router
download binaries you are interested in
the head of time
inject his back door into them and then
recalculate the hasher the hash
displayed on the website
was correct for the modified Mel by area
he did it with the J tagged a
it was amazing and awesome he totally
inspired me and
I think inspired lotsa lotsa people so
we just wanted to say that we wouldn't
be on this platform for him
so I open the device
the power I have a bust are
connected to my computer just switch to
the second
them or anything turn on the camera and
show you what the actual
PC looks like
them year
them
K
so this is the rather on the table here
a simple
pins
any questions all I think
were happy we're going to keep poking at
the stuff we've got some more time but
don't feel obliged if you don't know I'm
interested to see this part you don't
have to stay the slides
will make available I'm not was a
majority this is just an example how you
can do this and how easy it is
so if you've got questions you'd like to
ask feel free to come up with you
are interested to see this please stay
or happy song it's not
we won't hold you to it and we won't
leave you leaving
so all we need is a
ground Tx and Rx mmm so first we find
round
we said you if you use the more thing
you know you know this
this function
that you could you guys you that year
so to find the the ground usually when
you do is you look for something
like this a whole
in the PCB or a exposed surface
the frame
of the wireless controller like this for
instance
this golden strip will be using
connected to ground sometimes the ground
plane is obvious
the antenna and as
are also good grounds soldiers gonna or
these things one at the time a that's
the grounding
that's not gone the other way so
this one would be ground I'm it wasn't
going to Best Buy with ground
to that one that's it we're done not now
outside the fun stuff
gimmick to the last forever
said that too
a serial sorry go back the
different modes in the bus bar I'm gonna
choose you aren't number three the
and I'm going to speed up the bus
up most devices will be 150 in 200
some going to use that the
I have never encountered a situation
when I had
wear a hat that choose the parity bits
or any other information so that just
leave it as the fall
and be up with I'm going to use is
normal because I have brown
connected so much for the gives me an
opportunity to sniff
a as macros a lestat macros
I can do transparent bridge between the
bus hire
and devising a live monitors in billings
now and
bridge with no control it's a more
technical missed me but I'll
saw on this so it's nothing and
I take the wire from
the rx lying on the bus are defined TX
line on the vice
devices now powered all I'm gonna are
gone and Bo
each yet be number one
nothing the number two not or
you got something up the number two the
system moving up awesome nah that was
easy
you know it's a very for the record
no we did not I miss that was that
literally was a device
that was just bought a box so we
we we saw that we got the the TX other
device
now we need to find the Arts line and so
we can write
you commence I'm gonna put it on a
bridge mode take the other line
that the TX from the bus fire to the RX
in a device so I have
2 pins that one of them is the CC the
other one is
I'll rx and
remember the CC the battery connector
online somewhere
so Michael E I know this device with a
friend
with that the pen and start typing and I
can see it
on the monitor because
I transmit on the bus by I should
receive it back from
from the device so I know that was close
and
oh I have a shell what you know
super cool you know how to file system
and that completion ball nice you have a
%uh rip romp there so you have a sense
of what use are you probably are
got here yet
next and at them just things that
my able be Sony the really interesting
cuz they have no control
jo's can just play with it on see
this one
has star
so
more than 100 is an example you go to
the ww2
and you can see all the while now only
that
you can see all the permissions so these
are
execute minor show you which ones but
there we're
this is a for example because this
embedded systems even is this a better
system in particular shows %um
color very nice so these don't know on
but by being able to see everything the
Weber you can see
all the possible
screens EB interacting with Trey the
official web interface that the device
has you can see
which ones may be available which ones
are going to have more interesting data
in them
which ones are going to have more
interesting commissions if you're
looking for cross-site scripting
vulnerabilities a single injection
opportunities
command execution opportunities this
nixon casts so much easier
you've got all the source you don't have
to be plainly
scan or use any rituals you can just go
and look at the source and see
everything might possibly want out of it
everything that you know how to do
against a live system the airline
running in
running on you can now do instead of
having to blind people get advice
yeah
the her
there yeah
now you will get stuff like top or
necessarily also left for
on any other searched high and things
but yeah I'll
yes you have and and it it's a good
point you're always in see something
interesting
a I is a little it to some extent at
this point this becomes
and exercise in had you explore
a fresh in the connected system have you
explored to assist you just compromised
or the you just
gain control over so you can learn about
and do interesting things to it
and explain filesystem
looking for tools interpreting process
is looking for a crime jobs
looking for key files looking for SSH
files looking for anything like that
those are all
reasonable and appropriate tasks you
tell that the
non-volatile RAM you can
we take this device be configured with a
script and
so that's the problem so a 10 things
that we've found really useful
is just doing this for pure debugging
purposes be on the watch when we're
fussing something and watch
how it fails and how it crashes and
actually I'll see the logs becomes
really useful the you're going to do it
demo the fighting but it ended up taking
longer to run your solidifies test and
we really want to spend in here
we wanted to show you how to use Beach
the
was this device and basically make it
crash a
the problem is it takes about 10 minutes
get no
thats goes up memory and then it crashes
which is worth actually noting these
devices have so little memory that it is
very easy to overload them
another reason why becomes nice to have
this view into them so you can know when
you're pushing too hard you can back off
potentially and have something sings
any other questions
K
this is in our presentation ok this is
been useful to you
a we're going to continue booking at
this a little bit otherwise
if you go thank you