have no I don't gentleman and so here is
my presentation
it's about a higher low frequency attack
and defense took it so today I mentioned
before our presentation and it's more
about how to develop where it's less
about how to crack it so it might be a
little boring even though I graduated
from the morning on January University
and still a little rubbery and so I will
makes it as simple as I can ok so here
is my agenda and I started this
presentation is combine all our works as
firms 8360 unicorn team smoke and we
focus on development and a in all the
hardware such as embedded device off
I'll go to System cars and our job is
guarantees a rarity Security office she
was sixty and we are ready to shower
wall rocks in telecom and data and about
how to be a signal to how to sell and so
on so if you are interested as Jessica
White so that's about the french Foreign
you know they low-frequency and
high-frequency tax so how to get there
is a true ways and in low-frequency we
are you know there's Khamenei some key
card use government and in all there is
a smart card anime fair cost that's
already know about it so
2001 when you guys I don't know you do
you know about this and so let's just
skip to the US so this is a low
frequency attack and China we gotta go
to a neighbor and crawl and this towards
this to you can buy everywhere so if you
want to cry hard to justify it and in
all you put it under your president
button so it can't exactly say this is a
common but carries some SOCOM II into it
can it can burn false and it can change
the contact of your ID card so
everything so if just account all this
juice can do is just a nice errors so I
was and I you know I want to access
system and I want to call ID card I want
I need to do is you know bring a laptop
on the brink are bringing car door and
you know of course I need a bad show you
some huge and it's not complicated so
with as a developed a new hardware to
solve this problem and it's quite a
convenience just so you can you can now
access them with your family and with
the hardware that is so before we
introduce the details of this of this
hardware is done let's talk about how
CID access system works so this this is
the ideal accessory you know by ID card
ID card reader and the you know the
controller and so fast and easy credit
card reader will send out of the carrier
signals by the attending a carrier
frequency is about one hundred and
twenty-five the second these articles
reach the ID card readers working area
so so the restaurant which is made up of
competence and received the erotic
novels so ready for a continued to fast
motor or generator generator that powers
sittercity signals under the system
clock by this signal so severe disease
chip so that only the chip will really
the serial numbers from storage and as a
dedicated and their editors 000 number
all the carriers acknowledged by the
feds Mull regulating Cody and send it
back to the reader so I don't last this
reader we would emulate undergoes a
number of comparative data base and they
choose to open a door or not so much a
smashing of our production which he was
nominated the heck I'd approach to 430
weight as you know make some metal
badges 22 2011 to clone so this is the
first of all and all it can do is just
you know putting the card and the
carburetor so whether crises is working
this storage the signals are
communicated between the car on the
counter reader so his death
owners so you can change the serial
number and leave you know that he has
more than 20 this is the second one is
ours is ours so this one it can I mean
what do you want to and you can put a
serial number into and a president you
know President Biden and the only thing
you and so this is the
little bit of it can burn the caliber
furs and you know the only thing you can
do is just you know about 200 number is
important so we just developers a server
the server thing is the heck I deeper
and so way earlier and plugging your
phone and we also connected the app and
we would hype
what we want and you can perform over
all the ID card hacking you know the the
measure of all this matter is that I can
do so here is a detailed and added two
models controlled by your apt and as you
can see her you can carry audio
connector so when you use heat can just
plug your phone by the audio in fact the
you know the hardware details in office
he hired April it doesn't matter so you
can just sit next to ok so I applied
temples is and you know you can read and
summarize all these protocols to cart it
will find out to all all this article
protocol is included in this basically
crude as he's 25 cents and so but if
there is any see any protocol that we
already know yet it doesn't matter we
can record on replayed on does so you
can't do what he can do it all they look
for his card and a whatever he's managed
host coat and a USB phase code where
Murray
so while we do we use the audio
connector these ideas come from the
hijacker program program from the
Michigan University and you know you can
use power on about us so it's a power
and a decaying commuting head to between
your phone and the hardware
carries the original version of project
hygienic and it has also you know it
also has audio connector and they're so
proud of our 11 channel is used to
transfer data from the phone to my heart
so other updates as Mike East going
peace deals to change for data from the
Proteas so we designed this route to its
advantage for separate true makes this
the simulation voice signal adjusted to
the digital signal of the other
celebrity and audio signal after the
fountain has the PCBs so far this period
cuz he's iowan pass is Victor so it can
connect to the compactor to get of the
digital signal and probably opt out of
the DART rail and after our top three
bears and Mike voice signal so so
serious ship ease the brain of
Heidelberg and can this country were all
up and and you know as the club so large
storage story original signals so you
can play a referendum and as you can see
5 2010 heart beats so it's a pretty
pretty good it's pretty big if you just
want to record a voice again so is there
are two hours by micro USB battery and
but as you can see I see as I see it in
the industry partners sorry and and 502
powers by both so while your battery and
in need to downgrade to 313 votes and
microUSB it so we should be opposes
server to operate your vote
8255 and all they see if RTC 3558 that's
why we use it it's quite ship and it's
easy to yours
so is it hardware aspirate the
underwriters occurred to me later or
secure and we can transistor under this
this this Agreement is wise how do we
get out of the parameters of the all the
elements that we use radar and chip to
them this demonstration
chip 2008 model that has since from the
antenna design offices hi kar diya
person not quite complex could
complicate it saw all this notice all
the things you should notice it's the
digital and assimilation out and you
should I just 22 you're under the
judgment on tenor and do you know the
electron had a magnitude as that that's
all since you sure you should notice you
know if there's some designers your guys
you guys I believe all these things he's
quite easy to him after the hardware
design lets talk about their software
design and while you're the product is
quite pretty low power and as you so the
more time we can use under the mall team
the heck I differ with standby
so we split the highest toll so quickly
it so we're required the carries a lot
of my ID card products such as a
high-tech of the year and as you can see
that UK version so it's comedy using
china about 80% of our concern is also
used this product in China so just
quickly example of the protocol the 2k
10 all these data base is 60 64 bits and
including I started as you can see I
just doesn't say that I don't need to
repair it and so when his club I Z when
there is an ID card is close to this
software will be where dem that easy
125 125 Kandahar's signals so after
demolition under the security code this
final day of final data that we got
where exactly the same as you can see
easy's lower pictures details about
80 this guys know about him I just go to
the the the writer and it means the one
in north dakota and installing edges and
so so besides absolutely coats by the
mementos from met there will be there
will be some data parity-check so if you
want to go somewhere in the crowd at a
party other than an important and it's
only for guys to see it clearly doesn't
matter so what we want to assimilate her
car and it's the prison boys from the
radio so you can transfer the data into
the into these pictures from AD and I'm
sure you will
what is the lowest of the other North
debater
of the of this this format and format
into from an individual man just called
and 8 bids so whether I see some ID card
Iraq needs and read out readout is this
image data signals and the approach for
us as a perforce function so what do you
what you need to do to you to increase
the idea and I don't put a major formats
so I want to cum hard as you can see as
we mentioned before there's a lot of the
masses that you know from the doctor I D
car so there's a bit of code under some
general 80 factory letter word they use
but it doesn't matter decided cardoso
communism's we can just a recorded on
this story it's a story on the way we
needed to get out on the basis that's ok
so communication picture and routines
often and as it as it comes easy
differentials amendments code to compile
and compliance
communication between the a plan to head
to head the two and the value that I is
packing a little maggot so the
management just relying were reduced to
use this data bytes decoded data code
aids and a competitor competitor will be
used to transfer
simulator that drew the digital theater
and the delaware Dakota where these
matters to appear della flow and you
know the presidency is valid and as you
can see deal after channel yellow and
the right channel is named after the
competitor this is the new rule I never
lie so these chill if this very big
concedes the very depths of this picture
is all 672 and russia has denied entry
if you guys want to know about the house
so the committee communication between G
four from the haggadah protrude is
similar to the apt to it's also the big
flow and the difference with the icy
fired earth and the way to remove the
Bears and the at whatever text me Mike
and use the ATM machines a sous quiet
it's quite easy and besides this might
be a lipid difficulty first is this is
our first time your presentation but
don't worry we already uploaded all
these
may get up so you guys want to know that
deterrence presentations
time to crawl through our request under
give the address on the Temple of Hera
Pheri
greater as it is
record right track so just a normal and
now it's a presbyter
only regard this is is this how it it
requiring
so when speaking to me this is
processing the data off the NRA down so
long and a radio ad ID approved near the
courier you can see the context
so 11 we use the model
so you can see the digital changed and a
number on the screen so it means it can
read as a career as a contact out and
just trace similar to Barton and ass ok
simulators and workforce model so you
can just increase their idea and
immediate out another time where you
want to talk about and want to cry just
a tad bit and she was always has tapped
so hairy and what about the future as
you can see you can this is just a
little freakish hey it's just a
low-frequency climbed a sniff and a
summit on board for us but we are trying
to outrun out our doing our job to
combines the high high frequency into it
too long and hard to call another
thirty-point 30 points five six
megahertz discard all you know this is
here is the funny and romantic scenes as
does germany made in Germany Germany
many
I think it's amazing but its terms you
should use our laptop is not comment on
the so we are trying to combine the
functions into the have had a pro and so
now you can just talking to us access
system with your phone under your lip
piercings and a laptop or tablet quite a
bit after the hike and its and Taliban
the high frequency the frequency and now
he's there is an appeal is called DMV
such as apple pie are about his
attorneys for the MB is the PBOC these
people work and Sundays so easy to call
the house there is a lot of research
about is how to crawl on how to replace
a young record operate in china is much
much simpler and it's quite an intense
quite easy because it only needs to look
at how to cross into Japan opinion and
it's quite such as a machine and not not
quite that easy but in China just made
under read all this out and hear such as
Eid your name or your burst person dead
and John are under the valid data only
and is not included a really doubt it
and you know I starr said the Amazon you
can tell you don't use a CVV
you can just use this information and
you can buy
everything what you want so it's quite
how how do you read this all this
information so we've met a 222 rely out
but people use in excess of Sarah
so this is quite a comment but soul but
it's not it's not quite a comment all
it's not quite a cool thing so it
doesn't matter this readers and as a
result of this this is quite easy and I
saw it as a centre the commander with
the response and in care reform I S and
get all the information mentioned before
all this information is you can just get
it out in the area from ads and it's not
included how why we don't use an access
all your phone with tmobile and we will
remain a reader so their power your
phone if you want to read our college
really cows and it's so you want to say
it's not quite a snot snot companions as
you know you're putting to prepare for a
near his pockets and besides the current
the carburetor I'm sorry that I think I
readers AC a lot of its part is it has a
big power but it should be used with the
laptop so it is still big I don't want
to hold my laptop to solve it
it's much simpler than and as a way to
use or to chip in a white two radar when
you transfer the data and
receiver of the that's how I got this
young reader is a true to pass wider
radar and laser receiver receiver will
plug in your laptop or your ghetto did
you fall off and and if this were
transferred her from the reader and show
it off at all this is a serial port so
quiet it
classism the prison with quiet onda cero
control this device an account and a
connect to the tags you that's that's
absolutely zero chip it's our readership
and up by the SPI protocol and we found
a rear command our fares the response
and after all these things which has for
a response to your laptop that means to
your receiver so what are you can't get
such as if I want if I put this near to
my credit card and you can get as I
imagined credit card number provided
data under your idea number so you can
buy whatever you want
says that we use we put it into our
lives and as you can see you can say
nothing and so with all this message
will come out
so before we talked about his how to
attack us or let's talk about how to
defend eight so very some some already
have some products to defend a defense
draw such a drive-by derided as there is
a little bit funny animal am an american
product of them in our model car and I
don't know if you guys have some very
worried I might have the disease a guy I
met before and it's quite good but some
of the other day when it is alright so
so many girls don't want to use this
this and besides they embark on these
amazing but the question is is
chargeable 2012 the battery of these
this product to need to do is just
another one is quite sure that how we
will in madison parker defender to bed
at least a charmer and besides its
charitable besides the current
this one holding to find that you know
the hyperposite but I can transfer the
load so we combine these two functions
together it can't find low frequency and
a heart and a height of organs so it's
it's this present this product is much
easier than a to protect we mentioned
before so it all the things it is hard
it had to be there if there is a reader
and if they're ok you know stand out to
the signals with nonsense and detergent
dammit so the major problem of this
product keys 10 while if this ends as
battery and you know if you don't want
to retire due to every day and how
sensitive that means if there might be
some but it's quiet there is always
drama generally always so your batteries
will be run out quickly and besides we
want to charge of also the show this to
their products you might be saying it's
all the same problem and so we shouldn't
matter it's true the cathedral more and
more Singh and precise that the robbery
and the
sensitive come out of the fifth problem
that's our battery that means if more
accurate pepper and you know to solve
these sensitive problem we love our
power trigger barrage and to make this
as you know they they said we should be
like card as a credit card so we use
some of the PCB
our card funded M
this is a higher frequency is uniquely
his only career under the black one is
the electron was a reader so they tried
to find her so easy
area de antes on this weekly reader is
not but it didn't work as it sees no
vacancy yeah so I remember it is putting
its means it rocky
so hard to find Ares you know if you
want to put it in you want it and you
don't want to get out you don't want to
every time you want to tap tap
I don't want to play it out and so what
do we want to do is just lay there is a
bus car radar so there is some you know
some how to pronounce something that
there will be only carrier so we were
detected and the when we find out it's
about career or so the generals will not
be walked and this product's my beast
and by about one month's one was charged
on does so we just want to make it
longer and there is out there is in the
markets there will be some device to
detect you didn't wanna get us in South
under this level on this on this topic
these guys are all over so if you get
out of the market the device will be no
one be armed
August problem I met him before he's not
quite a barn and because you don't care
if it will be seen as a as we want my
site and you can use a large battery and
not quite as cool as you can do and so
if you want your own so here is out of
the shower I believe the fourth quarter
will explain so we just upload all these
three products that before we better
because our hardware to diner is married
is marrying in his home so we don't have
the old south korea scatter so we were
uploaded a one-by-one now I think the
young reader all these get have now so
you to focus on Opera class all of my
info over issues such as I mentioned I
will combine all are so this is our way
designers and thank you very much
on what you're doing it without using
the phone how do you have to be that
close to the contact info that one for a
tax would be effective task number it's
it's supported the e-reader under you
know it's it's quite a close ok and the
next one is there a way to actually
attach an antenna text if you could put
it in the closing an enclosure next to
adorn its like to camouflage could you
put in the extender antenna on to that
device and yes I believe it's not it's
quite a different hotel because the lake
are the reader's attention is you know
get our largest power about to attack it
don't have so much power as it did back
in the closure would be able to extend
that but I'll talk a little bit off line
21 that also the last most important
question can I buy one now and leave
Singapore with a hacker I D Iowa now I
have interviewed international any more
questions
know how to thank you very much