foreign
I work at Stony Brook the work I'm going
to present is Deb fast orchestrating
code for Quorum systems
what's special about this work is that
we're focusing on not algorithms not
designs but we're trying to write better
code that is easier to manage and follow
okay so what is a current system
her Chrome system has a foundational
communication pattern where we have a
node broadcast request to a group of
nodes and then collect responses
the system will then proceed with a
quorum
the Chrome size can differ for example
it could be majority
a super majority
or all of the nodes in the group
a typical example of Quorum system is
consensus systems based on considered
particles such as paxus and wrapped
so Quorum systems are widely used in
practice especially in Fault tolerance
systems such as coordination Services
databases and blockchain systems
Quorum systems are hard they have very
complex State transitions
for example we have a node broadcast
requests and wait for replies within a
timeout
there are lots of conditions we need to
process
or one
we could receive a majority yes replies
before timeout
or we can receive a majority of no
replies before demo
or a timeout we could receive majority
replies
but they are a mix of yes and no
or a timeout
you know we could receive no not enough
replies
and there is more
in advanced Quorum systems things could
be more complex mainly because
we need to process multiple different
sized quorums in a single broadcast
so for example in addition to the four
conditions we talked about
we could be waiting for a super majority
of yes replies before a second timeout
and or before the second timeout we
could receive enough wrote no replies so
that a super majority of yes replies is
no longer possible
or at the second timeout we could
receive not enough replies to form a
super majority
so
coding all these complex conditions is a
very hard job and the question we try to
ask an answer today is how can we make
the code of these systems easier to
write and follow
well first let's look at the status quo
what's our current way of writing
the code for the systems
the way we often use is asynchronous
coding style or event driven
so we write the broadcast in one
function
and then we have another function to
handle the reply messages from that
broadcast
so this rep so this reply message
Handler is usually triggered by a
message Loop that keeps looping over
incoming messages
and dispatch the message to the right
message Handler okay so why do we write
code like this
many for two reasons one will be
educated for many years that this is the
right way to write fast Network programs
and there are many famous open source
libraries such as dbv promoting the
style
number two
coding this style
is consistent with uh some pseudocode or
some types of formal specifications such
as TLA Plus
however coding in this style has issues
one of which is known for many years as
stack ripping
basically we're breaking the continuous
logic into two separate functions
and this means that we have to manually
manage the context share by these two
functions
for example in this case we have to
properly manage the entry variable
and and more the Callback function is
now triggered only once but triggered
multiple times
and as we develop the systems we write
more and more callback functions which
eventually cause too much cognitive load
for developers this is also known as the
Callback health issue
so how can we address these issues
well this brings us to the Eternal
debate of asynchronous coding versus
synchronous coding or
event versus threat
so here is a typical example of
asynchronous code or event-driven code
where we trigger RPC in one function and
we write another Handler function to
handle the replies
we can convert this asynchronous code
to synchronous code using thread so
basically calling the RPC will block the
thread well
coding this style is much easier to
write and follow
but it is potentially much slower than
the event-driven code because of the
overhead of using threads
and in the past many years people have
been using lightweight threads such as
fibers or stackful coroutines
to mitigate this effect and actually
it's proven that using lightweight
threads
has very low performance overhead and is
almost as fast as event-driven code
and this inspires us too so we built
this framework called devfast which is a
core routine based framework so it works
as a user space library that a process
can link to
we provide this uh stack for quarantine
interface so users can Define their own
tasking
we also provide a common utility
functions such as RPC and current
scheduling
we did spend a lot of time building
these features to help us build
distributions and distribute systems
easier but today what I want to show you
the most is the event abstraction that
we come up with to help us develop
Quorum systems
so I want to show you this interface
corout interface with a the same
broadcasting example
here is how we create a core routine
and here is how we do a broadcast
basically by triggering our PC to each
server and this RPC is now blocking
it returns an event object or PC event
ER namespace in our namespace we call
this event but conceptually it is
similar to a condition or a promise if
you're familiar with those names
and then we can wait on the RPC event to
collect responses
so here you might spot a problem already
that we're doing this weight
sequentially
so
uh you know each weight will block the
carotene so it kills all the concurrency
of other order replies
so it will have low performance
it is also difficult to express the
complex conditions such as a collective
Timeout on all our PC events
so this is why we invent the Quorum
event
abstraction
so a chrome event
is a collection
of events so here we add the RPC event
to a quorum event and then instead of
waiting on
the individual RPC events we do a
collective weight on the Chrome event
for majority
and the library in the background will
guarantee concurrency it will process
the replies out of order and unblock the
weight as long as a majority of yes
replies achieved
also it makes expressing complex
conditions much easier we can just go
through the conditions with a simple if
else statement so it will be much easier
to express conditions such as reject
or timeout
okay next I want to show you the
expressiveness of that fast using a real
example
epexes
so epexus is an advanced consensus
protocol
that has a fast path and a slow path
so in the broadcast if we receive a
super majority of yes we go fast path if
we only receive a majority yes we go
slow path
epexes is a very popular project is well
liked by the community including us not
only its design but its code is widely
used
in related areas
okay so how can we express if
expressively implement EP access
first let's try to draw the control flow
apexes in a human friendly way
first we have a broadcast
and then we wait for the conditions for
fast path
if it succeeds we go fast path
otherwise if
if if it doesn't we try to wait for
conditions for slow path if that
succeeds we go slow path
otherwise we go error handling
so now I want to to imagine how can we
implement this using a asynchronous
style event driven style coding so what
are the events
we need to process at least three types
of Events first
we need to process the reply for that
broadcast
and second
we need to process the timeout for the
fast path conditions
and third
we need to process the timeout for the
slow path conditions
Okay so
all these three types of events and they
will actually
form very complex
non-deterministic State transitions like
this which will further
satisfy or deny the conditions in the
main control flow
and out of order
you can imagine this will be very hard
code to write
so
how can we write code in depth fast for
this
okay in that fast we do broadcast and
initialize the current events
and then we'll wait for the fast path
conditions and then if it succeeds we go
fast path otherwise if it fails or
timeouts we try to wait for the
conditions for slow path
and then if that succeeds we go slow
path otherwise we go error handling
as you can see this is very human
friendly code right it's almost direct
translation of the main control flow
makes things much easier
well you may Wonder okay this all this
all is natural so what's it like to
write apexes without that fast
all right this is the code we copy from
epac's original code repo with some
simplifications
this is the message Handler function for
the broadcast
well first probably you may notice that
with with this coding style we often
have to mix the main control flow with
some minor case
you know conditions such as this is
handling a delayed message we have to do
early return
right this makes our code a little bit
untidy
next
you may notice that there are two to
do's
in in this code these are actual to Do's
in apex's code
and if you want to actually if you want
to implement the studios yourself
you'll find that
it is harder than I thought
so for the first Studio when you receive
enough rejects okay what you need to do
is you need to do you need to invalidate
the entire Quorum including you have to
invalidate all the future messages all
right so this cannot be a local change
you cannot like write three lines of
code here or make a function call here
to implement this you have to rewrite
the entire function
right second to do is similar it is
processing timeout
all right we know that processing
timeout in CR event driven style is very
difficult you at least need another
function call for this
and we know some nice hacks you know
from later projects based on epixes is
that you can trigger an empty message at
timeout right so that's a nice hack but
you know more and more such hacks in our
code you know harder and harder for
people to follow the code
so the last problem I want to discuss is
is this
so you may notice that in this code the
fast path Quorum and the slow path
Quorum the sizes are the same
they are both a majority
okay this is actually a special case for
apexes if they have optimizations that
when the replication group size is five
the size for both quorums is three
so they can write code conveniently like
this
however if you want to support more
General case like replication group size
more than five
you cannot write code like this you
cannot you cannot replace one of the
number with a larger number it will
cause liveness issues
so
if we look at the epactus sorry the dev
fast version code again
we don't have these issues
okay next I want to talk about another
example copilot this is not github's
co-pilot but uh consensus protocol
published in 2020
which has a nice feature that tolerate
any server fails slow
okay it also has a fast path and slow
path structure
copilot's code is based on apex's code
and it has about 2 000 and 500 lines of
gold
and we re-implemented copilot with that
fast so with all major features
implemented
our version is about 1 600 lines of code
in C plus plus
here I want to show you a comparison of
the algorithm and Dev fast version code
and the regional copilot code
so this algorithm description is we
directly copy and paste the text from
the paper
again First Step do a broadcast
the second step
gather the fast path quorum wait for the
fast path conditions
and the third step is
uh go fast path if it is satisfied
and fourth step is
if fast path is rejected or timeouts go
slow path okay
all right so
without looking too deep in the cold I
think we can already notice that
fast version is cleaner
right it's easier to understand
it's an almost direct translation of the
text
and it handles complex conditions such
as time out more elegantly
well
another problem I want to discuss is
very interestingly this is exactly the
problem we chatted earlier that
for a co-pilot the first path Quorum
size and the slow path current size are
no longer the same they're different
which means they cannot directly reuse
epex's code for this
so what uh eventually they come up with
a nice hack that they reversed process
in the slow path and fast path
so that it avoids the live news issue
it's a nice hack again it's not hack but
more and more hacks we have in this code
it's harder for us to understand it
okay
next I want to show you uh evaluation
comparing our copilot implementation
against the original copilot
implementation
so we try to answer two questions one is
about performance like
do we have a lot of overhead compared to
the original implementation
and we did this test on Azure with the
three replica setup
the second question we try to answer is
can Dev fast help developers to deal
with complex cases
such as fell slow so we measured this by
data field slow test in which we
injected different types of failed slow
errors such as
on CPU Network and memory
so this is the results for the
performance test the x-axis represents
throughput and y-axis is the median
latency
you can see that that fast version of
copilot has about similar performance
comparing to the original implementation
with a slightly higher latency
so the next question
fail slow so this shows the fail slow
test and each figure
the blue bar represents the case where
there are no
failures so it serves as a Baseline and
each other color type represents a
different type of injected fail slope
failure
and the expectation is the throughput
could drop but no major drop like not
like less than 20 or so
I do want to say that we verified
co-pilot in its original papers setup
that it can tolerate any server slow
down
however in our own tests which are
different
from original co-pilots test that we
noticed something interesting that in
some cases the original co-part
instrumentation has more throughput draw
than we expected
and in one case it crashed
in comparison uh that fast version has
no such issues
so I do want to emphasize that we're not
trying to bash
the co-pilot's implementation it is a
academic prototype which has done its
purpose well of validating the idea the
message we're trying to communicate here
is Fault tolerance is not only an
algorithm issue algorithmic issue it's a
also an implementation issue
okay quickly summarize my talk today
Quorum systems are very hard to build
and asynchronous programming style makes
it even harder
so we present that fast with a quorum
event abstraction to make things easier
and we analyzed two cases EP access and
Copilot
you're welcome to check our paper which
has more details on the internal designs
and more results of the co-pilot
evaluation
and it has a wrapped implementation also
has more discussions on fail slow
failures
uh thank you I'm ready to take questions