thank you
hello I'm Georgie bear from qinghan
University I'm very glad to share our
paper about data log detection in OS
kernels
data logs in OS kernels are caused by
locking circles
in concurrent
threats namely one thread holds a lock
that other concurrent threats want to
acquire
data logs are harder to find due to the
no determinism of Kernel concurrency
data logs can cause
performance degradation and even system
costs
there is an example deadlock in Linux
PTR FS file system
this bug existed for over four years and
it was fatally fixed in Linux 5.9
this bug is hard to find because
multiple functions are involved and the
related threat in the living is in
frequent at the wrong time
to detect the Deadlocks we need to
perform two basic steps
first we need to extract working
constraints in concurrent threats or
code paths
a locking constraint describes the
dependency of the health logs and the
Concur and the currently a catalog
uh second we need to detect locking
circles according to the extracted
logging constraints in concurrent stress
or code pass
a data log can occur in two threads
namely
apba data log or three
threads namely a b b c c a data log and
so on
many existing approaches use Dynamic
analysis for data log detection
and the most of them are designed for
user level applications
Dynamic analysis can achieve low false
positives and a supportive data log
reproduction
however the name analysis requires
substantial test cases to achieve good
testing coverage
and it also introduces runtime overhead
neuron testing
a typical kernel Dynamic tool is lock
depth which has been widely used in the
Linux kernel
it performs long-time monitoring and
tracking
based on the granularity of log class
according to log
dependencies and rules
some approaches
you'll study analysis for data log
detection
and then most of them are designed for
user level applications
static analysis can achieve good
detection coverage without actually
running the program and test cases
however it often introduces
false positives
and the lacks the support of data log
reproduction
so through static approach for kernel
data log detection is Racer X
it performs solosensitive and the
inter-procity analysis of the kernel
code
and then it detects locking circles
as deadlocks
however resources has a high false
positive rate of 46 percent
which limits as Effectiveness in
Practical use
in this work
we aim to design a new static approach
of Kernel data log detection
to achieve better accuracy and
efficiency
from start kernel data log detection
there are three important challenges
first
when extracting
locking constraints it is challenging to
ensure both the accuracy and the
efficiency
especially when the kernel code is large
second when detecting unlocking circles
it is challenging to compare numerous
locking constraints in loss of code
paths
finally to achieve better accuracy it is
changing to drop Force fossils with
short time usage
to solve this three changes we propose
three key techniques
first we propose a summary based log
usage analysis to extract the target
code path containing distinct locking
constraints
second we propose a reachability based
comparison method to detect locking
circles from locking constructs
finally we propose a two-dimensional
filtering strategy to drop false
positives
by validating code path visibility
and a concurrency
now let's see how to extract the login
constraints using our log usage analysis
the first step is to collect the target
code pass that contain log related
operations
our analysis use a fluency
field sensitive and interpret video
analysis of the kernel code
it also uses a Anderson steel aliens
analysis
to identify against the log variables
to improve accuracy
our analysis create and reuses function
summaries
to reduce repeated
early analysis
uh it also drops Target code pass which
contain repeated log related operations
there is an example of Linux effs fail
system code
in this example
we find that the functions effx free
block and the effs analog block both
called the function effs on Mark SP 30.
so when the function is analyzed
we create a function summary for it
this function summary stores the target
code path
uh and law created operations in this
function
so we can reuse this macro summary when
the function is caught by other
functions
after collecting Target code paths we
need to compute login constraints in
each code path
we use a static log site analysis to
handle the cases of occurring and
releasing logs
when a log is acquired we create new
locking constraints and add the lock in
the log site
when a log is released refund and drops
the lock in the log site
with the Locking constraints and Target
code pass
we need to compare them for locking
cycle detection
the first step is to identify the same
logs in different code paths
in this step we use a field-based
analysis according to data structure
type and field
the second step is important namely
comparing locking constraints in
different code paths to detect the
possible data logs
so traditional method used by Reser X
and other existing approaches is very
simple
this method starts the comparison from
each locking constraint
and compares the current knocking
constraint with with each locking
constant in other code paths
if matched the method replaces the
current location constant with the
Matched one
if not matched it selects another
locking constraints for comparison
there is an example
which contains four code paths
each code path has Just One login
constraint
let's start the compilation from the
coreopath
pp1
the detailed steps are shown in the
figure
after the code pass tp1 is finished
let's start the comparison from the code
pass tp2
the detailed steps are shown in the
figure
from these steps we find that some of
them are repeated
which are shown in both words if this
repeated compilation
can be reduced
blocking Circle detection can be speeded
up
based on this idea we introduce a new
structure named in direct login
constraint
it combines multiple locking constraints
for a reachable node
the definition is shown in the equation
let's see the mentioned example about
the mentioned example again
we still start the commission from the
code pass tb1 and add some indirect
locking constraints
during the comparison
so edit our login customers are showing
in Bound words
after tp1 is finished
we still starts the commemoration from
the code pass tb2
now we can use the indirect login
constraints in tpy
and strongly in both words
to reduce repeated collaboration
thus we can find that our comparison
from tp2 has less steps compared to the
traditional method
the job Force positives from two
dimensions
the First Dimension is to validate the
visibility
of each code path by using the 3xmt
server
there are two stages for validation
when performing log usage analysis for
numerous code paths
they perform lightweight and impress us
code pass checking to improve efficiency
specifically we perform tracking in just
the one function without handling
variable assignments so this tracking is
impress us but fast
when checking possible data logs
which have fewer code paths May perform
heavy weight and precise called path
checking to improve accuracy
specifically we perform checking across
multiple functions
and handle all the variable assignments
so this checking
is slow but precise
the second dimension is to validate the
concurrency of code paths first we check
whether the code paths have a common log
if so the two could pass a network
concurrently executed
second we check the core graphs of the
two code paths
if this could pass have common parts in
core graphs
they may be secretly executed at
different time points of the same thread
thus they are not considered to be
concurrently executed
based on the three key techniques the
proposed a new approach in the deluxe to
statically detect data logs in OS
kernels
we have implemented delos with the
column compiler
and it performs static analysis on the
irvm bed code
in the evaluation where you still have
to check the source code of Linux 4.9
and 5.10
the evaluation runs on a regular
personal computer
we use column 9 to compare the kernel
code
with the configuration of all es config
the table shows the detection results of
the loss
we find that by using indirect locking
constraints
the loss reduces much repeated
compilation
it also drops many false data logs where
validating code plus feasibility and
concurrency
the time usage is less than
seven hours which is acceptable
in Linux
4.9 reload funds 46 catalogs and 39 of
them are real
21 Deadlocks have been fixed in Linux
5.10
in Linux 5.10 kilos France
65 catalogs
and 54 of them are real
31 catalogs have been confirmed by
kernel Developers
The Links of some confirmed data logs
are listed in the slide
still all still has some limitations
first the loss has some false positives
for several reasons
for example
is field-based analysis can make
mistakes when two different variables
have the same data structure type and
field
moreover if it is analysis yes
intercrusted you and the following
Institute and thus not very accurate
in addition if code plus validation can
make mistakes in complex cases
such as array index assignments
second he loss also has some false
negatives for several reasons
for example
yes bottom up
analysis is not complete the handling
code functions
Laura it fails to perform an asset of
function pointer costs
in addition
he lost assumes that a code pass is
never concurrently executed with itself
finally let's conclude the work
data logs are dangerous and harder to
find in OS kernels
to detect kernel datalogs the proposed a
new start approach named Deluxe which
has three key techniques
in the evaluation it allows fans 39 and
54 real deadlocks in Linux
4.9 and 5.10
we believe the laws can be extended to
detecting other locking issues
such as double locks
and using sleepable blocks while holding
spin locks
thanks for listening if you have any
question please feel free to contact us