today i will present our paper face
efficient framework for transformer
replication on gpus
transformer is an important type of
neural network
it has been widely deployed in many real
world neutral language processing
applications
here i show example for sentiment
analysis
basically given a sentence transformer
predicts
whether a person is happy or not
if i say i'm happy
transformers should predict happy
if i say i'm unhappy
transformers should predict unhappy
usually we expect transformers to
predict the same sentiment when
substituting the synonyms in a sentence
for example
frosty cold and frigid are synonyms
so the transformer should have the same
prediction
let's say if transformer predict happy
for foresty and code
it should also predict happy for frigid
however it's not
the transformer may actually predict
unhappy for frigid
this is called
synonym substitution attack
it has been widely identified in many
applications such as hate speech
detection and question answering
and transformer of education tackles
this security concern
for group of synonym
transformer verification predicts a
lower and upper bound for labels such as
positive and negative
if the lower bound of positive label is
higher than the upper bound of negative
label we know transformer is robust for
these synonyms
however
transform verification actually leads to
heavy performance challenge
there is a second level latency of
transformerification this is much higher
than the mini second level latency of
standard transformer
so
we need efficiency
and we want to accelerate transform
verification the key idea the key
challenge is to support is unique
computing pattern
for example there is usually high
irregularity and 50 of sparsity in
transformation
if we use dense computation
there is heavy redundancy
if we use sparse computations such as
cool spots it is too dense
so let's look closely at how
transformerification works
thanks to the water embedding in modern
nlps synonyms usually have similar
warning bearings
so we can have an input bound on all
synonyms
then transformer verification propagates
this input linear bond to output linear
bond in a layer by layer style
and we can check this output linear bond
and see if it is if it makes different
predictions
let's look at a concrete example for
linear layer
in
transform inference we have a concrete
value for each neuron
suppose we have a neuron x1 equals 3 and
x2 equals 1.
we can
compute prediction y at 5.
and in
transformation we instead have a lower
and upper bound for each neuron
suppose we have x1 between 1 4 x 2
between -2 and 4 we have y between -2
and 10.
note that x 2 needs to adjust the
direction of inequality since we
multiply x2 with -1
so you can see this compute this
computation shows high regularity and we
need to adjust the direction of
inequality according to the sign of
individual neurons
and this is harder to compute on
parallel hardwares such as gpus
there are several challenges to
accelerate transform transform
applications on gpus
first
existing uh transformerification
framework utilizes a deep learning
framework like pi torch which which is
designed for the standard
but
transformerification shows significantly
different bond centric computing pattern
and straightforwardly deploying
transformation to this existing deep
learning framework usually lead to poor
performance
and second transformer verification
shows large diversity in the bond
computation
and such diversity makes it challenging
to hand optimize the gpu kernels
third
transform application involves abundant
memory intensive operations such as
reduction
and existing deep learning framework
usually only focus on the computation
intensive operations
such as convolutional layer and ignores
abundant optimization opportunities for
the memory intensive operators
to this end we propose phase
an efficient framework for
transformerification on gpus
phase have three major components
schematic aware computation graph
transformation
verification specialized kernel crafter
and the expert guided auto tuning
the first technique is schematic aware
computation graph transformation
let's first look at existing design for
transformerification
the major problem is the intensive
global memory assess
existing designs usually first split the
weight matrix w into two-way matrix w
positive and w negative according to the
weight signs
then we can use each matrix for
computing lower and upper bound
however
reading this matrix independently due to
redundant global memory assets
this heavy global memory assess will
lead to
high latency
instead we propose thematic aware kernel
fusion to minimize such memory overhead
our key idea is to exploit
transformation verification schematics
and the gpu memory hierarchies
as a weight computation level
we first load the weight matrix into
shared memory without distinguishing the
sign of individual scalars
then we split the width matrix w into
w positive w negative when loading the
data function memory to registers or
registers in our design we only need to
load the load the weight matrix from
global memory once
so
we can significantly reduce the global
memory size
at the bond computation level
transformer verification has important
schematics
multiplying the same weight matrix with
both the lower and the upper input bound
this is x lb and xub in the figure
we propose to feel the computation of
lower and upper bounds
in this way we can load only once the
specifically
we first load the input bound into
shared memory
then each thread loads independent
independent date from shaded memory to
register
finally
we directly accumulate output bounds y
lb and yub in the register
this eliminates the redundant
global memory assess during generating
lower and upper bound of the output and
further improves the performance
our second technique is verification
specialized kernel crafter
one problem with accelerating transform
application is the diversity across
verification designs
actually the computation is both
adaptive to the improved bound and
adaptive to the operators
for example
this figure shows the linear bound of a
relu layer when when the scale of xl is
larger than xu
this design provides a tighter bond
however when the scale of xl is smaller
than xu another linear bond can provide
a tighter bond
so the computation of transformation is
adaptive to the input bounce
and the computation is also adaptive to
the operators
figure shows verification for the
tangent layer
you can easily see the linear bound
voltage layer is quite different from
the bound for real layer
so there is large diversity across
operators during replication it is quite
hard to
optimize individual operators due to
this diversity
our key insight is to optimize
computation patterns instead instead of
a concrete operator
and we identify three important
computation patterns in transformation
they are generalized vector reduction
generalized elementalized multiplication
and generalized scalar vector
multiplication
let's look at a concrete example
for generalized element-wise
multiplication we have a generic
function f over lower and upper bound
this generic function f captures the
diversity during verifying diversion
operators
moreover this function only takes two
scalars as inputs and can be easily
computed on a single gpu thread
for example
for redo layer and the text layer the
only difference resides in the extension
instantiation of different function f
so we only need to optimize this
computation pattern
and the dtrf function designs can be
abstracted
next we only need to focus on optimizing
individual computation patterns
let's talk about
general a generalized vector reduction
this pattern widely exists
exists when verifying various
operators
a naive approach is a sequential mode
we can assign one thread to one neuron
and we use it this right to accumulate
32 values
in this case we need 32 iterations
so this design definitely shows low
parallelism
but in many cases
there are much more threats than the
number of neurons in a layer
so we can have the luxury to use
multiple threads for a single neuron
we design a parallel mode to improve
performance
we utilize special gpu instruction
shuffle down sync to enable 32 threads
to simultaneously reduce a vector
this enables computation directly
across
thread registers and in this case we
only need five iterations and achieve
high parallelism
another problem is the heavy memory
overhead during verification
to solve this problem we propose sharing
oriented workload scheduling
and our key idea is to exploit the gpu
memory hierarchy such as register share
memory and global memory to effectively
reduce memory assess
first we use a set of thread for example
32 thread to load input bound weight
xlw and uw from global memory to shared
memory
then this thread load input boundary
ways from shared memory and
collaboratively compute the concretized
lower and upper bound
this concretized lower and upper bound
are strong in shared memory which can be
assessed by individual threats
finally each thread independently load
individual xlw and xuw scalars from the
shared memory and then compute the
output output bound weight
here all threads in a whop are computing
the output bound weight for the same
neuron and applying the same
scaling computation so we can avoid the
warmth divergence
and we also note that input bound weight
are only loaded lens from global memory
which mitigates the redundant global
memory assess
our third technique is expert guided
auto tuning optimization
our goal is to effectively incorporate
hardware knowledge to find optimal
operator implementations
and our idea is to first generate a
metal file for each hardware on its
properties
then we can incorporate this meta file
to a custom model for tuning
verification operators
in particular we have two
designs the first design is a rule based
expert knowledge meta file
it contains hard rules
for hardware limitations such as
maximum shared memory material memory
size and the maximum number of registers
per thread
this represents the hardware limitations
and must not be violated
it also contains soft rules such as
number of
streaming multiprocessors and the number
of threads per
streaming multiprocessors
and this represents the certain
trade-off related to hardware properties
we also need to consider the software
rules when tuning the performance
and the second design is expert guided
cost model we first
estimate shared memory and register
usage and we can skip the candidates in
candidate implementations that violates
the hard rules
then we can train a custom model this
model consumes both soft rules for
hardware properties and tuning
uh performance-related parameters such
as tiling sites
finally
we can predict
a best candidate implementation
now let's see the evaluation
let's first talk about end-to-end
benefits
we compiled a phase with pi torch which
is mostly
uh used
used in transformerification we also
compile with tvm answer
and answer as
representation of existing deep learning
frameworks
as showing figure
phase is much faster than existing works
phase achieves around 2.5 times speed up
over pi torch
and surprisingly we know that
tvm and answer even bring slow down to
transformer verification
the main reason is that tvm and ansar
are designed for standard neural
networks and failed to effect
efficiently support verification
specific communication pattern
on individual layers we can also observe
similar performance
a similar performance improvement
in this figure we compile the
verification time of matrix
multiplication layer over the
diverse
input lens however
we overall we observe 5.1 times speed up
on average over pi charge baseline and
we also outperformed the tvm and answer
um that's all for my presentation thanks
for attention our projects have been
open source at this link and preview
please feel free to check out this
report thank you