hi everyone i'm jamming from qinghua
university
i'm proud to have the opportunity to
present our paper
finding box in programmable data plane
generators
this is a joint work with my colleagues
from ching hwan university and alibaba
group
over the past few years
programmable data plane has gained
significant traction in the networking
community
the packet processing logic on the
devices are programmable
and thus enable flexible customization
of the network
according to the intent
programmers write data plane programs in
domain specific languages
or dsl
then the compiler compiles the dsl
programs
and generates the binary
the binary will be finally loaded on the
programmable devices
however since the data planning
programming is still at an early stage
programmers have to manually take care
of many hardware details and dsl
specifics
this makes data plan programming not
easy
recently a growing body of research
proposes data plane generators or dp
generator
the dp generators can greatly reduce
manual efforts by providing high-level
pregnancy to express intent
and directly converting intent into dp
programs
thus
many researchers and industries design
various dp generators for network
monitoring
routing security and so on
with the prevalence of dp generators we
need to guarantee their correctness
based on our study
three types of mistakes may happen to dp
generators
the first is intent violation
the input intent and the output program
is not consistent
the second is security vulnerabilities
in output programs
such as out-of-bound register access
and the third is generator crash the
generator rejects some reasonable
intents without any output
using 40 dp generators
may result in serious mistakes such as
missing attacks and undesired package
processing procedure
therefore
we should guarantee the correctness
before using a dp generator
unfortunately
little attention has been devoted to
guaranteeing
the correctness of dp generators
existing data plane verification tools
focus on verifying the consistency
between specifications and dpg programs
however
these tools are not designed for
debugging dp generators
first
since they aim to verify individual
programs instead of debugging dp
generators
they can hardly cover all generator
force because they cannot enumerate the
numerous intent
second
to check intent program consistency
they require massive human return
specifications
which is error-prone and time-consuming
in this paper we proposed fireboat
a black box testing tool to find bugs in
dp generators
the key idea of fireboat is thoroughly
generating intents as test cases
and automatically performing program
verification
thus
firebot workflow includes two steps
intent generation and program
verification
first
to thoroughly explore the interspace
firebot takes the grammar and semantic
constraints of a dp generator as input
and generates all reasonable intents
then
firebot proves the generated intent
space to eliminate redundancy
and produces representative intent
this intent as input into the dp
generator to generate dp programs
or to find crash backs
to automatically verify the correctness
of generated programs
fireballs provides a general and high
level specification to express every
intense grammar symbol
and automatically derives the final
specification of each intent
then firebot formalizes the output dp
programs using these three
formulas and use the open source this
resolver to check whether these three
formulas have security vulnerabilities
or whether they are consistent with the
specifications
so let's look deeper into the workflow
first
let's generate all reasonable intents
reasonable intent should be first
syntactically correct to generate
syntactically correct intents we follow
a syntax guided generation method
each dp generator should expose the
grammar from expressing intent
the grammar describes the intent space
five vote uses the backers north form or
bnf
the most common grammar format to
describe the intent grammar
the bnf grammar contains a start symbol
and many expansion rules
this expansion rules can expand
individual symbols to combinations of
many other symbols
given a bnf grammar of a dp generator
generating or syntactically correct
intent
can be written as growing an
intergeneration graph
the root node is the start symbol
then we grow the graph by replacing the
symbols at each node using the expansion
rules
in this example
first the program symbol is replaced by
the statement symbol
the statement symbol is replaced by two
symbols
name and query
then we can expand the query symbol
using two expansion rules and generate
two new nodes
we close the graph until all leaf nodes
cannot be expanded anymore then we can
collect the leaf nodes as output intents
such syntax guided intent generation can
find or syntactically correct intents
however
only correct syntax may be not enough
because they may be semantically invalid
here we give two examples for invalid
semantics
the first example is undefined variable
reference
here variable r1 is referenced before
it's defined
to avoid this case we should require
that
only after we take the expansion rules
for variable definition definition
we can then take the expansion words for
the corresponding variable reference
this case actually represents a
dependency type constraint
taking some rules is dependent dependent
on taking other rules
the second example is repeated variable
definition
to avoid this case
we should recall that
if we take the expansion rules for
variable definition
we should not take the expansion rules
for the same variable definition
this case actually represents an
exclusion type constraint
taking some rules and taking some other
rules are mutually exclusive
with this semantic constraints
we can reject some expansion rules
during intergeneration
to generate semantically valid intents
now we can generate all reasonable
intents
however the intent space may be
extremely large or even
infinite so next we need to reduce the
intense space and generate only
representative intents which are enough
to find bugs
we first analyze the factors which lead
to the huge intent space
the first is the right parameter range
a symbol may have many possible
expansion rules
which correspond to a large node degree
in this example
a
bit number
has 65
536 possible values
for sphere this symbol appears multiple
times
the exponential combination can directly
lead to explosion of the internal space
the second is the cyclic reference a
symbol may return to itself after
expansion
which corresponds to an infinite depth
of the intent generation graph
for the first one the white parameter
range
we can keep only representative
expansion rules
the representative rules include three
categories
the first is the boundary words such as
minimum and maximum values for numbers
boundary rules usually represent some
extreme cases or conditions
and should be included in the test cases
the second is random rules we also take
a random rule in addition to the
boundary rule
the third is previously selected rules
when the same symbol is event is
expanded multiple times
we also include the previously selected
random rules
for the cyclic symbol reference
we break the infinite symbol recurrence
by limiting the recurrence time of the
same symbol expansions
such pruning is based on the
combinatorial testing theory and will
not lose intent representativeness
for time reasons i won't go into details
here
now we have generated both reasonable
and representative intents as test cases
these intents are then input into the dp
generator to find crash backs or to
generate dp programs
next we need to automatically verify the
generated dp programs to further find
security vulnerabilities or intent
violations
the challenge here is
how to automatically convert intents
into specifications for verification
because manually converting intents into
verification specifications is time
consuming and not scalable
we observe that
intents are generated by expanding
grammar symbols
so our key idea is first writing the
specifications of each symbol in the
grammar
and then automatically composing simple
specifications into specifications for
each intent
to uniformly express various grammar
across generators
we need to design an expression format
that should be general enough to specify
various grammar symbols
and flexible enough to for composition
we propose to express symbol
specifications as high level functions
the function is general enough to
specify the input logic and return
values of individual symbols and
flexible enough for composition by
combining function course
the function consists of two segments
a declaration function that defines
internal states of symbols
and an execution function that describes
the process in logic
here we give an example for counting
the simple count statement
can be expanded as counting on an
expression
if the expression returns true
the counter will plus 1.
so the specification for count statement
is like this
the declaration function defines a
counter
variable the execution function does the
counting
by calling the execution function of the
expression symbol
similarly the specification of
expression symbol contains the
declaration part and the execution part
when we have a code snippet like this
the specification can be automatically
derived by composing the specifications
for count statement
and expression
in this way we can derive the
specification for any intent given the
personal specifications
next
fireball formalizes the output dp
programs using these three formulas
these these three formulas will finally
be verified
currently fireball focus on the p4
language here we use the popular p416 as
an example to illustrate how to
formalize dp programs into these three
formulas
a p416 program is composed of several
programmable blocks
we convert each programmable block into
these three formulas
here we present an example for
formalizing
a match action table residing in the
control flow block
in this example
table t matches with the key k and has
two candidate actions
to formalize this table
we define a z3 free variable for each
input parameter of this table
we also convert the operations of this
table to a nested if the else statement
to imitate the action executions
then we can combine these three formulas
for different tables to derive these
three formulas for the control flow
block
with these three formulas and
specifications we can then perform
program verification by converting the
specification into these three
assertions on the c3 formulas
and then we use the this resolver to
check whether there are security
vulnerabilities in the generated digital
formulas and whether the formulas and
specifications are consistent
we implement fireballs in the
linux virtual machine
firebot has about 2000 lines of code
we use fireballs to test
three popular open source dp generators
including mapper and sonata for network
telemetry and poise for security policy
enforcement
we take two dp program verification
tours acryla and p4v for comparison
we have two evaluation goals
the first is the back coverage of
fireboat
how many bugs can fireboat fund
and the second is the scalability of
fireboat
including how long does it take for
firebots to find bugs
and how many human efforts does variable
take
first for the back coverage
tribot finds bugs in all three
generators by generating thousands of
test cases
including five security vulnerabilities
certain internal violations and one
crash back
we also present the back details in our
paper
to evaluate the debugging scalability of
fireball
we count the lines of input cumulative
code
and the running time for internet
generation and program verification
for the running time we can see that
both internet generation and program
verification in all scenarios can be
done within 25 minutes
for the human written code
fireballs requires tens of lines of code
for internet grammar
tens of lines for semantic constraints
and hundreds of lines for per simple
specifications
we can see that the personal
specifications occupy a majority of
human written code
however
fireball requires writing the
specifications only once and then the
specifications for all intents can be
automatically derived
we use existing tools to verify the
generated programs
we need to write thousands of
specifications for the generated intent
thus firebot can save massive manual
efforts by writing specifications only
once
let me conclude
we proposed fireball
the first tool to debug db generators
firebot thoroughly explores the internet
space
to generate syntactically correct
symmetrically valid and representative
intents as test cases
and then automatically verify dp
programs by formalizing programs
and producing specifications to find
bugs
evaluation on three open source dp
generators show that
firebot can achieve both high back
coverage and high scalability
thank you for your listening and i'm
happy to take questions