thank you
hello everyone I'm me outside from Ohio
University I'm glad to present our work
flight status
our presentation includes four parts
first we would like to introduce the
background and the motivation of our
work then we describe rather as detailed
design under implementation
we show the flat device evaluation
result in third part
finally we give a conclusion
now one of the memory technology
revolutionize the computer storage stack
Intel opt-in memory of a better choice
for interface
its device performance is attractive the
octane memory has usual acceptancy
which is similar to the ethereum system
also octane memory has high memory
bandwidths but it explained with
characteristics are totally different
from dram
for example Is Random Access performance
is much worse than the sequential access
performance
we introduce the first system
hierarchical namespace design
now hierarchical name space is basically
a directory tree structure also in a
virtual flat system touches namespace in
the faster Duram to improve performance
news or access file you know jump space
with hierarchical file paths
such a name space desire indeed improve
performance for slow storage device such
as artists or storage spacecraft
however is a decrease performance on
iPhone
we find two performance issues for
current namespace design
successful in namespace must perform a
fair passwork which turns a past name
into a file I know them
the first work need to resolve a path
component one by one which is low and
enough scalable
so specifically a past component
resolution includes the entry lookup
from VG check one point check and the
even Hardware I will transfer
we do a experiment to qualify the
possible performance impact
generally in a password occupies 14 to
65 percentage of execution time for 6 16
cores
more the whole password is not scalable
all file system Nancy increased when 12
Parts become lengthy
for slow story distance traveled on hard
disk now Hardware I will dominate but
for faster only run the performance
bottlenecks shift to the software
password design
the second problem is expensive name
Spec 3 True also because directly
entries logically for more tree
structure towards the tree cause Point
sensing which is interact memory access
also direct entries are distributed
across the device
towards named spiritually cause random
memory access
we also do an experiment to qualify
electric reversal cost
we create two data sets each other
contains one thousand thousand the first
is put all fails in a single directory
which simulate a platinum space a second
intercept profiles in a relative
hierarchy then we scan all files means
two data sets we can see from this
figure the three traversal takes a large
percentage of excrete time
the most important feature of mrm is
good sequential performance
however the three best namespace
structure on the routine is faster than
we wrap
a program space performance motivating
us to design a new file system for Vital
address for faster theorem and wrap
s overcome the imitation in traditional
hierarchical namespace design
it'll provide a platinum space structure
your fail I know that it's directly
index fellow four parts
in the name space has two other one
genius
first you get retrieves short and
scalable password because we only need
to look up the namespace once during
password to get a result
second direct entries are stored
conceptively in a device which requires
a cheap scan to read the whole directory
to realize that events we need to
overcome four main challenges
first we need to preserve the posix
Matrix in our classroom password model
design
secondly we need to improve direct range
operation performance
third we need to reduce the data
durability cost on our web
first we need to ensure Quest safety for
platinum space
we also set up four design goals with
these four technical changes
we present the flight status system
architecture in this slide practice has
a closer design
we briefly introduced this system
equation in the top down order in the
system called layer users still use
familiar theoretical parts to access
sales in a platinum space
we Define a coordinate password to
resolve a fair price with two different
password models
Universal system layer we designed a
lower range optimized e plus 3 called
the br3 which manages all carry repairs
in a platinum space
in the storage area we propose a right
optimized compress the index key it will
reduce the right traffic during key
updates
first let's look at the recording of the
past working time this figure shows two
different password models the component
at the time password model we solve the
path component one by one but it is
through an unscrew
our proposed four parts are the 10
password model we solve the whole path
at the time therefore it's fast and the
scalable
we describe each component in fact as
possible model here
approximate analyze generate a person
without any doubts or redundant slashes
component it flattered us use trendline
let's go first name you just remove the
no talk
analyze this component are connected by
the symmetic plus component finder
a arithmetic semantic path component
finder and the symbol links and the
monopoint components the question is
like how can we identify its metal
components during password
our solution is to create a special
financially for this component
because the pr3 always return the first
entry whose key is greater than a
request key for triple cup the final
entry will be returned during personal
hub
the total component arrests magical
issues during password
Suppose there is a doctor following a
boiling component
we cannot resolve doctor component by
just removing its boiling component to
resolve this problem
we give two solutions here
and the first one checks medical
component whenever meeting with a total
component during password
the second one is called the talk talk
directory as left to pass net
then we perform prefix permission
checking affiliate we separate
permission checking from past name
lookup and a proposed a two-dimensional
prefix permission compression to patch
permission checking
we find the direct rating of that part
of Ensure the same permission base we
Define a new data structure called
prefix permission compressor which
comprise those permission fees of
of different directory
then for previously structure in a tree
node before the compressor based on a
personal parts
to perform a batch permission check
first we verify user ID and group ID in
a task credential with the past prefix
PPC
then we compare the permission piece
between the q15 and compress the
permission piece we do the same thing
again for the path fixed PPC
if both task credential and the
permission fees are equal the prefix
permission checking succeed
without doubt is symbolic and one point
may cause name space switch
the past dispatcher similar third parts
to the correct password model
the password models which many includes
one point switch and the person name
cursor adjustment
finally a fair price work may involve
different possible models we coordinate
the different plus model model to result
a possible correctly
the coordination is achieved in two
steps we build password models as Black
Box
input a pass name the password models
are resolved in the first name
the first one of coordination is feed a
correct personal input to the model
the second point of coordination is
ensure a correct multiplying switch
on the virtual file system use one point
with the entry to specify a file system
instance in instant Space Management
framework
we also create one for flat address
instance which is used to use to switch
to the Fatima project smnm space
our second contribution is is range
optimized index 3. the pr3 has two
important features the first is and we
run friendly tree node design such as
also the three three node
another feature is supporting 3D range
operation
reactive range of operation in Platinum
space is much expensive than a high red
Conan space
the orange Operation addresses
challenges you know that structure level
we provide a compositional range
operation design
first we Define the two three primitive
the three joint and the three split
model 3 into a big one
okay you know three one is smaller than
a 3 2.
to perform a three joint we walk down
the three two to the same level as the
tree one then we perform another merge
finally we install three one into the
three two
the three split divided 3 into two
substrates with the splitter point x
next we Define the four pr3 range
operation the three flights and the
insert operation are implemented
implementing the Passover two three
primitive
the 3-5 operation the touch of substrate
from the original tree with a given key
range the three insert operation insert
a symmetric into a big one
the range updates modify the index key
of a specific range the range query is
similar to a text put
three
finally we design a full Direction range
system because based on a pr3 event
operation
directory render remove directory range
copy and the directory rename
the third contribution is right up by
compressed key design
we compress key in a tree node key
compression improves storage efficiency
and the reduced key batch of that cost
however key compression called key
adjustment cost for example key insert
costs key key prefix strings and the
suffix expander
there is too many small random data
rights which is harmful to the MLM
system
we propose right open my compressed key
to address this change the basic idea is
combining data provision and cache to
reduce data movement cost
we give an example to describe the
detail design
Suppose there is index key which is
breeding you two parts and the stored in
different memory requests
at times you want we Load One by data
from a prefix to suffix
instead of instead of loading one byte
of data we privilege 32 bytes of data
our time T2 will load two bytes of data
for Less prefix specifics fortunately
is two bytes of data are already in
Aesthetics
we just update the suffix pointer to
represent this key adjustment similarly
at time T3
okay there's no need to move the actual
data
the fourth contribution is namespace
Crash consistency design
ated ensure crash consistency both for
next best point and range operation
full name space pointer operation such
as create earning achieving crash
consistency is straightforward
we first prepare a position new data
changes in on user place then we update
the metadata automatically
finally we switch the system to a new
consistent state
for namespace range operation the most
challenging part is that it is
temporary ports into many species
our Insight is that twist bridge is the
reverse operation of the screen joint we
load substrate with address during
namespace Street
so as a result the names especially can
be restored during system recover
Frank Harvest is implemented the English
kernel based on pmfs file system
this is our experiment setup We compare
factors with six file system including
xt4 xfs Butters
in real opposite memory machine
we first evaluate the password
efficiency of seven cell system in six
different password settings
we chose three conclusions from what is
the experiment foreign cash first the
best achieve a maximum 28 times the
lensing reduction compared to others
we'll hold the cash rather also achieve
similar performance with rfl system
s all perform others with different
possible setting
next we related password stability and
sensitivity
we change the path component number from
1 to 50. then we measure a state system
currency
all the resistance increased
significantly except the Fret address
next we evaluate the threat password
sensitivity by changing the four
variables
the last level cache the br3 height the
access pattern and the process
oh during the experiment we finalized
threat base is extensive we choose
Rewards except to the fair process
we value for directly range operations
directly read direct remove and redirect
copy
and the directory name for first the
three directory range operation right
that has achieved a 2019 times the low
latency for proposing a new directory
range season cost for directive name
database performance is also close to
other file systems
we evaluated version of this performance
with two metadata intensive benchmark
trials over under Wimmer in cell bench
you can see from the experiment result
Fred FS greatly out of perform other
cloud system due to its optimized
namespace operation
we evaluate the flight address with a
real world application kit
if I have this achieved almost four
times the energy reduction 14 statues
for its optim optimal
directly reading the key to commit
application is dominated by the password
performance
threat address also reduce the great
committed lendency by
18 to 37 percentage compared to other
file systems
as a summary direct retrieve best and
namespace under root size high
performance and RAM system
we perform we propose a lower neural
system called
fats long five namespace structure
try the best incorporate three quart
techniques a coordinated password
a wrench optimized pr3 and the red
optimized index key design
the expand experimental results change
that brightness correctly improve cell
system maintenance performance
and this is our whole presentation thank
you very much