hello everyone i'm zukul wang from zhu
zhang university china today it's my
pleasure to talk about our recent work
fpga nick
upgenic is a gpu centrally cosmetic
it's a joint work
with homogeneous
gustavo
this is our outline first we will talk
about why
fpga nick
essentially fpga nick is an fpga-based
gpu-centric semanic for gpu powered
distributed applications
so the question why aphgenic can be
breakdown into two questions the first
one is the why gpu-centric symmetric the
second one is why fpga-based semanic
why gpu-centric symmetric the main
reason is that gpu's position don't
match is low in hpc and the ai
application
on one hand gpu consume most network
traffic in hpc and the ai application
and
this application has larger and larger
data size
on the other hand gpu's positioning in
the server is just a work of his boss
um cpu
cpu manipulates both nic and gpu
such an architecture
doesn't allow fan grained core
processing between nick and the gpu
therefore we believe that gpu dream to
be the boss of network data rather than
just the work of the current boss cpu
while fpga based manic the main reasons
is that the arms based on the ac based
money cannot always meet the two goals
concurrently
program
ability and the performance
on the arm-based manic the arm cpu and
the host cpu are connected to a nic
switch
therefore the arm cpu can do the smart
things on the neck
however the main bottleneck is that the
amp cpu have limit
memory bandwidth
typically 28 gigabytes per second
because the arm cpu typically only have
two memory channel
therefore
staging 100g network data
will overwhelm the arm cpu
because of his
low memory bandwidth
regarding the
basic base manic
there is no
general architecture for various
application
so we have to build a
custom
chip for a narrow space of application
however
each chip type out take a long cycle
typical years
and each chip type out
cost higher and the higher
when used a better process
therefore only big company like cloud
companies
can have his own semantic chip
because they
have a big
big market
now let's talk about what's fpg nick
two goals of epigenetic are gpu-centric
somatic and versatility which means that
epigenetic allows
flexible design space exploration around
smanik
to achieve these two goals
fgniq consists of three components
the first component is gpu communication
stack
this stack enables control and the data
plan of loading
next i will talk about the effect of
these two of loading
now let's talk about the effect of data
plan of loading
we compare the data plan of loading with
the case without the com
data bank of loading
when the data pane uploading is disabled
when we send data from nick to the gpu
the first thing we need to send the data
from
nick to the cpu and then cpu to the gpu
so the data path will be like this
with data plane offloading enabled the
data can go directly from
fpga nic to the gpu
besides
fgnic
allows appgi to use gpu virtual address
to access gpu memory
such that a system programmer can
use
easy fine-grained core co-processing
between fpga and the gpu
we don't decide that appginik is the
first work to enable p2p communication
between fpga and gpu but to our
knowledge
we believe that
fcnic is the first worker to allow fg to
use virtual address to access gpu memory
now let's talk about the effect of
control of loading
using one application scenario
processing network data on the gpu
when the control pane of loading is not
enabled the cpu needs to issue and set
receive commands to the nic to transfer
data from nic to the gpu memory
second cpu need to launch a gpu kernel
to
process on the network data
and wait
until
the kernel finishes
third cpu need to issue and send the
commands to the nic to transfer data
from gpu memory to the nic
to sum up
this scenario
needs three
pcie commands from the cpu
second
nic and gpu operations are hard to
parallel actually they are serialized
with control panel of loading enabled
gpu can directly manipulate itself nick
in particular
gpu can
send a
receive command to the nic
to transfer data from nic to the gpu
memory
send
gpu can directly process on the
data
when the
when the processing is finished
gpu can issue and
send commands to the nic to transfer
data from gpu memory to the nic
to sum up
control panel of loading only needs to
control
commands from gpu
so pcie
and nick and the gpu operations can be
easily paralyzed
the second component is hardwood network
transport which enable fast
lossless network processing with
hardware network of transport gpu don't
need to deal with complex network
protocol on which gpu cannot perform as
well because gpu is original design for
parallel computing rather than
network protocol which needs to
maintain states
as such
the gpu only needs to process the
network payload rather than law
network package
our current
network transport is from eth it's an
open source 100g tgb stack
nevertheless it's easy to generalize to
use
lockkey
the third component is only computing
which enable flexible 100g data pass
accelerator
which cannot be done on the asic based
and arm-based hismanic
the arm-based money cannot process 100g
network data
and the asic-based semanic
cannot provide flexibility
the goal of omnic computing components
is to enable versatility which means
that fpga need to support a flexible
100g that pass oscillator
in order to increase
versatility
fj nick
also supports three asthmatic models
neglect
of past and own paths
the key idea of directory model is to
directly connect this gpu communication
state with
hardware network transport for example
we implement gpu central network
which allows gpu to issue
circuit-like network communication with
remote gpu
the second model is off-pass model the
key idea
of path model is
to
allow only computing model to directly
manipulate gpu communication stack and
hardware transport for example we
implement only this operation on the
only computer model
such that
we don't need
any
cpu and gpu computing cycle and
don't increase memory footprint
the third model is on pass model
the key idea of onpass model
is allow omnic computing model to act as
a bond between gpu communication stack
and the hardware transport for example
we implement hyperlog log
on
on the unpassed model
such that the cardinality estimation is
being performed when transfer data
between gpu and the network
with these three components fcnic can be
a gpu sensors manic and enable
versatility around this monique for gpu
now let's see the location of epigenetic
in our system
epsilonic
acts as a pcie in the point such that
fgn can direct communication with gpu
without cpu being involved
now let's talk about how fcnik performs
at the beginning we talk about our
experimental setup we learned our
experiment in a small cast that consists
of eight servers each server has a
sonics fpga and an nvidia gpu
we implement
upgenic in sonic's fpga u280 or u50
as the gpu is for the nvidia
a100 or rtx eight dedicated
so go our experiment is twofold first we
validate fpga nick's functionality
second we validate fgnique's versatility
regarding fgnicus functionality we
validate the latency and throughput
between apigee unique and the gpu
regarding fgnics versatility we examine
the
performance of directory model of path
model and the own path model
now let's validate the fpga nexus
functionality
regarding fgnix functionality
we validated the effect of control panel
of loading and the data plan of loading
to examine the control plan of loading
we compare the latency between different
device
xo the left fig shows the latency
comparison
where the x y means device x leads from
device y
we have two observations
first
gpu ft has stable latency
because
gpu fpga has less noise
compared with cpu
second
gpu fgs latency is
much smaller than the sum of gpu cpu
cpu fpga latency
which means that
our control panel of loading works very
well
to to validate the effect of data of
loading we match the throughput
between two device
especially between the fpga to
cpu
or gpu
we can observe that fgnic can achieve
similar throughput when assessing gpu
memory and the cpu memory which means
that
means efficient of data plan of loading
now let's validate the fpg unique
versatility using 3 models
regarding the directory model we use gpu
central networking as an example
with gpu central networking
distributed gpu can communicate with
each other using socket-like interface
the baseline we choose is a case
without control panel of loading like
gpu net
in such a case
cpu manipulates a link so it's hard to
parallel nic and gpu operations
with fpg nic
control panel offloading is enabled
gpu can directly manipulate the nic
so it allows fine-grained core
processing between nic and gpu
we validate the effect of control
overloading using different network
transfer lengths from 2 megabytes to 512
megabytes
as shown in xs
we have two observations
first
control panel of loading is
significantly increased throughput no
matter the transfer length is
because control panel of loading
can easily overlap the nic and the gpu
operations
second when the transfer lens is smaller
control panel of loading gets higher
speed up
because
the valid transfer time is limited and
the zen
control operation dominates the overall
time
regarding of pass model we use only use
as an example
the baseline we choose is nickel from
nvidia
we enable rdma and the gpu directly for
the nickel
however nico still needs cpu or gpu
computing cycles
to finish all of this operation
and the nico also needs more gpu memory
footprint for storing intermediate
states
however
fgnic enhanced or reduced have pure
hardware implementation so it doesn't
add any cpu computing cycle and done at
gpu memory footprint for storing
intermediate states
we run our experiments on eight nodes
each nodes had
an fda and gpu
the results shown in the figure
excess is
that size where exercise is a past
bandwidth
we have two observations
first
app generic enhanced or reduced leash
cylindrical bus binaries as nickel when
the size is larger than two megabytes
second lg nic based audios achieve
higher speed up over nickel when third
size is less than one megabytes because
nickel has
high tone a lot of head than
[Music]
fg nick based all dues
regarding the onpass model we use
hyperloglog as an example
the baseline we are choosing is a case
without offloading
it means that
it performance hyperloglog on the gpu
so
it needs eight streaming multiple
processor to consume one kind g network
data
fgnik enable
of loading
so
we can performance hyperlogolog on the
path
on the fgnic
so there's no gpu cycles and
we compare the case with the offloading
and the result of loading
we observe that
fgn enhanced hyperlogolog don't
affect achievable throughput
it means that
aptgenic enable efficient on-pass
processing
to sum up rpg unique enable fast semanic
prototyping for more application
which is important
especially when each chipper type out is
really expensive nowadays
therefore we make
upgenic open source
it's available in github
that's the end of our talk now i'm happy
to take questions