so i'm going to talk about somewhat of a
niche topic today it's about hashing
design in modern data center networks
it's challenges and mitigation
techniques this is a joint work
with our colleagues from texas a m and
harvard
um today data center and wide area
networks typically employ multi-path
forwarding think about equal cost
multipathing ecmp
or its weighted variant wcnp
roughly how the switch hashing works is
when the packet arrives at a switch it's
first matched to a next top group which
is basically a list of ports that you
can forward the packet out to
that would get it get it to its
destination
the next step the switch applies the
hash function
which then indexes the packet
into one of the next top
and then forwards that
packet out of that port
so a good hash function should hash
flows equally across all the next hops
when that fails to happen
this is a problem we call its hash
polarization
and this can happen when you reuse the
same hash function or you use correlated
hash functions across different switches
on the same forwarding path so let us
look at an example
between node and a and node f there are
four equal cost paths
so ideally we want to utilize all of
them equally
so when traffic comes into a
it has only two next tops to go to
if the hash value of the packet is of
the packet headers is zero then you
forward it to b if it's one you forward
it to c
the problem arises at node b
what if you use the same hash function
as a the problem is
then
you will only use next top d
because all that green traffic coming
into b has hash value zero and if you're
using the same hash function at b you
will not hit e at all
so this is a problem because only two
out of your four paths are used
this is problematic because this leads
to poor low balancing and this tends to
result in high very high tail latency
which is detrimental to application
performance like you know uh for example
think about machine learning collective
communications which are known to be
highly sensitive to tail latencies also
from network operators perspective this
is just a lot of build bandwidth
being unusable because you're
prematurely saturating the link so your
usable bandwidth is significantly less
than your provision bandwidth
so here are our contributions in this
paper first we formalized the first time
this
hash polarization problem and this is
attributed to a lack of uncorrelated
hash functions provided in commodity
switches
there's a common misconception that
random seeds can create uncorrelated
hash functions which are actually not
true
and this lack of
uncorrelated hash functions become even
more acute with increasing adoption of
direct connect technologies topologies
so to mitigate this problem
we had designed two approaches one is
you know we identified a very common
forwarding structure that enables us to
reuse hash functions safely
and secondly you know we proposed
design an sdn based approach which does
not require any switch modification to
decorate switches using the same hash
function together our solutions are
near close near uh very near optimal for
dcn and we have reclaimed 33 percent of
network capacity otherwise lost to poor
hashing
let's take a look at google's data
center networks
this is a very typical conventional um
clo topology
uh
google
due to our skill
this multi-stage cloud comprises
five stages of switches
now this work was first published
revealed in sitcom 2015.
um and the with the lower three layers
of switches comprising the what we call
the aggregation block which connects the
servers
and the upper two layers of switches
comprising the swipe blob which provides
the connectivity across the aggregation
blocks
so for inter-block traffic it follows
every
every single packet follows a fixed
structure path which has exactly ahops
and it goes through the exact same stage
sequence
so this suggests a pretty simple
hash function allocation scheme where
you basically for each hop let's assign
a unique hash function
note that this means for
switches at
s2 s3 and s4
you will have two hash functions
assigned to northbound traffic and
southbound traffic respectively and we
call this scheme per stage allocation
uh
fast forward to more you know recent
years you know
around five years ago we started uh
building our data center networks using
a non-hierarchical
direct connect topology
what happens here is we remove the spine
blocks and we directly mesh the
aggregation blocks together
the problem here well first how do we do
routing
um so the inter-block traffic now either
goes over a direct path
or it goes through one transit hop
now if we use the same per stage
allocation
what we're going to see is there's going
to be hash collision
happening
between the source to transit hop
and the transit to destination hop
remember the same
uh
hash polarization example that i showed
earlier
the problem is at the source
s3 switch you could hash the traffic
apart no problem
but what if only the green traffic
arrives at the transit
so now at this trans you can see my
cursor right yes
let me actually bring it up the laser
but at this transit s3 chip
unfortunately you're only seeing green
traffic so you cannot hash it apart and
there might be might very well be
multiple links
equal cost links to the destination so
this is a problem
now what can we do ideally you know if
each aggregation block is assigned a
unique a unique hash function then
problem solved but that would require
dozens of hash functions at least
but you know unfortunately the commodity
switches offer only very limited set of
hash functions
and as i hinted at earlier
there's a common misconception that by
randomizing the uh by randomly seeding
the hash functions on the switch you
create uncorrelated hash function that's
actually not true
the
because the common implementation of the
seed is it's concatenated to the input
big vectors which consists of you know
other packet uh header fields that you
choose to hash upon
so you concatenate the c to the big
vectors and feed that into the hash
function so the effect of that roughly
speaking you can find you know more
theoretical proof in the paper the the
rough effect of that is it
it scrambles the next hop but it does
not decorate
so what can we do
we have
limited hash functions implemented on
the on the switch hardwired so you
cannot really you know add new hash
functions to it
and then we have a growing need for more
hash functions so we need to find some
ways to safely reuse hash functions
and here is one common pattern
which we call color recombination
again let's illustrate through an
example
same forwarding graph as before traffic
coming in and it's split to green and
red
for it to
switch b and c respectively
we already established that at switch b
and c you cannot reuse the same hash
function right it's not going to work
so that means we have to use a an
orthogonal or uncorrelated hash function
at node b and c
the result of that is for the next layer
at node dne now you have
traffic coming
from both colors right so you those two
colors recombine into your original
unpolarized traffic so now you can reuse
actually reuse hash function h
so where do we see this
color recon uh recombination pattern
it's actually quite prevalent it's very
prevalent in most of the two stage clo
block design
uh remember the earlier i showed you the
graph of jupiter topology you take a
jupiter swine block for example you have
the s4 it's a two-stage photic glow
and color recombination you can
basically map this if you unfold this it
basically looks like the forwarding
graph on the left
this allows us to save one hash function
at the stage four switch so i can use
the same hash function for northbound
traffic and southbound traffic
here's another technique
uh
what i didn't mention earlier was that
there are really two hash operations
involved in selecting the next top of
the packet
so after a packet is you know matched
into a next top group
the switch does two things one is it
first uh applies a hash function for
example crc 32 which outputs a 32-bit
integer
and then the switch modulo that 32-bit
uh integer
by the size of the next top group and
then whatever the remainder is that's
the index
for the port that you select
so the nice thing about this is that the
group size is completely controlled by
the sdn controller
um
we program them uh
it's fully under our control
and we have proved a theorem in the
paper which states that
if two group sizes are co-prime
then the two switches are uncorrelated
even if they use the same hash function
just to show a very simple illustration
same example again
packets arriving at
switch a it has two next tops to forward
it too
for all the
packets that have hash value 0 2 4 all
the even numbers will get to forward it
to b
and
even if you don't do anything at b
what happens is they're all going to hit
d and none is going to hit e
but remember the co prime
theorem what if we resize this group to
a co-prime number uh let's say five
and the way you do that is by just
simple replications
now let's see what happens
okay so zero two four they're still
gonna hit d
but starting at six you're starting to
hit e now
and then this repeats
so now
you know very nicely uh by doing this
little trick you're able to utilize the
previously unused path
there's a cache however
if you're paying close attention it
introduces us a slight weight skew um
previously the intended traffic split is
one to one between d and e but now due
to this replication scheme the new split
is actually three to two so there's now
you see there's a trade-off existing
between
the weight precision
and how many switch table ecmp table uh
entries you're going to burn
and we just talked about it which is uh
expanding resizing an ecmp group
co-priming resizing a wcmp group is a
little bit more tricky and i a simple
replication may not work very well so i
encourage you to look at the to read the
paper about this
let's see how we apply the this code
prime
co-priming technique in our direct
connect
dcn network
again remember the goal is to decorate
the
transit to destination hop from the
source to transit hop
i mean we could coordinate the group
sizes
between the two hops to code prime
but we found there's an easier way to do
that which is
let's not touch the source group at all
let's just resize the transit to
destination group to a prime number
which in the vast overwhelming majority
of the cases should uh be automatically
co-primed with the source transit group
the other benefit of only resizing the
transit to destination group is the
transit destination tends to be ecmp
whereas the source to transit tends to
be wcmp because of you know traffic
engineering
uh
for traffic engineering purposes so and
we already
said earlier that resizing an ecmp group
tends to produce less weight skew
without burning too many
switch resources
so let's look at some simulation results
in this presentation we're going to
focus on
multi-stage cloud dcm and the direct
connect dcm you can find more results on
isp networks or general uh wide area
networks in the paper
um the hash functions that we use is
called rtx7 which is a
broadcom implementation so very fairly
widely deployed
it consists of a family of seven hash
functions
crc32 etc
um to evaluate the effectiveness of our
hashing design we look at the link
utilization across
across the switches and we use
coefficient of variation to
quantify just how much imbalance there
is
also we do use random seed so each
switch is configured randomly seated
so let's first look at the cloud
topology we compare two configurations
the baseline
is
because of the lack of hash functions so
we
will apply the same hash function for
both the northbound and southbound
traffic
s3 chip
and our with color recombining we could
it allows us to allocate it saves us one
hash function
at stage four switch which
allows us to assign that extra hash
function to the s3 southbound traffic
so we compare these two schemes
so here is a
representative s3 chip and we look at
its down facing
ports there are eight of them
the blue bars show the the baseline
you can see that it has a pretty poor
low balancing
uh
across the the links but when you apply
color recombining uh the
low balancing is significantly improved
we're looking at a coefficient of
variation of 0.6 versus 0.05
and because of this we can
increase the effective capacity by 33
percent
uh a similar story uh follows for the
direct connect topology uh here we're
comparing again a baseline where we
retain the original
group size without code priming and we
compare with our technique of co-priming
the
source group and the transit group
again a similar story here the low
balancing performance is significantly
improved uh here we're looking at 23
capacity improvement
next we explore
a little bit the trade-off between the
waste sku and the switch table usage
the main takeaways are
which the results are pretty intuitive
as well by increasing the code prime
value from 9 to 73 we're able to reduce
load imbalance
by 80 so this loading balance is purely
due to weight skew
but as you increase the ecmp group size
you also burn more ecmp entries
and we also see diminished return after
a certain point
um both of these techniques have been
deployed in our production for many
years now
specifically in the
multi-stage glow topology we use color
combination recombination and it's not
just in spine block i would encourage
you to think about
other places where this is happening and
it doesn't have to be just a single
layer do the re color recombination
in our direct connect architecture
which is going to come out
in this year's sitcom we employ both
color recombination and co-priming
and we have
been able to achieve excellent low
balancing performance with a coefficient
of variation of only
0.03
um
there's still works remaining to be done
um i think
for one hash polarization detection in
live networks remains to be a difficult
problem the reason is attributing
loading balance to
hash polarization in the face of
multiple confounders is actually quite
challenging because there are many
things that could impact load balancing
think about wcmp traffic engineering
or elephant flow
um there's even harder problem which is
intermittent passion issues because
due to some
coincidental combination of your routing
you might
have
occasionally good color mixing which
might hide your hashing issue but when
you lose that
color mixing in some occasions you may
your service may see outages because now
your hashing issues start surfacing
so this will be an interesting problem
to do more research on
fundamentally we believe the way to
solve this you know
as good as the approaches that we have
proposed we believe the fundamental way
to solve this is
the switch hardware level is that we
really need the switch vendors to
provide
unlimited uncorrelated hash functions
and generatable by
seeding the hash function randomly
lastly um
i think how do we automatically detect
and discover this color recombining
pattern uh considering uh mirrored uh
multiple factors like routing uh hashing
the traffic entropy etc is also an
interesting problem to conclude
hash polarization is a real yet
underestimated problem in production
networks it could reduce reusable
bandwidth by as much as one third
we have
shown you uh two proven approaches to
achieve near optimal hashing
and we're actively working with our
switch vendors on better switch hashing
implementation with that thank you all
for your attention i'm happy to take any
questions