hello everyone my name is it's jin i
come from shanghai chowton university
epcc lab today i will give a talk to
introduce help rather than recycle
awaiting code startup in service
computing through inter-functioning
content sharing
in the first section i will briefly
introduce what service and the files are
and what are advantages and limitations
of using service model
first what is service according to
berkeley's view service equals fast plus
best
developers upload their codes as
functions to the fast system
user triggers a function through events
like http requests
the fast system allocates computing
resources and interact with the backend
services to execute functions
in the traditional i-space survey model
computing and the memory resources are
pre-allocated
and have no clear relationship with the
number of concurrent service requests
even if there is no request for a period
of time
resources are still occupied
on the other hand service can building
can charge per request without paying
for waiting
which can achieve more efficient
resource utilization
using servlets model we can achieve many
benefits like
on-demand container launching fine grant
resource scaling
offloaded management
and flexible scheduling
however these features also bring
diverter challenges
for example the event driven feature
means if a function is invoked for the
first time or there is no alive or warm
containers for it
the service system has to start a new
container to encapsulate its function
runtime
initialize the software environment
load applications basic code and run the
function all these steps
make up a code startup
and may even take several seconds
the code startup significantly recruits
increases queries end-to-end latency
the long latency problem
often when the function invocation is
short
in this talk we focus on the challenges
of code startups
and the high density and high
concurrency changes
are discussed in our another talk about
run d
now we know that the color startup is an
important issue
does it really compromise the quality of
service in the production
according to the zeus report of
production service trades
the function invocation follow a pareto
distribution
when we monitor the
the code startup frequency from the node
perspective
code startup invocations are less than
one percent
because most invocations come from
popular applications
however these popular applications
account for only 20 percent
it means that if we monitor the code
startup frequency from the view of
multi-patents
about 80 percent of all applications may
frequently experience code startups
to get a good experience with the
service model for most applications
we should optimize the problem from the
perspective of all applications
so in this section we will introduce how
to elevate the code startups
and analyze the efficiency of the
current methods
the pre-owned based methods create
containers and runtime in advance
one method of which is preforming
customized containers for each function
that includes all its required software
packages
it shows good and stable performance and
can just
and can adjust the pool size for each
pre-warm pool
however it brings heavy memory
consumption
azure study focused on this
exclusive preform model to train a
prediction model for resource-friendly
process management
however for most infrequent functions
the history execution trees may not
expose enough data to train an accurate
model
another method of pre-warming containers
is only installing common packages
and all functions share the template
container pool
this method is more memory space
efficient
but generating customized containers in
the specialization phase for function
from the prevalent containers
suffers from packages download and
installing latency overhead
the overhead may introduce from several
aspects and the performance becomes
unpredictable
first
all functions share the same pre-warm
pool
the pre-owned pool is more likely
breakdown with high concurrency code
startup
take
seo and
cut as examples
their functions are invoked concurrently
or in short intervals
to satisfy complex business logic
such as service workflows
this phenomenon attributes to the
inappropriate process
of the pre-war canada pool
so does it mean if we increase the
process
the code startups can be elevated
proportionally
we find that even though we set a larger
process
the code startups elevated converts to a
stable value
because many functions require runtime
environment
with conflict packages
or package versions
in this case the serverless system has
to retry with code setup
and
cannot be elevated by larger preview
process
in addition even though a function can
get a pre-warmed container that without
poor contention and an image conflict
its specialization
of loading additional packages
may introduce more overhead than
directly code startup
as shown
the code container setup takes about
500 milliseconds
the preform startup takes
15 milliseconds in the best case
but takes more than
1500 milliseconds in the worst case
for example the benchmark ddns
this is because functions in ddns
requires to load and store many
additional packages in the preformed
containers
and the packaging loading is time
consuming
when using template template-based
pre-warm pool there are trade-offs that
are inevitable
as reported from azure study most of the
invocations are from a small part of the
functions a prewarmed container can only
catch a small number of packages for the
low memory overhead
caching packages for frequently invoked
functions
improve the system efficiency
but results in poor user experience
and vice versa
in summary
if we use exclusive preload method
we need to adjust pool size dynamically
the possible solution is to profile and
predict for each function at runtime
however the overhead of building
predicting model for each function is
high
and infrequent function may not have
enough data to trim
so our insight is that the current
container prevalent method is not
efficient
due to several invaluable trade-offs
it is beneficial to activate code setups
without trapping in the same dilemmas
we therefore propose to elevate code
startups without relying on pre-warming
containers
the key idea is leveraging the warm but
idle containers
of some functions
to elevate the code startups
a function invocation that requires code
setup
may share an idle warm container from
other functions
our solution is called peggles
in nature
peggles is a kind of helmet crab
that use abandoned sea shells as mobile
homes
as a crab grows it needs to move into a
bigger one
however empty shears are filled in the
fabric string
so they usually arrange themselves in
order queue
in such way they could reuse others
share and move into it quickly
if we see these unsuitable shifts as
idle containers
can we make a cold startup function
like a crab to reuse other shears
the proposed scheme is effective only
when there are idle warm containers in
some functions
when the invocation tends to suffer from
the cold clinical startup
in principle only underutilized warm
containers that are active due to the
keep life strategy can be used by other
functions
otherwise always stealing a warm
container directly may result in the
code cleaner startup of the big team
function
fortunately service computing systems
usually a job keeper live strategy
for example 15 minutes
to reduce the code startup
the keeped alive containers are idle
before they are recycled
the widely exist dyno load pattern also
makes containers over provision at the
high load
these containers will become idle in the
load jobs as well
one may be concerned about the security
and privacy of the idle container for
reusing to this end we propose zygote
container to replace an idle container
it does not include any data or code of
the owner function
which means it can serve as a safe
checkpoint for sharing
in general the common packages required
by all functions are installed
as a shared domain is a zygote container
this content are mounted anomalously
into zygote
thus ensuring that others cannot
identify a function
each function that may use a zygote
container is given a privileged domain
and is only allowed to access its
corresponding packages directory
the privileged domain and the privilege
control are provided by linux operating
system and
different download users
so how does petrus work with zygote
containers it has four main steps
pedros will identify the idle containers
in each function pool at runtime
once identified pegruz will build zygote
image and then replace an idle container
with a zygote
if a to be held function is going to
code startup
fabulous will schedule a zygote
container and the fork a helper
container for this function to reuse
in the system each function may have
that good containers
so how does peg rules arrange their gold
containers for appropriate forking
we introduce a similarity featured
weighted random sampling algorithm
each select to be helped functions based
on the package similarity between
functions and the frequency of function
code startups
sf wrs policy reduce the number of
packages to be installed
thus minimizing the memory needed and
the overhead of creating zygote
containers
with above designs pedros can elevate
the code startup by reproposing a one
but idle container from another function
in this section
we will introduce our evaluation process
we use 10 best practice applications
with the most github stars from amazon
aws samples as a benchmarks
and other tricks to evaluate progress
fast profile and service bench
show similar results
as observed from replaying as well trace
pebbles reduced the number of code
startups by
84.6 percent
about
73.4 percent of all functions
experience cold startup less than once
in a day with pedros
meanwhile
ninety percent of the functions
experience cold startups less than five
times daily with pedros
the code startup latency is reduced from
hundreds of milliseconds
to 16 milliseconds if elevated
for end-to-end latencies
popular functions have similar
percent tail latency with open risk and
pedros
this is because the slowest
tail latencies
of these functions
still experience warm startup
as these functions are frequently
invoked
for the middle popularity and the low
popularity functions
there are
95 percent tail latencies as the latency
of the function invocation that suffers
from the code kind of startup with
openwhisk
paragraphs indeed brings lower
end-to-end tail latencies
finally we give our conclusion on peg
rules
in summary pebbles proposed to reusing
idle containers to elevate code startups
so it introduced like containers that
contain the shared domain and privileged
domain to provide security and privacy
when scheduling zygote containers
we use a similarity filtered weighted
random sampling algorithm
which can improve the inter-function
container sharing efficiency
another related track presentation
called run d
introduces how to construct container
runtime in service computing to enable
high density and high concurrency
startup
you can also contact us by email with
any questions
thanks for listening