foreign
University today I'm happy to introduce
our work on improving the performance of
RDMAs control Parts with a systematic
approach
this is a joint work with my student
farming Lou and my colleagues long-term
and hypoten
remote directory memory accesses is a
high bandwidth and low latency
networking feature widely adopted in
modern data centers and provides two
Primitives
for one-sided primitive the Nick can
directly read write servers memory by
processing server CPUs
two-sided primitive is a messaging
primitive that provides the same receive
interface
thanks to RDMA many distributed systems
including distributed keyword stores and
distributed transaction processing
systems can have dramatic performance
improvements for example raise Hashem
recently production disaggregated
tiverstop can execute a single keyword
request within 5 microseconds
however so rdma's data pass operation is
extremely fast our name is Control Plus
operation is orders of magnitude slower
specifically on our platform we measure
the end to end connection creation and
connection time of a cube here which
takes 15 milliseconds in comparison
posting and pulling an RDMA one-sided
requests only take two microseconds
more specifically the RDMA control
connection creation time can be
decomposed into three parts first
loading the driver context which
includes current device status and
creating the protection domain
second the application must create
Hardware cues both at the client and at
the server and we need to connecting the
skills by configure configuring them to
appropriate States
this time counts for 4 milliseconds
note that you allow QPR connection
different hosts must exchange connection
permissions through the network which
counts up to 1 milliseconds
from the above breakdown we can see that
the term is bottlenecked by the first
and two steps however our analysis
reveals that they are difficult to
reduce the time is dominated by creating
and configuring Hardware resources
resources for example creating the
hardware queues
one may argue that the Control Plus
codes can hardly affect the performance
of traditional RDMA enabled applications
including distributed QR stores and
distributed databases this is because
these applications run a sufficient long
time which amortize the costs of RDMA
control parts
unfortunately we find the control
process may still affect new
applications especially those that
require a good elasticity
one particular example is RDMA enabled
disaggregated keyword store in such a
setup the nodes are separated in two
rows memory loss these are nodes with
huge amount of memory with little CPU
resources they store the key value pairs
in their memory
second completely notes these are notes
that execute keyword store API 88 on top
of Domino's they have little memory and
has a powerful CPU so they execute the
key value API by reading the key value
contents from when I found the memory
notes using one-sided RDMA
animate this this aggregated camera
stores provide elasticity elasticity by
allowing directly dynamically adding and
removing company nodes and the high
loans it can add more Computing nodes to
improve the performance for low lows it
can reclaim the added nodes to for
better resource efficiency
for such a setup we can see that new
nodes need to dynamically create RDMA
enabled connections to the membranos
thus the high connection time of QPR or
the inevitably increase the tier latency
especially in the load spikes which
means there's a signal increase of loss
of the applications
so the goal of our work is to provide a
systematic solution to reduce audience
Control Plus cost from milliseconds to
microseconds and being compatible to
existing RDMA hardware and software
so to achieve so our basic idea is to
use pulling which means that we catch
the created QPS in a connection pool so
that later applications can reuse the
cash to QPS as long as one is cached
for example suppose application one
started with an empty pool as follows
the normal how do you make Control Plus
which is slow and is your data bus
requests after the qpm is created
after it finishes it can cast to qpm in
an Epic Air connection pool afterward a
new application application 2 can cover
the QP in the pool and the issue
automate request to the customer without
creating and connecting the QPS
however the approach has one important
challenge different applications qpm
cannot be reused and shared
this is because RDMA is primarily
designed as a user space solution which
means that QPS are not designed for
sharing between them
so qpe further has many complex data
structures spreading over the kernel
space and user space
sharing all these features and
coordinating between accesses of
different applications we believe it's
impractical
further sharing QP alone cannot
eliminate the driver loading cost in the
user space automate applications
to address this issue our observation is
that the kernel space RDMA so less used
also provides full functionality of RDMA
for example the user space automate qcm
namely ibv QP has an equivalent ipqp in
a kernel which supports all one-sided
and two-sided operations thus we can
shift the applications RDMA requests to
the kernel space qpx
based on this observation the idea is to
Cache kernel space QPS and put them in a
kernel space QPR pool
thus applications can share and reduce
these QPS since they share the same
kernel to allow the sharing we will
translate the user space RDMA request to
the online kernel space to be request
through system course
note that another benefit of a corner
space solution is that the kernel space
RDMA avoids the code straight user space
driver loading process
this is because the cuddle can pre-load
the driver context during the boot time
now we allow different applications to
share the QP to avoid creating them from
stretch for new applications
so another problem we are facing is that
how to reduce the QP process
so rdbqv is a one-q mapping this means
that we need a dedicated tube here to
connect to a different server moreover
due to the high performance of automate
it is desirable to use different QPS for
CPU to prevent locking overhead as a
result each machine needs to Cache n
plus and QPS where m is the machine
number in the cluster and it is the core
number at each machine to eliminate
eliminate all the control plan costs
this causes a significant significant
amount of memory used especially for
modern RDMA capable cluster with more
than 10 000 nodes
to address this issue we find
dynamically connected transport unless
used but widely supported anime
transport with commercials feature can
help
specifically a single Dynamic connected
QP dcqp can connect to different nodes
without a connection process as a normal
rc2p
the hardware will pick back the
connection requests with the RDMA data
pass request which is extremely fast
for example a DC reconnection Plus data
operation only takes three microseconds
notice that dcqp provides the same
semantic as rcqp which means that they
also provide a reliability
based on adoption of gctp the high level
idea is to reduce the QPS in the pool
with dcqp
so we'll replace all the r Securities
with one dcqp
consequently the kernel can avoid
stalling all the QPS connections to to
all the other nodes
so one problem of using dcqb is that for
each machine to communicate with a
specific host the host must have created
DC Target and hand off the target's
metadata to the client such such that
the client can pass this metadata to
each rlma request to indicate the remote
host
so the question is that how can a client
eventually discover the DC metadata of a
remote Target
a naive solution is to use remote
procedural core RPC for the current
so our debate you provide unreliable
datagram which supports connectionless
RPC
however there are two drawbacks of an
RPC based design
first RPC takes X consumes extra CPU
resources at each node
as a kernel space solution we cannot
dedicate many CPUs for to handle these
requests
second RPC may include long-term latency
due to the required securing and the CPU
scheduling at remote host
the desired way for the digital metric
Discovery is to use one-sided RDMA
so to achieve so we propose an
architecture that uses meta servers to
store DCd method related data
so metadata is in principle similar to
DNS servers that stores a mapping
between a remote nodes RDMA address and
the corresponding dcg metadata
notice that storing all the metadata of
all servers in of your cluster in a meta
server is practical because the metadata
is is extremely small it only consumes
12 bytes
so this separation allows us to use
one-sided RDMA to currently the match
data specifically we implement the meta
server as an RDMA enabled curios store
commonly exploited in literature the
keyword stored can be occurred in
one-sided RMA by parsing remote CPU
which is extremely fast and resource
efficient
consequently a whole connection and data
process only takes 10 microseconds for
for newly new connections
so our final challenge I need to mention
is that how to Multiplex QP to multiple
applications correctly
so to prevent a QP from not sharing to
prevent to prevent an application from
not sharing a cache QP will allow each
dcqb in a pool to be shared among
different applications
so we further abstract the shared QP so
that it gives the application an
illusion of an exclusively owned QPR for
example an application one and
application two they have a exclusively
virtualized the QP after the user space
nevertheless the request to The Virtuous
2p can be folded to the same kernel
space QP so that so that the
applications can always have an
available QP to use
however one challenge of sharing the
same QP among different applications is
that a shared QP can be corrupted even
when application uses correctly because
they assume an exclusive own abstraction
abstraction so if the QP is crafted it
means the connection which is no which
is slow
to this end we carefully add checks
before posting the requests to the
underlying shared QP and reject the
request that can Quant the QV stats if
necessary
specifically we check the following
three things first mail from request
whether the request content contents and
invalid operation code or a memory
reference second whether your question
may overflow the hardware queue
finally we need to additionally dispatch
the requests from different applications
to the practice
from the private destinations because a
shared QB's responses may belongs to
different applications
so after checking all these factors we
can now prepare provide an exclusively
owned QP obstruction to the application
for the shell QP without worrying about
QP Crab Shack
so put it all together with present QR
code a networking library that provides
a micro second skill automate connection
establishment and Community Onyx that
supports DCT QR code is 1500 times
faster than IB works the
de facto standard library for using RDMA
so you also apply many authorizations to
further improve its performance
including dcg metadata caching and
dynamic switch between DC and rcqps so
if you have interest to please refer to
our paper for more information
so to ease development we Implement QR
code as a loadable kernel module using
more than 10 000 rust line of code
we further add a little C shame later to
abstract the system core code for the
calco kernel so to support DCT in the
kernel we also Port the new user space
DCT driver implementation into the
kernel kernel space animate driver by
adding about 250 line of line of C code
to the to the metallics of Ed 4.9 driver
so krco is available on GitHub
so finally we present the evaluation
results of QR core aiming to answer the
following three questions
first how fast is KR course control pair
second what are the costs added to care
course data plan
third can care core benefits existing
anime existing applications that require
elasticity
our evaluations are conducted on a local
rock scale cluster with 10 nodes each
machine has one connect connect X4
Infinity band 100 gigabytes on it
so we compare care core with two Corner
Parts first IB verbs is the de facto
user space standard for using anime
second light is the only kernel space
item solution that leverage kernel space
rcqp for communications
so first let's exam the Control Plus
performance of QR code our first case
study is the performance of multiple
clients connecting to a single server so
from the figure we can see that
character is orders of magnitude faster
that works and lights notice that the
accesses are log scale this is mainly
due to the fact that Clark Hall replace
the Control Plus operations with data
pass operations namely one-sided RDMA
requests to curl the metadata to The
Meta server
light is faster than wolves because it
will avoids the driver loading process
since it's a kernel space RDMA solution
however both light and Buffs are bottom
acted by creating Hardware cues on ionic
next we present the performance of
creating full mesh connections for
cluster of machines
you can see that QR code also takes
orders of magnitude shorter time than
light and works respectively thanks to
the faster performance of connecting one
connections
so krco trades the performance of data
paths for faster control costs now we
show its data pass performance on a
synchronized one-sided animal read
benchmark
the client keeps sending one-sided
uneven read requests to a server in a
room to completion way so we conduct the
experiment by increasing the number of
clients as you can see both characters
and light has a latency increase
compared to RB verbs
the overhead has two parts
first they have like one Microsoft
latest increase due to the system core
overhead since we need a kernel space
QPR pool to uh to share QPS between
different applications
second calc has a slower Peak throughput
due to the instruction of DCT compared
with rcqp using light and verbs DCT has
has to reconnect has a reconnection
message so it speaks throughput Port is
lower
finally we show that QR code can benefit
existing RDMA enabled systems that
require elasticity we choose recession a
production disaggregated RDMA enabled
Cura storm
at times zero there's a low Spike for
the inner workloads therefore rules what
an inventory spoon new Computing nodes
to accelerate its performance
so care core can bootstrap all the nodes
within one seconds thanks to its fast
Control Plus in comparison both
satellite take several seconds to finish
the connection
note that initially cargo has a lower
throughput than verbs because DCT is
slower nevertheless we apply an
optimization to dynamically switch from
dcqp to RC cube in the background for
the applications and can regain the high
performance which is similar to verbs
notice that light is slower than verbs
and clear core at final time because it
doesn't support a low-leaf RDMA API
which is necessary for applying various
RDMA enabled optimizations exploited by
race
so in summary QR code is a micro second
scale automate control plan for creating
RDMA enabled connections QR code
achieved this by retrofitting DCT with
kernel space automate connection tool
still has a slower data path and thus is
not suitable for all the applications
yet we have shown that it can benefit
existing RDMA enabled applications that
require elasticity
so in conclusion we present KR call a
micro second skill anime control plan on
existing anime hardware and software we
show that QR code can benefit its
existing RDMA elastic applications
including RDMA based disaggregated QR
store we hope QR code can further
benefit more applications for example
RDMA enabled service Computing so thanks
for your listening