thank you
I would like to talk about the modulo
today which is a model based testing
tool
it's specially designed for finding
convergence failure Buffs in distributed
systems with the diverges listing models
these days there are various cloud
services and large-scale web
applications relying on distributed
systems
in this talk we'll focus on replicated
distributed storage systems where each
replica is a key value store trying to
keep its data set in sync with other
replicas
here's the one example convergence
failure but we found from
jira about database of Zookeeper so its
priorities labeled as blocker which
means it's one of the most severe bus
and its reproduction step is as follow
so you start server zero first and then
create some data items on This Server
zero and you shut down the zero zero
then you restart server zero this time
you start you also start server one and
these two servers are supposed to be
replicas
but then clients can cannot read those
data items on server zero while clients
can still read those data items on
server zero sorry clients cannot read
those State items on server one but can
can read data items on server zero
so servers are out of sync
clients May read inconsistent data and
make incorrect decisions based on that
which may resulted in catastrophic
events
so Patrick hunt who is the author of The
Zookeeper paper
left a comment saying this is a serious
issue
as is causing the follower which is a
server one
uh to get an inconsistent view of the
database
so it's a serious bar
and here's another example we found from
the same boat database and this bug
requires long sequence events to be
interleaved to find it so these types of
bugs can be pretty difficult to find
and also this ball resulted in several
soft tasks a couple of them are still
not still not closed and Bug itself
hasn't been resolved and it has been 10
years
and we found there are other similar
bugs in the about database
so it's recurring problem so we need
some kind of automated ball finding tool
for these types of Buffs
so what happens in internally
is as follow so
let's say there are two clients and
client One sensor put request writing
value one for some key
and after some time passed another
client
uh it's best to read the value that's
written by the previous put which is one
in this case
the key enabler for this is Convergence
property that keeps the replicas
consistent
what happens is client one sense put
request one of the replicas commit that
operation it becomes a different from
other replicas so replicas diverse but
then replication protocol works and
other replicas replicate that operation
committed so their data set becomes
equivalent so replicas converge
then client uh
read data from arbitrary replica and
still get the consistent value which is
very one
but what if a replica failed after a
commit the right operation
so in this case if replica that
committed the writing for the key with
the value of one fail and it becomes
unavailable for replication
therefore unless the failures recovered
Divergence across replicas remain
once failure recovery is made we think
mechanisms run and replicas replicate
and commit the operation just like the
the other one and they become converged
again so
uh that's how it how they reach
convergence but if there is a software
bug lurking in the resync mechanisms I
may manifest in certain Divergence
listing scenario and some of the
replicas may suffer from convergence
failure in this case the convergence may
never occur again and we call these
types of bugs convergence failure bus or
cfps
if a client happens to read data from
this faulty replicas then he will read
the inconsistent data
so there are existing approaches to find
balls in distributed systems
model based testing and model checking
is State space exploration
they systematically and exhaustively
explore the state space of the system
under test
but their state space exploration is
usually generic and not targeted
therefore they may easily suffer from
the notorious State explosion problem
on the other hand manual testing and
random testing explore State space
randomly but their state space
exploration is neither exhaustive nor
systematic
so they make miscorner cases
our approach is targeted systematic and
exhaustive state space exploration and
because it's targeted we mitigate the
state explosion problem
and because we systematically and
exhaustively explore the state space we
don't miss the corner cases
we made one a key observation that we
can convert the sequence of Complex
events such as the one on the left hand
side here into much shorter sequence
that's concise and reproducible
just like the one on the right hand side
involving the relevance events such as
crash could restart and resync for
example
and we can interleave this to find new
CFO BS
we further can reduce
these steps into Divergence and
convergence
so by focusing on interleave exploring
various interleavings of Divergence and
convergence can reduce the state space
explore significantly more
uh and also we separate abstraction from
the concrete execution
we developed the Divergence resync model
for that
it's Divergence resync model or trm uh
represents various Divergence resync
scenarios it is composed of abstract
execution model or AEM and concrete
execution model or cm am models the
target abstract Behavior where an and CM
models the target concrete Behavior
that's compatible with the abstract
Behavior behavior model by AES
so am is essentially a finite State
machine
um we use the depth first search
strategy
and state exploration is is
uh it's actually a repeat repetitions of
past exploration each pass exploration
starts at the initial State and Traverse
down each each stage that hasn't been
visited previously and it ends at the
leaf state where there is no more next
day to visit
we repeat this until we visit every
state in the state space
so we exhaustively and systematically
explore the state space of AEM
and produce schedules
each schedule is basically passed we
just explored
so it's a sequence of Divergence and
convergence
with this modulo Trends generates the
inputs and injects the
into the system under test to find the
box in the real these Theory systems
and benefits of separating abstraction
from concrete execution is twofold in
modulo so first AEM can be reused for
different systems under test
and the common functionality of the cems
that's repeatedly implemented can be
compiled as a library
modulus architecture is pretty simple it
has two components schedule generator
and concrete executor
user must specify and provide a DRM
including AEM and CM
am is going to be given to the schedule
generator
cm is given to the concrete executor
and CM is essentially a system under
test wrapped by a control layer
so scheduled generators is the one that
explores that am's state space and
produces schedule files containing bunch
of schedules
concrete executor takes each schedule
and executed by generating input based
on it and injecting those inputs into
the system under test via cem
after executing each schedule modular
performed bunch of read operations
to see the values of each key on every
replica
and check if there is any key contains
the value that's inconsistent across the
replicas
if inconsistent
Keys detected then modular razor raise
an alarm for detection of convergence
failure bus
now let me explain more detail about how
module use drms
so I'll use a example DRM we used for
zookeeper in this example DRM we have
two State variables
for the AEM
and those are replica State and online
State user must specify the number of
ride operations to inject as normal PS
and the number of replicas to use as
known replicas
with the norm replicas given we can we
can determine the size of arrays for
State variables
and each index in the array is for each
replica so first first index is for
replica a second index is for replica p
and so on
and then with the Dom Ops given we can
generate the predefined write sequence
we write values that are monoclonically
increasing
and based on this we can index each
right operation to distinguish to
distinguish it explicitly
so replica stay represents up to which
right has been committed by replicas
or replicas so far and online stay
represents the availability of each
replica
uh so here is what uh one example state
state s0 is we It's actually an initial
State and in this state uh every replica
has committed uh the first right
operation so set data is the right
operation we use for zookeeper
and so there are key key access values
are all zero so State variable for as
serious should be set as follow so
replica stage should be set as zero zero
zero and online stay should be set as
true true which means every replica is
converted at the very first right
operation and they're all online
and each state has a bunch of enabled
transitions and let's say we pick the
Divergence transition
which represents a Divergence scenario
where we crash the replica B first and
then inject a right operation so replica
ANC committed
then ANC crash
if we apply its Divergence transition to
s0 we we get to the next state S1 where
replica stays set to 1 0 1 which means A
and C has committed the second right
operation but B did not because of the
failure and online state is set to false
false false to indicate every replica is
crashed
in S1 there are also a bunch of enabled
transitions
and let's say we pick one of the
convergence transition
which represents the scenario where we
restart a and b and then let them
re-sync
if we apply this transition T2 to S1 we
get to the next state as two where
replica stays to 111 which means replica
B successfully replicates the second
right the the second right operation and
all the replications all the replicas
actually converted an online state in
the case the amp are online while C
remains crashed
so with this we can perform per test
exploration
and pass expiration produce a schedule
which is which is a sequence of
Divergence and convergence transitions
and concrete executor takes its schedule
and
um
get its transition and translate it into
the more concrete test inputs so for
example for Divergence transition
it translates it into the intermediate
representation
where crash B and write 1 to X and
question C are executed we just actually
get further translated into more
concrete test inputs
um
which is a q minus 9 for b z Theta
threat asleep Q minus 9 for a and C
and similarly for convergence transition
we can translate it into restart a and b
and wave for resync which will get
further translated into Java uh
to restart the A and B and and scanning
the logs for certain messages to be
printed out for the indication of the
resync
uh and once inputs are generated
concrete executor injects them into the
system under test at the correct timing
relative to some internal events so for
example we have a thread asleep for a
Divergence transition
after set data but before kill -9 for a
and C this is to ensure that ANC commit
the injected right operation before they
get crashed
foreign
so if we don't have this time delay it's
possible that ANC crash before they
committed so the test is going to be
deviated from the Our intention
um and for for convergence we have
scanning the law after restarting the A
and B
uh this means we wait until the leader
election completes and recent completes
otherwise it's possible in the next
transition right injection is made but
failed because there is no little
elected yet
so we need these kinds of
non-determination control
module is implemented in 8.k lines of
code in total schedule generator and
concrete executor are only 0.3 K lines
of code and 0.8 K lines of code
respectively
Divergence resync models takes up most
of the code which is
7.3 K lines of code this includes all
five drms we Implement method and among
these AMS are 2.8 highlights of code and
CMS are 4.6 K lines of code
and we applied modular to zookeeper
mongodb and redis
as a result we found 11 cfbs and we
newly discovered five cfps in Zookeeper
and one cfp in mongodb and we reported
them
and we also detected one known cfp in
mongodb and four known cfps in redis
and we found that the size of State
space to explore
is small enough so we could finish the
systematic and irresistative state space
exploration
for the AEM of drms we use to find
aforementioned box
also we could reuse AEM for both
zookeeper and mongodb so it shows that
modulo is supportable
and we made the repeated portion of cems
for radius trms as a library and
implemented each radius the radius is
DRM by extending
the based on the library so it also
shows that modulo is extensible
so in conclusion modulo is effective in
finding bugs in real world distributed
systems
our key approaches is targeted
systematic and exhaustive state space
exploration
and key ideas are exploring only
interleaving of Divergence and
convergence which mitigate the state
space a state explosion problem and
separating abstraction from concrete
execution via AEM and cem
uh therefore mojulo becomes more
portable and extensible and so modular
can be extended to find Buffs in your
distributed systems and the code is here
in the GitHub
so thank you very much and I'll take any
question now