hello everyone my name is tim kim today
i'm gonna talk about
timer does not work
fine okay then i will restart hello
everyone my name is tim kim today i'm
gonna talk about how to improve failure
handling or deep learning job failure on
shared gpu cluster
this work was done on collaboration with
srian zhang
zhongzhou lee sube lee and mj at unist
a shared gpu cluster provide hardware
and software to various users for team
learning model training and this user
can take advantage of several
functionality provided by this
infrastructure such as resource
scheduling storing data model and
handling the failure
this year gpu cluster is now commonly
used to run their workloads in many
companies such as microsoft amazon and
google
in this shared gpu cluster one major
source of resource inefficiency is
unsuccessful job completion due to the
job failure
that failure occurs during daily
training and this failure results in a
waste of gpu resources used until the
failure occurs previous studies focus on
workload characterization and
discuss how this failure affect the
cluster utilization
they found there are many types of
failure in shared gpu cluster and it is
hard to generalize and categorize the
failures based on each reason for the
failure
our research differs from this study in
that we present an actual method to
leverage knowledge from prior works
so
the key research question is how do we
deal with various failures to enhance
the cluster resource utilization
for failure handling we can largely
classify all existing job failure into
two categories
first deterministic of or dt failure and
second non-deterministic
or entity failure
dt failure is repetitive so it will
repeat with retry on failure such as
syntax error and corrupted data
on the other hand entity failure is
stringent and can be overcome with retry
on failure such as transient network
failures
now let's look how existing shared gpu
cluster handle failures in the presence
of dt and ndt
when the user submits the training job
and the job is scheduled the cluster
manager place the job onto the cluster
execution
now let's assume that training fails
fails before javascription complete
existing approach takes simple heuristic
to handle this failure the first
approach is performing a fixed number of
retries on failure
really microsoft cluster scheduler has
this kind of handling strategy
this can increase the job success rate
by retrying entity failures but it
wastes resources by retrying dt failures
the other approach commonly used in
practice is simply terminating fail job
this can avoid the worst retry on dt
failures but it sacrificed the job
success rate by not retrying ndt
failures
our work civila can differentiate dtn
entity failure and with visibilia what
we want to achieve is no retry on dt
failure and retry on entity failure
as the figure shows civilia has a
classifier and it receives a low
information of failed java low and
determines the failure type
deterministic or non-deterministic
we set the two design goal as two parts
first
it must be accurate in distinguishing
failure
also second it must learn various law
continuously without human intervention
before showing how to do this let me
first describe workload characteristic
from microsoft philly trace to reveal
the opportunity
because the time constraint i don't
explain trace itself in detail but from
the trace you can show how many jobs
experience dt failure and what is the
portion of gpu hours used for retrying
those dt failures
they are showing in the left and right
figure respectively x-axis shows the
number of gpus retested and y-axis shows
the portion of corresponding fail-jobs
on request stage of size
by this analysis five to 23 percent of
jobs experience dt failure and second
gpu hours spent for retrying those dt
failures as much as 12 to 20 percent
so we conclude classifying failures by
similar into dtn entity failure can save
significance of cpu hours not waste
wasted only quantity failure
given this opportunity for the rest of
the talk i will cover the two design
goals in more detail
first how to build a accurate classifier
while there are several possible ways to
construct a classifier we employ a rm
model based classifier as it is more
amendable to determine dt or entity
failures from textual job load
information
we use standard error stream of training
jobs directly into stdl and std error
load files
as explained in many preceding
researches
every software stack uses these error
rogues to record execution status
and add a related information
and the other training workload is no
exception in this part
so let's take a look at this example
this logo data shows the call stack of
prior
to triggering an error in the blue color
and the reason of the failure in red
color
one of the main challenges is that low
format is unstructured and become
diverse over time
this makes a static way like grab on low
data for specific keywords
impractical in the long run situation
and this is why we make automatic
machine learning using approach
since the low data is highly
unstructured the failure classification
need to polish the load with
pre-processing stage
this is how to transform a plain text
log before training
first the log sequence from each fail
job lobe is passed into the structure
format with evaluating the redundant
messages
after that the structural laws are
transformed into semantic vectors to
train the model
these semantic factors are calculated
not only by the word in the past look
but also by its significance by
weighting tom frequency inverse document
frequency technique
this pre-process load is used for
training model in sevilla at first
civilian needs initial training phase
with collecting low data
this data needs leveling by domain
expert
since civilad
civil has auto leveling process we think
idly this is the only phase that human
intervention is needed
we plug in two rna model statement gru
that are specialized on processing the
sequencer data we also made the
simulation plug in more model so that it
can feed on the change of dl models
now are we going to explain the second
part of civila
how to update the classifier without
human intervention with human
intervention in updating model needs
cumbersome process to build a new
training data set with leveling process
to address this issue we plug auto
leveling mechanism by using classifier
decision on leveling data
after similar decide the fail job is
whether dt or ndt the classified
instance is fed into training data set
with a level corresponding to civilized
decision
this auto leveling phase makes similar
subsequent training can proceed in an
online manner
therefore the decision by civilized
important because misprediction in one
step leads cascading effect to civilized
future performance
to address this issue we adopt a
strategy
where the classified decision made by
majority voting from multiple models
let's look at the scenario on
on top view here's the job placed onto
the cluster and the jar fails the
cluster measure corrects the failed log
data and display load data is fed into
similar and similar send the decision to
the cluster manager
based on the civil's decision the
cluster manager decide whether kill or
retry the failed job now i'm moving to
the evaluation
since there is no available data set for
dia job failures we constructed data set
for our study with 97 loads from data
center operator and 159 loads from
manual collected by stable flow we text
augmented the data set for more diverse
scenarios
in the evaluation we go over eight
training lines
to show how well given classifier
incremental update we start with twenty
percent of label data set
at round one representing the initial
training phase in sibila afterwards we
add 10 of each round auto level by
classifier representing continuous
updating without human intervention
for comparison with civila we use a
clustering method that is represent a
known machine learning approach each of
two rna models as a single model and
lastly the oracle which always use
ground truth level
the first question for evaluation is can
civilia classify failure type well
this is the result of entity failure
classification performance from round
one to a
precision is showing the precision that
we call as a metric the performance of
single rna model use case is better than
clustering method especially in recall
but both stm and gre model are
suffering fluctuation as clustering did
in precision part however civilian
performance is more stable than other
comparisons on both metrics
all the last round stimuli achieves the
highest performance compared with other
approaches also it is almost the same as
the oracle case
dt failure classification case
performance also shows same tendency so
civilized classification performance is
consistently high and comparable to the
oracle which used ground truth level
the next question is can sibila improve
cluster efficiency
we simulate it based on trace
from microsoft philly and the simulator
is from preceding research
we simulated three policy smallest job
first and two recently proposed policies
grass and kittens
the cluster simulation has 200 machines
each have a gpus
we have two competing policies oracle we
have 100 accurate prediction and fully
tried that we tried jobs with fixed
number of times like microsoft feeling
we calculated similar performance in
risk prediction applied to randomly
chosen job
we measured average of completion time
as a metric
compared with the fully tried case
predictive return improved 15.4 percent
for sjf and 6.5 percent for dealers and
kitties
also compared with the oracle case the
performance is only worth one percent
the last question is can sibila maintain
high job success rate with predictively
trying
when misreaction happens in ndt failure
some entity failures are killed without
retry this affect the job success rate
since civila's prediction is not 100
accurate i'm showing the effect of
civilian owned job success rate here
compared with the full retry which
achieved the highest success rate
civilized success rate is only 0.06
percent lower so in conclusion
sibila can provide a higher self-success
rate while reducing resource waste
so today i presented sevilla
with civila we can only retry on failure
when the failure is repeating civilized
highly accurate in classifying such
failure and through simulation we show
that we can actually improve cluster
efficiency this is the end of my talk
thank you for listening and i'm happy to
take a question