my name is indeed antoine and today i'm
going to talk about mccarran a
membership service for microseconds
applications so this is joint work with
rashid and athanasius from epfl as well
as huabing and bankfee and xavier from
huawei
so let's start this talk with an
overview of what data centers can look
like today well given that modern
applications tend to follow a micro
services or oriented architecture well
that data center is pretty much a zoo
with many micro services all connected
together in many integrated ways and
that's great because at the end of the
day you get like elasticity but the
problem with this architecture is that
when you have a failure like the one
here on top well it actually propagates
to many micro services and potentially
many applications and so that's the
reason why today maybe more than ever
failures truly are first-class citizens
that you should try to deal with as fast
as possible before they propagate too
much
but like failures are not a new thing so
how do we usually deal with them and the
answer is that this is pretty much the
reason why almost every system
distributed system uses selfies such as
etcd or zookeeper these tools can do
many things but what we are interested
in today is their ability as
membership services
so membership services quickly basically
they act as reliable configuration
stores so by configuration i pretty much
mean like what is the set of nodes that
are within the system
and it's very important that this
configuration or view or membership
they are pretty much the same are stored
in a reliable fashion because everything
in the system depends on having access
to this configuration so you don't want
to lose configurations
the second thing is that membership
services they are able to update this
configuration in a sequential manner
like by producing a sequence of
configurations and again that's very
important
because you don't want
parts of your systems to be evolving in
different ways
so for um
for
so yeah that's why we build a sequence
of configurations
and lastly they should be able to
invalidate old memberships
to see why the last point is important
we'll go with a small example so let's
say that within our system we have a
data store that is hidden behind the
cache and we have a client that wants to
retrieve value storing our system so the
thing it does is that it's going to wait
for membership and this membership that
it gets m1 there is that the cache c1 is
part of the system so it can use it to
actually retrieve the data the problem
is that what it doesn't know that this
cache has long been replaced by in a
second membership by c2 and so actually
the data it was retrieving from c1 was
stale and that's the reason why it's
very important that old memberships get
invalidated so that you don't have parts
of your system evolving in a previous
configuration
and the thing is that all these
all these features that are provided by
systems such as etcd and zookeeper but
the problem is that they do not evolve
at a microsoft scale so we end up having
applications like in high frequency
trading that operate at microsoft scale
but whenever there's a reconfiguration
or failure actually it suffers from like
huge latency spikes and that's a huge
deal
and so that's where we intervene with
our contribution that is macaron so
macaron is a membership service that
operates at a microscope scale
it's able to detect failures in as
detail as 15 micros to update the
membership in 10 and then to invalidate
all memberships in 25 and so all in all
this allows macaron to react to failures
in 50 micros and it does so by
leveraging rdma
because rdma is pretty much at the core
of macron let me give you a short
overview of what it is well rdma stands
for remote direct memory access it's a
networking technology that allows a
process to access the memory of a rev of
a remote one without invoking the cpu of
the latter
so in that example we have writer on the
left that wants to put a message
in the memory of the guy on the right so
the only thing it has to do is to send a
small request to its local rdma nic that
is going to fetch data in the local
memory and send it over fabric and
install it in the remote memory
and a great thing with rdma is that you
do not invoke the cpu of the machine on
the right and that allows for microscope
scale communication and great tail
latency
so now that we have another view of rdma
we can go back to macron itself
so the first task that macron has to do
is to detect failures very fast
and usually in distributed systems
detecting failures fast is kind of
problematic because we detect failures
by relying on timeouts and so when you
have timeouts you have two strategies
either you go with like uh very large
timeouts in which case you don't have a
lot of false positives but it takes
forever to detect a failure or you go
with short timeouts in which case you're
able to detect failures super fast but
you will have a lot of false positives
and that's a problem because you don't
want to suffer from reconfiguration that
are useless for your
system so
timeouts do not help
and
macron works around this issue but
recognizing that not all failures are
equal
actually there are like many kinds of
failures and for many of them you don't
need to rely on timeouts
for instance
when you have process faders you can
rely on
on the kernel to get some help and to
avoid timeouts
when you have kernel failures well you
can get help from the rdm and nick and
again not use timeouts
sure when you cannot communicate with
the machine at all for instance there's
power failure then you have to rely on
timeouts but hopefully because the
fabric is fast enough you can
tune the timeouts that you're going to
be using for rdma
there's a kind of failures that we don't
deal with and those are byzantine
failures they fall out of our scope
so let's have a quick look at how we
deal with the first two kind of failures
well when there's a process failures
it's process failure it's that simple
the app just pre-registers itself to the
kernel and tells it please when i crash
send my id over the network send a crash
notification and so when it happens the
canon is going to handle the depth of
the process and simply send notification
over the network this is that simple
this does not involve timeouts and this
is 100 accurate
but sometimes we cannot even get help
from the kernel for instance maybe the
cpu is hanging
so that's an issue and that's why we use
another feather detector that we run in
parallel
you see for that feather detector to
work what we mandate from the app is to
have a counter local one that it exposes
over rdma and it's gonna increment that
counter in a timely manner then as a
remote node what you do to detect a
failure of this app is that you're gonna
read that counter over rdma and if by
reading twice in a row you detect that
this entire counter has not been updated
then you know that the app has crashed
uh the very neat thing with that uh with
that uh failure detector is that
uh it works even if the kernel is dead
even if the app is dead because rdma
truly does not need the cpu to be
working to access the memory so the only
thing that you need to work you need for
that
failure detection mechanism to work is
that the argument nic is still
working
and the other nice thing is that this
does not
depend on the network asynchrony the
only thing that you need to be able to
do as a remote node is to access the
counter it doesn't matter how long it
took to access the counter it could have
taken like five years doesn't matter so
we don't have false positives there
and so
the takeaway is that really if you can
somehow manage to take network synchrony
out of the equation then you can have
fast and accurate failure detection
then the second part when you have a
nice feather detector that works at
microsecond scale is to update the
membership in a consistent manner
so to do so macaron uses plain old paxos
that plays a very nice trick
so because it optimized it for
optimizes it for rdma unfortunately i
would have to go over paxos very briefly
not trying to explain how it works and
why it works but how it works
so in paxos we have two kinds of nodes
we have proposers and acceptors
the acceptors they truly are the only
one to maintain some state and this
state is pretty minimal and for a
purpose to decide for instance on a
sequence of memberships the only thing
it does is that it's going to invoke two
rpcs at the acceptors and these rpcs as
you can see they are dead simple you
just they just get and the acceptor just
gets some value from the proposer it
uses this value to update its local
state and then it returns
one of its local variable super simple
the problem with paxos is that it
involves the cpu on both sides so the
trick we were playing there is that we
move all this logic there on the side of
the proposer
so we take everything away from the
acceptor except for the state and we
transform the original rpc into
one-sided one how does it work well very
simple first the proposer reads the
state from the acceptor locally and it
gets it local then it applies the
transformation on the local state that
it fetched and then it uses a comparing
swap to update the state of the remote
acceptor and the nice thing here is that
this comparing swap ensures that this
remote remote invocation of the rpc is
absolutely equivalent to an rpc that
would be accepted would be a sorry
running on the acceptor
and so the takeaway here is that by
using one-sided rpcs while we're
actually able to achieve blazing fast
consensus
then the next thing that you want to do
once you have decided in a sequence of
memberships is to make sure that there's
no one living in a previous memberships
previous membership
so if we go back to the issue we had the
beginning of the presentation so the
client had gotten a membership but he
didn't know whether that membership was
actually the active one the current one
the one in which everyone should be
should be operating
so what is the active membership we
expose that with a method that we call
the active method to which the client is
simply going to give a membership and
get back boolean saying yes or no this
thing is the active one
how it works that symbol the client is
just going to ask the membership service
then when it knows that that
that membership is active and when it
gets the yes the thing is activity knows
that at some point between the
invocation and the response of the
method
that
that membership was active so then it
contacts the cache
and finally after having read the value
from the cache it calls again active and
what it knows there is that because the
membership was active before and also
after reading from the cache then that
membership was active all the way
through the when we were reading the
cache so
this the read there was not pulling some
stale data
the problem with this approach is that
it has super high latency as you can see
in this example we just tripled the
latency of our cells
so how could we kind of preserve the
semantics of this active coal but make
sure that it has as low overhead as
possible
and our answer is to use lizes
and what we moreover what we want is
that those diseases should be as as
small as possible because the longer
leases are in the distributed system the
longer it's going to take to move on to
the next configuration so if we can get
these to work at a microscope scale then
that's great and that's what we do so
the clients delete the results of the
active method for 20 micros then they
keep on renewing the lenses that they
have on on this thing in the background
to be sure that they always have some
way of
getting the result from active locally
so if we go back to our previous example
now the client is split in two parts the
background and foreground and so as i
was saying the background is going to
get released and renew it so that now
when the client wants to read some data
from the cache
it can simply check
if the membership it has is the active
one locally
zero overhead almost
read from the cache
and then it's gonna send which again the
operation but with very low overhead
as you can see
and the great thing with that scheme is
that it does not require require
clocks to be synchronized within the
system that is
as you can see we never sent a timestamp
over the network we're able to have
these without communicating about what
this guy thought about the time was to
the membership service the only thing
that we require is that
the clock drift is approximately is
bounded so that the time when measured
at the client is approximately the same
as the time when measured at another
client
and this allows you to have because you
don't have clock synchronized clocks you
have leases that last approximately 20
micros
and because you are losing your overhead
is no more than 40 nanos at the end of
the day
so that was it for our macaron briefly
works i mean that's just a summary now
the question is how does it perform so
we are moving to the evaluation
so first of all our setup our setup is
comprised of eight nodes they are all
linked together via 100 100 giga bps
switch
we have three nodes that we are using to
replicate macron
uh two nodes that we use to for the
service that we're gonna benchmark
macron through and then we have three
clients that we use to put load on the
system the first point we're trying to
make in our evaluation was that indeed
by using macron you could build super
fast
distributed reliable services and so we
used macron to implement a replicated
key value store
so what we did is that we took
the state of the art for a key value
store that that is heard
and we compared our implementation our
replication scheme that is this one here
on the right with what you would get by
replicating it with mu new being the
fastest smr state machine replication uh
system available that is tailored for
rdma
so
uh
in all so what we benchmarked was the
latency of get requests of puts and also
the failover of the system uh in what
you can see is that for get requests we
don't have much penalty
between the version that is unreplicated
of heard and the one that uses macron kv
the reason why is that again we're using
the the active method as described
before which has very low overhead on
the other hand when your replicates get
i mean when you replicate the key value
store using mu because it's doing state
machine replication it has to replicate
the get requests so you will have a lot
of overhead and that's what you can see
here
then if we move to put requests
we're not getting like that much uh
performance and actually this is
attributed to implementation details
so
[Music]
so so you can assume that both systems
work the same speed
and finally for the failover here we
have a huge huge difference between when
replicated with new and when replicated
using macaron the reason why is that for
mu to be that fast it uses rdma
permissions and setting permissions
using rdma is a control path operation
and control path operations they don't
work at the microscope scale whereas in
the case of mccarran well as well i've
seen previously we can fail over in 50
micros and that's what we get
and so by using macaron you can be the
state of the art
then the second experiment that we have
is like
do they actually work those diseases
that you were describing
only lasting approximately 20 micros
because maybe it sounds a bit too true
to be
too good to be territory
so what we did in this experiment is
that we tested all these our leases with
different amount of network load and
different amount of memory load and so
we have four graphs
and so the x-axis is different
this is durations that we tried and on
the y-axis what you can see is the
proportion of requests or sorry of
fleeces that were renewed on time
and what you can see is that it doesn't
matter the the network load as long as
you're not
like saturating the network you will be
able to get your leases renewed in time
and that's what you can see here with
almost
with the leases being super stable
so
that was it for macaron let me conclude
very briefly
so macron is a membership service for
microsoft fast failover down to 50
micros
it's super easy to integrate it's really
it's just this active method that you
have to call at the right time depending
on the semantics of your program
given our implementation of this active
method we have actually very low
overhead
so mccarron
got
went through the artifact review wall
and it got both functional and
reproduced unfortunately we're not able
to make our guitar public in time to get
the first batch but don't worry because
the thing is now public so you can play
with macron and it's still a prototype
but you can absolutely use it to test
your applications
of course i couldn't go in all the
details so be sure to check out our
paper for more details
and that was it for me and i will be
glad to take your questions if any