[Music]
foreign
let's continue our program and next up
I'd like to introduce Yosh wandera who
will be presenting automating your
circuit maintenance notifications just
is a managing consultant that Network
the core
sorry Network to code and travel from
Minneapolis to join us today this is the
first time this is the first time Jose
is presenting at nalak
and it's a pleasure to have him here to
speak with us today
welcome Jose to Stage is yours thank you
so first off we want to thank the folks
at nanog for having this in beautiful
California as he mentioned Minneapolis
is where I call home my wife told me it
was 23 degrees in the morning yesterday
morning minus five Celsius you know so
I'm grateful to be here
so
um here to talk about circuit
maintenances and how do we look at
automating them and that's a a big part
of
everybody's environment that has a Wham
so first off a quick introduction why
I'm here why why do what gives me some
credibility to come talk here
um I'm a Management Consultant at
networked code I've been involved in
network automation really continuously
for the past three years in my time at
NTC
but really start diving into automain
networks seven years ago so before that
I worked in the retail environment and
Retail very large retail having to do
things on scale before automation just
doing a lot with cookie cutter
environments
um so I've been doing networking for
over 20 years now
um and then I've also an author of The
Open Source Network management book that
you can out there
so the agenda I want to talk about what
the problem is how do we look at
automating the maintenances and make
your life better better
we'll go into a demo and then we'll talk
about the libraries that were used
within this and I do want to call out
everything here that will be talked
about is open source so there's nothing
proprietary nothing about it that you
have to pay money other than just a
little bit of time investment to use the
open source
so the the current process for circuit
maintenances from an Enterprise
perspective this is just a
generalization it may not apply directly
to you you might have some better
processes than this but it's kind of
what's been out there
so it's very manual oftentimes up on the
upper left we've got the provider it's
in blue
um that says okay we need to take
maintenance on our circuit and then
we're going to go ahead and schedule
that circuit maintenance we'll send an
email to all the people that are
impacted and then in Gray over a very
manual process no nothing with
automation the email comes in it sits in
the inbox it's sitting there maybe
there's some searches in the inbox to
see your your primary or the important
circuits if they're going to be taking a
maintenance you want to be aware of that
but they just sit there
as it goes then you there's a it comes
to the day of the events the knock gets
a notification that hey this interface
went down they may go and look at these
circuits and say yep there was a circuit
maintenance or worse yet you get paged
so just a few of the risks that go along
with the things in a manual setup we all
designed the wands if you have a
multi-carrier environment to be able to
withstand a circuit maintenance or a
circuit outage so you very well could be
that you're as you go through the
circuit or your day that hey both
carriers decide to do circuit
maintenance at the same time
very large geography that's likely to
happen
if you have service users in the middle
of the night working in those buildings
where the typical maintenances happen
you need to communicate that that's
about good business sense about how do
we know that the services are going to
be available
maybe you get unnecessary uh on-call
page that's a quality of life I know I
don't like being woken up in the middle
of night even though with kids at home
they make wake me up enough but you know
let's not go ahead and call me because
there's a Planned
maintenance going on
and then reporting inaccuracies we we're
all judged on from a Wan perspective of
what that uptime looks like and be able
to provide services to the End customer
at those sites so we won't be able to
report on that and if it's planned that
shouldn't count against you
so there has to be a better way so this
is looking at taking a look at what we
can do with automation with these types
of things and again all open source it's
out there available today
um so we're going to talk about the net
not about circuit maintenance plug-in so
this is a plug-in that is built to
manage maintenance notifications from
circuit providers
within this there's a library that's a
python a python Library that's a circuit
maintenance parser Library so we are
looking at doing parsers
and through this process that we'll see
that will create objects that can be
accessed via apis inside of your
environment
that's both rest apis and graphql
endpoints and then look at past and
future maintenances that are going on so
be able to say okay what are maintenance
is coming up in the future in the next
seven days 30 days that we can start to
plan for or if we need to report on it
you can take a look at these in a since
they're in that data format you can work
with that and then also you can take
action so go ahead and put these
circuits all the monitoring involved
with the circuits into maintenance mode
so that way you don't get called when
the automated the event happens and it
goes down
and then lastly here we're going to show
how we can actually check to see if
there's any overlapping maintenance that
goes on that with your dual carrier
environments that you're able to say all
right there's going to be a complete
outage you can take action to call the
Carrier and say hey can you move your
maintenance that way the site doesn't
take an outage or at least notify the
end users of that
and last call out here this was all
started by Christian Adele and part of a
hackathon at NTC
so what that looks like from a solution
in an automated perspective the top left
is still the same it's all blue could be
automated I don't have enough purview on
the circuit carriers to say hey are they
automating this environment
but now
on the right side that your customer
environment is all automated so it's
moved from a grade to having a color of
orange in there we'll get that email
that will come in so we're still using
that same email notification process
those will be parsed and then created
have not about objects created that can
be used so from there then the not about
job will go ahead and search through all
those maintenances we know about what
site each circuit goes to and then
you're able to go ahead and say all
right we need to take action on that
particular site
beyond that what's coming soon is not
about has a feature called jobs we're
going to look to enable you to set your
business process inside of a not about
job that will then be able as your
business process if that's a senate
communication or to set the interface on
the device and monitoring into
maintenance mode so that way it's all
set for you
and then as well with this we have the
capability to have the state of the
maintenances be exposed via Prometheus
metrics so this by having that in a
matrix format you're able to scrape that
and be able to get that into your
monitoring platforms
so how are we doing this the first and
the best way that we can work with
emails is a maintenance notification
standard that was proposed that nanog
60.
um it was really the idea around
providing headers and using iCal to just
accompany the emails that are coming in
and then from those headers we can parse
the data very quickly without having to
do regex parsing and put these into
those objects
and so that's a pretty quick and easy
way for the providers to get to provide
value back to the Enterprise as they
serve
so today in the network to code library
that is available we've got support
specific support for EU networks NTT
packet fabric to Leia and Telstra and
there's a generic b cop provider around
that particular
proposal so if they just support it
without anything else any additional
headers we've got that all set to go
I'm not going to read everything on the
right of all the carriers that we
support via an actual text parser but
they're they're out there we do support
if they don't want to be adding the
headers for us that we can go ahead and
still parse that information
so what if my provider does not support
B cop today in the standard well we look
at setup email parsing this isn't
necessarily ideal because emails we all
know emails are just text and they can
change
we rely heavily on the fact that these
are need to remain consistent and that
we can then parse that and get the data
get your circuit ID get the start time
get the end time and be able to put that
into an object
our ideal State though um that I think
we'll hear out there you'll hear from
anybody within automation is being able
to work with apis if we can get an API
access from the provider that says here
is all the maintenances coming up that
is terrific
um we have another library that we have
called diffsync it's a python library
that takes just things from system a
system B and can sync those either one
way into or between the two and so we
would look at doing something with those
apis be able to pull these in as objects
but we're not seeing that as commonplace
today there's a cost that is involved
with providing the API endpoint
maintaining that API endpoint and just
have being able to keep it there
available consistently
so I've got a demo that I'm going to
share
um we'll jump through here in just a
short bit going throughout what we're
going to cover in this so first I'm
going to go into a few things within
notabot that are part of the not about
core project and how circuits and
providers look within this Pro this
platform but then we'll dig into the
exact go through email retrieving the
emails parsing those emails and then
looking for those overlaps
so as we go we've got our circuits we'll
go to the provider page
so on this page with the providers you
can see all the providers you have and
then their ASN number the account number
and the number of circuits
from there going into the detail page we
have that ASN number again the account
number the portal link that can be
documented and the contacts for it and
we see that there's 46 circuits for this
particular setup
so here are all then all the circuits
that we have going through
and then we'll take a look at what a
circuit detail looks like
first we have our status the provider
the circuit ID obviously the things in
blue you can click and move around on
and then on the right side we've got our
terminations so we have our a side where
it's going the Z side going into uh
provider but right now we have no
circuit notifications because there
hasn't been anything ingested yet
so as part of the not about jobs uh
we'll get back to the finding sites with
overlap but we'll go first into the
update circuit maintenances
here we're taken to a page where we can
execute one time or we can set this up
in a cron like every hour every day
every
multiple setups there
so as this job runs it this particular
one took about 10 seconds to execute
it's going through and check reading an
IMAP inbox on Gmail we support both IMAP
and Gmail today
and then it ingests all the data
so from there we can now go back to that
circuit detail and we can see that
there's a circuit maintenance upcoming
for in the next several days here
so we go into that maintenance and now
we have some more details we have the
description we have the status of it if
it's confirmed we have an acknowledgment
field as well but then we also have all
the circuits so your notifications will
come with multiple circuits it will list
that within the notification of what's
all there
from there we'll go ahead and edit and
we have the acknowledgment field set way
through your process you can acknowledge
these circuits and just document hey
someone is aware of this maintenance
upcoming and then we have that be able
to be put on this page you can also Mass
edit all these so we'll just go ahead
and put these all into an acknowledge
State and now we have the check box on
the left that instead of the X
along with this we have a dashboard this
is a configurable circuits with
maintenances in the next 30 days seven
days whatever that's configured to and
then devices since the circus connected
devices in Autobot we can say what
devices are going to be having that
maintenance and then some metrics as
well about just the average duration the
future maintenances and other pieces of
data we'd love to expand that as well if
you have a metric you'd love to see
we'll put that in
so now getting into the job with finding
sites with maintenance overlap
we'll come in and we'll run this one
time I have the same options can run
this repeatedly
but now just sort sort through all those
records and check to see if there was
any kind of overlap we should show an
overlap at LAX that LAX one two both
have overlapping maintenance from its
primary and secondary carrier and then
we go all the way through and finally we
have a log that tells us exactly how
many maintenance notifications we've
parsed through and this is only
forward-looking we're not looking to add
things in the past
foreign
so a few of the libraries that we
leverage here
first is the circuit maintenance Plugin
or the sake sorry circuit maintenance
parser this is a parsing Library it's uh
pure python you we've you can put this
into your own environment with or
without this plugin so we're looking to
continue to enhance this Library if
there's a library or if there's a
carrier that does not support or we
don't have support for this and you want
to use it we very much welcome either
issues on GitHub that say hey here's a
maintenance notification from this
provider can you make a parser for this
or if you want to provide the feedback
of hey this is the parser how it looks
go ahead and open a pull requests and
contribute back we very much will help
you through the process as well so
take a look there
and then what's shown here is the not
about plug-in circuit maintenance so the
QR code will take you to that page
specifically
to be able to go through and get
everything installed that we walk
through here
and then the link to not about itself
the source of Truth database
excuse me
so what can you do this is also what I'm
here to call to action can you help the
community
so first and foremost ask your provider
can they support create an API endpoint
that we can then go ahead and start to
create a connection from that API
endpoint and ingest that into into these
databases or your own databases having
that endpoint we're going to be able to
do a lot more with that
if they don't support the idea of having
an API which there's some costs involved
with that then ask them to add the the
iCal proposal of adding headers into the
their emails when I was going through
setting up this demo sign up a python
script to send emails adding the header
was very quick so I would imagine
hopefully they're automated their side
on the carrier side can you just add
headers that come into the inbox it
won't change the behavior of the inbox
today but we'll be able to get some much
more Rich detail there
and then lastly if you have a provider
that's not listed on the supported list
today Bring It On in let's see what
their maintenance notifications look
like hopefully it's a template a
one-time thing
and then we can write the parsers that
can be there and share that amongst the
community so not everyone has to do
everything for every carrier
so with that we've got some questions or
foreign
awesome
hi I'm Michael Costello Drive nuts uh so
you were mentioning the uh the
maintenance notification best current uh
operational practices work uh as I
understand it that group uh as the last
time I heard I think it was 2020 uh they
were trying to redo that work or restart
that initiative within the w3c and I was
wondering if you knew anything about
that
right now I do not have any information
on that uh definitely something that
we'll be looking to get in contact with
and and be fully supportive whether you
know from the process perspective they
really have that here what that in input
for it we very much welcome any
adjustments or anything else to
make our community better yeah if
they're still working on it I think that
they would really like to talk to you
yes definitely would love to love to
join in with them so thank you thank you
hey uh Chris Whitfield with Twitter
um you noticed there you had a long list
of carriers for whom there are
uh parsers which presumably read the
body of the email to pick out the
necessary information
um is there ever any
any collaboration with those carriers
um with to write those parsers
question one question two how often do
those parsers have to be updated because
the carrier has changed the format of
their maintenance notifications those
are two great questions
um first off I think this Library itself
is definitely new in 2022 that we've put
out
um so we're we're looking to Branch out
you know where our skin in the game
isn't around anything specific with it
and we just we're looking to enhance the
the way we manage networks
um so definitely this Library hopefully
we're here to help show that
um and then follow up on that yes we
have definitely seen this in our clients
where hey we had everything all great
for a particular provider and nope now
there's some new characters in it so
we're looking at some ways to continue
to enhance that as well I think that
just had some conversation yesterday in
fact around how can we enhance this
further to be able hey if that template
changes how can we still ingest the
important data because a calendar
timestamp generally looks about the same
a circuit ID from a provider hopefully
doesn't change too much you know maybe
we change a dash to a period or there's
a space in there but do what we can to
ex to take that information in
thank you and yeah
uh Joel maslak from Netflix
my question is do you handle in the
parser changes to the notification start
and end notices those types of things
indeed we do so there's a few other
things I didn't show in here and that's
a great follow-on that I know Christian
who's can't join us today would uh
absolutely he'd hurt me probably next
time I see him but yeah so we support
the change in notifications we'll also
change the date for that notification
and there's a change log that goes along
with that so we're able with that
maintenance notification we key in on us
the ID or we make an ID on it for it and
then we will track that along but if
it's got changed the date or if it got
canceled we're able to put that kind of
notification in
um the follow-up on that as well that I
didn't get into this is if you get a
notification with a circuit that you
don't have in the database whether it
doesn't belong to you or you're if was
disconnected for some time ago and it's
you're still paying for you think you
disconnected it in your source of truth
but the carrier's still billing for you
and there's some maintenance we can have
we also alert on that type of thing so
thank you thank you
awesome and thank you for the time
[Applause]
[Music]