[Music]
foreign
I'd like to present Marcus Hines and Rob
Shakir who'll be presenting emulating
Network topologies and kubernetes at
Kates right k8s I'm always confused
about that
we have too much tubercology Marcus is
an engineering productivity lead at
Google and travel from Mountain View to
join us today this is Marcus first time
on the nanog stage as he co-presents
with Rob and Rob Shaquille Works in
Google's Network architecture team and
also contributes to open source projects
and standards bodies Rob presented at
nanning for the first time in 2011 and
again in 2019. thanks for being us with
us todays guys
thank you very much I I it occurs to me
I probably should have updated my bio I
do do that job but I also do a bunch of
other things now you only seem to
acquire jobs at Google
uh so yeah we're going to talk a little
bit about some work that we've been
doing uh around emulating Network
apologies and our use of kubernetes for
that um we're presenting on behalf of
both Google Engineers as well as the
kind of wider open Comfort Community
which is one of the vehicles for this
work meeting open source
and
hopefully so we'll start out with uh
let's just run down what we're going to
go through I'm going to say well why on
Earth do we want to do this what are we
trying to solve what's the thing that
we're trying to do
um then I'll hand over to Marcus and
he'll introduce knee and talk about what
we're actually doing how that works and
then I'll come back and we'll try and
talk about the real world use case so
Something That We're actually doing with
this what's the thing that we're trying
to achieve we're meeting some of the
goals that we laid out at the start of
the presentation
so quick disclaimer first Marcus and I
are up here on the stage but we're
presenting on the behalf of a ton of
Engineers at Google and elsewhere uh
these folks are really talented they've
made really great contributions they've
really driven this work forward and I
think we've really seen in in this kind
of overall ecosystem the real benefits
of open source of getting views from
different places being able to share the
ways that we want to iterate on things
and really Drive New you know new
Innovative approaches that work for both
us as a network operator as well as from
you know other network operators as well
as equipment vendors to really build a
good ecosystem around this and it's it's
a it's a real Testament to think how far
we've come as some of the industry of
getting into open source did how these
collaborations are growing
um but absolutely want to call out the
talented folks that we work with and
make sure that they're acknowledged as
to uh we're just up here doing some
marketing for their work
so why do we want to look at some form
of network emulation why do we want to
look at something that gives us a way to
spin up nodes
um in a different way and kind of take a
step back to what are the things that
we're you know we're often doing
of course we are always adding features
to the network we kind of say oh like
okay we've just if we only had this one
thing then things would be simpler or if
we had this one thing then things would
be more efficient or we could reduce the
cost of the network so the reality is
that we're always going to be
introducing these these features and so
we want to find out ways that we can
make the the process of introducing
features as low cost and as fast as
possible and for many of those features
you know there's some of them that do
depend on hardware and having you know
exact like chips burnt or new new
silicon architectures that or new
hardware layouts that we that we would
need to be able to drive that work but
many of the things that we're doing you
know and especially when we're evolving
the fleet that we've got in the ground
or of course things that are done in
software or the things that we can
emulate in software so we really want to
say how do we get to the stage where
rather than having you know these like
array of labs that each each developer
kind of has to time share onto and say
how do we just basically make that such
that we can have an infinite number of
topologies at least one percent per
developer so you're not sitting there
waiting for the topology or you're not
sitting there thinking like oh well when
I get the lab equipment I'll do this or
are you breaking something doesn't block
other people so I really want to be able
to have that as a basis for you know
moving Network development into the same
way that we think about software
development I don't have to think about
software development you know can I can
I get to the compiler can I run this on
the machine right I want I just go do it
and then I get to iterate on it in my
own space so this is a real enabler for
kind of the velocity of adding features
to the network
so once we've added those features to
the network though we also want to be
able to say well how do we robustly and
repeatably test those those features so
we've got a set of things that we that
were running on the network maybe we're
evolving them maybe it's an existing
Network maybe we're changing something
in there we want to build of course we
need to build test them we need to be
able to test them before we deploy them
um and the the kind of theory here is if
we were to take something take those
those uh tests and we say well we can
run them on Hardware of course we can
you know we've all built labs and
there's large lab infrastructures that
we've maintained for many years but
they're pretty fragile you know Hardware
fails fibers fail the the
um Power fails all these kind of things
kind of stop us getting to getting to
the state the state where these tests
are easy for us to repeat easy and easy
for us to keep robust you know a test
failure happens and you say well is it a
hardware flake is it something to do
with a failure in the the actual
infrastructure was it that actually the
lab wasn't in the state that it should
have been even if I've got software
that's trying to make sure that it is
and so really by being able to say hey
we're going to take these virtualized
topologies I'm going to be able to turn
them up really quickly which means we
can start a new one every time that we
that we want to we can manage their life
cycle so we can take them from you know
turn up a bunch of brand new devices
emulated devices and then kick them off
in hermetically with a sorry with a
hermetic set of inputs to be in a known
state that kind of gives us a way to be
able to test things differently to how
we would have done before we can start
think about well actually like we can
run all these this test Suite all this
set of cases against these emulated
topologies that gives us a way to know
that the tests are good and then we can
move on to the hardware isn't now that
we have to wait for the hardware or fix
these flakes to know that the thing
we're developing or the thing we're
regressing is is good
and the it opens up a huge new set of
new opportunities as well which is like
sets of things that are really difficult
for us to emulate uh to do in physical
um infrastructure so things like link
impairment
well kind of what do I do I kind of go
and bend the fiber a bit but I can't
really do that repeatably I can't really
do that in a way that that creates those
non-happy path scenarios so another
opportunity we're looking at and thing
that we wanted to solve in looking at
this this kind of infrastructure is can
we start to think about well if it's in
software can we have fault injection can
we have ways to be able to introduce new
impairments to the to the infrastructure
the let us validate things
so we've now kind of like developed some
tests that are giving us some some
confidence internally but you know for a
bunch of our Network deployments we also
have a company boundary in the way you
know we have a supplier and we meet with
the customer and a lot of the compliance
that we've had in terms of those
specifications is about is you know
humans interpreting text whether it's
rfcs or rfps you know how we read them
we have our own interpretation and at
the end of the day we will all seen
cases where you know we we've
interpreted things differently so the
infrastructure doesn't actually work how
we want the product it doesn't do what
we need if we move that into code look
at the way that we can say well here
we've got a something like an automated
test case that gives us a clear contract
but we also like that gives us some you
know some part of that problem but we
need to have some way common way that we
can actually run that you know I want to
be able to give something to a uh to A
supplier and say hey just run this thing
and it does turns up from your from
nothing to your product running in some
scenario I care about and that then has
a set of testing that runs against it
that when that passes that's compliant
I'm happy with it
so we need to be able to have that that
we really want to look at a way to have
that um packaging to reproduce scenarios
in a way that we can also introduce new
vendors we don't want to have to you
know re-specify this across different
vendors
and then once we kind of look at the
these sets of compliance and individual
products we want to also be able to look
at scale and you know if we want to go
go and have a production scale emulate
uh production scale lab infrastructure
it's going to cost the same as it cost
or somewhere similar to what it costs to
do in production and so you maybe have
some of these scaling environments but
not that many of them and when you build
them you build them and they've got a
fixed apology and so you have one
environment but now you've got the
problem of like well actually well
production doesn't really look like that
because it's in between these two states
of the old way we're doing things in the
new state of doing things so we want to
be able to actually flexibly produce
these topologies at some scale I want to
be able to do a what if about what
happens if I had the whole new design or
what happens if I'm in some hybrid and
this kind of the thinking about moving
to some more emulation and more use of
software in this area was to say well
can we go to production scale and Beyond
it and verify at that scale
so this is really the set of problems
and I'll hand over to Marcus who'll uh
explain what he did when I moaned as a
customer
so uh y'all did have a slight preview
earlier uh with the OTG side of things
but uh now we're going to actually talk
in a little bit more in depth on what
KNE is and uh why we uh came up with it
so you know all those things that Rob
really talked about is what started us
down this path of trying to answer a
question of
how do we provide a virtualized
environment that actually scales with
our needs and I think that's one of the
biggest pieces of why we ended up at a
place with kubernetes
and the ability to scale from a single
developer environment on a laptop all
the way up to a thousand plus node
worker pool you know holding thousands
of actual container nodes simulating you
know large-scale networking we really
appreciated the the k8s environment
around life cycle management and that is
one of the was one of our uh you know
big blockers when we first started doing
emulation platforms was we were
Reinventing life cycle management you
know uh you know the various vendors
would provide us with a VM but VMS are
are you know not a stable API every
kernel version every new compilation can
introduce new dependencies on the host
that you're actually about to try and
run that VM on and whereas kubernetes
contain trainers have mainly abstracted
a lot of those details away and so
that's uh you know where we ended up
with hey
let's let kubernetes do what it does
good which is life cycle management of
containers let's get the vendors to
partner with us on developing real
container based Network os's and then
we'll work on providing the actual uh
wire transport to move you know the L2
frames across a uh you know emulated
Network
so
you know
when talking about container container
first again when we look at VMS VMS are
very fat uh they they were their own OS
I mean they're the full stack of os
whereas containers you know there can be
very low consumption uh can strip off
most of the things that really aren't
core to the functionality that we were
really talking about because most of the
time when we're talking about what are
we testing about a network OS we're
really talking about the control
processes right we're talking about user
space processes nothing magic past that
there is a forwarding plane element but
that forwarding plane element isn't
really normally is implemented by the
vendors in their own user space
emulation as well they you know the
whole point is to not use the Linux
kernel you actually want to you know
emulate some form of an Asic
um
by using k8s we also you know have a
clear standardized API for how the
vendors package that up we say hey we're
going to provide you with this set of
emulated interfaces when you boot you
map those those internal uh provided
Linux interfaces to your respective
Hardware represented interfaces
um we have an obviously standard image
format and we have a standard lifecycle
management system uh one of the other
big pluses in the ks world is the
operator uh pattern and so we've
actually worked with the vendors not
only to give us the images but almost
all of them have actually completed uh
implementing their own operators so you
even get the vendor ownership when using
KNE of not only do I not have to worry
about how to bring up the uh container
but the vendor actually owns that and
maintains how they bring up their
containers
um the last little point is well we do
also still support VMS because there are
certain os's which are not uh container
friendly we still have a mode for that
it's not generally the one we we go with
but obviously you know in the network
operations world we know uh we are stuck
with things for sometimes longer than
we'd like
um you know
all right we definitely when looking at
k8s it was leverage everything we can
and so when it came to well how are we
going to do these Network wires how are
we going to do the L2 connectivity
between the containers uh well we stole
what we could and we had found a really
good partner uh with uh Network op and
um who built meshnet which is originally
was a vxlan ve based L2 cni plug-in and
we worked with them to modify it
slightly so that worked with us in knee
and so
basically we can fire up a base just kns
cluster deploy the mesh net cni uh
deploy a load balancer onto it and then
we can just take the vendor container
operators deploy those and then we can
start firing up uh any topologies we're
looking for using just crds
fundamental concept
within akne topology
unfortunately we did pick some bad
naming in places because you'll see the
word nodes and when we we talk about
candy node we really refer to the
network node you're actually emulating
not the worker node that the k8s is
actually going to drive you know run the
process from
but basically we have nodes and links
and services and the node as we
described can be any vendor container
and the links are simply describing the
L2 connection that we're going to
deliver between the two two nodes and
services are simply going to be your
load balance service is exported through
to k8s from the nodes for providing all
the base level SSH gnmi greeby type
services that we support
mm-hmm
so where do you start
so unfortunately uh uh all of the
vendors have not open sourced all of
their uh container images yet so it is
on the the the person to acquire your
network images uh most of the vendors
and pretty much all the big vendors
support uh containerized version of an
OS so you can work with them to get
those once you have them you define your
node in a simple uh topology protocol
buffer and the services and links and
basically there's a knee command to both
create a cluster if you want to run a
local cluster as well as a k uh the
candy create which we'll just talk to an
existing kubernetes cluster
so what does that look like
um we try to keep it simple we just have
a simple protocol buffer that allows you
to specify what type of os you're
looking for what kind of node and uh
basically a config Element Section that
just says what container path are you
looking for and then we also allow you
mounting configs so that the devices can
actually boot with a boot config and
then at that point
um
you can now specify the interfaces which
are going to be these are going to be
the interfaces used by your link to
describe how how you want to do your
mapping so the interface section here in
this case we have a Cisco xrd node and
we are simply saying hey your eth1
that's going to be referenced inside the
container as a gigabit Ethernet 0 0 and
you can this allows actually you to link
your like say you have a actual
operational config that actually has
specific devices named uh you can use
this to help you map those so that you
can actually kind of keep a
um you know maybe a production like
config uh and and you could still use
that same config interface naming uh in
your emulation
um Services uh they're just defined
basically this is just giving you a
mapping to allow you to say if you want
to SSH to your device or you want to
connect to a open config gnmi service
um we have a you know kind of an
internal to external mapping this lets
you also normalize uh some vendors run
specific services on internally
different ports so we again this kind of
lets you have a consistent presentation
uh when you're coming out of the cluster
to say hey all of my devices my gmmi is
going to be in this case 50 000 uh 50
051.
links
[Music]
Rob and his pictures
um so links uh we go with uh just a
simple
um setup of saying hey give me my easies
and those are basically going to build
uh once once the crd gets populated
meshnet will go to work and actually lay
out your Vees between all of those
worker containers and we actually did
just actually landed a change to where
uh National originally used vxlan vxlan
has a couple of issues around mtus and
things like that so we actually replace
that with actually a grpc wire transport
so this allows us to basically send any
MTU between nodes and so we can support
you know whatever
um whatever whatever Trend you know
whatever frame size needs to be there
um also some inner working with like
Isis uh since the Linux kernel itself
sometimes will uh eat those eat pdus
that match specific Max by going to grpc
wire and pulling the Linux bridge out of
that mix lets us send uh sends those
frames without any issues
uh here's a simple simple topology
um basically this is a three node
topology with lags between the devices
and so we just want to show you roughly
uh you know this is what we would
consider a pretty small topologies like
actually this is one of our simplest
topologies we use during our testing of
knee to make sure we didn't break
anything
um this shows you the node uh the the
node interface and then the interface is
connected to it uh through its interface
names through the uh mesh net links and
then to the remote side uh we have like
a simple visualization that basically
will produce these pick topologies based
on the provided uh Proto
so whenever I mention the vendors these
are all the vendors that are currently
supported within the ecosystem uh Aristo
Juniper Cisco Nokia and keysight uh you
know have all given us you know major
props around
um
you know working with us not only to to
give us the container images but also to
provide operators
um you know keysight especially you know
if you saw the presentation earlier uh
big contributor on being able for us to
actually have a full production
um platform for traffic generation and
uh
protocols
uh additionally
you can actually start any container you
want if you specify just a what we call
a host node you can start up any Linux
container that you may have so this also
lets you take it not only to just like
kind of a functional test but you could
actually have a full integration test
here as well because you could bring up
any of your own service controllers in
this environment and that would talk uh
consistently across everything
okay so that's Kenny in a nutshell I'll
talk a little bit now about what we're
actually using uh Kenny for and so this
is coming back to some of the the use
cases I was discussing at the start
what we'd like to be able to do is
programmatically repeatedly validate
Network deployments and of course when
you think about that statement you think
about muskrat right which is an under
um of course you don't what you have you
do is you come up with a terrible
acronym and then you figure out oh it
sounds like an animal and so then you've
got you've got your logo canned so
that's that's what we did
um too much confusion of lots of muscles
pictures around the office so on that
throws the open network device automated
test Runner and API I told you it was a
terrible background
um and essentially what we this is in
the wider ecosystem we've been working
on is a way to be able to have a test
framework that is very user-friendly
promo I'm a network person wanting to do
some Network testing and abstracts a lot
of the details away from you so how what
what the framework breaks down into is
we have a test that's Express are
expressed in code
um this is the part of the kind of
consistent contract that we're trying to
provide
um we write them in go and the network
teams that want to write tests own this
this test case what the test case looks
like is it's calling a bunch of
undoubted apis and those apis expose
some of the sort of fundamental parts of
the topology of the topology that you
might need to do details about the test
bed you know I'm dealing with an
abstract device tell me what this port
name is because I actually need to know
it at this point in time or push some
configuration read Telemetry from the
device do some operation like upgrade
the OS or prod a demon that's running on
the on the device and then the traffic
generation so your test case looks like
essentially a relatively
um opinionated set of apis that give you
a clear sort of readable test case uh to
be able to express your your test in on
that herself then takes those sets of
capabilities expresses them through a
binding into the actual infrastructure
in the lab so that's the you know the
physical or the virtual resources that
the tests run on so The Binding layer
here is something that we'd specifically
introduce thinking about well okay we
might want to do this in not only in our
own environment not only in other
people's physical environments but also
in Virtual environments where we want to
abstract some of the differences between
the you know the fact that that there
might need to be a reservation system
and a physical topology that says well
can I get hold of this device versus in
k e well you've probably got your own
thing so the answer is yes you can have
your own device so the the overall
breakdown here is a a set of
infrastructure that gives us a way to be
able to express these test cases that
takes into account that we've got this
emulated uh and physical infrastructure
to be able to accelerate that
development
and what that breaks down into is that
something that we're building is what
we're calling as functional or
Standalone testing essentially we're
trying to build a set of tests that give
us a way to work with simple topologies
whether they're one device or you know
small number of devices to be able to
validate the functionalities of the
device you can really think about this
like well I've got this black box sort
of function that came in that was the
network device and I want to think about
how do I unit test it and how do I then
start to integration test it so that as
we move forward we can think about the
changes in that infrastructure running
through a CI CD pipeline in the same way
it would have would if it's code but
give us some way to when a test fails we
don't have to say well okay this this
complex topology failed let's go debug
it it's like as simple as well this unit
test will so of course all the other
things fail so let's start there and on
that gives us the way to be able to
express these things and after the the
infrastructure the provides away the we
interface with the different parts of
the the the the system that are going to
deal with the test so for example if I
run through a kind of basic test case
the test case will come up that before
the user gets any of their code run on
data goes makes a reservation call gets
whatever the underlying system is as
part of that reservation call one of the
things we do is reset the configuration
of the device to some known config
config based config that you can start
with and then on that allows you to step
through the test case
abstracting from you what the device
under test is and the automated test
equipment like traffic generator that
would sit alongside it that help you do
some black box validation of those
devices so this is something that we've
been using KNE for helping our
development of and and on that draw is
the way that we realize it
did not expect there all to be a white
slide there
um
so how does k e help us in this
um it gives us a way as I kind of said
that we want to be able to you know
start out with I've got this new feature
that I want to run on the network device
I'm going to start out with well I spin
it up on my laptop
I have candy running I have xcc or
another traffic generator I have my
device into test container and I can
iterate I can experiment I didn't use
anyone else's resources to do this
um and we we can then take those those
changes as we commit them put them into
open source repository we're building
this test like around open config and
you kind of think about the the way that
we get some of the other abstraction of
the devices through those the the
standard data models and grpc services
we've been working with to make this
these test cases portable across
different implementations so now we
we're integrating these test cases into
open config but now you can just run
this like you would run any CI CD
testing so you say well I could launch
it with a GitHub action startup a VM in
gcp or in wherever you would like it to
be spin up
um KNE on that and then create the same
topology and have this as a repeatable
process that runs
so we're going to do a demo
unfortunately Greg who is our the tech
lead for for and outro wasn't able to be
here so we're going to run through the
video of the demo and then we'll come
back and have some some closing thoughts
so I'm hoping this is just going to play
okay
any guidance on how to get it the video
to play I assumed it would just auto
play
okay
audio
foreign
before we set up knee itself we first
need to install four of its appliances
I'll start by verifying that I am go
installed
I need Go version at least 1.18 here I
have 1.19 which will work fine
next I'll check that I have Docker
installed
walk around hello world and I do indeed
have Docker installed correctly
third I'll install Cube
Cube Kettle is a command line tool for
interacting with kubernetes
download it
and install it
done
and fourth I'll install kind kind is a
tool for running local kubernetes
clusters in Docker containers
I'll install kind version 0.14
now I have the dependencies of candy
installed and I'm going to install k e
itself
I'm going to clone the knee GitHub
project
I'm going to CD into
the knee CLI directory
I'm going to build the knee CLI that's
the only part of knee we're going to
need to build here is the CLI tool
that has been built and now I'll verify
that knee has been installed and set up
correctly
now we will create a network topology
with KNE
the network topology we are going to
create in this demo is available as an
example topology in the knee GitHub
project under the name two node ixia
CEOs
it contains two nodes
the first node is named OTG
OTG stands for open traffic generator
open traffic generator is a new API for
generating test traffic developed by the
makers of ixia
so this is our node for generating
traffic
the second node is the Arista node
it's our device under test
here it is specified to be an arrested
device
that is running CEOs
it is bootstrapped with a fairly minimal
config
referenced by this file
that configures its interfaces
and ensures gnmi is set up
finally the topology creates two links
between interfaces on the OTG and Arista
nodes
before we created topology we must first
deploy a kubernetes cluster that is done
with the knee deploy command
Caney comes bundled with an example
deployment definition kindbridge.yaml
that uses kind to create the cluster on
your local machine
for me
with the cluster deployed we can now use
the knee create command
to create our topology
here we pass the do note ixia CEOs
topology that we referenced before
we can use Cube Kettle to see the pods
that are running in the topology
foreign
here you can see a pod for the
Arista Duty one for the Ott controller
one for each of the o2g interfaces and
so on
you can also take a look at the running
services in our topology with Cube
Kettle get services
now we will look at some ways you can
manually interact with a running
topology
you can push config to a device with the
KNE topology push command
for our demo purposes it will push the
same config that has already
bootstrapped to the device so it will
just be a no-op
done
you can also SSH to a node with the Kube
Kettle exec command
we have now logged in
we can run an arbitrary command like
show version
we can also verify gnmi is available in
working on the device
first we'll install gmmi CLI
from the open config project
there it's installed
if we looked at the config on the device
we would see that the username and
password
set up for the gnmi server is just admin
admin
so let me set those here before I run my
gnmi CLI command
genome icli is also going to expect an
IP address and port
for the gnmi and point
we can look that up with Cube kettle get
services
we see the Arista node has an external
IP
of 192.168 1854
and
it is running GMI is running on Port
6030 which we could also look at we
could also see that from the config
so with that information
now let's send a query
to gnmi COI to that IP import
and we're just going to query this state
of the interface named ethernet one
and there we can see the gnmi
notification for the state of that
interface
the final piece of this demo will
involve running an undocher test on our
knee topology
we start by cloning on datra from the
GitHub repo
now that it has been cloned we will
build on datra the indatra readme says
first to run go generate which Auto
generates some of undoches apis
now we run go build
it is built successfully
to run an undocher test on KNE we first
have to configure the k e binding
on Dodger tests can run in many
different test environments KNE being
just one
each one of these environments needs a
binding that lets on Doctrine know what
the available devices are and how to
access them
or a configuration for the k e binding
in this example
is a simple three-line yaml file
it specifies the username and password
used by the device which here is just
admin admin
and the knee topology on which the test
will run
that's all we need to configure the k e
binding
now let's look at the test we will be
running
every undoctor test needs a test bed
which specifies the physical resources
it will need to run
the resources are specified as abstract
constraints not specific physical
devices
The Binding then resolves those
constraints to specific devices at
runtime
here is the test bed
this is a simple test bed that requires
one device under test or dut
Y and one piece of automated test
equipment or ate
an ate is a device that generates our
test traffic
and it constrains the dot in the ate
to be linked on two ports
finally let's look at the logic of the
inductor test itself
test main is the entry point for
undocker test execution
every undoctor test begins within a test
Main
that calls and daughter run tests
this test has three test cases test
config which tests our ability to push
vendor config to the device
test gnmi which tests our ability to
query the Dutch gnmi service
and test OTG
which tests our ability to configure the
open traffic generator node and query
information about it via Gene MI
here is the test command we will execute
when we run any on Dodger test
we pass a flag that specifies the test
bed we want the test to use
and because we're running on KNE we also
specify a flag
for the k e config which I showed
earlier which here lists the username
password and k e topology
we now run the test
here we see the devices from the KNE
topology reserved by the test for the
Texas execution
in the test passed that concludes our
demo
cool so hopefully that shows the the set
of tools kind of working together you
know going from we'll we'll admit that
we cut out a little bit of time waiting
for things to build because it seemed
like sitting here watching actually
build was a bit too much but it's a it's
close enough to real time that you can
kind of go from nothing to a deployed
set of infrastructure on your on your on
your machine and run and write you can
store some very simple test cases but
these this set of apis are extended to
cover much more and approach calls into
other interfacing with the device other
Telemetry retrieval type type tasks
so that that sort of lays the foundation
for this this wider concept that we've
been aiming for for some time which is
the this kind of idea of a test driven
design
um driven development for network
devices so essentially we want to be
able to style with okay we want to do
something new with the device we want to
be able to go and then design the API
whether that's a new open config model
because it's a configuration service or
it needs some new Telemetry whether it's
a new grpc service like gnoi or a new
even kind of routing protocol like
gribby go and design the API look at the
way that we develop tests using on data
so EXT using the either the inbuilt
helpers the inductor has or inductor
gives you a way to be able to access
things like raw grpc connections to
devices such you can iterate on on new
things and ideally test that against a
reference implementation so we don't
want to have to wait for there to be a
commercial available or a production
quality implementation before we start
looking at how this thing should work we
want to get those learnings of writing
code earlier and writing the
implementation earlier on so we have a
couple of reference implementations that
are open source there's a there's
lemming which is a reference
implementation of a network device that
has a gnmi server a grebe server it's
got support for bgp right now
um it's being it's got an emulated data
plane that can actually pass traffic and
so this gives us a way to be able to
quickly start to look at like okay we
want to be able to play with this
feature this this thing we're thinking
about let's go prototype it let's figure
out what it looks like let's look at
what the API should do let's write the
test that gives us the compliance
contract gives us a way that we don't
have to go and write an RFC to go and
describe everything does and actually
much more coherently describes what
should happen and more completely
describes what should happen in that we
also have a implementation of a
reference traffic generator that I think
was mentioned earlier that essentially
it's not meant to be a production
quality thing but if you're looking at a
new way that your new protocol or a new
um packet format that you may want to
play with gives you a way to be able to
add injection of that without
necessarily having to wait on other
requirements and then that gives you the
compliance contract to go and work on
the production implementation you say
okay I understand what it should look
like I understand how to spec it I can
explain to somebody else I've worked out
the nuances of it and now we can go and
look and implement this on a production
device
and reuse the things that we've
discussed on data for the test case k e
for the way that you play you use the
actual commercial implementation that
you you could take and and deploy that
into production based on that that this
pipeline which we think gives you a much
quicker way and a much more coherent way
to do feature development on network
devices and builds on this kind of the
overall concept of moving to
programmatic interaction with devices
which the open config project has been
working for the last uh seven or eight
years on
so thank you very much uh this is Marcus
and my email address
um everything that we mentioned is
somewhere in the the open config GitHub
uh there's probably some description of
it on openconfig.net as well thank you
very much indeed
[Applause]
yes
well thank you very much Marcus Rob that
was a great presentation thank you
oh we have a question we do have a
question okay
a little slow
I'd like to ask um so if you have a new
vendor who wants to become supported
from the key any perspective uh what
steps should they do to to get that
support edit
it's okay
um
okay
um I'll take it
um so in general
um the the barrier to entry is uh if you
can produce a container
um that's step one uh once you have a a
standard container at that point uh in k
e there is a node specification and a
node interface and uh the really
lightest way and and the way you should
probably bootstrap in is to say fulfill
that interface so you literally just
write a go module which fulfills six or
seven methods of basically you need to
create a couple kubernetes objects and
basically your service and your node
definition and we actually do provide a
default implementation uh but most
people do need to tweak that just a bit
and at that point uh you need to tweak
the topology Proto to add your new
vendor type in and at that point that's
pretty much it now uh again as you go
forward if you want to productionalize
that then learning a kubernetes operator
and then having a full kubernetes
operator deployment is obviously a a
better long term but yeah all you need
is that
any online questions Michael yeah we
have two well it's actually one from
Matt peacock
does o n d a t r a allow you to specify
link Management in your topology or even
link always perfect I.E can you add lose
latency to links
that so that's one of the reasons that
we went and implemented the grpc wire
essentially it would be we're kind of a
bit constrained as to what we can do but
it's an extension that now we've we've
landed the the grpc wire implementation
we're starting to think about well they
should be disinjected latency there
should be this injected impairment and
we've even started to think about well
should there be ways to be able to have
like lower layer errors injected so can
I start to have like bit error rate from
a what would be a transport system or
something that the optic might see so we
can start to test those paths but it
doesn't today but it's it's on the plan
okay
clear
okay thank you again guys thank you very
much
[Applause]
[Music]