[Music]
foreign
Levy is a lead engineer at at T an
active Community member Nimrod has
communicated coordinated connectivity
for nanog conferences in the past and he
spoke first spoke at the nadog stage in
2017. we're happy to welcome him back to
the stage for the third time today
presenting increasing IPv6 utilization
in consumer networks welcome
thank you
hi thanks for having me here
um so yeah we're gonna talk about
everybody's absolute favorite topic ever
IPv6
um because nobody's presented about that
today maybe
um
so I'm not really going to spend a lot
of time on you know what it is how it
works or whatever but we're going to
talk a little bit about why we really
really like for real this time need to
move to IPv6 because really
um yeah particularly looking at consumer
networks so you know I work at ATT so we
have a lot of Wireline customers a lot
of Wireless customers
um eventually we're gonna have to build
out uh some sort of cgn whether that's
you know Nat 444 or map t or whatever
really uh technology gets settled on
um there's going to have to be
someday somewhere we're going to do it
and the way the traffic currently sits
and we'll see some some charts on on
some of the breakdowns
uh it's the the scale of that cgn is
going to be immense uh there are going
to be other networks that that are going
to face those same kinds of problems
um so it's just there's so much V4 out
there that we're going to have to deal
with we really need to be shifting that
needle more than than what's been so far
um
so uh yes uh so the cgn so we a lot of
networks already support IPv6
um we have some
um at T you know Comcast lots of lots of
Provider service providers already
support V6 all the way down to the CPE
uh so the the networks are there a lot
of content providers already support V6
a lot of content is available over V6
so we support all the networks I think
not all the networks but a lot of the
networks are very much ready so how much
traffic are we really seeing in V6
um I kind of broke some some charts down
in uh looking at different kinds of uh
networks that connect to at t uh the
darker green shows the total traffic and
the lighter green overlaid is the amount
of V6 traffic that a DNT is receiving
from various kinds of networks so these
providers some of them look better than
others in terms of how much V6
um we we see from from particular
networks
um all the way up to over 80 percent
um some you know 60 percent
um you know this is a different provider
that does mostly streaming video
um they have a you know just lower
percentage but you know not bad
um
things get a little bit dicey this this
particular provider has uh you know
think VMS that uh that get spun up to
support different Cloud applications
um so they're you know much less
percentage
um and then these are CDN providers that
uh that don't host their own content but
you know distribute
um other
um other folks content and so they and
they all of these networks like you say
you can see here they have some V6 so
they all support V6
um but really why we're not just we're
not seeing very much this migration has
been
a long time coming and um we expect it's
going to have this very very long tail
uh moving forward from V6
so again I we started looking at it why
why don't we have more V6
um
this this number I'm not sure I really
like this number very much um mostly
because I don't know
exactly how they arrived at it this says
that you know the top thousand websites
uh globally only 28 of them have V6
I'm not sure how that how this number
maybe somebody can clarify that because
I didn't see it on uh on that website on
the this is from uh the internet Society
for example at T if you look up att.com
there's no Claude a record for it
um but if you open your web browser and
type att.com you're going to get a
redirect that goes to
www.att.com which is hosted by one of
those cdns that does in fact support
IPv6
so we know we have a lot of content
that's out there that supports V6 the
network support V6
maybe there's another reason that
there's not quite so much V6 traffic and
so I think that this might be part of it
this is a listing of a of an actual home
network the the green
on the left side is the list of devices
that uh that are connected to the
network and uh and on the the right
column
um the the green indicates where it has
a V6 address
um there are a few devices that might
not be connected at the time that that I
think could support V6 that aren't but
ultimately we've got 10 maybe 15 devices
out of 28
that are doing V6 that's not a great
number
so that kind of leads us to uh where
we're heading with this is
there's a lot I think that there's a lot
of content out there that supports V6
but is really being accessed to only on
V4
um because of these end devices
so how do we get these end devices
upgraded normally we need you know
vendors to push out software updates
we need consumers to buy you know
additional uh by new devices nobody
likes buying new stuff that basically
works
so
really how do we do this
can we get you know can we incentivize
the vendors to to support you know older
Hardware can we get them to push stuff
out
can we get you know uh customers to buy
new things how do we do this do we just
wait for stuff to age out
um
you know I don't know about you guys I
hate waiting
um
so
we got to looking at this and thinking
about the the problem a little bit more
and it occurs to me that we have
standards for Nat six dns-64 and that
six four so this is a standard where you
can have
islands of V6 only devices that can
communicate with V4 only services
the way this works is the uh roughly the
the client does a DNS request
um you have a modified DNS server that
that substitutes its own answer uh for
for the real answer and uh and you
forward that traffic to a translator the
net six the NAT portion of the net six
four
and you repackage this V6 packet into a
V4 packet send it on its way so you have
this uh this end-to-end communication
that uh between devices and devices that
speak different protocols
so why not turn it around
um let's do Nat four six and dns46 it
turns out to be a little bit more
complicated because in the dns-64
scenario you're able to take that ipv4
address of the the real server and embed
it into a V6 address and so you you get
to save that state in the address itself
clearly you can't do that in the other
direction if we could fit a V6 address
into a V4 address we probably wouldn't
have this problem
um so
but I still think that there's some some
possibilities here all right so the flow
kind of looks like this very similar to
what happens in the dns-64 flow
um you know you have an ipv4 only device
makes a DNS request it hits the CPE
which is the DNS server anyway
and so instead of forwarding that that a
request out to the DNS resolver it makes
a quad a request if it gets that quad a
request back or answer back then it'll
it can associate that with a local only
ipv4 address we can probably use you
know 100.64 for that and route that
internally
um so you build that Association you
have to save that in a state table
um on the CPE the CPE then replies back
to the endpoint
um with a uh with the a with a response
to that a request
um so that's that's kind of the DNS
portion of it
um then you have the NAT portion of that
so the host sends a uh sends that packet
out to the Gateway it's a CPE
um routes it to you know the translation
layer because we're already translating
on that CB anyway
and uh and so it looks up in the state
table what what V6 address goes along
with this V4 destination repackages the
packet sends it on its way and then
everything in reverse on the way back
um in theory this should work pretty
well um I've had some initial
conversations with uh with folks who
work on CPE and um they they think that
this is pretty possible I mean they like
I said the CP is already doing
translations anyway so this shouldn't be
significantly different from the
translations that it's already capable
of doing
um clearly we can break things
um we're modifying packets in Flight
um things things are going to break
um one of the big ones that we can call
out immediately is dnsic if you've got a
client that's doing DNS SEC validation
um you know we've modified that DNS
request so or the DNS response so this
is going to fail but
realistically
um you know these are clients that
aren't supporting V6 I'm pretty sure the
likelihood that they're going to be
doing DNS SEC validation is slim to none
um another possibility is we could have
some applications that might be
embedding literal IB addresses in in
their um in their responses
um you know some kind of custom
applications so maybe the client makes a
request out
um and then somewhere in uh in there
it's uh it can see that
um that it's a v V4 or V6 address and
it's going to say you know go make your
response to this other destination
um
and so if if the server sees that that's
coming from V6 then it might embed a V6
address somewhere in there
and uh the client obviously you know
because we're having this conversation
doesn't speak V6 at all
um so that's going to fail it's bad
practice to be embedding those uh those
raw IPS in uh in there anyway you should
probably be following DNS so hopefully
we won't have too many of those kinds of
things
um but you know ultimately
we're uh at the end of the day if we can
we can get some of these things
implemented then we need less cgn
capacity
so the uh you know so that that means
that the uh that the isps don't have to
have as much as much built out there we
can start shuffling things over and the
other nice really nice thing about this
is that it works um it kind of it fails
back to V4 right so if if that initial
DNS request never gets a quad a response
if it only if only an a record exists
then you do your regular ipv4 routing
your regular whatever Nat translation
um and then if that's being if that's
just a Nat four four on the CPE then
that takes place there and that works
fine
uh and if that happens to be you know
cgn you know not 444 in the uh in in the
provider Network or map t or whatever
then that also works it just it kind of
fails back to that uh that ipv4 path
um
it should operate very transparently
um to all of the customers you know
where there's some caveats in there that
uh that we talked about that you know
there could be some others but um but
generally speaking
um this should work you know really
transparently to the customer uh I would
expect the cost of of doing this over
time should be
um should be much less than operating a
much larger scaled cgn the other nice
thing that we can do with this is that
it's not dependent on the provider
Network
um so in in my network you know in att's
network we control all the CPS we
certify the software it's rcpe and we
push out all the firmware updates
obviously not not every provider Network
operates like that but this still works
independent of the the provider Network
so I would Envision a scenario where you
get your you know whatever router you
have you plug it into your isp's
connection and it detects
hey you have a V6 address available
would you like me to set this up to push
more of your traffic over to V6 uh could
be a very simple solution for
a um for a customer for an end user to
do they don't have to be you know one of
us that knows how bgp works and how all
of these things operate
um so you know what's uh what do we do
next
um
I think the next move here is uh is to
work with our CBE vendors
um and our partners over at different
um uh different manufacturers to to get
this functional
um see if it actually we can make this
work and uh
move forward from there
um see from the clock I actually ran
through these slides a lot faster than I
intended to
so we have plenty of time for questions
but I wanted to call out some folks that
that helped me a lot with uh with
refining some of these thoughts and
ideas
um and uh
that's uh
that's kind of the end of my idea here
um any questions conversation anything
from
anybody
Lee Howard from ipv4. Global by cocoa
stream Bank
um I can't resist talking about IPv6 at
any opportunity uh I think what you've
described is uh fairly similar to the
silat function in 464x lab right there's
it because you're translating from four
to six whether or not you're translating
from six to four later which is great
what I'm hearing from uh from isps
around the world
generally smaller companies is that they
can't deploy IPv6 or they can't save um
on on ipv4 addresses because they can't
get vendor support in the CPE whether
it's V6 support or 464 excellent support
or map T support whatever whatever
transition mechanism they're looking for
um and I've been trying to find a way to
to get to more of those vendors because
of course a lot of the CPE vendors are
repackaging open wrt or an equivalent
and the packages exist you just have to
you know install the package and turn on
the button but if you don't control the
CPE then you can't even get that done so
I I'm still you know you're right you're
absolutely right the next step to do
that would be to talk to the CPE vendors
and I've been having a really hard time
getting in front of CBE vendors
yeah I um thanks for the the comment
that's uh I think that's great I if we
can if some of the some of us as
providers that that do control the CPE
if we can start pushing some of these
things in as as standard functions then
uh then then I would hope that they
would become more available
um you know generally in in other
networks that um that that maybe aren't
at T
uh thanks uh Thomas tricks cloudflare uh
thanks for that talk that's really
interesting couple of ideas
um how do you see this interacting with
quite a few vendors
primarily building new features on top
of ipv4 and then doing IPv6 a year or
two years or never later when it comes
to proper carrier stuff because at that
point you're going to do V4 on V6 on V4
potentially on mpls
right so
um
the way the way I kind of see this
working it's really sort of independent
of what's going on out in the carrier
Network so whether you're doing a cgn or
a map t or whatever you're doing you
know you're kind of Distributing this uh
this translation layer down to the CPE
so it can operate you know completely
independently on at that level pushing
the traffic to to V6 you provided the
applications are properly you know
performing DNS lookups and and and using
you know the DNS to distribute the the
host names but
um then if there's still things that
that really really are only on V4 and
don't have the quad a records then it
just follows the regular V4 patterns so
I don't really see any conflict there as
far as I can tell but you know hoping uh
I I could be wrong maybe yeah
an additional question then how do you
see that interact with happy hour goals
um
so the the target for this uh this
transition mechanism is really for um
devices that don't support V6 at all
right so there's no happy eyeballs in
that uh equation I think
Lee Howard again I um since there's
nobody else at the mic I thought I'd
also asked you um one of your uh points
that was the that uh cgn May uh there
may be a performance difference
introduced by cgn if you're doing a net4
cgn but you're doing V6 natively and
that will be an incentive for other
folks to deploy V6 which which would be
great
my testing which is a few years old now
didn't hasn't seen any any measurable
latency through CG it was it was sub
millisecond so we can't count it okay um
have you done have you seen it no I I
don't have uh any any hard numbers on
that but you know we would hope that
that that would help you know just even
the idea of that right right that you
don't want your traffic to be going
through the cgn so you know let's uh
let's let's do it the other way there's
lots of other reasons to not like cgn
like if you want to do rbls or you want
to do geolocation or you need to do some
kind of reputation or other information
based on IP address and gee suddenly
you've got shared fate that's there's
reasons to not like that but um yeah
that particular one oh geez maybe you've
got data point yep absolutely
Philip Simon's Network to code
um I I've worked with quite a bit of
Enterprise environments
and in the Enterprise there's not a ton
of
um
like pressure business use case to
deploy both Stacks because then you have
to manage a second stack
um and there are security implications
to not wrestling with it but most
Enterprises just don't wrestle with it I
like the idea of putting back pressure
onto the client side to say hey use IPv6
because otherwise your connections are
going to degrade when you're going
through cgn instead of just going
directly to whatever your server is do
you have any other ideas at putting some
gentle back pressure to kind of like
force Enterprises to think about and
reconcile that and make it a valid
business use case where they they have
IPv6 yeah I mean Enterprise is uh as you
point out a very very different Beast
um you know they they can run their own
little Walled Garden whatever they want
inside
um and and then a lot of Enterprises you
know will carefully control what goes in
and out so
um you know it's a lot simpler I think
for an Enterprise to just you know slap
a proxy that is V6 enabled or you know
whatever their application education
might be on their border and they can
I'm happy to let them do whatever they
want internally but clearly at some
point they're going to be
um they they there's going to be a need
for them to talk V6 externally
um which is you know kind of a different
problem but I I don't I'm not sure I
really have any any other uh ideas at
the moment for uh for pushing
Enterprises in that direction so it's a
tough nut to crack
thank you thanks
any anything else for anybody else on
the web anybody
great thank you very much for your time
[Music]