[Music]
foreign
he will be presenting internet impacts
due to the war in Ukraine
Doug is director of Internet analysis
for chemtech where he works on internet
infrastructure analysis
prior to Kentuck he was lead analyst for
oracles
internet intelligence team which was
formerly dine research and Renaissance
this is Doug's seventh time presenting
here at nanog Doug first spoke at nanog
in 2010 during a lightning talk session
about accidentally importing censorship
uh thank you welcome Doug
[Applause]
the largest war in Europe since World
War II is currently taking place in the
Ukraine a country with a robust internet
infrastructure that's been taking a
beating over the last eight months in
this talk I'd like to share some
observations from the internet
measurement perspective from folks uh
like myself internet Watchers
and um
this conflict is taking place in the age
of the internet and there are a lot of
unprecedented developments that have
taken place uh in this this year we're
going to talk about those starting
uh with what's your place has taken
place in Ukraine
so this
this story for me started two nanogs ago
when we were all in Austin when I
started we were winding down in analog
84 I started getting increased from the
media to confirm DDOS attacks against
prominent websites in Ukraine
so it started with the Ukrainian Army
website some banks were hit these were
Graphics I was putting out based on uh
kentic's aggregate netflow seeing these
DDOS attacks they're confirming them
over the course of a week the uh attacks
migrated to government and um uh cites
the parliament foreign Ministry
executive cabinet were hit with DDOS
attacks you know none of these attacks
were novel there's no novel technology
or record-breaking in size but they were
effective at disrupting access
especially for sites with limited DDOS
mitigation in place
but at this time the Russian army had
amassed on the Ukrainian border and it
was a lot of debate what was going to
happen uh the skepticism whether they
were actually going to invade we found
out the following day on the 24th of
February when Russian soldiers started
pouring over the border and attacking
Ukraine
one of the first impacts that we saw was
this uh an outage in the European
satellite operator via sat
this is a screenshot from Iota which is
an internet outage the dashboard put out
by Georgia Tech that is a public tool
with internet connectivity stats the
line along the top in green has bgb
routes those didn't have an effect to
put the didn't suffer any outages but
the blue line is is active measurement
so pings of things in this as dropped
dramatically within a couple days it was
confirmed that there was a destructive
malware that had been uh deployed into
this network causing ground terminals to
essentially self-destruct
and and later it was connected that this
was part of a Russian cyber op to go
hand in hand with the invasion uh
knowing that a lot of the Ukrainian
government was relying on this service
once the fighting started we saw a lot
of outages of just uh the major major
telecoms of the country so trioline is a
national Broadband provider this also
expect these guys experienced a an
outage probably the biggest one in the
initial days due to a separate fiber cup
they also uh experienced an outage uh
within a couple weeks of a Cyber attack
we didn't get a lot of elaboration on
that but it was something that we could
confirm in data so in this in the
graphics on the bottom the one from Iota
uh showing the March 9th Cyber attack uh
the Blue Line like the Via sat uh you
know the responding hosts drop uh down
uh significantly and then this is a
graphic from cloudflare who has their
public tool a radar
um that you can look up uh traffic for
any as or country
so Euchre Telecom or Ukraine Telecom is
the incumbent of of Ukraine and by our
stats kentic stats so this is the
seventh most popular destination for the
country so this is for traffic so it's
not the biggest Telecom but it's
important uh as
an incumbent it provides service to a
lot of government uh functionality as
well as it's the provider of Last Resort
for rural areas where it's not
profitable to have other other options
so it's a it's an important Network it
too is suffered a number of outages in
those opening weeks lasting typically
for a few hours and as we'll as we came
to learn was getting restored Often by
technicians going out to the recently
damaged
uh of damaged area due to bombing
UK Telecom also suffered a Cyber attack
we don't know all the details here but
we do know this was facilitated by Uh
Russian forces taking over a yucatalicom
facility and using the credentials of
captured technicians from ecru Telecom
to get inside the network and bring it
down uh this network was then uh this
outage only lasted a few hours but that
was uh the the cause of that
so those are all outages on the extreme
uh on the extremities of the internet in
Ukraine but um there were also how the
country connects to the global internet
was affected as well and this is an
example of one of those changes so we
have a product kentic Market
intelligence that tracks uh that
classifies all the as relationships
within the country and then scores them
based on address space going across the
edge and then this enabled us to do some
kind of longitudinal analysis to look at
how is Transit changing through time and
so this is an example where we saw
Vodafone Ukraine lose Transit from MTS
as a Russian mobile provider and around
the same time that their parent company
Vodafone out of the UK suspended its
partnership with MTS out of Russia Over
The Invasion so the real world events
have effects on Transit as well
uh going through the country uh all the
transit effects of this year they
typically fall into two buckets one the
one on the left for example data group
losing uh Transit from Ross roscom
another Russian provider this one I
don't know the background if this was
due to a infrastructure
failure or a conscious decision to not
use Russian Transit on the part of this
this company or the other if they didn't
lose Russian Transit then you saw stuff
like this that we saw from bullia which
is a mobile operator for the country
where there's a lot of instability uh as
different Transit providers are are
getting knocked out and traffic's
shifting to from one to another they
stay online but uh it's a
uh it was had it was an unstable period
there
so shifting over from uh Ukraine over to
Russia there was a lot of impact on uh
the invading country as well
so two days after the invasion uh
Ukraine's minister of digital
transformation put out a call to the
world for a volunteer I.T Army of
hackers to attack these 31 prominent
websites
this is a first that I think many of us
have ever seen if you wanted to
participate in this conflict and you had
sympathies to the ukrainians you could
from your bedroom uh start you know
launching attacks on things he called it
World cyber War one and this actually
continues to this day each day there's a
telegram Channel it puts out things to
attack it even includes advice on what
you which U.S cloud providers are most
lenient on allowing you to launch
attacks from their Network
look it up
um even before that uh even before the
the call to action we started seeing
DDOS attacks against Russian targets
these are typically prominent uh
symbolic targets like kremlin.ru uh
again I was as this was happening I was
putting out uh and we were seeing this
in our data and just confirming that
things these things were taking place uh
the banks the major banks in Russia were
also targets of these things
and so as a result uh Russia started
taking uh evasive actions to get out of
uh the path of some of these attacks one
of the uh things that we spotted was one
of the this e-government self-service
platform for Russia uh was normally as
is four by as it only have its routes
announced through Ross Telecom onto its
International providers and and peers uh
on this day all the routes came down
this is a view out of Iota because from
the outside world it looked like the
went off the cliff and this network was
was taken offline and left the global
routing table which it kind of did the
um but the routes were still in
circulation within within Russia the the
site was accessible within Russia but
this was a tactic to try to limit the
impacts of DDOS attacks coming from
outside of the country
foreign
the it Army call we have this other uh
request that again people like me
haven't seen anything like this before
where the government of Ukraine asked
that Russia be disconnected from the
global internet their requests I can and
right included uh revoking the cctlds uh
for Russia withdrawing the right to have
V4 and V6 uh address space among other
things
unsurprisingly I can and ripe uh refuse
to uh you know to do this
um wanting to stay out of the the
political
um uh any kind of political stuff plus
the view there is that um you know the
internet is a neutral technology and
shouldn't be used in this manner that's
all setting aside how would you unpract
the practicalities of trying to
implement such a thing but nonetheless
it took place and this led to a
conversation that start that uh this
Converse controversial idea of
um you know could there be uh internet
this internet sanctions project could
you use the internet governance model to
kind of crowdsource if you uh what you
would want to block in a in a in a
country if uh if you chose to do so so
the idea is to try to limit collateral
damage on civilian access to information
which doesn't serve anybody's purpose if
you were able to cut them off because at
this time if you recall says a few
months ago there were people that were
were companies that were blocking
everything in Russia and so that's not
that's kind of a counterproductive move
so this this hadn't really this this
effort didn't really catch on but it's
another uh you know we're breaking new
ground in this age of the internet
so the uh in the the opening weeks of
this conflict did not go as planned for
Russia the news looked bad and so as a
result of the Russian government ordered
the blocking of independent Russian news
as well as foreign news sites and they
did so uh using a piecemeal mechanism so
there is no great firewall of Russia as
much as they would aspire to have such a
thing the way it typically gets
implemented is the government issues an
order each ISP has got to implement
these blocks on their own and so you end
up with a kind of a piecemeal
um approach and so uni if you're not
familiar with them this is the open
Observatory for Network interference
it's published a number of reports this
year this was one documenting the
technical mechanisms used to block these
sites and uh it's a screenshot from uh
from that report
so this effort led to uh inadvertent bgp
hijack of Twitter on March 28th so for
less than an hour uh this one Russian
Telecom uh announced uh hijacked this
slash 24 belonging to Twitter and it uh
they probably intended to keep this
local just to Black Hole the traffic
within their Network it leaked out onto
the internet and caused some disruption
what's interesting is that this slash 24
was the same slash 24 that was hijacked
one year prior almost to the day during
the military coup in Myanmar so in that
case the government had given the order
similar to Russia uh block these things
Twitter's on that list and you're on
your own of how to do it and so one of
the providers in Myanmar a year ago then
uh uh decided they were going to
announce uh the same slash 24 it leaked
out at an exchange in in Singapore and
users in South Asia and Southeast Asia
uh had trouble reaching Twitter for a a
period of time
so the difference between what took
place last year in Myanmar and this year
in Russia for this prefix is that in the
intervening time Twitter uh created Rose
for all of their routes and so this time
around uh there was if for a networks
that evaluated uh did RPI evaluation
this would show up as an invalid it was
getting rejected and I think that
limited uh quite a bit of the the
propagation of this route and I don't
think there's a lot of practical impact
but this did take place
so another uh another unprecedented
development was this announcement by
Major backbone providers to curtail
operations in Russia uh so on March 3rd
uh 20 2022 this year uh cogent sent an
email to all of their Russian customers
saying that tomorrow this is they set
this on a Thursday tomorrow's Friday
tomorrow service your service will be
discontinued due to the invasion
um
so we uh uh caught wind of this uh and
um wrote something up in the end uh ttk
uh trans Telecom the other National fix
fix line provider of Russia and Beyond
which used to be vimplecom were among a
handful of Russian networks that were uh
that were in the end disconnected on
this day uh within a week Von was
reconnected and other Russian customers
such as like Ross Telecom the state
Telecom Russia that was a coaching
customer was never disconnected
um and in the end uh illumin within a
couple days had announced uh their own
version of this statement saying that
they were taking immediate steps to
cease operations in the region
um you know no no customers were
disconnected I think their logic is that
their traffic handoffs take place in
Stockholm and Frankfurt so they're not
really operating in the region uh it's
it's semantics but in the end uh Russia
continues to be well connected to the
global internet
links also had uh decided to disconnect
Ross Telecom fun a meal out in ripe had
a good analysis of the impacts of that
but in the long and short of a Russian
continues to be connected to the global
internet
so if you've been following this uh uh
this conflict you know the initial phase
was uh the Russian army was trying to
attack Kiev to quickly topple the
government and take over the country
that didn't work out and so they
changed their strategy to focus on the
East and the South areas that they had a
better chance of of taking and so
uh this is what we um uh some some
comments on that so in the Eastern Area
referred to as the Don bass region the
dawn is the river that goes through that
that part of the country
we're talking about specifically the
netsk and lahansk and so these areas are
starting you know historically have
often uh used Russian Transit simply
because they are uh the proximity to
Russia they border uh Russia
um when this when this all this conflict
started uh happening in 2014 many years
ago uh there was a lot of disconnection
and rewiring of just uh just getting
Transit from Russia and uh so they end
up being a bit of a partition between
these parts of the of the country
luhansk uh you know both these areas are
um have been over the years uh
self-proclaimed independent uh areas
independent from the central Ukrainian
government and it's a bit of a lawless
place so there's a lot of bad uh bad
stuff that comes out of luhansk if you
recall the bgb DNS hijacks of Route the
Route 53 and my ether wallet well that
was directed to a Data Center and uh
users were directed to a data center in
luhansk to get their
cryptocurrency stolen a couple months
later there was a bgb DNS hijack against
major payment processors that too was
redirected to bogus sites in uh and
lahansk so um there is a as I mentioned
there's an internet partition if you
were to take a rape Atlas probe or run
your own trace route from something like
the netsk on to something in the main uh
part of Ukraine you may find a path not
unlike this where you get directed up to
Moscow to Saint Petersburg over to
Stockholm Frankfort back to Kiev uh onto
wherever where you're running a trace
route to and so these things may be
right next to each other uh on a map but
as far as the internet goes these things
are very far apart in fact they're you
know on the order of a Pacific Ocean
apart
as far as round trip latencies
another thing that took place uh was
this a switchover of the city of Curson
over to Russian Transit so in March 2014
when Russia annexed the Crimean
Peninsula from Ukraine one of the things
that they did was uh prime minister
Medvedev had traveled to uh the uh the
semester poll or Sephora poll made a
speech about how
it was unaccessible that uh Crimean
traffic or Russian traffic would go over
four networks foreign being Ukraine in
that context and ordered Ross Telecom to
build a submarine cable uh over the
Kirch Strait the little uh bit of land a
bit of water that separates Russia from
Crimea uh so in my this is back in my
days with Renaissance we were following
this closely we spotted the appearance
of Miranda media uh this
as201776 uh in July 2014 and then uh it
started carrying traffic within a week
uh over that year a lot of uh the as's
were switched over to uh Russian Transit
and
um we saw something similar happen in
croissants it was a city in the South
and so I had worked with the New York
Times this summer on a interactive uh
piece that made the front page of the of
the paper uh this is a visualization
based on some of the data that I
provided them and then on the left if
you can can't tell the difference I made
the one on the right as my animation uh
and um so I'm looking we're looking at
this is the bgp level as is switching
over uh and if you look at the beginning
like right now you have got many paths
to Ukrainian providers connecting to the
uh the Ukraine and onto the
international uh Network International
uh Global Internet switched with uh all
going through a single as Miranda media
that goes again through a single as rust
Telecom if you look in this graphic from
New York Times the little dots in the uh
and croissant are the as's but they
didn't want to uh mention the word as
because they have to Define uh internet
routing and uh no one was going to
understand that
so uh
let's see
so if you've been following the news
again you know the in recent weeks
there's been this Iranian uh excuse me
uh Ukraine camera counter offensive
uh followed by a Russian retaliation
so the Ukraine has been gaining ground
uh uh especially in the East around uh
kharkiv and then they did this uh
um ambitious attack against the Kirch
Bridge so I mentioned the Kirch cable
the summary cable that goes across the
curse straight that was built in 2014
well four years later there was this
built this bridge is both a automobile
and a train bridge was built in 20
finished in 2018.
um this is what was uh attacked just a
couple of weeks ago
uh I uh I'll give credit to remain here
from iaj who spotted the uh the impact
on the internet there really wasn't a
lot of impact to uh Crimean internet
connectivity they must still rely
primarily on the submarine cable I would
have thought that they would have used
laid some cable on the bridge that would
have been taken out but there really
wasn't a lot of
a lot of impact but the um two days
later uh the Russian forces launched
cruise missiles into cities across
Ukraine and uh we we saw impact uh this
is our net flow uh data aggregate
netflow showing traffic dropping off in
different cities uh as power stations
are are taking out fiber lines are cut
and there was um there was quite a lot
of Destruction caused on these
retaliatory attacks
so to wrap up
um in the end uh Ukraine has stayed
online so these are grass I made uh or I
gathered together in the you know
opening 30 days of the uh of the
conflict uh showing by a variety of
different
mechanisms uh different data sources
that Ukraine stayed online uh and each
show some sort of a dip so in the top
left we have Iota looking at bgb routes
there's only a slight dip most of the
routes stayed up there's uh their active
measurement the blue line is a bit of a
dip as things are unreachable either
they've been broken let power as out
people have turned things off and then
these other ones are traffic based so
you have cloudflare on the bottom left
and Google in the bottom right also
showing a a decline in the volume of
traffic and then uh it's a graphic from
our Aggregate netflow and so this could
be explained by a number of
a number of reasons you know and after
the initial invasion you had hundreds of
millions of people or not hundreds of
millions millions of people
um uh fleeing the country and so that's
going to have an impact on the uh uh the
the traffic that gets pushed in and out
of the country uh there's also uh
infrastructure that was getting
destroyed uh that um it's going to
affect traffic and then also even for
the folks that stayed in this country
you know life was not the same after
February 24th and so that too has an
effect on how they use the internet and
shows up on all these stats but in the
end the state the country stayed online
it has a very robust infrastructure that
a lot of people have commented on
but this is an important footnote in
this uh in this story of this conflict
this year you know this the maintaining
internet connectivity in this country
has been critical for a number of
reasons it was crucial for the
government to Rally Global support Jihad
zielinski with his cabinet in the
streets of Kiev uh recording videos
saying they're going to stay they're
going to fight and help us uh with our
with this with this battle
uh critical for news organizations
coming in if you've followed us
certainly in the opening weeks uh
reporters were able to file stories just
on their iPhones connecting to the local
mobile service uh the internet was
useful for that
and then for ukrainians to show what was
happening in their country and be able
to uh connect the loved ones let them
know that they are still still okay
and this was enabled by uh technicians
these are folks this is our industry
this is our people of our industry in
Ukraine going out to places freshly uh
attacked uh sites getting to uh getting
destroyed these guys had great uh great
risks themselves uh yeah
thank you
at Great risk themselves would travel
out uh to recently attacked places
reconnecting fiber lines and keeping
their countrymen online
it's a it's an inspiring thing
so in the age of uh age of the internet
here's what uh
um
this war shows us we have these DDOS
attacks the I.T Army uh launching stuff
both in Ukraine and Russia outages due
to the straight fiber lines and cyber
attacks uh knocking things temporarily
offline and then this heroic effort by
uh Ukrainian technicians going out and
repairing severed fiber lines
there's a lot of blowback against the
aggressor in this case the Russia uh had
to silence their own social media news
blockage and um and there was this
discussion of like should they be
disconnected
um that's that's something new we're
breaking new ground on this and then you
know this uh the
assimilation of of Curson into the
Russian fold to uh not just the internet
we I see it from the internet
perspective of the transit being
switched over to Russian Transit but the
phone lines they have a Russian you know
country code you have to dial to reach
them now uh the everything that they
every part of society gets uh
assimilated into the Russian way of
doing things and we'll see uh if this
current counter-offensive is successful
in that part of the world
maybe at some point soon we'll see this
switch back to Ukrainian Transit it's
something I keep an eye on
and if you'd like to help I'm sure if
you've attended any nog event in this
this year you've probably sat through a
presentation by the keep Ukraine
connected effort uh those are these are
folks in based in Europe that are
sourcing a lot of fiber optic equipment
they are physically driving it into
Ukraine to equip those folks you saw in
those photos a couple of weeks prior to
keep them flushed with equipment to keep
the repairs going they take donations
money they take equipment any if you
want to help this is an organization
that you can use uh to do that
that's my talk does any questions
all right
howdy thank you for that talk uh so I
guess right now what I'm seeing in the
news is this interesting delineation
between the terrestrial networks which
is our business and the non-terrestrial
networks right like Starling right
exactly so there's this convergence
that's clearly happening right now for
us so I'd love to hear your thoughts and
opinions on the potential termination of
the Starling connection yeah starlink is
kind of uh yeah I guess that's a that's
a glaring Omission in this talk is any
comment uh around starlink so
um it is a is a big Topic in the news so
this is a closed system this makes it
difficult uh to study from an internet
measurement standpoint if you imagine
you've got a Ground Terminal goes up to
a satellite and then bounces down to a a
ground station somewhere in your cell uh
as the is the uh the way it's configured
there are uh they had announced uh
um new sites in Kiev at least he's in
their geoip that they published there's
a Kiev ground station
um it's not guaranteed that's where they
would come down but it's it's it's
challenging to see and we can see
traffic that gets mapped as Ukraine but
it's uh it's hard to know
how much of that is um
uh
yeah I don't know I don't know how much
we have a insight into starlink and I
also say that all these graphs of this
is all this is all terrestrial uh
connectivity fiber terrestrial and um
there is no way that a satellite service
is gonna replace the capacity the
terrestrial fiber fiber is going to
offer and I think some of the reporting
it gets a little confused I I find where
um uh yeah like even the Ukrainian
government recently said starlink that's
keeping the country online I was like
well when that's not possible uh I'm
sure it's super helpful I mean as a
former military Communications officer
uh like I'm sure the the way that the
major contribution is tactical
Communications uh that's where this
would be super useful but again Elon
Musk didn't didn't invent that that
existed a long time ago I carried an
iridium phone in Iraq in the first year
of the war like we had uh satellite
connectivity uh before that but anyway
don't get me going on starlink uh but
it's a it's a
it's it's definitely contributing I I
you know it's helping I'll see you uh
Chris can I get the guy behind you uh no
you yeah sorry hi uh Marty strong from
meta uh two things I learned and one
quick question
um you said about the Russian Transit as
far as I understand
the fibers would deliberately severed
because they didn't want Russian
connectivity to Ukraine I'm sorry can
you say that one more time the Russian
the fiber across the border from Ukraine
into Russia was deliberately severed
okay I think he said the 28th because
they didn't want the connectivity to
remain okay the number of Russian ixes
and other operators actually had Pops in
in Kiev that were completely cut off at
that point
um sorry deliberately severed by
ukrainians yeah ukrainians okay
um the the part on the the Russia slide
about
blocking actually the Russian regulator
has their own DPI equipment in the
Russian operators so they are pushing
out the blocking rules themselves
and there was a case where they they did
this before The Invasion where they were
trying to throttle
I think it was Twitter it was I'm
familiar with uh yesterday yeah they
they were they were blocking t.co the
shortener but then they ended up it was
a regex uh thing so so when we have been
blocked recently because of the
extremist organization that that was
rolled out without the knowledge of the
operators in advance it was just blanket
pushed out and then
The Operators yeah so there is some
that's a fairly new development that
there's uh there is some centralized
capability but then um uh yeah I don't
know it's it's it doesn't cover
everything and so that's typically the
large the largest operators that they
have there okay equipment in um the
question I had was on your slide with
blown up infrastructure did you find
that there was extended periods of
outage not necessarily by fiber Cuts but
by the electricity grid being down
um well I I the graphics that were up
earlier I think are representative of
most of the stuff we saw were it's uh
usually things appeared from an internet
measurement standpoint this is the best
I can do uh to be restored in a matter
of hours
but is that a a technician like in one
of these pictures uh create a fixing a
fiber line or a power station coming
back online
um sometimes that's hard to to tell the
difference so I know some of the
infrastructure was down because when the
grid was bombed they are light Ila sites
ran out of diesel in their generators to
keep the science online so whilst the
fiber was not cut they couldn't keep up
all the repeater stations sure to keep
the second one to end which was actually
a lot more difficult because they had to
fix the electricity grid and not just
splice Vibes together
all right thanks thank you all right
Chris I think it's going to be you
last uh Chris Woodfield with Twitter
first off happy to be an RP and Kai
success story yeah thank you for
pointing that out
um so uh but this is your talk not mine
um is it so the question I have is
what what was your what was the external
observations and the difference in the
impact between the Myanmar route leak
and which did not have rpki and the
Russian the Russian right League that
did
um it is really hard to is hard to
compare apples to apples in this case uh
so you have in Myanmar uh a leak
happening at an exchange uh in uh the
Russian case is going through Transit
relationships
um and uh yeah there is a difference in
the amount of propagation but uh there's
so many like there's other ways people
filter stuff besides RPI so it ends up
being you know if both were the same
league coming out of the same as then
maybe you'd have a chance of of reliably
comparing the two and seeing the effect
of rpkai uh but given there's so many
different factors I think it's it's hard
I I guess I I in my heart believe the
archive helped uh the propagation what
there wasn't very much propagation this
time around and I think rpki was was uh
important for that thank you thanks
all right thanks
[Music]