[Music]
foreign
to the screens Dr Hussein badran who
will be presenting internet Evolution
approaches at itu-t why should we care
Hussein holds the position of Regional
Technical advisor North America Bureau
with the internet society and he's based
in Ottawa Canada
this is Hussein's second time presenting
at nanog and it's a pleasure again to
have him speaking with us today welcome
Hussein
um the aim of the topic of this is this
talk here today is really to provide an
um an insight into discussions that are
happening at the itu T that look at
internet Evolution approaches and they
can have significant impact on how the
internet would evolve in the near to
distant future so awareness of these and
being participating being active in
these discussions is quite quite
critical
so The Talk The Talk today is um uh
composed of just looking at one of those
the key critical proposal at the itut
being discussed over the last several
months
um finding some insight into the new IP
proposal what are the key concerns the
internal society and other stakeholders
have seen into such proposals
um and then how this is being evolved to
to our date to today and then looking
into some um uh positive and effective
and successful evolution of the internet
particularly on vertical and specialized
Networks and reflecting on some very
recent developments are just two days
ago regarding the similar new IP to new
IP proposals so some of the acronyms
I'll be using in today's presentation
relates to the itot itut is a
specialized agency of the United Nations
it's a short for international
telecommunications Union
telecommunication centralization sector
that has several study groups that look
into
developing new standards study group 13
to Future networks 11 for signing and
requirements and then there is an
overarching
body this actual application
centralization Advisory Group looks into
the logistics and the operation and
approving these uh the questions being
studied at the study groups wtsa is
really the work to the work to
communication centralization assembly
were really the governments of the of
the world get together every four years
to agree on priorities of
standardizations for the next study
period
standards development organizations sdos
and Etsy is the European television
standards Institute
the new IP proposal
um is something that really that has
appeared in the in the itu as early as
2018 uh throughout a focus group that
was created
um to discuss the future of the internet
and how the internet would look like in
the year 2030.
uh This was done to a contribution to
tsag in 2019
um and then proposals started to emerge
into uh direct direction of the future
is this new IP proposal in 2020
um the terminology was changed to Future
vertical communication networks but
really the substance of the proposal has
has been kept kept intact
um the another key step is and after
significant opposition from from many
governments and and the same Society
members and other stakeholders and it
was cited at the itu site group 1311 not
to accept the new IP related questions
as new work items for for new standards
and as well as stop discussing new IP at
least until wtsa which took a place in
March 2022. so that was a decision taken
in um in December 2020 as but as we will
see really proposals very similar to new
IP with the elements of new IP kept on
coming to the iitut looking for standard
development in the same in the same
framework
um and these proposals actually have
appeared as from March 2021 under
polymer polymorphic networking as well
as immersive real-time communication
systems that we will look into a summary
of these proposals
um
um and that's also not only in study
group 13 and 11 also in study group 17
which means with security aspects of the
uh of of networks
um security guidelines for autonomistic
communication services for IMT 2020
networks and and Beyond so it is very
critical to keep really engaged and
aware and Vigilant to these proposals
and collaborating among the multiple
stakeholders that can be engaged in such
in such activities
um so the it the focus group on network
2030 came up with some technical reports
and the Gap analysis
um as as shown here in the year 2020
June 2020
but the key observations of this work is
that the Gap analysis were very high
level
um gaban answers here looks into what
the it2 iit2t should be doing versus
what other standards organizations are
currently doing like 3gbp or the ietf or
IEEE so the governance is performed by
the team here at the focus group was
very high level quite superficial and no
no format engagements through Liaisons
between the itu and
um and these other organizations took
place which means that there was no
formal discussion of the proposals
as a normal view quick overview of the
new IP proposal presented to itut uh
during 2019 and 2020. basically it has a
proposal from Hawaii to develop new
network protocols and architectures by
extending and redesigning the
traditional IP supporting new services
for a new internet by 2030. so the the
objective is not is not hidden it's not
being hidden it is the new network
architecture redesigned traditional IP
and the new internet and there are
elements of this that will cover a
couple two of them semantic addressing
as well as domestic services and
intrinsic security
as you see from the graph here new IP on
one side versus the traditional IP on
the other sides are complete replacement
was really the desire
much semantic addressing which is a key
component of the new IP proposal looks
into
extending the the address space Not only
include the version 4 or version 6
address but but new ID is to be added to
the to the address space including
individual ID so if you've got what is
called people IDs or service IDs for
quite a service Assurance between both
ends or Content ID to identify the
protocol and the content being being
sent between the sending and receiving
entity of course as do as well as the
device ID and then the IP IP address so
significantly more information is is
being provided is expected divided by
this proposal about the the participants
and the information be being sent so
really a foundation for Mass
surveillance
um that is being built into the new
architecture uh that's into the to
replace the current IP IP and the
current Internet
on the on the deterministic forwarding
side
here the aim is to provide delay
guarantees And Delay variation
guarantees and we're very stringent
guarantees in the order of multiple
microseconds or fractions or
milliseconds and multiple and and uh
multiple microseconds so very strange in
terms of guarantees are expected by this
this proposal
um and um some analysis done by itu
study group 12 which looks at quality of
service and performance issues of of
networks have identified that such
guarantees can only be delivered in a
local or city-wide Network and if a
distance on a regional or Global basis
such grantees can actually not not be
delivered so the the what that's being
asked here is not realistic to be
delivered by a global a global internet
architecture
so the key concerns in this in this
proposal are
um the lack of interoperability
introduced by by putting uh underground
a new architecture that is not really
interoperable with the existing
architecture new addressing scheme
um completely addressing scheme which
actually will lead to internet
fragmentation so this is an outcome that
will be expected for introducing such a
global architecture and success success
of the internet has has been based of
innovation and standards that are really
incremental you'll base one Innovation
on top of the other one success on top
of the other it's an evolutionary
process not a revolutionary process
um uh along with this line capital
investment in the hardware and the
software in the network infrastructure
why they buy it by The Operators by
national research education networks for
Enterprise Networks
will will be actually at that threat
um if such a migration
takes place to a new protocol and a new
architecture Without You consideration
for the investment protection okay and
the the the proposal tries to sell
future Technologies engage current
Network architecture and services which
is really not really comparing apple
apple to Apple
um
a laptop automated networks is not
really lack of capability because the
deployment of services is driven also by
market demand and consumer demand not
only by technology and standard
advancements
so something really some false claims
have been have been made in this this
proposal and they'll articulate also in
the in the next slide
um
um the the current networking
environment is not only the internet
that is based on multiple heterogeneous
networks interconnected together
so this network cannot handle to
heterogeneous networks such as
okay well-known um false false claim
ultra high throughput can be supported
today for sure given the high definition
Services being deployed on the network
today within a huge amount of video
conferencing services at high quality as
we are doing doing now
the fact that low latency is required is
not really
um on a global global basis it can be an
original or local basis but very low
latency be required on a global basis is
sort of something that is not not really
realistic
these concerns were put forward by by
the European telecommunication Network
operators Group which is the alliance or
group um we bring together the European
Telecom operators and they have raised
their concerns directly to the the chair
of study group 13 when the decision was
being made in cyber 2020 to stop or
Advance this new new proposal and they
articulated three three major concerns
that high investment the water Telecom
networks and infrastructure
infrastructures should not be threatened
by deployment of new Internet Protocol
as well as it is very critical to avoid
duplication of efforts that should be no
overlap between what the itu is doing
versus what other sdos and standard
organizations are doing
giving giving example the ietf and the
attribute and also the the internet
protocols and their success has been
that they were developed in a
multi-stakeholder environment that is
open
um available for stakeholders and bottom
app fashion not such as the the ietf and
the i2b are not driven by top-down
processes as in the in the itu which is
the government-led decision-making body
here I present two examples that
happened in March 2021 in proposals
after the decision to stop discussing
uip and as you will see the elements of
new IP are presented in these proposals
so one the first one is polymorphic
networking what's called pilot
and here
what is proposed is a new type of
network architecture and potential
Network model for the future six
donation mobile communication network
using some some
buzzwords and keywords to do to to
attract attention but the key points is
that this proposal looks into addressing
um routing schemes switching modes
interconnection modes Network element
forms transmission protocols that enable
the network to support specialized and
customized Services which means a new
Global architecture and it became very
clear once we looked into what kind of
addressing scheme this network is
supposed to use
by the way this proposal is based on on
one paper published in an uh in a
journal that really is very high level
and does not provide any justification
for such an approach
the addressing scheme I was referring to
is here is shown here it's showing that
it's really a multi-semantic addressing
scheme very similar to the original uh
new IP proposal again requiring
in addition to the iip addresses in the
header identity ID Content ID location
ID multiple information being gathered
from by by descending and receiving
parties which is really the foundation
of our widespread service
um institutional uh surveillance
mechanism
concerns here are that that proposal is
a research topic really it's not and
it's far too early to seek International
standardization
The Proposal does not include sufficient
information
um for the need of a new architecture or
its potential use our Gap analysis would
work related being done at other sgos
and such discussions of such proposals
that we look look into the architecture
of the global internet to take place not
at the igu but at others and other
centers organizations particularly the
ieta
the second proposal looks into the other
side look side of the internalistic
services or in other words immersive
real-time Communications and here the
proposal looks into
how can can real-time services such as
um
um heterogeneous homographic type
Communications
um or two additional twins to be
incorporated into a future architecture
providing guarantees including ultra
high bandwidth ultra low latency
strict simple synchronization that is
similar to what we have seen from the
original Ip new IP proposal and the case
studies in this in this scenarios
um uh the two one two Key signs
presented are the digital twins as well
as the holographic type communication
services and this service by the way
they are currently being being delivered
on existing existing internet
architecture and architecture today is
scaling up to support such such services
nevertheless this is what the proposal
coming again from from from China to uh
for a new Global architecture that
supports these use cases
um that we have seen for the new IP
proposal a new IP proposal
um
as a new standardization item for the
itut study group 13. here again the key
concerns were this is a research topic
it's not really ready for international
centralization as well as insufficient
information why actually this work is
needed why a new architecture is needed
given that it can be supported today on
existing internet
and whether the itu is a place to
discuss these person's other standards
organizations like the ietf
the building moving from these efforts
to continue at efforts and persistent
efforts to bring in new kinds of
evolutionary scenarios for the internet
at the itu-t not all Evolution passes
are really harmful to the internet the
other Evolution Pathways which have
proven over time to be very successful
in expanding in the internet and
providing
um The permissionless Innovation that
the internet is based to and one of this
direction is the vertical or specialized
networks but Innovation takes place more
on the edge of the network
and definition of a vertical or
specialized networks is um that they
typically use protocols that are
optimized for the deployment scenario
being manufacturing architecture
agriculture Smart City
smart health and the like and the
optimization optimization here targets
less overhead I.E High higher data rate
um or or throughput and at the same time
higher speed
and this optimization typically take
place at the physical physical layer of
the network or at the data link layer of
the network or the Mac layer of the
network
and in order to achieve the efficiencies
that they that that is is aimed for they
these protocols avoid the complex
routing decisions and because these
sound institutions will require
significant processing and relatively
long headers in order
um and this would really increase the
complexity of the protocols and then
reduce Network throughput
so these networks would run being
controlled either the physical layer or
the max layer and then one single point
in the network
will be the interface to the to the
internet and hence the incorporation of
the IP header would be would be
necessary but the rest of the network
will operate at a much lighter lighter
overhead and header header structure
an example of this is what this Etsy is
currently working on for smart
manufacturing domain
um
there's a non-ip networking group
um or isg industry specification group
that really looks into building some
sort of protocol for and smart
manufacturing manufacturing site and
they um they came up with a protocol
protocol structure for this particular
particular requirement where we have
um a large number of robots that need to
be controlled in a very small time frame
and between every uh 100 millisecond
1000 or more robots being being
controlled so a real-time interface is
is required
and here a protocol was was put a
protocol proposals put together at sea
for this client of specific scenario uh
smart manufacturing site called flexi
link Network model and here they propose
a a simplified header header structure
as well as a flow or virtual circuit
circuit
mode of transmission so the connection
that's environment becomes a connection
oriented environment between between the
switch and and the the controller as
well as as the moving moving entities
the robots at the on the floor of the
manufacturing manufacturing site with a
simplified packet text header structure
as as I mentioned so this protocol is
optimized for this particular use and
only in this confined confined domain
and single domain environment so no
signaling protocol was was specified so
it cannot be really replicated or
expanded to a global global original or
architecture which is contained with
this specialized Network or local local
control Network very
welcomed Innovation at the agile Network
for specialized application another
specialized application is within the
smart
Smart City or smart connectivity domain
Laura land I'm sure you um it's quite
it's quite well known we're really an
innovation in the wireless wireless
domain using space Spectrum technology
allowed connectivity of multiple smart
devices that have a low power the low
throughput requirements the qualdera
sensors we connected to base stations
and then from there the Gateway is
connected potentially to the to the to
the internet for routing for routing
decisions
to reach the final Final Destination so
another Innovation on on the the
smartphone activity smart city city
domain that is um again expands the
evolution expands the edge of of the of
the network with multiple large number
of smart device connected to to the the
controllers
the third and final example is the cdns
and the content distribution networks is
really an evolution of the internet Edge
to allow
um
um the caching of content to be as close
as possible to the end user instead of
being stored in central location have to
Traverse the network to which the the
end user at the edge so this is an
evolution of the of the of the IP based
Network that allows for higher higher
higher throughput better experience
um to be delivered to the to the end
user
um
um and it's a revolution pass for for
the for for the for the internet uh for
video services this is an example on on
the right it shows hierarchical
um cdns to allow multiple caching levels
to deliver high quality video Services
um applications to the to the to the
endings
um uh finally just wanted to mention
some recent recent very recent
development that took place uh in in
this in this domain so new IP is not
something that happened in 2020 and we
forget about it it is a continued
continued effort and consistent effort
by the proponents of new IP to try to
introduce new architectures for the
global internet through
um the itot in this case potentially to
other areas but through itut is why we
see the threat coming from at this point
and this newer newer developments took
place
um
for example at the wtsa in March 2022
here originally um there was a proposed
resolution on cyber security included
reference to Intrinsic security as we
have seen this is one critical component
of the new IP proposal
so we're very critical that this term is
not accepted in the final final version
it was replaced by for example something
called security by Design which is a
more understandable more confined
confined term
another resolution on centralization of
non-radio aspects of international
mobile telecommunication to
Communications had multiple references
for the focus group work on future
networks which means that future work
should be based on the outcomes of this
future Group which is really direction
of new IP so it was very critical that
this proposal is not accepted and the
final version of the resolution has all
this kind of these kinds of references
omitted which we are able to
successfully achieve at wtsa at wtdc
which is the word application
development conference
had had a proposal from from China
coming into a resolution that deals with
deployment of IPv6 particularly in
developing countries and introduces
slightly introduced a term called ibv6
plus that was very vaguely very vaguely
defined
and wanted to build to have efforts done
by the it2 for capacity building of
deployment of IPv6 and V6 plus and if
you see that what what the examples of
what kind of Protocols are under ibb6
Plus or under what kind of Technologies
are under this IPv6 plus included the
gymnastic Services included multiple
addressing schemes included
I use use of AI very open-ended very
Loosely defined that allows you to
introduce anything including a new
architecture into such such a resolution
and this was um really a big storm at
the the wtdc and it was uh
not accepted to be included in
resolution 1-130 and all references was
only confined to IPv6 deployment and
capacity building on IPv6
the last one I wanted to mention is
something that's happened actually just
48 hours ago on on Monday
and here another study group at the itu
and I said look that these environmental
aspects of of Delegation Networks
and Dr proposal coming again from China
to creation of a new question which
means a new standards a standard um
password new standard to be developed
that looked into environmentally
sustainable development and operation of
ICT Network so it is the title is quite
it's quite Beyond and not really benign
and not really will catch any attention
but if you look into the details of the
proposal
the details of the proposal has this
particular this particular paragraph
which is very very alarming study how
the reduction of network layers and
flatten the overall Network architecture
would achieve so and so new network
architecture solutions to replace the
traditional three-layer Network topology
review and reducing the number of node
devices
so basically it's a completely new
architecture of the global global IP
based Network it is flattened reduction
of network layers that production of
network nodes coming up with new
protocols so basically we are back to to
the framework that looks into some sort
of a new IP to replace exist existing
Global Internet architecture and this
happened only 48 hours ago and until now
it is being being debated I present
intervention on behalf of the Indian
Society at the planning meeting with
study group 5 on on Monday and we are in
discussion hopefully this will not go
the aim is not go through as an accepted
question but this shows that there is
persistence in in providing
um a venue to discuss and and
standardize a new Global architecture
for the internet not only for from
future network side but here from the
environmental side and environmental
sustainability and climate change is
something that we all kick care about
and we all want to achieve
positive positive steps in this
direction but here this this particular
paragraph shows you that the aim really
or the tool touch is here to actually to
work completely redesign the global
architecture of the of the internet
which is a very certainly very
threatening uh very threatening
threatening approach
so it is important here that the key
Point here is important that we are
aware of these developments happening at
the itu team and iqt is open not only to
government delegates but also to sector
members and sector members are can be a
private entities Telecom operators
vendors it can be Academia research
research entities
and the sector numbers are allowed to
contribute submit contributions to
discuss this
um and make make presentations of these
contributions the only thing they're not
allowed to do is to have a vote like the
government to government delegations
have a vote to order to move or to stop
um a proposal from becoming a standard
so in summary
um proposals like new IP they pose a
very significant threat to the global
internet model and architecture
and although discussions of new IP were
stopped I study group 11 and 13. in
December 2020 as I mentioned but there's
a persistent persistent desire
persistent effort by by the proponents
of of this uh new architecture to submit
um other proposals that include elements
of of the of the new IP purpose
two various study groups at itut not
only selling Group 13 and 11 which deals
with future networks over signaling that
were original original custodian of the
uh new IP proposal but to the security
group study group two now and most
recently to the environmental study
group and as you see this is just
ongoing and continuing
um coming with very strong persistence
to the to the I.T and various vigilance
participation
um being aware of these discussions and
raising these points at different
different four including Forum of nanog
where
um large community of network engineers
and experts participate
um is important so that the
participation and engagement can be can
be increased at the same time Innovation
is key to the evolution of the internet
and we see Innovation particularly in
vertical networks that expand and evolve
the edge of the of the of the internet
is very useful to the evolution of the
internet and very much welcome and they
are basically driven by by demand and
need not by just an international
standard that will imply and dictate a
specific architecture to be to be uh
deployed okay
thank you thank you so much this is
um I hope that this was was clear and
the messages will came through and I'm
happy to take take questions thank you
so much
foreign
do we have any questions we're saying
hello thank you for your talk uh Andrew
tall my question is about whether the
new IP and Alternate identifiers ideas
have been reduced to anything more than
PowerPoint slides as in of any
specifications actually been drafted and
are is there any code that people have
started writing around these ideas
actually this is an excellent excellent
question the proponents of of the new
IPA framework have repeatedly claimed in
conferences and in a different form
including side meetings as the ATF that
they have prototypes working prototypes
of this code and and this this switching
architecture and so there is a claim
that that the components for example
Huawei have built prototypes
um and uh um are ready for demonstration
of these of these Technologies they have
not been publicly seen as far as far as
I know but the claim is is there and
it's been documented in in some research
papers and publications
we need to keep in mind that China is a
huge Market on its own so deployment can
can take place there without the rest of
the world be being aware of this uh of
this taking taking place
and there are support there is support
for for this Direction coming from from
uh certain certain countries
um that could also be a ground for
initial deployment
so here again awareness vigilance and
participation in the discussion is quite
critical to understand really the
reality of what what is being proposed
but I believe from from my experience
that it goes beyond just Sparkle's lines
yes there has no been standard
specifications but will stop the effort
is still continuing and persistent to
develop standard specifications but the
the demo part
um is has been ongoing scenes uh for for
quite some time
thank you very much
thank you
any additional questions
well thank you again for the present
today and thanks for your time today I'm
saying thank you thank you it's a
pleasure thank you so much
[Applause]
foreign
[Music]