[Music]
foreign
I'd like to welcome Michelle stazinski
who will be presenting seamless data
center interconnect options using evpn
and various tunnel stitching Michelle is
a 20-year industry veteran and currently
part of the product management team at
Juniper Networks cloud ready Data Center
business unit this is Michelle's first
time on The Dan on stage welcome
thank you thank you Chris so hi everyone
thank you for the introduction so this
session is about data center data center
Data Center and data center interconnect
so it's a North American operators uh uh
event but data center is important for
uh operators
especially we observe that in Europe
most of the service providers we work
with they are deploying massively Edge
data center Regional Data Center and
National Data Centers right to deliver
5G as a
as a coherent solution with the right
bandwidth with the right secure access
to the data closer to the user so that
session is all about this
obviously we've seen also during the
pandemic time that getting this fast and
reliable secure access to data was
important as well
so making sure that the statistics you
are getting
on time
you got that from the reliable source
was critical right so pandemic is over
but still there are a lot of lessons
learned also so this session is actually
about how to deliver data center
interconnect replications of the data in
different regions of the country
in a simplified way so deploying data
center uh interconnect it's not
necessarily something new we used to
have vpls for many years many telcos are
still using vpls as an approach next gen
moving to the evpn mpls as a service
but in this session we'll see both
angles the data center evpn vxlon inside
the fabric as well as the DCI simplified
way of deploying the DCI other than just
using npls as a transport
so here is the agenda of this session so
we'll explain actually why seamless data
center interconnect makes sense and how
you can actually
integrate that solution in your Tooling
in in order to simplify the way you
actually deliver the data center
interconnect service
then we will go for different data
center uh seamless connection options
with different encapsulation formats uh
some examples of the of the packet walk
involved within the in the seamless DCI
and we'll finish on summarizing uh
what's what's good what's bad about all
these Solutions
so why CMOS data center interconnect we
mentioned about different services like
5G storage replications uh symmetric
storage replications between the regions
Metro replications in the larger cities
that's another use case so deploying
these things only using uh mpls as a
technology sometimes it's not so easy or
has a specific cost right Associated so
that's why uh in the industry we came up
with some of the simplified solutions to
deploy uh faster the DCI solution
so for any uh stitching functions that
we will see later on they are especially
making sense when you deploy EVP and vxi
inside the fabric so means that you have
your Leaf spine super spine or Leaf
spine Leaf three stage IP close Fabric
in the line and then you actually have
to deliver the interconnectivity with
one site or multiple sites right so
obviously in the Enterprise
context quite often it's like two three
sites I visited last well last week one
of this reddish Federal customer they
they're just having like two main data
centers and deploying small original
ones
so
on the other hand in country like
America you typically deploy much more
data center sites for the same service
to replicate the data making sure that
the user gets gets it quicker
so seamless teaching helps whenever you
deploy your data center with a VPN vxlan
then it can actually help you to scale
out
means I deploy two sides but then maybe
my service is growing and then I need to
connect more of these Regional or
smaller Edge data centers and in order
to scale out I need to have a form of
control over how many of these tunnels
I'm going to create when already in my
fabric
I have a pretty decent number of
overlays so with the new stitching
Solutions which are now ratified at the
ITF level in RFC 1914 we have actually a
tooling which helps us to control
that scaling
at the edge of the fabric at the DC
Gateway level or at the Border level so
we'll go through different topologies
architectures where in fact that RFC
1914 is applicable
and that gives you as an outcome easier
architecture extensions whenever we need
to connect another pod in the DC we
would connect that new pod to just a
pair of Border devices instead of
enabling a nice mesh of vxlan tunnels
with all individual devices of the same
data center fabric we'll see that on the
diagrams it's going to be much easier to
actually understand
second point
whenever we build a lan ethernet data
centers using a VPN vxlan we still have
a bit of flooding right it's not that
ethernet is part of the ethernet is
flooding as well so in order to reduce
that flooding between the data center
sites we have a tooling which actually
helps us to either
identify which workloads needs to be
extended and it means that at the border
of the data center I can precisely
Implement my flood flood firewall
filters to control the rate of the
flooding between the data center sites
right instead of having like a full
overlay
which actually goes directly to the leaf
where the server is connected and just
would simply flood that server
immediately right
additional virtualization options that's
another motivation so when we have
different DCS we can actually have some
Acquisitions so there are examples of
service providers they are just buying a
data center provider and they already
have some evpnd external deployments in
that situation we can use the
virtualization options of remapping the
vnis from one site to a common data
center internal dni with that RFC 1914
improved operations it means that
extending uh the the L2 domain from one
side to another is just much more
simplified we don't have to call the the
core IP guys when we are managing the
Lan data center we can do it ourselves
so it's just a simplified way of
delivering end-to-end connectivity
what are the two main use cases so we
talked about the DCI so far and so it
means that we can have large or medium
DC's and then different formats of end
caps you can see here on the slide that
we have the vxlan to vxlan as one of the
stitching option then another one is the
vxlan to mpls and the VXL to srv6 not
yet so much popular but I think this one
is going to be a uh let's say popular in
a couple of years whenever the the Telco
deploys srv6 for the 5G core
and then the second use case is the
multi-pod right so you can have DC
fabric one DC fabric two and then it's
delivered as a pod pod 1.2 then in order
to interconnect these two parts we'll
use the same technology from the RFC
1914 to actually Stitch the tunnels for
the land from the land purposes to get
the uh interconnect tunnels between the
pods
and then last one as an example of
service is uh the server overlay
connectivity so we know that VMware is
also betting on evpn they have the type
routes supported in their solution so
whenever we want to concentrate uh the
connectivity of VMware with the with the
IP fabric we have in the data center
then we can stitch the type 5 tunnels
from the VMware to the to the fabric
itself
these are the main two let's say DCI
plus multi-pod from the architecture
point of view these are the two main use
cases
so I talked about the simplifications
how to simplify the DCI connect so
whenever we have the fabric deployment
you can see here we have one site with
leaves spine and border so let's say
this is site a this is site B and in the
middle we can either have a dark dark
fibers connect or just another level of
super spines and we can simply in this
option one use the L to hand off simple
flood and learn connectivity with a
clear demarcation points that's one of
the option I I just split my domains
from the interconnect to the fabric
using a simple L2 handoff right very
popular whenever you have just two sites
to interconnect not a big deal I can
then use either another domain of VPN
VXL in the middle or just deliver the
evpn and PLS as a as a DCI technology
then the second option is where we have
a an Ott over the top solution we have
let's say two data centers to connect
small number of leave devices in site a
and the site B
and then the leave devices will just get
connected directly via the tunnel once
they signalize all the route types using
the bgp then they got connected together
across the intermediate IP domain
directly so for very small deployments
this is the easiest way of getting a L2
and L3 connectivity between the data
center sites that's why this is really
popular as a solution and then the focus
of the this session is really the option
three right because the option three is
like stitching this line tunnels you
have inside a
to the interconnectivity using still bgp
as the signalization protocol
so we are not changing anything from the
evpn DGP control plane point of view we
are just rewriting some of the control
plane messages to terminate the Lan DCR
DC and originate new tunneling from the
border right so we have that notion of
Border spine border Leaf we'll see that
on the on the diagrams and then we still
stay consistent with the control plane
messages same evi evpn instance for
people that deploy the VPN they know
what I'm talking about but this one is
is really offering a more coherent
solution so we can leverage things like
Mac Mobility for example from one side
to another in case of option one
whenever we actually break the domain
using just an L to hand off then all the
beauty of evpn from that point to this
point at the edge of the fabric is just
disappearing right because it's just a
flood and learn mechanism
in case of this option 3 which on which
we will focus more today we can actually
scale out to higher number of sites we
can limit and unify that scaling at the
uh at the specific Border level
and then we have three other options I
don't want to confuse you more with uh
there could be more options but I
highlighted six of these options so
there's option four where actually you
uh Stitch not to the vxlan but to mpls
so you preserve the same evpn
instance called EDI EDP and instance and
then we stitch from vxlan as a transport
to npls at this level
so that helps whenever you already
deployed mpls in your network to
actually connect quicker your original
data centers
and then we have option five whenever
you don't care about L2 you may have
that situation that people saying I'm
good enough with IP only right
so in this case
you are actually deploying your
ipvpn type of approach using just vxlan
as an as a transport so it means I can
have my ipvpn like
uh Service delivery closer to the server
and then terminate my type 5 instance
tunnels at the border Leaf level similar
to what we've seen for the L2 part and
then Stitch these type 5 channels to the
type 5 interconnect tunnels
at the border to reach the remote site
and then last option option six
where we have a very very simple
scenario we have the prefix
advertisement from the leaf devices to
the borders and then the Border Leaf is
handling all the advertisement to the
ipvpn mpls whenever the Border Leaf is
directly connected to the mpls cloud
so six options will focus on two of
these options uh in the in the next uh
slides I will first start with the type
2 to type two stitching VPN and then for
type 5 to type five type two to type 2
for Mac advertisement for any L2
extensions and then for type 5 it's uh
for the IP prefixes again
if you need to deploy both Services you
can do that if you are good enough with
IP it means the option you would
typically consider is the type 5 to type
5 stitching focusing only on the on the
traffic prefix IP prefixes
advertisements
so this is the example diagram of the
topology just two sides we have fabric a
on the uh for example in one data center
location we have fabric B in another
location either in the same country or
in two different countries and then we
have in the middle an IP core which
actually is delivering just IP
connectivity from a fabric a to fabric B
and the overlays are crossing that that
core IP domain
so in case of the stitching solution we
actually terminate the EVP and vxlan
domain at the border spine level right
and we originate what we call the
interconnect vxlan tunnels
so it means in case of the Border spine
solution I can unify my scaling between
the two data center sites so if I deploy
the smaller site in fabric b and a
larger site in fabric a
my
border spine block will unify that
scaling it means I can
actually unify that number of tunnels
terminated on each of the sides and just
use a same number of uh data center
interconnect channels between the Border
spines
so it means instead of letting this guy
sitting here
to create a an overlay tunnel directly
to my leaf 12 like this which would be
the case of the Ott solution I will
always always point to my local border
devices as next hops right
so again leave device instead of
creating a direct tunnel like this with
all the other guys from the remote
location
the leave device will point to two of
the Border devices as next hops to reach
all the Mac addresses or IP prefixes
from the remote site
so for people who deploy already Fabrics
using a VPN technology obviously there
are all the different uh signalizations
involved in the creation of the tunnels
right first you need to signalize
everything using bgp so we have on this
diagram an example of 32 bits uh ASN
numbers allocated for all the live
devices sitting in each of the data
center site and then we have the ebgp
creation uh establishment between the
spine devices and leave devices and that
same goes for the DCI we have the ebgp
ring with the core IP devices in order
just to have a first underlay
reachability and then the overlay evpn
signalization done
so what happens when I need to stitch
these tunnels the condition is that
my Mach 1 address
will be advertised to the remote
location but I will rewrite the original
ESI value
from the VPN type 2 route I will rewrite
my route Target
and I will obviously use also a
different route distinguisher
in order to actually terminate My Lan
vxlan on the border and then originate a
completely new VXL tunnel to the remote
location
so as you can see all my auto Discovery
routes Mac micro IP uh the the type 3
routes they will have the new actually
capabilities in terms of uh control
plane and that's how we connect to the
remote location based on that EVP and
control Play signalization We originate
new uh data center interpreting tunnels
the good thing is that many many things
is happening actually underneath
so it means there is that built-in bgp
automation which helps us to deliver
that kind of solution
and we can be very specific in terms of
what kind of vlans are extended from
fabric a to fabric B we'll Define that
as an operator we can Define that at the
at the border spine level
so that's for the L2 extensions I need
to talk to Mach 2 from fabric a I need
to talk to uh to mark 2 in fabric B
I can Define either I want to do that or
not if I want I'm defining that at my
specific block architecture so that's
that's really good because we want to
know what's going on in our Fabrics
right from security point of view it's
really important
and the next scenario instead of using
uh
spine devices as borders we have in this
situation a new block called border Leaf
block and in this case it's very similar
to what we've seen so far uh we we still
Stitch the Lan tunnels you can see in
the blue uh to the data center
interconnect Tunnels for the DCI
purposes
okay
and then similarly we have what is
called the interconnect TSI and that
value of 10 bytes is a standardized
value
and actually represents the site
identifier right it means you as the
operator
we are the as operators we can identify
precisely speaking from which actually
location that given Mac address is
coming from
so that interconnect esi2 we can see on
the left hand side
will actually be used as a tooling to
identify whether this map comes from
site a or site b or site C or side d
right we can have more than two sides so
pretty good as a tooling to really know
and understand what's the origin of the
uh of that given workload
so in this example we can see that this
this is just the creation of the tunnels
from one vehicle to another vxlan and if
you read that RFC 1914 then you will
understand that there are other end cap
formats you can use the one I mentioned
at the beginning where actually I
stitched from vxlan to npls it means in
the middle I have my mpls cloud
and obviously in this case
we have other
parameters to to actually fulfill from
the control plane point of view we will
be using for example mpls
label aliasing
which is not for example the case of
vxlan there's no labels in VXL right so
I think in this this room we have the
best representation of mpls Specialists
so in this case we would allocate at the
border leaf uh an mpls label in order to
load balance the traffic to these two
guys sitting in fabric B at the at the
border Leaf level I will use the
technology called the mpls label audio
sync
in case of vxlan it's all based on
overlay ipcmp I will use my destination
interconnect ESI which I allocate for
the given data center site I will do the
active active forward into these two
guys sitting in the fabric B in order to
reach the MAC address sitting a in
fabric B connected to the leaf device
so I talked about the scenario where you
don't you may not need a L2 extension
you may have that situation right you
you are deploying a new network
my L2 I just need my L2 in the fabric
between the Fabrics I'm happy doing just
prefix advertisements
everything is IP based what I still want
to deliver some level of virtualization
so I'm deploying my ipverse as a way to
virtualize my uh my network so in this
case we can use the type 5 for ipverf to
ipverf model and get also the similar
connectivity between the sites by
terminating type 5 channels at the
border leaf and then originating a new
set of type 5 tunnels to the remote
location
so obviously there are some changes in
terms of a control plane
in case of type 5 VPN we are not using
the concept of ESI when we use the pure
pure type 5 ipversal IP verb interface
less model in this case we will load
balance using uh just overlay ipcmp
however for the site identification in
this case there is a new bgp attribute
so we have in this room probably the
best concentration of bgp experts as
well
uh so there is a new bgp attribute I
will also talk about for that particular
use case where we identify the given
site
with not only the ESI for L2 purposes
but with the new bgp attribute called
The Domain path d-pass
I'll show you that later on
So speaking about uh seamless tunnel
stitching we can have more complex
designs in this case where actually for
some of the federal deployments we need
to make sure that some data stays in the
given location it's like per contract
that you don't move data
or you're allowed to move the data from
one location to very specific remote
location as per contract if it's not
respected you are breaking the law in
the country right so in this case we can
use the technology of uh tunnel
stitching at Mac verb level isolation to
make sure that the data gets replicated
to the right data center location
so in this case you can see that the
stitching technology is delivered at the
common border block for two different
pods and only the magverf AC goes down
to the data center site C
and then only marked worth a b stitching
goes to the data center side B so it
means with that technology you get an
opportunity to really control where your
your data is saved or replicated right
very important right this is not just
the imagination of the vendors this is
per requirements of the of the legal
let's say requirements
so mcverf is nothing more than the
definition of evpn instance so you know
uh that we have in the case of VPN
different type of acronyms that
sometimes means the same thing it's
nothing more than EVP and instance the
backwards right
okay so a few words about the
implementation part
so in case of implementation uh we we
add oops sorry
in case of implementation we have a new
dedicated block where we Define in fact
how these uh extension will really look
like so we can simply bring the
definition of the site
with that interconnect ESI that's going
to be our site identifier
so some more significant numbers can be
used for example just to say this is
site one the other one is site B so uh
because it's uh it's a 10 byte value so
we can define a lot of these sites and
then whenever we have to be very
prescriptive in terms of the definition
of the vnis we will Define which
workloads really are extended to the
remote location
so the new routes targets same thing we
actually Define besides the land
specific route targets we will Define
the the data center interpret Network
targets to have a common understanding
between different locations
and then another example whenever we
don't want to do L2
we just want to uh actually manage IP
prefix reachability in this case we have
that new dedicated block
as an example of how to introduce the
interconnectivity for IP purposes only
for data center interconnect
so if we remember the diagrams we've
seen so far right
um
this one where actually prefixes are
originated here
they go down up to the Border
and that's at the border Leaf level
where I will Define that block
right at the edge of the fabric
so from the verification point of view I
mentioned that we can uh use the site
identifier as a way to trace the origin
of the of the MacBook addresses so in
this case we have for example all the
Mac addresses I learned here they are
coming from specific site
and in journals I can precisely actually
uh
specify either I'm searching for Mac
addresses from remote locations or uh oh
I'm I'm care about is uh well the
definition of the Mac addresses that are
local to the fabric
and then from tunnel perspective
we have a specific Flags
which will tell us either
I have my uh reachability for the one
connectivity the DCI connectivity or to
the fabric right
so we can see that that's another flag
that we added in order to distinguish
between a different type of vxlan
tunnels right
so in this room is anybody deploying a
VPN or
did okay I see some hands good
so uh
so that's that's something we actually
uh do because uh obviously there are
some devices which can
have 1000 tunnels the excellent tunnels
on the box but it's not just about
scaling scaling is one of the part of of
the story but it's also that operational
aspect right I am the admin of the
fabric
even if I can support 1000 tunnels on
the box managing 1000 tunnels knowing
where they go is Pretty Tough huh when
it's one thousand two thousand tunnels
even if I can scale on the box
if I check my logical interfaces
associated with the vdaps having two
thousand of those on the box is pretty
big right whenever you deployed it on
multiple sites
so just to sum up the two differences
between a couple of differences between
the stitching options for L2 versus L3
Mac versus IP
so we have a stitching of type 5 we
don't create any logical interfaces it
means everything is based on the rewrite
of the next hops right I don't have to
actually care about how many of my
logical interfaces I created at my
border leave devices everything is
handled at the next hop level
ESI concept specific to the L2
connectivity it means I will do my load
balancing to my destination ESI in case
of L2 not the case of type 5evpn
configs we've seen that for L2 purposes
I will handle my configuration in side
my Mac Verve inside my EDI and whenever
I'm deploying just prefix advertisement
in this case I will just use my ipverse
in terms of implementation
and the last point we already talked
about that load balancing is in case of
type 5 instances done using ipcmp
so I already mentioned that uh for all
the data center interconnect Solutions
we have a new attribute which is
emerging in the industry and it's called
the d-puff d stands for domain path
and actually is uh
something that uh probably in the coming
couple of years we will identify other
use cases for that attribute but mainly
was uh was defined for the data center
interconnect purposes
so just as a problem statement so we
have this topology again very similar
topology we've seen so far so whenever
there are prefixes advertisement from
one side
to the remote site we may have a
situation where because everything is
based on ebgp that the remote location
will rewrite the us as path right
the as path will be Rewritten at the
edge
and we will get the same prefix we
advertise to the remote location
we will actually get it back
from the remote location and accept it
so the Border will become quite confused
on either go through the remote data
center to get back to prefix one
or uh
as an admin you understand every single
prefix you have to manage and you apply
a lot of Route Maps a lot of policy
statements to manage your routing Loop
situation right so in order to simplify
the way actually you control the origin
of the IP prefixes or evpn longit
prefixes
uh the industry or the community came up
with the new bgp attribute which by
default will block the prefixes with the
domain path domain ID
in the list of domain IDs if we see our
own domain ID we'll drop that control
plane advertisement so we have a loop
prevention mechanism by default
integrated
into the into the solution so if we come
back to that diagram it's pretty it's a
little bit bigger so we have two domains
domain one domain three and it means
whenever I get back at Graphics from uh
site B with my local domain one in the
list
I will just drop that control plane
right
and always prefer my my local one from
the reachability point of view
and of course if we want to use that
domain path as a way to identify sites
it's also another mechanism to do that
right
so what's it's pretty cool as a solution
it's applicable for IP prefix
advertisement as well as for evpn Mac
advertisement right so we get a specific
bgp attribute it was mentioned that it's
alert learning is part of the objectives
of nanog so for people uh who didn't
know there is a new bgp attribute now
you can talk about
okay summary notes right so uh seamless
tunnel stitching summary notes means we
have a solution which gives us an
opportunity to create a DCI Services
um break the domains the overlays
domains in multiple places in order to
scale out
we reduce the load
play control plane uh because we we
simply uh
uh instead of accepting all the remote
location adpn routes we are just
actually considering the DCI for any
remote location so we reduce the rib
size and the Fib size thanks to that
solution
improve the DC and DCI control overlay
domain creation we've seen the debuff as
a way to do that
simplify day-to-day operations
we can have the pre-established evpn
tunneling between the site and then
whenever I need to connect a new Leaf in
the fabric it's going to be hooked up to
the
to the spines only instead of getting a
new Leaf device and originate an
avalanche of the extern tunnels it will
just connect to my local border devices
and be already directly connected to the
remote location
normalized scale again if you remember
the diagram we could use border devices
as a block where we normalize the
scaling between the sites
and then additional Point quite
interesting
that whenever we terminate these tunnels
On the Border we can add more security
into the fabric right
so I said that data
storing the data in the OR delivering
data storage is very important also from
the reliability and the security point
of view to make sure that we get the
data from the right origin
and so whenever we deploy the stitching
we can actually get additional L4 L7
inspections on the interconnectivity vni
instead of just running an overlay
directly to the remote location I can
terminate my VX stand on the border and
then put it directly into the l47
inspections right very important
same goes for uh the group based policy
so people who deploy it in the room
already VPN vxlan you know that there is
that additional field in the vxlan which
can deliver which which can get you the
opportunity to deliver micro
segmentation
so in this case with the DCI we can
also leverage the group based policy IDs
between the data center site and respect
the uh the segmentation level from the
one fabric to another fabric
so one of the emerging part in in case
of the group based policy in the DCI
context is to actually advertise the
group based policy ID as an additional
bgp community
so don't be surprised if you see that in
some of the ITF Publications
and then flood rate control that's
another aspect I terminate my VX funds
on the on the border
and I can Implement my uh flood rate
control at the border before allowing
any traffic from remote location let's
say I have an attack right adidos attack
coming from from the one I can block it
before it goes directly to the server
so I can put in place by DDOS policies
at the edge of the fabric to protect my
servers with that solution as well
and that's that's all I have for today
five minutes for any questions I know
that you some of you deployed a VPN so
even if it's not DCI related I'll be
more than happy to to get some questions
from you guys
we have still five minutes
any questions
maybe from juniper
no
so for Blake Lewis
authorized traffic ingestion
uh into the VPN are you aware of vxlan
implementations that offer similar
protections
now on vxlan we don't have that today
uh so what's a good question thanks for
it uh so on on vx1 the only thing we we
can do uh is uh to actually inspect the
tunnel in transit on the firewall
so means you have your uh
routing vni that goes across the
firewall and then all of this is
inspected at the firewall level for
advanced policing
that's what we have
any other questions from
people in the room
please
thanks for the talk we know it's from
kisai any thoughts on what's the best uh
overlay interconnect for you know best
man bandwidth or latency considerations
or outage for example we have had
multiple these data centers which have
been you know locked by outages so any
considerations that service providers
need to take or Cloud providers to take
which overlaid technology to choose when
system is doing well or you know when
detecting outages and bringing sites
back up
thanks for the question so uh for the
outages detections there are uh
standards for oam also for vxlan and
another one to detect quicker the
bi-directional state of the tunnels of
the overlays is to actually get a BFD
inside the vx1 tunnel that's another
much more simplified than oam so there
is actually a fully standard RFC on this
that you are running your BFD inside the
VXL tunnel to get a bi-directional
communication check
that would be one of the solution
the second question came in can you any
cast a Gateway across borders
and within but with cross-borders
I didn't get the final part any cast
anycast okay a gateway across borders
within the within a border no problem
right but across borders okay across the
sides yes yeah so for any cost uh
obviously if you remember the diagrams I
was showing so we have that distributed
anycast IP Gateway on the leave devices
uh in case of the DCI Solutions
obviously in this case we advertise the
the Mac IP actually to the remote
locations right so uh the
the local proxy ARP state is maintained
in all of these Solutions right
so that doesn't change from what you
have in the fabric still you will
continue to advertise your Mac Mac IP to
the remote location if you extend the
the L2 context to the remote location
otherwise if you don't extend it stays
within the fabric only
was that the the question
now in this case you can either stay
with your evpn VX on L2 in the fabric or
if you extend it you still preserve the
same approach of getting a anycast
gateways in one location and the other
location right some say same any case
Gateway would be replicated in the
remote location
so it means in consequence it means you
still have to do all the control plane
rewrites at the at the edge of the
fabric right for the Mac IP
yeah
any other questions
no questions okay so I hope you enjoyed
this session please I will be around uh
roaming uh in this location and uh we
can get either coffee or beer in French
English or polish which language you
prefer so I'll be more than happy to to
hang out with you guys thanks again
[Applause]
[Music]