right so we've survived another year did
everyone have fun again yeah brilliant I
am start with asking for feedback all
the cons do it and it's really important
we want to know what you liked what you
didn't like what you want to see you
next year and yes all the negative stuff
will probably hurt our feelings for a
little while but it will make it better
next year so please tell us what your
light tells what you didn't like we have
plans for next year so it will
definitely be happening and we need to
know what you want us to do another
thank you to all our sponsors again
without them today could not have
happened so yeah hopefully visited the
booths that were there you look at the
websites for a room if you need services
from them later on and how long I forgot
to mention earlier Hallam if you don't
know runs a security course as part of
the commuting Parliament honors and
master's degrees so if you want to to
get into security that's one option and
yeah I sport earth supporter yeah we are
looking for sponsors for next year
boogie marketing teams when we started
asking companies this year I think we
started a bit late and budgets had
already been used up so the sooner we
get in there the better so we're going
to be asking if you can ask your
marketing teams if you enjoyed the corn
the more sponsors we have the better we
can make it party understood earlier
doors open about 6 30 or whatever jessen
freaky finish foods going to be from
about seven ideally your caps to get in
but if you've not going to count for any
reason we do have some last year's
wristbands just come find me or kneel at
the door and we'll give you a wristband
make sure you get in just about any kids
that are left they are loading I think
it is just around the corner with it
although the edl stuffers gone away and
it's fairly clear out there now so many
prob
quasar tomorrow when i looked at the
sheet last time with about 18 people
signed up on first game nor beyond the
second game so if you want to get signed
up still plenty of places you can get
yourself out of bed for a 1030 game it
was really fun last year bookstore we
only had two books left so yeah if you
want one of the last to take it I'd
rather not have to look them home and
was quite a lot of money in the
collection tin most of the crew Sims
last year green t-shirts of doing an
amazing job I've done very little in
terms of sort of helping out on the day
the crew have done a great job chris has
been running around getting old photos
caluque and Andrew from the unique I've
done all sorts of video and I'm Tom
Cooper as i was done a lot with it as
well i forgot to put his name i'm sorry
yeah the videos we're going to get
processed and sorted as quick as we can
and get them online I've dunno how long
it will take I can't promise anything
but we will get this past weekend Jamie
helping out with the speakers Luke and
Donna official crew there from the mud
Bob so the not official crew but there
there is good house now we've just spent
the whole day teach people a lot pick
anybody learned a lot pick for the first
time yeah good few people so it's not as
hard as you think when you start to get
into it just get quite addictive again
we've got ideas for that next year we're
going to expand it maybe have some
workshops and do a bit more with it a
bit more advanced skills if you want it
I've already said the day crew comes
realized I've lost the slide yeah I've
lost slide Neil for thanks to neil for
organizing all the University side of it
yeah we couldn't have got the venue
would ever do sorta doesn't do it Mike
for working on all sponsors so yeah
without in Gary one side the sponsor one
side them on it one more call for
feedback and i'll be tweeting this link
out so don't worry if you forget it
and that's it thank you all see you next
year and ya thang