Oh welcome to the end of still come 2018
so everybody enjoyed it yeah a good yeah
Guam we've got some stuff to give away
just be ready to catch are we gonna work
oh ho all right everybody just ignore if
I'm the important well I am the
important one look at me not him
I've got the talking kind of microphone
[Applause]
Yeah right we're going to say thank you
to all the sponsors socially the start
MWR
main sponsor give us a loss of money to
be here today yay thank you
Netta toot who will be keeping you happy
this evening please pave the party
[Applause]
security security security look good
order status net that covered the food
and the lunch and the breakfast and all
that stuff and of course how I'm thank
you very much for the venue if you're
interested there courses go talk to them
right thank you to the crew me Mike Neil
[Applause]
it takes about four or five months to
put all this together but then on the
day we tend to just hand it over to the
crew I mean they really on the day yeah
we did the real bit of firefighting but
they look after everything
so yeah big thanks to all the crew and
all these t-shirts kids crew our our
crew a whole lot speakers the speakers
who come in today the workshop people
yesterday they give up their time for
free we don't we're not able yet to
cover travel costs or a combination
anything like that so they come in they
do that yeah you will stick you in
something next year will be very nice
we're sticking some up
mr. Scott thank you for doing your
sticker style again this year and the
crew helps out on it we'll come back to
that in a few minutes for how much you
raised but putting a lot of effort and
also the the vendors that send us all of
the amazing swag we had millions of
stickers he'll talk about it later but
sticker stickers from all around the
world it's Christmas Cooper where is he
he's there thank you to Cooper this guy
drives flies whatever all around the
world to record videos he doesn't make a
penny out of it he is just the a/v god
as it says on his shirt it's an amazing
job how many a thing yeah videos are up
online now how much 10 10 to the 3rd
yeah most the socks are off they will be
up the rest will be up pretty soon yeah
let's get Barisan
Oh Cooper's also asked me to say thank
you to Gemma and Ross there the Uni AV
guys they've helped us out today up in
the booth at the back gives a wave and
also I forgot to put him on the slide
but thank you to Chris for doing all the
photos there will be a gallery up at
some point at some point I've got a few
things to give away now we had there was
a pole for the the best speaker the
special speaker award Gilley where are
you career
the pole was only one person doing the
pole but he is one
here's got the seat your back
[Applause]
he's got the CH books and the folk this
book with the man on the cover there you
go
[Applause]
charity to bring the by stall and the
stickers stickers raise 40 a 11 hundred
quid bring a by 133
we've also I kind of if I put a slide if
it's not we've also sold the st and the
amiga hoping that the people put
legitimate bids down so they've raised
about 200 quid for those as well so
that'll be adding on to the total once
we've claimed it in Scott do do your
stuff
press the button on the bottom anyway
right we're going to do the raffle draw
so if you hear your number out we've got
18 of them here Robin I will pass you
the ticket and if you just come down and
get it now I'm independent come down
quick otherwise we will keep drawing 861
go move 893
[Music]
[Applause]
935 how many of these do I have to do
anyway I hope you like number two it's
2-2 to 566 the neighbor of five six
there we go
873 come on 873 500 that is the biggest
rally for marathon next week 486 next
[Laughter]
852 a round of applause for Wes who made
the single largest donation on the
sticker stand today please 311 we've got
235 for the social engineers on the road
it's down to 200 says how many tickets
we sold pretty good 498 please be in the
back
Robin makes the exercise 498 499 and
it's going to 198 still nothing Wow
early people went home early 918 in the
back that's bad
[Laughter]
[Applause]
528 please be in the front in the front
is it another one that is for left to go
709 quicker cover get it seven runner is
here to win Rome eight 728 going once
going twice gone 199 876 the three of
them the three of us we just keep 726
come on 585
793 good man steak stay put stay there
how many more one more
wah 724 nobody 238 there we go
no stay put stay we know that we don't
finish where's your cape
snipers alley Sam where are you hiding
Sam up here alright snipers alley you
were shooting at the put ones the table
you're really at the shoot at the Gong's
and the cops and stuff don't think
anybody got a perfect round so nobody
got all the gongs all the cups but the
winner Dean are you in here yes there
you can eat that
[Applause]
I've trained you well you also get to
keep any doubts that you can find laying
around
somebody else has acquired a child now
sit next to where of your fancy kids
track Sonya you want to call for sensing
about the kids track no we don't be able
to shut her up all day and now she
doesn't say anything
go on that's mad young children behave
adults behave you two behave yeah thank
you very much for anybody helped out
with the kids track today it's brilliant
ears have been utterly awesome and very
dependable and really thank you to all
the grown-ups for actually collecting
their children at the end and of course
did you know that three of the kids on
Kidz track may have won challenges today
on adults challenges down in the atrium
keep an eye on at Tanya and the kids
crew put a lot of effort in today I
nipped up there a couple of times to see
what was going on and there was a lot of
destruction and a lot of learning a lot
of all sorts of things up there it was
brilliant when Mike see if we got some
adults into that kind of thing next year
we'll see we'll see working progress
right
Pippa's logic challenge I apologize I
cocked up the link earlier on turns out
my tinyurl equivalent doesn't lie
underscores but like we had four or five
entries five entries will pull the
winner out of the hat right to the Bukit
go and read the name
Bethenny's fascinate come up right sugar
hum okay
nothing to buy you've got a choice you
can either take game developer Barbie
I've got it right this time or we've got
a 25 quid PI Maroni voucher I thought
you might
I will send it on to you I've got your
mom's email address stuff I'll pass that
on okay well done the results will be up
on the site later if anybody does want
to play off any of the kids who didn't
look at it I'll put the results up or
the the answers I should say party as I
said at the starts doors will open when
we're out of here roughly on time at the
moment so by 6:45 it's a nice buffet
that we're putting on we're gonna do
some PowerPoint karaoke mention it's a
couple of parents it there's a couple of
slides in there that are definitely 18
plus most of it should be okay but a
couple of bits are a bit dodgy blend
do not let your kids anywhere near
PowerPoint karaoke thank you
so says the compliance man
dual core I have seen him is in the
building or was in the building
somewhere he's gonna be on from about
nine so I'm checking from a bit before
you'll need to budget stick it in once
you get down there we will be issuing
beer tokens but we'll do it once you're
down there and you'll find out how later
kids obviously are allowed in but no
booze but we can see it's yeah your
parents responsibility you're the one
that's going to spend the night with
them or the morning and the bathroom and
whatever party if you've not been there
before got out of the main atrium via
left via right look for the big metal
building or big building with metal roof
you can't really miss it that's what it
looks like yeah the funny money said all
this at start and I corrected it what
one Lille will get you a drink
would is worth to Neils I'm worth for
Neil's perrolli quiz that tomorrow
morning I've no idea what a sign-up
sheet went but there is a sign-up sheet
people put the names down and the worst
space is left last time I looked I'll be
walking off from novotel about half 9:00
or so so finally then walk over that's
the address if you get really stuck
lunch is after 8:00 the results so
Sheffield's got a big outdoor festival
on this weekend with thing called
cliffhanger which is kind of the british
bouldering championships for climbing so
if you don't want to come to the pete
sir and the quasar i'd recommend if you
like any kind of outdoor sports get into
the city centre those all sorts of
mountain biking there was if mining last
year there was yeah you name it it's
there so it's worth a walk round before
you go and get your trains or your
motorway home and like sweat out so we
got to do
Chris he's that yours I had this for
about a year as finally managed to give
him back a couple of conferences ago and
he's left it again
did you bring name today in which case
we've had that for about two years
yeah right at this point I think we've
delivered some we kill the live stream
for a minute please
at the back we kill a live stream yeah
we've got thumbs up right as I said it
starts about Mike plucky monkey what
we've done is we've got a con teachers
anybody who knows him if you want to
come and find us in the bar afterwards
or sort of now as we're packing up we
want to write a message on it to him
we're gonna send him a big care package
so we've got all the conference swag
from this year last few years all sorts
of all the goodies that that is going to
get I think you'll appreciate it but if
you want to stick your name on the
t-shirts and writing a message go find
Mike or myself later on and you can get
the t-shirts
hopefully nobody Nicks the the sharpies
so we can carry on writing anything else
you want to add for that no have I
missed anything did we win we won
apparently
I think it was it's tennis sure oh yeah
you put livestream back on now if you
want to but we're both done yeah
whatever
right enjoy the part oh yes well I think
we will send out a survey questionnaire
what you enjoy what you didn't like all
that kind of stuff when you finally get
Rhodes writing it it's that walkabout
if you fill it in like all the
confidence you say will really
appreciate the results because then we
can pass on demographics based on GDP
are whatever we can pass on basic status
statistics through to the sponsors and
hopefully sponsors will come back next
year and do it so enjoy the party see
you all next year
[Applause]