so i'm here to present some software
that have been working for as part of a
different project i'm working on with
silencing so they have to do with mobile
forensics as anyone you ee-oh by in
forensics I so I would like to apologize
because I mean slow at the start of
every talk might take a few moments to
pick it up so what we're going to talk
today is so just more or less what I
mobile forensics or rather constraints
that everyone has stabbed mobile
forensics has come across some common
grounds in different devices different
operating systems that you have when we
doing the forensics and how could we go
by achieving some form of automation on
the lease in values forensic scenarios
and operating systems we're going to
have a demo on a piece of software that
we've been working on that tries that
tends to do this automation for you so
finished yet but hopefully by the end of
this month we have an open source
release of that true we will also see
some other software I've developed the
CSM correct position software and memory
process down there which all of them are
going to be part of the final release of
the software these ones should be
released by the end of this next week
like so more or less mobile forensics
you doing forensics but mobile devices
you have different operating syst
so basically what this organ Clues
mobile devices themselves the systems
that they've interacted with and mainly
systems that acquire the backups for
those devices communicate with those
devices and so on and any other
peripheral devices such as removable
storage sim cards anything else are
connected by so when moving east into
these talks that's really changing so
nowadays mobile devices are smartphones
are full-blown operating systems the
same themselves they done on the area in
platform if caught the Android one is a
full-blown New York system you can do
pretty much whatever you can do on a
Linux system on them the other ways
Lorelai's is a unix-like system if you
did enough people so they're easily
programmable through a number of
interfaces the frameworks that they
provide they repealed with the defense
in mind which makes it harder for you to
Luna forensic analysis they have a bunch
of lockdowns keys and crimson staff
hardware and software and picture makes
it a bit more complex fire fire before
anything artifacts I want to extract
evidence from and so on so what I'm
issues with this mobile devices what
were the issues with mobile forensics
the biggest issue is that this world the
smartphone world constantly evolves from
one year to the next in a few the next
few years are going to come we would see
constant updates every couple of months
new features if
more applications and so on so in this
kind of environment of constant change
is very hard to maintain capability I
went to the forensics the mobile
forensics if something changes
constantly it's hard to do to know that
have a fixed process to in forensics on
those devices if put some clothes and
regulations changing some of them are
trying to force mobile devices to change
the way they're doing things we have
corporate driven changes for example
they've been some hiccups about the
hardware and software and flip shoulders
in provided on most devices so you have
different operating system different
file systems in use of the devices
different applications different
peripherals and all these many things
that make it hard for you to do the
forensic analysis then you have the
constant updates and changes like we
said so how do you achieve animation in
this constantly changing environment
what you can do one thing that you could
do you cannot actually help hold
everything so based on the current state
of the address of an Android device or
on iOS device and hard code all fixed
locations that are can acquire
information from that's most that's what
most commercial entities have been doing
but nowadays in trying to change things
and make them or generate the program at
Leeds is that every time something
changes you need to give up those
changes need to write some more code and
in the end you're going to end up with a
huge application more or less supports
or the legacy
stuff but it's hard for you to keep up
with a new stuff and so if you're doing
it yourself you would have to sacrifice
your personal life and then maybe not
money whenever new operating system
update comes up for a different I think
for the application and so on so if you
want to reduce the load in eating
something framework that could support
these things you know to find the common
ground between applications between
operating system existence between how
everything works or advice because to be
honest mobile devices the same thing
over and over again just a few things
changing on the top they all run on an
alien platform they all have some sort
of a framework which is using on open
source systems like SQLite or what's an
angry anyway open source systems
basically they all have more or less the
applications across platform
applications for example different
applications that are built for both
devices they use more or less a fixed
they have a fixed structure and we use
fixed there are tips features in which
are common between different versions
you can also plan for change so you can
accommodate change in this framework to
make it easier to implement updates so
when something gets updated but a new
version of an application comes having
something changes you have to be able
with lead for level effort to
accommodate that change so more or less
you're not the lower level like you said
that
were in the platform which is a ra on
Android we have x FS filesystem the
newer versions anyway the f-18 for the
SD cards we have been a Jeff sx4 the iOS
system which is the upholds proprietary
file system of course the most common
thing is the third a storage which is on
both devices and using SQLite databases
so this is one common thing that they
have which we can use to generalize
differencing acquisition process you've
got the configuration files or Android
are mainly in XML mean I always more or
less than XML themselves just a
different format that can be converted
to excellent and then you've got the
applications on top that ran on java
game for android and iOS objective-c
which is more or less naming cold as
well so like we said we've could be
SQLite databases both these operating
systems use a central storage unit
provide information such as SMS call
logs calendar tasks and so on if God a
system configuration stored in the XML
most of their own XML files and some of
their own or key value files so we've
got more common denominators between
those these two operating systems that
we thought that we thought and when you
talk about cross-platform applications
and frameworks that support these things
or for example Facebook a facebook
application or any other major
application of these devices the exactly
same application same way the award same
data bases so you've got more common
things on these devices that you can
people so having that you might you can
build some sort of a layered system that
can do the extraction for you I can
automate the process between different
techniques that you have on different
devices and come up with there's also a
top so for example different file system
so we can have something that
understands the file system itself
device system structure so which files
in which folder where I can find
configuration files or where I can find
the storage for the devices SMS messages
the application part said that knows how
to go in there and extract information
from applications of an iOS and on
Android you will know that look facebook
is using this database file in this hard
on Android in this part of my ways to
store information for example chat
messages and he has the same exact
structure the same tables same contents
same schema of the database maybe the
names might change but always the Shema
remains the same configuration so this
is the most volatile piece that you can
find
it's completely different between
different operating systems but still
you can have one layer at a specific
point that says look if I want to see
which devices which bluetooth devices
these devices associated with mobile
operating systems have that
configuration file so the information is
the same I want to see their devices i
want to see Wi-Fi connected networks so
the information is the same is justifies
low interchange so if you know where to
find the files you can parse the entire
thing into a higher level and make it
under standard and put it in a cuddle so
the color of the top would contain this
information you would categorize
Information Network Information
application formation where else we have
configurations of the device and so on
based on that and based on their rules
yet that might specify in these
different layers you can come at the end
after you do all the parsing or the
translations and yes it can build a
timeline it should make your life with
forensic analysis or mobile devices much
much much more easier so more or less
the system that we are building has
piece architecture so we have at the
moment we're accommodating Android and
iOS mostly under heat but iOS is coming
up soon so we have they're not the lower
level layers that can handle the file
system of devices they can do the device
extraction themselves
can't dance of the file system they can
go they can dig into that physis and in
st. Luke this is a location where
applications are stored this is a
location where the wireless
configuration settings are stored you
also have the backup has seven
extractors they can pull the backups
from the devices and start in the
analysis on top with slightly different
settings then on top of that you have
the application configuration process
the application person purely knows how
each application works and how it can
pass it what known entries I have for
this specific application for example
Facebook what's up the Android Browser
the Safari browser on iOS so on and the
configurational person understands where
the operating system has all the
configuration settings and such and on
top of that avocado the color is just a
generic way of presenting information so
I have information about the device imei
or PM for example the market rest of the
Wi-Fi interface or Bluetooth interface
and so on you've got some settings of
the device the applications which get
past
the networking information that might
have and so on so how can you
accommodate change in this specific
architecture it's simple you eat modules
you have a module for that application a
module for a different application now
we're module for a configuration
settings of Android you stay on your
version on them as well so when the
Virgin changes you know that nothing
might have changed I've got a new emoji
for that specific thing so you can
define the location of the configuration
files you can define which catalog that
specific thing goes in you can define
the parts to known fields for example
have an XML file that contains
information I want to pull out that
device so I'm saying this XML file that
specific path contains in this expert in
this XML path that information which is
let's say a string which contains the
mac address of the wireless interface or
it contains that why the Wi-Fi networks
that this device was corrected then you
put the applications same thing
applications have for the help files
random images data files and databases
so you know for example that the words
of application has a database in there
that's called a mistaken main main not
TB which is an SQLite database which has
these tables and in that specific table
have a field called date which I have to
translate into let's say a unix
timestamp because it's different and
then that table as the mess
were sent from that were exchanged using
this application and then from there go
up lanius we extract that information
and we have to get a meaningful way
right so an example of this
configuration files
so this is an example so we've built the
application in such a way that it could
accommodate custom configuration changes
and ways to define what you need and if
this example here is the core android
browser application what the higher
level stuff too they can identify that
that specific application so they can
identify the location of that specific
application and from that point they go
into this configuration file here and
they say look which are the known files
that I have and for example it's a
browser to not db5 so when I pass when I
when I reach the point when I pass this
file what I'm doing is I'm looking at
this configuration and in here it says I
have a known table called history so
there's a table in this file called
history which has a field named date
which is in
it's in WebKit time stamp which I would
have to convert into a unix timestamp so
if you did accommodate changing stuff on
each field and then from there I'm just
saying just telling the program that if
you've got a point to parse this field
parsi as a date so I know that we've
done that amazing that application in
that table are a field that is a date
field and from there we can build up and
come up with a timeline because we
already know there is a date filter so
we'll release how these things are you
can build these rules it's quite simple
actually but hopefully we think that
with putting anything everything that we
need to make these definitions actually
alright so if you don't have this fizzy
we come across an unknown application
still works so it's still automatically
processed the databases the
configuration files but it doesn't know
that that specific field set date so if
you not do need timeline generation if
it doesn't look like that piece of
information is a day but you can extract
the database and you can do it yourself
and hopefully when we release it we're
going to have a nice right clip art from
that you can do it that you can say this
is a date for example it would handle
money
so you can also specify SQL pods I can
get executed so you can pass the table
in a backpack for month so the idea is
that for each occasion you just write
small pieces of information that you
want to pass and add them just drop the
file inside the android apps folder and
automatically adds it in processing
itself
and for the configuration files for
example so we've got a configuration
file name wpa supplicant taught corn an
android device which contains
information about the usage of Wi-Fi
networks in this case the directory of
this file is nice Wi-Fi and then the
user data partition which we're not
going to get into at the moment and in
there what we can do we can specify
regular so this is this a regular
expression configuration file so you
write your rules to parse fi in regex
formula which is exact yes so what it's
saying here is that so is a catalog
network you filed as a title known
thighs connected networks here and I
have a container in there so network
so if quantify their I will have to warn
you this is done that I've been from my
own device to ourself also hopefully
nothing we it is in there so this is a
configuration file so when I said I had
a container is this one this thing here
so basically this thing here so you've
got many of these entries specified the
network's I can correct them this is
marcus information acting food from
where there are all the networks
connected to hear they are all in cyprus
so 15 the UK
or information all right so this is it
this is the file that this emoji for
that specific file and here I'm saying
that I have a container in there that
has specific values and I'm saying that
the SSID was in divided you in there is
the network's name then the access point
others and security time and the husband
and the pilot those things get past so I
just covina phi inside for them despite
and it gets parsed automatica so it
extracts that information information to
beautify and same goes for any other
kind of files this directly so this is
harsanyi i haven't completed yet e
entire configuration file on how to
extract Wi-Fi information from android
devices another example will be blue to
information which is a xml file
which contains information about the Oak
adapter and end devices
and also contains any keys or any pins
that have used to associate to pair with
those devices so so this is the xml file
and this is a configuration on how to
pass that XML file which is basically an
ex parte stream which tells the
application how to find that specific
entry pull the information and in that
entry have for example the device
hardware address and so on so these are
the configuration files relatively easy
to write so these are the modules the
application that relatively easy to
write so you don't have to rewrite the
entire thing all over again so you have
to do when something new comes up you
just change the virtual top and then
putting the changes in the application
automatically parsing fully
now we've talked about timeline
generation to save you the hassle it's
not done yet but the idea on how to do
it is designed it but we have to do some
more eggs according it would be done but
more or less bases itself on those
modules of the modules that we write
configure how we pass information so
based on that we have most definitions
you know where everything is and Baeza
we have for example we're building a
timeline so we know we need the date
fields so paper based on you know
whether the date fields are and maybe so
we have the categories of the files
probably information this bluetooth is
Wi-Fi is something else is SMS we can
also up maybe in some other version
accommodate like icons and colors for
different things and we can take all
that information put it in a bit hi to
some analytics on top of them and come
up with something like this so a
timeline of events of that specific
mobile device this example here for
example you put an incoming call
contacts name duration of the court date
and time and then the contacts to DB
file was modified because it maintains
this information in there and then you
have for example an incoming SMS in the
message what if occasionally SMS s5 then
access on a website so will be the
timeline so we can extract what happened
in this scenario in this incident
so what we have so far
the idea is to come up something
with some things that works on this
rusted pipe and on top of these we can
also put a touch screen
have a nice plastic part on top of those
then you can take these devices oh when
the incident take place only two it will
be doing so basically you won't even
have to take or less the device back to
the office or in your lab you take this
you go there to plug in the phone you
touch something on the website i'm just
going to show you and extract
information stored on the USB or
something and go back to the lab hook
this up on the network and then access
and do the information parsing and so on
i was going to do it there one piece
father and a half time to set it up so
all I can we show you the device or less
anybody can have any extra things like a
sim card reader you can plug it in and
do extra extra extra information now
so this is he the application at we
ability so this application is running
on tight phone on a framework called
cherry pie so the idea is is to have a
last very tight running on a chain time
then running this application which we
don't know what we call it yet we might
go for a pee so the beyond them they be
on a cherry on a pie or listen so you
can do with this itself so the idea will
have does allow him to view it in
smaller screens with SIA good start
framework so you can leave device
extraction the sim card extraction and
then from there you can go and you can
create the cases and Tommy case aside
walk officer
so the thing is we do the device
extraction we wouldn't have to do these
things these parts here for for this
demo 1 i'm going to do I've mounted the
logical image of you uses data partition
where in stored under / mount / so we're
going to do the just the application
extraction so i'm specifying to his
application look of the users partition
mounting that location in going to be an
analysis on the specific for them Oh
things starts fussing the information
what we have like I said this is from my
device so right so it's finished so we
get you get the interface here device
info so this is your catalog more or
less I will extract that for now you
just have the apps more or less working
at the moment so we have the
applications have been installed the
date that they were installed this is it
red because it doesn't use information
stored on the device to determine the
date it is uses metadate healthy for
them looks like the information but if
you specify you so basically if the
final release which is read the
configuration file of the device
tell you this application was installed
at that time so we go into the
application what it does it lists all
the files and folders of the application
instead of ala kulli the module a
reserve our supplemental information
that we have about this application if
we click on a file it will tell we give
us signature type of the file size back
x user ID mode and so on from there you
can go on you can do it to save unify
you parsi the new it do a headstand
extract the strings of the vibe and so
on so these are down here as well or you
can bother you just can't go and click
back and it will parse it for you so
just click on the web view log to be
each which weren't supposed to do that
you the browser to dot TV now in here we
can unit bookmarks from the device we've
got the dates down there which we could
pass we specify Intel create a module or
ask to these applications modulus saying
that look the browser to the TV table
bookmarks field created is a timestamp
so past hour we've got the history and
this was supposed to be partial America
and in some code changes
yes near here wrong for some reason see
so if you feel the configuration
emotionally for this application will
also dramatically preview the day so
translate it into a date and gift for
you nice thing about these doors so
process the images stored in the
database to go through them
we would need to fix the interface a
little bit
to put you for example the temporary
files generated by sqlite the right
ahead to look for example which you
can't pass you there are ways acid
anyways but we do you click on view in
wood to the heck's time of the
application both we'd maybe extract some
information or you close so bored to
extract swings and you through the
strings and see what's in there as well
the same goes for every five on the
device with Weaver if the application
recognizes the format it would pass it
itself so it recognizes those hp5
database files xml files make a person
for you and you could view them nicely
so this is the music player installed
service collection air some excel file
pic you give you the contents of the
five
so even without the modules you can
still do some analysis at this specific
point of the application
alright so the next application I saw
creation for sim card forensics the
reason behind meeting this application
or less was because I thought this
device to play chief device about two
pounds is a sim card reader and
supposedly he should walk when Queen
backups are putting some fancy
information from sim cards I've tried
almost all the applications i could get
my hands on these on my hands I can do
sim card forensics and known them worked
maybe I was doing something wrong five
okay couple of them work but then like
the way they were doing things and I'm
also pretty chilling I didn't want to
buy more expensive more expensive
devices to really extraction so with
that in mind basically what I have to do
what we have to do was or less
understand how the same cards work sim
cards or smart cards are essentially
full-blown devices they're everywhere
credit cards train tickets for most
everyone the ones used in telecom in the
telecommunication industry run on that
Java card operating system which is
essentially Java it more straight down
and eat for this specific things so it's
a no credit is it it's a whole computer
system in a small device so in there too
we gotta see you the RAM or the other
stuff you can communicate with them for
a specific protocol and ask for
information has been to execute stuff to
send you stuff and so on so when you're
doing forensics on sim cards won't
extract some information that
information is stored on the seating
cards I system
the file system is structured more or
less like any other file system it's up
it has folders and files folders are
named dedicated files and files a
reception name that event terrifies so I
run through it can communicate with in
using the apdu protocol over a serial
connection information the sim card that
could be useful in forensic analysis the
ID number of the sim card the mobile
subscriber number of the user which will
tell us the country the network the
actual subscriber identification under
the telephone number assigned to a sim
card the last dial numbers and location
information so the last location of the
sim card go by n these are still there
except the smss are sort of the devices
nowadays but one every devices you will
see the low key the LMD last higher
numbers location information being there
so and also the IDS we see how you do
that ok let's just go through this
specific one so when you connect to the
sim card what you do we communicate we
initiated connection with a sim card
with a smart card and then you say we
should command specific bites different
commands different with bites and so on
and you say that I want to select for
example go into this directory which is
the master master delegated fight it's
the root directory haven't said this
files don't have names they just have
IDs on a sim card so the idea of the
root directory is this then work what I
want to read the file
tell the sim card give me the contents
of 52 f into you can look up all these
things that existed at the European
telecommunications standards authority
they to be sketchy when you can extract
information from there even that you
understand the way they write things or
you can experiment find them up
you