so welcome everybody it's like oh thanks
for being here I'm not watching the
football match that's a good thing too
so thank you so this this is actually
presentation that I've given a number of
times already but essentially it's about
a study I did about two years ago now on
why ransomware became so popular as an
attack vector has a penis and why they
were talking to so many people and if
you actually take a look at the trends
in malware 250 2015/2016 with a peak and
the real wake-up call for our industry
and for customers is basically in in
when one a cry came along and it really
hit badly right so when wanna cry came
along people started to wake up and so
and ransomware as actually although it's
still very much present we don't see the
kinds of campaigns which we saw before
one across so for those of just one
little disclaim yeah so one disclaimer
I've never used this to do anything
malicious okay this is purely a study
this is purely things I did it was
purely a mishit of what I did to
actually be able to run some research
run some tests against tools and see how
the tools were basically detecting
ransomware and what I could do to avoid
those tools and also to build in to see
how you can build better make indicators
so this is me essentially that's me
nowadays because I'm bored and
tired of this industry people are so
full of nowadays including myself I
will admit it I've been in this put in
this I've been in this play for thirty
plus years and that's why I'm that last
picture is me nowadays it's just I don't
find anything really new I don't find
anything surprising and I'm tired of
summer and I'm tired of something's
going on those I think some of you know
I run B so I'm one of the directors to
be sighs London I'm also currently the
quote-unquote Data Protection Officer
for the idea SS a UK chapter so like I
said in 2016 there was a massive
explosion of ransomware
going on and if you looked at there was
the campaign's were just exploding and
exploding and I'll show you a little bit
more about that what I mean by later but
I one of the at the time I was working
for a product vendor and one of the
things they were trying to get into was
the enterprise detection and response
right at the endpoint detection and
response so I'm looking at how you could
actually detect new you malicious
software without actually having any
proper indicators so I needed to I
wanted to kind of build something will
allow me to test the rules to test them
all set but also to provide certain
tools that we could use to actually
demonstrate the capabilities of actually
picking things on so the thing is I this
was never released from the public right
so what I did here it's never been
released in public I've never said I've
never used it in any malicious way right
I just want to make that clear it's this
is clearly an internal thing and it was
used for testing and building demos so
ransomware 20 you know 2016 I mean
everybody was saying this was the other
ransomware we had massive massive
amounts of campaigns every month we saw
more more campaigns and it was mostly
variants of one or other of the types of
ransomware towards the end of the year
we even started to see some really weird
types of ransomware but we started to
see one really interesting thing is that
you could actually buy ransomware as a
service on the dark web so you could
actually go out and buy an existing
ransomware to actually what an existing
exported it kept company and ransom and
use it to ransomware so you would get
the ransom you would get a cover the
ransomware and the rats whereas the
service would get a cut as well so if
you had information to help you exploit
a company you could basically use that
information to then go buy your
ransomware as a service which is
interesting because how far gone how far
how easy and how far are we into this
process of actually industrializing
things like ransomware right and that
was one of the things that led me to
kind of look into this so then there was
the other aspect so if you've ever
worked for a vendor company you always
get the BS and the crap from sales and
marketing saying we need to be able to
show that our products as this and this
an app when we show our practices and
listen
or when there's a new campaign that
comes out we have to be the first to
respond and write some really nice
article with debo I'm like yeah okay
everybody's doing it everybody does it
and the problem was really the sales
guys they were all like well we have a
ransom but we have a lab demoing malware
and things like that
but we need something that we can
contain and we can demo it at any time
in that and whenever we're in a customer
site so the sales engineer is like I'll
give us something give us something
you've got two ways to actually handle
that in a product in the in a vendor
space you I ever build a set of scripts
so I say you know you can build instead
of PowerShell scripts in that simulate
the indicators or you can build some
feet you know like simple files that
simulate the indicators or you can
actually use real real ransomware or
real viruses and actually run them on
your on your environment so if you like
go to trade shows a lot of the companies
that are claiming they're doing your
course advance response that usually run
in real live samples inside inside of
sandbox or inside a closed environment
so I want so one of the things I said
it's like well actually you know some of
the research I've been doing a faster
and things and we could actually
simulate a simple ransomware all right
so let's look back at 2016 why this why
this was probably the year of Aransas so
I actually if you pull some of the stats
that came out so source you know proof
point did this graph and if you look at
the graph you know the graph starts like
end of 2015 but you see towards the
middle of the year just the curve starts
to climb drastically right so there's a
lot more and more it's like it just
massively starts to climb and we start
to see more and more three content pains
and in the same way if you break that
down what was really interesting is that
we started to not see any more malicious
URLs and that's I think because the your
the mail systems were actually and all
of the all of your network devices were
actually starting to pick up URLs so
they would stop you from going to a
drive-by type attack what we saw more
and more of is actually at you know the
malicious documents but the black line
is actually message JavaScript
attachments so
the ways that these guys are getting in
as they were actually sending zip files
of JavaScript's inside and it was they
were obfuscated in a way that the user
would just click on the zip file
double-click on the jet JavaScript and
it would run in W script making happen
and you get them what you get the
ransomware that will take over the
environment so I think you guys heard of
Sevilla Martens right so he runs a
honeypot I was actually running a
hundred he wants an email honeypot I run
an email honey put so I could contact
him I'm like can you confirm some of the
stats that I'm seeing over 2016 because
I was seeing some really interesting
patterns and he goes early okay what do
you need so you actually he's once he's
got a lot of blank instance and he runs
all these stats so what we saw is that
you essentially get weekly campaigns
right so these are the campaigns that we
kind of saw over the over the year and
you can you notice but like towards
around March it starts to build up so
you start to get these you'll start with
a small spike where they're actually
testing the campaign and then towards
the end of the month you get like a
massive spike right and this is almost
like a DevOps type of our activity
they're like they're kind of sitting
there going okay let's test this let's
let's see what we can get out of it and
they start to improve their methods and
you start to see all these spikes and
these are essentially the same types of
ransomware that you're seeing over a few
weeks and you see and if you look at the
whole year we just have that continuous
pattern right so there's an
industrialization of this activity in
the ransomware industry you know the
ransomware industry where these guys are
actually starting to build campaigns and
they're testing their campaigns and
they're releasing the campaign it's and
getting some effective drive through so
this is this is the same thing but
targeted a lot more to one month right
so if you see at the beginning of a
month you've got that you've got that
testing and then slowly you get more and
more precise on your on your activities
and the number of emails what you see
but this was reassuring week after week
you know month after month so there was
this there's so some of the some of the
collisions when I came up come up with
us because of the
the the scripts well the attacks that
you're seeing and the types of emails
that were seeing it was really a you
know and in this dust realization of the
process they were basically testing
refining their their their activity but
finding their scripts refining their
their code and relief and getting more
and more precise so the other thing that
was interesting is that we took apart
the attachments are we seeing if you
look at the big red one so this is
actually the big red portion of the pie
chart is zip font so that's in 2016 we
look we start to see less and less of
them
traditional document attachments and we
started to get more and more zip files
and inside the zip files you would
usually find a JavaScript or a C script
so the rest is basically love different
versions of Word so there's a few more
these are because if files as well
there's different types different
formats as it fast so you've got all of
these types of zips plus then you have
word which was the second biggest really
if you take outside of zip then Excel
and some some mixed octet streams
usually corrupt emails so what is
ransomware really right so what what do
we define is ransomware well if you look
at the industry this basically we
thought we look at Mac somewhere as
variants right so this is a chart from
f-secure but it's I really like it
because it again demonstrates the
expansion of ransomware as in 2016 right
so if you looked at 20 2016 is here so
if we look at 2016 here you kind of save
it before 2016 and 2015 is a very few
variants of variants of different types
of logins I'll explain in more detail
what a variant is but you've got less in
2015 you got more and more in 2060 right
so 2016 is just a complete explosion and
a lot of them are very similar to each
other they just hope they might have
different little they might have
different names but they're all bait
though or usually a monthly they'll be
based on certain campaign and we got
some familiar ones like you know March
2016 we've got the tire sober these
or for things that we saw repeated over
over the over 2016 and when into 2017 so
what is what we tend to see is that
you'll find that there's four different
variants of ransomware so the first one
typically what you'll see is some kind
of scripted to fit ransomware right
so the scripted ransomware is
essentially you'll have some kind of
command line a Python script or PHP
script and even PowerShell
right you can actually do a full
ransomware just by using PowerShell
what's interesting with these types of
methods is which you're using tools that
get flagged as green by most malware
detection systems right so when you
actually downloading this ransomware
you get a PHP interpreter so if you look
at the this this command line here right
so eight if you if you know if you've
seen this she's used to man line tools
you might recognize that command line
that command line is actually 7-zip
right so basically what for this
campaign what they did is they took
7-zip recompile they're a bit but it
still looks like 7-zip renamed it and
we're just basically zipping the files
and that's a rep piece of ransomware
right it's not it's when you think about
the the fluff that we've put onto
ransomware where it's all this you know
I want to cry it attack the you know the
SMB stack and everything and then in
encrypted or you equipped in the header
you don't need that much you just can do
it with a simple 7-zip utility that
archives the files with with a password
the second type is essentially you're
using a compiled script and using some
kind of simple hashing mechanism so
you're using base64 rc4 sha-1 and
Blowfish so these these this type of
France where is actually quite simple
and essentially what happens is is that
you just it hashes before
and you can usually easily decrypt them
if you figure out which hash it is so in
these two first two types of ransomware
when you hear one of them and malware
vendors say oh I've got a script do you
clip to the Decrypter or you're locked
up machine it's because they're usually
using one of these type types of
techniques because it's easily to
reverse it's easy to understand or
identify the key if you can get a sample
of the script you can basically get the
key that that was used to password
encrypt the file the next stage up is
actually using proper cryptography so
there you're trying to look at a EES
gloss best FREE des rot13 XOR and what
you're typically seeing there is that
some kind of secret key in the code it's
usually hidden so it's hard to find but
they're using traditional methods of
encryption this is basically the
ransomware that you don't want to have
because it's almost essentially
impossible to reverse unless you
actually get the key and there's
different types where they'll actually
have a key management system in the
background so they'll generate different
types of keys the fourth type is public
key cryptography so usually based on RSA
you don't see many of these actually
land as ransomware mostly because it's
really hard to manage public key
infrastructure you need a key management
system in the background you need to be
able to generate essentially what will
happen is you need to have a system that
generates your back-end private key
gives the client the endpoint that you
want to ransom a public key and I
publicly encrypts the data and then once
you pay the ransom you get the private
key to decrypt it it requires a lot of
effort right because you do need to have
a system where you can generate keys
store them safely keep them if you want
to get paid as a ransom they offer you
can't just do this we really and just
have something that goes out and ransoms
of the machine oops
so then you look at actually how they're
going to deliver this encryption segment
this should quit from technique well
simply it's like a five stage a five
stage process you the first is the
delivery which is usually the email or
drive by something like that when you
execute a script or you guys acute your
Pearson your piece of malware that
malware tries to find what files need to
be encrypted it does the encryption then
you have an optional stays of spreading
so you might find you might use an
exploit and actually try to get to the
next machine or you might use a dropper
that lands into a shared shared folder
and you use that shared folder just as
you have stopped it stemming splits down
for other machines to when they hook
into the share folder they've run the
script as well and then you get a ransom
note usually all right and then your
machines kind of locked out and you need
to pay around some more you to restore
backups or whatever so how do we
actually do that so how so so now we
have an idea of what ransomware is well
what can we do to actually build one
right what can we actually in that
obtained and do to do this kind of thing
well first it's a piece of software
right so you're going to go through a
software development lifecycle but I'm a
lazy git and basically I don't like the
this is like program management and
project management or latch it and you
know this was supposed to be like a
really small quick project and I've done
that don't get me wrong I've done
software development in my past and you
know I love developing software but
having to deal with all this stuff just
wasn't the purpose of what I was trying
to do I wanted to do something quick but
I could easily distribute but I could
easily get up and running to test to do
my tests so I switched to a different
method which was basically I said okay
I'm going to mindmap what I need to do
right so if I might map what I need to
do I'll have an idea of the structure of
what I need so this is my this is the
mind map but I came up with right so we
talked about the delivery part right so
in the delivery part
like there's two ways I can go I can go
with a web drive-by or I can go with an
email and if I go over an email I can do
a JavaScript in a zip or I can do a word
attachment or an Excel attachment so
what I did is I said okay the easiest
what's the easiest easiest I can do well
email what attachments simple to demo
simple to make execute I'll use that so
that was my first path so then you
actually get to the encryption aspects
right so I saw this orange stuff let me
zoom it in a bit so how do you start
with your encrypted so first you can say
okay wait a minute
I need a language maybe the programming
language it is a program so I'm in the
programming language so you know you've
got your traditional C++ C hash I'm like
I don't really want to do that it's just
like it's really complicated you have to
have all these libraries you need to do
all this all this stuff you know I could
just we know if a PHP Python I use
PowerShell to use or maybe I use one of
those so I said okay well let's just use
PHP and I explain why a little bit more
in detail why just shows PHP afterwards
so then you need your your you need to
choose your encryption method so in your
encryption method you've got different
choices you can do as I said some kind
of proper encryption like with AES or
you can use some simpler techniques like
rock 13 or X or I chose X or so a very
specific reason it's easy it's it's easy
not to mess up because if you XOR a
string with a string you just reverse it
you just react so that whatever the
result was with the original string or
the or your encryption passwords so it's
a reversible it's easily reversible
technique or I'll get it later but it's
a simple simple process and it works so
then you need to code so that's going to
actually encrypt all your funds so first
you're going to have to set your key
right so you set your key you get that
code then you're going to pass your disk
now you don't want to pass the whole
disk does anybody know why you don't
pass the whole list that's one reason
there's a much more important reason you
want to be able to decrypt it later but
if you pass the hold it yeah exactly
your hip wonder if you hit one of the
windows libraries or if you hit one of
the system libraries and you clip the
system files you'll create a bit you do
a blue screen or you've crashed you've
lot you're in your environment and if
you crash your environment you've read
some basically you won't get any ransom
out of it because it's useless the other
aspect really is time because the longer
it takes you to do time to do that time
is that you end up being detected faster
so you're gonna built you're going to go
through each folder you're going to
build an exclusion list and then you're
going to look for documents the same
thing so so some this is where it was
interesting because you see different
ransomware it's handled the documents
differently some will target very
specific subsets of documents so I look
for all the office type documents right
they look for dark text excel zip and
JPEGs and things like that some were
just like blatantly encrypt everything
that's in certain subfolders I chose to
actually look at certain certain
document types because it's a little bit
more apparent plus you have the tools
that on your machine so you can show
that the files been encrypted so then
you have your actual run environment so
your run environment you're going to run
your spirit that parses the files does
your encryption you set a registry for
persistence and you show a message now
so I said okay this this is good but
wait a second I need something more and
I'll explain why I need something more a
little bit later but I had to get to
that green part right so this dropper
aspect the dropper aspect is a little
bit more different because essentially
you've got this grid but how does the
client actually get to that script or
how does that point that that the the
endpoint but your that you're attacking
actually run this spits so you need
something to actually drop your
ransomware and that's what that's what
you typically see in the in this
environment because you're going to have
to load something you don't pop ever
going to have to load your own code
at all to actually do the encryption and
really importantly build the crypto it's
really important trust me so a little
bit about encryption right does anybody
recognize the bottom encryption yeah it
says a well it's probably the second
time I've done this is somebody's
actually recognize it so the season
where was probably one of the first
encryption methods what we know of right
essentially he basically had a wheel
where you turn the letters and you
wouldn't it was let a substitution
essentially that actually mathematically
evolved into rot13 rot13 is essentially
the same principles the Caesars well you
just shift your alphabet by 13 spaces
and you encrypt based on that the middle
one is an actual X is X or essentially
you take your original screen apply a
downstream signal and you get the
encrypted message with the downstream
signal if you reapply the downstream
string or you come back to the
unencrypted signal the middle this
middle block chain thing where it's just
block cipher that's AES and the top one
is or I say so an RSA although it's
probably the best type of encryption you
can use again very complicated because
you have to have two separate types of
keys right so X or this that's the
mathematical represents a representation
of XOR
so if you XOR your straight your
original your original data with 0 you
get 0
if you XOR the data with itself you get
0 again if you explore the data with a
river with another string you'll get
exactly a reversible string basically
essentially if I reverse if I do the XOR
of a and B with C then I get a is X or I
hate math their conclusion is I hate
math and the reason I chose this is
because there's a ship
there's a shitload of sample code on the
internet right so I make my own life
complications like if I can find some
really good simple codes to use I'm
going to use the simple code and it was
really easy to implement in PHP which is
language I chose to actually do this so
you need a working environment you need
something like VMware as well as some
coding tools such as notepad plus plus
or Visual Studio
now if you've done coding visuals the
IDE is like visual studio stuff like
that
there are painting nails they
are really complicated they load a
shitload of libraries it takes half the
computer memory and when you're
doing something very simple that you
want to write you then you want to test
it and you do quit coding and you want
to do it in VMware it's a waste of time
it's a total waste of time
worse being eclipse it's like
every time I launch eclipse it takes
like 10 hours to boot because
it's just updating all this right
so I don't want I just I was like
sitting there going no I don't want this
I'm just gonna use trusted notepad
plus plus it does basic code you know
highlighting it's simple to use I don't
need anything complicated Oh
remember to snapshot really important I
learnt the hard way this is what
happened to my development one one day I
accidentally double-click on the file
and the thing locked so I lost
like a couple of hours work luckily I
use next door right simple I can just
reverse it with the same passphrase well
it works if you actually codex or
properly and you don't make a mistake
when you curtain the eggs or flat so I
lost the couple of hours because I had
to go back to three versions of what I
was doing in my own I was is my snapshot
but I learnt the hard way so I started
snaps I shouldn't have shot him give me
five minutes and cleaning off because it
started to get it quite heavy so choose
it but my point is choose your tools
wisely right because you're going to
need those the snapshotting effect is
really
good he also needs to be careful because
it's got to be something easy to deploy
why did I select PHP well I started to
play with these tools right PHP push
PowerShell in Python the reason I took
they're very simple right I wanted to
make this simple and what I found is
that the PowerShell is really great it
would have been really awesome to do
because I wouldn't have to deploy
anything I could have just done the
script and done the encryption problem
is unless you're actually running
PowerShell v3 plus all the updates you
actually don't get a lot of the
necessary functions that you would look
for if to actually read files and
encrypt files so and the base if you
look at the base windows 7 window
you took the power show instance is very
basic right there's not that much
functionality in it it's powershell 1.0
by default so you'd have to update
PowerShell to actually get this to run
problem to get anything done properly
Python the problem was every time I
tried to basically use Python I ended up
having to also drop like 10 dll's now
PHP that was a little bit better because
I could actually start to look at very
simple executable right and then then of
course there's the word file to look at
sort of delivery I ignored the zip file
because actually zip actually introduces
more complex aspects where you need to
think about how you're actually going to
get the user to click and I just wanted
something very simple to demonstrate a
very basic fishing and plus ransomware
so we so that's how we got to PHP VMware
in a notepad plus plus so this is this
is so I used to do a little bit of UML
as well so I kind of broke this down to
you and I'll just to make sure that I
wasn't missing any steps especially
after the one time input is my machine
by accident
and so I set the pro code so he set path
that's where I'm going to start and then
basically I go into a loop I do a find
file when I encrypt the file rename a
file and I texted sort of more files
when I go back this
is really important because this loop
actually foils some anti some anti
ransomware taking up techniques right
because you'll find that some anti
ransomware rule sets and things like
that they look for a file rename and
they tried to stop the ransomware once
you hit the file rename problem is your
files already encrypted so even if you
stop the rename your thought the content
is still encrypted and I've and I've
found a few products that fail in that
way so this is the actual code right
it's very simple it's PHP so I set the
passphrase I made sure I put the actual
passphrase inside the comments just
because I could forget it
I base64 encoded it it simple
obfuscation is stupid
yo no you then start to look for your
folders right so you're going to look
for your photos and then you're going to
open each directory and you're going to
go drill down in each directory I'm
ignoring win NT boot system windows temp
temp program that data application
there's a whole bunch of photos what I
may ignore to avoid risking a death so
then I check see if the file extension
of the file is equal to something so
Ted's it raro rr0 tar gzip doc bike
sells a whole bunch at the end I open
the file and I start the encryption
operation so everybody know PHP here do
you know what the read does why I have
so in PHP so this read basically it says
read the file pointer for 1024 bytes
does anybody know why did I've only seen
to 1024 bytes and not reading the whole
file speed and time so speed of time if
I can do it fast I get less detected and
also I get more I get more traction but
there's another important part if I
crup the header of the file the files
useless right so it's technically it's
not really encrypted but it's
technically encrypted because you can't
use it anymore
right the whole goal is to stop you from
using the file so I've technically
stopped the far from being useful I've
saved time and I've basically created a
cryptid fun and it's fast the other
thing too is that if you have really
large files like GP eggs very large deep
Paisley if you have certain you know
it's like I was talking to an oil and
gas company once you know some of the
large data files they have can span
gigabyte you know it can be gigabytes if
I only hit the header I'm saving a lot
of time because encrypting a Giga by far
is extremely time consuming and CPU
intensive this just keeps it very simple
very light and it avoids certain types
of detection so once I once I close the
file
I then rename it so then I then rename
it at the bottom right so I admitted
this earlier of it is that why did I
choose PHP is because it was a simple
way to do it with and I could drop the
PHP interpreter very easily was small if
you look at the top window it's 66 K
only but you have to be careful which
version you're using so I started with
the latest version problem is as soon as
I dropped the interpreter and I try to
run it I got that error message you have
to have a DLL all right but don't want
any TL else so luckily PHP has a whole
bunch of archives and you can go way
back in time right so I thought to go
back and so I found I think it's version
3 I've avoided me having to drop any
really specific dll's
so I took in 3 and we go to that so once
I do that you can so you've got your PHP
script and you can actually test it
right so you can test it it does the
runs don't get much output
is good but then your files are
basically encrypted right so I've got my
dog cryptid that's good so are we ready
well we've got it back far we've got
executable got a script
well we but we still need a delivery
method right so phishing attack simulate
let's simulate a phishing attack which
is the primary object the primary
delivery method that we've seen the
simplest method is word file or a VB
script in Excel well father VB or DD e
and Excel with the VB or DD e so
everybody knows what did he write is
right CDE allows you to basically run
CMD straight out of the straight out of
Word or Excel it's much better it's much
faster and it gets less detective than
scripting and it doesn't require the
disable scripts done with the new
security settings disabled scripts
actually doesn't work that well anymore
but with dde actually works pretty well
so this is up here this this is an
example of dde so basically when you
open your excel file did he eat yeah the
ddd text which you have a teen unique
request inside the excel file and it
tells you do you want to update the
external data you say yes and it runs
that CMB right it's if you I mean if
you're a penetration tester this is a
much better way to actually get a
footprint than using losing vbscript
nowadays so this is an example vbscript
so I hate VB script and I was like oh do
I need to do this so I found this so
this is actually a piece of Russia it's
a Russian toolkit for products so I tell
you just think it basically builds your
VB script for your word file completely
right and well and I'll show you what
else it does in the demo but essentially
it allows you to not only put in a VB
script on open but it allows you to do
it on clothes it allows you to allows
you to put in code that actually removes
the BB script from the word file so the
actual word file gets updated
you don't see any more than so the very
bespoke disappears but it also will
encrypt the original data in the world
file and make it look like it's
encrypted so when you when the code runs
it decrypts the it because the it
decrypts the text so it looks like it's
something's happening which was
interesting this is a really good
demonstration of a fishing technique
right and really useful because it can
help demonstrate that the mechanisms
work where that we do so I've got my
word far I've got my DD line but it's
just the powershell that's downloading
mice mice my PHP script but where do I
put this all right hold on a second
I can get out my neck systems really
small whining sisters three four a year
on AWS turnip on AWS I looked at the
terms of conditions it's not against the
Terms and Conditions
I'm just hosting a file on a web server
so I spin that up so VPS is a really
useful nowadays especially if you like
doing demonstrations like this or you
building something like this we're
trying to research this stuff because
you can spin up things automatically hey
so I was in Kuala Lumpur at first at the
first conference two weeks ago I guess
you guys heard of aw workspaces they're
really shocking useful I did CTF just
with my Chromebook an AWS workspace so
it's it's fun
I kind of love iws because you get lost
out of you can get a lot of
done with it
is that enough well so I talked a little
bit more into some of the campaign some
of the more advanced campaigns actually
excuse export techniques to get a
foothold and spread and potentially do
more than just run somewhere your
environment so I was like wow I
had this this could be really cool so I
started to look into this so these are
the different types of loaders right the
common loaders what you see right so
you've got snooze dried expired Citadel
cover er Andromeda smoke out X canes
Cronos tired and regen the most comments
that we saw a really in 2016 with Zeus
products and buyer and
and ayah those were the ones that are
most active in 2016 most of it been
taken down now but what's interesting is
if you have access to the dark web and
if you have access to certain certain
parties you can actually get access to
you can actually get these toolkits but
you need to speak Russian or and you
have to have an introduction because
these guys basically work on networking
and work on who you know and how you'll
know right so you have to be something
you have to have a relationship and you
have to have knowledge of you know you
have to get introduced to get some of
the cooler stuff and you know echoey you
get money basically up there see this
says this little red box here says so
you can get this tool key for $3,000 its
latest exploit works on Windows 10
things like that luckily I not but you
know I have my I've got connections so I
asked a friend to ask a friend so I got
what I did is I ended up using garlic so
this is the GAO extent that a console
there any of you seen this before it's
like a full CMS oh well you know
like configuration management system
once you've got that dropper on the
machine
it basically registers your machine as
an agent tells you what the waste
architecture it is tells you what
antivirus it has tells you what it was
installed when it was last seen if it's
offline online that's the last green
shot it takes so you can specify the
screenshots so it'll actually screenshot
the machine every few minutes so you
know what's going on on the machine so
you can actually look as an admin you
could actually see if it's a sandbox or
if it's a real user and you've got stats
on where the machines are coming from on
a lot which was really useful because
then I could see when the sales
engineers will actually try it testing
and trying the toolkit right when I
wanted but I finally gave it to them for
demo purposes but what's really
interesting is once you have these
agents registered in there online you
can send additional commands so if I
needed to do a really deep down demo or
if I really need to do something really
deep down I could actually start
basically send using this to send a
man's point
toolkit right just dump it use the
command line there and the best part is
this is just a PHP page on your web
server it's as simple as that that's how
they that's how they basically do it the
C and C is basically an injected web
page on on your web server and that's
how they get all this all this
information so it was really useful
because I was getting a lot of data out
of this I was getting URLs I was getting
vision of how this worked and they
provide you we were talking to generate
the dropper and it has really good
options like these ones anti debug in
techniques at the LED but that's the IV
any mp3 my anti VirtualBox all you have
to do is click the check box when you're
done
and you can generate different mutexes
so every time I could generate basically
different versions if I you started to
get detected or anything like that right
so extremely useful this is how simple I
mean this you know this is how simple
what we can be so what does it look like
so this is a Nega so basically this is
me opening with phishing you see this is
the encrypted page it looks encrypted
because of that script generator I click
on the enable function it gets decrypted
so for the end user it looks really
riddle right he closes the file now
nothing that really happens like you've
seen ok Windows Explorer died that's
actually that's actually the export kit
but the one good thing is I did it on
clothes so you it takes a while now I
introduced a lot of latency here does
anybody want know why I introduced a lot
of latency here is I know not to be
detected this is basically the longer
that you can draw out your actual tag
face the more likely your your art of to
avoid sandboxing techniques a lot of
sandboxing techniques what they do is
they look at the behavior and activity
after about one or two minutes right so
by introducing this
we can see I've actually built in a kind
of anti detection mechanism right so it
was that the aspect was to generate as
much data as I could from the aid from
the different talkie so I was what I was
using and you seen so now that
ransomware has kicked in it was real
it's actually real quick once it once it
kicks in and you see all the files are
encrypted so it was as simple as that
right so writing the initial it's so
it's not that hard writing the initial
encryption program was really simple
because I could just basically pull
something an encryption algorithm off
and code off off a website I could just
look at it and you know adapt it to
whatever programming language I was
using the more advanced part and the
more challenging was actually that that
second layer of export and delivery
methods right advanced the advanced
techniques that we were right but I
ended up using although it didn't take
that long it took me
total time less than 24 hours
yeah with ever all the toolkits and
everything if I look at the time it took
me to code everything that I did it took
me less than 24 hours to actually build
this which is interesting because if you
look at the stats 38 percent of victims
actually pay the ransom
right and further further studies
actually showed but 59% of people paid
personally and only 37 plus asked their
employer to pay right yeah of office
workers and I found this really
interesting because when I when I
researched these stats after I was doing
this so I was building a whole
presentation campaign for for myself
team and I was like this is really
interesting because if users are so
afraid to actually go to their employer
saying hey I'm sorry but I think I
clicked on something wrong and my
machines equipted and they're paying for
the for the ransom themselves there's a
problem of what we're doing in the
industry
as security teams we're not educating
people well enough for them to actually
sit sit down and say oh I've made a
mistake I need to go communicate it
with in storing an aspect of fear but
stopping people from actually take doing
the right things and taking the right
decisions so if you think about it total
effort versus benefit in the yes box and
that's how I came to a kind of like the
conclusion that it is kind of quite
simple if to actually build the thing
still campaigning that's a little bit
more complex but you have meat means to
do that so the effort isn't that much
for the amount of money that you could
potentially get right so then one of the
other aspects also looking at was
looking at how to use this to test
certain certain endpoint detection tools
so the basic inscription suit won't
trigger IVs because I'm just using a PHP
engine but flags green from Norway she'd
put it in the eyes total just widescreen
next-gen protection didn't really flag
it until I turned on script blogging and
I was talking to a guy who works for
that company I'm like this why don't you
block scripts through the way oh we
can't blocks gets it away because half
of the half of a corporate environment
uses ad and they have scripts running so
we don't default block or scripts right
okay but by using a script because you
can essentially avoid that's the first
I've done the real promise when you
start to introduce those export kids
that's when you get detected but if you
if you know I mean we all know that
there are ways to modify your code and
to actually do probably more thicket
generation and things like that so you
don't get detected so you we heard a lot
about advanced you know user endpoint
behavior analytics type solutions what
they do is they look for massive far
more notification patterns over a short
period of time and I introduce latency
into that encryption process into the
script and you ETA doesn't detect it
anymore because just if you if you
manage to randomize the latency between
one between the modifications of each
file you start do you start to
to kill the pattern that they're looking
for right so once you kill the patent
that they're looking for you basically
stop stop him from actually detecting
you the other part was I found that a
lot of tools actually flag ransomware
based on the extension when the file
gets renamed I was like okay that's
stupid that's partially effective maybe
I was like okay this I can't get
around this easily just randomize the
extension right yeah well you don't need
to it's simple math right well that's
not math but it's simple logic so
evolutions there are none as you notice
I thought of a few things going back to
PowerShell potentially looking at
actually building all the you know not
using PHP but using a dynamic compiled
script that would actually generate
different versions of the tool every
time so you wouldn't get detected based
on the signatures randomizing the
encryption on matically randomizing the
extension but I can't stop because this
little guy phoned me where is he he got
while I was doing this he got sick
really sick cost a lot of money and I
was like Oh a bit away from the computer
step away from the computer because you
start to think things anyway so that
what that's it go if you missed a spare
for questions if you have any but thanks
for listening to me not watching the
match I'm assuming sweetly most right
could be a France even final
[Music]
yeah I did and I was that's one of the
things I was doing because I was looking
I was doing competitive analysis as well
I can't really talk about that location
[Music]
I'm not doing it in the presentation let
me let me put you this were those things
that I said about detection in there but
applies to basically every vendor what
I've tested well I mean most of those
they use they use the sandbox and
techniques right so they try to explode
explode the the attachments in a sandbox
and if you just latency if you do the
juice whole bunch of other detection
mechanisms is you can bypass where the
invades it's you want to hit the 90
percent I the 10 percent of the guys
that really want to get into your
organization
you're never gonna detective yeah I'll
get in anyway wait the circle you know
the switch from from Phoebe scripts of
dde with one of the biggest things that
happened in 2012 2017 right we started
to stop we stop seeing VB script and we
started seeing a lot of dde attacks that
why because office turned off scripting
by default and it's really hard to turn
back on now but DeeDee they haven't turn
off because if you turn off the EEE then
a lot of companies are gonna go why do
you turn off do de all of our
spreadsheets little coq10 500 megabyte
spreadsheets can query all those
databases you turned it all off right
and it's the only probably found is didi
is it's the length that you can actually
there's certain limitations on what you
can put
strange so you got to be really creative
put it works it's cool we got to phone
my sister
Rick thanks guys