hello so gdpr
you've got 30 seconds to leave the room
before we lock the doors so some of you
in here will be experts on you can have
some of you won't even know what it
stands for I will try and Kate a few all
and there is no Who am I cause I don't
have that kind of size ego like some
other speakers like in truth on to UM I
have but basically I do GT PR and
security and data stuff so any questions
I know seriously the format's of this is
slight difference what you have today
there will be no questions at the end
for two reasons one it's bit dull doing
that and two it's lunch some I want to
want to leave so please please please
you've got questions heckled anything do
it in the talk okay just say shout out
whatever just heckle please do that
because you'll all learn more from each
other than from anyone else and if you
are brave enough so you do that then we
have sweets or money bouches for drinks
tonight so yeah please in please
interact everybody so GDP are so GDP R
stands for general data protection
regulation it's about data protection
again you probably already think this
but dull and basically it's an EU thing
so European Union has been over the last
sort of 20-30 years trying to get data
protection law out there and there's a
lot of people in European Parliament and
commissions and committees and what live
out and stand there like me and tell you
that privacy is the way forward and in
Britain were a bit different because we
don't really care and so what's happened
over the years in the 80s we had the
idea of a Data Protection Directive so
the EU have directives or what a
directive is is this idea that I'm gonna
tell you what to do pretty much going in
to implement at your own way so country
goes thanks very much I'll create my own
law so in the UK we had the Data
Protection Act and that's our
interpretation of what the EU won now
all 28 EU Member States we've got
own interpretation which is nice that
means differences and so if I try to
create a company in the UK I go worried
about different laws in these and
country than you use the Bev a problem
so that we have this idea of any
regulation you know really got to do
this and what that is when you decide in
a regulation it instantly becomes law
like that in every country in the EU and
so what that meant was back in May last
year every country in a year or twenty
eight instantly the GDP I applied to so
GDP isin our law wasn't there very
exception clauses for each country other
countries can specify so yes it's a
really great question so the EU GDP I
says it's what you have to do this is
the law but there is scope for what's
called derogations and derogations basic
needs meaning exceptions and the idea is
that certain parts of the law the seats
all around if you want to jump in and
the idea is the certain bits are so in
country specific I'll give you an
example in Denmark there's no ability
for the Danish regulator to find
companies you can't do it so they have
to actually criminally make you liable
so that's one of the delegations and one
other one is what is the age of consent
for children for data protection and in
the UK the default is 16 bit could be 13
those are kind of things and this kind
of variations now where we kind of are
is that this GDP are kicked in two years
ago and what's really happened since
then is everyone's dancing around about
GDP are saying it's really bad really
exciting guys has plenty of fees you
have to please everyone keeps just
moving a bit because it's such an
amazing talk that people will keep
coming
they hate the game or whatever
yes I will come to that I'll come to
that yeah seats give me a nap on it's
nice and cool in here so if I see GDP
are six different people especially in
this kind of geek community we're in
people think different things so if I
thought of a business person you might
think scary you might think I'll guard
data breaches everyone thinks of
different kind of thing with GDP are so
first thing is it is a response special
from the vendor's is it's all about the
breaches you know get stock both so
you're getting it free that's what
breach can look like apparently but then
as other people say it's all about fines
and you get this kind of yeah it's all
about the money if everyone's getting
fined a billion dollars now my reaction
is slightly different to that so I have
a very much kind of view of bullshit and
in case any of you missed it there is
actually an 18 plus rating on this talk
you're in you're stuck so basically this
talk is really about the bullshit that's
going on inside GDP are and what's
bullshitting what's not and I hope
they'll help clarify that especially
with your questions and yet sweet some
money get me later and so what is super
really all about was really about right
now and not these right in right Matthew
right mark right or the Wright brothers
who you may know but it's actually about
right for us everyone in this room is in
scope of GDP are we're all protected by
GDP our what that means is that GDP is
really about you about me it's about all
of us
it's not about companies PCI I so
they're actually about securing and
locking down companies and finding
companies GDP always about giving you
all rights it's quite different really
and people get that bit mixed up some of
the rights that are out there that we
all have is this one anyone all this one
is erasure so
it's a beautiful thing and so so arisia
and also notice the right to be
forgotten now this came up several years
ago when somebody in Spain said Google I
want to be production basically from
Google search results and they said in a
chance and the you said yes make it
happen and it did and this kind of
concepts essentially is now inside
European law which means it's now part
of our law and it says if you become
cold data on you you have the right in
principle to say delete it if you used
to be a British Gas customer and you're
not anymore you fix them you don't need
my data anymore
get rid of it that is the right to
erasure essentially now it's a really
cool concept but if you think about
let's say where you work and many of you
will work in IT and through thinking
about all the things fighter to you I
used to work for your company or I used
to be a customer please delete every
trace of me just think about that how
what when your IT managers do you go and
do it what would you do you know it's a
pretty big search where is even that
data
the other question is think about
backups how do you remove a record from
a backup it's basically not possible
especially when it's in tape so an ID
customer service still got things like
microfiche and microfilm it's tough its
physical stuff so the question is what
you do with all that and there's a real
big problem at the moment in not welcome
anyway inside inside gdpr because people
are saying the lowest thing I have to
remove the data I physically can't what
do I do and one of the theories out
there is that if someone gives you a
request they remove my data is you you
write down a piece of paper and if
anyone ever restores that back up on to
server you have to go back and look for
that little record and go in proactively
delete it that's never going to happen
and you know we all might right do that
writing down wherever happen and so
there's other backup vendors are saying
actually maybe we should do backup
spectrum not use tape so a rage is a
really interesting area where people
have got problems now another right is
the right portability and portability is
really cool right so portability means
that if your data is with one company
let's say a bank or spot
by in the context of Spotify think about
your playlist history or your your
playlist that states for about you it's
your data it's not really spotify x' in
the context of European law and what the
whites portability means is that when
you do let's think my competition for a
second why'd you stay with Spotify well
I really like it but also moving to
Google music would be a pain in the ass
because of I'd have to redo it all the
right portability means that Spotify
from May next year has to give me an
export function and Google app to give
me an import function that's really cool
stuff and the the export import thing is
also when I ask my data he asked me in a
human readable format was relevant to me
it can't be XML and it has to be
exportable and to format than something
else can import to probably XML in that
case so if you think about banking
that's an area where they've been doing
this for years you've now got really
fast banking in the UK like five days to
do it
so portable is is something that people
are going to be getting more into and if
you're in a business you have to think
about how data might be portable
thinking on this one about moving my
paper when you normally sign up for
service and nobody read through it yep
I'm going to sign up the Spotify four
years ago now GDL communicate I get
maybe new bike at some of the like
playlists when Junko really takes it in
the voting is not mandatory
yeah we'll a lot of providers of
services have all the user base as well
to really verify a new set of terms and
conditions so yeah it's not two
questions really going on so come main
actually EPR kicks in when it officially
applies everything has to be valid from
then so there's almost no history so if
they sign and not come to Sekhmet when
they site because if you signed your
particular weird a little weird kind of
way before without certain rights you
now will have those rights from a next
year
however those new rights will come with
contracts and every contract from May
next year last be rewritten so every
term the condition you have ever signed
will have to be we consented we sign
I'm a next year essentially every
contract and I mean every contract in
the whole of the EU will happy we don't
manage here so Facebook okay Google+
Karen they're going to be taking me to
say if we have everything well
everything well and some of it you've
already signed like Google of started
rolling out some new new stuff and we
sort of get used to it or get bit blind
to it so a question does it's almost the
effect its retrospectively inviting that
contract yeah yeah essentially yeah so
from May next year it's like it didn't
matter what happened before now you have
this right you have the right to erase
you even I'm a customer ten years ago so
for inside the customer British Gas ten
years ago from me actually I came up and
say it's only trace of me if there is
delete it you've got no right to it
process assures use already so well is
the really good question about how far
does a ready to go and what can you do
and what you should do and ultimately at
the right inside the law inside gdpr
says you have to do as a company the
best you can you know what's feasible
you know if it's going to cost you a
million pounds and you want to go on a
shop you'd say and I won't do it or I
can't do it at best I will do this so my
advice for everyone is always do as much
as you can and advise what you can't and
why and help the kind of the people on
the ground the data subject understand
why and what's going on and most of time
people don't really how many of you have
really phoned up someone sort of raised
my data or what date have you gotten me
usually many people do I've just
basically either our souls or what is it
or they're just really angry with the
company so yes this is a great point so
and all these rights are caveated by
what's feasible what you can do and what
other things come into play it's great
point
so what referencing a referencing yeah
so so anything you're saying
yeah so yes it's sort of yeah loops in
and that mean more detail about Docs if
you're in the credit industry there's
some other cool bad stuff as well so so
basically a look at a finance
organization they have like minimums of
happy editing 7 years so I can't say I
left and nothing building cited last
week now arrays my data because that's a
good example where they say yeah in
seven years we'll start talking about it
there's certain things you can can't do
I work with a housing leasing company
and they have to keep everything 10
years plus their largest lease which is
20 years so essentially it's best
endeavors but any other laws that come
into play and in the data collection
laws legal laws credit referencing laws
well there's kind of other things they
override gdpr he's also just invoice
yeah yeah this is a cracking point this
about and we have this view and all of
us are sort of guilty for it an
insecurity of let's create a data Lake
so it's this idea of let's collect all
the data we can on everything we can
because one day will be useful won't it
and I know a big system integrator that
has done this create this massive data
Lake and one day they will find a use
for it and it spent millions on it and
gdpr comes along and goes you should not
collect data in the first place unless
you have identifiable reason why you
need it
so in all contexts when you're
collecting data you shouldn't be asking
for ten different things and I'd be a
really great example when you signed up
still con it asks you certain bits of
information but other cons ask you for
more I mean like why do you need that
you'd actually need it to get give me
access to the conference so you should
really give me a bill to say no to
everything it's not basically opt out of
giving that information or things like
if you come to steal con what is your
sexual preference they've no need for
that are you a member of a trade union
they've no need for that so that's the
kind of thing where you shouldn't be
asking stuff you don't need and you
shouldn't be collecting data and
processing it unless you've got a good
reason for it
intention was making the big production
out they don't see that's yeah it's like
not everybody not every one of those out
there yeah this is this is a great point
if the people looking at GDP are is like
like discipline the genesis of data
protection in reality Genesis happened
earlier on we're now in like Leviticus
or juice your honor may good that one
but so we're basically they're further
down line but essentially Data
Protection Act or data station detect
director when it came out V you had
loads great stuff in it
it's just that haven't ignored it and so
from looking TV browsers brand new thing
can I just with yeah yeah exactly no one
who really enforced it much especially I
feel in the UK and so people said well
there's an accepted behavior and I'll
talk about some examples of that link
you and join if we just do on a little
bit quicker and then we'll keep getting
through them it might be some boring
bits waking up some questions in a bit
but yep so another way is it's quite
it's a small one but essentially if your
data is out there then you want the
right to rectification so essentially
someone's places something about you
it's not right you've got the ability to
say to them you've got my Jeff details
wrong or whatever or or good example is
you change your name to 10 different
reasons when a pretty modern site of
these days and people's name change the
dress changes genders change whatever
you have the right say to the people you
have this data amend it make it right
and you have to do that in without undue
delay which basically means as soon as
possible so I know you're thinking this
is the most exciting thing you'll see
today essentially and you know this is
this is the best thing in the world it's
so so cool well it's if you can argue
that you know the worst jobs out that
there are even worse jobs out there you
know well boring
but the thing is you say that and you
look at it and go yeah I'm not waiting
yeah
spot spot the foreigner and but but we
saw you look at it in gay guy this is
dull and but then cool people come along
and make you start to look at it and go
actually you know Elon Musk comes along
goes well all right let's start turning
boring into something really really cool
he wouldn't work wouldn't want to work
for that company so staged texture is
sort of a bit like that on the surface
it's like oh god why me mean here
talking to listen to Carl but then you
start to get involved in Ingo it's quite
actually quite cool stuff but more
important about that is there's a lot of
money in it and I mean a lot and whether
you're a GD PR consultant or whether
you're doing the projects off the back
of it almost every organization you guys
work for and it's probably got gdpr
project specifically or projects that
come off the back of it or someone said
and now I need a pen test for that or
need assurance for this or whatever this
there's a huge amount there and what do
you think it dull are not at this really
good career pattern yeah money so first
question I always get with brexit is
sorry with this it breaks it go well
surely that comes into play well if you
think about brexit and what's going on
like we don't really know what's
happening just about a pretty much it's
just quite sort of some certainty the
brexit will happen in what March 2019
and so if we play out what's going on
and we really focus on the dates and if
we if you think about the dates with
brexit and where we are now and those
dates if you GT politics in May next
year so we now have European law
applying in the UK so but then a year
later of nine months ten months later we
leave the EU now what's going on is that
the UK government and also the Queen
under instructions from the UK
government she's not an expert on this
by any means it's
is they've both said we're carrying on
so from the key dates in mind from when
we hit brexit in March 2019 in the UK we
will have a mirror or we have the great
repeal Act and the repeal Act says that
anything in UK law adopted from the EU
basically couldn't do a find in replaced
in a place a year with UK is it sort of
that kind of thing they would mal got
are what we call it Data Protection Act
2 or UK GDP are or GDP our next-gen or
with a better machine learning so yeah
that make it better actually
but basically does the key date so it's
happening it's already in law now
because we're part of so if we embrace
EU law it's applying that word applies
key applies from May next year now we
got us before about rolling and the two
best rolls I know are Darren Martin I
might know him in fodox great guy and
Martin Lewis have money-saving expert
and Martin Lewis run as people that like
it doesn't let anyone get away with any
fucking shit at all like any companies
like he's having you and it didn't give
you ten ways of being screwed over and
Darryl's one of the people that you have
a beer with them and he says we could
fucking do that couldn't we we could get
in like that and he comes he's got the
best ideas in the world and one of the
cool things that these two in talking
with down especially in Martin is going
to do it is involved in sort of like
data portability before the ideas this
isn't cause of subject access request
and what that is you might further the
freedom information at associate means
that you can have certain people for
what the data's got on you and it's in
part the Data Protection Act already
essentially in the GD P R that's really
formalized and says a data subject which
is me can submit a subject access
request and say British Gas give me all
the data you have on me and they have to
do that within 30 days and it doesn't
cost anything they can't charge for it
and less I like send ten requests every
day and being our sole unless it's
vexatious it has to be free never do in
30 days that's pretty tough stuff and so
this subject access request
you can basically be a subject access
request role and go out there and do
that and for instance none of this are
really going to do it because we're not
artists generally but when you want to
be what a really nice website to be
would be a website you could go to like
Saar generator calm other than here owns
that and complacently get basically site
nothing there yet the basic go to engage
drop-down which company do you want to
trial British Gas okay my name is
address send and they have to do
Thursday semi on my data that could be
really an asshole move but that's the
kind of thing you could do the subject
address of questions abilities
especially don't ask for your data now
interestingly data privacy event a sort
of focus people are really saying by if
someone asks for your after for that you
need for their data you should give it
to them
my response is if you going up sky and
say give me all my data why are you
doing that because maybe you in ask but
really you just had a bad experience so
my first advice is are always actually
triage the process and if you say what's
up well let's say phony doctors they
give me a data you don't really want
your data you just worried about
malpractice suit you want some evidence
or you want an appointment so often you
don't need to submit the SAR is the
subject access requests or thing it's
about focusing what the customer really
wants so I'm more of a kind of real
world view personal saying as to what
they really want and if it is their data
that's fine but often it isn't the
question but just going sorry oh that
statement yeah you don't you don't get
anything statement so yeah you're
absolutely right so it's always seen
this internal employees just saying give
me all the date you've got me and they
said yeah look for a job but yeah it's
that yeah ex-employees a great one this
is where it comes into this point about
what can you legally do because of
certain requirements you have to keep
data for and if I say delete all my
emails that got me in them while I say
well no because it's two copies of every
email one that you've gotten well the
recipient got so there's like certain
things you can do can't do a legality
but yet it's just trolling on a major
scale
females yeah it's yeah it's a pain so
the next question always get I'll
speaking to American sharp at last night
good good guys saying yeah this is a
European Union and give a shit and you
get this kind of but this kind of
response and so but but the truth of the
matter is that and the week so let's
let's talk about skating whether it
actually does matter so the European
Union GDP our remember I said it's
focused on you not companies so if a
company around the world is targeting
you for business services or whatever
was got your data because they're
interacting you let's let's say American
Airlines let's say they had no offices
outside of the US but they were still
selling in sterling or still with
selling to people in the UK and we're
still taking the UK transactions that's
a good example of where they are parked
in the UK in Europe and therefore
they're in scope so therefore any
personal data they processed relating to
EU is fully inside GDP are and what
happens is that if you're outside of the
EU but you're in scope you have to
appoint a representative inside the EU
and that representative is your bitch
that is going to get screwed by the
regulator so essentially when the
Italian regulator says you've been
messing around with the Italian people
they come after the local presence of
that companies right great question so
the scope of gdpr is essentially on fire
level data so and you think about what
that is so empty on the computer
anything backed up that can be restored
onto a computer anything the clearance a
filing cabinet I like to think of it as
anything that if you had a temp they
would like to steal you know it's a
stuff that was my final day
grab those files run off so it's
essentially not stuff on a whiteboard
it's not stuff in a notepad that's
unstructured and not stuff on post-it
notes
anything else that's viable is in scope
so it all depends on that what a system
or fire it's on the computer it's
searchable so that which viable GPR
brings IP addresses oh yeah IP addresses
IP address and sign up to Google by my
appearance that you know you want well
and I see how I do business so well this
is a great point so yeah great great
great point everyone so in GDP our RG
Pro is all about personal data and they
define personal data is anything that
can be used let's say can be used to
help identify a natural person and our
natural person is one of us a natural
person is a European citizen or resident
that's not dead and ie people that care
about six dead people you see down so
but the point is an IP address can
sometimes you have to look at the
context of it so let's say if it's one
public IP about of AOL to global proxy
for a billion people behind it
irrelevant if it's a public IP of
somebody in a County where there's one
house
thank you know who it is so that's the
kind of concepts of it so a log file if
there's data in that can help identify
people absolutely scope you want to
protect it so how are you makes me laugh
indicate that we actually delivering it
yeah it's a really good question we put
the subject taxes request process a key
part of it is okay thank to the question
who are you
and so you've got to ask for certain
amounts of data if you don't ask for too
much continually that kind of you know
the war again but the idea is ask for
what you can and if there were audio
customer you probably already got a
methodology there but that's a good
point stuff you have to think about and
how you provide it as well so this whole
fuck this shit you're not my mother
well person wish your mother is
Elizabeth denim and at CSC in the UK she
is what's known as the Information
Commissioner so if you hear about people
say the IC o---- that's the stance of
the Information Commissioner's Office
dodgy talking about her office in
Wilmslow not on physical one but all the
people in it but she is the Information
Commissioner and Canadian cool and she
really really knows her shit she's
really really she's not previously
activists she just gets it so she's like
well
if you really tried if you trained only
people on dates per section and you
still fail because of some super zero
day nation state whatever so I player
you know you did a good job as opposed
to you took the piss you're getting
fined and that's really the whole
premise of way we're going that's going
to cutting through that crap
so the ico in the UK is one is the UK
regulator and there's a single appointed
canonical a one-stop shop of a single
regulator like head regulator in every
country or 28 countries in the EU and
they're the people that enforce give you
advice cool thing about them even though
in government Department really and
they're really helpful just email them
or phone them up and say I'm doing this
thing with data or IP address in a log
file and they go yeah in this context
here's ten different examples Wyatt
Wyatt is and here's where we find
someone that did this on the other
that's really cool not like a government
department so I really like the ICF some
people hate them but they're dicks so
and the other big thing big bullshit
thing is about fines so you'll hear this
thing about 4% so inside GDP are four
percent of your global turnover of your
parent company is the biggest you can be
fined so in the case of Google that's in
the billions and people saying everyone
was getting at fine four percent of the
global revenue or if you're small
companies I say under half a billion
revenue the maximum is 20 million euros
which is a lot of money for corner sharp
so people get put out of business and
this can be really bad it's not going to
happen and this is reality for a global
mega 4 percent fine it's gonna be so
unlikely and there's a few reasons for
that one well the finds themselves have
to be dis wasted and it's a really cool
word they actually use it inside the law
this way so the idea is they sort of
know it's basically goes a bit further
like we want to find 10 million pounds
but we want to stop every one now so we
basically find you a bit more which is
court sort of cool at the same time if
they go too high then they're putting
people out of business and everyone's
just going to go now and it's not going
to bother so stupid
we've got to sort of be reasonable now
at the moment in the UK we have a limit
of 500,000 pounds under the Data
Protection Act so we're moving from 500k
up to 20 million euros or potentially
billions depending on how big you are
now what
the other reasons other cool thing with
fines is only you countries meet
together in this little board and talk
about harmonizing all the rules are
harmonized inside the law is a
regulation but the cool thing is finds
out as well today one Italy might come
out and go right way to find someone and
just prove we've got to find someone
million quid or million euros but then
if certainly Germany go what for the
same offense we're going to go 50
million then suddenly out of sync a bit
they have to keep meeting to keep it
kind of ratcheting up so we have to
start off make a point but it can't
start off too high because nowhere to go
and then start leveling out these kind
of levels but for this thing of copper
may next year if you don't train if you
don't for instance by our super duper
machine learning algorithm whatever then
you're going to get fine 4% if your
whatever is just bullshit so if you hear
those kind of numbers just take it with
a booking create assault and say yeah
that's fine we have to do stuff but the
bigger point is it's not about being
faster than the bear if you look at
thing killers as dynamos are there and
say it's not being faster than the
person next to you if you're an industry
let's say finance don't be the worst in
finance be one of the best ones you to
the best just think the ico with our
little team over in well-known shesha
they're the ones that have got to do
this work regulate advise whatever
they're going to go after the
low-hanging fruit and if you're the ones
making an effort you only good place 10
fine to go to Central Treasury in the UK
which is basically their kind of inflow
for them to go and do what they want
like all war money yeah yeah exactly
where's the ICO don't get any event
fortunate well not directly and they
said they don't actually want any direct
yeah this is a good point so there's
actually sort of two level to find
you've got this kind of Maxim headline
find a four percent or 20 million euros
and those are offenses like rights
focused really or a specific focus on
data security and incidents whereas
there's a lower level of fine and a low
level of finds interesting is actually
for weird concepts
if you ignore generally security or if
you try and get consent from a child
well won't finding as much it's a bit
backward and that kind of thinking but
essentially there's two levels of finds
have said so when people are dancing
around with fine to take it a pinch of
salt and kind of move on now let's talk
yes so fine
technically do apply to everyone so
whether it be public sector private
sector or charity which is called a
third sector now the problem is that you
can't start finding NHS ten million
pounds because they may go alright
there's 10 million pounds can I have 10
million pounds please for my budget it
just doesn't make sense and and charity
as well they can't stop what in charge
that business but let's talk about
charity specifically cancer research
they got find I think it was 16 K a few
months ago and that nine charities got
fined really badly by the ICO and what
happened was they were doing a number of
things that were legal but accepted
perhapses currently in the UK now one of
things the all the charities were doing
they got fined were wealth screening now
well screening is this thing where
essentially I donate to cancer research
UK given that my details they then get
that data set go to Companies House and
get the other dataset who's a company
director and then go to lakes they
LinkedIn and go let's get that data set
motor together and go Oh Carl Gottlieb
donor company director works in IT all
money right and then put me on to the
big donor list I'm now wealthy
apparently and then I'll start getting
targeted for more money in a different
kind of way that's well screening
perfectly legal if you ask for consent
which none of them did because because
one it was an accepted practice so why
would you and this is illegal now in
subject protection at not even gdpr but
the great line is from all charities
they said we would ask for consent but
if we did no one would give it
now imagine that in a kind of sexual
harassment suit like I would have asked
her but she's going to say no so when
it's yeah so it mom
yeah it's for the ICS web now Who am I
to say what you yeah empowering you with
the law so I'm so yeah they got fine
force doing stuff like that and it's a
real it's quite heartbreaking to see
fines for charities and you think what
great on street or cancer research doing
where that money actually goes specially
Great Ormond Street quite visceral but
some Google is a great example I just
said before about this for something non
debts fine four percent well I decided
to eat about outside of data protection
law
gibble just got fined three four three
point four percent of their global
parents turnover for competition law for
there was it whatsapp acquisition the
way to handle that and talk talk
so it shows they've got to you know they
can do this kind of stuff and talk to it
was a good example where they got fined
for basically being complete dicks and
what happened with talk to was yeah
there's book wall security didn't even
have a wife or whatever and got done by
sequel injection by script kitty but
everyone that could happen to anyone
really it's not that bad but it's the
fact that they've leaked so much data
out and then handled it so badly and the
IC have said if you get breached work
with us phone this up let's have a chat
don't be an ass about it so what does a
breach look like well at the beach and
so a bit apparently a breach dive about
data being coming out or people trying
to get in so over here that's a breach
but essentially those are two of the
worst stockbrokers I could find on
secure and see my wife good googling and
so if you talk about breach and breach
handling what did you what gdpr says is
that which is horizons scenarios is that
if you get breached
you have to notify the ICO or data
subjects are basically customers
depending on the impact so else plan
example out you've got an encrypted
laptop full disk encryption and leave it
on the trainer's go an Excel spreadsheet
armed with some children's
faces and full Excel effort details all
about the name address should you inform
anyone well under the GDP are no GPR
says you don't legally have to you can
if you want to you can tell anyone you
want that's relevant but you don't
legally have to because they would argue
that the encryption means that there is
no feasible ways that data to be
recovered essentially there's no data
there now other people might argue yet
data is only encrypts it for a few years
until people come up with a way of
decrypting it but that encryption is in
that is an area where there is guidance
saying look that's a kind of
circumstance and it's all about impact
it's can people be hurt by this
if I leave names and emails from less a
still con in a bid in Sheffield could
that hurt people will only people are
emerging through the bin analogy
believes that really sensitive date like
going to hurt people so this is the kind
of difficulty that way you have a breach
like their AAA did when they've got now
legally 72 hours to notify people and
yes notify the icao the regulator and
notify potentially if you're if you're
impacted and so this is sort of
problematic because it means you have to
very quickly work out what's gone out
there is it even your data you know if
you find a spreadsheet on place pin with
names addresses and I'd say Scottish gas
that's your data is it how do you know
how do you know if as a company if I
said to you there's a spreadsheet names
and email addresses that your data has
been leaked on place VIN how would you
know how do you know it's not somebody
else's and that's that's problem one
let's say you know it is you then got to
think what is the impact that this I've
got out has it been maliciously stolen
or is it one journalist we know has got
it and therefore no one else has if
that's the case and it's not been locked
down had it been leaked or has the
journalist got it from a tip now these
are all really difficult things and then
it's a case of what can people do about
it is that going to hurt people is name
some dress is going to hurt people as
own phone book so there's a lot of stuff
that goes in and we can't why always
those people say is especially techies
is data breach handling is actually
really complex it's really an art and
you must have a process of how you're
going to handle it and assess assess
what you do quickly so you know what how
to process
but it's not just a case of something
happened tell the world we can't have
that kind of view of things an AAA was a
great example where a lot of people
jumped on the view of something's
happened tell the world and a a sort of
did the opposite of said well we don't
really know what we'd do so I'm not
gonna do anything and got caught by that
and and we'll talk more about the a in a
minute but thought thought was a great
example of what not to do and they
basically said hardly not affected
nothing bad to really happened
no one's going out fished the never bad
thing did happen people got fishing
people got hit by it they didn't know
how much data got stolen they had no
security it was and they tried to evade
the icao it's a complete mess and chief
exactly looks like Harry Potter got
fired and so fantastical Bank is another
example of where they just messed up a
breach handling as well
now gdpr says that as a controller which
is me to hold data like a D as a
customer let's say Scottish power their
controller you give data to them they
might send all our data to Microsoft as
your for hosting in the background or
backups or whatever now they're the
processor processes defined it's someone
that takes a direction so what's cool is
that previously like now if your loss of
data it's like whatevs
we're in some now incoming in GDP our
whoever's liable right hilariously
whoever fucked up the most is going to
get fined the most it gets a portion so
that's a really nice thing to bring
processes into scope but just moving on
to the a a per second so press the
photographer chap you'll see floating
around actually quoted it and asked the
ICO what their view of it is now if we
sort of dissect Chris's tweet a little
bit so Kourt first thing is he could
tweet the ICO and get an answer how many
government departments can you get an
authoritative answer on that's really
really cool because got people on
Twitter waiting for this and you know
pretty much know that stuff so the first
thing is sort of the question really is
should they should the a have notified
people now in the current law unless
you're a telco or a bank let's say like
salt talk or Tesco Bank you don't have
to legally inform data subjects like you
you'd have to do that's and this is why
we look at American press it looks like
this breach is happening every second
because they're always notifying people
could a lot of them have to do with in
UK so telcos or banks so AAA never had
to actually tell you that it went on now
they should at certain stages but they
didn't so the first question is should
they did they have to tell you the
answer is no but the question is some
more really should and what the ICO came
out with a bit of a kind of woolly
answer but essentially they said the
focus really is you have whatever
happens when you get breached or not how
have you handle the breach
you still keep data safe the EPP screw
up the data if you even if you notify
people beautifully in breaches it's
still lost the data is still screwed up
is still gonna come after you depending
on what happened okay so talk talk it
was a stupid sequel injection thing
they're worth a fine if it was a
nation-state thing like potentially Sony
that he can maybe say maybe let them off
so and they're saying yeah we'll get
investigate it in the art but that's a
cool example of where the ico are
getting involved again so let's talk
about some more trolling stuff so we
talked about whistleblowing now the cool
thing about all this is at the moment
most people working companies got no way
of whistleblowing some really big ones
do there but whistleblowing email just
where you can say I think bad things
happening go and look into it please
don't find me I hope this emails
anonymous it probably isn't damn I'm
fired where is that now under GDP are
really cuz you know that some teeth
going into it you can tweet them you can
tweet them ago I work for a dickhead
company please go and look into them
they've just stored all the data in a
bin somewhere you might want have a look
you know yes you can be a complete nob
and be a troll on it or you can be a
legitimate whistleblower now that again
if you think about this putting power
into your hands you're currently whether
you're a European citizen or not you are
currently here now which means you're a
resident which means you are all inside
scope of GDP are so we all have this
kind of right so that's another example
of where you can be an ass or you can be
sort of quite cool about it and so try
and improve things so I'm going to sort
by to eat my shit moment now and eat my
shit moment it's the really really
shitty stuff that you all used to
and British institution Royal Mail let's
talk about them this is a consent form
currently which says basically here's
some sick boxes if you do not wish us to
do it here's some more tick boxes again
and they flip the language around so
they actually moved from do not wish to
do so you're either going to tick all of
them on none of them and you're still
going to get screwed and that's the kind
of shit that's been going on and it's
been technically legal for a while under
sort of data collection law in the UK
and so that is changing and the cool
thing is that some may look at that and
you go this is it's just stupid
there's actually a website called called
the dark patterns there focuses on this
and you get to dark patterns about
Twitter handle where it basically all
the weird ways they trick you into
buying like extra insurance on flights
and stuff and mishandling content like
that so um you know it's all my reaction
it really is like it's bullshit and it's
simple just ask for it you know this is
what it should be it's like do you want
subscribe yesterday it's called if you
want to subscribe but what's been going
on have been trying to trick you into
getting your data and thinking somehow
that's valuable but having data on
people that donors who have given you in
the first place is stupid you end up
with these massive databases either
customers ago yeah I've got million
emails on my list so don't buy from it
no what's the point man so people really
should be thinking about minimization
which is a great point earlier on about
saying well I don't think you've got a
million emails of crap in your Excel
spreadsheet how about you get it down
for people that actually want consent
like for instance I want to consent to
Tesco loyalty club so get money off I
want to do that that's great I do want
to consents to the Aldi Club because I'm
not really bothers cheap enough so don't
force me into suffer that one two and
the quality of data is always going to
be much higher but better for business
if you get consent right so let's talk
about some more really really big
bullshit stuff and your big Arne level
bullshit stuff so let's talk about
adequacy not inadequacy like some of us
might feel but just a talk about this
thing called adequacy and adequacy is
this view that
European Union looked at country and go
your adequate from a data protection
perspective some really dullards that
work for them to have to do this and
there's another obsession going on in
summer and one of the assessments
they're doing is at the US and adequacy
means that they trust another country to
send data there so in the clip in a
moment we have something called privacy
shield privacy shield is like the child
of something called safe harbor which
was an agreement that said us don't mess
around with data I trust you I trust you
right the u.s. went bust and so yeah and
then it's a big part of that so the
after we write it and came up with
privacy shield and proof shields like it
kind of seriously guys don't mess around
with our data and inside the EU well
okay - all deemed an equal when brexit
happens people saying well surely we've
got to meet some aim about this won't be
deemed adequate or not or if privacy
shield fails because trumps going to go
know and break apart all data section
laws in the US what's going to happen
surely all that if those two agreements
fail the u k-- n us can no longer
process european data it's not going to
happen people have you saying this i'm
not apologetic if the US what if the
european union one day say us is no
longer adequate don't send them data but
we can watch you stop using us companies
is it going to happen it's not going to
happen so I'm unapologetic in saying
that's not your problem
it's a problem for European bureaucrats
policies and yes there's some work to do
yes that's fine but it's going to work
out UK isn't just going to become an
island where we can't process European
data it's not going to happen and
therefore yes there'll be some more
agreements not your privacy shield to or
whatever but it won't affect any data
flows that you can hold me to learn
happily and the other one is that okay
how to fix GPR encryption encryption
sees at the answer so
I am so that second line I am say like
song goes I've got PGP key my what fuck
and like get yeah maybe I don't deem
that yeah email or your DM me say well
yes basically encryption what's
encryption do yet encryption anonymizes
data or takes it out of the kind of
ability to let's say you get breached
laptop on a train
it doesn't take it out scope like
personal data doesn't disappear
it's just encrypted if I've got a laptop
with a full disk encryption and post-it
note underneath with my password are
still in scope of GDP are so the
encryption is not a magic answer it
helps massively if you encrypt all your
data make it really hard to get to the
keys or whatever really well key managed
you know you could almost argue that
it's a deleting data encrypts it and
throw away the key whatever the point is
encryption doesn't take data out scape
it doesn't absolve you of gdpr
it's still all together the data is
still there it just looks a bit
different might have some greed words in
it and so the point is encrypt as much
you can they come nicely safe way but
yeah you better protect the keys as well
so for me that's that kind of massive
pile of bullshit and you will see those
two things again again encryption or
adequacy UK is going to fall for cliff
well it's kind of stuff yeah don't worry
about it so what do I want to leave you
with really and one word money money
it's one of the biggest motivators we've
got and you can have a really really fun
job that's related to data protection
please don't shy away from it is this
kind of really dry dull things that you
can't get anything out of if you are the
most aggressive pentester red teamer
that hates even the word data well the
big area where money is coming into that
space is saying I don't care about
vulnerabilities find some data now at
the end of a red team's hat so here's
what we found it's like thousand
vulnerabilities and it usually goes I'll
put that in my filing cabinet the shape
like a bin where really what you say is
we found this spreadsheet we found this
piece of data and we found this and this
will be a fine on the GPR
that's the stuff that goes right okay I
was going to see so that's going to
chief exec how do we have a four million
pound project to mitigate that what
would you recommend is it firewalls is
it consultancy what do we need to do who
do we need to train if you only want
this training can you do train and give
you some more consultants they already
do another test and it sounds and this
is my I'm sort of salesman as well I'm
not great well and so but what happens
is every kind of an issue that is really
relevant to a board level issue and now
gdpr
is on every board risk register if you
can tap in for that even if it's just
through the route you're currently in
whether the most hardcore tacky things
or training thing or whatever if you can
tap into that create a need then what
we're seeing is budgets being created
all over the place so I'm not saying to
you go and be a date protection officer
don't be a consultant like me in data
section or GDP or whatever I'm saying
understand it and understand how you can
use it to do the stuff you love and make
a lot of money day rates for data
protection consultancy because massive
shortage of them now are pretty damn
good come May next year it's going to be
taking them it's going to be great and
all the work that's going to spin out of
that it's going to be fantastic as well
so wherever you are you will financially
in career level benefit if you've got
the right attitude over the next year on
it so have a bit of a read and go make
some money get some questions it's going
to be far more accessible and tangible
to an exec board to provide budgets into
organizations and hey Vaughn ability to
Anwar so it's a good way to not just
make money but get money to do thing
exactly what does the vulnerability look
like you can't rule one out on piece of
paper where so there's an Excel
spreadsheet everyone knows what that
looks like and feels like works on you
so it's an Excel spreadsheet is people's
passwords on or data or whatever or
inside leg measurement that's visceral
we understand what is and saying there
is a spreadsheet floating around the
internet but you know you absolutely
right it's really another kind of
language that connects with people so I
feel thinking really technical stuff try
and relate it to this
need of data focus stuff any more
questions at the backs I'll open fire
person yes politely so no so there's a
point that is actually the ISO of great
they've actually got guidance on current
law and future law about CCTV and
essentially if because that can if it's
used to biometric data by magic reasons
there's greater levels of security
handling around it so look for guidance
on that the yeas and escapes I'll just
get something to some subject I pursue
Christ yeah
so essentially this access request is
always to the controller because there
are people holding it like responsible
for your data if they've got a joint
controller which is where they're kind
of like half working with somebody else
then they'll have an agreement of who
can owns that process when they've got
processor behind the scenes that they'll
have they'll be the proxy to go and ask
for the data they need they won't defer
you out to them all you have to do speed
to the control essentially wants that's
their responsibility yes they go take
days to rotate on board
finally this has been a quiet be you
know page so this comes back to great
questions this comes back to other laws
so where there's other requirements to
on top of that data so let's say a
criminal a good example at the moment is
PPI claims banks saying I want to keep
it longer in cases another screw-up and
after we're experts we go back and give
you some money
so in those considered Constance's let's
say criminal background checks or could
be using a criminal case they Trump gdpr
and so therefore you'd have to get back
to the
subject and say look we can do so much
yeah yeah exactly this um essentially
they'll do as much they can as they have
to do and it's lunch almost so thank you
everyone thank you for the question
[Applause]
you