okay hi Diane I'm Avada Kedavra I'm like
everything it's the easiest way to find
me if you can remember it I've been
informed that it's very long and very
difficult to remember but I don't really
understand why because it's like Harry
Potter killing curse but with cat what
is sorry it's like that table - I don't
understand why it's so hard to remember
I think it's super clever
alright so I work for Mozilla and I work
with rust a lot I don't know how many of
you have heard of rust have used rust
there are a lot of people who are crazy
about rust and it's pretty misty and you
have this idea of safe versus unsafe
so when we talk about rust safety
basically you're guaranteed type safety
and memory safety
I know I've spent some time doing buffer
overflows and integer overflows and such
so it's really nice that these are
prevented by default in a language it
really limits the sort of undefined
behavior that you see by default all
these things are are prevented young
guns have dangling pointers data races
integer overflow and debug builds buffer
overflows and iterator invalidation most
of these are done at compile time
integer and buffer overflow Prevention's
are done at run time but we can minimize
these by idiomatic rust uses uses
iterators so generally speaking if you
have an array you're not iterating over
it with indices if you do in safe rust
you can still overflow your buffer if
you code like a proper little
restoration then you're not going to
because you're going to use an iterator
so you're not going to overflow because
that orator knows where the end of the
buffer is um so unsafe like what does
this even mean there are things that you
cannot do and say
Frost so we have to go and look at what
this borrowed checker thing is the
borrowed checker when you code and Russ
is both your best friend and your worst
enemy it's always yelling at you and
then you have an argument with it turns
out borrowed checkers right you're wrong
100% of the time you are never ever
right so if you have a value and you
assign it to a variable X X owns the
value now you assign that you assign a
same value to X I mean to Y now why on
is it it's moved from X to Y if X tries
to access the variable that is now owned
by Y the compiler will throw a beautiful
error
well looks a lot like this you can
borrow a value immutably as many times
as you want but you cannot change it you
can only have one mutable reference at a
time otherwise you invalidate all of
these safety guarantees that you have in
safe rest what this does is this
prevents dangling pointers um you rest
checks the lifetimes of variables
instead of garbage collecting you just
make sure that nothing's ever deleted
until you're done using it so like I
said you can't do everything in safe
blocks sometimes you really have to
violate these rules there's one
situation in particular that I'll
highlight in like a minute
and the key thing that you can do and
unsafe rust is you can dereference raw
pointers usually you do not want to be
messing around with raw pointers when
you're in safe for us
well you never want to mess around with
with raw pointers and safe rest and
generally speaking as most of us are
aware messing with raw pointers can be a
recipe for disaster
right there's one function in particular
mmm transmute where you just take a
point
and you tell it to be anything you want
it to be and it's extremely terrifying I
was using it once and then I told my
bosses like you know I feel like there's
got to be a better way to do this I
really feel like I should not be doing
this he's like yeah I should do
something horribly wrong anyways the way
that we control it is you denote
something as an unsafe function or an
unsafe block you can only call unsafe
code from other unsafe code but you can
encapsulate it so like if we had a
function foo cuz I wanted to call unsafe
so what you would do is you would have
function foo and then in the unsafe
block you would call unsafe fail so that
way you can encapsulate unsafety within
safety and this is how the standard
library handles a lot of this so you can
do tons of things with purely idiomatic
safe rust including like coal see
functions because they'll be wrapped in
a safe wrapper so this is the results of
little programs that I wrote on the rest
compiler code so the rest compiler is
written and rest which is always a
really great spot to be when your
language and what it does is the
compiler is composed of different
modules so all of these lines here these
are different modules and the little
numbers that you can't read are the
percentage of unsafe functions and
unsafe codes and also the number of
panics so panics are basically oh no
something's gone horribly wrong we need
to abort runtime immediately and this
can be kind of dangerous when you use
them they are going to lead to undefined
behavior but they will you know
terminate your program unexpectedly so
shows the amount of unsafe code and all
the compiler modules
a lot of them are zero so that's good
you know that means that the rest
compiler is theoretically pretty decent
rust code one problem is a lot of people
come to rust from C and they're like
iterators doesn't want to use an
iterator just like let me write a for
loop like I usually do right but that's
where you get into problems and if we
want to write C for code not only do we
have to use the safe language we also
have to write it safer so one problem
the worst is that I saw at a glance
five minutes ago with some Lib
collections at 25% and this makes sense
if you're implementing the collection
data structures you're going to need to
use on save code how it is anyways so
the way I did this is I just went text
line by line have you ever used count
lines of code yeah I just went line by
line and counted the number of unsaved
code this is like the worst way possible
to do it but yeah it gives you a pretty
good idea of how safe the code is
written realistically you need to create
a simplified abstract syntax tree and
test your predicates and all these
things that programming languages people
love to talk about can also categorize
the the unsafe code as is it FF I you
know are you calling in C codes are you
just writing on safe code and then
borrow a checker I don't know why there
aren't more memes about the borrowed
checker because it really is your best
friend and your worst enemy when you're
developing a rough so maybe someday I'll
have time get around to this ideally
what I'd like to do is look at the rust
ecosystem as a whole script over all
github all the people who are trying
rust out and then ditch it immediately
and then some of the people stick with
it and see you know our rust programmers
coding safe-ish rust and you know what
can we do
given these measurements of safety for
libraries like is everyone using some
library that's a ton of unsafe space on
which
can use attack surface realistically
tsunamis this is my cat Batman this is
how you find me hi I'm Avada Kedavra
everywhere any questions I mean I could
probably add all of these up but now
they're broken out by module and you
just go over it for what it's worth I
really enjoy working with rust it's got
a bit of a learning curve but cargo the
package manager is fabulous I love the
package manager and that's how I judge
languages now so I like your package
manager or not maybe else so like
something that you can look at if your
is if you are do referencing raw
pointers or if you are calling and
demand transmit functions I mentioned
earlier those should kind of trigger
warning signs like we really need to
make sure that we aren't doing something
horribly wrong here this might be
somewhere to dig a little further to
stuff like that really and if someone
decides another really bad smell for
rust would be if you iterate over a
collection using indexes indices index
me if you don't use an iterator because
that's a really easy way to violate all
the safety guarantees without going into
unsafe code
i Bullock with ecology and recline
models to my sort particular on face I
should certainly not for us so I know
like there's built in cargo fuzz
so you can fuzz programs pretty easily
aside from that maybe I don't know so in
the income statement there absolutely no
change whatsoever going to cold and the
Crocker will be happy to do whatever you
know not necessarily an unsafe code it's
not like the Wild West like it's not you
know all holds barred like let's just do
whatever we want what it allows are
basically these things so compared to
see the undefined behavior that you can
get and unsafe for us is very limited
you're generally not going to get
arbitrary thankful so yeah so I mean if
you if you go you know from safe Russ
into an unsafe block and you're calling
into C code and that C code there's all
sorts of ridiculous stuff yes then all
sorts of ridiculous things could happen
in that C code that is being called from
Raja and there is so there's I'm working
doing some work to try to figure out you
know how we can protect ourselves on the
rough side when you're calling into
these unsafe boxes and these unsafe C
functions it turns out that really the
only unsafe boundary that you can say
you know is really secure like the hard
wall is this module level so basically
just like the project level you know
like I work on a browser and so our
ideas modules is you know we have the
net crate and we have the style crate
and we have the script crate so those
top level module those would be the
unsafe boundary so if you did something
horrible it would be consumed it would
become contained yes that's the word it
was keyboard it would be contained to
that module they can affect the entire
application the entire module oh it can
affect the entire module the module is
not necessarily the entire application
it could be but it could also be a
component and you know where it rest is
a pretty new language it hit 1.0 and
2015 so you know we're working on trying
to figure out what exactly it means to
be unsafe and what exactly are the
limits on safety cool language fun to
work with it does make your life easier
once you get used to dealing with the
mr. Barrow checker all right sounds good
if you're interested in using Rustom
they're on IRC a rush channel rust
beginners channel everyone's very
helpful everyone's very friendly thank
you
[Applause]