if you work I've done its current
security work so Firefox and firefox for
android I've been
building tools and things so if you use
tools like I was exactly been helping
Simon various out with a bunch of the
newer features on that and and being
promised her that I both have the
reasons a lot to talk about this and
some experience with the subject matter
so Mozilla came up with content security
policy it's a technology that was her
would you be specified by ms other
people and I worked on it a bit in
Firefox developer tools warnings that
you can assist he was code I wrote and a
better reason to talk about it because
by coming to Brazil my colleagues in the
various browser vendors that work
together on building standards for the
web they work very hard to build
security features for the platform that
we're providing people and yet they are
fairly rarely used so I want to improve
web security we have a situation
particularly with this technology that
it's really heavily only used sertoli
some numbers there is a blog recently
most recent American which
you know you're doing presentation you
told me to ignoring these screens and
having different ears if you're wanting
to have more than one tab it's a good
idea if you're going to use so this is
from the very very code blog and they
did a head of survey will over to the
very security that is in hand health and
they're used and when it's finally
learned it will see some numbers on on
various security payers and among those
numbers are some figures on use of CSP
there we go failure to help us to
improve reception and there we go we can
see that at the top million sites as mr.
violet sir there are approximately 400
of them making use of content security
policy in the survey data so if we
hundred after the top million isn't many
sites and that's a sad thing it's a sad
thing if you build a platform it has a
really useful security feature and
people don't use it too much so that's
really why I want to do the stuff I
wanted to talk about how that's really
useful thing out there and people are
not making enough use of it so in the
talk about CSP that's that that's the
plan for the torque and first of all I'm
gonna start off by explaining some
context because we need to understand
some things before we can make use of
the technology so it starts up talking
about precise riveting and who does work
Network depart
who has the secure websites secure
websites until okay hooters of the
development type stuff this is sad we've
got a room from people at our own
numbers and which so into the red cross
site scripting because that's valuable
context then we're going to talk about
the CSP and what it is and why it was
created I'm going to talk about why CSP
is difficult as a technology for people
to implement and with the focus of the
talk is about making it less awkward
because CSP has been around for a couple
of years now people have stayed away
from any drives and there are tricks
that people can use to make use of it
that men might not be aware of and then
I want to talk about some common
mistakes people make when visiting this
technology so most of all kinds of you
if you know what cross-site scripting is
okay so we'll know a bit of a cross-site
scripting do we know about different
flavors of cross-site scripting share
our game is pretty hamlet reflect
reflect it okay scored okay first two
hunters I expected anything else darn
okay so there we go so sometimes we
categorize cross-site scripting by
reflexes and stored in the case somebody
who doesn't know what those things are
let's have a look at an example of
reflective cross-site scripting so there
we go here's what I made earlier they
say document which takes a parameter
called test we've managed to stick some
stuff on the URL and we request the page
the payload is reflected back to the
client and executed in the browser in
the context of the site Bieber visiting
ok now I'm Don is a little bit different
now sometimes we categorized by whether
a cross-site scripting attack is
reflected or stored we can also
categorize on where the attack happens
and this is white dong cross-site
scripting is interesting because
conventional cross-site scripting your
reflected in stores the glue
before these are vulnerabilities of
existing server code where inputs
provided by the clients is replayed in
the response donbass crops cross-site
scripting takes place on the clients and
as javascript running in the document is
served by the server and the
vulnerability is in that javascript and
what makes that interesting is that you
don't need dynamic content serve from
your server at all to be vulnerable to a
Donald cross-site scripting attack you
could have static content on your
website for example a brochure awareness
it's alongside implications which can
potentially cause problems to the rest
of your application by nature of the
fact that they're horrible to DOM
cross-site scripting and to look at an
example of that again we learn a
document and immediately see the script
is executed but this happens in this one
different way so rather than being
reflected from the server the issue is
actually in the HTML observed we looking
straight ahead we'll see there's a
script element if we look inside the
script opens we'll see that when the
document is loaded something from the
hatch part of the URL is put into
something unsafe in an HTML in this case
and bad things happen it's actually
pretty good advice to never use a range
female if you using original you should
know that there's probably something
faster and there's certain something
safer okay so that's all we need to know
about cross-site scripting cool start
now cross-site scripting shares a
interesting property with lots of other
types of vulnerability and David in the
last session at a conversation where he
was reading of problems with different
sites and what do you think about a
common theme application security if we
think about and stack overflow cigarette
super injection
keep overflows to think about
prescription from an injection
use-after-free longer reaches all that
sort of thing what's the one thing they
all have in fun what one of these
problems have income what unites these
vulnerabilities can we use your input
yeah so user input is data wait what
happens to that data in all of these
cases then yes there is a failure
validation routines possibly and that
results in some decks are being
interpreted as because what instruction
okay so all of these vulnerability
classes they stem from the fact that if
we don't design systems properly there
can be confusion within a system on what
is just data to be processed as data and
what is actually instructions to be
processed as application logic okay so
in the case of a stack overflow you in
the overwriting important pointer in the
case of command injection then you can
make your an interpreter of commands do
something it should and they look pretty
much the same in terms of the mechanism
of how that happened is there like this
all differences but fundamentally is all
have the same problem okay and if we
look at all of the extent we can see
that and over time people have come up
with ways of mitigating vulnerabilities
of each of these types so in the case of
a stack overflow people came up with
ways of putting in Canary values on the
step so you know something too
you can make sure you clean up after
yourself in a safe way or in the case of
sequel injection people came up with
ways of making type safe and
parameterised query so you couldn't put
something in in such a way that it's
unsafe and going back to a little bit or
tell you're on the reason why and
certain legacy PHP techniques for making
database inputs and what we're remove
was because there were other central
ways of doing things and again
developers stayed away from them in
droves and if you do pen testing work on
PHP applications today you still find a
sequel injection everywhere because
developers event to the habit of doing
the wrong thing so content security
policy tries to imitate some of these
mitigation methods and the way it does
it is by saying we'll look and we need
to make sure that we have separated
content then which is data and content
which is instructions and anything which
we can't be sure of as being an
instruction in subway we have to not
execute it okay and the way it does that
is by providing a policy we need to
document asserts the client and
typically it's via response header and
that policy says this document and for
example by default won't have any
England scripts or it won't have any
inline styles and therefore when the
browser see something that looks like an
inline script role in line status as now
I know that I'm not supposed to be doing
anything with inline script or inline
styles so I'm not going to treat them as
instructions I'm not going to execute
that script I'm not going to apply that
style to the document a sense of policy
and it secures content that's all there
is to it and we can talk a little bit
about what those things what policies
look like anna wagner but the key thing
here is we're talking about separation
of denser and instructional talking
about clear delineation between what is
supposed to be code and what is the
place to be and data to
in a different way so let's look for
example here we have a cell phone
content security policy hopefully it's
not broken last time I did this took a
kind of mistake here so but the head of
a top content security policy and we can
do various things we can say things like
defaults or self so this is telling the
document that by default I don't want
you to trust anything that's from a
different origin to the origin that this
document was served from the case a
certain example calm over an SSL then
we're only looking for secure documents
serve for example okay and then we can
refine for various classes we can say
objects or to know I don't really follow
any plugins please any plugins just
don't load them from anywhere this will
out completely and by default in a
Content security policy inline scripts
and inline styles are for then you can
turn that off you can turn anything off
the deposit security policy but by
default inline scripts nothing point
script value attribute so your gamma 0
event handlers they don't work either
and also saying well if anything goes
wrong with this policy if what I'm
trying to apply this policy to this
document something Bronx you know that
one your sign of something going wrong
maybe someones founded a cross-site
scripting attack on our site and they're
trying to exploit our users well you can
send reports to provide a URL to say
send me information what's going on here
so i did a example earlier on of a
reflected cross-site scripting try the
same thing with a sample policy apply
okay so there we go we've got the same
page to be solved for exactly the same
document and the only difference to this
girl mckinley father to network panel
request looks exactly the same the code
is exactly the same all this difference
is that here we have content security
policy as generic as they get just a
light just allow stuff from this origin
and don't allow inline scripts and
inline styles and despite the fact that
script is injected into the document you
can find me know whether up in here
there we go this fighting falcon script
is injected CSP says no i'm not happy
and we get handy little notification to
say thank you setting of a lot of
learning of a resource so we had a
vulnerable document there that was as
vulnerable to the simplest possible
reflective cross-site scripting attack
and because there's a CSP applied to the
document and any browser that supports
content security policy and that's a
growing number that tap would not have
succeeded right so that's a good thing
we like that only security so that's
constant security policy and that's what
it looks like at a high level
the room number browser support like we
do and you know so web distorted it for
a while and so Safari supports it blinks
of course obviously so opera arminta
chrome support it five bucks per
supported alien relations for ages so
it's really only internet explorer that
doesn't support it and I saw recently
that they're working on it now which is
great so we're hoping that means that
soon everyone supports that needs to
subset of this which is good okay and
there are a bunch of different directors
you can apply so the source directives
you can specify where you want certain
things to learn from so by default for
the top or scripts or style model
objects connectors for things like xhr
for making XML HTTP requests or if
you're using web sockets or something
like that the next source is useful to
know about just that talk to that we can
and make connections to and so on so
we've seen an example of a Perseus be
applied to a document and we've got an
understanding of how it works that's
great right everyone should be using
this because even if you've got these
vulnerabilities most of your users have
browsers that mean that they are
invulnerable to the right surely that's
a good thing well actually the numbers
are showing the beginning tell a bit of
a sad story if only four hundred or so
of the top million sites are making use
of CSP I think we'd all agree that's bad
news because we'd like all of the sites
with you to not be following it across
site scripting in the browsers that we
use but it's not all that bad because
there are already some major sites that
make use of this 20 for example they
haven't yet by dcs peter to twitter.com
p version in the side you are using the
browser but everything else they have
applied it to so if you're using the
mobile version of this site if you're
reading the twitter blog if you're using
tweetdeck if you
center of using the translation center
or Twitter for business or any one of
those things Twitter robots ESP
everywhere and that's good and one of
the good things about pretty using it
everywhere is that you can go to Twitter
blog and can read about their stories
and deploying it in these different
sites and they're quite open about what
they've done and how they've done it and
the challenges that they found and the
challenges that they found can be as
useful to us as they come into new
because when we are sending people to
the various standards bodies that we're
looking at this kind of thing we can say
this is a problem in practice because
people have this problem or people have
that problem and that can be a useful
feedback cycle for us so there are
already some major sites using this and
there are some even more major ones who
are shortly 2-5 and have mostly been
waiting on some features of the newer
version the CSP standard that I'll talk
about in a little bit and another place
where is used is actually in web
browsers themselves so a lot of people
don't riddle is this book and who saw
the news in the last week about this
breach browser has written in no embeds
chromium you can build your own web
browser from JavaScript it or see that
yeah okay well lobbying said Wow web
browser written in JavaScript and
actually a lot of most modern browsers
aren't just written in C and C++ lots of
protein stuff tends to be written in
with the technologies Firefox for
example there's a smallish gecko core
and everything will the application
watching this is on top allows written
in javascript is displayed using and
dissolving HTML so it's kind of
analogous to how a web application works
and with the important difference that
if you've gotta cross site scripting
there you've got a big problem so modern
browsers are applying csps to the bits
of the UI and that implements of using
those technologies bits of pro use it in
that way and this is Firefox are being
worked on in that way and another
interesting area are things belonging
and chrome apps or Firefox OS apps if
you have an acronym chrome you have the
option of applying a CSP to that and the
father to us example is an interesting
one because he have a phone where the
entire operating system including things
like the keyboard and the home screen
and stuff are implemented in html5 and
with some of the api's the phones
allowing to you just like being able to
make calls or send SMS or things like
that it can quickly get expensive if
something went wrong with your phone in
that way CSP is applied by default to
anything in file to us that requests any
kind of privileged access to the device
and as a result of this kind of thing we
start to get metrics that tell a very
different story from the injection I
gave at CSP being underused so yes only
about 400 out of the top million sites
make use of a CSP the eighteen percent
of all chrome document loans the
problems the chromium project
CSP of la vida okay now if you're low
adoption makes you think twice about the
technology turn it round and tell
yourself that you're one of the bad
eighty-two percent if you don't use CSP
and hopefully that'll make you think
differently about it so perhaps at this
point you're thinking you know that's
awesome but we've already go outside
okay and some of the restrictions you've
talked to us about already would make
things really hard okay so if you're not
allowing inline scripts by default
that's kind of a headache because we've
got inline scripts all over the place
we're using them for Google Analytics
it's the way our devs did things for
years okay and sure you've told us that
if we apply a policy we can if we want
to turn off things like the restrictions
on inline scripts and inline styles but
then if we do that our policy will be
too relaxed so actually be useful for
allowing inline scripts and we've got a
script injection problem then we're back
where we started right so CSP can be a
series of them or balancing act when we
are applying it to the testing
environments and we really need to think
about what we can do and the reason this
is important for me is that if we build
in security features into browsers if
we're going to the trouble of going
through and the standards process to
build things and it's really important
that the security features that we build
can be applied to the web that we've got
and not just the web that we want to
build because the word that you want to
build sure the internet might be
doubling in terms of the number of sites
that are active every two years or
something like that but that still means
that in two years time half of the sites
are vulnerable to all this legacy stuff
right so what can we do what what's
happened well one of the things that's
happened is that people who went away
and decide that they wanted to use CSP
some of them found problems with
libraries and things that they used
unless LOL it's a nice idea but we can't
use it yet and some of those people went
along to the people whose stuff didn't
work in that environment the went alarms
the authors and things like and jQuery
or other front-end frameworks or even
service I framework saying they're doing
this step here it makes it impossible or
really difficult to apply this
technology that we quite like I can fix
it please and nicely some of the people
that maintain those things have gotten
biomed fix those problems so if you're
using a mobile version of a widely used
JavaScript likely for example you'll
probably find the changes have been made
relatively recently to allow for things
like and usage in scenarios were even
that is disallowed or usage for
scenarios where inline script is awkward
so and so forth so that's a great thing
and I'm on the server side and
frameworks have started gaining support
there are open tickets on the January
project for implementing CSP as part of
the January cool generator and excellent
web framework if he is Python which is
not
good and and debt already support via
third-party modulus for gender James
safe a library called generous ESP which
and I've been doing a bit of work on
recently as well but most importantly
that CSP is getting a bunch of new
features we've realized the fact that if
we're building for the world we've got
there's something that's too restrictive
means that people can use it and so CSP
walk by one or two is is actually now
known how supports to include things
like inline scripts but to do it in a
safe way and probably thinking your
house I can work how's that little
superseded its parent work and now there
are better tools available as well so
some of the things that were really
awkward to start off with like and in
either of the browsers where you're
making use of CSP because protein or
Firefox supported it and you had a CSP
violation the warning messages were
frankly author I told you very little
that would have gone wrong in tribal
finest policy to this document so the
browsers have better support to tell you
or whether on or why and various
third-party tools have been built which
and I need to do things like analyze
your site and find out what would be a
good policy to apply to that site so
that's changed as well so let's look at
the new features in CSP tune and have a
thing about how they work so the first
one is and a feature called non source
now nonce is a number used once we know
what that is and sauce these would be
the scripts that we learn when we are
learning documenting their browser okay
and non source is really quite simple
it's a way of saying okay what we need
to do is we need to distinguish in the
document that's loading between the
stuff that's supposed to be there and
the stuff is really should ok so we're
serving a document it's got scripts in
it already and we need
because we need them to be there but if
a script is injected we don't talk about
2x EG and the way that nod sauce does
this is it says we're going to pray turn
on so we're going to store that in the
policy so now and what we're going to do
is we're going to attack with little
attributes on the script element in the
documents which one can we intend to see
okay so you create the script element
you give it this nonce in the HTML view
/ setback and that is the nonce in the
head of matches the roles on the scripts
attributes you know that this script is
supposed to be real so let's use the
same example that we have before I had
to change it to include some inline
script that was supposed to run so let's
do that and to prove the javascript is
still working first of all the time of
the policy is applied over they live
so that we've got a policy here you see
that that's a non studying in the policy
and to prove that the scripts that are
in line is still executing we can have a
look at the page we can see that there
is no script which is supposed to be
learned there we go so this is the
script that's supposed to be run there
we go so I'll document load we're adding
a click listener on this button to cook
that you can see that it works ok so the
script is meant to be that is still
working but we're still doing our
injection if we look further down in
Dublin we can see that the injected
script earnings is still there
and yet it isn't executed and the only
difference between this script and here
and the one further up is that the one
further up how's this not attribute
settle okay and this be really useful
because if you've got the legacy stuff
all you have to do to change your
application to make use of this is to
set that response header find all the
places where you're doing scripts audit
them carefully to make sure that they
don't have anything in the detector a
MacLean generated by the server for
everything and then add that attributes
to the script tag okay so you can take
something it might be years old it mind
you full of cross-site scripting holes
but because it's an internal system you
need to keep using you need to keep it
running you can apply this to it and as
long as the browser you use internally
supports this feature you've got a way
of mitigating that particular problem
which is great right that's a good thing
but my started out when we talked about
cross-site scripting describing the fact
that the piece there are and scripts
which can run that there is there are
cross-site scripting vectors and things
that can run on the server and things
that can run on the client to know your
Dom based stuff that runs in JavaScript
it doesn't fix the problem completely
for us because we might have your 10 15
years of static content on our website
that we don't really want to have to go
through and change may be used to use an
old content management system that we
don't have a license for anyone we've
got all these generated files we don't
have to go through them all and remove
all the inline scripts and because
they're static we can't do this trip
where they're injecting this header and
this script attribute so what can we do
there and that takes us on to be the
next thing that takes us on to another
CSP to feature which is called a source
so that sauce has something to do with
hashes and something to do script source
again right and in this case what
happens is when we're serving the
document what we do is we say okay we
know that the whole of this document is
not something that we can change it's
something that we serve statically from
this okay it's just an HTML file we
can't inject these scripts attributes
these notes attributes so what would you
do instead is going to take all of the
inline scripts in the document I'm going
to generate a hash of them a case with
each other and then such a 512 ash or
something I'm going to serve a CSP
directive that has in its a list of all
of the hashes to the scripts that we
want to run okay house again we can show
this in action so I'm going to take the
same directives s that we had before I'm
going to do exactly the same thing
you've got the same hash part of the URL
is the same document on the only
differences as you guessed we've applied
at CSP and this time we can see
a hash that sends with that policy that
says there's a script here but I do want
you to run and anything else I don't
want to happen ok so again we've got the
vulnerable home and changed we've still
got this script in the head of the
document which pulled something from the
URL hatch and does bad things with it
it's still there it's completely a
modified but again CSP is saying there
something you try to happen here that
I'm not happy with don't do this please
so the content security policy has again
lot but we can allow other things that
take place in the document to work by
using these hash values no actually this
wasn't the example of wanting to use
maybe I'll go back to that again ok so
those are two new CSP features and
that's kind of nice now I mentioned
earlier on that when you're using these
features you've got to be really really
careful because if for example you wrote
something which took your existing
content and just applied policies to
them using scripts hash using a sauce or
will answer us then you'd have a problem
that you're just giving the tension
vulnerable code a free pass to run in
the browser by so you've got to be
really careful about how you do that
kind of thing now I talked a little bit
earlier on about a Django little they're
called Jango CSP which allows you to do
a bunch of CSP things
well framework the thing that I need for
jos ESP was to say wouldnt it be great
if we have a way not only automatically
inserting the script elements with the
attribute set in the document but also
preventing developers from shooting
themselves in the foot when a user okay
so they only have a custom tag in Django
which says and here is a spirit and
anything that happens within this script
and can work because we've we've set
this afternoon what some attitude as
budgetary but by default if you find
anything within that that is generated
if you find any other Django Taj or any
other Django variables just stop it from
rendering okay so you could create
something which contains a script has
got a automatically applied and nonce
attribute on the script element and if
you try inject anything in life that if
the template design and does something
stupid it says now you can't do that and
but developers won't girls right
because sometimes they do actually need
to do the dangerous thing but it's
important for us to security people to
be able to review those so what we can
do here is if you absolutely need to
shoot yourself in the foot potentially
then you can say okay on a script and I
want it to be dangerous and then you can
use his cutter panelized or whatever to
enovia templates and sale is something
we need to review because someone down
and development needed to shoot yourself
in the foot so there we go that is the
sort of thing you can do with these
features which is useful
okay but even if you use things like
this we still have some problems for
example I mentioned at the beginning if
you're not allowing inline scripts you
have a problem with your script valued
at you so if you've got a link if you've
got non click handler in donlon 20 stuff
that says run this function enough to
return values files go and follow the
link people use this quite a lot it's
been part of the web for a while this
isn't going to work unless you're
allowed and safe and long and if you
allow and safe in line you basically
need and apply the first place but there
are ways you can use to fix this kind of
thing and one of the little toys are
playing around at the moment is at all
which takes an existing document and
when it straps all of thee and ten
pounders that use this method of doing
things and turn them into a script you
can include in the head of your
documents and apply them the new proper
way so that you don't have inline
scripts induction which can be useful
thing so there we go and I talked a bit
about better tools are talked about how
there are things available that can
allow you to take your site as it is
feed it through a tool and get out of
the tool what is the most strict
possible policy to apply to that buttons
all those documents and there's a tool
by chap I local hospital which you can
install their browser browser add-on we
can browse the site that you're looking
after and get out of it what the
strictest policy that could be applied
to that site isn't it can be some wins
even on that mean even if you allow
things like inline scripts being able to
turn off anybody being able to inject
objects too useful for various reasons
and there is benefit to apartment even
if you're waking
week and there are also hash generation
tool so the static examples I showed you
there and I generated those using a
fairly simple script which literally
just takes the documents you've got sure
that were looking to scale come on well
there we go so we're going to say all
the stuff with in that directory there
is sorcery directory I want you two to
generate hash sauce attributes for that
so you run that and then we can catch
this file and see the policy that which
is generated so you can take loads of
HTML source files or even PHP f in line
with in that and just generate the
hashes which can be a useful time-saving
thing again don't do this without some
serious review of what's going to happen
when you do that but it can save you
time while you're doing there are other
tools that people are building and
people are building reports dashboards a
colleague of mine and visitors building
walls really cool and another one is
being worked on by some people young
that's the Russian search engine and
there are many other tools out there for
making it's easier to do various things
with CSP so you've got a few ideas for
how you can apply CSP to stuff you only
got me thinking great I'm going to go in
there but before you do I've got some
words of warning okay the first one
comes from the chap I mentioned who did
the user CSP to infer a policy from the
site he also did a header survey which
is kind of like the head of surveys to
other people
will do but his was really specifically
about CSP which Arsenal is a
photographer follow a look and in that
look at what people are actually putting
in their policies and to his dismay he
found it very often people are applying
policies that are completely useless so
let me show you the variable obviously
you'd think if people go to the trouble
of enabling the header working out what
the policy needs to look like that think
about what the policy and that they're
applying and I think about what it does
and it turns out that they're not done
at all so this is for some organization
which is not gonna call out so we can
read it if you like thanks good enough
but never know CSP which basically turns
CSP off again so a pie policy that
doesn't apply any policy good work a
star okay and serves an example of a
thing you can do so if you're applying
the CSP high and make sure that the
policy you're applying makes sense don't
justify the policy that serves itself
off is that done don't you and another
thing that people do is people forget
about the same origin policy right this
okay well we've got this application and
it's running on Jan you or whatever the
support system really nicely we're going
to turn CSP on and we're quite safe okay
but even those things that provide these
nice TSP features might apply the policy
in consistently so here we have the
documentation for Django CSP if you've
shipped a configuration of jenga which
uses this and you've left the defaults
on and you've got the admin app turned
on
internet which people do sometimes don't
do that but people do you'll notice that
admin is not covered by the CSP
configuration so if there's a
vulnerability within the app in part of
replication and the usual that's being
targeted by the attack and can see that
page or if it sort of page before
logging if it's just reflected and those
are just for anyone then you potentially
got a problem there so if you're going
to make you services make sure you're
quiet consistently and in particular
with regards to apply it consistently
think really carefully about static
content because people again will go to
the trouble of a pile of the CSB bells
and whistles to the dynamic parts of
their site and forgets about the fact
that maybe they've got something
somewhere else would uses some old
JavaScript library or or so old and
flash document introduces them to an
add-on type vulnerability so remember
the stuff that can be vulnerable clients
as well as the server and apply the
policy to everything that you can and
the things that you can't apply move
them onto a separate subtly why
Gilliam's of join you don't have related
domain type attacks so those are some
common mistakes that can be made now
that's all I wanted to talk about and
I've left a little bit of time for
questions seems no one
Harold so you've got any questions like
lasted I don't want to move the books is
it all about looks we've got what I've
got to two copies of object time to
JavaScript this book is not to knowledge
would he called the HP if you want to
write all the realities put something on
that that's a joke by the way completely
what good stuff in PHP are you can see
them Oh wicked cool perl scripts oh
goodness me books they'll fly as well as
you'd think okay so there was a question
over here what's your question Steve
reason or create a policy where there is
a hospital fighters there's a legitimate
roof so the pressure was is there a
legitimate reason for a bio policy that
doesn't require policy and there are
legitimate reasons for applying a policy
that almost my lots of high policy and
that is that you can be very specific
about what you're alive allowing an
organized so if you're being tricky
about things you might be able to set a
specific path to cover a resource that
you know is vulnerable whilst not
touching the rest of the thing okay in
terms of applying a policy that doesn't
actually do anything the only thing I
can think of it wouldn't make you do
that is if you want to be able to say
UCSD MCV and so yeah by the company you
were reason why people would do that you
have to decide which pitch you didn't
want people to get set up if you haven't
anything except you need to decide what
that thing is preventing and it may be
any bits in future versions of the very
first developer tools people will do
things like saying okay you're at yacs
even actually it's useless though so
stupid pizza or things like that and
there are people working on various
projects for providing five times that
they also in five developer tools and I
don't know about the other browsers but
I'm sure different vectors little bit of
way as well if you have a static
all-star
what's to stop remember if it's
targeting rejection just rudely shifting
at this static lunge funding is not a
knowledgeable the waters so who is 0 so
what you do is you have a separate long
value what every response that you send
so that the attacker can't know the
value when they try to inject the idea
is that if the attacker can see what the
Lord says you've got worse problem
anyway so make sure that your most value
especially sufficiently random secondly
changes with every request pick another
number three that for everyone don't you
know yeah I I you miss a spot yet
anything I saw on the IE features matrix
thing of surface in the WC space that
they actively have people developing
exact moments well a couple would bad
girl
is there not a network anchor blue
straight ahead with one standing if
you've got networking equipment the
strip space that it doesn't know about
you probably want to send that and
obviously network that way its installed
let for a long time right doesn't that
is understandable so editor like through
quite yeah I feel like with various
recent security features if you've got
no except the stretch things that
understandably lot of problems so don't
just a flight + X prime actions or h st
s there are lots of four steps as well
if you've got LeVar Burton will strip
step out of and request those contexts
you might be have their issues any sort
of business websites have followed the
tracking bugs and advertising the loads
of these sites
is that approximately there's nothing
wrong with some to your business if your
business points that's tracking
affiliates or worse that's them yes so
you can theoretically your maximum
editors font size is only determined by
the supper table using not already the
courses and your club is users have
their wealth of choice well and you
could have very large and will be logged
response headers but generally I think
people are starting to come around the
fact that using these pictures by
feeding judgment their husband owns
isn't that security practice any moment
and you can you can do various things to
make one of these policies a little bit
easier than they might ugly and we look
cute Pacific for everything and and in
many cases just disallowed we realign
scripts is going to pop that anyway even
if you've got scripts autistic people
all of the various things we've got so
this facility in that you can in theory
tell everyone you want to practice that
might be difficult for the Marines in
this perspective practice you might be
sending
Firefox is a lightning that if your
ability where you can inject the header
into the response and I Jack they
content security policy yeah which ones
are safe from they are brave the policy
so the specification says that we have
multiple Cespedes concepts there should
be an intersection of those and in terms
of exact behavior they're happy posting
marriage proposals so and was an issue I
sort of
there are other interesting because
seriously well don't relate to how to
fight
what do you handle months has been
generated for swift acts we also
survival tool to generate ashpit
obviously that passive then go insane by
the pace motors yes so for hash source
to work up here each time of the pages
surbhi has to have the same script as
this idea so so what would happen if
someone put script here with that same
tag and is it isn't actually a
itself in check for so someone would
have to find the hash collision in the
hash algorithm is matched to a
wheelchair the table check so any sort
of the existing package what happens is
first two checks against various other
and types of source attribute that
domains or keywords and then it said
what I came to take this thing doesn't
match any other so now we'll do the
expensive steckel tapers content but it
will crash it and we'll prepare are you
Annette to get out she's an impostor
what am i finding mention which is
potentially useful and the u.s. CSP
standard has support for including the
policy biomedical so if you have a web
host it doesn't allow you to set your
own heads and you can maybe make use of
that as yet it's only supported in
Ukraine is there's a lot of arguing and
standards but whether or not it should
be allowed for these reasons but that's
the thing that's completely okay in your
patience