my name is Molly mean I live in East
London
contractor freelancer independent type
person i say type because usually then
did the role that end up in are like
either officer or specialist or analyst
but it always ends up being your filling
in for somebody because they're looking
for a permanent member of staff or
there's a lot of businesses usually work
that's kind of overflowing and you said
up can you come and handle that for us
that's why i started out in the world of
desktop support back in the days i
wonder who remembers the lovely windows
311 and it was kind of it was good times
cuz you know used to kind of go in and
print your calls out and actually go
through the building and fix people's
pcs and you know what people actually
said thanks to you I'm gonna heard that
in infosec for years people don't like
me and info stick but that's how i
started out those those were fun times
and i kind of fell into InfoSec that was
the best kind of picture i could put it
i didn't literally fall but during some
of the work that I was doing as a
desktop Support Engineer I well my boss
asked me one day old do you want to come
up and help me out with an investigation
come on come on come on Arden all these
late comers
so basically just doing the intro sent
me as much but I was just saying how I
fell into infosec and essentially it was
all careful okay I forgot to press that
sorry so I fell into this hick basically
my boss said look we're doing an
investigation do you want to come along
help we vestigation sounds quite cool
considering at the time I was working
for what used to be known as Customs and
Excise before they turned it into hmrc
and in the National investigation
service socially supporting the guys
that used to go out and do the raids and
the knocks and used to kind of some of
them infiltrate the gangs etc so
interesting times and it turned out that
there was an investigation going on and
there was some evidence being compiled
but somebody who works for customs and
excise let's just say who's kind of
broke and he was supplying some of the
information back to the people that
there was supposed to be investigating
so we had to kind of run up and in the
dead of night to any movie of his server
and all those sorts of things in kind of
presenting presenting evidence but it
was through that that I caught got a bit
of a bug for the info 6 I'd of things
are fortunate it is quite interesting
it'll be different from desktop support
you know I've done that for a while now
I'm all kind of moving to infosec so
before I kind of go on I'll just say
what it doesn't contain I'm not super
Lee technical so this is not going to be
a hacker tight talk but what it does
contain is how to kind of be an
effective member of an infosec team
within the kind of corporate environment
it's based on my experience over the
years as a contractor having seen good
info SEC and bad info SEC I'm call it
popping your bubble in the corporate
environment because I wrote an article
last year and somebody said all that
might be a good presentations awful let
me see what I can do
and you're thinking what the hell are
you talking about well these bubbles I
don't get what you're talking about but
as I'll go on hopefully I'll kind of you
know elucidate a bit more and we'll kind
of you get the message in the end so I'm
not so uncommon day for me and lots of
people I've worked with universe sec
kind of turns out there's a there's a
number of things that you do and then
you kind of go into work and your kind
of you in your routine so imagine you're
the cove in the middle there the info
sit pro and you go in and you have your
meetings the meetings that you have
planned your outlook calendar the
meetings that come up and when somebody
knocks on your door or kind of stands by
your desks and goes like that or starts
kind of saying no you free are you free
those sorts of meeting so it's one of
the things that kind of takes up your
date the other thing that's I've kind of
notices incidents you can't plan these
because they'll just happen and then you
have to kind of deal with them and then
your day turns into an incident because
that's all you're dealing with
third-party reviews of downloads of and
again those that you know about and
those that you don't and you get
involved in those and this is slowly
beginning to kind of build your day
projects have done lots of work on
projects as a security consultant
analyst and kind of convincing the right
people that they should be engaging
security from the beginning and then
having the arguments that oh well you
might well need a pen test hair etc and
then kind of getting the right people to
budget all those in so this is kind of
slowly it's beginning to build into a
day of a corporate info sick person
press then oh okay I've had lots of fun
with document reviews all mokan you
review that can you review this and then
when you make changes you have the other
arguments over all you want us to do
this but we've already kind of rolled it
out etc etc so I'm slowly building up to
kind of the typical things that I've
done
and then there's a reporting so whether
it's like reporting to management or
reporting to on projects etc you kind of
get involved but there's method to my
kind of showing you what some people do
with enterprise Amaro if you're a nympho
sit person so if you look at that lets
you kind of go through your day and it's
usually something around those there may
have been other kind of spikes that
could have put in there but I thought
these are the ones that I've kind of
mostly seen and mostly done so if you
kind of think about that for a second i
mean i'm not sure if or anybody wants to
play hannah but is there a pattern here
i mean i'm i'm basing it on my
experience but you go in and you do your
thing and you kind of go home you're
kind of not so uncommon day becomes your
business as usual you're in your bubble
so essentially it becomes routine for
you and you know when who notes the
picture in the background because
anybody recognize that sorry yeah is but
do you recognize the quote if I say
there you go see and people often call
they quote him so much you know if you
know your enemy and if you know your
environment you weren't these 100
battles and all that kind of stuff yeah
but the thing is in the business world
you don't know the or actually you don't
know your own environment let learn the
enemy so you're saying well okay then
what do you do what do you what do you
do how do you actually pop your bubble
so the next part hopefully I'm going to
kind of extrapolate a bit more
so take a typical environment you've got
these lovely bubbly type circles i drew
you've got legal and HR and finance and
the rest of departments typical ones
there's one word in there that you have
to kind of be cognizant of your in your
bubble but guess what some of those they
have their own issues and kind of bubble
bubbly type problem to do with so you're
not the only person who's going in to do
their job to go home that's what most
people do so as infosec pros we need to
be cognizant of that we can't just kind
of go and knock on people's doors they
were right you should be doing x y&z
because essentially they're being
measured on different things they have
their own targets they have their own
culture they have their own team
dynamics and the politics within those
their own measurables so one of them
kind of the messages I'd like for people
to take away is that as info see people
we need to be able to appreciate that
it's not just us well in our bubbles
other works in some places where in the
security team the tech guys don't even
like the info sick guys if there's been
occasions when people you know you're
supposed to be liaising with each other
and talking to each other and kind of
spreading the message the business about
why you should have you know why should
build security into things but if the
people that are supposed to be doing
that can't communicate with each other
we've got a problem there's been a
couple more than one place where I've
kind of as a contractor I've landed in
there and I've gone to the techie guys
to talk about something and and I my
work is usually in that side of things
and it's all oh you're the first one
who's actually come to talk me and I
talk to us in the kind of actually get
into the depth of things and ask
technical questions and kind of probe
certain things the other guys haven't
like really why is that and so well you
know they come along as they all would
do the policies we're doing the
awareness wedding the ISO stuffing you
guys always want the command
line etc scepter of doing all the proxy
stuff all the technical side of things
and have never approached us i said well
have you approached them and so we'll
know well if it's a two-way thing so you
that the paint is that everybody's in
their little Bob they do their thing but
if there's an in an infosec department
and then those two don't talk to each
other then I think there are problems
because if you can't do it within the
info State Department how how do you
convince the business that you should be
able to security into things
so I thought you know what it's a hard
sell this talk right it's not technical
it's not rock star e but I try and
introduce a bit of a game into it so it
was a play bit of a game oh good I was
hoping for her so I found these cool
little icons right and they looked not
like people love it but I thought you
know you could place kind of possibly
which department they might belong to
right so I'm getting a few lumps I'm
seeing some people probably recognize
potentially so i'll go into what the
arrows mean in a bit but just for the
bit of fun sake on the top left who's
going to kind of be bold enough to say
well where do you think she fits in what
department all right so yes she was a
child because when we're not when i
found thee when I found the life as I
put yes she looks like an HR person what
about the dude in the middle Kate let's
have a look I was so surreal what about
the lady on the right well so I heard
somebody call the right one out of a
solemn PR what about the one on the
bottom left I was going for yeah he did
mommy's new job so I thought okay well
then he might well be kind of in that
category potentially well I was being a
bit more positive but yes then the dude
in the middle and then well possibly but
he resonated with IT for me so I'll
bonding in there and then the guy the
fun looking good
hey what's pilots so that was a bit of I
I wanted to make it light-hearted
because it is you know it's the
difficult topic to talk about when I
hope I got across but they're the arrows
and then the info state pro in the
middle is like you me whoever works in
department but the arrows are that
message I'm trying to get across is you
should be ordered Olympus it department
should be the one that reaches out to
those departments or other five put a
few here there are others in an
environment but you should be making the
effort to say right okay this is what we
do this is how we do it and go and talk
to people find out what they do on a
daily basis because whenever I kind of
start a new role I go and actually kind
of introduce myself I by people of
coffee take bags of jelly babies around
you know build that relationship at the
beginning with as many departments as I
can with their heads ideally but if
they're not available because usually
got they've got a calendar book town you
can't get into them but if you can
actually go and talk to the people say
right what do you face on a daily basis
what sort of issues you face you I've
I'm talking specifically from personal
experience and people have said you know
what you you know it's very rare for
your department to come and engage with
us we like the fact that you've just
come to us and introduce yourself to us
and kind of you know you're open and
that's what I think you have to be like
that you have to kind of make those kind
of moves um when I was in desktop
support I went to room once and they had
a whiteboard right and it said hit list
on it and guess which department was the
top IT right and there I am i I've got a
call she my hair I'm gonna fix
somebody's pc in am i what and one of
the guy said oh um where are you from I
said look I'm coming here to fix her and
says pc can you point him to the right
you know put me in the right direction
that I said why have you got term IT as
a hit list because you know what you
don't come in here right you say you fix
something and then you get lost then
nothing's fixed or whenever you call you
you kind of follow us off with things
and offer okay well something's gotta
change and then from that day on I kind
of
even though I didn't have a call to fix
I went and talked to them right every
every other day you know just a bit of
kind of like chat bit of social
engineering if you want to call it that
but building the right relationship
right and they took us off the
whiteboard so it's all right and then
they started calling me late magic mohar
you doing right because I was always
there so whenever they ranked I picked
it up and whenever they could if they
saw mean the canteen they asked oh look
i know the calls not logged but would
you have a look and it's that and that's
the same thing i brought into investing
and i think as people who work in the
industry we need to do that we need
actually kind of yes our jobs are
stressful and we have our own objectives
but if you're going to build the right
relationships you've got to go and do it
I'm point in cases a lot of times when
people sit through meetings and they
don't introduce each other they kind of
do the right sort of communications and
I've been into kind of situations where
I'm going to go and come and sat in
meetings that won't even I didn't have
to be there but let's at all Cheers
infosec I you know we can come to you
about this and you know people talk
about this I don't like this anymore to
be honest I never really liked it but
people processing technologies I think
that you know we all know which one's
the most important one out of those
right but it's there's only one that
really kind of actually matters and it's
that one it's always down to the people
so ways down to kind of building the
right relationships so I looked at that
politics I looked at the personalities
sorry the people process and technology
and I thought there's something that's
even more critical than that it's
personalities politics and frost because
if you don't understand the kind of lay
of the land within your environment that
you're in and you don't understand the
kind of inter dynamics and the teams and
the cultural issues the rest of it
doesn't really matter because you're
going to you're not going to be able to
fit in you're not going to be able to
say right you know what if I talk to so
so about this that might not go off if
I'm talking to a project manager about
building security in from the beginning
or
going to the techie team to talk to
about a change I need to build those
relationships in the beginning I need to
understand those three because it's
that's the key think trust if you've got
to build that up so as I kind of slowly
wind down I've got a few takeaways so
over the years I've seen kind of good
info sake and bad info second then
somewhere in the middle and people have
been talking about Brandi infoset
department but in my head about that for
a while and I've been talking about it
to a few people over the last few years
because essentially you do need to kind
of get out there and market yourself and
I've always said can't become your own
little startup think of it like that
think of it like you should be kind of
dynamic and actually build security out
and give a night give a name to it
create content net well I say pull one
took base you're always kind of sending
things to people's her oh you should
come to this presentation you should
kind of read these emails etc etc but if
you flip it around and create engaging
content that's suitable for everybody
and has different messages for different
levels and put it out there and then if
you branded yourself properly people
would come and pull it and actually look
at themselves and view it themselves
rather than you saying where I do this
do this do this this is security because
they've got their daily job to do to
bring out the personalities bit this may
work for some places it might not work
for others but look at the people within
your team and actually kind of get them
on the internet do video kind of things
that do like little sound bites so that
the business knows who they are rather
than some person in infosec nobody knows
and then the first person that the
business sees when they well as an
infosec issue it's that infests it going
or the woman and they don't know they
don't they don't know who he or she is
and never seen them
be seen and be known what do I mean here
so as I surliest is you got to do the
meats in Greece you've got to go out
there and kind of sell yourself you've
got to actually go to the teams and
actually kind of build those
relationships walkabout I used to do
walk about people for a bit not so she
should just go to random county
departments at hi I'm oh I looking for a
sec and it builds that and then slowly
people begin to build that respect you
know when management has briefings and
they kind of stand up and they begin to
talk about objectives and kind of
successes of the last month of work
somewhere and I that used to happen on
an everything week they did it and I
said to the info SEC team will why don't
you have a little spot in there why
don't you kind of get answer all right
you know this is infosec and these
things happen and this has been in the
news something that's of the now and
people get and share some data share
some info you know couple of minutes and
people said oh well we've never
approached management to be there we we
you know nobody in the team wants to do
it I thought well you're trying to kind
of sell it to the business but you're
not making an effort to actually get up
and do anything and when you've kind of
got these things going the last word is
kind of you know you've got to keep it
going you can't just say oh well this is
a one-off thing and we've done it now
and you stopped because with everything
in life you once you've got the ball
rolling you need to keep going drop
shadows so
again we've got a bursting your bubble
is kind of you've got to go and
instigate the Job Shadow stuff again
I've seen place where they did that and
it sometimes it works it there's
obviously places where it will be a
little bit more difficult to do but on
the whole people welcome it when you say
hey to some come spend half a day with
infosec and will show what we do and how
we do it and then a people reciprocate
it so you can go and sit with legal and
HR and any other department within the
company Taylor we'd like to see what you
doing within from doing that you see
what they go through on a daily basis
what their issues are and you spot
things you should know what there's
something coming up in one of the
projects that might help you to do with
is easier and as secure as possible and
it's it's going to be instigated by
inpho sick team whoever leads there
needs to be able to say right these are
the approaches that we need to take you
got to be able to share information talk
to the business about how many passwords
resets you had and how many incidents
you solved and you know build something
where you actually share that info
because again with two siloed we kind of
do the things and nobody really about
knows about it and we don't kind of
what's the word celebrate our successes
type thing so you've got to share the
information and that you know all comes
down to being open again we all know
that we've info SEC has always been
what's it you're a blocker you know you
always kind of get in the way of us
doing things well if you're open and
you've you know you share information
and you instigate those sort of
relationships people begin to understand
you a lot better because you need to
understand the business in order to
actually sell yourself and actually
market yourself a brand the team and
actually become somebody who people can
trust and people can know and say all
right well you know what I've seen so
many looks a bit dodgy I know who to go
to report it to or something along those
lines so people actually you've built
that relationship you pop your bubble
and that's that's the kind of sort of
tape that I've taken on it over the loss
god I've been carrying now 10 so it's
it's actually being open so my final
slide who's done a bit electronics in
their time
you got the analog and digital so as
humans we're kind of analog creatures
are continuously variable right but
we're always applying kind of digital
solutions to things and as soon as we
kind of understand that it's all about
people and actually building the right
relationships we will begin to move
forward and yes technical solutions have
their place but ultimately it's about
being open being doing the simple things
and people begin to actually read things
will resonate and will actually begin to
get the message out there a lot better
than we have been so I think for me that
may well be it thank you very much still
con think I'm done ya know thank you
very much thank you
you