cool everyone it's coming on
so I normally start this talk with a
quote and generally it's kind of a bit
buzz weirdy so what we're gonna do
instead is today we're gonna start that
talk with a question instead and that's
the question of if that works cool of
what does Agent Smith from the matrix
what is the Joker from Batman
and what does Darth Vader from Star Wars
all have in common and it's not the fact
that they're all from movies it's not
the fact that they're all bad guys it's
the fact that they're all bad guys with
motives and purposes right so that they
all do what they do for a reason whether
that's a enslaving humanity in the
matrix or building the Death Star in
Star Wars all of these bad guys do
something for a reason and then in these
movies as well we'll see the heroes use
those motives and those purposes against
the bad guys in one form or another and
that's kind of what offender profiling
is right so cuz offender profiling is
all about creating a knowledge base on
malicious actors so what about looking
at the bigger picture behind attacks so
that we can better protect us and our
customers coming back to that quote then
it's about pre-emptive security about
the idea of doing something now spending
some money now spending some time now to
help protect ourselves in the future an
offender profiling is a type of
pre-emptive security as I said offender
profiling is all about looking at these
people it's all about building bigger
pictures building knowledge bases and
understanding what's happening I want to
break step into three main areas I'm
gonna talk about what offender profiling
actually is I wanna talk about what
already exists so some white papers some
research papers that use offender
profiling and then I'm going to talk
about how else we can use offender
profiling how we can use offender
profiling in security operations and
some practical methods for doing so the
stole Konami lasts around 20 to 30
minutes so they've added on some
additional stuff where we're going to go
through how we can use these methods for
offender profiling with real-world
attack data to begin with Oh Who am I
well my name is James Stevenson and this
time last year I was a student at the
University of South Wales studying
computer security as well as that before
that I was an intern at alert logic a
computer security company
these days I'm a graduate in BT security
I've also run several websites Jim's
team sent up me hacking SOCOM
and I'm also on twitter @ underscore
James Stevenson that's kind of like all
the boring stuff right though we don't
really care about that so coming back to
offender profiling right what is
offender profiling I keep talking about
it but what actually is it as I said
offender profiling is all about that
knowledge base right but knowledge base
what does what does that actually mean
so for a fender profiling we can break
that knowledge base down into three main
areas information on the target
so the who and the what who is our
target of an individual a group are they
government organization and what was
targeted so what specific asset was
targeted to build that knowledge base we
also need some information on our
attacker
again the who and the what so who is our
attacker are they an individual a group
of a state-sponsored
and what attack vector did they use
finally the last piece of information we
need to create that knowledge base is
just some general information and that's
when did this attack occur and why did
this attack occur and it's all of this
information that comes together that
allows us to build this knowledge base
that allows us to look at the bigger
picture of these attacks there's an
example I liked giving for offender
profiling and I'll be also like event
because it's simple so easy to get our
heads around it stayed here for Dossett
area so a denial of service attack let's
say we're protecting a customers Network
and they're continually getting dosed by
a Scandinavian hacker group let's say
between the hours of 3:00 and 6:00 each
day and then for the rest the day its
drips and drabs so we can tell our
customer okay put extra load balancers
in place at these times and then for the
rest of the day use what you usually
have so here we've used defender
profiling reviews pre-emptive security
and some general security techniques to
help protect our customers so that's
what if in a profiling is but why is it
important why do we need it well this is
a quote from the Los Angeles police
chief so actually to do a predictive
policing but I think it describes
offender profiling quite well it's the
idea that we're not getting more stuff
we're not getting more money
we have to use what we have now
effectively and that's the same in
security so security is not the buzzword
it once was
does it have the endless budgets it once
did it's all about utilization using
what we have right here and now so then
if we can use offender profiling if we
can use pre-emptive security to put some
security techniques or precautions in
place now and that can help us protect
against something exponential in the
future so that's why if then a profiling
is important but why security important
right we wouldn't be here today if we
didn't believe security was important
well this is a statistic from have of
impound I'm sure most of us today know
what happened print is but if you don't
it's a database of breached account
credentials where you type here in my
address in and it tells you if you've
been part of a data breach so this is
the amount of compromised accounts that
were listed in happened on the 12 for
the second 20g right listen it was
really interesting right it's
interesting because well it's a massive
number but it's also interesting because
it shows us security isn't going
anywhere it shows a Security's in it for
the long haul because as long as we have
things we have things that can be broken
as long as we have things that we've
broken we have things that need
protecting so that's why offender
profiling is important that's why
security is important but what already
exists were some examples of white
papers of research papers that use
offender profiling this is a white paper
by mandiant paranthesis white paper I've
read it's on a PT one in Chinese hacker
group target Western organizations
believed to be state-sponsored this
white paper goes into hue PT Moana
because into their motives goes into
attack patterns and builds a bigger
picture on who they are and what they do
it's got another white paper here this
was written by FC Co so why paper is
similar but this time it goes into the
Callisto group but again builds a bigger
picture on who they are
except motives looks at attack patterns
and all in all it allows us to see who
these bad guys oh I'll find a white
paper this one is slightly different
this is by McAfee
and this is McAfee's annual fat report
this white paper because in a whole
range of different
protectors different motives different
attack patterns but again builds a
bigger picture on all of them and we can
probably start seeing a pattern here
right because offender profiling is all
about that bigger picture it's all about
building that bigger picture to help
protect us so that's the example of how
we can use offender and attack profiling
in research and white papers but where
else can we use offender profiling if we
cast our minds back to you 2011 where
the Stuxnet worm is super prominent it
targets a PLC so programmable logic
controllers and it's reportedly damaged
1/5 of a brand's nuclear capability but
actually if we cast our minds even
further back we knew very little about
Stuxnet and Ralph langit says at best
who's a industrial control systems
security consultant and he says well
yeah at the time we knew very little
about Stuxnet we do know who it was
targeting we didn't know who made it
they were looking for certain things
that right so they had the code and they
said well we're looking for system calls
were looking for timers data structures
and really anything that can link us
back so that real will target and this
is a great example of how we can use
offender profiling so not just build
bigger pictures on attackers but to also
build bigger pictures on targets as well
so profiling the target and then they
made their own knowledge base so they
said well it's a highly bulb written
code it's probably sabotage it's got a
high-value target and to be honest the
target is most probably in a rent and
this just shows us how we can use
offender profiling for other areas how
we can use the techniques in other areas
and it's not just about profiling our
attackers so what's one more way that we
can use offender profiling or attack
profiling techniques well as I said
earlier I which in a security operation
center I worked in a company called
alert logic for all in all around about
a year and at a high level we can break
a security operation center down a sock
down into two main elements we have our
customer and we have our stock our
customer will normally have an IDs an
intrusion detection system a wife web
application firewall
some sort of logging system they'll then
send those logs to our sock in our sock
we'll have analysts who will review
those logs they'll say well what's
actually happening here is this a false
positive is this a false negative well
then write up some form of feedback and
send that back to the customer and this
generally works really well right we get
this very good feedback loop we get logs
analysis feedback and yeah that
generally works really well the problem
with that though is we're any of looking
at one attack at a time we might be
looking at multiple incidents or
multiple events but really we're any of
looking at one attack and the problem is
we're not looking at the bigger picture
right the bigger picture of which we
said was so important for offender
profiling so the question is could we
implement offender profiling into
security operations well yes we could
have been done one of the ways we do
this is by latching on a framework to
what already exists by adding a
framework for offender profiling to our
sock rather than starting afresh so the
way this works is we take our logs as
usual we analyze them as usual but then
we also start bucketing that information
we say well this attack is related to an
attack you had a month ago this attack
is related to an attack you had a week
ago and this attack is related to
another attack and never one of our
customers I said so here we're sending
that information back to our customer
with our general analysis we're sending
it back and this is allowing our
customers to compare attacks to
prioritize attacks which I just simply
understand what's happening so this this
is Alice Alice is our security analyst
for an up-and-coming security startup
Alice manages a small team of security
analysts and it's their job to deal with
security incidents as they come in these
instance can be an array of attacks and
it's then their job to action those
security incidents so actioning can be
anything from writing up feedback to
phoning a customer remoting into a
system and generally that works really
well where that doesn't work really well
however is when Alice's team is swamped
they really get swamped and that speak
all of these attacks are prioritized on
time so the sooner all attack comes in
the higher priority it has and Alice
doesn't like this right Alice wants to
find a way the hey no team can
prioritize these attacks based off other
factors because what happens is we get
the high-risk attacks drowned in a sea
of low-risk attacks so Alice has done
some research and she's looked into
methods such as looking at risk looking
at frequency looking at attack
classification and these are the methods
that were going to be talking about for
the rest of the day so now when Allison
our team received these security
incidents the safing assuming that the
higher priority attack has the higher a
risk it has as well and then they can be
actioned accordingly so you might be
thinking well James that's great
sure it's time to dive into our first
method for offender profiling well not
quite before we do that we have to do
something I like to call methods zero
for offender profiling and method zero
is all about building an information
classification or an asset profile right
it's all about understanding what two
are protecting because at the end of the
day you can't protect what we don't know
as a sedalia are in a website James
Stevenson dakhni
that's an asset that's something I'm
protecting that's its name
well it's classification is it high risk
is it low risk it's description well
it's a wordpress website running an
email server back-end its owner
custodian that's myself and followed the
user that's the public that that's you
annoy and again the reason why we build
these asset profiles is so we can better
protect them let's say we have two
assets a high-risk asset and a low risk
asset and we have a malicious actor
targeting both of them if that was the
only information we had which of these
assets would we prioritize well it
probably the high risk asset right
because I'm less intrinsically of a
higher risk and we'll see how this comes
into play later on but for now we just
need to know that to better protect our
assets we need to know what they
actually are so moving on to our first
method for offender profiling this is
called method one attack
frequency plotting and I found out the
name of this method because actually
describes what it's trying to do because
it's all to do with plotting the
frequency of attacks the way we do this
is we take a time frame so here we've
got the time frame of around about a
month and whenever we see an attack from
a specific malicious actor to a specific
asset we increase its frequency it's not
simple as adding one there's some maps
behind it but really we just need to
know it increases and then if we don't
see an attack from a specific malicious
actor to a specific asset we decrease
that frequency we half-life it so what
we end up getting is these peaks and
these troughs for attack frequency and
that's really useful because that now
allows us to compare attacks so here we
can see two different mulches actors we
can see a malicious actor from Russia in
a red and the malicious actor from China
in a blue we can see that the malicious
actor from China continues to attack the
ad set throughout this time frame well
the malicious actor from Russia attacks
stops attack stops and continues so
again if this was the only information
we had which of these attacks would we
prioritize well it'd probably be the
malicious actor from Russia right Oh
China even because that was far more
frequent it's far more pressing on us or
our customers well the run from Russia
is just lesser and we'll see this come
as a trending pattern for us so moving
on to our next method for a fender probe
volume this method looks at risk it says
what is the risk of this attack to my or
my customers organization and the way it
does this is ask several questions we
then answer those questions with a
number between zero and ten questions
like the complexity of attack ease of
discovery ease of exploit loss a
confidentiality integrity and
availability and these are also broken
down into two sub categories likelihood
and impact we then take an average of
each of those sub categories times them
together to get our overall risk and
that overall risk will be a score
between zero and a hundred where the
higher the score the higher the risk so
again then if we had two malicious
actors or two attacks one attack with a
risk of 70 and one attack with risk of
thirty which of those attacks would we
prioritize well a problem in the risk of
seventy right because that less
intrinsically higher intrinsically has
that higher risk and again we'll see how
all of this comes together later on we
go to our next method for a fender
profiling so here I really didn't want
to talk about the cyber kill chain right
some people love the cyber kill chain
and some people hate in sub kill chain
Lucy that don't know the cyber kill
chain is a method by Lockheed Martin for
analyzing the life cycle of malware
exploitation right generally works
really well it's got several areas from
reconnaissance to weaponization to
actions and objectives and their
sections that the malicious actor should
undergo as part of deploying malware and
again generally it works really well
where it doesn't work really well
however as it's generally overused it's
used in a whole range of areas and
security when brilliant only be used in
deploying malware so what we're going to
use today is a far more generic kill
chain model for computer security a
model that has five areas from research
in the target testing infrastructure
actively attacking actions which is
doing the thing and then finally
covering tracks and planting backdoors
and these are the stages that the
malicious actor might undergo as part of
their attack and you might be thinking
well James that's great and all but what
does it have to do with offender
profiling the reason why we do this so
we can pin these categories to our
malicious actors so we can say well at
this time and date malicious actor a was
in the research stage well at this same
time into eight malicious sector B was
in the actions stage so if that was the
only information we had which of these
malicious actors would we prioritize
well it'd probably be the malicious
actor in the actions stage right because
that one is favored along in their
attack the malicious actor in the
research stage may never get to that
stage we're going to help an ultimate
method for offender profiling this
Murphy can be the simplest or it can be
the most complex because it's all to do
with asking questions and the simple
answer is we might just not know the
answer to them we ask questions on the
target and questions on the malicious
actor
questions like well who was the target
within individual a group a government
organization and was anyone else
targeted was this part of a massive
reconnaissance attack was this part of a
singular spearfishing attack we then
asked I have to ask for why were they
targeted for example why was company a
targeted and not company be next door
taxes once I've asked questions on the
target we also asked questions on the
malicious actor again we asked well who
were they within individual a group with
a state-sponsored and what was their
motive was it malicious was it financial
was it hacktivism and finally well did
anything happen leading up to this
attack was there anything in the news
was there anything in social media were
there any new laws or legislation passed
and finally it's all of the information
from these questions that allow us to
answer this final question and that's
with the information we have now with
the information we have in our target
and the information we have a non
malicious actor is this attack likely to
continue because building a bigger
picture is great building that knowledge
base is great but actually understanding
if we're still at risk is far more
important so moving on to our final
method for offender profiling this is
called method 5 that really could be
called method 0.5 you can stead of
looking at at offender profiling it
looks at offender categorizing it says
can we create a sub unique naming
convention for our malicious actors that
we can glean information from the way it
does this is it breaks that naming
convention up into four main areas
information on the location so where
they were first seen the date they were
first seen the risk level for that
malicious actor so again that's that
number we saw earlier so that number
between zero and 100 and finally the
last octet of the first scene almost
common IP address related to that
malicious actor so again the reason why
we do this is to have a sub unique
identifier for our malicious actors so
here we could use IP addresses we could
use MAC addresses we could use
cassia's this is just one example of
something we could use
so now we have it we've kind of looked
at the first section so we've looked at
what offender profiling is and why it's
important we've looked at whatever it
exists so some white papers some
research papers that use offender
profiling and what's always that how we
can use offender profiling in security
operations from this next part of the
talk I'm going to go through how we can
use some of these methods for offender
profiling with real-world attack data
now when I was creating this talk you
couldn't decide just don't there's to be
a live demo and it's not to be a live
demo so if someone crashed in the middle
we're gonna be going through this live
attack data but it's at a cater from the
past so we're gonna be going through why
session decisions have been made on this
data so what are we actually gonna be
looking at well we're going to be
covering most of the methods we've
spoken about we're gonna be looking at
methods 0 so we're going to be building
an asset profiler and information
classification we're gonna be looking at
methods 0.5 so we're gonna be
categorizing our malicious actors then
we're gonna be looking at methods 1 2 3
so we're gonna look at attack frequency
attack risk and the category those
attacks fall into now you might be
thinking well James was this attack data
coming from well we're gonna be using
some honey pots so we've got three small
honey pots set up across Canada Germany
and Amsterdam and they're using mhn
which is the modern honeypot Network if
you want to know more about it that's a
link to an article my website that gives
you a brief synopsis and how it all
works now the problem is when using this
honeypot data Brian if we were to
profile them as they were all the honey
pots might be the same all of the attack
data might be the same so what we're
going to do insert two sprucing it up
we're going to imagine that these honey
pots are what they're pretending to be
so what do I mean by that well this is
our first honey pot this is a honey pot
based out of Germany this is an
elasticsearch honey pot so if you don't
know where elasticsearch is it's a data
aggregation tool kind of like a database
but not quite but we're going to use our
imagination and we're going to pretend
that this honey pot is what it's
pretending to be so we're going to
imagine that this elasticsearch honey
is no elasticsearch sivir that it
belongs to a fake organization called
feedback systems is a medium risk asset
and it's probably used by their software
engineers but for one reason or another
is accessible via the Internet
our next honeypot honeypot is based out
of Canada this is a general website
honeypot but we're gonna use our
imagination again and we're going to
pretend that this is a blogging website
with a login form a few articles and
we're going to pretend that it belongs
to another fake organization called tech
blog so a medium risk asset and
accessible by the Internet our final
honeypot or our final asset space of
Amsterdam this is an industrial control
system honeypot and we're gonna use our
imaginations again and we're gonna
pretend that this is a
telecommunications industrial control
system high risk asset and primarily
used by highly trained staff so there we
have our free main assets right we've
got our feedback systems elasticsearch
asset we've got our tech blog blogging
website assets and we've got our
telecommunications industrial control
system asset so as well as these free
main assets we also have free main
malicious actors we have a malicious
actor from the US a malicious actor from
China and a malicious actor from
Bangladesh so throughout this talk we're
going to have two icons on the lower of
the screen one of them is going to be a
flag and that's going to indicate which
malicious actor is currently attacking
which asset we're also gonna have a text
box and that's going to indicate which
asset is currently being targeted so
looking at our first malicious actor our
first motion actor from the US here we
can see our honeypot dashboard alright
we can see all of the attacks from this
malicious actor to this asset and what
we can immediately see is well to be
honest there aren't that many attacks
they're happening in general time frame
but there aren't that many compared to
the attacks we'll see later on
it's not that many at all next we can
look at the risk so earlier on we said
that workout risk for these attacks is
by answering several questions questions
like the complexity of attack ease of
discovery
ease of exploit lots of confidentiality
integrity and availability so these have
also been broken down into two
subcategories a zero to five subcategory
and a six to ten subcategory and again
these are previously been answered but
what we can see here is to be honest
again not only does this attack have its
low frequency it also generally has
quite a low risk and we'll see that
reiterated later on and then finally for
this attack we need to look at the
category this attack falls into is as we
said earlier on that's a big factor that
comes into the risk of the attack so
this is well this is an enumeration
attack so it's not going to fall into
the research stage it's not gonna fall
into the attacking stage it's going to
fall into the testing infrastructure
stage so we can see all of that
information reiterated here right we can
see how generally low frequency we can
see our category and we can see our
generally low risk so if we go back to
Alice how might this attack fit in a
security operation center well generally
it's got that low risk we can see the
sort of information you might want to
see but it's been prioritized quite low
because generally there are far more
important attacks that need to be dealt
with first moving on to our next
malicious actor or malicious actor from
China again we can see similar
information in our honeypot dashboard
but this time we can see a lot more
attacks we can see are in about seven
pages or eight pages of ten attacks each
rather than the six previously what we
can also see this time is a lot of them
are happening in quick succession and
what that shows us is that this attack
is probably automated or has an
automated element and again let's just
bear that in mind for later on again we
can look at of risk so again we're
saying what is the risk of this attack
to us or tech job block and again these
are pretty answered so we've got
generally similar answers to last time
right but this time I've got some in the
six to ten category and what that shows
us is that this attack or this asset is
a slightly higher risk than our previous
asset finally for this attack we again
look at the category
we say what is the category of this
attack so if this is a brute-force
attack against that login form we saw
previously then it's probably going to
fall into the actively attacking stage
and again we can see that reiterated
here we can see our frequency our
category and our overall risk again we
can see how that might fit in a security
operation center we can see how an
attack like this might be prioritized
compared to others and we can see the
sort of information we might want to see
if we were a security analyst we want
our final malicious actor so again we
can see very similar information in our
dashboard in our honeypot dashboard we
can see an array of attacks from this
malicious actor to our
telecommunications industrial control
system asset and again we can see a lot
of them happening in quick succession so
again that show is this okay well maybe
this attack is automated or has that
automated element again we can look at
risk so we can say well what is the risk
of this attack to our new asset so our
telecom asset and for this one would
assume that would have a lot more in
that 6 to 10 category right because this
is a higher risk asset rather than our
two previous assets we're looking at
something in a different level so yes
sure we can see some in the 8 to tens
that general range and then finally for
this malicious actor we can see well
what category does this attack fall into
this says that this is a directory
traversal attack so it's going to fit
into that testing infrastructure stage
and we can see all of that reiterated
for the last time we can see our
frequency our category and generally a
higher risk than we've seen previously
and finally we can see that reiterated
in Alice's security operation center
again we can see that this has quite a
high frequency it's got the high risk
and we can see the different parts of
information we might want to see so
we've kind of looked at how we can use
real-world attack data with these
methods for offender probe wallop the
next part of this talk is really just
summarizing what we've gone through and
the real takeaway of this talk is to
be more like Alice right they say idea
of taking that step back building those
bigger pictures building those knowledge
bases whether that's using industry
tools like the cyber kill chain the
diamond model for intrusion analysis or
if it's by using some of the models
we're spoken about today because it's
all about allowing us or our customers
to look at what's happening to
prioritize attacks compare attacks or to
just simply understand what's happening
to us or our customers kind of a next
and final take away this talk is
inspired by this quote and it's all to
do with intrusion analysis network
analysis security analysis because
generally they're all to do with
understanding something if we look at it
kind of the bare bones they're all about
understanding and in the cases where
that's about understanding an attack
offender profiling shows us that every
attack is orchestrated right that every
attack has a motive and a purpose and in
better understanding that motive and
purpose we can better protect ourselves
or our customers so we've got around
about three minutes 20 minutes left and
thanks to you and the organizers as well
you've got any questions feel free to
ask me now come find me afterwards you
can also find me on Twitter underscore
James Stevenson as well yeah thanks guys
[Applause]