so ladies cuz I'm going to watch the
game right the dark arts the path to
destruction target power me build a
global engineering and construction
company Monday fifth the third 2018
operating system tales chat client
pigeon connected to IRC has joined up
light testing now at the target is one
to internal SMTP relay okay okay so what
we're seeing here they've discovered
that SMTP is open on a target and to
attempt to manually access SMTP an easy
way to do it is to telnet on to that
service on port 25 connected to power me
build calm hello you say hello you type
hello to start the SMTP process mail
from admin power me build comm sender
okay so they're spoofing an internal
email address receive recipient to Jay
Tim's at power me build calm okay data
hello dot huge mail for delivery huge
mail for delivery how they are so
vulnerable wiki when you're going to
launch the nuke any sec whole time okay
using strops send mail script - send
mail the script the target email
addresses a list of email addresses - B
is the actual email - f from - s is the
subject st. what was in the email I
still don't get how it works all that
was in the email was simply that an
image tag with the SMB request or UNC
exploitations I love the outlook clients
will also trigger an embedded UNC image
from an email that comes from a trusted
source okay I get that when sending it
via the SMTP service externally but from
an internal users address
it come it comes from a trusted source
it'll land an auto trigger rainin hashes
responder is started I'm not saying
nothing con responder did you tweak the
firewall to allow inbound from their
range yep it's not that maybe they just
blocked four or five outbound leave it a
bit right I'm off to play fortnight
catch you in a bit no probs about two
hours later anything con responder nope
looks like we need another way crap okay
I'm off for the night catch you on the
other side
call chapter 2 Tuesday 603 2008 has
joined yo yo yo yo what's up I had an
idea I'm all ears
we need to scrape as many usernames as
we can he looked for any examples of
internal email addresses no probs but
why I've been looking at their external
IDs they got an ssl VPN I see where
you're going this but what about 2fa
two-factor authentication who says
they've got it so looking on Google on
their domain will very quickly reveal
internal email address formats often and
as you can see here we got hate sender
which happens to be a media relations
manager including their phone number all
useful I found an internal email address
by Google it's fake sender wicked now
we've got an address I can use prowl to
scrape more so say okay this is Matt
Pickford's prowl so to run it you do -
prowl followed by the name that would
often appear on LinkedIn with the
company that they're associated with
followed by the format's which here is
first initial dot last initial at their
domain name bingo there you go from
being Yahoo we have managed to find cash
credentials which looks at cached
credentials from LinkedIn so this is an
essence scraping LinkedIn but using the
search engines cached records to give
you the information the reason why this
is great is because you don't need
credentials with a link to you'd have to
do any of that mess it just works you've
done it yet yeah just completed now ha
we got over 200 usernames fishing with
dynamite
okay I'm going to call it a day no min
but if you kept an eye on the share
prices a power me build yep
fairly steady last few months there's
the share prices presently call buy a
few more shares in them why more so we
have a history of buying before the
crash you have a lot to learn my friend
call right I'm off catch you later
chapter 4 a Wednesday 703 2018 or blight
yo you want yeah just about to test
those usernames I'm gonna use burb to
brute force them you show us how you do
that yeah no problems okay so here we
have their SSL VPN and we're going to
capture that using burp Suites so we say
it to intercept and we put a username in
and we puts a password now the username
is anything but you put the password
that you think that a lot of users are
most likely to you so here we've got
password with an expiration mark on the
end now
[Music]
so we send that to intruder and we
select the username parameter and then
we paste in the usernames that we
managed to get from prowl and we're
going to subject those to the username
parameter against that chosen password
and we're going to hit go now obviously
in the real world we have the pro
version I have the pro version but for
realism I like to use the free version
for this purpose and who can see it's
quite slow so you're going to miss the
England game the reality is with the pro
version you would fly through and the
real reality is if any outside of
threats were using it they would
probably look at the Java file via video
on YouTube and figure out how to get the
pro version so what we're looking for
here is a length change a length change
indicates that the application has
responded to something it's of interest
to you so any length change would
potentially indicate that we've got a
set of credentials that work but
unfortunately as we're seeing here it's
coming to an end and done and we've got
nothing but just to zoom in to show you
so here's the request that I intercepted
and the username is the parameter of
interest so we highlight that and that's
where we inject all the usernames and as
you can see there there's the chosen
password and this is what you would get
if you're successful this works all the
time and for actors also use it you can
see they're empowered and we've got a
different length so you know the
credentials would have worked crap I was
sure we'd get one you try can I try with
MSF Metasploit yeah yeah just make sure
you run it for a proxy chain but help
why not so here we are we've got Cisco
SSL VPN brute-force a login utility
module that's catchy and we're going to
use it so we've got the same username
list and we're now trying it with this
always worth double-checking with other
tools now what you're looking for is a
green green means good so we'll see if
we get a green it's quite quick
we have agree we should have a few more
greens in a minute and it will end and
there we go so it ends and we can say
successful login with J Smith and
password explanation mark no have a
close up and what it found now it's the
same user but it's the different ssl
profiles but it's managed to get access
to so that user has access to all of
those ssl VPN profiles got one wicked
what's the account j smith password top
work
don't manually test it yet how come you
need to leave it sometimes in case
they're monitoring also use a VPS from
their country why on a VPS just to blend
in a bit make you look local okay I'll
get you use one of the credit cards that
gave you a few months back right should
we call it a night good call catch you
later
first day o 803 2008 has joined yo yo
what's up I've got a VPS is in the same
country I'm just about to test them so
here we are we're logging in via the web
browser and you get this which is not
particularly useful what you want to do
is use the Oni connect can luckily
anyconnect client which allows you to
login i discussed recently by default
it's not set to a defined user's laptop
so all you have to do if you get
credentials is download a copy of any
connect and you should be able to use
the credentials by default so here we go
we've connected and just to show
everyone you can also do it with Ubuntu
Kali Debian any kind of Linux flavor
using open connect which then gives you
direct access to their SSL VPN on your
Kali box yet works
I can VPN in we've opened connect great
time to be stealthy let's hold off for
the night I hate it when you say that
chapter 4 o 903 2008 has joined I guess
we got spotted brute force saying you
see in the media reading now which cites
ok
targeted by brute force attack hackers
fail he tried the VPN yep not changed
the password still works they think it
failed not sure which a plate call leave
it for a few days
share price is affected a little nothing
particularly odd
celsa not old just son empower me build
yep
meet back in a few days called tent for
the 3rd 2008 a has joined you on Sunday
11 PO for a new on doesn't understand
two days Monday the 12th for a 2008 a yo
you about yeah my time back cool the VPN
creds still work let's get this done
down you ever you see me nope what is it
you can use it to find any network share
that you can write a payload to and then
gain access to the machines no I show me
and that's the tool they'll be using
crap Mattox exec so what you're seeing
here is they starting at all and they're
giving it a subnet range it could be a
single IP address or us or a summarized
network here they're doing summarize
slash 24 adding a user name for the
account that they gained on the outside
and they've used to VP own it and
they're using a password and add the
domain
and here we go we've got a green
instantly green means that you can
offense Kate against that box
pwned on the end it means that you've
got local admin rights on that box very
common on internal network you'll see a
user pretty much any standard user with
one or two boxes that they could have
got local admin rights on there you go
as a closing of what you're looking for
close up working for pwned
we should be able to access 192 168 0 10
using Pierce exec you want me to do that
yeah go for it so here we are have
Metasploit and we're using Pierce exec
so it's pretty much set in the same sort
of commands you set in the user name the
domain name the password and you set the
network address or not subnets you set
to the single IP address with Pierce
exact on MSF
we have a problem service failed to
start file not found
ok pxx failed it's saying service failed
odd as he can't isn't the local admin
groups maybe it's because it's not a
physical local admin no idea sorry don't
stress there's plenty of ways to skin a
cat think we should call it for a day
for now not a bad idea catch you later
Tuesday has joined hi-yah time to think
yeah you won't believe this I went back
afterwards using say MA and that words
and call what did you get budget managed
to get well around in the cats with it
and I've got all the logged on user
accounts come on share the love so here
we go using it with the mimic apps which
on the end which logs into the box and
it obviously reveals the passwords that
are stored in memory and you can see
we've got the original count but we've
also got an M limp turn whose M limp
turn standard user account connects us
the central share what's the IP address
anything nice in there that's the IP
address normal data and some nice
passwords saved in Docs very common
including one which has passwords for
their corporate accounts media sites and
/ apps log it's going to be a bad day
for someone then let me say the PR
doctor oh yeah no prob scrub it here so
what we have here is a temporary share /
tour don't change anything if you test
any of the accounts here they are
downloading the file it's slow because
it store
tee's you got it just looking now so we
have a load of accounts to their
corporate PR sites and we log into one
of them starting to feel a bit sorry for
her you're going soft no as if do me a
favor can you explain how you found the
docks with passwords in them what did
you search no problem
it's really easy just open any directory
in windows at the top right search box
drop in the following contents password
it will then search for the defined word
in all docks it's always worth putting
in Facebook LinkedIn and other defined
words like that instead of password as
well
well that search recursively yep nice
you mind if I try go for it
so though they are copying it and
posting it
and there we go about five or six
directories deeply found it instantly
and there you go
that's cool thanks right what now we can
sell the PR accounts on afterwards how's
the share prices since the media blip
the wind down a bit we're going back up
people forget fast it'll be fine
you think we're ready not quite yet so
that machine I got the credits off but
drop the local admin hash off it and
pass the hash to a few other machines
slowly did you find anything
yeah the accounts were used I was able
to access another machine grab a local
admin rights an RDP to it grabbed a copy
of responder for Windows and left it
running you get much a couple of hashes
but couldn't reverse them so add an S CF
ball to the file server
what's an excel file take a look at the
SMB share server so you can all clearly
see there's the SCF file I can't find it
there are hundreds of files what's the
file called sorry look for the one that
starts with an @ symbol I called it that
so it always be at the top of the
directory there you go
you can name that anything you like and
inside of it you have an SMB request ok
I say it so when any user that opens
that shared directory results in their
machine making an SMB request to the IP
address in that file and I've been
sneaking the hashes let me see well yeah
so there we have the machine the
compromised and here we have a standard
user just going to the share folder to
grab a file just viewing that directory
will result in the hash is being
captured all runs a little bit slower on
Windows there you go we got hashes and
there we go that's the selection of the
hashes that were captured I managed to
reverse over half of them and a sort is
a domain admin and there you go that's
the password for the domain admin well
so we got all we need right nearly I'm
going to copy all I can from the share
folder you need any help now dude you're
done touch back here tomorrow Wednesday
1453 2018 has joined yo yo what you
thinking
Nicola needs and uploaded ready ready to
share on paste so there we have the file
power me build code has been released
oh no she want me to tweet it yeah good
call you do it now should be picked up
momentum by the morning power me build
hacked we released to the world there's
the link tweets live call right once the
news breaks keep an eye on the share
prices they'll drop quick I'll keep an
eye also night for now mate Thursday
1503 2080 8:30 a.m.
looks like Perry builds been hacked just
spotted it on Twitter and I'm still
looking for a CRT and check team leaders
because I'm a recruiter
trending para me build hacked data
release reports career in the para me
build company responsible for
construction projects including power
stations and government offices has been
breached has joined morning as too early
for me dude you say in share prices yeah
dropping like a stone per me build seize
it shares crashed by 78% following the
news of the security bridge they're down
80% is it time yet buy as much as you
can or didn't say done and now we wait
how long do we sell him your feet
typically shares crash for about one to
two weeks before people forget and they
start to rise again leave it a month or
so then we sell them hi
till next time yeah mate I'll contact
you in a few weeks let the heat pass
burn everything he used call Friday 1603
2018 and if you missed it here's an
email from Jim tusk sent to power me
build employees about someone purposely
sabotaging the company and all read it
because no one was know to read up right
I've dismayed to learn this weekend
about security breach potentially
conducted by power me build employee
resulting in extensive extensive
damaging sabotage to operations
this included potential direct ho
changes to the family build operating
system and default user names and
exporting large amounts of highly
sensitive power me bill data to unknown
third parties the full extent of his
actions are not yet clear but what we
have learned so far is pretty bad
potential motivation from the
disgruntlement following not being
awarded the promotion in light of these
actions not promoting him was definitely
the right move however there may be
considerably more this situation than
meets the eye so the investigation which
is started will be continuing for a week
we need to figure out that he was acting
a low or other power me build employees
were working or people working outside
the organization as you know there is a
long list of organizations the one
family builds died this includes Wall
Street short sellers who have already
lost billions of dollars and started to
lose a lot more they're also the oil and
gas companies the wealthiest industries
in the world they don't love the idea of
power me builds advancing the progress
of Greene builds don't want to blow your
minds but rumor has it
companies are sometimes not super nice
vendo the multi multitude of big
competitors if they're willing to cheat
on a deal maybe they're willing to cheat
in other ways most of the time when
there's a bet making your confidential
information it's a declaration of duty
or an outright sabotage the reason
really is something simple like wanting
to get back at the company as a whole
occasionally it's a lot more serious
please be extremely vigilant particular
over the next few weeks as we attempt to
ramp up work once more if you know or
suspect anything please send me a note
as much information as possible will
follow up this email as the information
is discovered thanks for working so hard
to make power me build successful Jim
chapter 5 Monday 903 2018 and this is
where I come into the story
my name is no lines and I work for a few
I was bought in alongside a team of
experts to try and work out what happens
at the initial meeting were informed the
following an attempt to brute force the
sslvpn was conducted by a potential
outside actors the attempt looked the
attempt looked to fail an internal user
called Joe Smith a home worker from the
sales team logged in by an ssl VPN and
over a few days copied internal data and
released it to a third party who looks
to have released it or labeled for its
release to paste to insinuate a hack to
damage the brand Joe Smith has been
suspended from work we requested Network
diagrams and a meeting with IT security
and we were given that that's a pretty
typical Network diagram ish today it's
pretty bad doesn't mean anything to you
and you just given it okay large global
network the SSL VPN terminated here so
he looked back up there that's where
they got in clients got in they use a
scene we asked to review rate it was
logging internal domain users failed off
attempts we asked if it logged SSL VPN
failed and successful authentication
attempts yes two failed
no two successful attempts
successful attempts require Cisco ASA
log reference 72 to 0-5 wants to be
enabled and there we go
so what it shows you is the user name
their external IP address and the fact
that they had authenticated correctly or
if using the a triple a server log of
seven one nine zero two two rolls off
the tongue you get a much shorter
I think nicer message it says the
username has a Penta cated what's
interesting is there's not on by default
and they listed under error messages so
successful authentication failed
authentication I say is a security log
not an error log so why default they're
not on and you can bet your life not a
lot of people log that especially not
the Penta kated ones it's common people
don't tune their seams or feed them long
logs that can help so when was the
initial brute-force attempt on the SSL
VPN it was Wednesday the 703 2018 1535
and here we can see the logs of all the
people unsuccessfully authenticating
against their SSL VPN golden question do
you use two-factor authentication on SSL
VPN well if I quickly mention this 2018
and still global organizations and not
using two-factor authentication on
external endpoints into their network
we're at the point where two-factor
authentication is almost been broken
from an automated point of view people
are releasing tools and scripts that can
capture the multi-factor authentication
tokens and then you can replay them so
I'm thinking you need to hurry up to
start using it before two factors also
not of any use okay
this is a golden replied they're not
presently using two-factor
authentication they're looking into it
okay do your windows dcs log event ids
to see who and when event kated yes we
do would you like to see them here we go
we have the window logs and you can see
that I'll tell you minutes but someone
has successfully authenticated so from
the windows logs it was possible to
identify on the 12th and 3rd 2018 around
11:45 at J Smith attempting
and failed to login to every domain
machine apart from one which if enter
kated into that's odds that should have
raised an alarm with their internal team
immediately to start investigation
here's another good question where was J
Smith at 11:45 from the 12th of the 3rd
2018 well they thought he was working
from home they didn't bother to check
that so J Smith was actually on site a
meeting with Linton strategies at their
head office yes starting to get painful
so can you verify the meeting and a
location actually they could yes and he
was there Monday the second Oh 4th 2018
so the audit was completed and the
report was sent in and here's a summary
from the executive summary and the
following details at no review of the
results of the on-site security
investigation conducted a family build
head office on the 7th of the 30 2018
around 11:35 an attempt by remote great
actor or actors to gain unlawful access
to the sslvpn solution used by pammi
bill to enable remote workers access to
the internal resources was identified
while originally disregarded and the
belief that the attempt that they're
tempted attack on that date was not
successful reevaluation based on the
collection and review of machine
security was collected while on site
indicates that the access on the above
date was gained by the threat actors or
actor following the capture of user
domain identification externally
available services were identified as
requiring only single factor
authentication
the combination of inadequately secured
externally available services combined
with poor password choices results in a
trivial Bower from the threat actors to
gain access following the capture of the
domain credentials other unexpected
internal occurrences were identified
indicating that further accounts were
compromised and used to extract data
while on site it was recommended that
the SL sslvpn
should be disabled and all internal
domain cap should have their passwords
reset the SSL VPN wasn't disabled and
all the accounts were not reset Tuesday
deferred Oh for 2018
Hayami build co and co step down
two weeks after revealing a massive data
breach pammi build announced two of its
executives a retiring effectively
immediately Wednesday to for foe for
pammi build sharing has closed a record
on high has joined seen the shares yep
sell my name is my exploit when 600 on
Twitter thank you for watching
[Applause]