20 so we can start thank you very much
for being here in the lightning talks my
name is Stephan Hagar I want to talk
about weaponizing layer 8 and before we
get into that a very brief introduction
my name is as I just said and I'm
repeating myself okay and I work for a
big company in Germany doing mostly
security research I work in IT since
1990 or something like that and my main
focus very often is psychology and
getting users on board as well so the
good question is why is this thing not
working and the second question is why
am i doing this talk we have been for
years and years and by we I always
include myself of course we have been
calling our users names problem exists
between keyboard and chair lay a problem
losers
what have you and over the years we kind
of expected our users to become better
at security by insulting them that kind
of didn't work so I'm thinking about new
approaches on how we can get our users
on board so security comes easy and
naturally to them and is more an enabler
than anything in in their path because
basically I think that humans matter
there have been a lot of talks at
conferences about how users are not
really the weakest link that can be a
very strong asset and I'd like to talk
to you about a few methods where I think
we can actually turn them into a bat
as that so before I actually start with
methods why is it important that to me
that people actually know how to have a
certain security awareness a certain
behavior in the internet and that is
because cyber and I'm using that word
yes how cyber that cyber really impacts
the physical domain in order to
illustrate that point think back to last
December
we're an online game called MCS co-led
to somebody being killed by this by the
police because basically two guys who
are fighting and haggling about a sale
and it was something like I think one or
two dollars and one of the guys said you
know if you don't pay I'm calling the
police on you I'm swatting you this is
an actual work I think and the other guy
said well go on then that's where I live
but he gave the wrong address so a
heavily armed SWAT team arrived at
somebody who really hadn't any idea what
was going on
opened the door saw the police and for
some reason reach for his waistband and
got killed so cyber does impact the
physical domain and there are ways how
people's life are really influenced in a
very bad way that is why I think it's
very good
to teach a few stupid tricks to humans
so stupid human tricks isn't actually
referring to stupid humans but to the
stupid tricks
I should have made that clearer I guess
you know that cliche from the pen pen
testers who want to get into a company's
Network and just throw out USB sticks in
the parking lot labeling them if they
are creative nowadays I think I would
write Bitcoin wallet on a USB stick
because that probably gets a few people
greedy or finances 2017 or something
like that because the idea is if a
person finds a USB stick
they will plug it in but you can not
only target greed you could target
friendliness of people so for example if
you find a USB stick at your work with a
photo generic photo of a guy or girl and
a small teddy bear what would you like
to do probably you would think yeah that
is something I would like to return to
the owner because although we in InfoSec
tend to be a little bit more cynical and
shaded humans channel returned to be
nice as long as you don't get to know
them and so many people will pluck USB
sticks in to see what's on
and actually I think we are guilty as
well because we know that hey plugging
in an unknown USB stick is a stupid idea
so we do it in a sandbox because we are
as curious as the others but we're going
to plug it in and at our company we have
that idea - yeah come on users want to
plug in USB sticks they found give them
the opportunity but do it in a way that
we control so we build something sorry
for the chairman but we're a chairman
company so it would be called something
in German we we build something we call
wires VN groove kiosk which means I'm
just wireless examination yes
and basically it goes like this you
authenticate with your ID card and then
thing says hello Stefan and you can plug
in your USB stick and it just transfers
data from the USB stick to your office
PC so there's no need to plug in your
USB stick to the office PC and
potentially infect the whole network and
of course on the way from that thing to
your office PC there's a lot of stuff
going on like virus detection sandboxing
and so on and so forth if a virus is
found it's not going to be transmitted
to your inbox that's as easy as it gets
we didn't want to help the users in the
first place with plaquing unknown USB
sticks we just wanted to have a way how
users could get their files their
PowerPoint presentation was something
they worked on to the office PC when
they started working in the morning
because before we had that you had to
wrap you USB stick in an envelope send
it to another team they would scan it
send it back and that would take three
or four days this is more than IT so
this really helps and funnily enough
people plug in I can plug in their
private USB sticks as well because this
is so isolated it's a Linux machine it's
hard that you can't basically in fact
that and so we're giving users what they
want and making our network secure at
the same time the next thing I think we
are completely doing wrong is fishing
fish
as you probably know is still one of the
lectures how you can attack attack a
company so we try to get users to read
links to hover over the links to see the
real link to try to find out whether a
shortened link is malicious or not and
with puny code and everything I think
that even experts have a hard time
telling a phishing link from a genuine
link just by looking at it alone so it's
much more interesting to talk to users
about indicators of because
every phishing link every spam email has
some in it and those I obese
very often are clicking no of course
money somehow money is involved either
it is a small sum you pay now if you pay
now and a large sum you would have to
pay later or of course it's the nice
nigerian prince who really likes you and
would like to send you 19 million so of
course the underlying reason why people
are sending our phishing emails in the
long run very often is money so the
maids are going to be about money and
this is a dead giveaway i don't have to
hover on a link if somebody says you
know you have to pay 66 euros now click
here then i just know it's a fishing
ling very often it it the next thing
that is always an indicator as
well ah threat the implied threat like
we just had pay 60 euros now or five
hundred years later or it's a threat
like your computer will be insecure if
you don't click that link or something
bad will happen
or maybe something good will happen now
if you click it but something bad will
happen later so there's always some kind
of implied threat and with that very
often comes the third indicator i want
to talk about and that is urgency
because our minds work better if we can
think longer about something urgency is
one of the indicators how people are
tricked into clicking links because it's
a click now you have
seconds to win this Mercedes SLK if you
click that window just now and this kind
of urgency kind of numbs our critical
facility in our brains and if you see
two or more of those indicators of
in an email they are easy to remember
even for everyone who doesn't really
work in IT and doesn't want to know
about IT and that is a dead giveaway
because at the end of it those people in
your company if you're not working for a
small pen testing company but for a
global company with lots and lots of
people they want to do their job and I
think they rightly perceive IT security
to be our job in the long run I don't
know how we get there I would like to be
able to give our users a browser where
they can click any link and email INBOX
where they can click any link without
any hesitation because they are
protected in some way or the other there
are a few ways to do that but
unfortunately 15 minutes is not long
enough to talk about that but we can
talk about that later or in the break
room I love talking about that stuff
it's harder to keep me to get me to shut
up then to talk about that the next
thing what I really like is taking
social engineering methods to people who
are attacking us I'm pretty sure every
one of you has heard about CEO fraud in
the last few years so see all fraud
costs Google and other really large
companies hundreds of millions there was
one company in Nuremberg where I live
who paid 34 Millions and CEO fraud
basically works like that an employee
gets an email or a call from the CEO of
course it's not the ratio but they don't
know that and the CEO more or less asks
for money and says you know you were
finances I'm doing a deal in country X
and to seal the deal we need to have 30
million transferred to that account but
it has to happen today and you mustn't
talk to anybody else because otherwise
the business is in danger we might lose
it
so you mustn't talk to anybody and can
we transfer 30 million today if we can
there's a lawyer who will contact you
and so on and so forth and this has
nothing to do with IT security in the
beginning because it's just a classic
scam but it works really well and seeing
that other companies lose really
millions of euros makes it clear that it
is very successful and that it won't
stop
in fact there's another company in
Nuremberg who gets bombarded with
sioffra and they get got so fed up that
they did a really cool thing they
forward all these males to this sock and
the sock just changes a little bit in
the email address so that the Betty
probably doesn't notice and they say hi
I'm sorry but you probably forgot that
we have this new payment portal in place
since two months where you can actually
do all the payments yourself because
you're the CEO do you want your login
credentials again and so the attacker of
course is right yes please and they get
login credentials for a payment portal
they log in they do the transaction and
of course the money this never get
transferred right but the problem for
the Betty is they have to put in the
Iban of the account where they want the
money and now this company goes and says
you know that Ivan this is fraudulent we
are going to tell the police and we are
looking at our transactions have you
ever sent money to that Ivan to that
bank account and if so then try to get
it back and blacklist it we will never
send money to that account and I think
that's ingenious and we're trying our
companies now trying to get other people
to interact with us and have some kind
of publicly available data based on
those Ivan's
unfortunately gdpr disagrees a little
bit with us at the moment so but still
if you're interested in exchanging data
it might not happen now but I hope it's
going to happen at some point
get in touch please
the next thing that might be something
that hasn't been said at a lot of
InfoSec conferences is I would urge
people to write down their passwords and
before you behead me not us not in a
company environment but if you think
about your friends your elderly
acquaintances your gran your granddad
and people like that I think it's
perfectly fine for them to have a
booklet with their passwords written
down with good passwords written down
instead of having password one
everywhere the reason for that is that
different threats have different
solutions and if you think about it if
somebody breaks in at your Gran's house
and stands in her flat then this burglar
is not interested in their Facebook
password because they want the valuables
they want to see what's there and steal
stuff they're not going to the password
booklet and steal that and even if they
do you have greater problems at the time
and if you can't persuade your friends
and family to use a password safe then I
think using writing down passwords in a
private environment for people who are
not endangered or targeted by political
organizations or whatever it's perfectly
safe
on the other hand if you are working in
a company please use a password safe and
do not write down your passwords because
people like me would probably come by
your PC and read it and log in as you
but that is another point whenever we
are very often info security tends to
have this this approach of
one-size-fits-all I need to protect
against everything and I think that is
wrong I think that makes security
unnecessarily strong in some places and
silly in others so just think about what
the threat is and what you could do to
mitigate it one thing I haven't seen in
the wild which but I like the idea is if
you have a company just register a
website that has nothing to do with your
company
and provide an email forwarder to all
your to all the people working at your
company because nowadays the email
address is the digital identity for most
people right probably most people in the
room will have several email accounts
but a lot of people just have one and if
that is broken any attacker can reset
passwords they are going to be sent to
that email address and so on and so
forth and if you have a email for water
and the address of the email for word
shows up in have ID being pawned then so
what they still don't know the real
email address that is lying behind that
they can't attack my real email account
because they only have the forwarding
address there are problems with that as
well because basically what happens if
the employee leaves the company will
they keep the forwarded address and so
on and so forth but this is another idea
how we could progress with that so
basically my call for action in that
very short talk is not to buy the next
box not to buy the next generation what
have you blockchain dark cyber secured
appliance thingy that you're just
plugging in and hoping that it will do
something but educate your users and try
to actually find out their ideas how
they work where security is really a
pain in the ass for them and try to
relieve that pain because basically they
want to do their stuff they want to do
their accountancy while you want to do
security and all the while just please
do not despair because basically we have
chopped security that is cynical of
course because we will never fix
security or we won't fix it at the
current state but instead of being
depressed just find out what you have at
your company or how you could actually
make security work better by enabling
your people and this is basically no
better than expected this is basically
my talk there's a long version of that
coming up if you are interested in that
and if you want to talk about that any
time
thank you for listening are there any
questions sorry I was just you know
right there I've handed it in
well I'm going to do it very likely at
the Illuminati party at Bethlem and I've
handed it in for deep second Vienna and
t2 in Finland but of course I don't know
whether they are going to accept it I
will have it in my pocket for b-sides no
leets sorry
so I will hand it in four pieces Leeds
as well alright okay thank you