they'll heard from hackaday today I'm
going to show you how I hacked my 1983
Datsun Z engine control unit case you
couldn't hear me out the garage there
I'm still bill Hurd and this is still
hackaday and today I'm swapping out my
old stock engine control unit from my
1983 Datsun 280zx T with a mega squirt
that I built myself this is a kit it's
made by Bolling's and grip oh and uh
it's it's not open-source hardware but
it's cheap hardware and then the
firmware is available you can make
changes there's all kinds of trains to
it I'm running what's called mega squirt
two extra allows me to do lots of cool
things in addition to the normal ECU
functions now what's an ECU the ECU
generally controls the fuel to air
mixture in your car you might control
the spark they you know where the spark
occurs in the combustion cycle of the
engine and it can control a lot of
things for example I've got mine
controlling the the fuel pump speed
things like that so lots of things we
can do but why would you want to do all
of this
well that unit I just showed you is
hardwired it's set up for a certain
amount of fuel that it expects for a
certain amount of air to make the engine
run at optimal well if you change that
balance you'll need to change the
balance of the fuel and air you know
that that goes along with it so my case
I shoved a lot more air in the engine
bigger turbocharger also I've made the
cylinders bigger and the stroke longer
and so there's a lot of things going on
and I needed to give it simply more fuel
alright and that required like bigger
injectors in a bigger fuel pump but also
then controlling the pulse width of that
I'm going to show you that in some
detail so in and why this old cranky car
in 1983 well some of you may know I
worked for Commodore back in the 80s and
part of getting to CES shows which were
always January of you know of the new
year inevitably a Datsun Z would park in
the parking lot around
November and then just not move until
the snow melted and it won't appeared
magically from the snowdrift and then I
would have it towed and then I would use
the bonus I got for making the CSU and
go buy another one it's kind of funny
when they tow the car away to be a
little sad pile of rust and nuts and
bolts but it's it's kind it's a car
that's kind of near and dear to me so I
spent some time customizing this car so
before I talk more about the ECU I'm
going to show you about how the basics
of how engines function and I'll show
you all the things this is controlling
here's a block diagram of a kind of
typical engine let's call it that where
the red arrows represent the trip of the
air through the engine alright so
starting from the air inlet in in my
case we go through an air flow meter and
the reason is in this case is it's all
about mixing the right amount of fuel
with the right amount of air now in my
1983 Datsun Z there is this thing called
a flapper that had a door that opened it
closed and it would give you a value for
how much air is going through it's kind
of arcane actually then it went to the
throttle body and this is where the
accelerator hooks up hooks to through a
mechanical linkage and this is what you
know you're used to stepping on how you
interact with the engine and you might
think that you're adding fuel to the
engine well not directly what you're
really doing is opening a stop gate that
lets more air into the engine so what
you're really doing is adding air every
time you step on the accelerator and
it's the ECU that figures out how much
fuel then to mix with that air but it
starts with you letting the air in in
most cases in the carburetor days the
same thing except that it was the air
whistling through the venturi that added
more fuel than but it's but it was the
air you opened up the air gets into the
manifold which is simply a name for the
area above the where the Pistons are in
the valves and everything and this is
where the fuel injectors spray into in
this case and it mixes before it gets
sucked into the Pistons and then it
leaves it in the form of exhaust so the
ECU controls the fuel injection
how often or not how often but when to
fire and how much fuel to mix in and
then there's things like the cylinder
head temperature in my case in my Z if
the temperature sensor is broken or the
wires unplugged my car won't run okay so
it's so this is part of how dense is the
air so how much fuels so that's part of
it and then there's an oxygen sensor and
exhaust in my case I've actually added a
second one so that I've got one for the
loop of the ECU working and then another
one for just sensing on my dashboard
things like that and then there's some
other little things going on like
knowing where you are in the cycle the
crank crank case position and ultimately
control the spark plugs now I'm not
controlling the spark in mind just yet
so now I skipped one and that was the
manifold pressure there is a second way
to tell how much air is going on you
know how much fuel you need to mix and
that is the manifold pressure the harder
you step on the gas the more of a
suction is created in this manifold by
these pistons running up and down you
can sometimes hear it whistling you know
on some engines and if you get a hole in
your manifold the air car won't run well
or one of the hoses comes off and it's
because it's trying to pull a vacuum
here try to suck this air in and it's
it's it's not it's not being measured
correctly or something now there's a
second way as I said instead of using
the air flow meter you can monitor this
manifold pressure and that's what the
mega squirt does is is I've left my air
flow meter and in case I want to go back
to it but in this case it measures how
much vacuum in when you're pulling hard
the more vacuum you get and then when
the blower kicks in when the turbo how
much overpressure there is so these are
the basic connections of an ECU to a
fuel-injected engine here's the air flow
meter I wanted to show you just how I'm
gain Lee does this thing was that
there's the valve and here's where the
the measuring flapper and here's
actually different shapes of elastomer
cut to make a variable resistor that's
spring tuned and everything and this
thing in normal operation is doing
something like this
to try and measure the earth where's a
more modern airflow sensor this is a
heated wire airflow sensor and you can
actually see through this one this is
from a bmw m3 and basically it measures
how much heat is removed from a heated
wire by the airflow through it so a lot
better than the flapper but again you
know it's something to be said for
monitoring the manifold pressure or the
actual air flow through into the engine
so and BMW thought this was good enough
to use on one of their sports cars okay
let me show you some of the cool stuff
what you're seeing here is a virtual
dash panel and you can program these
change the look and feel and everything
but I'm just showing some basic controls
and what we're doing is we have a
simulator plugged into our mega square
this simulates the car I can change the
throttle position the throttle position
sensor the temperatures a few variable
things like this and you can't see the
LEDs but they're telling me I'm at idle
and that the fuel pumps on and that it's
firing the the fuel injectors and if you
want to have a cooler dashboard there
are a bunch of others that you can
select from I'll just so now as I modify
my rpm I could actually build this into
the dashboard if I wanted to we also
have the option of doing a data logger
where we can make very different things
and it will get logged by this and then
we've got a natural analyzer that will
help us with the tune-up based on our
driving conditions and we're going to do
that one last but let's get back to
basic setup and this is kind of what
it's all about this is where I
unfortunately I can't make it go
vertically because I don't have a you
know I can't modify the manifold
temperature but this is the RPM and I
can modify these variables around here
to adjust the fuel air mixture and you
should hear it I can actually while it's
sitting there idling and you'll hear go
doo-doo-doo-doo jin-yi and that's really
cool too suddenly it dawns on you that
you're controlling the actual fuel air
mixture in your car so and we can
oh this you know it's a 3d view and
there's a lot of other maps similar to
this and I will show you one on the car
that's running where it actually does an
oval as we step on the gas and release
as the manifold pressure you know it has
load going up and then coasts coming
down I won't go through everything here
but there are engine constants and
injector characteristics I tell things
about how big my injectors are I went to
35 pound injectors they're called
we can control how the engine gets
primed it squirts extra gas in there get
extra fuel in there too to get your
engine running when you first start it
and then also it will enrich the fuel
based on temperature and this is real
important at least in the case of my
vehicle one of the tuning functions in
here is we have acceleration enrichment
which basically says when you slam on
the accelerator it tries to give it an
extra shot of fuel and actually it's
about the only thing monitoring the
accelerator does is in this kind of
setup so there's a wizard in here where
I can say Oh monitor it this way but if
we watch down here in the lower left I'm
going to change the accelerator quickly
and we get this indication right here
that it just gave us an extra shot so
that's one of the features built into
this here's a 3d ve map of the engine
actually running and we see now the
range of motion of the manifold pressure
and the RPMs with the fuel enrichment
shown as a spectral map with the red
being the most fuel and
being the least all right I'm running
out of time but there's just so much to
show you that that's possible with these
things with the the mega squirt you know
they have things for running your
detonation sensor there's launch control
you can run nitrous system you can
control your your turbo boost to connect
as a controller just a lot of things but
one cool thing I wanted to show you is
you can create your own outputs by you
pick which output you want and then
there's just a wide range of values you
can say well hey if the fuel load is
this or if the battery voltage is below
a certain amount and something else is
happening the pin goes higher the pin
goes low and I do something similar to
that to control the speed of my fuel
pump so nice of boolean program ability
also built into this and and finally I
showed this just briefly before in this
version I some versions can actually do
all the logging inside the mega store at
the Version three mine's an older
version of the mega squirt too so I
actually have to my let have my laptop
plugged in and running while I go out
for test drives and it will take the
values that it sees programmed in and
compare them to what it thinks the
optimal value should be based on the
actual running of the engine and then
make suggestions and you can go ahead
and apply that it's a learning easy you
in other words and they have these now
you can you know for the newer cars that
have obd ii and stuff they plug right in
and they're self learning well here you
got to get a little more involved but at
least it can learn and there's reasons
for that for example I wouldn't know
like when you're going at a high rate of
speed and you let off the accelerator I
wouldn't know how much to lean it off to
clean off the spark plugs or to wet the
the walls of the of the Pistons of the
cylinders but this should no tricks like
that so that you end up getting a pretty
reasonable tune just by taking it out
and driving it come back and then you
you look it over and then you save it to
the ECU
so a very cool feature and
finally here's the inside again this was
a kid I built so it was the last of the
through-hole versions if I remember
correctly this is based on a 16-bit
processor called the m9 MC 9 s 12 C 64
which is a 16-bit computer
microcontroller microprocessor
upgrade from the old 60 hhc 12 by
freescale back in the 90s and it's it's
got like a 24 may clock and 4k and 128 K
of RAM and flash beds got things like
building km bus and whatnot but the main
thing is this this is from 2005 so this
was around before so many of the arm
variants and everything we have now you
can find lots of things with can these
days but yeah this has some time on the
jumpers are actually there was an area
to build circuitry one the few times
ever used the area to build circuitry as
I brought in some other signals from
from the big ass connector here on the
side and I've made low-pass filters and
this some of this goes into my fuel fuel
pump logic stuff like that also I'm
playing with a anti detonation so I
don't rely on the old ECU and of course
drivers big honking rectifiers and
drivers for the fuel injectors you know
which is in relays which is what this
thing ends up driving so not much to it
like I said it was an inexpensive kit
that I put together myself and rivals
the the features of the thousand dollar
kits that are $1000 devices that are out
there today and then there was the lo
mega sim this was also get like 50 bucks
or something this just it's basically a
VCO and some potentiometers but I I
ended up I built one and then I bought
one because it was really nice to do
while working on this thing so not much
to it alright well I hope you found that
interesting I had a blast restore in
this car like I said it was kind of a
legacy thing for me back from the 80s
90s when when I used to drive these
things and uh gosh I've got a mile of
weld and wire in the car I've
powder-coated I've redone the engine
down you know well I opened the engine I
didn't even know what my
that crap was and now I do so and now I
get to put this together put it back in
the car and get the car running again so
bill heard from hackaday I don't even
know what we're doing next time but
stick around and we'll figure it out
together