[Music]
they'll heard from hackaday today I'm
going to be hacking the OBD port on my
late-model SUV just kinda for the heck
of it as I said I'm going to be hacking
away at the OBD port in my car here
today and I'll probably say ODB at least
one time during a load EDC or some but
onboard diagnostic obd now that's that
funny little connector that's up under
your dashboard as a matter of fact when
my older cars failed they changed the
laws here in New Jersey I take it in
they couldn't get to the plug like
getting a straight shot at it and they
failed me for emissions because they
couldn't plug in so now everything they
want to know about my car I get from the
onboard diagnostic OBD port now this
here is like a little wireless dongle
that you can get to plug in these are
real popular these days you have your
own scan tools that allow you to plug in
and learn what's going on in your car
but I had a different thing in mind what
happened was I had installed a usable
GPS into my late-model Ford Explorer and
so that silly Microsoft thing kept using
my cell phone asked where the heck it
was just horrible thing so I stick it in
and I get a harness adapter and I've
done this dozens of times but this time
the VSS signal the video speed sensor
signal was not present in the harness I
didn't notice right away right time but
I noticed when my GPS would show me
driving about forty yards to the right
of the actual highway and things and
what happens is the GPS is a combination
of asking the satellites from time to
time but also knowing the speed of your
car and so it can do some dead reckoning
especially the satellite signal is weak
or whatever so I go to look for the VSS
signal and I've had to track these down
before this is just common alright you
can get it you know it's usually in the
car somewhere it hangs off the
transmission sometimes at the cable I
mean the sensors Hall effect sensor
something and they day sometimes they
hang off the wheels for the speed but
that's kind of for the
the breaking what I don't want to get I
own terrified that a microprocessor is
in charge of the brakes of my car anyway
you slide alone messing with that wire
and what I found was I couldn't find the
VSS wire i alternate li rented the
schematics directly from Ford for three
days dug deep into it found that the VSS
wire indeed does not come anywhere near
the dashboard it's not underneath the
kick panel where it used to be on some
other cars and in fact the finally the
place I found it was where they had a
wire say knew how fast to make the
windshield wipers go silly reads only
but only digital version of the VSS wire
in my fork in in the past it used to use
them so you knew how loud to make the
radio but they I guess they quit doing
that or that's a GM thing or something
so what I wanted to do is make a small
circuit board and this is just an insane
little thing if you see the way I did it
I'll show you here in a second that
takes that reads the OBD port so you
plug it in leave it in and creates a
speed pulse for a GPS so big ole
elephant dragging a mouse right so I
want to show you how I did that and
talked a little bit about the obd part
of obd onboard diagnostic protocol and
you know some of the things I learned
while playing with this now here's my
first pass at a board that does what I
was talking about which would interface
to the OBD port in my car and create a
pulse basically you know you'll see I
did a really crazy thing I'm using
surface mount for the chips because of
the available the available space here
and then I still used actual
through-hole resistors and stood them up
on end like the old transistor radios
that just simply because I hate hand
soldering tons of SMT resistors so you
don't take up too much room and I did
get it to fit but but this was a
full-blown does all the different
versions I so enjoy 1850 and stuff and
I'm going to change that I think so on
board we have a basically a UART four
obd made by a made by obd solution
strangely enough but it's called the stn
one one one zero
the 1110 and basically it takes care of
it I'm going to show the schematic here
but it takes care of kind of the
protocols for you and then I threw on an
80 mega 3:28 like in your Arduino ish
type things so it sits on the board and
notin so basically what I've done is
emulated taking an Arduino and a can
shield right and this is made by seed
studio and you can do that if you want
but I wanted mine to fit in a little box
so I kind of jumped in and made my own
little thing right here's the view of
the PC board I made for this video
inside my CAD package now I toyed with
the idea of doing yellow with black silk
screen and two things one what if it
looks like crap on the video yeah I just
I couldn't risk it and second I use PCB
way overseas for my boards these cost me
a buck each and I get them you know
within a week except for black silk
screen raised the price to like two and
a half bucks each so I went back to my
normal blue and white so here I am if my
normal colors and you can see like I
said I I did this crazy thing of
standing the resistors but you know once
I started trying to make it fit I just
got lost in trying to make it fit so but
here's what the schematic looks like and
I'll tell you never ever do this okay
don't cram all the stuff on one page but
with that said do as I say not as I do
again I get so involved with just trying
to make it fit so I have a processor
page with the static protection for uh I
say you should say surge protection and
the regular page but there's too much
here to try and show you so I'm going to
break it down further I mean show you in
one page here's the main part the stn 11
10 that I spoke about
and again this acts like a UART to
convert all the protocols into just a
UART it's not like setting registers and
having to learn in this case the can
protocol or the ISO protocols or
anything
pretty much does that for you given that
you know how to query out using an ATC
type command set like the elm327 I think
is the super subset of it and it
actually acts kind of like a modem in
some ways so here's here's that part and
you know it's available in a surface
mount or a dip and again it takes care
of old stuff this thing costs like
eleven dollars so you're paying for the
software on this now the can shield I
called you I don't know why they call it
a ship we call them daughter cards
people my age and probably shows our age
but the you could go with the standalone
can controller that's what's on the
shield but I'll tell you what you got to
learn something about can protocol
you've got to learn about extended data
frames I think and then at the end of
the day nothing says that's the OBD
represent a version of the protocol it
scan protocol and what I first heard of
came back in the late 70s early 80s for
uh for automation in the factory
manufacturing automation so been around
a while but I just want to talk this
thing like a UART I'm going to get this
project rolling along get a video made
out of it so I stuck with the stn 1110
so let me show you this in a schematic
where where you can see it so to go
through the board schematic in a little
bit more detail remember that obd is
several different protocols not per car
but the plug has to support it depending
on what kind of car you're plugging into
you're going to be plugging into in this
case you see Ford uses Ford modern-day
Ford uses K and high-speed but it used
to use one of the one of the ISOs and so
I'm sorry one the J 1850s remember that
we have J 1850 variable pulse which 1850
pulse width modulation variable pulse
width the actual frequency will change
with pulse width modulation only the
ratio of highest to load change but
there's more involved for J 1850 pulse
width modulation the main thing they see
is that
based on five volts and if we look at
variable pulse width it's a seven volt
creature yay so right off the bat one of
the things I want to show you is that's
the way we deal with the 5-7 volt the
defied the seven volt need is there is a
control line that indicates when it's
and pulse width modulation mode or
variable pulse width and that changes
the 5/7 volt signal to be your powers
power rail to be either 5 or 7 and it
does this by changing the ratio of these
reference resistances on an LM one one
seven of adjustable voltage regulator
similar to the low dropouts four five
and three except this one is not preset
to a voltage it uses these ratios and
basically you count on this resistance
here to be almost zero when it's on and
when it's off you'll see this 240 volts
or 240 ohm here we see the J 1850 in
their interface and one thing I'll say
is all of this stuff needs heavy surge
protection the automobile is a horrible
place for power surges you have huge
inductors right starter motors all those
we call load dumping so I'm not showing
a lot of that right now you might see it
later just attacked on the schematics
but if you were going to production with
this is a big part of what you can't
ignore is how to protect all this from
the environment it's in also automotive
temperature ranges are just horrible
right minus 40 degrees hot car was that
iron 2130 leave it in your window right
melt so here's the J 1850 though and you
can see that you know the transmitter is
if sets basically it's got a low and a
high and this sets the correct
references and then for the receiver we
end up with two halves of an op-amp
which basically just different
thresholds that's that's pretty much
what's going on here and then these
again go into the 1110 and it turns it
into a York signal into ASCII for you I
so 91 42 is has a basically when you see
a K in an L line that's that's the
signals involved in this it's a 12-volt
based protocol and as it says this is
Chrysler European or Age
vehicles again up to about 2008 here's
the interface for that just pull downs
and actually the speed of these
important I have a feeling I'd have to
check the speeds on the 22 22s by the
way I grabbed most of this right out of
the application notes for the parts -
people make these parts no more than I
do at the moment if I was a production
design for production you better believe
I would tear into these to the minutia
right because that's that's how you make
things work in production here's the
transmitter is your basic common emitter
output and then it uses a op amp with
again a preset threshold here as a
comparator I'm sorry this is compared
I've been called an op amp which often
comparators are op amps but lm339 is an
open collector version that's very good
at what it does and so this is the third
part of the LM 3 339 and this is the ISO
91 41 protocol and then we have cam and
I haven't been showing you the speeds
but KN is the fastest they you could see
the speech but now now we're into the
high speed stuff this is since 2008 and
we find that it's got a voltage the high
and lows so it's all below 5 but the
high it welds 4.5 as we see here and the
high and lows are 3.5 and 1.5 volts you
will not build your own key and
transceiver most of the time you will
use one here's the can transceiver I'm
using um if I go completely if I make a
version that's just canned based
I'll probably go back to making
everything through hold maybe I can make
it a kit throw it up onto Indy or
something but this is a canned
transceiver not to be confused with a
can controller right this is a whole
processor thing or I'm sorry this meant
an Augmented processor like they show a
lot of pic variants and it speaks SPI
this is just the correct electrical
interface to the car now again I'll
throw in my things as es des des D you
need to protect these devices from all
the crazy voltages you'll find in your
car and let alone that you write strange
commands to your
Caron caused it to fall out do that kind
of thing now I've been talking way too
much just showing you the hardware
involved so I actually want to show you
this working I'll cover more about the
actual obd codes that you need PIDs
parameter ID that we send a request
information an OB D bus doesn't just
stream information you ask it things in
the ECU or actually transmission might
respond and then there's a diagnostic
trouble code at DTC and that is that
does originated from the obd bus tell
you its problem that your check engine
light usually means there's a dtc
waiting to be picked up but first i just
want to show you remember i want to go
get the speed of my car so i can vary a
pulse with very simple right well first
we need a car well doesn't fit in here
right plus you're not going to go out
and really work on your car outside and
hook strange hardware to it without
knowing at least works so I have here a
obd simulator stimulator whatever you
want to call it or Dax like a car I got
this one cheap off eBay for like 70
bucks or something you can buy these in
the States could good ones from no
manufacturers there are a couple hundred
bucks if you're doing serious work
that's what I do but I'm making a video
here so if we look at our obd stimulator
here simulator says sim right here you
see we can pick today all kinds of them
right now set mind set for iso 91 41
we'll see if that works and then here
are potentiometers that represent the
different things about your car remember
i was interested in the speed of the car
and if i turn this the speed actually in
shown in kilometers an hour will vary
okay now what I just noticed here a bit
ago is there's actually the PID written
below at 0 1 0 D so what I want to do is
ask this device here about 0 1 0 D and
it should come back with a speed between
0 and 2 and 255 kilometers per hour here
I've got my simulator plugged into a
development board and it's made by obd
solutions same people that made the chip
that's on here in fact here's the chip
this is the 1110 hit this is an 1170
it's a cousin to
here's all the driver stuff that's all
over my board here and this processor
that I'm just showing here because I
lost my hackaday pro trinket while I was
shooting here so I pulled this one out
represents the processor that's down
here but what makes this good for
shooting here today is it's got a
built-in USB to serial adapter and let's
see if we can pull the speed out of this
thing here on the Left I've got my
terminal program hooked to the virtual
comport on com6
and it's got the reset message I will
warn you this has kind of the standard
old problem of carriage returns and line
feeds not kind of mapping each other but
when I give it an ATV just like it will
note them it gives me back my message
now remember this is all about getting
the value for 0 1 0 D which is right
here and that is the speed right next to
it C rpm actually 0 1 0 C but let's go
ahead and ask for the current speed and
what it's done is it's overwritten
itself but it replied with 41 0 D and
then B 5 which happens to be 181 I
looked it up ahead of time and sure
enough on the speed here it's up for 181
km/h if we go ahead and change the speed
and ask it again now we get a DD so all
this to get that little value to pop out
of the OBD bus of your car so as you saw
I was able to extract the the speed as a
bite without non-kin protocol anything
like that just a little bit of ASCII and
that's why I did it that way again
designing for production IBEW well I'd
want to do it the cheapest way which
means you invest more upfront in your
design and less and using other people's
expensive stuff but that's a cool little
chip in my book so next time I'll be
working back on this thing here again of
doing the software for it and I'm going
to probably treat this more like a
real-time operating system meaning I
want to use I don't want to sit in
Assyria
Loup i won when you use the counters and
timers to create those pulse widths and
and do so in a way where it's rooted in
you know relates to the crystal
frequency right real time I'm a hardware
guy right
I like in-circuit emulator and hopefully
I designed this sucker good enough that
I can actually in circuit emulate and
not just do a bunch of printf because
I'm a lousy programmer I like in-circuit
emulator 'sons so that I should be able
on this one I think I use the debug wire
pin so bill heard from hackaday uh part
one of two parts of obd this being the
hardware stuff next time we'll do a
little bit of software for creating our
pulses so that we can drive a GPS off
our obd bus so still heard from hackaday
and we'll catch you on the next part
[Music]