they'll heard from hackaday today we're
going to be programming a Cpl D from
start to finish
here's a small selection of FPGA and Cpl
D boards this one's an altaira
FPGA and you see a lot of pins broken
out on it this is our Tara this is cool
you can do high level video programming
on that real high level stuff you don't
have to worry about the color planes and
stuff it tracks everything for you we've
got a lattice this one I did a couple
years ago this is a full of video based
DSP system where the processor and the
DSP work was all put in a pga form and
here's one I'm working on right now this
happens to be a CPL d but it's hundred
forty four pins it's got a close-coupled
SRAM on this one and I also have another
version that's got a some level
converters on it so let's start with him
I wanted to take a moment and show you
the board that I designed up here for
our little test it's it's not hugely
complicated this is it is a four layer
board but it took me about an hour to
lay out the power supply and and the
multiple voltages for that and then an
hour with the auto router constraining
the auto router to come up with this but
what I want her to show you is these
CPLDs and FPGAs these days are have
multiple voltages in a standard four
layer board you would put VCC on one
layer and ground on another they usually
say to make the ground on top it lowers
the inductance up the top components and
adds a ground shielding value to as to
some of the components on the top of the
board but when you have three voltages
including ground what do you do so I
wanted to show you that let me turn on
some layers here and see if we can turn
off allure so this is a combination of
the inner two layers where there's no
really there's no signals on here other
than this is the power supply and this
happens to be the 1.8 volt supply for
the CPL d and so the 3.3 comes in on one
of the layers but you have to break up
the layer so these two colors are where
I jump from layer to layer so I don't
you know construed you know constrictor
you pass from getting through and also
to keep the impedance down multiple
exits but when you have a loop like this
the noise can't hit the end of the line
and bounce back and and the impedance
doesn't go up suddenly at the end and
stuff like that so this is just kind of
like the only rule when you deal with
these kind out the only rule but this is
a major rule to when you're dealing with
these parts is to get them a good supply
so let's move on from here and let's see
if we can get this thing working so here
we are inside the design software called
Cortis for altaira brand of CPLDs and
what I did do is I did look up the pin
numbers and I created output pins and
I've labeled up LEDs they hooked to some
LEDs on the board I just showed you and
then we've got an input pin which is for
the clock input and what I'd like to do
is make a counter that counts the 50
megahertz oh it's you know kind of a
high speed therefore if trying to view
with your the human eye so we're going
to divide that down to some LEDs and
should be able to see the LED blinking
at some point if we slow it down enough
so the first thing I need to do is in
the in almost all the PGA's in PLD
architectures there's a global clock a
clock that runs to every flip-flop in
the place to where all you have to do is
set a bit to turn it on and this tries
to eliminate the skew of the clocks
across the chip if you took the output
of things and ran it to the input of
clocks you'd get a big mess so they
always tell you don't don't make the
input of a clock be due to a
combinational logic it should be this
global clock so let's make this a global
clock so I'm going into altaira
primitives buffer let's try there global
here I've opened the assignment editor
for the whole part this is cool because
I can see the shape of the part in case
you forgot well where my pins are
located and there's a concept here that
says that these are in IO banks
input/output banks and actually the
banks are programmable as a bank as to I
can set one to be three volt 3.3 volts
and everyone to be 2.5 so I've got a
clock going in here and I'm using some
some output pins right up here and so
down below what I did was I I named the
the pen out 138 because I knew I knew I
wanted on pin 138 the PC boards done
then when I went in and picked the
actual pin number for the part I made
138 equal to 138 so that's just my way
of saying hey I've pre assigned a pin
but but they better hook together when
you're done and then we also have some
other things you can see the different
voltages that we can do here and Lavoie
is TTL a voltage CMOS I don't see any
low voltage differential there and then
we also can set some of the output
current drive now this is a simple
device trust me this list would be a way
is a lot longer in a more modern FPGA so
we're all done with the assignments
which takes us back to the top alright
and so next we need our counter so what
I'm going to do is we're going to come
over here and I'm going to do a file new
ver log HDL file
and bear with me while I type this so
I'm not putting resets or any of those
things that you're always always
supposed to have in there I'm just as
just bare-bones for a demonstration here
and yes I type much slower since I lost
my finger all right so we're going to
save the bear log file we just did in
fact I'll just do a save all and now I'm
going to here's the file and now we're
going to just right-click on it and
create a simple file and it's going to
fire up the compiler real quick so let's
let's install that symbol that we just
made
yes it's the encounter all right
see if we can do a little bump and run
here oh yeah I love it all right
I'll save all and we are going to set
the parameter so there was one value I
didn't describe it but I embedded the
ability to program the width of the
counter so the counter is now 63
flip-flops wide so to speak and I just I
I always try and use buses and try and
use these span values like this whenever
I can include an in real deep in d8 DSP
type stuff so let's uh see if this works
excellent the compilation is done glad I
didn't have to do that by hand and let's
throw it over to the workstation on the
bench and download it see if it works
here's the programming part of the
quartz software so the first challenge
is always getting the USB blaster to to
be seen especially in the x64 world and
maybe I'll blog about the specifics of
that there excellent so we go ahead add
that as the hardware and this is the
part if you design these boards that you
always cross your fingers for and when
it sees your device it's a it's a woohoo
moment so woohoo all right let's
associate this with a file that we want
to program it output files keep up with
me
and you don't wear your glasses one time
okay here the download finished and
immediately the LED started blinking
which is what all this has been about
all this programming just a make some
LEDs blink in this case you can see that
it is embedded in the flash a comparison
without having to reload that reloaded
from the programmer so let's review a
little bit we started with the part
shown here which is a CP LD device from
L Tara this is a 570 device again 144
pin flash based and inside of it R is an
array of logic blocks so here's here's
what a typical logic block looks like
these are reconfigurable they have
things like adder mode and stuff but
pretty much it's it's what you see here
there's some luck up tables and there's
clock selectors and that kind of thing
and it's it's basically the
jack-of-all-trades block for this device
and what we what the compiler does is
take your code and figure out the best
way to use these blocks to accomplish
what you told it to do so in this case
it's this fair log file as we see here
and this is extremely simple that's why
actually I wanted to type it it right in
front of you was this is and nothing
more than at the positive edge of the
clock take whatever is in the value and
add one to it so you heard me say I
didn't do resets or anything like that
well in real life we would we want it to
start from a known position in real life
but we also wanted to start from a known
position so we can simulate it I also
pushed down the width of it you see
prama equals seven here seven just
happens to be a default from the top
sheet I told it 63 which means 64 bits
and that means I can call this counter
over and over again using different
widths just by specifying different
widths on the top sheet and that that
makes sense because that's where I'm
going to see the bus with so I can look
and say ah there's a bus of 64 lined up
with a counter of
sixty-four so this wasn't meant to be an
end-all be-all of CPLDs of course I just
wanted to go through each of the steps
once because I'm convinced that you two
can program a CP LD the software is free
and really at this point the the hard
part's getting the find and aboard
that's that's just a simple CP LD board
so I'm going to be on the lookout of
some of those for you alright that
brings us to the end of programming a CP
LD that went by kind of quick but that
was the point we did one of everything
all the way through and and the point is
you can do this if you haven't done a
programmable logic before so who knows
in a year from now maybe we'll be making
our own arithmetic logic units or if we
can get into the DSP stuff that'd be
really cool or some cool things you can
do so meanwhile bill heard from hackaday
and if you have a mind to keep hacking