bill heard from hackaday today we're
talking about high speed design okay
what do I mean by high speed design well
in part it depends on what you're used
to and in part it's about when the rules
change we talked about conductivity as
electron flow in fact we had it all
wrong right will you show it picture
coming out of the plus side of the
battery and lighting the light bulb and
that is all about electron flow that's
about current but when we get to high
speeds and that's a funny definition too
because I don't just mean the
fundamental clock that's in your design
I mean the edges of those clock which
have a much higher high frequency
content than that fundamental frequency
and we'll talk about that so I've got
all my test equipment and I got the good
stuff fired up today I've got frequency
domain stuff such as my spectrum
analyzer and my vector network analyzer
and I've got a really accurate kind of
old but really accurate time domain
reflectometer and I can see picoseconds
with it a fraction of a nanosecond right
and doing that I can actually look at
what's going on on the height on the PC
board itself
and I've made PC boards to test it with
so let's get started
okay before we get started here I want
to make a comment about rules of thumb
Engineering's full of rules of thumb and
they do help when you're trying to you
know have twenty variables in your head
and you're you know you're trying to
start to plot that path through your
design goals in considerations but my
first rule of thumb is be cautious of
rules of thumb all right and we're
finding out more and more as our
equipment gets better that some of these
aren't based in fact and also medicine -
there's some things over there but rule
number one or a rule of thumb number one
for me is at high speed it's about the
e/m field the electromagnetic field not
electrons all right it's kind of like
the photon wave thing are you
is that particle or is it wave well I
solved for both so when I look at
something I look at it as if they are
electrons and I look at is if it is an
e/m field and we're going to talk about
the Yuma field consequently if it's not
about the electrons in the conductor but
this field that goes around the
conductor then I'll tell you that the
signal energy you know especially a
multi-layer PC board is in the
dielectric what the insulation yes
that's where the energy is all right
electrons aren't energy yes there's a
rest you masculine but the energy you
know this is Maxwell's world right it
flows that damn near the speed of light
given some loss and some drag and some
other factors and these fields surround
the conductors and the intersect inside
the inside layers of a board and then
you have to design knowing that okay so
the third thing you're gonna like this
one is square corners might not matter
hardly at all that's a speed you're
using and I'll go into that a little bit
now I made an experiment to show you in
addition to the math so I hear a lot of
times it's like I've seen people it's
like they know one rule and it's like
don't use square corners if you if
that's the only rule you know you can
use square corners because it means
you're not dealing with the other 29
things so here's an Irwin for you on a
regular on a standard PC board the
impedance and we're going to talk about
impedance the impedance changes based on
the direction it flows on the board do
the glass weave having a directional
component to it I'll show you that I'll
show it I got the equipment here is an
edge on of a multi-layer board in this
case I've shown to ground plane and then
there is a conductor in the middle and
it's surrounded by dielectric so this is
actually a three layer board in other
words ground signal ground what you see
is first off around the conductor is the
magnetic field in a way to recognize
magnetic field as it tries to form a
circle whereas the
electric field the e of e/m couples to
the return path as well as the conductor
so tries to include the return path so
this becomes one animal from here to
here here it is the energy is in the
dielectric by the way what's the
difference here's a Rick Hartley for you
what's the difference between light and
electricity frequency all right now this
is important and this goes back to the
last video I did about inductance and
the bigger the loop the higher the
inductance at high frequencies and this
is all again if this is iam field
creates this phenomenon it takes the
path of least impedance not the path of
least resistance okay
no impedance has some resistance in it
yes but if if here is the source of the
voltage current gosh I keep saying
voltage source of the current by the way
Maxwell's equations don't actually talk
about Moldy john told you actually have
to derive that from it because it's all
about energy if this was a light bulb
and this was a battery the signal the
the signal would flow to the light bulb
and then come back diagonally right just
low frequency kind of electrons but at
high frequency it as it propagates down
to here and it's going to do it at the
Bossa T factor of the PC board so we're
talking huge fractions of the speed of
light right iam field bang bang it
follows the single path in the return
path so the blue is the ground playing
this fringy color is the current density
on the ground plane or representing the
the return cart and the purple is the
signal path itself on a signal layer
here's a diagram of the inside of a PC
board this is the glass weave that gets
a coat coated with epoxy as part of the
lamination putting these layers together
and the orange traces represe
traces on the PC board and if underneath
this was a ground plane or VCC pain
plane something of low impedance you can
see that the dielectric the insulate of
value for glass is different than the
value for just epoxy with no glass so if
the trace comes down the middle here
it's going to have a different impedance
than this way consequently a trace that
does go horizontally is going to have a
different impedance than a trace that
goes vertically and and there's
different weaves and they're becoming
more and more well-documented and the
answer to this is we need to have the
glass we've spread I have it rolled out
spread out so that the gaps are very
minor and of course this is a trade off
between again the adhesive of the epoxy
and the glass weave itself so guess what
you end up paying for this stuff as you
go further and further into the
high-speed design room ramifications but
I wanted to show you this because this
aren't did an experiment to see if I
could with my test equipment see if
there is a difference between going
horizontal vertical or at a 45 degree
angle all right here's a PC board and
actually I've got several of these that
I shot on to test this in this I used
PCB way and I've got their dimensions on
here in both metric and English that are
used to calculate the proper width to
get the proper impedance knowing that
this is not an impedance control board
I wanted results I could show you so I
used a regular old board not impedance
control PCB way was nice and sent me one
that was impedance controlled where I
could solder an SMA connector to it and
see the effect of a true controlled one
but I like this one because I've got a
horizontal look trace I've got a
vertical trace on the bottom you can't
see here and and if I were doing this
for real I'd have this in a stand that
gets you know so went laying flat it
doesn't pick up something so I've got
diagonal horizontal and vertical and
then I've got a trace with
is in it and then I've got a trace with
a whole bunch of right angles I don't
know if you can see it here but this
trace actually twice as long as the
others because there's some twenty or
thirty right angles no no radius to them
at all and we're going to test to see if
I can get that glare off for you a
problem with shiny black things we're
going to see about the right angles
before we're done worried about TDRs
time-domain reflectometer you know
they're used for cables right and and
we're measuring feet meters right
distances like that a slow-moving pulse
I can actually use the the frequency
generator built in my scope and a little
T coupling to create the pulse that goes
down and races back and get pretty
reasonable a resolution at PC board
speeds which is six inches per
nanosecond I need a really fast rise
time where it's still going to be going
up by the time the signals banged off
the end and come back it all gets muddy
right so this actually started out as a
video about making high-speed pulses I
I've got a whole folder here of step
recovery diodes of Avalanche transistors
in avalanche mode Jenny list did a
mercury wetted high-speed step pulse and
Alan woke on his channel shows you how
to make one with transistors so and I'm
just going to do that till I came across
let's get it here this little guy for
about sixty dollars this has 32
picosecond that's point zero zero zero
zero zero zero zero zero zero zero three
two seconds or if you're a nanosecond
sky like I am its 0.03 to of a
nanosecond and he did with laser drivers
which you know I got a believer are more
repeatable than avalanche mode of a
transistor so Leo Bart Bodnar comm is
where I got it for like 50 bucks I'm
never making a pulse generator again he
does
this is a CSA 8:03 I got off eBay this
is a communication signal analyzer and
what it is whereas an oscilloscope has
higher higher sampling rate than its
bandwidth this has lower sampling rate
than its bandwidth but it does multiple
traces there's no one trace that could
do 20 gigahertz this has a 20 gigahertz
bandwidth whoo nice eBay fine right so
in the pulse rate coming out of here
it's like some like 12 nano second 29 I
forgot to look it up but it's lots of
zeros and this little and so what that
speed of pulse does means I can see
individual features on a PC board let me
zoom in and we'll take a look here I'm
at half a nanosecond per division right
here is the 50 Cal fifty-caliber she's
been out of the army deal on 50 ohm of
the cable all right there's the the the
problem with the connector you notice
connectors aren't perfect and you'll see
that our impedance is just a little
higher than the cable but it's kind of
close so let's take a look at a vertical
direction and see what the impedance we
get from that here I've moved the cable
in the Terminator to a vertical
direction and and actually you can see
the backside of it the the the graddic
oh that's a graticule that's not lit up
real bright but this line is right on it
that's the 50 Cal of the cable and you
see our impedance actually is higher in
the vertical direction than it was the
horizontal direction so now the way
around this that if you want to if you
use standard boards I'm trying not to
call them cheap if you want to use
standard boards you can the board
to the side inside a bigger board so
that there are no angles running exactly
horizontal and exactly vertical they're
run and I think something like 11
degrees or 16 degrees or something gets
you enough mix a horizontal horizontal
and vertical we've components that
you get a better control of the
impedance here's this red impedance
control board you can see my SMA
connector there on the side and you see
we do have a much smoother experience if
you want to call it that now with that
said I can't put a termination on this
so it's not quite an apples apples
comparison but it is you know looking at
it from just one part is also doable and
in this case it looks like an impedance
control board to me now I've hooked to
the trace that has a bunch of vias on it
now I cheated I didn't these are the
worst case we as they are in tenez
they're acting like stubs there are
nasty little things and look what it did
by the way we fix that with things like
back drilling and stuff like that we'll
talk about that later if we do a true PC
board turnout here at two hundred
picoseconds per division can your scope
do this look look at what's going on
here right and what's great about this
is I can actually keep dialing in to see
the effect but look how much it came
down off of off of the 50 ohm so so vias
can have an effect in real life they
wouldn't be quite this bad because you
would do them better I just threw a
bunch of vias on there wondering if I'd
even see something that would show up
you know for a video for hack a day yes
they do so let's take a look at right
angles I know I'm dying to take over it
take a glance here's the board with a
whole bunch of right angles again no no
fill adeno no no radius you know
anything yes you can spot it there
that's them right there boy if this
matters a lot to you you're a better
engineer than me okay now in real life
this is not much you pick up other
artifacts and I'm going to show you a
formula because this this isn't you
can't say they're never important but
it's a ratio of the width to the
frequency that eric boe Girton
describe better than I can so I'm going
to show you that about when you do need
to worry about right angles and the
answer is yes yeah of couple gig and and
up yeah you do
but at frequencies especially our dwee
noise frequencies that they're there
nothing so go start a fight with
somebody over this one let me know how
it goes
so the whole argument about square
corridors had a couple of origins in in
the old days of RF at high high voltages
you would clip the little any any sharp
piece sticking out of the solder blob
because you'd get a Corona there
well I'm voltage does need to not have
corners yes but not at 5 volts three
volts or 1.8 bolt so the whole argument
came down to this represents this
triangle represents an additional width
so it comes along at one width it jumps
to a slightly greater width and then it
becomes a skinny width again and that
change in width is a greater capacitance
and so a change in impedance and yes all
of that's true
so two things one at six inches per
nanosecond this corner is going to go by
in a Pico second or you know some small
number so just the sheer speed of this
wave propagating down here and turning
you know it's just Dwarfs you that
little bump in the road and if you get a
PCB manufacturer it says Oh acid
collects in this corner get a different
PCB manufacturer I don't know that that
was ever true I think that came from
somewhere else like chip design or
something like that
so but Eric's done the math for us and
basically he's saying that in in mils
it's 1.6 femto farad's that's even
smaller in a Pico farad or a Pico farad
1.6 Pico farad 20 mils is 0.02 o of that
and you so it's very small capacitance
and he gave us a roll thumb Eric's known
for DES
finding rules of thumb I think he's got
one says watch out for rules of thumb
also but he says if you rise times less
than 10 picoseconds and you're doing 50
ohm you only have to worry about this if
you're trace is wider than 50 mils well
what for me to get 50 ohm on most of
boards I use you know I'm down five six
four seven mils I'm nowhere near 50 ohms
so I'll never come across this in what I
design I don't think so here's the
here's the whole argument about the
corner with math and this is from an edn
magazine where Eric posted one of his
rules of thumb so I didn't have
equipment like this back in the 80s it
existed I didn't have it when I worked
for Commodore hey we were only like one
of the top three computer manufacturers
here's a board I did that has a wire on
all of six million units 5.7 million and
it's because I got a real bad I'm gonna
stick a TDR on this I'm gonna pop the
wire off and see the difference maybe
make that a chaser video or something
where I just delay out sucked so bad
that I had to provide another pass so it
wouldn't reflect and do a reinforcement
cancellation thing I think waves write
on the board and my best fix was to add
a wire if we try to move the trace on
the board I might just move the problem
and I only had a couple months to do
this anyways so if I'd had this tool
back here I could have said aha
and still might have had the wire right
so I got to stop there man we're like
into twenty five minutes already in
these videos they're supposed to be ten
minutes long and I barely scratched the
surface of high-speed design stuff but
hopefully you start to see you know as
we go up in in rise times and we can we
can look under the covers and see the
impedance and start to care about what
the board is made out of and right
angles don't have the effect we thought
they did right when we were younger so
bill heard from hackaday I really hope
to make a second one of these where I
crack out my vector analyzer and
the the s-domain the the imaginary
domain of frequency and whatnot and I
even have my spectrum analyzer I'm gonna
go back to those corners to see if
they're spraying that's the other thing
they say is they emit emi which can hurt
you in ffcc not at these frequencies so
don't heard from hackaday i'll see you
on the next one
[Music]
[Applause]
you