they'll hurt from hackaday today I'm
playing with a universal active filter
it's a pretty cool little thing it's
Universal as I said but this one's
programmable or controllable I should
say now I like that because it's a lot
easier to talk about the subject when
I'm not chasing all kinds of issues
around with the complexities of a filter
but first let's talk a little bit about
what a filter is and what it does a
filter is a way to select information
that we want or in this case a select
audio that we want it also rejects as
part of that but we tend to think in the
positive of what it accepts so in this
case I've shown a 3-way speaker like we
used to have in the old days and here
there's a woofer a mid-range and a high
ion and a tweeter in the speakers and
when audio comes in to what we call the
crossover its job is to send the low
frequencies down here to move this big
cone of air and get the power in there
but if you sent that same low frequency
up to the tweeter you'd probably blow it
out
so the crossover sends the lows down
here but then it sends the highs up to
the tweeter and and gets you nice
clarity in there but if it sends those
same highs to here and here it would
muddy the sound so the little highs go
to the tweeter the lows to the woofer
and then what's left in the middle you
know it's the mid-range and goes to the
mid-range driver well this is what it
would look like on a graph here if this
is low frequencies remember 20 to 20 K
they used to say in the old days the as
the frequencies are coming up in
frequencies and this is going to the
tweeter finally the high frequencies
start to come through and this is called
a high-pass when we do this and that's
this thing here the low-pass is where it
starts out or we're very close to starts
out it might do something like that
sending the low frequencies down to the
woofer but then it tapers off and and up
at the high range it's not passing him
by the way we call this a bandpass and a
band stop as a way to think of this and
then finally this is what we call a
bandpass filter where the lows don't get
through the highs don't get through but
the middles get through and so there's a
band associated with this
that this is allowed to pass a a band
stop or band reject would look like this
and we're not doing one of those today
but since we're talking the words that's
what it looks like let's start real
simple here with filter components what
makes up a component and here I've shown
just a simple low-pass with two
components and a simple high pass filter
with two components low-pass think of
this capacitor at like a battery it
stores voltage it resists a change in
voltage so if this were a battery and
you would like to connect it to a charge
of disconnect it connected it smooth
that out it'd be kind of like well I'm
still 12 volts and you're right across
me so I'm 12 volts even if the input is
just changed to 11 volts so low-pass
filter this resistor the the response to
this is a very linear to 2 pi RC 1 over
2 pi RC for this and so you make this
component bigger and it'll slow down you
make this component smaller and it'll
speed up make this component bigger and
it'll slow down make this come on so you
see there's a very linear relationship
high-pass filter there is no direct DC
path through this if there's a sudden
change on this end the change will go
away it'll see it for a second
whatever can get across this bridge but
then it'll come back to normal so only
those events those high frequency events
get through now the way I had to look
finally learn to think of a capacitor
was I was probably in fourth grade and I
had seen pictures and they'd show their
little electrons on one end I'm like
what but then I realized it's kind of
like pressure it's like when when the
signal hits it pushes a certain amount
across so it goes like that and then
comes back to its to its default and
once I start understanding that that the
more that this the the better the
capacitor was for conduction in other
words the lower the capacitor more and
more of these electrons could get bit
through but then they'd still at the end
the day come back to where they started
and so only high frequencies can get
through here a way to think about it to
tell the difference real quick is
low-pass is closest to DC as it gets 1
hertz 1/2 hertz well what's the next
thing well it's DC right there is no DC
path through here
there's a very filtered DC path right
here loves DC right so not to
oversimplify oh by the way we call this
this called a simple pole I call it a
real pole filter meaning that there's
nothing that is going there's nothing
unusual going to happen there is no gain
involved you will never get a voltage
out of this higher than what you put in
etc so the the down the downside of it
is it's simple but it's just got a real
rich gradual roll-off compared to what
we can get out of some other filters and
I'm going to show you those before we
leave you we'll talk about Chevy chefs
and vessel filters and those kind of
things where you can get really
outrageous responses but you do it with
a lot of trade-offs so sloppy Oh RC
filters but hey they came first the part
I'm playing with today is a UAF 42
universal active filter 42 you can see
it here on the screen
it's an old part I just pulled it
because it's got an unusual property not
unusual it's got a cool property that
we're going to play with today and that
property is it keeps us from doing math
which excites me so here you can see the
the chip itself at the bottom we've got
op amps and op amp is gain and gain is
needed when you get funky with filters
otherwise it's gonna be that passive
slopey roll-off I showed you I don't
know if you can see this but here is
some of the math you'll see that it uses
the the the frequency domain known as s
and the this math is not trivial unless
you know how to do it here's a close-up
on an excerpt from that and from the
spec sheet and now the S domain has been
broken into regular math force but I
still I want to just have fun I don't I
don't want to have to do all this you
know all this math I just want to show
you what an active filter can do and how
to play with one so let's go back to the
workbench I'm going to show you how I
used this part in what was unusual about
it that allowed me to just get right
into playing with all right we're on the
bench here with the schematic of the UAF
42 and it's pretty much a self-contained
active filter
and by self-contained I mean it's got
some resistors and some capacitors in
built into it along with these op amps
and both the capacitors and resistors
have been have been trimmed by laser and
if you if you were to look closely at
the math that I showed you that we
didn't do you'll find that you can't
guess at these values when you go to
make a filter and these are nice round
values here but if the tolerance was off
by 10% on these you can get some very
strange effects whereas with an RC
filter you know the resistor gets
smaller it gets faster the capacitor
gets bigger it gets slower not in a
active active filter so it's got the
high-pass output here a low-pass output
here and you see I've drawn the symbol
for both and a band pass output here and
all's they are as taps in various places
on these three op amps as they talk to
each other and I'll show you that if you
think about the signal going through
this as as change in time a change in
phase the this op amps listening to the
future this one's listening to the past
thing you know that's the way I see
these things but really they're
interacting very carefully to produce
these these these outputs these bandpass
what makes this part usable here today
is that there are two external resistors
and when looking through the math you
see I found that if they're equal then I
can treat I can trim this thing's
frequency by only changing those two
resistors they do want to be equal or
again you get into a different area so
what I've done is I've got a dual gang
pot that I got from like digi-key and
I've made these resistors track each
other so here's the board here's our
dual gang pot and it's coupled into the
in place of these two resistors right
here and let's see what happens when we
put it on the scope so I'm going to show
you a piece of test equipment here that
we're going to use to
display the the effects of our filter
and this is just my old HP function
generator and it can do sine waves
square waves that kind of thing but what
I'm using it for today is what's called
a sweet frequency generator in other
words I'm going to sweep a frequency
starting from 60 I'm sorry starting from
80 Hertz and I'm going to go up to 5
kilohertz and then there's other things
like the amplitude you know I'm going to
set this for about half a volt of input
and that's going to give us the ability
to inject a variety or a sweep of
frequencies where we know the starting
and ending point and then we're going to
look at how the filter reacts so again
this is my sweet function on my function
generator i frozen a sweep here where
you can see it start and end this will
be moving around later a little bit look
a little noisier if i wanted you to get
intuitively what's going on and that is
here's the oscillator starting slow and
that's going faster and faster as this
goes and eventually as it goes all the
way across the screen it'll be going
that's its fastest so later you won't
see this as much you'll see just a
couple bumps of the slow part and it'll
look like a big smear but that's what
we're doing is we're starting an
oscillator at the low frequency and
telling it to go up to a high frequency
so here's our board with a probe
attached to view the high-pass output
and you can see as I turn the knob that
the high-pass part which is which is
here
is moving up and down up to the top of
the range so set here only high
frequencies are getting through out of
the sweep remember the sweep starts at
low frequency and goes up to a high
frequency alright on our bench here
we've got all the probes plugged in and
on the oscilloscope here I've got all
the channels firing and I've put it in
two dots mode just to help with the
display so some of this is a little
mushy but you'll see what I'm talking
about here on the left is where our low
frequency starts if you remember and
here in the blue this is the high-pass
filter because it starts not passing
much and then balloons up and then from
then on it is passing high pass this big
ol peak here is an artifact of the way
this circuit is operating right now and
a lot of times we call it a ripple or
just a non-linearity as far as I'm
concerned at the moment the middle one
is our bandpass you see that it's not
perfect it's got some residual amplitude
not near as much as the high and then
the the low pass you'll see on the
left-hand side it's pulling and slow
pass before it ripples out and then if I
try and move it so you'll see I'm moving
it down towards the low pass not much
low pass going on a lot of high pass or
I'm going to the right which is higher
in frequency and now I've got a lot of
low pass and I'm shortening up the the
high pass and meanwhile I'm moving
around in the middle is the bandpass so
we've got three different functions
coming out of out of this filter at the
same time so I'm going to stop there for
part one
let come on back for part two we're
going to stick some static signals and
let's stick to square wave in and see if
we can make a sine wave and let's pump
some music to it actually have a do the
crossover thing like we showed and to my
left you see the slow sweep frequency
will actually throw that on the speaker
see if we can hear what some of the sine
wave stuff does what it sounds like in
the harmonics so bill heard from
hackaday i'll tell you to keep on
hacking but I'm going to tell you to
come on back for part two actually