so next up I have kind of an S for
tradition I have a prepared speech to
read from from someone that's well-known
in the community so every year at s4 we
look to the future of control system
security while learning from our pasts
hot issues come and go discussions and
arguments are made for ones position
research is shared but it's the people
that are most important to the continued
success of the community this year we'd
like to recognize one person in the
community not only for their
contributions in 2016 but for their
potential in 2017 please sir the SCADA
diva hard hat is awarded as a reminder
to the recipient to stay grounded in
their craft not to be swayed by popular
opinion to not degrade into marketing
speak to resist the urge to upload new
malware used to hack electrical grids to
virustotal
to further advances in ICS pew-pew cyber
maps to not publish attack white papers
publicly without White House approval
and to be open to others thoughts and
opinions in recognition of this person's
passion for ICS security and to their
future success
the skated evo 2017 award goes to
michael Asante of neck sands defense
Michael is unfortunately in Salt Lake
City right now so we will have to mail
him his hard hat but we hope that he
wears it with pride throughout 2017