[Music]
welcome John and Chris to the s4 main
stage good afternoon everybody I'm John
Chris and we are here to to talk to you
about a methodology called cyber pH a
that has been used quite successfully to
help companies assess the cyber risk to
their industrial control systems
it's based on some a lot of work from
the from the ISA standards and the NIST
standards but it's unique in many ways
and that it's it's very application
oriented process and it ties very much
into two well-established process safety
processes so very happy to be here it's
actually my first s4 though I don't know
why because I've been in this field for
about nine years and I don't know why I
haven't come to Miami in January before
it definitely will not be my last and so
we're going to talk about this this
process we've already been introduced so
we're going to skip these slides and
what we want to get across here is is
how these risk assessments can be part
of an overall cybersecurity program and
how they can tie into particularly in
industries that that have hazardous
processes how it can tie into
established process safety methodologies
and the impact of of cyber potential
impact of cyber on safety and helping
understand that how it ties into the to
the well-established standards that are
already out there and then we'll go
through I'll quickly go through the
process itself the methodology through a
quick example and then Chris will talk
about lessons learned as as he has
applied this as a significant part of
his program so again very happy to be
here kind of incidentally here by way of
Alaska because that's where Dale and I I
ran into Dale in October in Alaska we
were working at the same client and I
was facilitating one of these cyber PHAs
and endale
said you know you this is something
industry needs to know more about it
please so please come to ask for and
talk about it so that's why we're here
turn it over Chris okay thanks John
all right so as John mentioned with the
our products and chemicals and based on
all the increased risk and changing
landscape for the ICS cyber my companies
decided that they needed to have
somebody spend full time dedicated to
working on on cyber and try to protect
their plants as also mentioned my
company has a very wide footprint I have
over six hundred plants or facilities
worldwide so it's quite a challenge to
try to address all that so as part of
that on when I got assigned this role I
decided to go out and figure out okay
what are the questions that I really
need to answer to try to address the
space and make sure that I we have
success in my company and so as I
canvassed some of my stakeholders are
these are some the questions that they
ask is my plant system ICS system is it
secure from cyberattack as a system been
compromised already from management of
change perspective if I make a change to
my system will that change affect the
security of my system will it make it
less secure also from a firewall
perspective as soon as you start talking
so everybody says well just take a
firewall on it but you know what type of
firewall how many times how many
firewalls do I need for a particular
process trying to understand that you
know do I need to have you know dpi do I
need to have IDs what do we really need
from a firewall perspective in what
rules do I need to have configured in
these firewalls amazingly enough we find
a lot of firewalls or configured as
permit Indiana so having a firewall
there is just not good enough the last
two questions they'll really get at why
we need a PHA and why the PHA really
adds a lot of value from a cyber
perspective
and that is how do you know when we've
spent enough how good is good enough I
don't want to spend any more than I
really have to to secure my plants and
without a a PHA that answer is not quite
forthcoming so cyber is really all about
risk management is that's something that
a lightbulb went off in my head you know
once I really got into and understood
what what cyber is all about so in order
to address cyber you know one must
really understand
um risk because again Simon's about risk
management so the first things you need
to do when you're trying to assess your
risk is understand what it is you're
trying to protect okay so first thing to
do is to go out there and really
identify what your critical assets are
you know what is it you're trying to
protect inventory those assets then and
then maybe you might want to classify
these assets in terms of possibly you
know what what's the consequence of one
failing then you really need to
understand what are the realistic
threats your whole design will be based
on what you consider to be a realistic
spread and also you might want to
understand also what the probability our
likelihood of that threat being realized
is and what the consequences may be
identifying existing vulnerabilities and
the consequence of a compromise is is
really important um are we talking about
just lots of visibility are we talking
about lots of control of our of our
systems and our assets are we talking
about potentially equipment damage
product interruption or even injury or
possibly fatalities so it's really
important to understand what the
consequences are compromises once you've
done it really need to assess are your
current safeguards appropriate for the
risk that you have once that is
understood it then leads you to
understand what your residual risk is
so after this risk assessment and you
understand what your gaps are what your
residual risk in your process is then
you can begin to understand what is a
comprehensive plan start develop that
comprehensive plan to address cyber risk
at your companies and that could include
in addition to the existing
countermeasures what additional measures
are required from that that could also
that's not just the technology that may
also include modifications to your
existing work processes your policies
and procedures and then the final two
points are and this is will really help
you when you start to put together your
plan because we all have limited
resources and you really want to expend
your resources where it's really going
to make the most difference so coming up
a PHA you might have you know five
hundred recommendations I can't do all
of them so you got to figure out which
where is going to be the most important
one so prioritizing those
recommendations and then evaluating them
for cost versus complexities it's a
really important step and final four I
turn over to John just want to mention
her risk assessments are really
important but really there are only one
component of a comprehensive
cybersecurity planning program and so
again you know John's gonna talk more
about that but recognize that if you
don't have a comprehensive program
you're probably not going to have a
whole lot of success so what I want to
talk about now is the actual to cyber
PHA process but in order to do that I
want to take a little bit of a step back
and talk about a little bit about the
origins of the process and how it ties
in with existing standards and best
practices so everybody here I'm sure is
very familiar with the NIST
cybersecurity framework and and the the
identify function which has under that a
sub category a category of risk
assessment but I think if you ask ten
people what a risk assessment is
particularly in a for a control system
you probably get 10 different answers
because there's not a lot of stay
in the area of how to perform these
assessments what the NIST framework does
as any good framework should is it
establishes some baselines some base
requirements or recommendations and
those tie in this slide directly then to
or a reference different existing
industry standards the ones that I have
highlighted are the is a 99 or 64 for
three references because that's relevant
to ICS there are other ones as I'm sure
you're aware that the standard that the
framework references that are generally
more IT centric risk assessment
methodologies so there's a lot of
different ways to perform a risk
assessment so I'm going to focus of
course on this cyber PHA methodology and
how it ties particularly ties to the is
a six to four for three series of
standards so if you look at those
references from from NIST more directly
it ties to the two - these requirements
in the two - one standard which
basically says pick a risk assessment
methodology conduct a high-level risk
assessment identify your control systems
make sure you understand them have
network diagrams prioritize them then
perform detailed vulnerability and risk
assessments and then figure out how
often you're going to do those and
document the results of course but it
does not talk about is how to perform
the risk assessment that's still yet to
come but I'll talk about that in a
moment where is a is going with the with
in terms of helping users with the
actual methodology but PHA the term that
Chris and I have thrown out a couple
times now it stands for process hazard
analysis and the reason this this
process or this methodology has been
given that name is because PHAs are very
well established risk management
methodology in the continuous process
industries particularly in oil and gas
and chemical and other hazardous
industries with hazardous processes so
this is a cybersecurity conference so
just make sure everybody is aware of
process safety it's basically the
prevention
of bad things happening in industrial
facilities like fires explosions
releases of chemicals or gases and so on
they could impact particularly they
could impact health and safety the most
process safety programs also extend to
looking at financial and other impacts
to the organization and one of the key
premises of process safety is this
concept of layers of protection that you
want to have multiple more the higher
the risk or the higher the consequences
the more layers of protection you need
to prevent an incident or if there is an
incident to contain it to mitigate it so
this is a fairly common diagram that you
see in discussions about process safety
explaining this idea of layers of
protection and in modern systems we have
control systems and safety systems and
other layers of protection to prevent
incidents and then the PHA process it's
been around for decades it's a very
organized systematic approach to
identifying these process hazards and
understanding the the risk associated
with them how likely are they to occur
how bad would they be if they happen the
basic the basic formula for risk which
is likelihood times consequence been
used for decades and the focus is on the
equipment implementation the utilities
human actions other external factors and
for many industries is this is regulated
if if you fall under OSHA PSM or a EPA's
RMP program or some of the offshore and
pipeline sectors are required to do some
level of process hazard analysis or
process safety management or process
safety or pipeline safety management
program so it's been around for a long
time well accepted by up by operations
groups as part of an ongoing risk
management and safety program there's
two basic types of studies that are done
has ops and Lopez as UPS identify the
hazards and it is the quantitative
methodology layer protection analysis is
more quantitative but both of them are
answering the questions what are the
potential hazards and are there
sufficient layers of protection - - to
manage that risk - tolerable levels very
similar for those of us in cybersecurity
when we talk about defense and depth
layers of protection is the very same
similar concept another another key
factor in any Process Safety Program is
usually something called a risk matrix
which is the organization's definition
for what is tolerable risk and it talks
about things like health safety
environmental company image for example
and on one scale the consequences and
then the likelihood on the other scale
and if you'll notice this is an example
but this typical of what you find in a
risk matrix is that there are orders of
magnitude so this is not a precise
science what we are trying to understand
here is relative risk and whether that
risk is within the company's tolerable
guidelines or not in other words what
things must accompany respond to
so a typical hazop might look like this
they typically as up worksheet might
look like this and when we do a has up
we break the process down into units and
nodes and we walk through with
operations and engineering and other
folks to talk about what are the
potential hazards what could go wrong
what are the deviations how could that
happen what are the causes most
importantly what are the consequences
and how bad could they be and they get
scored according to that risk matrix and
that gives us our our initial risk and
then we look at its okay so what
safeguards do we have in place to
prevent that what layers of protection
do we have to prevent that and so what
is our what is our our mitigated risk
and then oftentimes these are followed
up particularly for for particularly
hazardous threat scenarios we we do a
deeper dive in safety called the lopa
layer protection analysis to look more
deeply at art what are those layers of
protection are they truly independent
and how good are they unfortunately one
of the drawbacks this is a very mature
established process but one of the
drawbacks is it does not take into
account it was never designed to take
into account
deliberate actions and and so cyber
events for example or even really take
into account the likelihood or the
probability of a control system not
doing what it's supposed to do it kind
of assumed that it's going to perform
its function that the alarm is going to
go off that the safety system is going
to take action so one of the challenges
we face particularly now with modern
control systems is that they're
intelligent programmable and and they
are integrated and it's possible that a
single vulnerability could disable
multiple layers of protection so we have
to study that because there's a lot of
other factors involved that could and
other safeguards in place that can
protect the system non-programmable non
cyber so these studies unfortunately it
has up in lopa studies don't take that
into account but if we extend the
process through what we call the cyber
PHA we can take into account the cyber
risk and and see if that then is is
tolerable or and address things that are
not so to help visualize that going back
to my earlier diagram we've got the
basic control system and we got the
safety system but in reality today those
are oftentimes networked together and
common HMIS common engineering
workstations common networks so it's
possible that a single threat actor
could potentially attack both the
control and the safety system and either
initiating an event or prevent a safety
action from from from bringing the
process to a safe state the safety
standards have also recognized this
there's there's a lot of standards and
safeties ice I see six and five eleven
is the predominant one for functional
safety and the latest version of that
does recognize now that a security risk
assessment needs to be carried out
because safety assessments are limited
to looking at usually at random failures
or systematic failures but not cyber and
not deliberate so the design of the
safety systems now need to provide
resilience against cyber threats as well
and then it points to guidance from two
different sources tra t for a tech
report from the SAT for committee and 6
2 4 4 3 3 2 so 3-2 is a is a standard
under development but pretty close to
being is going out for 4 ballot it talks
about the process of how to finally
answering the question how does one
perform a an industrial control system
cybersecurity risk assessment and it
presents presents a framework for doing
that
it tries not to be too prescriptive but
provides a framework for how one might
perform such an assessment so I want to
quickly walk through an example for you
so you can see rather than go through
that flowchart the basic idea is very
much like a PHA and PHA we start out
with pn ids as our drawings and we break
the process into units and nodes and we
walk through systematically
we do the same thing in a cyber peach
except our dot our drawings are the
network architecture drawings so we
start with a system architecture of the
control system all the way from level 0
up to level 4 and we break it down into
units sites units and zones and nodes
and we can walk through the system very
systematically and look at what are the
different threats so this this worksheet
is a pH cyber pH a worksheet you not
surprisingly it looks an awful lot like
a has up and it's based on that
methodology that's been as I said very
well accepted in operations as a way to
systematically walk through the system
but in this case our zones our control
system zones are our nodes our control
system components and our deviations are
our threats are different instead of for
example a valve malfunctioning our
deviations are a control system fails to
perform it's it's expected function for
example so I give a simple example here
but the idea is we walk through and we
identify that what could go wrong which
are the the the deviation what are the
causes
these are the threat actions what are
the consequences which need to be
used the same language as you would use
in any other risk assessment what's
what's the impact to the organization if
this happens and we quantify that using
the same risk matrix so that we're so
we're comparing apples to apples in
terms of risk we're not trying to use a
different scale for cyber risk risk is
risk particularly to management it's all
about health safety financial and other
impacts to the organization and then we
identify what's the initial risk and
very much like it has up we then look at
okay what countermeasures do we already
have in place this would be our existing
layers of protection or existing defense
and depth and how good are they are they
good enough against different types of
threats and different types of attacks
and then we identify and what is the
residual risk taking into account the
existing safeguards what's the residual
risk and what can we do about it
as I said it's it's it's a very
systematic approach it really encourages
the team to come together across
disciplinary team to come together and
think about all of these different
aspects actually a lot of a lot of cross
learning takes place during these
because because it encourages discussion
about these different threat scenarios
and encourages discussions about how
realistic they are and you know if well
facilitated you can make sure that they
don't go off on down rabbit holes but
stay focused on the task of really
understanding the process and the cyber
risk and being able to answer those
questions to management about why are we
recommending this and why aren't we
recommending this because the the
without an approach like this you're you
have a couple choices you can just apply
all of the best standards and practices
and all the different technology that's
out there but nobody can afford that and
it would likely be overkill and actually
could interrupt caused more problems so
that the idea of this process is to go
through and really understand where
which vulnerabilities can lead to the
highest risks
and then you can focus on shoring up
those vulnerabilities or closing those
holes so I said it uses the same risk
matrix and then one of the outcomes
there's several outcomes one of the
outcomes usually would be a properly
zoned system with the appropriate
barriers of protection at the different
zone boundaries but that not to say that
that's the only mitigation but that is
one of one of many outcomes and turn it
back to Chris to to kind of wrap up the
session here thanks John as John said
this process really works on it is it's
a pretty intensive process but the
results coming out of there are are
normally fantastic and they give you a
real basis for really on doing your
system design actually after the fact I
have implemented a system this process
on numbers of my my plants and one
things I found long after the fact is
that as you know sometimes your project
manager or your project engineer will
come back and challenge you know why am
i spending all this money on these
particular technology and this is
actually a documented basis that we go
back to us and here's why we're doing it
and if we don't do this this is a risk
that will be left behind so it's
actually gives you a very good basis for
defending why you're spending what you
have to spend on on cyber I just want to
leave you with a couple of examples or
considerations for a cyber security
comprehensive cybersecurity program for
for ICS systems that I've had the
ability to go through first thing is
assembling a core team you need to
understand within your organization who
owns security and I'm not just talking
about at the plant we're talking about
all the systems that are connected to
your plants and all of it needs to be
protected so find out who all your
stakeholders are assembled them together
and also don't don't go it alone on you
know well as many of your organization's
feel like mine a lot of smart people
when everybody has ideas on how to how
to do things um but it's probably best
to go with somebody who has actual
experience has gone through this process
numbers of times so find a experienced
partner who has who can not only walk
you through the process will also train
you so that your team can can then work
on someone independently going forward
you want to also you know develop a
common mission vision for for that team
so that you know if your program is
going to last multiple years which it
should and to keep the team focused
around what are the important methods by
which it's going to function I you want
to start with you know as built a system
you need to understand what it is that
you have as I mentioned before that will
help you and consider a phased approach
for me because I had so many systems out
there I had to figure out how to focus
on the most important first and also
since this sour PHA is a pretty
intensive program process you might want
to consider doing a high-level
vulnerability assessment before you
actually get deeply into this PHA use
this opportunity as a training
opportunity for your teams a lot of
times you'll find that your IT teams
some of them have never been to a plant
and it's a good opportunity to to get
everybody on the same page taught the
same language and understand why we're
doing what you're doing on document your
deliverables and then also remember that
you know you can put a whole lot of
technology in a plant and you can create
all these systems but you might be back
doing it again five years or ten years
from now because the environment has
changed so think about how you're going
to maintain and sustain these systems as
you go forward I'm here a number of
deliverables deliverables like that
come out of this process won't spend any
time on them but just like to you know
point out that this is a you know a
well-documented process it's you can go
methodically through it and you may
consider these deliverables when you
start to look at trying to put together
a request code to work with a consultant
or my partner with you and finally in
conclusion from risk assessments you
know there's a lot of good information
you can get out of it as we we discussed
today you can determine you know what
plants needs to be addressed first so
you have your priorities all all decided
um you can intelligently design and
apply countermeasures to to your systems
on to reduce and manage the risks that
are are remaining it also allows you to
prioritize your activities and your
resources the most important ones first
and then you will have an understanding
of which countermeasures are going to
give you the proverbial most bang for
the buck and understand which ones will
be the the easiest to implement and what
catch the the so-called low-hanging
fruit and then finally it's establishes
a firm basis for you to make your
decisions regards your your target
architecture on we and my company we we
determine what our target target
architecture is based on a lot of this
analysis and then we will go back and we
will revisit this every couple of years
to make sure that these systems and the
architecture is still valid given the
changing conditions that are out there
that as we know the cyber world is not
one that then stay the same it's always
dynamic and you have to take into
consideration the fact that is changing
and update and keep your your defenses
updated
to protect you against it so that's all
I have thank you very much for listening
and I give