[Music]
welcome to the closing panel I'm very
pleased to have two guests with me not
only because of their experience
reputation and knowledge but because
they are the two most frequent attendees
of s4 so on the far end I have Ralph
Langner of Langner communications in the
lagna group obviously he's most famous
for his work on Stuxnet but he was
coming to ask for well before Stuxnet
and and since that time is written books
and right now is working on a project or
a product called ot base which is an OT
security program and I know a number of
you in the audience will be taking his
class on Friday about how to create an
OT security program and Ralph has been
here for all 10s 4s this is actually the
10th s4 so we appreciate his support
yeah that was the only reason why I
could correct Stuxnet you know all that
preparation that has for that helped me
develop the capability if you want to
have some fun you can watch like the S 4
2008 Langner presentation on hacking OPC
or something like that you did an OPC
server one way but whatever 2007 year
one okay and then immediately to my left
is act tutor he is currently with INL
has been there for a little less than a
year and is responsible for so many
things I can't even mention them all but
definitely the ICS security efforts
there amongst other things I don't know
them all myself yet but I'm trying to
catch up and Ralph's hat I'm sorry
Zach had a perfect record until last
year he missed last year's s4 but he has
attended nine of the ten s4 so we again
we appreciate his support and I thought
in this final panel yeah
okay thank you you know so I thought in
the end I obviously have a lot to do
with the program and what we're going to
talk about at s4 and it's geared based
on things that I think are important and
what I wanted to do was talk to these
two gentlemen about maybe other things
that we haven't talked about s4 so why
don't I start out Ralph with you what do
you see as one or you can mention more
than one if you like important issues
that we're not addressing either at this
conference or as an ICS community you
know first before we go into the details
I think one important issue of that next
next year we should have a
pre-conference Welcome Party I've been
saying that to do for so many years now
but all right by the way you could you
can thank Ralph for this moving down to
South Beach it only took him four years
to convince me but the reason we're in
South Beach is constant recommendation
but if I think about any subject matters
that I believe are a bit
underrepresented two things come to my
mind and the first thing would be I see
a complete lack of a discussion on the
iio tea at this conference and I think
this is very surprising at least to me
because we should consider or we should
realize that this discussion is
presently going on in full steam but
it's not Colette at this conference
within this audience and I think that's
that's a bad thing so as probably
everybody in this room knows there are a
bunch of conferences on the IOT there
are even a bunch of conferences on the
security of the IOT excuse me but we so
far agreed we didn't discuss this in
detail and what you would probably guess
is if you actually go to any of these
conference I just had the pleasure to
keynote one of that code of these con
is less for you would expect that you
won't find a lot of ICS talent there
including the speakers and I don't think
that's a good thing that there is a good
development so there are presently
witnessing the IOT or industry internet
discussion taking off as we speak and we
have little stakes in this discussion
and I think we see we should rather try
to change that quickly so if I remember
my talk last year in fall in Washington
DC most people in the audience and also
on the podium had very few ideas about
how let's just say an industrial thing
as they called it would be different
from a smart toilet or a smoke detector
a wristband smart wristband and I think
I had a bit of a hard time just bringing
at that point home that if you are
considering let's just say a big pump in
an industrial setting nobody in our
space refers to that object as a thing
right because when you talk about it as
a thing
you're completely stripping of its
function and how that physical function
is embedded or is messed up with all the
other actuators in that industrial
setting so I believe everybody in there
in this audience should take an effort
to participate in this ongoing
discussion make your voice be heard
because there is a reason to assume that
if we don't make ourselves heard with
our subject matter expertise
we'll just revive history so you'll see
the same thing in my opinion as Dale
alluded to at the end of his talk
remember back in the 90s when when
everybody was going to Windows PCs and
local area networks connecting to ICS
and all the
in gaseous vendors were moving to add
network interfaces to their products and
when that happens the idea was well
what's wrong with that I mean nothing
bad is going to happen because you're
just using that as an Aeron you're just
using that to to do our HMIS in a more
cost-efficient manner and you know a
couple of years later everybody knows
that it is a big deal and it this this
lack of thinking it through got us into
the mess that we presently are so just
in brief everybody knows when the
vendors try to plot their existing
products to that Ethernet based
connectivity they ported the the
protocols etc on a one-to-one basis so
they didn't realize that when you go
from zero point two point two networks
that that something like authentication
would be a great idea and now we have to
live with that and at the same time
those vendors told us well you know
nobody told you to connect all those
devices and networks to the internet
right so yes you're using OPC you're
using D comments error but we are not
telling that you should connect all
these things to the Internet
fast forwards now the same vendors tell
you the exact thing you got to connect
everything to the Internet otherwise
you're going to be out of business in a
couple of years we will see protocols
promoted as the core technology for the
IOT not modbus/tcp necessarily but for
example prophy net profit net is touted
as the best networking protocol in order
to make the IAO t happen and just in
case you didn't know what first many of
you will know pro Fiona does not include
authentication ethernet/ip does not
include also education and so this is my
my fear presently that you're forced to
repeat history and I think or or I
experience some kind of
urgency here because as I said this
discussion is going on at full steam and
we are not participating in that so I
think knowing you all these years I mean
we got a lot of i IOT
presentation suggestions and submittals
they were primarily about look how easy
it is for me to hack this you know a
small device and those probably aren't
of great value to us because we know you
know if they weren't designed with
security just like we had 50 0 days in
2012 we could find we could fill the
whole agenda with this what an end Zack
I'll ask you and then maybe Ralph you
can chime in what kind what should we be
talking about on IOT when we get
together in things like this or what
should be the way we attack solving this
problem well one of the things I've
noticed over the years and I kind of
changed my position after you know some
events of the last six months or so I
used to always define things between the
kind of Internet of Things and the
Internet of trivial things
so I would always make fun of you know
nest thermostats or smart toilets as you
mentioned you said that with a straight
face and I tried to do that myself as
well and then when you see but we all
knew the capability of a botnet of IOT
devices and sure enough those trivial
things became important and mass so some
of the other consequences of what we do
with the connected Internet of Things
one of the things we can talk about but
before I talk about smart and give it
back to Ralph I just want to talk about
the the theme of this conferences here
come together and kind of uh
congratulate Dale and and applaud all
the audience because ten years ago when
Dale was starting the s4 I know his
premise was that we needed to to bring a
bunch of people from different parts of
industry of academia the National Labs
government together to talk about the
problem because there wasn't really a
structured way of talking about OT type
of cybersecurity in a way that was
really meaningful for all of us and I
think that a lot of the other
conferences that have come up in the
meantime have been different
formulations of s for some bigger some
smaller some less successful but but
none of them that are any more important
and you've done a really great job doing
that all together Christian I
I want everyone to and and well with
that all those good words now let's uh
so did you have any I mean how should we
be addressing this i io t thing as a
group i I know in my talk one of the
things I mentioned was I feel like just
saying we're going to address IOT is
almost an impossible problem because it
is so big I mean so one of my answers
was taxonomy we need to start saying
let's split this into cases we can deal
with but what what do you either I guess
Ralph we'll start with you Leon what do
you think is is a fruitful way to start
talking about securing this well first
of all again remember this discussion is
already happening unfortunately it's not
happening on this stage so there are a
couple of other conferences some of them
focusing on security as I said the the
conference that I have attended less for
it was the security of things forum so
obviously they have a bunch of talks on
on security on cyber security certainly
I agree with you that it does make a lot
of sense demonstrating how to hack a
profile net installation is not very
different from what we have seen in
respect to Modbus and anything else that
doesn't include authentication and a
reasonable level of security but I think
there or at least I have seen a couple
of interesting thoughts to our
collaborations on the subject you know
there are there are a bunch of smart
people in that space especially on the
IT side of things and they have some
concept for how and trying to establish
a secure a IOT if we agree that you're
going that way and that this is a good
thing and certainly I would put the
emphasis on protective and mitigative
strategies I think we must have this
discussion because it is clear to me
that the risk that you're introducing
with the IOT is a magnitude bigger than
what we did so far because now you're
just going to hyper-connectivity and I
productivity means you're also
increasing your risk at the same time
because first the the number of
potential infiltration points is rising
and second the cost of consequence
potential cost of consequence is also
going up as well and so we gotta have
this discussion on how to secure this
new thing or maybe also include
discussions on where it is definitely a
bad idea to apply all these concepts
products its strategies etc and I mean
they already gave a couple of good
points in his talk because again this is
happening right now as we speak
preventive predictive maintenance using
remote access and then the vendors
certainly if if only for convenience
they want to have all the functions
available they want to be able to
theoretically completely reconfigure the
remote device and this is a discussion
that I think is necessary to have and
also single out those areas which we
might want to exclude another area would
be include the regulator's what what is
our position as the ICS security
community what what should we tell
governments on on where to place
limitations on which specific risks to
observe and to to limit because I'm
under the impression that that this
input would actually or could make a big
difference well you know one thing that
I think and Ralph's hit on it initially
was that s4 should focus on on I iotv
the industrial internet of things as
opposed to trying to solve that at large
a problem of consumer electronics etc
IOT is also going to give us a new
explosion of data when we've already
been in the center of an initial
explosion of data so all of the sensors
that we have out there that are coming
in people are trying to implement Sims
but still trying to determine whether we
use that same just at the OT floor how
do we integrate it with with business
the IT OT
conflicts that we may have again and
then with IOT that exploding of
information the potential to have even
greater sensing capabilities out on
plant floors and operations but being
able to aggregate all that data and make
use of it so potentially some of those
areas that can talk about you know new
ways to use data efficiently and
effectively within control and I would
see might be something that that could
be appropriate for the s4 yeah let me
jump in on that because that is a is a
good junction to my my second issue that
I think is underrepresented in this
conference and that is the whole big
field of security automation my opinion
is that if we don't get our act together
rather soon on how to automate our
procedures and strategy we will be in in
a deep mess because just of the
complexity of the rising risk you will
and already are engines at some place is
no longer be able to try to address the
problem by by having a bunch of guys you
know dedicated to the task and they were
meeting let's just say every week and
they are sitting in a room and then
they're discussing the risk and they are
doing some kind of analysis by hand well
I mean focus is no longer going to work
this is 2017 you're drowning in data
we're drowning in complexity and also
remember that that this human driven
effort just doesn't scale we don't have
enough experts and the only way that we
can solve this problem is by using
automation and I have to add that I'm
very very optimistic about that because
if you see the the level of success in
other fields I mean just remember the
presentation on machine learning earlier
or today if you see what other fields
are doing presently using artificial
intelligence machine learning
you name it modeling to me is out of the
question that technically it can be done
we
have the capability already but we just
failed so far to apply it to an area
where most people agree well just
remember Obama's executive order 1366
well this is one of the most critical
problems that we need to address right
and let's see what the next president is
going to say about that around one of
the things that that I think also comes
and takes that to the next step and when
you made your list on day one of the
different areas that you mentioned it
and we did talk about our machine
learning today and some good aspects but
beyond automation you know we're now
talking in broader industries and in the
defense which is somewhat interesting of
autonomy as opposed to just automation
instead of human-in-the-loop but human
on the loop and some of the issues that
we'll see with that you know a lot of
the artificial intelligence machine
learning programs that we see today you
cannot actually go and walk back and
understand how they made that decision
it was a good decision
we programmed it correctly it learned
appropriately it made the right decision
but we don't have the visualization
tools that the math the language to
understand exactly how those decisions
came about and if we're going to move
into autonomous systems for for drones
for surveillance for operations then we
need to be fully convinced of how those
decisions have been made and I think
that's something that we're going to
deal with especially as we get into more
automation because that the next step
and we still always you know say oh well
they'll never use your wireless in this
environment and then two years later Oh
there'll be no such thing as a
cloud-based control system right so if
someone say to me well will never do
autonomy I mean certain critical
controls I'll say just just wait five
years ago back there the security
automation is kind of interesting in the
sense that and and I'm trying to think
of a parallel and it doesn't an analogy
and it doesn't come to my mind right now
it's not being done at all so you really
I shouldn't say at all but it's not
being done very much the types of things
that you're going to automate it's being
done in some places to some degree but
it's not one of these things where you
have this process that's widely deployed
and effective that you're automating
it's almost more that it's not widely
deployed and effective it may be
automation is the only way to get it
done I don't know if that's what you're
saying but there are there examples
where you go from not doing it well or
not doing it to automation directly you
know make that big jump well first of
all I think we have already seen some
very impressive examples of on how
security automation can be applied so
just for example I just suggest for
everybody if you haven't already done so
to look up the the DARPA cyber Grand
Challenge from from last year and what
they did so in a nutshell they had
hacking teams competing against each
other every team tried to hack into the
other systems but the challenge was that
they that they weren't actually allowed
to use human input so it was all
pre-programmed and the the software that
conducted the attacks also used some
machine learning so it has been able to
to identify or to search for new ways on
how to hack into those other systems and
at the same time the software also tried
to do some self healing some self
patching just to give you an idea that
so this is happening already this this
happened last year and what I believe we
should do is sue to to explore how all
these existing approaches technologies I
mean ranging from from the computing
power that we presently have like AWS
kerchief and to the algorithms that are
out there so the case studies that have
been done and explore rather quickly how
we can turn that into good use into our
specific field ranging from from try to
address complex tasks like how do i how
can i use that at some high value
facilities to to protect high-value
targets like nuclear power plants just
as a reminder we still don't have
they're any good algorithms at this time
to determine what the critical digital
assets are at nuclear power plants you
will if you think that's easy I can tell
you it's very very complex so when when
the US nuclear industry started out
defining a method for doing that they
were under these assumption they would
end up with axis 8 when your authority
critical digital assets and no they were
talking about a couple of hundreds if
not thousands pretty good digital assets
including those new plans who use analog
safety systems so that for me is I try
to allude to to that problem in my talk
less you're at on this stage that
suggests me that that we need to try to
find some some algorithms some heuristic
algorithms in order to address that
tough problem and certainly another area
where where I see a huge potential for
security automation is everywhere there
you need to scale up your efforts so you
know you're not looking at a low number
of high-value targets but you're looking
at a high number of let's say medium
value targets well certainly automation
would be seen as a way to help leverage
some of the workforce shortages that we
see by using the experts you know better
one of the things that we might also
look at you mentioned the DARPA cyber
grand challenge but drive is also
running a program now called radix or
radix depending on where you're from
that incorporates some some elements of
of automatic recovery automatically
Constitution you know ways of developing
alternative systems or testing systems
after an event I think a lot of people
here will be you know looking at those
types of systems and how they might
impact what the impact might be of
having that type of help come in to help
you reconstitute your environment after
what might be a significant event and we
can imagine you know something you know
on the order of Ukraine happening in the
US and how would you know be able to use
external resources who may not have the
full knowledge of your of your plant and
its actual configuration have autonomous
or automatic systems be able to come in
and identify configurations and rebuild
blueprints etc so some of those things
are also very interesting but
we'll all have to play a little bit of
catch-up so you know look up there the
University of Illinois and some others
are doing some good work in the area
lots of companies and when DARPA comes
in like they say they they will they
will make a big splash they'll hopefully
bring enough brainpower on to the
project have enough good results we can
then all leverage off them for the next
five or ten years and weed the labs and
some of the universities that are
involved are hoping that I'm working
with the asset owners that are also
involved with the project okay well I
want to make sure we give you time so
what ralph said here's a couple things
we should be talking about here and and
and also in the community has broader
what do you see as maybe things were not
paying enough attention to at s4 or the
broader community as a whole well you
know I love listening to rough talk
that's why I said yes when you when you
asked me to come over but well you know
you know one of my my pet peeves forever
has always been up in Metrix I think
that we've gotten away from the concern
about really understanding you know what
to measure how to measure it and how
it's impactful and it just kind of you
know moved on there have been several
well-funded studies on metrics and I
think they all came back negative ly and
conclusive and I think that that is I
put a damper on we required because
operations go on right so we have to
look at other ways of measuring the
performance and the impact of our of our
systems the other thing that I know
Renee Taran must spoke about and that we
are very actively pursuing in INL is I'm
looking we're at a consequence based
approach to or managing our systems and
problems rather than try to deal with
threats that you may not fully
understand especially out in acetone or
land that they don't have the full
sediment makes on the threats
vulnerabilities that are increasing and
being discovered every day it's hard to
develop a risk paradigm when you can't
keep those two variables anywhere near
but but you know what the most severe
consequences are in your environment in
safety engineering and other engineering
disciplines as she mentioned you know we
can use those consequence based
understanding to then engineer out some
of the worst things that could happen to
us there's a new bill out or another
proposed bill while Senator King and
rich that it caused a lot of press last
year and I think we've worked with the
legislature to come
collectively as a community to let them
you know that that what that automation
isn't bad that computers and critical
structures not bad but there are
appropriate uses for different
technologies you know you know analog
safety systems for critical systems as
opposed to you know having everyone you
know use it's the same wires the same
devices to be able to really you know
mitigate some of these security concerns
and so that consequence based approach I
think is something that we'll be working
on more this year and you'll probably
see a lot of different things come out
for next year or maybe the year after
that's for a conference on consequence
based types of approaches and pilots I
know we're I'm just finishing up a pilot
with the utility and hopefully we'll
have something good to we can come to a
few baths with that as well okay but
that it's and it works across systems so
as I said before other engineering
paradigms whether it's you know
mechanical engineering construction etc
you know let's what what do we have to
do to make sure the building doesn't
fall down that the bridge does not sway
in a violent you know when they look at
those consequences and those are the
baseline engineering things that we need
to do I think that we'll start seeing
that in in both retrofits for critical
assets and also in new engineering
architectures the metrics is kind of
interesting and it ties a little bit
back to way back to what I talked about
in the mini keynote as you start to talk
to your board of directors and your in
your sea levels and you say we have
these problems we need to do something
they're looking for some quarterly
report that shows we were here we wanted
to get here and you know where are we
and perhaps raising that bar so the the
driver for the metrics I think you
talked I don't know how many ice cores
ago like six or seven ago absolutely
with mark fabro about metrics I think at
that point and and there's still a need
for them but they were very technical
engineers security person kind of
metrics and and the other problem that
we have with the metrics was that we
couldn't link it back to security you
know we started you know learning how to
measure things but couldn't necessarily
measure the absolute impact on making it
yourself more secure someone mention
that one of the talks earlier here today
you know you know IT security guys ot
security guys your problems I mean you
go to this conference that's four
you come back and you want more money
for more security so can you tell me
that you know if I give you this money
that will be secured in six months well
no not really
well that will be more security if you
tell me how much more secure will be
what we still don't have that capability
either right now benchmarking and
comparing ourselves to other members of
the industry and not trying to outrun
the bear you know too much but to stop
running the competition used to be a
good you know benchmark but if there's
an adversary that's looking to impact
you it doesn't matter what your peers
are doing because it's your security
that matters not the at the aggregate so
are you optimistic about metrics I mean
and NRF the same question you think in
two years from now we'll have useful
metrics that are at least consensus
agreed-upon for how you determine how
secure your ICS is not at all right now
I don't think that we're studying the
metrics problem the way we had been in
the past that we've gone back to doing
more effective operations more
understanding risk and consequences and
that may be a good thing but I still
think that we need to come back to the
area of metrics later on the other big
thing that has been brewing for it for
10 years along with the metrics is is
the science of cybersecurity and once
again we can't really you know become
more of a scientist Accor or truly
engineering discipline as opposed to a
black part until we have those those
measures we can compare you know the the
actual capabilities of one intrusion
detection system versus another and in
absolute terms and rather than just the
effectiveness of the user interface you
know whether it's appealing to the user
and then and we still use it but but
true effectiveness so so ralphus and you
may disagree but if you agree that
metrics are something that we are
important what's your feeling on them is
this something that is achievable in the
in the next you know one to two or three
years or is this something that we'll be
chasing five years from now I have a
great feeling about metrics because
you're using metrics in the right
service security program now over 30
base 40 days no no that's that OD basis
product but all but the the the
programmatic effort that that you're
using comes with metrics no since two
years since the introduction of the
program and we were seeing the results
and and the asset owners the clients are
happy with that because they just as
anybody would guess so you can do
comparisons you can benchmark yourself
against your peers you can do
comparisons how did we perform in the
last cycle what are our goals in that
specific domain for the next cycle and
that works just great and I think the
the the the one aspect you should be you
should think very hard about we never
made an effort to to reach any consensus
in the community okay so what I'm not
talking about what you're doing what our
clients is completely proprietary
however I would also assume that if if
you would have a discussion on what
you're actually doing most of you would
agree that this makes absolute sense it
might not be perfect it certainly is not
perfect but it's useful and so in my
opinion the the the problem that we are
self imposing on many of our efforts is
to reach a consensus first because
before we start to do anything I think
that's a flawed approach especially
because you're running out of time we
don't have the luxury to to to get our
act together over a decade like with all
the big standardization efforts that you
see going on at IEC at ISA etc I don't
believe that we have the luxury I think
presently our biggest problem is that we
are out run not just by the threats by
oh by all the attackers in this world
but just by the complexity alone then so
this is this has been my my approach for
the last couple of years don't wait
until you reach any consensus again I'm
happy to to have a debate on the metrics
that
we're using it and the basics are
actually published in in the white paper
the ripe ot security framework that you
can find on the internet but experience
has shown it works it works pretty well
it is not perfect but it that it helps
guide the effort for all clients for for
the asset owners even though we have a
regulator who is quite happy with that
approach so I'm probably much more
optimistic than you are and and and I
will agree that that we deftly can't
wait for a consensus or even a right
solution that we have to try things and
and see when they work and then spread
the word throughout the industry so I
totally agree with your approach and I
think that right is another good
mechanism for that but once again
someone mentioned before that some
machine learning algorithms or maybe the
motion sensor of a game that can that
can predict your movements once they got
it working they went back and said we
really don't know why it works but it's
working well and I think too for it to
be the science we really have to be able
to understand because then we won't be
able to push off from it to the next
step you know one thing that I heard
throughout a number of sessions in and I
just heard it again is this concept of
time you know that our cycle time in
this space is traditionally very slow
very slow adopters I think Brian Owen
brought it up in the certification panel
you know if you're talking about
certifying products and in your writing
new code every three weeks or 12 weeks
and deploying it with what you mentioned
about IOT I mean they're running
full-speed they're not going to wait for
this community to catch up do you have
any idea how we accelerate this
community ability to bring in change and
bring in new ideas you've you've been
convicted so many conferences in your
roles over the years you know this
community very well how how do we change
that culture so that we do the change
quickly well you know I don't think it's
necessarily you know say you know this
community the community of engineers
cybersecurity professionals IT
professionals we're all ready to jump in
I've mentioned to both you guys before
that I'm so sick of hearing about the
latest wake-up call that we've had in
the industry it's amazing any of us get
to sleep at all because I know every
every week every month there's a new
flavor attack of the day and it's like
oh this will change everything right you
know CEOs are now on board and I call it
the half-life of awareness sometimes you
know when something bad happens if
nothing else bad happens in a week it
dies down as a month it dies down again
and once again people that have other
problems that they have to focus on um
and so you know I'm not one of those you
know who likes to tout the cyber Pearl
Harbor but you know things do happen
attacks have happened you know you know
botnets of IOT devices etc we see all
this happening but until it happens to a
specific industry or a specific company
they don't tend to be on board until
they've had their own awakening and we
have to be able to leverage the
awakenings if nothing else I would also
think that you're observing some kind of
a mindset problem here and I think that
overall the the mindset in the whole
factory automation community and even in
some parts of the service security
community or in the ot security
community is a pretty static like let's
just wait for what is evolving in terms
of standards for example so what what I
would like to see and I think we were
seeing the beginnings of this is that
that some smart people some smart
companies some innovative companies just
start to to get bold again yet just turn
back the clock a couple of decades I
think when more econ decades ago and
develop the develop the Modbus protocol
it was kind of bold oh I mean that they
just put in so I cannot imagine that
they had a real task force working for
weeks or months on the protocol
definition to me it appears like this
was done over over a weekend like a
rainy weekend and then some some
engineer said well you know I have
nothing better to do nothing good on TV
so just define that protocol
and I have been missing that same spirit
well let's just come up with a smart
solution and we will see chances are if
it's really smart and and if it produces
some benefit then the market will
actually use that so in this respect I
want to encourage everybody just come up
with your local smart solutions and I'm
actually pretty optimistic that we are
in in a time where change is about to
happen
in this area and this field change is
about to happen so as most of you will
know there are a couple of stars up
recently which have successfully raised
a lot of venture capital I think the
time is right to for entrepreneurs or
smart companies or even scientists if
you're working at the academia to just
come up with a smart solution and I
think the chances have never been better
that that this complete static
environment will pick up your solution
and you will have defined the next de
facto standard let's just hope it's
going to be better than Modbus yeah well
you know I think you have a good point
there and and timing is a lot I know a
lot of innovators and adventures you
know obviously work in the last nine
years with DHS S&T and the cycle times
for you know government procurement
industry procurement and others that can
be very long but if there's a solution
that's that's needed to build by things
and I think that time Modbus came out
there was getting ready to be an
explosion of automation you know at that
level and they were there at the right
time with them you know one of the the
first things available I think that as
you mentioned now there is getting ready
to be another explosion and trying to
you know foresee the types of things
that people will need the way to you
know bring autonomy or automation and
I'm not sure that economy is something
that we're ready for yet within this is
a area with all of the the data that
we're going to have to be able to use
that data for the sensing of operations
of security of other areas may be the
thing that will will get us to that next
phase okay well why don't we close with
I mentioned again at the beginning of
the conference
Peter teal question you know what is
something that you believe to be true
that most of your colleagues and other
people in the industry disagree with and
and Zac I'll let you go in disagree with
anything I say right that's what
happened there um it's always easy for
me because I'm so disagreeable right but
I'm sure I blow it up for you so of life
I think I've already mentioned I think
that that's a true true metrics are are
really important and we're going to you
know miss the fact that we don't have
them very soon and I would beat the drum
for you know studying metrics and
getting a baseline so that we know where
we're at in the future that's
interesting so you think that that the
importance of metrics is not recognized
by the community again I don't think
we're doing anything about it okay
well as for me so a thing but what most
people disagree on what with me is that
I am convinced absolutely convinced that
we can solve this problem we can make
critical infrastructure Osiris secure
just do it yes I actually don't disagree
with you on that I think I there's
actually a session I did at s4 Europe
called defense will win and people were
just shocked but I I really I really
think we have advantages in our sector
that are completely different Dale has
changed I mean you know I don't know
maybe I don't know my daughter or
something oil even finalized something
but in any event I really appreciate you
guys coming up here and sharing your
thoughts and raising some new things
that maybe people can discuss over beer
I hear them pouring beer behind us so
I'm I'm hoping they're ready for the
craft beer bash if if they're listening
back there you need to remember to bring
up the ramp or they'll storm the stage
and and they won't be able to get up
here but they'll be behind us but I
guess I just I guess I just like to to
close the event if we could just by
again thanking our sponsors
we couldn't put on the event without
them thanking all our speakers for
traveling so far and working so hard on
their work and their research I hope you
enjoyed that and if you did I hope you
reached out to the speakers and gave
them your thoughts and ideas if you see
Liz Daley and the daily events crew
please thank them they put on all the
fun things or all their responsibilities
so if you had fun here they definitely
were a big part of that and lastly I
just again as I said at the beginning I
do appreciate you all coming it means a
lot that you'll spend your time here I
hope you got some value out of it and
and we hope to see you again next year
as for 18 is January 16th through 18th
back here in Miami South Beach and with
that if you're ready are we ready for
the beer can we open the curtains okay
thank you as far as clothes yeah all
attendees are now welcome to come on the
s4 main stage for the craft beer bash
and personally thank the speakers
sponsors and staff for helping make s4
17 happen