please welcome to the s4 mainstage Dale
Peterson thank you very much it's really
good to see so many familiar faces out
there and smiling in the morning that's
great
welcome to the 2017 edition of digital
bond s4 and I just really want to thank
you for coming here I know your time is
your most valuable commodity I really
appreciate you coming here for three
days and we're going to try to deliver
great value for your time here over the
next three days now our theme for this
year's s4 is come together and at the
beginning of s4 every year I stand up
here and give a little mini keno try to
introduce what's going to happen where I
think the ICS security market is and
most years I look like that you know
very angry very frustrated a little bit
depressed you know five years ago at s4
12 and s4 13 yeah we had gone through
what a lot of us called The Lost Decade
where we didn't make any progress or any
substantial progress on securing our
control systems in literally 10 years we
had level 1 devices PLC's are to use
that were insecure by design and our
asset owners were basically stuck with
having a good perimeter keeping the bad
guys out and maybe detecting if they got
in but really not being able to secure
their system and you see the other
problems there you know no SPL I think
at s4 2012 there were actually 50
different 0 days and we had a lot of
brilliant researchers there but it
wasn't because they did brilliant work
it was just because the stuff was so bad
and I think the most frustrating thing
to me back 5 years ago and why I was so
pessimistic is the ICS security
community
to accept this you know that this was
the way it is get over it it's going to
be this way for the next ten or fifteen
years so it was it was not I guess it
was a time for me to vent when I came on
stage five years ago whereas now I'm
completely optimistic it's all rainbows
and unicorns and sunshine and and
everything is really great and there's a
lot of good reasons for this optimism I
mean most important and you know this is
my hot button but we're finally getting
rid of insecure by design we had a panel
session at s for Europe in Vienna last
June with a lot of the major PLC and our
two vendors and believe it or not
they're adding things like signed
firmware secure boot even secured ICS
protocols with authentication and
authorization enforced at the PLC so
this is just a huge step and really
brings us two main things first of all
if you're an asset owner you now have a
choice you can decide what is my risk
today should I spend the money to
upgrade to this new secure system to
reduce my risk before you didn't have a
choice you had to live with it because
they were all that way now you have a
choice and secondly we can stop digging
this hole you know we even over the last
15 years we've been putting in brand new
systems that were insecure but I
designed now we can put in secure system
so this is really good and and that's I
think the most important thing but you
see up to on the list there on the slide
a lot of other things for example
training we now have training programs I
know Mike Asante from Sands is speaking
this morning fans can train thousands of
people now on ICS security as can is a
some of the more boutique trainers like
Joel and Jill who's speaking this
afternoon on the sponsor stage you know
before he could only teach 30 students
at a time now we have online training
from Joel and others they can teach
thousands so we have better training we
have people understanding
that security is more than just buying
equipment you see things like the NIST
cybersecurity framework or Ralph
langner's ot security framework where
you're actually looking at putting
together a whole program instead of just
buying a widget and really I could go on
and on a lot about the last bullet but
we're in a very exciting time not only
from security but what you're going to
see in the next generation of ICS so
this is a fantastic time I think
actually the best time to be an ICS
security and I would even broaden that
it's a great time to be in the ICS
community as a whole so we are at this
time with all this possibility now where
the technology and the will is coming
around to actually do the right thing
and to build more secure and reliable
and efficient and better control systems
and the way we what we need to do to
take advantage of that is we need some
groups that typically don't talk to each
other to come together to work on this
problem if we don't do that we're
actually going to lose our opportunity
that we have right now and there's three
different groups that I want to just
touch on briefly that need to come
together now the first one o T NIT
you know I always say this is an
advanced audience you don't need skata
SEC 101 you have all heard this for a
long time that ot NIT need to get
together the good news is it's happening
I mean there are many success stories
with companies of different sizes medium
and large companies where this has
already happened it's a done deal
they're doing it and there's a variety
of ways to solve this problem but
there's a few things I think that you
know I wanted to just highlight shortly
that people don't understand that seem
to be getting in the way of this the
first thing is a lot of times OT when
they say we can't work with IT they're
thinking of desktop management and
you're right ot and desktop management
should never get together you know you
do not want to manage your control
system like you manage your thousand
user desktops or 10,000 users
tops but when you think of it and if you
have any experience working with
mission-critical IT the type of system
where if it's down for 10 seconds the
company can say we lose this much money
that is almost identical in terms of how
you how you install and maintain an OT
system and how you install and maintain
and mission-critical
IT system and I know in the audience
because I know a lot of you we have some
even skeptics still about the need for
ot NIT to get together even if you are
skeptic and you say I T should stay
completely away from OT you still need
IT you just need the IT skills so
somehow we have to bring the IT skills
to this equation we made the mistake in
past years when people were installing
Active Directory without domain admins
people are running managed switches with
no idea how to actually manage them the
world is getting much more complicated
now your next control system or the one
you put in the last couple of years is
going to be running on a virtualized
platform you are going to need people
with those IT skills on how to install
and maintain a virtual environment or
you will fail
same thing with storage area networks
cloud services so there's no getting
around it if even if you want to keep ot
separate you need IT you're just going
to be building your own IT department
now the real reason I think why ot has
been so hesitant to get involved with IT
is that ot has basically been a pile of
crap I mean you you know it was nothing
that IT could do I mean 10 year old
operating systems you know hubs instead
of switches no one understanding
anything about management it was
installed incorrectly it hasn't been
maintained for a decade there really was
not much you could do to come together
now fortunately
especially the people in this room that
I think are more forward-thinking asset
owners but I think across the board
we're seeing this change
so you're seeing most of the systems now
either today or in the next five years
will be new systems that can be
supported now I've been kind of hard on
ot IT is also going to need to step up
I'm sure you've run into the situation
where IT says what we do support 9:00 to
9:00 to 6:00 Monday through Friday
you know they can't work with ot if they
have those requirements and it is a fact
that a lot of a lot of these companies
that have control systems are not used
to running mission-critical IT
so they don't actually have the
experience on how to do it they are
going to need to step up and understand
how they can provide the services needed
of course there's there's culture
there's language there's what's
important to an ICS there's some
learning involved but I actually think
the biggest thing beyond understanding
that these are mission critical systems
that require different than desktop
management I think the biggest thing is
is respect a lot of times if you're and
I know we have some people coming from
the IT world you go into ot and you see
this old stuff that's may not maintained
and you think these people are really
stupid they have no idea what they're
doing they're incompetent but what they
don't realize is that actually putting
together and making a control system
work the number of points two displays
the complexity all the things that have
to be built in to allow a couple of
operators in a control room to manage a
factory or a huge process is truly
amazing it's actually much much harder
than anything an IT or IT security so
we're talking about smart people that
need to be treated with respect and I
think what you just have to realize if
you're coming at it from that side is
that these people that went to school to
be electrical engineers or chemical
engineers really didn't do want to do
patching of servers or workstations so
the OT NIT one coming together I think
that is well understood I hope that's a
little flavor as to how we can be more
effective there the next two though are
a little different so the next two pair
that needs to come together is
operations and senior management whether
it be your board of directors or your
c-level people I don't know how many of
you are familiar with a gentleman by the
name of Peter teal he was one of the
PayPal co-founders he has a really
interesting question he said tell me
something that's true that almost nobody
agrees with you on it's actually a fun
question to ask someone sometime or to
think about yourself you know what are
you absolutely convinced is true that
everyone else thinks you're crazy my
answer for the last two years is that
the board of directors and the sea
levels are ready and willing to spend
substantial money on ICS securities I
contend that getting budgets to improve
the security and reliability of your ICS
is not an issue at the board or sea
level right now the reason I say that
and we have a lot of data points on this
but believe it or not over the last two
years we've been having to slow down
senior management they want to spend
more money that can then can be
effectively spent they want everything
fixed in three months once they learn
about how bad it is and what risk they
had unknowingly accepted they say how do
we fix this what is it going to cost how
do we do it who can we get and of course
you can only implement so much change at
a time I'm sure some of you have been
involved in safety programs it's like
that you can't just throw unlimited
resources and accomplish it in three
months but that's a very positive
indicator when you talk to them they
understand risk and they actually
understand that the money we're talking
about is relatively small compared to
the risk that they're accepting and
compared to the things that they spend
on their other budgeted items and I
guess one thing I like to do if you
really run into a
with this is pull out the list of the
funded projects in IT and look at what
they're funding and how much money
they're spending and then look at the
criticality of the control system I mean
most of these companies they are in
business to produce a product to deliver
water to to refine oil you know the
control system is the reason they exist
and yet the idea that they wouldn't
spend a certain amount of money on these
systems as opposed to putting you know
upgrading let's say their internet
server that provides their benefits to
the employees
it's just laughable it is a really easy
sell at the right level now the
challenge when I say come together is
the plant managers and I know we have
some out there and the VP of operations
as well as the subject matter experts
who advise them they really need to step
up they need to be bringing the case to
these high-level executives as to why do
we need to spend this money
what risk we currently have how we will
reduce that risk and this is very new
because they're typically used to adding
or coming up to the board or the C
levels every 15 20 years asking for a
big capital expenditure to put in a new
system and then going away and saying
you know we won't will bother you you
won't bother us just leave us alone for
15 20 years
okay that's changed and if you are the
plant manager it's a little bit
embarrassing to go to your bosses and
say by the way we have this huge risk
that we haven't addressed for years and
we need to spend this money now it's a
little bit embarrassing but I think you
can handle that because it's a problem
across the industry and if they talk to
their peers they'll see this as an issue
everyone's dealing with and it really is
better than the alternative the
alternative if you as a plant manager
don't initiate this coming together is
that the board or the sea levels are
somehow going to learn of the risk that
you have not told them
about that you are accepting and it is
not going to be a career enhancing
activity for you and I have two examples
up there one we had a food and beverage
company that just was you know they were
one of the ones going as fast as they
could to do as much as they could
because it was pushed and I asked well
why you know what caused this I'm sure
we have some consultants out there
usually it's one of two things either
there's been an incident and they're
there all of a sudden reacting to the
incident or someone got religion and in
this case the food and beverage Co
happened to be in an event it wasn't s
for but he happened to be at an event
and sat next to the coca-cola Co and the
coca-cola co o said oh this is what
we're doing and here's the risks we have
and we're you know we put this program
together and then our clients went back
to his company and started asking
questions and got some really ugly
answers so you don't want that to happen
you want to bring the issues up rather
than have them push down the other
examples is pretty similar
you probably recognize that's the front
page to a Chatham House report a board
member of an electric utility client
read that passed it out passed the
executive summary to all the other board
levels board members all the c-level
executives and all of a sudden the same
thing happened they started asking
questions they were I don't think
horrified is that strong but they were
very concerned about the risk that they
had and they you know they went flat out
to try to address it so you want to
again you want to push the the VP of ops
the plant manager you want to initiate
the coming together because it's going
to happen either way and you want to
control that now the third area and
final area I want to talk about coming
together it really has a lot to do here
with what you're going to see on the
main stage over the next couple of days
and that is our ICS community needs to
bring in role
dated field now you could you could say
IT is a related field but there's a lot
more that we need to consider and I just
put some of them up on this list machine
learning is going to have a dramatic
impact on control systems over the next
five years we need to understand it we
need to incorporate it into our
strategies we have a great session on
Thursday morning with Katherine Hume
from fast forward labs that is just
going to blow your mind I mean it is
amazing what we're going to be doing
with machine learning and the same thing
with cloud services of course there's
risk to these so we need to find the
right way to do them how to use this
technology how to use it securely and
reliably and I actually have a session
Thursday afternoon on how we can
approach to that psychology related
field how would that apply we have a
great talk from clinical psychologist
dr. Eric Shaw who used to work in an
Intelligence Agency and you know one of
the problems you always hear about
disgruntled insiders being the toughest
ones they're the ones that can hurt you
most and it's very difficult to find
them you can use clinical psychology
statistics and email to proactively
identify disgruntled insiders and the
numbers are amazing and then it's not
theoretical it's actually happening
conflict theory to understand your
threat environment we have Dick Clark
keynoting on Thursday we have one Renee
Turin from NSA and Mary McCord coming up
from the Department of Justice we added
Ben Buchanan he's speaking later today
and in do a book signing at the Cabana
sessions but you'll get a lot of
information on how to think about threat
how to understand how cyber weapons will
be used and defended against and and
whether you like to term or not how
cyber warfare will take place and we
have economics and a variety of other
things so we really want to embrace
these related fields bring in the best
people understand what they are figure
out how we can use them and bring them
in sensibly into the ICS world now this
audience here a lot of you we don't have
every leader in ICS in ICS security here
but we have a lot of them I mean this is
a very good representation and I went
through this in the crypto world back a
couple of decades to go too long ago
where you have a group where maybe
there's a hundred to 500 people and
everyone knows everyone and to a certain
extent sometimes people like it that way
it's like well we're the ones that know
it you outside or stay out and and there
can be a tendency to be a little petty
about who knows what or insular and not
let others in I think we really have to
work hard to avoid that you know we need
to encourage people not only to come
into ICS security proper but to bring
knowledge from related fields in we need
to open their arms and and bring that
knowledge into ICS security and my hope
here at s4 the next three days is we can
play some small part on that we have
three stages going on so you have the
main stage where you'll have advanced
sessions but not deep technical sessions
for the most part on ICS and related
fields we have Stage two which has the
gory technical stuff and I've seen the
presentations a they brought it this
year there's a lot of technical details
if you want it you'll see it on stage
two and then we have the sponsor stage
we moved up for those of you who are
here last year
we moved the sponsor Stage two right
right on the first floor right when you
walked into the place the sponsor stage
is right there and we challenge the
sponsors issue we said look you know
there's a lot of times ask well how many
people will come to our session how many
people should we expect and said well it
depends how good your session is right
there's there's two other stages going
on they have choices you need to bring
it or you're going to have an empty room
I'm proud to say that the sponsor is
really
stepped up this year you have people
that are keynote or speaking on the
sponsor stage you have very technical
talks on the sponsor stage and I'd
encourage you to definitely check out
that agenda as well as stage two in the
mainstage so one of the one of the ways
we're going to get you to come together
is we're going to bring you a lot of new
information but probably the more
important way is this is a really good
group of people here and we want to set
up and we always set up s4 so that you
have time to establish and re-establish
your relationships with people that you
need to be talking to so of course you
have the hallway con you have After
Hours and South Beach which is always
fun but we have a lot of social events
where you'll have time to sit down and
literally meet almost everyone here
tonight after the last session we go
over to the Botanical Gardens just a
short walk and we have a welcome party
that's going to be really fun Liz Daly
does a great job on the food and
entertainment and she's got some real
surprises there and if you happen to
have a spouse or guests they're welcome
to come and then tomorrow we have the
Cabana sessions and that's really the
time that a lot of people liked last
year we set aside the afternoon to enjoy
the Miami Sun around the pool and you
really have time to interact with your
other attendees and the sponsors and out
at the Cabana sessions this year there's
there's some virtual reality there's
robot challenges Cisco brought their
kegerator so you can try to hack it to
get a beer
there's awed mented reality and all
sorts of other entertainment and food so
I think you really have a good time
there but I also want you to really
connect with your fellow attendees and
so with that I just want again welcome
you to s4 and I hope I have a chance to
talk to each and every one of you thank
you very much
you