[Music]
our next speaker is Eric Schweickart who
leaves the Tofino engineering team
within Belden's industrial cybersecurity
platform
he'll be presenting how deep is your
deep packet inspection let's please
welcome Eric thanks it's Eric where the
Kay actually there's a little typo in
there so so I've been with well Tofino
actually we started as as buyer security
at the time so that was back in 2007 so
I got to learn a lot you know from Eric
let me change her name obviously to
tofino and we got bought by Belden in
2011 so I managed the software
engineering team for Tofino to move down
to the u.s. from Canada so I'm actually
the guy that I wrote the Modbus TCP UDP
enforcer the OPC module Ethernet IP
modules so those are the D packet
inspection engines that are actually
built into the Tofino itself so you know
over the past 10 years we you know I've
learned a lot about the industry and you
know my my real interest is you know
Deepak inspections so this is kind of a
great talk stuff that I'm really
interested about so the question is you
know how do we kind of compare you know
different products you know there's a
lot of companies out there that produce
you know deep packet inspection
technology you know malware detection
that kind of thing but how do you really
compare them so it's kind of a tough
question so we kind of came up with you
know sort of the plan of like what I'd
like to talk about today so we have to
sort of define these terms you know the
control plane data plane and then what I
want to do is you know keep in the back
of your mind you know what is the Modbus
protocol look like like from a Wireshark
perspective you know how what is the
packet structure like dnp3 and Ethernet
IP specifically you know Ethernet IP
with sip sip on top of it and then how
do we sort of take everything we know
about these protocols and come to some
method to compare against them and what
do we really care about
if you're trying to actually protect you
know this industrial control system so
you know I like math so I kind of came
up with this like a grading scheme so
going from sort of these qualitative
mechanics to some quantitative ways it's
kind of easy to compare things with some
numbers and then I've kind of want to
outline things that you know you can't
really just consider right in the engine
itself you know how usable is it you
know that kind of that kind of stuff so
first thing we need to kind of get some
idea of terms so so there's the data
plane the control plane so the data
plane traffic is like your you know
you're getting processed data it's stuff
that you're you're monitoring you know
it's usually controlled by the actual
ladder logic you know someone's program
this PLC it should function this way
it's monitoring some specific valve some
pressure gauge that kind of stuff you
know typical protocols you know Modbus
dnp3 Ethernet IP you think of goose I
see 104 so then you have the the control
plane so this is the stuff you can do
sort of dangerous things with so you can
think of you know this is the version of
control logics running on your you know
Alan Bradley Rockwell PLC so it's the
ability where you can update firmware
you know this is the stuff that we
really care about so you know in Shriner
they've got this vendor specific you
know function code 9b this unity
programming ofs software you know you
can think of rockwell they've got this
pc cubed embedded or CSP v4 for some
legacy PLC 5s and in kind of the desktop
terms it's like oh you're gonna do an
update on your Linux kernel you know so
it's gonna affect all the user space
processes you know maybe they've changed
some system calls you know windows you
do these sort of Windows updates it's
changed your system you know Service
Pack 1 to service pack 2 that kind of
stuff so this is the updating of the
actual operating system sort of firmware
that's running in it so unfortunately
you know a lot of these protocols
you know Modbus you know dnp3 well
there's you know some authentication but
I don't you know in brownfield
installations it's probably hasn't been
used so there's really no authentication
so I could you know go to show Dan go
find some PLC's on the web
connect to them you know it's kind of
crazy so we really need some Deepak
inspection mechanism to be able to
differentiate between these control
plane and data plane communications so
let's sort of think of some some common
protocols so Modbus Ethernet IP dnp3 so
they all have this you know in the
Modbus case you have your MP op header
you know there's this function codes
specific address ranges and we Ethernet
IP sip you've got your Ethernet IP layer
there's the Ethernet IP commands you
know it's this common packet format
embedded in that you have all your
actual sip messaging so you be the
object services so there's these these
fields that are predefined you know
their specs for this you can get the RFC
but what we're thinking about when we're
trying to kind of compare these is well
you know Modbus really simple it's like
in lar f sees like hundred pages and you
think of Ethernet IP you're looking at
like a thousand you know dnp3 1200 so
the complexity really varies depending
on what protocol you're actually looking
at so and you know speaking to that the
actual complexity of the implementation
of your Deepak inspection engine has to
be more complex to support the
complexity of the protocol itself so you
know you think of sip you have these
multiple service packets so even
portions with say in the protocol itself
become more complex so in a multiple
service packet you actually have these
embedded sip messages so you could have
you know 30 sip messages within a single
TCP frame you know how does the PLC deal
with this if it doesn't expect this you
know does it support it
you know dnp3 has segmentations so you
know these are all things to keep in
mind when you're thinking about you know
this product supports it but what does
that really mean how can you really
grade these against each other so how do
we compare so I've sort of talked you
know probably you know in a quick manner
of all the different protocols so you
know if you think of one packet format
what does this actually mean so you have
some Modbus frame it's got you know some
length field you know how do we compare
how do we kind of you know take all
these disjoint protocols put them
together and think you know what do I
need
to actually protect my PLC so if you
think about you know a lot of the
vulnerabilities the kind of stem from
the same kind of things right you're
looking at you know malware packet
fuzzing type things you know you're
adding two F's to the end of some packet
you know what does the PLC really do
with this or the HMI you know if you're
sending response frames so if we can you
know cover to the that 80 to 90 percent
of vulnerabilities out there you know
we're looking a lot better than just the
plc with no protection in front of it so
what do we what do we really need to do
so this is my this is my rant slide or
actually have two slides about sort of
the signature based approach so you know
signatures that's really you know in my
opinion kind of the way it works is that
you know you to build a signature this
there has to be this vulnerability I
already published so you can go back and
actually build a signature against it so
you can mitigate that attack so it's
really this reactive mech mechanism
rather than some proactive mechanism and
you know with signatures you can build
one that says you know I'm gonna look at
one specific byte you know what if what
if the malware has a malware mutation
right so you're adding extra fields to
it you know changing offset values so
not signatures you know no longer good
you have to go you'll get a database
update so I think you know a lot of
cases the signatures are only as good as
what your signature database contains
within it in addition you're essentially
building a black list rather than white
list so you know you get the signature
database Oh someone's gonna change
we know one byte value or maybe one
offset oh we need to get a new signature
so it's this sort of constant iterative
process we're just trying to build up
this this big black list so it's not
it's not really practical you know in
the in the ICS world you know maybe in
the IT IT world it's kind of makes more
sense and obviously you don't want to
have an internet connection from your
your plant out to the world to be
getting these these signatures back to
your device so the only place that I
really see this may be being useful is
proprietary protocols where you can't
get the RFC you know hopefully we can do
something maybe you can reverse-engineer
the protocol a little bit you know build
up some signature tack
we mitigate these attacks but you know
if you're gonna do something you're
gonna write your own deep packet
inspection module you might as well make
it the best it can be so there's there's
obviously better ways to go about doing
this so just in general you know depth
is more important than prep because you
know if you're looking at one packet or
one byte in a specific packet well you
know are you really supporting that
protocol it just doesn't really make
sense so we really need to sort of get
the fluff or the marketing flood out of
there you know we support 500 protocols
well well you know what does that really
mean how deep is it
you know how secure is your network by
using these you know signature based
systems ok so moving on to sanity
checking so what I've done is kind of
come up with specific things to look at
you know in each in each product so
sanity checking for me is like it's kind
of the gold standard this is this is the
most important thing you know it can
help you mitigate you know 80 to 90% of
those vulnerabilities out there so to
build this what do you need to know well
you need to really know the protocol
inside note you need to get the RFC you
know you need to understand you know if
I have some length field and some
Ethernet IP frame you know what does
that mean on a specific sip service or
sip object or you know for a Modbus
frame what does this really mean so you
know you're speaking about you know
Goose you know there's type length value
field so you need to be able to actually
iterate through these frames and
actually look at you know what it means
what's this action so unlike some
signature based approach you really need
sort of this this all-knowing you know
full protocol implementation and that's
what the whole point of sanity checking
is so this is kind of my comparison item
number one so so if a product is gonna
claim that it can do sanity checking
that means it has to actually understand
the whole protocol so it's looking at
every single frame it's looking at all
the bytes you know obviously there's
some trade-offs you don't want to incur
too much latency for things like you
know goofs you know so when you're
developing these things and hopefully
you know companies that are building
these things are getting the RFC's
they're really understanding what
the protocol means so I think so for me
as far as a grading scheme is concerned
this is like your your number one
comparison item so then I went to the
next thing okay so we talked about this
control plane data plane how do how do
we actually go about differentiating
these so we need to have the way to say
okay you know for Modbus I'm only going
to allow all the reed coils you know I'm
gonna block read/write registers because
it has right capabilities you know with
sip maybe because there's
vulnerabilities in the tcp/ip object so
that's like hex f4 f5 you'd want to just
block those you know once the system set
up you and put your deep packet
inspection engine in there and you're
gonna block any actions to that because
well it's setup you don't want to allow
someone to have the ability to change it
so I kind of call this the action filter
so if you have the ability to also you
know block specific register ranges well
that's kind of bonus points so as we're
kind of thinking of these qualitative
mechanisms we can put numbers to it as I
get further on here so the next thing is
is about state checking of the protocol
so did a response have an initial
request you know did a request have the
specific response and depending on the
protocol you know maybe there's like in
DMV threes case you might have these
asynchronous events coming back so if
you have some engine in there it needs
to understand this you know if you're
thinking about like dce/rpc stuff like
OPC you know on 135 it has these color
IDs so a request has a call idea of one
the response has one so you need to
actually be matching you know the
request response so that someone can't
just be sending a whole slew of these of
these frames and maybe extra training
data as an example so I turned this
state checking so you're checking the
state of the protocol itself so the next
thing is about response packet
validation so to what extent are you
actually looking at these response
messages coming back so this is
important because you know ad mccrane
Kristin Strunk published some dnp3
vulnerabilities probably a few years ago
and a lot of them are actually attacks
in the response direction against the
HMI so you
p3 is widely used in the power
transmission distribution so they have
you know these substations or
outstations sitting miles away from the
actual you know plant the plant
operators so if someone were to actually
gain physical access to these out
stations they could you know modify the
plc send back invalid data to the plant
and you know corrupt HMI or feet at
false data and actually the plants you
know now down no one has any idea so
this is I call response validation and
then there's the vendor specific stuff
so this I'd kind of mentioned this
earlier so you have these you know
vendor specific functions like this
function code 90 from Schneider you know
this far as Ethernet IP they also have
their own sip specific codes you know
bender you know hex 300 no rock walls PC
cube CSP v4 so it's all these kind of
you know unpublished well published
internally but not published out to the
world but you know for for a dpi engine
to really support these things I think
it's important and you know if you use
these protocols and your network you're
probably gonna want your dpi engine to
actually be able to interpret these
these frame types so then I have this
kind of a cool and Eric Eric Byers and I
kind of turn this pipeline messages so
we first looked at this in Modbus so
what you could have is you know if you
think of like CPUs give it your whole
you know up cope the pipeline so this is
the same way so you have you you know a
Modbus function code read you pad it
with a Modbus function code right you
can put this in a whole sequence or in
the case of like Ethernet IP with you
know these multiple service packets well
you have this lookup table within the
frame itself and then you could just pad
you know all these frames in it you know
just hi to read and write and then maybe
another read and so on and you know with
dnp3 it'll pad all these d3 objects in
there so if your actual engine doesn't
iterate through every single object how
can you guarantee that someone has an
embed it's something you know within the
frames along the way so that's my
comparison item number six so you know
there's six items obviously you know
this is just
sort of a template you could expand it
as much as you want you know it's it's
really up to you so we have these
qualitative things that I've kind of
described and then I've you know this is
kind of some fake product just come up
with some specific values so then you
have some some numbers here so on its
own maybe it doesn't make sense but say
you have two products you kind of go
through this the same scheme you can
actually compare against the two of them
you know maybe 66% it's not great but
maybe it's better than the 40% of the
other product does you know based on how
you want to value the product itself so
how do I actually come about these or
how did I come to these values you know
what really constitutes you know a four
for sanity checking or really any any
value for that matter so this this is
kind of the harder the harder part
because it's a bit subjective you know
so for me and like how we've kind of
implemented things or how I'd gone about
doing this is well heck I'm gonna do
everything right you know it's a
thousand pages of a spec well I have to
cover it otherwise how do I claim that I
actually cover the protocol you can't
write so you know in this case for
sanity checking you know if six would be
you cover everything completely but a
four as you know for this Modbus
function code 15 you know maybe you're
only looking at you know two bytes worth
or maybe three bytes and you say well it
doesn't really matter you know what
could someone to do with this although I
don't think that's the greatest approach
but the reality is you know when you're
developing these things you know there's
obviously time involved resources all
that stuff so so when you're looking at
products you know you could come up with
specific values for this and then for
the action filter so this is the same
kind of idea so I went through the
things that I thought were the most
important of what a dpi engine should do
and I kind of came up with these with
these values so in the case of this
action filter so this is like you know
I'm gonna differentiate between control
plane and data plane actions I'm gonna
drop these specific function codes type
codes depending on the term is for the
protocol um so I think dnp3 is a great
example for this because there's so many
different things you can filter on so it
has you know the data link layer
transport layer application layer so the
application layer has these
function function codes so like your
select direct operate that kind of stuff
and then embedded in the actual the
object level or the dnp3 objects now you
have group number variation function
code qualifier code so if your product
can actually allow you to granulator
granularly filter on all these things
well then you know to me that's that's a
four and you know you could expand this
sort of grading scheme how you want you
could go to decimals if you want you
know I just chose sort of whole numbers
but you know if it can do pretty much
everything then maybe give it a 3.5 I
mean in the end it's really you know the
customer that you're trying to figure
out you know what do I really need here
so then as I was sort of going through
this there's a lot of things that
started popping into my mind about doing
this so how do you really gauge depth
it's if you know like I know the taffy
nose case I've written the code so I
kind of know you know how everything is
built but I have no idea how the next
vendor has done it so it's really hard
to be getting this information you know
other than you know making your own sort
of pen testing tool you know these are
the things I care about put this device
in there as a black box and send these
packets and try to detect this obviously
the numbers are a bit subjective it's
really up to you how you would go about
sort of building this and then also how
it's actually been built so you know
maybe it's a signature based system you
know maybe it's a full protocol
implementation you know maybe there's a
proxy involved or maybe you're feeding
data to some other system so you have to
kind of take these things into account
when you're doing this and then thinking
about protocols well maybe some company
did a really great job developing some
DPI engine for Modbus but their dpi
engine for dnp3 is awful you know so you
can't just say well this products great
I've looked at one protocol I'm gonna
use three of them you know so you have
to really you know take all these these
factors into account so and as I
mentioned earlier you know when I built
this this scheme it's like okay well
what is 14 of 21 mean is that really
good so you have to kind of compare
multiple products so I think it would
make more sense from a customer's
perspective they would kind of go
through these things so some of the
other things that I was kind of thinking
about is you know we have this dpi
engine built somebody has to actually
use it so if it's not usable to a
customer you know they're not gonna
understand well this is a Modbus
function code six it does these specific
things or you know this is an Ethernet
command
it's send our data what does it mean you
know these are things that you know
probably we take for granted because
we're gonna spend the time and look at
this stuff but the reality is if it's
not usable for a customer it's not
usable and then there's things like so
in the case of you know Tofino where
intrusion prevention so we're gonna drop
these frames we're not gonna you know
we'll alert that kind of stuff so you
know is it useful to send these TCP
resets to either side you know restart
the session you know generate messages
does this product do this does you know
this product do this so these are some
things to kind of keep in mind and then
you know throughput and latency I didn't
even mention this in here depending on
what protocol you're gonna try to
actually protect you know maybe it you
have these high latency requirements
maybe it's some proprietary protocol
that it really matters you know how fast
you can be interpreting this data you
know you also should think about how
many network streams are going through
the device
you know how fast can we do these things
and then yeah not all dpi
implementations are created equal so you
know for one protocol it might be great
the next protocol it might not be so
great so this is my plug so obviously
Tofino was kind of my baby so so
essentially this is you know Industrial
Security appliance it was built always
for the ICS world we didn't come from
the IT world and move into ICS you know
security was always something that has
always been you know on the forefront so
we have this idea of these little
security modules so if you bought the
product you're only gonna you know use
specific protocols that you care about
so just as an aside so for this dnp3
implementation so when we develop this
you know we have the ability that we can
actually filter on all those things that
I was talking about earlier so you can
do the application layer function code
filtering you can look at all your group
number variation function code qualifier
code all that fun stuff so it's as I'd
call it like a full protocol and
tation and this is some buildin slide so
this is about bringing together the OT
and IT so I guess 2015 Belden bought
tripwire so for the OT side where you
know Tofino Hirshman Garrett calm
it was pro soft and then tripwire on the
trip wire side we're kind of IT so we're
trying to bring together these these
companies so we can you know come
together which is what Dale's sort of
mantra was for this cool so any
questions so first a comment and then a
question the comment is woe to him I see
CP is you've had experience with that
that you could comment on that actually
you know I've been asked but I to be
honest I haven't really looked at that
protocol yeah well we could talk about
it over beer
yes stage later but I'm wondering had
you thought about normalizing this I
like what you've done I'm a classically
trained systems engineer so this is a
true pure trade study right the trade
off study but you haven't normalized the
data that have you thought about
allowing a customer who's creating an
RFP and doing an evaluation to wait the
different pieces so that you can
normalize it because some people may
care more about one quality versus
another have you thought about adding
that to your yeah well I was kind of
trying to touch on one of my points was
just about okay you know obviously
proprietary protocols or vendor specific
ones you know for them they're gonna
care that your implementation for dnp3
is good versus Modbus if they don't even
use so yeah I mean that's that's a great
point so my hope from this was that you
know we can really like as an ICS
community come up with some way to kind
of gay
this stuff I mean obviously foreign
business stands for competitors but the
end goal here is we want to protect
these industrial control systems and
really we should all be trying to make
the best software we can so that's kind
of my my hope for that other questions
there's one in the back
Thanks so I'm curious let's your to my
Modbus so it's clear that you could have
a capability to say for example block
Modbus right register 100 you know
certain ranges 100 to 200 yeah so that's
fine but what if what what's your answer
if I'm like a process control engineer
and I don't want to think about Modbus I
want to think about this is a pressure
vessel and I don't want it to go over
600 degrees how do i express that one of
your rules right so I mean it really
translates down to you know on the wire
you're gonna see it as some Modbus
commands some function he's gonna
represent it maybe as a tag or some
other reference so kanata fee knows case
we have this idea of test modes so what
you do is you put in test mode run all
your commands get a syslog message or an
event message saying you know it's it's
it's blocked this specific Modbus
function code this address range and
then they would go about creating rules
for that
so it'll permit it in test mode when you
move to operational you have these rules
built
however it's not going to correlate you
know this is me looking at this pressure
valve oh this is Modbus function code X
so if I bought the pressure vessel from
GE I would want them to give me the
Tofino rules so that when I'm when I'm
working on a management console I can
say temperature range as opposed to
Modbus functions which I don't ever want
to look at ya know that's I mean that's
a good point