[Music]
to the s4 mainstage Dale Peterson of
Digital bond so the title of my talk is
the simple solution to securing ICS in
an IOT world and I was tempted to just
say don't connect them and drop the mic
and walk offstage who's that yeah but I
had to fill some time so no so I that
would be fighting the future we know
that our ICS at least some of them are
and I would argue most of them will be
connected to external devices to cloud
services and other things and and how
are we going to do that and how are we
going to get in front of this challenge
I think one of the problems we have and
we need to get our heads around is the
terminology because terminology can be
helpful and unhelpful a real good
example of this is is Joe Weiss who I
like to call the Paul Revere of our ICS
security community because last decade
he was a guy you know we have a problem
we have a problem he did tremendous work
on awareness but he likes to point to
the NIST definition of a cyber incident
that says not only is a cyber incident
when someone attacks your system or you
get malware on your system but if for
example you reprogrammed your PLC
database and didn't scan it and it
caused a problem or you miss configure
to switch it's a cyber incident anything
that is happening over a communication
channel on an ICS that causes a problem
fits in this cyber incident category and
in a sense he's right I don't disagree
with that but then when we make that
term that global and that encompasses it
tends to be less useful to us and what
you really need underneath that is a
taxonomy of types of cyber incidents so
we can begin to decide how to protect
against them
and I think the same thing has happened
to us with the industrial Internet of
Things or whatever you want to call it
industrial internet industry 4.0 we have
basically included anything that could
possibly do monitoring and control in
this definition I was at the AARC event
in Orlando I guess it was about three
years ago when they first began using
this term and I'd go to a talk from an
asset owner who had a very traditional
SCADA system that had been deployed
eight years ago and they were calling it
IIT you know and what is your i io t
strategy and every dcs was that and and
eventually I talked to Sid who does some
of the cybersecurity work for a RC and I
asked him flat out I said are you saying
that I IOT is everything that we called
ICS plus everything new and and the
answer was yes so it has this same
problem where it is just all
encompassing and so if we ask the
question how are we going to secure a
IOT or industrial internet it's very
difficult to come up with a useful
answer and I'd even take it a step
further I'd say when we look at how are
we going to secure our ICS we have a
tendency to look at them to
monolithically so for example everyone
tends to jump to the most dramatic case
the nuclear power plant or something
that if it's out for a minute could cost
tremendous amount of money great
inconvenience affect the economy or the
environment we tend to jump to this and
and certainly it's important that we
secure the nuclear power plant but the
way we secure that nuclear power plant
is probably very different than the way
we secure a chewing gum factory a
factory like this maybe runs two
eight-hour shifts Monday through Friday
and a one shift on Saturday and if
they're down for seven days it's not
that big of a deal now they're not gonna
be happy about it but they just run
three shifts till they catch up and they
produce their product
so securing this is going to be very
different than securing a nuclear power
plant and then if we look even at a
different I guess dimension think about
all the small ICS we have this is a
small municipal water system and in this
example they have two people in their IT
department and that those two people are
responsible for the email server the
printers the VP's laptop that's
constantly breaking and the SCADA system
okay so they have really no chance of
doing a good job with their ICS security
policy so we have a lot of different
conditions but for this talk today I
want to focus on I want to use the term
that most of us have lived with for the
last three to five years ICS to mean
traditional DCs SCADA PLC based control
and tackle what is a simple solution for
connecting these ICS to external devices
in the example I'm going to use most is
the cloud so how do we take advantages
of these services while still protecting
our ICS before I mentioned when we talk
about ICS we tend to jump to the worst
most dramatic conclusion like a nuclear
power plant when we talk about things
like cloud services we tend to jump to
the easiest one to secure and the one
you hear most often is this idea of
predictive maintenance or efficiency
studies so the idea is you you have your
ICS it's creating all this data you send
it out to this third party vendor or
probably your ICS vendor or somebody who
knows the industry they crunch the data
and they say oh you know you were
supposed to do this maintenance at six
months but it's been dirty or you need
to do it at three months to prevent
downtime or if you change this setting
you will generate more power and this is
really a tremendous service this is
something that asset owners like because
it allows them
to have less downtime and more
efficiency and of course the vendors
like it because they can make money from
this service and this is a real easy one
to secure I'm sure you've seen a lot of
you have seen this if you need the data
out in the cloud or wherever you want to
send it you can just send it through a
one-way device and that way they have
the data they can offer the service but
you don't put the availability or
integrity of your ICS at risk so this
one is really simple and a lot of times
people jump to this but what we're
finding and these are anonymized
conversations that we've had over the
last couple of years is they really want
to do more than predictive maintenance
so in this case our the the client was
the asset owner and they wanted this
predictive maintenance service and the
vendor says well we need to access this
server on your ICS to get the data you
say well no we don't want to let you
into our system we'll send you the data
through one of these one-way devices
vendor you know repeats no no we have to
get the data we send the data this goes
back and forth back and forth literally
in the example I'm thinking of it was
over 10 calls in over one year before
they finally agreed that we could send
them the data and it just seemed really
strange but then you look at the shoe on
the other foot so in this case the
vendor was a client the vendor who
wanted to provide this predictive
maintenance service was a client and
they said hey we want to offer this
service but we know we're gonna be asked
a security question so how do we have a
great answer when they say will our ICS
or our underlying process be at risk by
getting this predictive maintenance
service no problem you know we can have
a variety of tiered options and the most
secure option for your most
security-conscious clients would be one
of these one-way devices we can
guarantee them that we can provide the
service and we will not be able to get
on their network so we will not be the
source of an attack and then you get to
the truth
the vendors say well we have visions for
the future where we want to do a lot
more than just predictive maintenance
where we actually want to be able to
access the ICS so they don't want to put
in this capability that restricts them
from offering future services and and my
my guess you know I heard rumblings in
the organization's but when we were
representing the asset owner the same
was thing was true the vendor wanted to
provide additional services and so I
think what we're going to find in action
it's happening today is vendors will
want to provide a variety of services
much beyond predictive maintenance
including things like remote operations
remote engineers almost right in some
cases running almost everything remotely
and there are going to be cases and I
think the industry is under estimating
the number of them but there are going
to be many cases where it makes
financial sense for the owner operator
to take advantage of those services
either because they can do it with
acceptable risk or they're not doing a
good job on their own
so we need to come up with a way of
dealing with this and my simple solution
is four steps the first step is probably
the hardest in the most important there
needs to be a definition the vendor has
to define in this case let's say the
cloud service provider needs to
specifically define the set of services
they are willing to offer remotely from
the cloud to the owner operator and this
has to be a very granular definition the
owner operator needs to understand what
would be the impact if that cloud
service provider was compromised so if
he was able to do all the things that I
want to allow him to do what would be
the impact to my system and they need to
be able to live with that now this does
not mean that you you you don't look at
the security of your service provider he
should be following best practices you
should be getting the certification
Haitians and in fact it's it's a little
bit scary because we're seeing a number
of vendors in this industry not learn
the lessons of what's already been done
they're basically creating these
services and trying to figure out what
is the appropriate way to secure them
rather than taking what has already been
developed and proven but even with a
vendor providing good cloud services you
have to assume that they're going to be
compromised and then what could do what
are you going to allow them to do to
your system so for example you could
allow them to operate but not change the
logic or program you could allow them to
operate part of your plant you could
allow them to write to certain function
call or write to certain registers so
turn certain things on and off or change
certain settings but not others again
you're getting down to that level of
granularity I put request Diagnostics on
there they're just almost as a as a
counterexample this would be something
that could be pushed out but if you are
going to allow the cloud service
provider access into your system then
the value of deploying a separate
unidirectional gateway or one-way system
or data diode whatever you want to call
it is much less so as soon as you're
allowing the cloud service provider
access into your system you might as
well Lao whatever you're going to permit
based on this agreement now I want to
take just a slight detour from my four
steps to talk about I think a really
exciting field and I think the the next
talk on the cyber PHA is really
applicable to this you know if we think
that we have agreed with our cloud
service provider that they can do these
things remotely into our system if a bad
guy is able to do these things they will
be able to have some level of impact
today one thing we could do to allow
remote services is relook at well is
there some safety control is there some
way we can change our control logics so
if
the bad guy gets into the cloud and if
he runs these commands the consequences
are lower so we can actually be re
looking at our safety and our protection
philosophies to reduce risk for remote
operations I mean this could be
deploying non cyber safety mechanisms to
prevent bad things from happening
it could be processed based for example
maybe you'll allow them to run this
critical command but there's a physical
switch in your plant that you have to
flip before that command will be
actually actionable so I think this is
this is a real good area where if you're
going to want someone to do remote
services you're going to have to go back
and look at your safety philosophy and
and I would point you to Ralph langner's
presentation at last year's s4 where it
shows a real good example of modifying
safety the way we look at safety for a
nuclear feed water system so you may be
able to extend what you think is
possible with remote services or cloud
services if you adjust that okay so step
one define cloud service provider a
Sedona specifically what you're going to
allow them to do number two then is to
find a way to enforce that so you're
going to need a security perimeter
device that restricts them to these
pre-approved items now the good news is
I'm sure a lot of you saw this if you
walked around the Cabana sessions
yesterday and we have even more vendors
as attendees anomaly detection gateway
devices with deep packet inspection for
ICS is a very quick growing a very
competitive field with lots of options
out there so having something like this
should not be difficult it would require
the the cloud service provider to
partner with one of these vendors and
say okay here's what we want here's the
let's say the menu that we want them to
be able to choose from and when they
choose this mem this menu item we need
to be
able to enforce it in your device this
also might be a great area for
certification testing because once
you've once you've defined what's
allowed through what should be allowed
through put a device in place to enforce
that then steps three and four are
really just making sure it works so step
three would be making sure the perimeter
security device works properly and
hopefully this would not be something
that each asset owner would have to do
ideally this would be something that the
vendor would be able to say hey we we've
done this testing here you can look at
the test reports the system actually
works and and most asset owners might be
willing to accept that of course you can
test it if you have your own doubts and
then number four is a little bit
different and this is a number four is a
little bit like fuzzing the idea is
you've agreed to allow this
communication through your security
perimeter from let's say a potentially
compromised site out on the internet or
in the cloud somewhere if that allowed
traffic is allowed to reach a PLC or an
engineering workstation or whatever you
choose will that cause a negative action
let's say an unexpected action on that
server of course if you allow them to
send a command through that command is
going to be activated but this is really
similar to fuzz testing and the nice
thing about this is if we've defined the
hole in our security perimeter tightly
then this testing doesn't have the code
coverage problem that fuzz testing has
we should be able to actually test the
entire amount of what is allowed through
the security perimeter and validate that
it for example doesn't cause the end
device to crash so this is this is my my
four-step simple solution it's and in
the first step again it's the most
important the vendors needs to say these
are the remote services we offer the
asset owner needs to say yes I will
accept these services and and they're
well-defined
you put a security perimeter device in
place that restricts the cloud service
provider
to those services and the asset owner
understands the impact if that cloud
service provider is compromised and is
willing to accept it and then steps
three and four verify that the thing
actually works and those services will
not damage your system to an
unacceptable level now my fear is that
the ICS community we have we have a bad
history of opening Pandora's Box without
understanding the implications of it if
you think back to the 90s when we
started connecting corporate networks to
ICS we connected everything up and then
later on we decided we needed to start
worrying about how to secure it we bring
windows in and then we start to worry
about how to secure it I mean we're
seeing this with virtualization all
sorts of technologies the the key thing
for us here is that we don't for example
start allowing a cloud service provider
unrestricted access to our ICS at the
beginning because it's very difficult to
pull that back at the end this is
something that we need to get in front
of and I'm hoping that this will give
you some ideas with your projects on how
to take advantage of these these great
new services that are being offered at a
risk level that's acceptable to you
thank you very much
you