I K kid and slam know any
individualize anything so I'll just sum
it up never let me be screened by me
I'm so i wanna talk about really is
kinda taking a a hacker race approach to
mathematical discovery while I E
you should and how you can a
with an example from something I did
recently I don't know how long it's
gonna take me i've been prepared based
right Bahraini but something sometime in
the
reason kinda five to 10 minutes but
probably I am
so why you should well first we'll
I mean maybe not everyone agrees with a
spot
I think discovering new mathematical
things is one that the mice
radium things that you can do a because
for a brief period you know something
that nobody else know
is and that is a I think
a very exciting thing is not as
inaccessible as you might think there
are lots of things
that can be discovered that you don't
need to come to spend
years and years studying to get to the
point where you can understand them and
start to think about them
and some of them are are relatively
accessible to being
saw the course having discovered
something you can resist the urge to
to tell people about it so that kinda
private knowledge doesn't last very long
and other people aren't nearly as
interested usually as you are because it
causes more fun to have
this goes on yourself in the head by
something that someone else is
discovered
I am butts I'm the other thing is that
in a pure mathematicians as a whole
they're kinda chalking blackboard kinda
people right pencil and paper
I'm it's a pretty old school profession
on the whole I mean
you know they they do use the more
applied mathematicians use software and
it's starting to creep in a little bit
too
I'm so the more kinda traditional pure
mathematical well but it's
still really in a pure mathematicians
are mostly
not hackers and Packers amaze the
speaking of you might have my conditions
and my kinda creates opportunities right
there are certain kinds of problems
the a much more just a baller a ball to
us or to pack his approach than two
into a pencil and paper approach
into nitrates opportunities people like
us to discover things that the feeling
petitions might have missed with their
with their blackboards I so you
I mean the particular example I have in
mind is something I did
kinda recently like in the last couple
weeks it was
them I was a problem that I E I say
it's a problem I heard about it already
its and as far as I know
the the best kind of theoretical results
on this problem
prior to this was at the proof was
written by an anonymous user on 4chan
say
is very atypical for mathematical proof
that the unique in my not in my
experience for mathematical great
I'm and the problem is the following one
so
I am ambulances lie I'd now like fire
engines they gave me know Nino Nino
I'm going me know all around the going
on me I'm
was piping and i doing by I
and so what's the shorter sequences
knees in orders that you need in order
to get both possibilities in their
ni no ni that you got it got me know the
first day
knowing the the second that that by the
possibilities are in there
okay but fire engines you know I died
I'm not an expert on sirens maybe
someone here is Lincoln
tell me more details about sirens but
them I you know when you hear sirens
going off on the streets in london
is not just needs no was all kinds live
Wiggles into
the another signs save I mean suppose
there were three signs up on the can
make me know a wearable
I am then withdraw more possible
permutations that he got
like a bear with me Nino level
as one of them I me we will know law
some but say should be six save his life
nor on the way below
Norway will need with only naw
we will know 18 right six possibilities
Sunday
I am
so wat is the shortest
kinda sequence any the normal way both
at the firings and complain that will
get
all those possibilities in there
somewhere I am
so I know the answer to this I'll see if
I can do it
I am and I think about this for a second
Nino away baloney
nor need we were able nor on me rice I
i'm
safety think about thank you I
say I mean if you if you if you think
about that you'll you'll see that all
that
every see all 6 possibilities have been
included in there somewhere
but there are any nine sounds in that
sequence I'm so
it's more efficient than just doing all
that 6 possibilities
one by one I'm you see you've saved some
effort
and that there's a there's a cleanup
algorithm that you can use to construct
this
kinda sequence a different number thus
and so simple permutations with my
ill-considered title I'm because someone
in about nineteen ninety-three decided
that see permutations what they want to
the call the sequences
because may contain all the possible
permutations
so they're like super because they
contain the mall I guess is the idea
like a superset
I am side anyway so
that you can concise implementations and
it turns out bats
but or symbols I'm not gonna attempt
today that s
I'm sorry I didn't think about it but I
need to practice law small I have today
before symbols
I am it is this was 24 plus
9 it must be 3333 sounds long is the
shorter sequencer find signs that
contains all the possibilities
and in general the construction guys it
goes
delayed by what factorial is I K
I'm so it's it's a summer factorial safe
but
save us for five signs it will be one
factorial plus two factorial plus three
factorial pass for factorial
plus five fights Oreo
and until about the spring of this year
it was all know whether this
kinda but say point if you do one point
to a possible do with me
but up to five factorial the answer is
I'm and so you can construct a sequence
of 153
II with the five signs be it would be
like Kat de Remy
last side is that right if they were it
was maybe more a musical
kinda fire engine than the traditional
ones I am
so that they will be at the second 253
dire a mother
Bob the I'm the the
there's a probe as I say that the only
written version is proven I'm aware of
was written by anonymous 4chan user
I which proves that's the shortest
possible sequence
I'm would be 152 sounds long say there
was this kinda unknown question
was the 152 or 253 the sources 1-for-5
signs
and a bloke who whose day job is
designing processes but
in celeb who obviously is a mathematical
hobbyist
write a C++ program that user relatively
clever
kinda technique T will find out all the
possible
and shorter firsts five simple things
and anyway but the answer is
153 is the shortest but the eight
different ways of doing it and not just
the obvious way
I am Sunday
then I have time ne three-minute pop 80
K
said the fungal the traveling salesman
problem I
serve as a salesman who has to travel
and to laws in different cities to sell
his
on underwear to all the people have
these different cities
and he was do this in the most efficient
way possible so he wants the route that
has take the shortest distance the
visits all the cities
and then returns to where he started and
a.m. so although maybe it's no obvious
this particular problem is kinda the
same problem really
because your cities although different
permutations
I'm going to the rate is the number of
difference and
that you had to do to make the next one
I
say you want to make all the difference
all the different permutations
by the shortest possible route so
basically it this
is an instance of the Traveling Salesman
Problem and it also turns I'm that very
very smart people
have been working out will have ways to
solve the traveling salesman from
ever since some guys a rand corporation
in the nineteen fifties first kinda
started typing this
and it's really really well study in
there are really really fucking good
algorithms for doing it with you can
download for free
and they have a competition every year
to see which ones the best
I and so so the quest for proper sex
symbols was totally unknown
bike I kind of noticed thats it was the
same as the traveling salesman problem
so I downloaded up right ankle LKH
which mine solutions the traveling
salesman problem I am
and on a in a way to it input syntax and
at this thing into and I left it running
overnight and then
when I wake up the next morning it had
disprove this
hit disprove this 20-year-old conjecture
that
the sort of thing for sex symbols would
be 673 symbols long
was the conjecture I think if you if you
add it up I
but is not rape is not true at all is
well that 672 symbols long
I had gone undiscovered for twenty years
but I see you can discover in one night
just by kinda but reading the manual for
a
c:\program and leaving it running home
health aides I am
so that's really the end to the story
thanks
the
anyone every question who will be cool
uploaded a
cut three page paper to the archive yet
not technically published but get enough
money
I
up Obama to back
to like who stop by the fullest up a
little
you
sorry
I D died it's amazing edits to the
online encyclopedia means two sequences
yes can say that there is a sequence
related to this problem
which said that it was connected to be
equal to these other sequence which is
the sum
all but factorial zone I submitted my
edits a
saying it was connected to be good that
sequence but actually isn't
and included a reference to that to my
thing at who and Bama question at the
back
I'm I can say that yeah I left it
running for a few days but it didn't
really seem to be any
anywhere even close to the conjectured
band so I think some
more intelligent approach is likely to
be needed disperse have been
as far as I can sale but the other thing
that's unknown is what the actual
minimum is for six
so I'm the program the uses a heuristics
already searches for solutions but it
doesn't prove that their minimal
I I tried an exact solver that proves
that the solutions manual it ran for a
week and then crashed
a so I we I so don't know the answer to
that
go thank you program run out time
so cold