GB USB stick or should I just walk
sometimes I do love softer magic
so I guess I'm going to talk about
software defined radio
I whose her to suffer defined radio okay
this may be born this may not be we'll
see I
what is it why should you care and the
really simple thing about it is
I yes hi I'm interesting up my name's
Derek by the way
I so to radio in which most to the
functions are moved from hardware into
software
and if there's one thing that we know
about hardware there was expectedly
outlined in the talk about the badges
Harbor takes a long time to develop and
want to develop that you really don't
wanna change it
because it's expensive and all that
softer on the other hand
each recompiling you like oh you know I
felt that I'm gonna change is constant
recompile and run again and so when
you've defined the radio that way that
means you can just
download a new modulation scheme and
start instantly transmitting
or receiving a and what that means is
this a lot apps
are free software out there that can do
this there's a lot of other things
i commercial sweet stuff like that and
yet basically this is an example of a
radio frequency coming in
and in hardware you have to actually
build up the capacitors build-out
are all the stuff to be modulated in
software some the streets
ike specially can you read his block
diagram Cheick
I one FM receiver like drag run awesome
arm sis this is
you know the 101 so signals you have
analog signals which is what
the actual entire world is any need to
convert them into digital
because you computer unfortunately
doesn't store analog values
so an analog signals to find for all
possible times and his street time
signal is only defined for certain
usually regular intervals and what this
ends up looking like
is have a continuous thing coming in and
you sample
see your sampling rate is one of those
critical you know things when you're
looking at a softer defined radio
you end up with a whole bunch of
different sample values and
there's a whole bunch it so you have
these values and now you have to figure
out
what was the original signal that this
represents and see you
for each time stamp give a value and the
more bits
the you have in your analog to digital
converter the better the resolution that
you get
the better that you can figure out what
the original signal was
so you know more bits better is to take
away from the slide
and who comply connect the dots
what we got here to shout it out sine
wave
looks pretty obvious right it's going to
be that 08 but it could be that
and it could be that so
this is called aliasing and you have to
sample at least twice as fast as what
you're expecting to receive
on and so what this comes down do is
generally what they do is they put in a
great big filter that enforces this rule
and not wait you're no longer having to
his government might be it might not be
you know that way you're receiving is
psych going to obey this law
and so this means you have to be
sampling fast enough to receive whatever
signal you're interested in
and her voice this is usually about 1.6
kill her tits
arm if you're transmitting like beer
when the radios
on but it can be quite a bit wider or
can be quite a bit narrower depending on
what are you doing I
Morse code or digital mode or you're
trying to transmit
on you know Ltd for your phone is what
20 megahertz wide I believe at least in
some configurations
this one st art looks like and basically
an antenna
and then there's some mixing so that you
can extract are
lots of information about the signal
accurately get the representation back
getting the amplitude and phase arm and
the frequency
all in one go and filter and the new
convert
analog to digital but some I'd
somebody's St ours
you end up plugging in VN audio cable as
we call this a sound card STR
and you're letting your PC do all the
work so these tend to be a lot cheaper
arm and you get these quite cheaply
online
on yes receiver architectures
II if your radio but you're party
already know this
if you art there's probably no point in
me explains sigh I should confess that I
am remixing a slide deck that I already
had
on so this is what it's actually really
quite cool
you're receiving a whole bunch a bomb FM
radio station so here we turned into 10
I 10 5.3 and you can see
I is a signal here that speaking and
this is what it actually looks
like when you're receiving and FM
broadcast station
now it's quite cool here is you can
actually see it starting to decode
the radioed a year I service stream
service on as you can see it's decoding
the information that normally see
displayed on your car stereo
and that's actually the sidebands here
his role that digital information is
conveyed along
CDC it's very graphical environment its
I very intuitive to work with you can
tune across you can see how big should
be felt s
arm and so many many more radios are
being built
this way out band with some common modes
a priority said
they vary you have to be sampling at
least twice as fast as whatever the band
with
is here arm and this
this is what I want you to all go away
and by it's about 10 pack but ten pounds
fifteen pounds comes with an antenna
and I use plug this straight into your
I'm PC laptop I A
Raspberry Pi has lots of libraries for
dealing with it
and this handles all up the converting I
into digital signals and yet its
regional aid
a TV tuner and as somebody found out
that if you poke the firmware just the
right way with send you the raw stream
I and it receives from about 50
megahertz 22.2 gigahertz
on this varies depending on which exact
model you get some other million go up
and I hit wifi 2.4 gigahertz
I something fun in here I all the cell
bands
our coverage here and while most today
conversations are in cryptid muster the
data streams
I you can pick up a whole bunch of the
signaling stuff and say oh
a new cell phones arrived ur you know
somebody's receiving a call
II and expecially right around camp
right now there's the GSM cell network
and that's actually being run on
software defined radios so
all the GSM work is being done on a
completely
I off-the-shelf computer it's an open
source project called open BTS
Heights you could download this and be
running your own cell service
you should have a license if you doing
this or you can do it in a basement very
very very quiet
like are but go get a license with you
arm or metal shipping container
totally legal if you're in a metal
shipping container arm
to the best of my knowledge I am NOT a
lawyer et cetera to an american
on but arm
it has relatively poor performance but
honestly for fifteen pounds
who cares on you can actually receive
GPS
I don't know how I don't know why magic
lots have magic on but FM AM radios
on pagers so if you're near a hospital
or something you can actually read
pagers or near some business which
stories pagers on ATVs
is what airplanes used to report their
location so if you're near an airport
or just have airplanes flying over you
can actually
r load up a free piece of software and
trace the plane's
flying over you arm what's a good fun
our weather balloons like they've been
launching
you can track using this I satellites
yes you should gone by wannabes they're
a lot of fun
and yet like three coffees cell go do it
I this is the expensive version
it's like six hundred dollars 400 pounds
I or more add by very very flexible
much higher quality and you can digitize
lots
stuff but once he could be receiving 30
40 50 different
voice conversation conversations
simultaneously
if your computer or support it and
and some card interface if you Rd
animate radio person already have a
scanner
you can often just connect arm an audio
cable from this
to your computer and get started with
the software I think
yes software on if you type in
SDR software defined radio software
it'll just
pull up this list for you also see if I
get that I
they'd get the slide posted somewhere on
the wiki or something
um but these are all free I and they're
kinda going
STR sharp is about the simplest when you
can download it does run cross platform
I don't know about Mac but on me
%ah
interesting I am on OSX
explicitly don't yeah
I well grab on the older versions then
they it does work fine I STR console
is really nice a me that might be
Windows and Mac only
on HD STR is fully open source
as is STR sharp actually arm sounds like
something really bad happened recently
I get new radios open source and its
cross-platform
and it's actually the most powerful one
arm and that's what a lot
universities use a research out but you
can use downloaded
and there are reasonable guides online
which
I think I have coming up next I it's so
this is what
any radio I looks like when you download
the graphical companion
and you can see we have a signal source
coming in and we filter it
and we look at an FFT which I think I
is just the way form that we are seeing
before showing intensity
I over frequency low-pass filtered again
stempel squelch so that we don't hear
just shy
all the time on do a
narrowband FM receive and
output out to the sound card and you can
receive
FM radio I and so again that's
yeah says that looks like and this is
the FFT
down here siege get the nice output and
you're listening to radio
on it looks complicated but
you can use it with one these tiny
little fifteen-pound tuners
it's a great way to get started arm and
you listen to all sorts of things
on YouTube videos yes there are lots of
YouTube videos
on covering the new radio covering
the RTL STR tuner which is the little
cheap dinner
arm what's resources online and its
just going to get bigger and bigger and
bigger because hardware is expensive to
modify
software is cheaper to modify arm ships
yes more resources after getting started
with iight signal processing
so if the concept of discrete-time and
continuous-time signals completely new
to you
I these top two web sites completely
explain it I
is a free text book on digital signal
processing arm
and and this is a dead pit a dead tree
book
on but I its excellent
you can pick up used copies very cheaply
and it's good fun
I thank you very much and I hope people
are interested in something find radio
books like that