a Kate so
this is really am kinda screwed so let's
do it
can we all just if you that's on the
screens to stand up companies load space
here
a suck up love it's a video to show and
when the Sun comes out it's very
difficult to say so just come a bit
closer
and a what we actually have here is not
a problem it's an opportunity
to can meet some other people don't
don't don't hang at the back back on
this loads of fun going on down here
that's it just made a little bit closer
okay
no problem alright well and will manage
my own other art will come due in
Braille describe
what's on the screen thanks
a cake in your say can he make a thanks
very much doing that and
apologies for the for the glitch there
so my name starts with L
I I am mad just go talk about
um some stuff that I've done trying to
one project tonight kinda deviated often
found in
wanna to other interesting things that
going on around the house
and just give you and a very I just
wanna kinda setlist set the same here
and on I know no electronics am
and I know no electronics because I'm on
a biologist really
and so I I'd agricultural physiology and
crop protection
and I this %uh the bottom left
picture here on the screen is is kinda
corn growing in poly tunnels that we
check in on
I work with a lot of data to do with
experiments that come out of that so
I really do electronics by any means and
and
the other thing that I've that is
relevant to this at the not
a recently made knowing is I've been
doing some welding
and on the bottom right there again i I
had to come to describe it to you but
it's an
this is a three bottles and beer
which I gave to my neighbor's Sun when
he reached 18 years old but I welded the
mall into a steel case
so the only way he get into it was
trashy take an angle grinder a hacksaw
to it
if he actually wanted a drink appear am
so that it is effect yes a break the
bottle
and its teasingly made to look as if you
can just take the bottle out but
actually
when you try and you you fun at Cardiff
so
the SI my background is that every
inning Electronix and
I just became very interested in the
last reply actually my son don't want
for Christmas is also want to Christmas
I am my son's quite old actually
families 23
a term and I i think is very interesting
but
term a bone upton's a background
understanding why we actually needed to
transfer pilot
with really resonated with me on
different from the generation that
couldn't afford a BBC Micro
but you know did use one use friends
ones in a dealer programming a bits and
pieces with that and I think that
term
yeah i i totally understand his
his statements about or understanding
that the number graduate also
potential graduates are applying for
courses who actually have an
understanding computer sciences declined
in decline declined in the UK
and has been a real shame that's not
necessarily
gonna set as well for the future it's
not really things are gonna build our
computer science capabilities in the UK
and and you know with national
curriculum is being followed
the Excel
thing how to do prayer power point
presentations and has to excel
is not really the thing's gonna push for
the frontiers for us so
I think cam you know that there are two
pies just a brilliant brilliant
a phenomena the that's come about and i
i'd
I never cease to be amazed by these
projects and this
I mean everyone knows this one with
damage the band am
in with a have signed up to describe the
pictures were gonna sit sons come out
but
am I'm to my baggage the bear the the
project to
but the recreates and Felix
Baumgartner's jump from outer space but
using a teddy bear
around 3pi in a total budget three
hundred pounds
whereas sir the nasa budget for Felix
Baumgartner's budget was $30 million
and but you know it's just will rice on
one for the open source crowd to
actually
actually do that and United
the school projects the seats are
occupied I think you're amazing as well
as just really great ideas that they
come up with CAP feeders
pill dispensers lap timers sports
equipment all powered by round trip I
projects so
I found that really interesting and I i
10 do
I'm Chung FAI little things that I can
do around the house among other things
again I'm gonna have to skip to lead the
Suns come as been cloudy only
arms are described to stay on the right
hand side here
in this blank piece if they're screen is
a Paula builders de Bry which has been
dumped
on a byway near our near where I live
and friend mine is the estate manager
for a number farms
around here and this fly-tipping occurs
is Sam
is a real pain is real pain to him
because he he's the land
has to clear all this up and it's a real
pain or city environment this
that poisons and toxins are in there and
some cases as asbestos is left behind
and and in those particular cases that
the local
am authority have to come along clear it
up
but at the landowner is the one who is
mostly responsible for doing that and
them it's a real it's a real pain and
this happens you know as soon as spring
come
people do house clean outs phil has
become a lot more active
and and this occurs an awful lot and
it's a real
a real nuisance um so a
just this is a kind in a pub
conversation often happens that with me
on a Friday night
talking to friends and still couldn't we
do around 3pi projects
to see if we could detect the presence
author fly tippers or perhaps capture an
image or see if we can recognize in some
way
and are unitary authority the where I
come from
what their response to this is that they
will rummage through the day brain if
they can
find a piece of paper or somewhere
identifying the culprits
then the most they will do his rights
the maleta
and say we think you dropped something
would you like to come pick it up
am and that my friend his the local
state managers now part
a National Farm awareness group which
has a local
a local meeting this now chaired by a
cantankerous
and police official whose fail in its
retirement and he's at the opinion if
you just
for me anyway I'm identifying who these
people are election is gonna rest them
which would be a lot more effective than
writing the letter so
with that as background we think will
that could be to apply project that
would help us
try and identify and his light it is our
now I'm just gonna say expectations now
by the into this talk
I'm not going to identified any fly
tippers because this talk is actually
how I got slightly distracted from this
project
doing other things so a.m. but you know
watch this space and it is actually a
little bit of the plagues I have hit a
couple technical difficulties and it has
anyone who knows anyone who can help me
a it would be it would be really helpful
so first off
we figure the if you want to assay way I
think it's me and is anyone is listening
to me
time in our house or the pub I'm it
wants to take the presence is someone
can we just use ordinary PR detectors
connected to the pie
am so on the left-hand side here after a
picture of these
the stand a PR detectors you have as in
burglar alarms
and said your burden on your house is
mine safety in each room
now I managed to get hold native these
of a freecycle upside just
doing my usual scare freecycle looking
for stuff to fill my carriage with a
notice somebody
said they were moving house and they had
a today so I'm
I just grabbed them I R my round pick
them up and I had no idea what I was
going to use them for but
like many things I just happen to have
it had lying around when it came became
useful
so I had some unease and I thought well
that this is good I'll
I'll see if I can just kinda put this up
to the pie and
and detector movements I'm now that they
are the way they actually work is
you have to give them a 12 volt power
supply and I seen as his burglar alarm
systems will run up to
a 12 volt battery so you have to feed a
total
supply and then there's a and open
circuit which you
you can just detect the presence also a
closed-circuit
which you can take the present the
opening of on the pie is in the GPIO
port
so and I'd I'm and I don't program a lot
size is kinda small little python script
something to test this
I'm so I can have Rick this up on a team
was aiight rip the cupboard of love
one in our study covered snow my wife is
very patient with me
I'm but I it gave me a big enough board
to put all the pieces out on so I
screwed all the pieces down like this
and i connect today's these sensors up
to
am some cat five cable and some Ethernet
ports suck it has put them in a run them
out
and that kinda works and so I thought
what I really want to do was tested in a
real situation
am and this was about some and I guess
it must have been about
a beginning October a last year so I
thought what i'll do is i'll see if I
can
detect the presence of children
Halloween coming round the house cuz
Palin's not like it used to be is it
this there's a lot more activity now
so I so will disappear really good
looking to see if I can to take kids and
they put it at but a sound out or
something
so am so this was destruction number one
to what I should I just describe a good
to see you again
so I I haven't had to stroke the scopes
trial
lights which I'd picked up from
somewhere some years ago and I still
wouldn't be good if I could have a turn
those on with a bit have
Thunder as the kids come down the drive
is a
so I am circles have been switching on
240 volts and again this is I know no
electronics I do know you need a kinda
a 240 volt relay so on the bottom left
there had two bills
a 240 volt relay which am another via
the wave
these these works which 240 volts is a
coil which have to activate but I
couldn't find one with the low enough
voltage
for the pie to work I can only find a
fine vol.1 so I had to
by another expansion board called the
pipe
by sup purchase this time a by an
expansion board with a
which I could switch five holes ways and
then I could switch
am the than a kiss it should 12 volts
that was needed for the
for the base relay for this summer's
switching one relates which in other
related to turn on the 240 volts the
stroke so
a so that's what you have to do more
than just turn on the strobe would not
I happen to have a Papillon much ahead
that my daughter and I made many
many years ago with a nivel hanging out
and
so I and my does it did textiles project
once at school and have on these
taylor's
manikins you know Salida you put a dress
on so
I put I thought have that I'll put up at
him as shown on the head
and and then I built this box about this
is kinda small tar the size box here
and site a just build a wooden frame and
then I lined it with black cloth and
then a putter
a a nylon cords a black non goals on the
front and put the manikin inside
strobes inside so its dark when the kids
come along
you know they don't seem to think they
finally get to the door
the Lightning comes on and they see this
body inside not so that's the idea
okay
so that censored number two in the sense
number one just a texan coming down the
driving puts out a scream
so that's actually what I was doing out
on the right hand side here again you
can see is very well in this light
and you can just see the puppy much
ahead but I have to video here
and which we hope in the sound will work
on a
so I'll just say what to look for a with
the light level so
the first thing is that this first PR
sense can you offer should be a cuppa
screams
to hopefully scare them and then if they
make it to the door
somewhere around about some you should
see the strobes cutting
and and the box be eliminated so
let's let's see what happens
said
her
okay so that were a 10 was really ruling
out that we had two lots that ran back
up
the drive as I never your
really upset someone and I in
the only have held to ransom by am much
equities right okay so that was number
one thing
so that was so can we detect presence a
network's and
you know was still a long way from
flight it can at this point
so the next thing was can we am to see
that's
Camry a
get get an image perhaps and I wanted to
try using the pike am now
when I actually started thinking about
the surrounding the or think that pie
can I just been announced so this is the
5-megapixel
camera board for the Raspberry Pi am
so when they first came out it was just
a standard camera
and damn the that the thing was that we
figured most
fly tippers will do stuff at night so
what we really need is is infrared
and the the problem with that is a
well at that time there was also a big
demand for this for in for a pie cams
because I was kinda mean
on the internet people who were taking
the filters often turning them into
infrared cameras kazi it just has a blue
filter over the front
so them so I sighed looking a bit like
the general success rate moles
about 30 percent so mostly they just
naked the cameras so
and one out there is a so I was really
up for doing that is only had one
and and again this was another purchase
II
eugenia try and get stuff for free but
I'm you know if I'd if I can a a try to
avoid purchasing
set but then it turns out that there's
such demand for this that the infrared
pike and came out you can buy the
blackboard which is the
the the the one on the bottom left there
I'm to
to just put into a strange Iran's reply
so I get quite excited at this point is
we may get visual you know
am so connected it all up am now the
software used to this
ago if you've done any am webcam work
with the pie
that the software mostly using his
motion it's it's
its open source is a really good one
called zone minder which is
which is a lot heavier duty and you can
now
you can come describe parts have your
image in get so minded to just monitor
changes in those parts you could do that
to an extent with motion
and promotions pretty good at skylight
way in get up running and you can
you know detect various things happening
with it
so a so that now there is a version of
motion has been
that somebody's knocked up for RAM for
the pike am
at so I had to download that is a as a
four-car I'm guessing they'll remember
july to
am but I a damaged that got that going
that looks pretty
that that was working quite well so now
I'm thinking I need something to detect
detect motion and that's really where we
get the subject at all and that is
am that I thought I would am
on it so it has won a bit before that's
right yeah
again robbers are described what's here
so much if I'm gonna put this outside
date to catch light sabers
it has to be weatherproof it has to have
night vision on issuing an apt infrared
camera
in it had data access and he's be secure
animal people kinda picking up walking
off with their
so this is where the welding comes in so
I am
I'm I made this so
this this is a.m. so this is a standard
army ammunition box you can get these
mommy surplus stores
or and or or on the web about kinda six
to 10 pounds many and what size you get
sigh I thought to put the camp the Paul
II in the camera inside is to drill a
hole in the front
is since mob of actually does am
does class stain glass making she's
really good at cutting glass eye goes to
cut this
this piece for the front his as she
contributed to the project as well
support this matrix this infrared
matrix here to eliminate the area so the
camera comes through that
through the whole here at the front and
you can access it
father by the back and
they're very secure okay so all the bits
and pieces all sit in the back here
the like this now so he's a top tip
other way
these these a really good these boxes
what we use them for geo caching feeding
geo caching a budget catches in them
I'm but that they're its heights a.m.
really water-resistant
so if you welding
something onto one of these and you have
it closed what you've got is a very
highly contained pieces there
which you're then going to heats to 1500
degrees C
and am if you haven't got your visor on
what you get is a global
loan you can easily get as you get a
global steel that comes firing out at
your face
at a very fast rate at Knotts so if you
welding and keep the door open
there learned that the hard way and I so
that's a that's pretty
you know that's all good chunky staff an
Arbil some brackets to pull onto
I'll onto tree I so I figured that now
they've got my balls priced
was proved by someone who just test this
on my best option I talk to testing was
to do it out the test our cap flap
so am
bunuel a on the left hand side they're
on that picture there's two solar panels
now buy now
I start buying stuff in this project is
going up in price and I'm really worried
my wife isn't gonna be very happy about
this
but the solar panels is a break to exile
relies on Amazon you can dispel send the
stuff to a different address
and pick it up later so she doesn't see
the stuff coming into the house
so that in a is
the breakthrough moment that was so we
got this solar powered
I'm gonna alarm bash in the bottom of
the in the bottom of the
camera there pound of soda powers
especially by the way this is one might
the power management is the thing this
morning and I like ap lab tests on the
right hand side exit button while
wheelie bin
and just see the bottom edge of out cat
flap which is where I
place the camera to what and I figured
I'll just see our cats coming in and out
the cap lap these are our cats
there be bottom blues there to Black
Cats
am so my am I checked visit be quite
interesting to see what the bottom blues
are doing through the night and
see where I'm at. detecting it bebop is
the one on the right with the dodgy I
I'm and he's that he's the boy and
one on the left is blues the girl the
brother and sister
that's enough about my cats right so I
am
bug or video here missus see my to
squint to look at it
am so this was a so I was really
surprised first off i'd I
I ended up with this
am I didn't see any motion from our cats
whatsoever
but this one arrived am we've called
long tail
suspect number one a who arrives at the
step you can see has a sniff around
now is interesting because two days
after this
I was a past a field
those outside in our village and I saw
this cat it Russ Roman of a long way
I'm is a easily up and a half a
kilometer away and this self-same cat
was there
but they say he didn't go in he just had
a sniff around as you can see and then
he walked away
for a bit okay so that's thats
long tail number one and let me just
me on to right said the next one
is this one here on the left a.m.
going on who steel plant me one that let
me just give you the rundown him
rights so this one here
on the left that this is a a separate
different tack
a short sale will call him stumpy
codename stumpy
and you can see he actually goes up and
into
the capeci entered into the house and
am looking at the time stamp emotion
times them so these images above
the way motion works by the way is it
just it takes a Jay pay and then another
J pagan a competitor in if there's a
difference and it starts laying down Jay
PEQ so all these videos are just
is Jay pics have been strung together am
but a few seconds later am he
am he exits on the right hand side
being followed by beep bop but you can
just see there who comes out say
he only stays in for a few seconds in be
bop I think
just moves of and season of the premises
completely we always knew he was useful
that cap right so that's
so sound now for now I've got two
different cats coming into
into the house budget I'm not just can't
believe this analysis
how me these cats in a bit with a
feeding so
next day
a we get this one on the left hand side
and I'll a Cal describe this to you
if any the screens working right that's
on the left hand side
I have another cat as a ginger cat code
name change
who actually enters the house and in
that video
he has just entered the cat flap but now
what's interesting
is that he he stays in every three
minutes
and he exits
three minutes later we don't know why
there's no bebop
so on the right hand side he's just
exiting here
but three minutes not all possible today
with 3 minutes what he's probably eating
the food is me
so this this in gave us an idea for
another project
which this is a work in progress and let
me just describe this to you
and again because I am the screens are
brilliant so top left-hand side I have a
cap flap
am thats am has RFID detection if
a on it now the those chips the cats
having the next business standards for
that and it's a four centimeter
field feel distance evening and I'm
figuring that we could
have the cap flap able to read that
other I
and I don't mind about they can come in
it does matter the cats can come in
I just wanna hear the county's and on
the bottom left there is actually a good
description ever web service you can go
to
send the chip ID and I'll give you the
contact details
for Leona okay now some figuring the cat
comes a top left the cat comes in the
cap flat round trip I'd reads it
it goes out to the web service it comes
back the contact details
then at the middle at the bottom there
you'll see
that the year %uh the cat the same to
the house
is then imprisoned
okay so we've now got the
got the perpetrator in the house we know
who it belongs to
I K I'm we've got evidence them into the
house now the
the top right we've got the cat food on
the lab balance
interface to the pie so for that period
time we know how much food
that kansian and what we then do is we
also generates the invoice
the meow Mix
which goes straight to the owner and a
course Sims is paid they can have the
cap back
so thats
there thank you so
so that that's a work in progress if
anyone wants to help me with that one
cutlets this get in contact okay so
and right said I've kinda summarize
where I am right
you know I'm able to detect motion I was
set to a neighbor's cats this is where
we only flight it cam right now
on the left hand side I have the
location where fly-tipping
am was supposed to be mounted two weeks
ago um
it wasn't mounted because I have a power
management problem
I which I will describe gee I don't know
any pictures all but it goes like this:
I'm I had a burglar alarm battery in the
base of the
a the at the module and
I had solar power batteries and I took
out the battery and the solar power
panels solar panels to scout camp so
on chairman local Scout Troop I can help
out our scout camp every year
we thought it would be really cool to
take the battery
and the solar panels to scout camp so
that all the Scout leaders
and maybe some other kids can recharge
their phones and
one guy came along as soon as I put a
load on The Bachelor this battery by the
way was inside one of these ammunition
boxes
a suitable alone on the battery there
was a lotta kinda flickering in the
early days
and the battery started expanding like
this now we often have accidents on
scout camp we have to put the ball in
there
in the first aid book but we've never
had sulfuric acid burns
so I'm really just slam close the lid
and a answer like the battery so
am thank you and so
firm I have to
I have to do something out power
management basically at this is that the
last bit I need to put in place
I mean it's going to get my head around
what needs to be done in order to keep
the thing topped up with power
side and Kim going back in revisiting
I'm
one other thing I did I did mention I'm
was
that I need to have secure data access
and we also have them
there's a wife I don't go here
for accessing it and am so you its cool
flight flight if Cam is the network and
the password
if ever you're there is get off my land
so
this is a so that's my presentation I
just has one side here which is a
picture but you can see but is basically
a plea to anybody who knows anybody who
could help me with the power management
on this
I'm I would be really grateful my might
Twitter
ideas then on on that um but
with that that's a that that's what we
did with that that the Capitals
anyone have any questions
yeah and his wife might find yeah
hahaa a that's right any more questions
the summer
not so much a question but a though such
a guy doing photovoltaic care
workshop for earlier be spoken to him
well I don't think I'll try and catch up
with them yeah I'm
I would have been done that work should
have been able to cut they're all kinda
full there's some good in Syria
yeah I'll try and catch up with him well
worthwhile yeah you get things
anymore
I walk into going to close at hand and
say thank you to Derek again