was his attempt to remember more or less
to take his aggressive cost-cutting
philosophy
to the world of business computing which
didn't really go down too well so again
rather than having a proper disk drive
it was using these micro drives which of
these yes littler and postage
stamp-sized things with the tape loop in
them horribly unreliable
so yeah this went down like a lead
balloon in the business world although
one of them did find its way into the
hands of a certain finished student
saying who were to have had a broad
spectrum with his his pocket money and
so i ql with pocket money and used it to
tinker around with the operating systems
so we all know how that turned out
so in the end Sinclair had to sell this
sell-off the the spectrums intellectual
property to this guy almond sugar and
the computing world moved on people
moved onto the use of the atari st in
the amiga and that sort of thing and all
across the country the spectrums
generally got handed down to everyone's
younger siblings and which meant they
were coming companies like codemasters
that briefly made a killing out of these
of cheap and cheerful cartoony adventure
games those of attractive to this new
younger markets and sold her like just a
couple of pounds so it's just total
pocket money stuff and and in the
inspect computing community today I
think dizzy is it's kind of a bit of my
fingers to clean gods that it's is kind
of a given weight was the beginning of
the end of it for the spectrum it's it's
like a bit so he did derivative and it's
and so yeah they did they can they can
carry on for a few years for this sort
of thing but eventually they supply
software from the likes of codemasters
also dried up and the magazines and so
run out of things to show it to report
on so they ended up closing down this is
the big final issue which was big in the
sensitive with 64 pages rather than the
32 that it's gone down to think there
was a general feeling that the well that
is possibly the magazine cover tapes
were part of the death of the this
spectrum software industry because it
was saying these magazines are just a
pamphlet with a where the cover tape on
the front so they sort of further people
who do have stuck with the spectrum
right at the end we sought suddenly
drops into the little bit and and then
well there's still a community around it
was being kept alive with these sort of
fanzines it's sort of mail order and so
anyways it's so pretty nicer and not
know sort of community in its own way
but eventually it kind of turned from it
being the mass market thing to us being
the sort of eccentric preservationist
sort of like like steam engine
enthusiastic or something
incidentally they directed the steam
engine enthusiasts get really pissed off
with the steampunk people for saying
yeah you're just trying to ride on the
coattails of the whole steam engine
thing with but you're not actually
really living the real thing not really
getting into the holes vowels and things
that's just get really pissed off with
that stuff anyway yes
so I'm for for a long time then this
spectrum being propped up by these sorts
of fanzines and a lot of derail bits
into a bit side which i didn't get any
slides for which is another of pretty
active than subculture witnessed within
a subculture of the spectrum which is
the demo scene so further mentioned at
some length in previous talks but just
as a real a bit of recap this is way it
came out of there
the and software piracy scene where p.m.
people to wear pirate these games break
the protection on them and then to show
that they do they've done this they
putting a little intro sequence with
their logo and so 15 a few flashy colors
and things and and it just as a sort of
a bit of digital graffiti as it were and
eventually this sort of the took on this
line its own life
an art form in its own right and matt
and people dropped the whole game
cracking side of things and just focused
on the demos and this went on on the
spectrum as well it was perhaps never
quite as big as things like the
Commodore 64 in the amiga but today was
fun thing to be a part of it was some
people that were there was the whole the
mail swapping thing in the roofing home
from school evilly oh it hoping that you
might be some some jiffy bag from a
far-off land like Poland or
Czechoslovakia is it was then and are so
who knows where and and so people were
you know using these demos ways of
exploring the hardware and just learning
new tricks and it's kinda and I think
this was kind of summarized the spectrum
Tina as a whole in this sort of Iran it
wasn't really driven by commercial
pressures people were able to to really
explore the spectrum as a platform in
its own right and and and really
discover and what so and the water they
are the hard ones really capable of and
one thing really severe head into this
was the arrival of emulators so we
didn't take really have both feet in the
past we did as well as sticking to the
spectrum we had we had real computers as
well so emulators sprang up to let you
to make your pc behave like a spectrum
but with with all of the annoying things
like the five-minute tape loading times
cut out so so the these collections
sprang up so you could like CDs you
could get in HMV with the emulators and
thousands of games that you could just
instantly fire up and and and and so say
this is and and telling and as time went
on people were discovered a lot more
these simulated became more and more
accurate and as well once the holiday
was capable of emulating it at a lower
and lower level so so the so as we
discovered more about the spectrum these
emulators improved as well
now around this middle to the end of the
nineties of a lucky few of us got access
to the internet and what we found was
something quite surprising was that what
we thought was this sort of little and
little island this this and this is a
tiny close-knit community was just like
one island out of many and so one wants
people to get onto the internet started
googling for not googling also be
stirring or whatever for out for the
spectrum we're discovering these other
some other things happening around the
world that we kind of missed out on the
first time round and so so one example
of this is an in during the there sorry
over war there were and a few a a couple
of guys who were in order to distract
them from the horrors of this they work
on and a spectrum emulator of their own
and this is an incredible story behind
this of how did they had they would have
like maybe one or two hours of
electricity a day and when they probably
have power cuts like we had just before
but Sir and so during that they be
coding frantically and then during the
rest of the time they be just working
out the algorithms on paper and yeah and
and in in the end they came up with
something that was so pretty and
competitive emulator for against the
other things existed at a time and and
and and it releases amazing what I came
up with their and so other bit others a
bit of the have where please wait IDing
with the european history is so yeah so
there is in in in the city of torreón
in Poland it we know it turned out there
was some this signal a TV signal
intrusion stage by this a solid Oscar
the anti-soviet movement and that this
was certain by a couple of academics
that's a store near university using a
spectrum and this series of random the
it's of electronics so the spectrums of
they've been an inspiration hackers
throughout the ages and it's also
interesting to see how it sort of
feeding into these moments of european
history it's like the the spectrum of
the sort of computer equivalent to
Forrest Gump is this underdog various
bits of surfacing every now and then and
in these unexpected ways but perhaps the
most intriguing of all was what was
going on in in Russia because it turned
out that and so so the the spectrum it
end at some point someone had managed to
smuggle an original spectrum through the
the Iron Curtain and because of because
of the and they did the world the way
that Sinclair had to had to have driven
down the costs and eliminated all this
custom circuitry like Ben head was
saying about that there's only really
one custom chair and if you were
determined enough you could replicate
that in standard logic and that's
exactly what what the muffins in Russia
did they came up with these and these
designs that were basically they got
have passed around just these blueprints
for these spectrums reinvented with with
with the locally available components
and pretty much every city and town in
in the Soviet Union they would have some
kind of electronics geek who would be
her he would be having this little
cottage industry of making these
spectrums out of whatever bits and
pieces they had to have the had to hand
with these are whichever to the
keyboards and things whatever bits of
plastic so it's all sorts over here
what like really whatever materials they
had to hand so if they had like a job
lot of these five Indian sockets then
that's what they would use for all the
connectors regardless of whether it's
actually made any sense for that
particular application because yeah just
make do with the whatever materials i
had available this is the Sinclair
losophy reborn effectively and their the
years of intriguing thing with this was
that and the big and along with all the
hardware of course came the software
pirated of course and and and they in
fact have disk systems because they're
well they it was bigger then they kind
of adopted one British system but this
single I never brought out an official
disk system he was too still insistent
on the microdrive stuff but a couple of
third party ones and one of them are
fairly obscure one called be two discs
it's find its way to Russia and that
became their standard so that they would
receive these discs of pirated games for
from there for local dealer and because
the and this was all happening in these
of beginning of the nineties they didn't
really experience whole progression of
of their video games as we knew it so so
so things like so
Jet Set Willy that meant that absolutely
nothing to them because then they would
still get these discs with hundreds of
games on and well for a Russian kid
growing up with with these things all at
once well which one of them are you
going to sleep on say yes this is
state-of-the-art and obviously it's
going to be the duty games so these
games that we in the West work i know
for thinking this is like the the low
point of this other of the spectrums
software parts in Russia this was the
this was like the absolute peak of
achievements tho spectrum nostalgia in
Russia is now is all about dizzy so yeah
a jet really manic miner means nothing
so now we first we've come full circle
in a way with the spectrums of
fashionable and retro again so yes the
these bags and things and the this is x
500 for airtrain as an actual adidas
product a few years back I didn't think
they'd acknowledge that it was an
officially licensed but you can see what
they would
they're so yeah and so things are still
going on there with inspector community
people are still discovering stuff is
collaboration over the internet so this
is a one thing is is that how to brought
in after that Ben hex talk there's a
talk of recreating the that the ula
their custom video chip industry
hardware so this is the the prototype of
the Harlequin which is a spectrum clone
which it was built by a guy called
Christmas is based in Wales and he
actually brought this along to a
gathering of spectrum geeks at a party
in Oxford so we so the these things that
go on every now and then and have to say
when the the barmaids have came along to
our table and saw the sort of massive
components and wires she was a bit too
apprehensive and was like is that a bomb
okay and yeah so it's nothing it lost a
bit of the through the connections got
loose in Tranzit so I think once we
finally got it working we dead one of
our party to showed the bottom is
working again
so yes sometimes and another server
major achievements of these these oxford
park meetups was what we also had the
the young our first glimpse of the
spectrum net which is the an ethernet
interface for the spectrum and it's a
thing with the lot of these interfaces
you end up with the day the interface
themselves are actually kind of doing
the en that they have as much processing
power on board as the original spectrum
is not more but it's still very nice in
intellectual pursuits and and so one
thing that isn't so here we got like the
first prototypes of this so playing
around with the match one of these
meetings in Oxford and we decided on the
spot that what we're trying to do is get
the spectrum posting to Twitter so this
is again this they are they much mr.
Gloucester and in Oxford and this was
the is the tweet from spectrum that we
ascend
from from spectrum to a laptop that was
bridge to the local Wi-Fi hotspots so I
do think there really should be like a
blue plaque on this on this comp now is
the first spectrum spectrum twitter
stream from here
unfortunately can't do this anymore
because they're they've no live in 400
and all sorts of things and for a while
the guy who know produce the the the
spectrum getting to face you would i go
to the record computing fairs and would
have a spectrum set up with with the at
twitter client where you could put in
your username and password and and
feeling good look mind posting from the
spectrum on Twitter that's pretty much
more later on types but but yeah you
can't do that now because you've got to
authenticate via or the book because
small to be fair and i think it was the
entire point of twitter moving to a war
with to stop
p people setting up a random bits of
hard racing go on enter your username
and password into this but it'll do
something cool so you can't really play
known that so yeah and the suspect 2010
uses the and sacrilegious spectrum in an
fpga that there is a developed by a
Ukrainian developer and this is actually
my pride and joy i'm using this familiar
concept later on
it's a biscuit nicer contact thing that
so it's a as these sorts of developments
are happening all the time its release
if fascinating international community
is an instantly with the issue with some
of these and the the these clones if you
try to make them above board
there's an issue with the spectrum
firmware because since it was passed on
from Sinclair to turn Strad the
intellectual property now ultimately
resides with the rupert murdoch so if
you actually want to build these things
and ship them with the spectrum rom then
you would have to come up with some some
deal with their within so as a way of
getting around this actually works on a
project
years back to like produce an
open-source clone of the and now all of
the spectrum firmware that led that
actually look reproduce like basic that
let everyone basic programs and so you
will be enough to run games and things
and unwanted cool for this project was
that we have got hold of the zx81
firmware which you too and various of
legal authorities didn't go to sky so we
were able to to to use some of the
routines from there which had been
passed on to the spectrum and those
included the and the trigonometric math
routine this so not only did i
eventually find out what sign cause and
did and town did I eventually became the
custodian of the sine cos and tan
routines so I know it made me I realized
that this is must be what site is steven
moffat fields and the growing up
watching Doctor Who and then and then
eventually becoming a writer on on
Doctor Who am selling field running the
show and so well simple pleasures he
make me happy and of course now we've
got some the light of the roughly party
to keep her so to really bring back this
idea of a computer that encourages
programming from the get-go rather than
a computer that's just an appliance and
yes he has it all know it so here
roaring successes is hopefully going to
and to inspire a new generation of
programmers just as i was with the
spectrum and might not have the the
their keywords printed on the keys but
if it can help a few of the children of
today slay their own bug-eyed monsters
then I think that the future is bright
thanks very much
think of a question by Rafael yeah yeah
so yeah I think this is a time for
questions certain you
and yes the Sun kupic that was it was as
a noted as a successor to the spectrum
this was i get in anyway with more of
the aya in 8-bit competitor to the st
and the amigo and and I and I guess the
selling point of it was that it was more
or less compatible with the release is
some software for the spectrum so so the
makers of it were that were hoping that
it would be that will be a natural or
grade path but and I think it was that
project though it was slightly to
plagued by problems i think they were
too late in actually getting it to
market by watching whichever particular
Christmas it was Christmas 1989 I think
so they kind of missed the boat and
people had already moved on to the st
and amiga which meant but that they
never really became sort of breakouts
and success in its own right it's always
became a sort of postscript to to the
spectrum but yea throughout the nineties
he was the is a lie close knit community
a lot of the fanzines were of the
spectrum and sank you pay based so this
be a lot of shared heritage that
well okay Saul thanks again right and
ella ya rush often hopefully yeah we see
you stay