people yeah
here now day the
a
hero
I I'm yeah
the you J a
I'll well
of the many him
all the
all bro there yeah
their
lol her hero
all really law all
go world their own
in UK
fun this use any Aloha called
all %uh you
long well I the
Paul
him
rules below the
finally overflow
gold
that role
doing wrong any mall
year you'll home
who allegedly call
hold me
router long dude
wrong %uh
him %uh for
d
these the room all
here rural
the
and growth
here it
you the A&E his
see lucky
little gold and
on 0
me the floor
my all
lunch fair along tonight
cool him
all the my
all review
all I'll
who all
I'll they were
or them
they're all mall all
people yeah month I love you
Hills me
he know your
hold
weather
world we will the
10 single follow here well
voluntary all
you
for third and
much are well
just what yeah
you good the record
your call
owners
you there he called
law overall yeah
%uh
you yeah %uh
honors harmful meter old
and cool
yeah long
in he
world you see
yeah you know while I'll
you can see
laws yeah %uh haha I'll
hall %uh
did and pile up
I long
you
rather all it
old back yeah
okay through
the world and then build
world for
you
and
marble
mall other
you third
whole mall
you I'm Laurel or
all
many all all
hale's on
all
yeah mama bro
little old his grier's
her that I'm
whole when on the whole
here all
for war believed
Omaha here
for here home
little you
the lead all under
that's what we do good books label
yeah
the will
the you well here
3 back to old mall
home worth
the mall roles the
full hit you
Honda of whole
the all
to in you
the the
all mom Hill
up
home all is
honey ho
all the it made the whole
toward
all I'll weird
nor
run so it
%uh youthful program
cool
which cool
me and I'm her cool
I'll their
any all world
I'll the whole of let 3
known use all
for well all
or year
%uh put the miss you for him
the I
ca all
up heard bad
me
other ground
yeah re
long whole strong
with and
per their
Hill from you
14 yeah
people
now way
pie in
on
you old
all
use
yeah this blog yeah
of
real for haha
here
see
you okay
%uh Google for labeled
all all all a whole
from driver do
for software all you
this is a
long-standing
room cool
that yeah and
you annual her
0 here
bow the
hit that home
long hair cool
were of
yeah anything
through you
%uh 30 hall
lost
well his there'd
good all loophole
their machine for
home
you
I'll you there
your on here
on there
who'll
their do this
cool
here
use go
%uh seeing all those lines well
all
usual
mister the whole thing so here
more practical all
food there whole that are all
30 all
all their to
those but page all sale
effectively
old
I'll the
his her
I'll cuzo
all
all mine yeah
whole all who'll
wall Bowl low
or other love go
for your yeah
home
yeah will be there
for all
you her
%um
of moment home at home
p
you relics Islam and
long yes
here again luthuli
while them body
on their right mom
sondheim all home
along or the
a lot fall
the this and
natos will I
film yeah here or
one here red little
who with %um
home
day there
blue run all
up
we long
all him
hard
all
a holler he had
all on us
you here hard
wall all for
love you all all
here this home
her
of her Ross mall
the mall not this here
all than usual
%uh home this right now
will not there moon rock
room
the aid but
calm down the that
mom all com
you home
lol called
all old
here
want to make something happen more
humor unlawful
do love you all law and
his him
all see
test love it gonna sell
these people any
weird
for me all okay
little or
gold member gary is created being people
but also rejected by nato
in with %uh pulled off the loan excluded
by the for my cousin
had written about the whole bottle make
got left so this is very deceptive
stuff because it looks like they fought
really hard about it and it means
something for Saif
but you just don't quite understand we
thought that's a long time
and we try to make mathematical models
have this but in fact
when you get to it and you got
experiments and you go and talk to the
architect what we do
we collaborate with a very smart and
fine I'll IBM architect
on this stuff you find this does not
describe what they actually do
okay and if you talk to
%uh architect about that text they say
this kind of thing
all horrible Harley incomprehensible and
confusing text that no one compulsory in
with
not even the people who wrote it on this
wall
want to people right so
a misery a misery I say um so there's a
basic problem here which is that these
the defection in the industry that we
can write true specifications
and safe programmers just read this book
I write your program
a seeming only the facts in this book
and then
well then what do they do
they go away and I read a book I didn't
really understand it because it is not
comprehensible
does not have a meaning I am and then
they write the code Bali that trial and
error development process by testing
against the particular implementations
that they have
on the particular execution also they
happened to explore
right so this is rubbish but you can't
use these for special occasions
to test programs you can't use them the
test at the hardware
those what intended you can't use them
certainly not to prove properties were
anything
and as we see can even use them to
communicate
between the organizations that are
making the thing
new organizations that in using the
thing which is the basic things
specification
or be able to do I so in this set sent
none of the specifications really exist
it's all imaginary it's a happy dream
so what we do
um I was raised up and as experimental
scientist
and the Oracle Financial come least
slightly to our rescue her so
we can indeed we have invented some
mathematically precise models and how we
think these things behave
not how they were looking for aid but
just how they behave from the program is
.2 few
and many make tools
but don't just cut late one call but for
the small programs explore
all of the possible execution to give
you the set
the everything the diesel al annette
you can run experiments on my fame
console programs
a to compare and then compare the
experimental data
to check that is all all the experiment
lee allowed executions
all actually allow by your model on
and sometimes they're not too if they're
not been either
you found a bug in the person so and you
think pop we win
all you found a bug in your mobile and
you get to pick up your mobile into it
true
and then you say we would I on then
in order to know whether these things a
bugs or not you have to talk to the
object
what's not a Celtic took is someone who
can by definition tell you
with observe purchase a behavior is a
bug or not i'd
it's there in 10 but matters here and
also you need to talk to them to make
sure the mobile
match their intuition to get some
assurance that you all
talking total month and then you get
some other validation so you can prove
they both these machine model you can
prove that you can compile
c11 concurrency down to these machine
models and that gives you a bit more
confidence
but all of them are the so sensible and
then
goes all the singer/actress better if
you go back to one
and do it all again better as he
probably worth of stuff from first time
so a is this rocket science
no rockets onto I think at 1:45 on stage
I can't remember which
I am it's not very hard
really so all we've done
is right down well
we've yet identified one of these
abstraction layers that we really care
out and we've written down a description
all
not just some implementation but all the
behavior we think should be allowed that
abstraction layer
and then we've tested real systems
against that
uninformed so we've written down those
those definitions about affect the
behavior
in some random mathematical language
doesn't really matter wat but you could
do anything
anything which is clear and concise and
has on ambiguous meaning
you could if you really have to doing
Seco so long as you understand that your
writing down
a definition of all the allow behavior
and that definition must be executed
we'll not as the system
but as a test oracle to decide if some
observed behavior is allowable not so
that the thing that people don't often
do
it's very easy is not worth it
all the time you know it you're building
some app up for something
you may not even have a clue beforehand
what it's supposed to do for any of
these infrastructure things that we
depend on
and that's all reimplemented in many
contexts it's clearly were
and when you've done that then you not
limited your testing process that was
still stuck with the time being
you not limited to the few ad hoc test
that you
you right now you're gone Oracle looking
tell me whether
any behavior is good or not you can do
random testing
you get in
is any better coverage and find millions
bucks
okay I can't even read that flight
%uh I said that
I am so I said that first time stop
pretty much so why im there was some
reasons why building robust system the
heart and there are things we can do
about it
and some them all absolutely trivial and
then in the longer term
for some hope for on it for a vacation
so
II give you i think is a very cautious
optimism
but I also thought you a to think about
this kind of stuff because you just
imagine the situation
50 is now a hundred years from now boy
civilization just a thousand years from
now if we don't
fix this stuff up if we don't fix it up
stuff up we will have
the x86 abstraction the sockets API
the SSL API imbedded through some
dos least active emulation layers in
everything we use
for the rest of civilization
the end thank you for your attention
if you've got any any questions a
question
five questions free almost 50 minutes
Bowl next talk
car
have you done
the work or even the acquired experience
up
how these prices my whole he's getting
easier as died try her
I'm did different place if we met we
know how to do it much better than we
did before and that they were
so there are some questions and relating
to howl nondeterministic how loose a
specification you need
that relate to how you can write that
specification in a way that makes
actually usable and there are other some
sociological question that how you talk
to the designers all the sea standards
committee or whatever
in order to get them to understand that
this is a good idea if you walk into a
sea standards committee meeting
and accident a show them a piece of
paper with a little too much math in
like an upside-down I a then they they
go you know all queasy
because that's just not the language
they were lookin we have to take care
with that kind of stuff any more quick
question
question over that
home I totally agree on the design
for language but think most prone
most are Texas move on construction
Arc'teryx want to build a computer or
with every Arctic possibility people and
they have to agree to stop them
to Compostela broker should
so communication remains key a
I'm yeah I but
how can you prevent that there are
additional cost to complex
it to expand make threw up
so it's an interesting question to how
to how can we arrange for there to be a
pushback
against adding complexity that's really
tough
but at least a programming language
design and the summer these abstractions
the mere fact writing down I E
clean specification the forces you
to notice the complexity on which
otherwise
if you just have a texter language back
it's very easy to just say
a which will let with gun and a new
feature we're just talking a couple
paragraphs of text here
and that doesn't force you to understand
how it interacts with everything else
so that I mean this is not a total
solution I think there is a total
solution but that does give you feedback
mechanism
that we don't have at the moment one
behind you
find you Bihar
do believe there's much more market at
the moment
for formal verification not have the
likely to the itself but I've
programs written in like a market
I think not much I think there is
potentially a significant market bull
on was a very particular
systems infrastructure to be verified I
so
if I had a verified hypervisor with us
for just about to do tonight
running on my phone I would be a happy
man when I come to MN cam
and to in the industry want that kind of
thing and there are some companies
doing that he said he'll poor thing from
her commercialization
but I'll as owner buying I'm last one
last month
sorry for PHP is the worst
language in a mall which one would you
say is the best
a fire is open I was thinking about
giving this talk to not answer any
questions that general for
and in some ten I don't know
I'm not in a position to know I do right
a whole lotta code on
what I do when I'm up I in my group do
we use O'Connell on Haskell and sensible
you know functional imperative languages
that
very good for this kind of semantic
infrastructure kind of work
in other contexts I'm not going to
comment
K enough thank you