so I'm my name's to livings I'm I'm
really just a doggy
I actually recently got my first dog 56
years ago and and I made a bit of an
error getting my first dog and by not
researching properly i got two German
Shepherds i'm sure many people do is
their first dog i could be home to a
german shepherd who is looking for a new
home because she wasn't fitting in with
your existing family had I known better
that might have set some alarm bells off
and does she was wonderful
right up until the moment that I took
her to the park and she saw another dog
launched in and attacked it and put that
dog in the vets that happened within 24
hours of me picking her up so it was a
bit of an education the next two weeks
were emotional at best and involved dog
training twice a day and some of which
one to one
I was calling a dog exerted a German
Shepherd expert i'm near Birmingham who
trained police dogs for a living and the
complication being that i had time two
little girls then our big girls don't go
away summer and and the dog would treat
me as master and then as millions and
that was illustrated most appropriately
about a week after we got her where I
told Jessica the youngest she would have
been about six at the time off for doing
something stupid in the garden and the
dog came to my side and growled at the
girl that confused me
I didn't know what the hell was going on
I didn't know how to explain the
behavior I just observed and it put me
in a difficult position because I now
had the safety of my daughter to
consider as well as the training of the
dog which I didn't fully understand so I
spoke at length to this gentleman
burnham who train these dogs he had five
acres of land here at a farm here and
this dog training firm and he was quite
happy to take her on as a project and
retrain her in his environment and
that's what he did
we took the dog out there
one amongst great two years I rehomed my
first dog within two weeks of getting
her butt coming out of that I then I
went on the internet and I went through
every video every book and my family
brought me book after book after book
about dog behavior dog training and more
importantly how they interact with other
beings and out of that I decided then
that I was ready about six months later
to get a puppy and you'll see her on
well not on there because no one can see
anything on there but hopefully on the
screen you'll see echo is a little brown
and white springer and she was my first
puppy and I scratched render and
eventually we will see and what she does
and I think got a second of these or who
you also see energies appears in a lot
of these videos and the reason being
diesel is a very calm dog he's a very
easy doc to catch on video triggering
behaviour in other dogs so kind of
disclaimers I'm not a dog behaviorist
i'm a student a geek of dog culture and
I study it as a hobby
I'm not a professional please don't take
what i tell you as an absolute statement
of fact please apply your own knowledge
your own experiences and it certainly if
you have a dog with behavioral issues
i'm quite happy to talk to you about it
quite happy to give my input but if it's
a serious issue please engage
professional help and this is not dog
training this is not the purpose of this
discussion all I'm trying to show you is
some of the ways dogs interact again if
you want to talk to me about dog
training some of you already have our
see some faces that have called me in
the field i love dogs to bits
I've spent a lot of time with esther and
widget down there just because i lost my
dog fix after leaving them at home for a
few days and I'll spend as much time
with you talking about dogs you can bear
ab I just said there are exceptions to
every rule don't take what I've said is
red
it's a general guide you'll find it's
true in just about every situation but
there will be exceptions there will be
dogs that of
learned behaviors particularly from
other dogs which are different to what
I'm about to show you
so what I'd like to start with is
something particularly unusual i want
two volunteers preferably who don't know
each other and preferably who don't know
anything about dogs just to come up
onstage just quickly for one minute demo
go on some of them any one of those are
hand and there's another hand I just
there was a minute I've got to speak to
them without the mic just for a moment
these guys have just seen each other end
of the field
I'm going to interrupt their because
what I was after was that first second
and i don't know how many of you spotted
it but these two actors did it perfectly
having no idea what i was trying to
illustrate what I was trying to point
out this gentleman didn't have a
particularly high opinion of this
gentleman and what you saw was him walk
and he got some distance away and just
stopped just to see engage what this
gentleman was going to do this gentleman
who's met about a year ago and had a
much higher opinion of him came in quite
quickly and claiming quite close quite
quickly and so I don't you name mark
francis leaving about the same name that
would be confusing not actually took as
micro step back because Francis was
coming in so comfortably and we'll see
that happen with dogs
thank you both so what we saw their
hunting spoken and they already
communicated with body language that is
so important in human culture and as
humans we read it all day every day we
don't know we're doing it because with
so relying on voice we make judgments
based upon tone of voice and language
and guess what
dogs don't have that they have a bark
which has got about six tones to it but
they are actually reliant on body
language their approach to each other
how they walk the direction they walk
the speed they walk the steps they use
the position of the head position of the
tail is a key part of how they
communicate in that first meeting they
are so good at reading dog body language
that they read human body language ray
better than humans do to everything that
you see when you speak to someone else
and you think oh not sure about them
you're interpreting body language but
the dog walking with has judged even
more became a greeting is generally a
very respectful a well-behaved dog will
greet
another dog with great respect they are
absolutely merciless if that respect
line is crossed so if we saw there where
Francis approached mark a little too
much and human step bag a dog might lead
with a step back but if that say puppies
coming in a puppy comes in Fast and
jumps on another dog that will be
merciless it will grab the puppy by the
throat it will throw it on its back and
quite often it was struggling to put a
porn it to say to that dog you've
crossed a line but what's wonderful
about dog culture is that that is an
instant forgiveness room approach so the
moment that the puppies given up and
said actually okay I'm sorry I cross the
line the double let up and usually we'll
just play we don't really do that human
culture when we make her judgments that
generally permanent and Francis approach
mark mark felt a bit uncomfortable my
probably would have held that and
discomfort for quite some time until he
got to know Francis a little better
dogs don't do that they have figured
almost immediately what we've got now is
a video I know I don't see the video i
don't really know if you do those that
this dog here is diesel in the harness
and then those better which is the puppy
little bulldog with no harness on and
what you've seen
I don't nobody can play that again let
me see what we can do it again so you
can watch it is the tip business of tail
wagging everyone's most uncomfortable
there sniffing each other they're
looking for us to face and they're
touching noses that smelling each other
but there's no real fast movement
there's no head above every other head
there's no tail tucked between the legs
or tail up and yet they're generally
pretty content one of the things that
happens with dogs
that's really really common it's not a
myth is real is dog dominance within a
pack there is always an alpha dog that
alpha dog is exclusive to the back
there's never two alpha docs there's
never a p2 dog but there is often
an alpha dog this transient so for
example i'm in a pack and alpha dog may
disappear at go hunting another dog will
step up that role but it's not a
hierarchy in this in the sense that we
understand it there is one alpha dog and
then as all the others the alpha dog
gets mating likes it's the one that
disciplines the other dopes it's the one
that leads the packs on hunts and it's
the one that's respected by the dogs and
bizarrely most of the time the alpha is
not the most aggressive often the alpha
dog is the one that's calm and
selectively dominant so it will pick
dogs that have crossed a line and it
will put them in their place it will not
attack every dog that comes near it but
it will defend the pack to generally in
a controlled manner and only get
aggressive if it truly needs to the
hierarchy below the alpha dog is way
more complex it it's not a hierarchy
where one dog is higher than the other
it's a hierarchy where in some aspects
may be in food one dog will get a shout
over the food before another but that
dog may not be the dog that takes on the
Alpha role if the alpha dog is away what
you'll find and sunny my house I've got
in essence two alpha dogs between the
two canines because I'm my alpha dog in
the house when I'm in the house they
respect me and I make sure they respect
me and I'm quite vicious
what in a a physical manner but I'm
absolutely merciless with their behavior
if they cross the line are not happy
with say for example stealing food from
my plate they will get disciplined we're
not talking about physical discipline
without hurting them
i'm talking about a body language
discipline we're going later those don't
respect me but between the two of them
my female dog echo she's the boss of the
house when it comes to toys there's no
way that diesel will try and take a toi
avec OU but if Jesus got food
ok will not try and take to food of
diesel and so even know
two of them have their own little areas
where they are dominant in the the whole
pack
I'm the boss and when I'm away the Alpha
roll generally falls onto diesel the
mail
there's a number of reasons for that
which will kind of touch on later and in
the domina's process and as well see in
the videos in a moment the dogs
generally generally demonstrate a
physical prowess they will generally try
to act big so you'll see ahead go up
you'll see a tail got you'll see the
shoulders come forward they will stand
over the other dog and they will make
that dog try to feel small
obviously if you've got two dogs doing
that you can get an interesting problem
because eventually one of them runs out
of height and consequently it's by far
the most common cause of dogfights
they're not a fight like they're trying
to kill each other their fight trying to
demonstrate the physical press saying
I'm the alpha dog so you'll get a dog
approach you'll get another dog stand
tall stand tall and you'll either get a
dog back down which is by far the most
common because they don't want to fight
anymore than we want to see it or if
they can't settle it will be a brief
scrap scrap is generally very fast it'll
typically last 5-10 seconds at most and
sometimes sub-second and what you'll see
is a dog snap at one of the others
muscles they made try and push the other
way or mounted in what looks like a
meeting but it's not the mating is where
they're jumping on the back to say I'm
bigger than you are
that's where all these are the gay dog
videos that you've heard about seeing
about and nothing has been referencing
some various sitcom culture where you
hear about getting Dobson is not a gator
at all it's a male dog trying to
dominate another male dog by mounting it
so next we'll go to video 2 videos and
then I got diesel which is the spring
with a harness and then there are two
black labs now there are both black labs
but they are two different dots which is
why you're seeing two different
behaviors
it just so happens that the two
behaviors I call with both black labs
and
hopefully you'll see the detail you'll
see one dog actors dominant and one dog
act is just like complacent simple
meeting I can't see a thing hope for you
can
did you see it
let me see was just a nice board meeting
lost the tail wagging assistant anything
they tend to sniff each others butts and
circle round
that's because the same plans are in the
butts not because they like the smell of
poo and they'll circle around smelling
each other and the scent means a lot to
them is how they find each other in the
wild is how they track each other next
up we've got diesel the same dog meeting
a different black lab and this black lab
is a lot more dominant he's not
aggressively dominant but he makes it
very clear to diesel the diesel is
considered lower in the pack then here's
if you can see and just about the tail
is very very high the heads very high is
distilled in the sniffing and circling
but he's making it very clear he's
bigger diesel diesel has quite a history
which i won't go into today we don't
have time
diesels quite happy to be the submissive
dog and he has a history that makes him
a little bit timid he's quite happy and
we'll see later on in some of the videos
that diesel does take some extreme
certain steps to show submission which
is what we go into next add submission
is the counterexample dominance
it's where at dominant dogs come in it
and the other daughter feels threatened
wants to make it clear that it's no
threat to the dog so in diesels case and
he's about to meet but also be using
okay for this exam is about to meet
2morrow dogs mackin doable mac is a big
golden retriever very large male and and
Dougal is a tiny little Wesley westy
little white westy despite the fact that
echo is significantly larger the mac so
even Dougal little westie the echo will
show submission to Dougal match just
because of how do go holds himself and
Dougal is a very strong personality mail
with two strong personality males
appearing on my front porch might happen
to have the camera ready
echo came bounding our house and when
Oh
and you'll see exactly what she does
hopefully and there was the westy
briefly his echo just coming out and
she's put a bone right down on the floor
he might be able to see her tails
wagging she's quite happy she's not
upset but she knows that she's that
submissive to these two so remarkable
again she's coming back now that is
still showing dominance necklace just
rolled straight over back she's not
saying make me meet me what she's saying
is don't worry I'm no threat to your
dominance I'm happy for you to be alpha
dog let's carry on and it straight after
this she jumped up and they run around
the garden play together you'll see dogs
walking around the field they will
explore it's in their nature when
they're in the wild in a pack
they don't generally hold a territory in
a fixed sense the territory will flex
and Rome as the dogs explore you'll see
this wonderful behavior where there's
lots of tail liking and this is echo and
a lovely little tale going nuts she's
actually quite content there stood there
but she's also trying to tell me that
she wants the boards in my hand so she's
making it very very clear that she wants
something she's quite content tails
wagging headed normal kind of height
we've got another video here of where
echo and easily just connect need which
means unfortunately about to see you
soon urination apologies for like close
your eyes if you sensitive and echoes
way over the other side of the field and
Diesel's near me and on the second at
the moment there's diesel barriers so
I'm video in diesel was quite content
he's sniffing the ground tails Waggin a
little bit we going on there at this
point whenever we got sound man doesn't
matter what happened was there is a
point from echo echoes over the other
side of the field she's finished an
export and she's bored now and I'm
carrying a frisbee and you get a sharp
bark separated from another sharp bark
and that's the play bark and the
playback is very different
to the aggressive or defensive box
it'sit's very sharp it's isolated in
making me get a few succession but it's
an isolated bark she barked at me and as
the camera swung round I don't know how
much he caught she's looking at me as if
to say where is my first baby i could
see it's hanging around your neck
you look like you're playing whoo player
play for dogs when they play with each
other is part of their development
it happens pretty much until their old
age some go to play less than others
some don't play with humans more than
they do with other dogs but they all
play and they play as part of their
genetic upbringing as their way of
playing sports
just like we play sprint races to see
who's the fastest 10,000 years ago when
we were hunting thats printing was what
quarters game when we see how far we can
throw that javelin throw is how we call
up right folks are doing the same thing
they're teaching each other behaviors
that teaching each other sport the
teaching each other rivalry they're not
being nasty about it just like if you
play rugby you maybe shoulder barging
someone over but you're certainly not
intending to hurt them
the same is true in the dog world we've
got three videos in succession here all
of which you'll see the dogs actually
been quite physical with the other dogs
but in no way they're intending to hurt
them and you'll see first of all amazing
honey Maisie is a cockapoo she stands
about yay tall she's kind of gold in
curly hair but like which it is fast
asleep down there
not quite and and then there's honey who
is possibly one of a small this
long-haired dogs ever see I don't
actually know what preach years but
she's tiny like a koala and long head
like a golden retriever
she looks like a brush that's Maisie
they're jumping up bouncing
and just like humans when she's playing
she's quite bouncy you'll see the
vertical movement even when she's
running back is raising and lowering the
polls are bouncing when she stationary
she's bouncing off her posite where are
the poles of forward
she's pushing a pause out to bounce and
make it clear that she's interested i
want to play and then everyone like
they're amazing accidentally knocks me
over
she's running around and jumping over
and she's clipped or the pools and
professional significantly larger honey
the little dogs going bowling / no one
really minds if the honey was truly her
she'd squeak she didn't and they just
got up and carried on playing so even
though there's quite a significant size
difference in that Maisie who is
significantly faster than this to find
little dog is quite happy to play the
chase be game where if you're human you
put your hands over your shoulders and
run like that where she's pretending
just to be fast enough for honey to
capture i just given a mountain so next
we've got diesel my dog teaser with the
harness and bella bella is the bulldog
we saw briefly earlier on and and they
are playing in a similar manner a better
is actually quite a physical dog part of
that is because of a statue she's only
young she's only about seven months old
at this point but she's very muscular
she's very physical dog and I don't know
what he saw there was a point where she
just got a little bit out of control and
diesel picks up his poor and he bats are
over the side of a head to flip onto
aside and again he's not really having
ago he's just say that's a bit much and
the moment the poor has touched her and
she's on a side they get up again an
accountant plant quite happy and this
one is quite entertaining the loader is
the kind of silver and white
she's ass brutal so Springer poodle
cross she's absolutely insane
I've never seen a keep still and even
when she's only she doesn't keep still
and and she's
chasing this black dog had never seen
before I think it must be visiting but
she's so excited that the presence of
this dog Jonny switch
yep and that she's failing to listen to
her owner and if it unfortunately with
the sounds not working be right here
behind me
the only thing no more no more no more
company
no I'm sure you can imagine if your
three-year-old child had a
radio-controlled car that they are
managing to chase the local capped with
and it mother or father went German can
you can keep that know that the child is
going to be about same amount of
attention is loaded us and load it has
absolutely nothing until Kate walks over
grabs me by the collar and dragged her
across the field is quite entertaining
to watch but as it's not great way of
training the dog the point there was
that loader was quite happy to play will
carry on playing until she is told that
this is inappropriate
one thing I wanted to show you is what
happens when a dog is uncomfortable and
this is important for the human
interaction and uncomfortable dog will
show another dog very very quickly I
don't want you to approach now that
doesn't necessarily mean it's scared it
might be scared it might just be I feel
I don't want you to come near me I want
my own space and we have this was
ecodiesel and Bella again equities
almighty echoes got the red harness on
deals about the black harness on these
are was quite happy playing with bella
the two of them are quite playful dogs
but echoes very independent and he likes
to play with the frisbee she likes to
play with the ball she likes to play
with people she's not interested in docs
just the way she is and about halfway
through this video you will need to
watch it there is a brief moment where
echo makes it very clear to Bella that
she is not interested so this is diesel
and better hear echoes off-screen of the
known she's actually
barking doing the playback i referred to
earlier on which Bella hears about now
and decides actually all go and see what
echoes up to maybe something later
delegation turns her head that she
wanders off towards echo is running
around echo warnings are there the head
came up the lip came up showing teeth
and Bella comes round to chase thinking
that echoes playing and echo comes
around the back of me opens her mouth
nips Bella on the muzzle and runs off
and she's just telling Bella right here
right now
not interested no pain she's not hurt
Bella she's not intending to draw blood
she's not intending to even really draw
any pain reaction out of her she's just
saying
not now yet another reaction as well you
get fear fear happens quite a lot with
exceedingly dominant dogs approaching
exceedingly submissive dogs and we do
actually have here
saxon who's an enormous Shepherd very
very dominant personality diesel his my
daughter back harness and Fergus who's a
little black think he's a cocker spaniel
and diesel Saxon has been playing
together a little while at this point
when focus comes on the scene Saxon
demonstrate some very interesting
behavior diesel comes along but erm it's
the Saxon Fergus reaction that we want
to see so its senses laid down here
can't see focus on this screen will be a
little black large there is over there
now focus is actually trying to play
with Saxon and there's a lot of tail wag
he keeps bouncing on his paws he keeps
to his head intersection on a player one
player will play on the Play is bouncing
bouncing about Saxons maintaining that
dominant starts he's standing tall
standing over the tails rigidly up in
the air sometimes it works slowly but
it's quite high up in the air then the
reaction from Ferguson is actually quite
confused he doesn't know what to do he
wants to play but he keeps being told
I'm dominant I'm dominant and the
reaction from focuses the tail wraps
on between his legs he puts his head on
the ground that's not enough sucks and
let up and eventually Fergus lace
completely on his back as if you say
okay I don't know what the hell's going
on
I don't want to play anymore are now
scared at that point Saxon wanders off
aggression is seen in dockside anyone
that's seen the news and seeing dogs
bite and injured people will know the
dogs are aggressive but it is
fortunately exceedingly rare ab what
people often see as a dog fighter a dog
fighting with humanism misunderstood
battle of wits and domination or
misunderstood play the actual true
aggression while it exists is
fortunately exceedingly rare it occurs
primarily as a result of a previous
incident is not exclusively true but
often it will occur as a result of a dog
being attacked by another dog when
they're younger so you might get a
shepherd puppy that was attacked by a
lab who misinterpreted some behavior
that Shepherd does become racist there
are dogs many dogs i know personally who
have become racist and it's bizarre to
see in another species but there is
Tilly who's a boxer dane cross she
stands about yay tall see if you put
settles on my shoulders our heads up
here are not very tall it doesn't really
show with the ship stage but in GOP and
she's a lovely dog she's quite well
natured but she's utterly racist to
Polly's if she sees a colleague she
flashes back to behavior that she had
when she was a puppy where she got
attacked by kali she's a colleague she
will run across the field and she will
try and kill it and there is no no no
see
and unless that Connie rolls on its back
pretty quickly
she's going to try and draw blood as I
say it's rare but it does happen if you
see it happen
don't get involved the tops of very fast
the fight so fast the teeth move quickly
way faster than you can get involved and
if they just want to get involved
that's up to them i personally would but
i would not recommend that you do have
similarly if there's a dominance battle
don't get involved let the dog sort it
out and they will generally fight until
someone backs down and that someone
would usually back down before they lose
blood if they don't you're probably
better off out there anyway so these
behaviors we see how dogs interact how
he helped us and this is really where
I'm coming from this whole course stems
from me watching on the field children
get terrified of dogs because of how
their parents react to the dogs around
them and that the classic reaction which
I've used many times we can already is
where a child is walking on happily
going to school talking to his friends
maybe on his scooter and the parents
spies the dog running towards them and
they grabbed the child's hand and they
do that and what that triggers in the
door there's a whole number of things
first of all the doctor sees the tension
immediately and runs over to see if it
can help the hands come up and we saw
earlier on what happens when a dog wants
to play the balls come up and they jump
on each other they see the child go
tense and turn side on and maybe even
run away and we so rarely wrong that the
moment the child starts running the dogs
going to think the Charles playing if it
wasn't interested
it's not going to run its going to stand
side on and it's not going to show any
real reaction to the other dogs so what
we've got is a human culture showing the
dog a behavior is direct contradiction
to how the dogs would illustrate the
same behavior to each other
similarly the welcoming behavior that we
have is a direct contradiction to
another to the way the door to each
other so if I see someone I know like
this invisible gentleman here i might
smile handout i'm showing teeth
I've got handout i'm walking in quickly
i'm doing an aggressive dominant
behavior that a dog is used to when it
sees other dogs so when we actually or
interact with a dog we need to behave
different
to how we behave with humans and
recognize the change in her behavior
first rule when you speak to the dope
show no threat that means you don't run
up you are eternal side on you're not
showing teeth you're not showing your
eyes don't show the many clothes you're
not running towards them you're not
running away i'm just signed on
Oh usually crash down because it brings
my head down I'm much less threatening
the dope is no longer receiving these
gentlemen personality in the video we've
got two decent better playing again and
yes these videos were all taken a one
day and my wife Jo crunches to say hello
to bella who is the white bulldog and
you'll see actually better react
negatively to begin with because when
joe says hello hello hello
when joe says hello she's actually stood
up and she does this and Bella even
being a puppy and not being a hundred
percent sure of dogged language knows
that that's not great and you'll see Joe
then immediately crouches down because i
have to order a couple of things and and
then Bella starts becoming welcoming
hopefully we can catch this so this is
just diesel umbrella just sniffing each
other wandering around together they've
had a bit of a player at this point the
no longer really running but that was
actually trying to play with ezel be a
little bit of a scratch their from Joe
and ballot gives a head up she's not
sure what's going on Joe crouches down
now Bella becomes welcoming Nolan jose
no longer a threat
she's quite happy to have a bit of
sniffing what actually happened there
was the Bellas started to climb on Joe
and Joe stood up to demonstrate a better
actually unlikely with that I'm now
dominant again let's get away from the
play if you're going to start jumping up
and it's a wonderful piece of education
that i use on a daily basis with dogs
that are already trained dogs that are
well-trained is that i will crowd the
mountains stand over them if I want them
to back off from what they're doing and
i will crouch down and stand side on if
i want to play with them or show no
threat
you didn't just be approachable unlike
in human culture is perfectly acceptable
to walk up to another human in dog
culture that can be considered quite
threatening approach if they don't know
generally what they'll do is there
walked 6 10 feet away from someone and
they'll stop they may lay down they sit
there may just stand there but they're
generally just stopping to show each
other
I'm not gonna rush in and threaten you
and then generally one of the dogs will
break the standoff and they'll come in
nice and slow details wiping and say
hello
don't smile it's really important it's a
natural reaction in human culture but if
you smile you to come out and a dog
culture that's a bad thing you're not
necessarily going to cause any truly bad
reactions but you're certainly not going
to show the dog behavior that you want
them to see and one of the wonderful
ways of introducing yourself it's just
put your hand out face down nice and low
well below their shoulder level so that
if they want to they can bring their
head down and sniff it they might make
it see what you smell like to see what
you taste like but generally that you're
showing them
hey I'm no threat but no time are you
going to that dog you're offering a hand
and the dog can choose to come to if the
doctors is not to come to you don't
chase it
the dog will either perceive it as play
or a threat and you probably don't want
either of those reactions
this is william oh I don't let me take
that I'll give a quick brief here is
good what's going on if we go back to
slides we have at so William is a little
boy he's quite a regular on the field
he's 33 or thereabouts he's about to go
to school and he started out being
scared of dogs and I happened to catch
on the day i was doing most of this
video he was walking with his parents
and I ask them if they'll be okay to
video him with diesel who pined of knows
him so we can catch the behavior
yes I think we can skip through school
and what we'll do then i just described
briefly what happens we'll skip the
videos and Williams a little
uncomfortable he's still not a hundred
percent sure dogs but he's he's okay
he stood with his parents diesel is sat
there I lost him to wait while I get the
camera ready and then I release him in
diesel wanders over to them to say hello
he goes to the parents first because the
parents are offering body language
that's more favorable he just guys one
by one and he ends up going to win and
win the little boy is stood there
waiting for these would come to him and
just for a fraction of a second deals
only about this far away William has
second thoughts and he takes just a half
a step back and the act of doing so
these are doesn't even break step he
turns around and walks away
he's taken that just this tiny step that
we as a human party wouldn't even notice
as a I'm not comfortable and he just
wanders off he's not worried he's not
concerned he just thinks Williams not
happy I'm not gonna go say hello
the couple minutes later Williams
chilled out again and we'll try and do
the same
these are comes over and this time
William who's a lot more comfortable
again he's only three and he runs a
diesel diesel comes over just a nice
little gentle tailwags stop six feet
away yet
Williams couple as you take that step to
start closing the gap William colors
hands out and diesel freaks out he's not
sure what the hell's going on now last I
approach this kid
it wasn't confident this time the kids
come running at him with his hands in
the air
diesel turns around walks off quickly
and hides behind me doesn't know what's
going on it doesn't understand it he's
not worried as such but he doesn't want
any part of it and at the same time the
third video which i managed to catch
will skip over is that and there's
another dog star that comes over and
start his kind of seenus comes over to
say hello to this kid and William has
actually learned from these two
behaviors and a star comes over and
stops in front of him William also stops
star then progresses forward and William
progresses forward and they have a
wonderful sub-second momentary meet
where star sniffs William William looks
at the dog gave book and then star
wanders off and that's exactly what they
were trying to achieve in the dog
it is vertically have taught William how
to behave around dogs just by his
parents letting him play so we'll skip
over those videos you two-timing with
tire cover this little bit if you want
to discourage you got approached you you
can choose to stand tall
so you're saying to the dog i'm more
important I'm superior non-dominant I'm
not interested and if the dog continues
to approach one of the wonderful
investment yet one of the wonderful
things you can use a simple app very
sharp noises quite firm quite loud quite
distinct and that's exactly the sound of
dog bark will make when it's trying to
scare another dog off its a couple barks
jam together and if they get really
enthusiastic you get as they're really
trying to say i'm not interested and you
can use that noise to stop doing
something we'll skip over the videos cuz
i'm being around them and encourage play
quite simply bounce around if you don't
want to encourage play standstill
i'm looking at we've got one child in
the audience is falling asleep on that
interesting but if she takes a natural
human behavior and is discouraged by
daughter runs away the top will take
that as a play dr she stands still
the dog will be comfortable if you want
to play with a dog one of the wonderful
ways of triggering it bounced on your
hands in front of it if you've never
done this with a dog do it it's in
various the dog goes oh my god humans
are and they will bounce all over you
they will run around you know jump on
your back the baby uncomfortable just
stand up
keep still the dog will know you've had
enough and it will stop any questions on
every hand up pretty good time we had no
time no time to tour the catch me catch
me outlets
thank you