hello everybody welcome to each of we're
going to kick the keg of I would say
that and
this gig is kind of comedy a nice a kind
of comedy in the I know the I'm funny
but I can't guarantee anyone else
so it's a thing way if you wanna be down
the front that would be amazing
but also even if you don't wanna be down
the front we need you to make quite a
lot of noise
I'll do that Waldie now
is I'll do that like a compact what we
need is he's awake while although I'd
like to go
plays just when would you please welcome
to stage or hosted peak show off
is me state by the
thank you very much indeed
this is tremendously exciting is
tremendously exciting
but let's be honest is also a little bit
awkward where fields
in the mid love wherever this field is I
just got on the truck
did anyone else come did anyone else get
the shuttle bus
to the site's there's a lovely bit
whether San unmarked
truck and you stop when they go get on
the truck
a my first thought was no happy story
starts everybody get on the on Mar
struck
as I was very frightening hello everyone
hello at what we gonna do now is
a thing I do called each show off and
appoint a peach of
is its little bits have me and then it's
longer bits
of people who really clever talking
about whatever is that they like
so they can talk about things that
obsessed them things that they do in
their everyday lives
and I go all over the country doing
things like this I am what is
technically known
as a science comedian keiko who
that was exactly the right level love
who is required to the site's comedian
let me tell you why in 2012
the Independent on Sunday named me as
one of Britain's
top 5 science comedians kinda big a rule
there are currently 6 science comedians
in Britain
is why a sad to claim to fame to have
their
a sadly that one right that fact has not
yet made it onto my Wikipedia page
on how to Wikipedia page the two weeks
game each year if you've got a Wikipedia
page
me I thought this place we flew them
people hacking in from the other side of
the world pretending to be someone else
getting themselves Wikipedia page you
killed your
no I do Wikipedia page two weeks is
currently
where I am learning just how awful human
beings all
because it's it's this amazing see
evening
back a passive aggression there were
only two lines
in my Wikipedia page and people are
fighting over every single word last
week
my Wikipedia page began Steve cross
is a comedian it now begins Steve cross
is a self-described comedian genuinely
can look any view our editors can even
take out because it is so hot
am rights so we've got we've got some
families in the room hello kids
hello hello now I should say I don't
normally compaq extra children only I
compaq eggs in like sweaty pub basements
and things
so this is a little bit of a challenge
for me cuz ninety-five percent to the
stuff
I would normally do I can't do and the
first time I ever
I ever compared to take where with
children in the reams last year
at the Green Man Festival and
I didn't know what to do it's like my
job to get you all really excited so
that when I bring on the people that
know about science and technology
engineering and all those amazing things
that you're going to cheer them like
crazy a so I didn't like it was the I
asked all the children in the audience
what their favorite things were
and then if they weren't popping into
enough I would just shout their favorite
things at them
because the best way to get any child
really happy and really interested in
what you're doing is just to go
why Libya okay see
it doesn't work at all am but I what I
wanted to share with you is what what
the kids have 2013 you're into
and kids a 2014 if you're into these
things i wanna know about it so as to
these kids what's your favorite thing in
the whole world
and I'll go to the edges stage and I'd
lean down
night was favorite thing so the first
kid I went up to
i sat what's your favorite thing and he
looked at me
and first divall he pushed his glasses
up
because that's what we do when we
thinking
glasses I like nerds cigarettes
they just give you a chance to do a
thing why you think and it's free
he looked to me and he said lightbulbs
not I can see the point of fact because
that's really cheap parenting
he wants to always what we gonna do well
I just change the light bulb should we
tell him that light poles the toys
and I was quite fun now than in the next
kid I went up to us it was your favorite
thing in the world
I looked him and he looks at me look
deep into my eyes
and he looked all the way down to the
bottom of my soul
and he actually set darkness
so I went
so he went
darkness
and comedy that is a kid who is really
annoyed
that the show that we're doing a thirty
where I will be properly drunken sway re
is adults only am at so that's all very
exciting
kids in the room considering kids are
doing to them have any view any view
into science
to do science is cool yes
now are you know I wanted to tell you a
story about when I was a child
and I'm only telling this story in order
to watch your parents windstar whole way
through
and try and tell you never to do this so
when I was at school I was
the kid that was good at science and I
was also the kid that really knew he was
good at science
and I was also the kid you haven't
really developed any of the social
skills
that would prevent this from being
annoying to give you an idea of the kind
of things that we used to do
way to physics practical yet to take
lots have measurements
by changing one variable I mean standard
physics stuff
what my friend and I did was we did the
first measurement we did the last
measurement
which align the chewing them up and then
we just made up the other points
being slightly off cuz we're not perfect
we want to send the message
so I we've made it
up with scattered the points a little
bit we got busted and the teacher came
over and he said
there listen Steve Duncan there is no
place in this world
for theoretical physicists to put this
story
in more perspective Duncan who I did
that with
is a professor a theoretical physics at
cornell university now
it's absurd anyway the other things that
we used to do with science experiments
that you weren't supposed to do one of
our experiments was called
what happens if you put a spoonful have
your cats
into a desk everyday I would scribes
experiment you properly
as a scientific space experiment methods
a desk
was taken it was in it was there in the
beginning we didn't like bring in a
special desk
at into the desk was placed one
heaped teaspoon it's important to be
accurate when you're doing science was a
level teaspoon is heaped teaspoon
of natural yogurt each day observations
day one nothing day to
nothing day three the desk smells
day 4 the desks smells
really bad day 5
the desk is not there anymore apparently
they took it away
and burned it it was the only way to
deal with at all sucked in his inquiry
disgusting
anyway as enough about me I'm gonna
bring on some people who knows and stuff
about some stuff to Mitch if you like
people who know some stuff about some
stuff
the
the you're an amazing audience absent
issue already spread out and win a giant
tents normally
both of those are the death of joy but
you also joyful it's brilliant
am I'll that's so this is a lovely first
was it some of the first level in three
nice
M and the so many brilliant people here
all come together
not doing the things you normally do not
shopping in the shots you normally shop
on
Mattman share price has gone down 5
percent just today
right I'm gonna bring some people that
know some stuff by step ladies and
gentlemen are you ready to meet your
first Keech of us today
though it's got to be more than that and
not getting paid as you know
they're only doing this for love and
attention so you have to show them love
and attention
ladies just are you ready to me of us
kicks off tonight the likes you please
login to the site
Cerro y yeah
the hi everybody
thank you very much am great see all hit
thank you
I know a competing against three so many
awesome talks am
so mine if there wasn't and I am a PhD
student
act UCL and the thing that I study
is errors things going wrong right so
I have to say up front that any areas
that do occur during the set
about intentional and very well
choreographed okay
just to be prepared site let's talk
about aris
right Sarah I hear you cry why should we
listen to you don't even have your PhD
yet
well firstly that a really mean thing
fee to bring me up right now okay
PHD's a hard time trying really I'm
trying a.k.a
a hand in a few weeks I kuru my
supervisor just got my back alright
and secondly I I don't actually
need a PhD to be honest with you because
I actually have something
that better right academics we're all
striving
to be cited by now appears we're all
striving to have people
read our papers and write about them but
screw that that's not for me that's not
for me it'll
more why meaningful is far better it's
far better
which is why my name appeared in a
national
newspaper recently Sarah wiseman
University College London here we go
that's a far better than getting my
academic peers to cite me okay
this is a national newspaper and what's
more what's more is no longer
am I just a lowly PhD scientist 09
now I'm a scientist and
not only at high now bean lifted to the
bank serving
scientist I'm actually a Daily Mail
accredited scientists thank you very
much thank you
appropriate reaction I think and as such
this new position I come up with gems
such as customers who make mistakes are
not
idiots what that's mind blowing it only
take me three or four years to come to
that conclusion okay
that's a real insight you're not gonna
get that a wonder the universe or
anything
is Nani each right
okay so as you can get from this I like
talking about aris so
let's start thinking about why
areas matter okay so I'm gonna ask you a
question
what do you think a.m. bar charts
and NHS patient safety records have in
common
the answer is and about to try and make
a joke using both
in my case i strap in and get ready now
I am going to show you some
data from a this is being taken
legitimately from
from the NHS right this is not made up
in any way this is stuff has
beat this naturally occurred in the NHS
okay
so the graph I'm about to show you is a
graph showing you a subset of patients
that were admitted
to geriatric care the last few years
okay geriatric care being
care for elderly people right can anyone
see any mistakes in this
yeah
no one on this graph is over the age of
I am so that's a bit of an anonymous not
just talking about the fact of
for got to label the x-axis I know that
okay I know that you will so that day
but I know it too
again it's not just having at this end
of the spectrum happening at the other
and inspected
so this is going to be a graph love all
the people admitted to
adolescent psychiatric care now on this
graph
is under the age of 30 now I don't know
about you
right but I do know some immature people
but no one is so immature
that medically speaking the NHS will
treat them
as a child now what is going on here
what's happening well
either a year these people these medical
workers they're entering this data into
medical records
and making some a recess living up when
they enter this data all
and which i think is more likely this is
proof that benjamin buttons and don't
exist
okay and I think it's not just happening
with
age it's also happening with gender so I
mean that show you a graph
all the men in the past two years who
were pregnant
this is male admissions obstetrics
gynecology and midwife
epistle hosts okay again is someone
making a route when entering the data
into records or is it brief
that this type the film is more of a
documentary than we could ever realize
now okay those those those graphs were
kinda stupid and
they were funny right there there is
resulted in kinda
stupid statistics coming out and that's
kinda amusing
am but unfortunately sometimes areas
that happen in the medical domain
they're not so funny right when people
enter some data
it can mean that a patient gets
seriously harmed or even killed
and so as a result of this we are trying
as
researches into technology to understand
what happens when people make the stops
there is why these air is happening
now I'm a scientist and the way the
ivory settings is that I stick people in
a laboratory
and I get introduced okay and this is
hard to do when you're studying ARA
like for two reasons now one reason that
you can study area in a lab
is that when you get people into a party
situation everything becomes quite
artificial in
fake and so it's hard to take the
results from the lab
and generalized into the real world
school ecological validity
and so that means studying areas in a
lab is quite hot
the second reason it's quite hard is an
actually just makes you really bad
person because
essentially I'm bringing someone into a
room sitting with them
and waiting for them to fail and that's
just bad feel so lonely and I'm
but luckily luckily I don't need to do
everything
in a laboratory I can get some data from
the real world
and that is what I and my fellow
researchers at UCLA doing
we taking to Twitter to get real
examples Vera
so what we do asking people to switch
from the primary use of Twitter which is
getting incredibly and legitimately i
right about baking competitions
and we're asking them to instead help us
with our research
and so all we're doing is asking people
to every time they make an era
is to tweet about it and tag it with
hash tag
every diary it two straight quarters at
and then that simple thing will allow
our website a retiree to Aug to go
through on a Twitter
and collect these examples a Paris which
creates is amazing
database %uh slips and mistakes
now I'm gonna talk about its mistakes
briefly
as it ever researcher I'm actually quite
a bad friend am so the other day
my friend he well a few months ago he
ended up breaking up with
his girlfriend now it's a normal story
right
this his girlfriend had head gone out
one night and had kissed someone else
and he was thank you he was he was he
was that he was distraught he was it
destroys US and
and it was a pretty you know it's a it's
a terrible thing you know he was really
upset about it and he was like
all but Sarah she said I made a mistake
H
each she made a mistake you know that
she wouldn't do it again and I was like
no no no don't
forgive her you need to break up with
her you know his
but she's just done is libelous let era
as a mistake
and if she can make that saw a mix-up
with every terminology who knows what
else she is capable of
okay that indicted down to you also well
I'm gonna do is help
you be better friends than I am I'm
gonna just give you to fit the
definition between 6 mistakes
so slips these are things that you
plan completed correctly in your mind
but then for whatever reason when you
execute it
it goes horribly wrong so an example of
that is the classic freudian slip
way you say one thing you mean one thing
but you say a mother
I thought that was a long time
and now a mistake air on the other hand
is where you
execute the plan perfectly well but the
plan
be made to begin with was wrong so an
example a mistake era
is when you incorrectly let your friend
about era terminology
while they're going through severe
emotional trauma like I did just that so
is an examples up some Sep some states
let's look at some more
examples era using a retiree now
wanna my favorite favor air is that we
collect on a retiree
is is just so beautiful just so subtle
okay so what we normally trying to do
is great isn't it a retiree sometimes we
get there was a
era de res coming into things and that
is just so beautiful right
either it means that cows are tweeting
from the workplace
ol it means that some people making
hilarious
meta errors about era and I just think
that's beautiful I
that's my favorite error that we collect
I don't care what else it says it says a
retiree I'm happy air dairy
I'm happy tonight is making a right when
I turned the air dairy
I think I did intentional I meant to do
that now let's look at the actual
examples affairs that we collect okay so
they'd
they range from the Monday so things
like
and people trying to enter use that pin
code for their
ATM cash machine and trying to am but
try to put into their Bergeron okay that
is if any straightforward era and its
it's something
while learning about their terminology
that is called an associative
action slip okay so they range from the
mundane like this
to the kind of silly an example if
someone
forgetting to remove the cocktail stick
before eating into a burger
thats is an example and omission era
and emission slit they range from the
mundane to the silly
to the really really silly this is an
example
have someone hurting themselves whilst
air drumming to the eighties pop rock
hit
Africa by Toto that
is an example uva sharing too much on
Twitter slip
okay before I go on I just point out
that all of these areas
a.m. they would ship these ones just
came from my sister
which is a a brilliant way to get around
the ethics is showing the streets in a
show like this
and be a pretty way to make fun of my
sister so tick tick it's a win-win
situation
now the reason that we collect the slips
is because
the thing that make people accidentally
into their paid into a better alarm
all make them try and use at least a
card to get into the house
these the causes that those areas are
exactly the same
as the cause is a bear that make a a
nurse or a doctor
pram the wrong number into a few pump or
makers slip up when they referring to
patients in award
and so if we can understand this massive
databases
everyday slips mistakes then maybe we
can kind of
extrapolate from them learn from them
and take that knowledge
and apply it to designing interfaces or
designing processes in hospitals
and we can design them to their less
error-prone and said we support the work
is more
and help them avoid era from happening
so I mean I'm gonna ask you guys to help
out with the researchers have a simple
request
and the next time that you guys make
a slip or mistake in the real world and
you're really embarrassed
but no one's around to see it then
please
tweet about it and then just add a tag a
retiree
and then we can collect it and then we
can all have a massive laugh at your
expense
am and also like for science
or something
whatever am so that's been my set thank
you so much for listening if you
interested in any other types have
information era I don't know what more
to say am my a
to it and let's hope so no era themed so
please like getting
in contacts have a chat about things
thank you so much to list their thanks
the draft
so
Sarah mentioned that she works for UCL I
also work for you CLG like the t-shirts
I had I had a meeting with a very senior
man
and a very senior mans said we would
like the university to merchandise
more like an American University so my
brain went
0 a specific american to divest it that
was great did anyone else think of way
through that though
if they're collecting that data of you
tweeting you can just lie
you could ruin it forever you could have
said there is data saying
the eighty percent at the errors that
the british public makes
all related in some way to toe toes
Africa that would be a paper
that would get in nature just so that
they could get the social media clicks
from a
it would be brilliant rights we have
another acts his eyes on ex tax: already
Ross wedowee which is double checking
this
because I think about your compass is so
much going on we got people it should be
arriving and then running on Thursdays
a are you all set okay pretty ladies
judge when are you ready to be your
second peak show office after
the lease my said the rabbi
0 the few
gonna here
did Kim weird
birth me
we mapping rather
mapping and
me mapping I'm up organized
is an organization Public Library
when technology in we do
open source tools for environmental
monitoring
share with you wanna to look
I'm
you can see very well ever tell you be
there maybe we should
any air photos want DIY
and absolute mapping is another way
so you Phillip huge balloon with helium
and you send it
up I'm their different ways to attach
your camera to your balloon he can he
was played very well
but here we have I sorta contraction
be cavett and here a bottle
you put Louis your bottle and you put
the camera inside
never take your camera as as you send it
up
1,000 feet up in the air and the you
break your after if
in one of the ways to think AB year
pipeline
her balloon line get cut off and your
balloon flights to India or somewhere
makin me email you back your camera or
at least you're IndyCar
with your valuable pictures but in an
issue you
I'm happy or just a little bit kite
mapping
am this and click here
in idea like I and i know i love you
guys
are makers and doers so
miss you review this is Barney really
need
army is I am Pixma and
sorry I said tight make height to Delta
kite
really huge it flies and also to win am
it material that is again easy to get
festival and it easy to fold a swell
so then was really nice n Easy
about it
he can weekly wrap it up put it in your
backpack
have aspired come apart put it in your
bag and law
travel with it so what are the questions
that I get a lot
is when we use Skype when you use
balloons I think
self-explanatory and also
probably balloons are review
if you're gonna do urban mapping if you
can't do more
outdoor make out wilderness foreign
oceans you when i use skype
am one other problem %uh
using item balloons on like drone in the
have to watch out for power lines but
recently
people have been mapping slums in
Nairobi you know what they do
for power last night in there have the
real
do real family have one here
okay
who the real your text you height your
balloon to
only got power line well hoops been
and they just throw it over the Caroline
and impacted on the other side wouldn't
recommend that because you could lose
your kite a balloon
but people are amazing people are
ingenious and
what other things everyone highlight
about
with wave that we in public lab do
I am environmental monitoring and
develop tools
for micro-environment learning about I
am i mean
exploring is that we want to define
around inclusion so all the material
are affordable locally sourced
acceptable
in very cheap am using each people in a
way that we consider that
everyone have an expertise so welcome
people wanna do
software Park weight involved sexually
working with data
or developing the software better
for their so that we can make different
kind the matter get different kinds of
herma other people just wanna do the
actual mapping
other people went to the campaign other
people wanted to the promotion on my god
I cut myself
am so do I show you pictures
and we've had lots of fun think mapping
all around the world
so public land community kidnapping is
actually
half-a-million been done by over 3,000
people all around the world
so this kind here have been in
Italy yen I'm not gonna brag and EMF
quite
and has been will be fine
and now we're gonna give you a
demonstration are on how we attach
the camera to
and the cut so you
in
okay I'll take over since we've had a
bit
help blood bar
I am this
is called the pic event any sort you can
still see it on the picture behind me
it is simply
a platform to hold the camera underneath
the kite when we do cut mapping a lot of
people wonder
while lifting near the cameras attached
the kite it's gonna blow all over the
place it's going to be really
there's a lot of turbulence I we don't
actually attach the camera directly to
the Chi
reaction it passed a camera crew
platform that is
attacks to the cut line about 50 meters
below
with the kite flies so this means that
you have less turbulence
be if you just attach the camera with a
string you still get a lot of turbulence
and you still get a lot a blurry
pictures
so we you something called a peek at
that which is this platform
if you can see it in from me here it's
either this purple has a lot of things
going to berry's loops
that are attached to to Pisa would
imagine this is there's a line
attached here in this line is moving you
can see that the platform
is more or less course it's still moving
but it's more stable
finished the camera was attached
directly to the line
its call the peak a bit and if you
google that is really simple there are
all sorts of animation show how to
string up
all you need is a piece of wood you cut
into shapes you can attach the camera
with with rubber bands
elastics and then I've just attach to
metal loops you know these kind of
screwed loops that you get the hardware
store
but if you wanna really fancy P give it
use actual
police because then you get even less
friction
cousin is gonna demonstrate how we
attach the camera
okay so we've just got the camera on
attached to a small pad of paper and and
paper towels just two to make it nice
and even
a little bit shock absorbent then she's
you see is quite heavy duty elastic
bands
and we've got a little on peace ovum
tooth-and-nail thats put into the wood
to hold the elastic bands in place
we put in for elastic bands all the way
across
and as you'll see in a moment you don't
have to adjust the left
the elastic band so the lens can come
out and you can take pictures otherwise
of course you're elastic bands prevent
the camera from
from opening up properly but it's really
secure
and on top of it all we've also got this
line here which is a security line which
we attach directly to the cut line
so in case something were to fail with
the peak event
the camera will just slide down the cut
line
and you still you can still retrieve it
then what cindy is doing here now is
adjusting the elastic band so the lens
can come out
I don't know how well you can see this
in the hold up in the air
you can see the camera is just a touch
the former platform
if I turn the camera on the lens can
come out
nice freely take pictures and this is
automatically set
to continuous picture-taking so you
actually
rather than controlling what pictures
you're taking your taking a massive
pictures
and then sifting through afterwards to
take the nice ones that are not learning
not overexposed and saw
eBay think
the actual mapping and their the way
okay to protecting the camera we want to
share this one with you
and will you do with the photos after
dependency can use an early online
square magnet being a picture you select
you lose them you don't need you
referencing because you used to be
player in the background
%uh the program and to align your
pictures so you feel there's a row to
hear that bro
look like this road so %um lightning
menu speech the pictures together you
export your map in multiple formats
you can take your Mac the map being used
in also to form originally was
prototyped
for the BP oil spill in 2010 to map to
get public data
for the damage to the wetlands and the
shore shorelines and how
now within really being and make public
or talked about and the people
whose livelihoods were being affected
couldn't really fee
good picture of what extent of the
damage so that was really good
people have been using it for all sorts
of things like for example
had a conflict resolution in israel so
making maps together
had between Palestinians and Israeli and
which may be right now would be really
useful but maybe not very possible
amber to talk about the sharing up
spaces ankle creation up space
and also been used for disaster relief
and then my mental health and plant
health in farming
et cetera et cetera so get another app
another application is
for demonstrations if you've got a large
gathering of people often the media
doesn't quite know what the journalist
don't know how many people were there
sinew not given workshops at at these
journalism festivals and their
people a stunning usable that is a
really cheap alternative I don't know
I don't member you mention it Cindy this
Tyvek
the material costs for the Skype date
incest into pounds
and the the the
rate of course costs about 12 pounds I
believe and not the rig I mean the
real the real the Regus sissy
costs nothing it's just piece of wood
and
the camera you can get cameras like this
for Oct 25 pounds
so all in all it's a pretty cheap
alternative and the last thing I'll say
is you can see these are the sparse for
the
for the kite you saw me on folding the
kite it folds up nicely I can put in my
backpack
you literally have a very on a you know
easily portable system for taking re
high quality pictures
that you can then upload and share with
people
the for now
the good news is we have a first aider
outside a
lol as a nice to see people suffering
for. there are two little bit you know
they mean it when they keep going as the
blood sprays everywhere
and that was incredible incredible
and we've got one more 10 Keeks to show
off to you
at is currently running outside sorting
Cindy out so I can introduce in a little
bit
and His Names Rossi looks full at
Bristol which is Big Science Center in
Bristol love you got steel slides
okay and ross is kind of the big star of
their YouTube channel
so this kids all over the country
watching ross blow things up
freeze things and blow some more things
up
I'm not saying is repetitive it's not
lazy judge me ready feel quite ok each
show off in the afternoon
though the energy levels are falling is
it's too long since lunch
anymore don't worry late is a Jets win
please welcome to the site
sixty-third I
I like I was a show with its Korean
Apple to call you
Bletchley open-wheel from Exeter places
so I'm US will have a good day
yes glad to hear it I would have been
here for a couple of hours
I'm already absolutely nothing at 107 my
tent earlier on
and what's very friendly people help me
out everyone's very very nice so
I'm enjoying myself very much so far and
someone is Russ
and that today I can be talking to you
about various
animals because what I want to tell you
all packed is saw something known
as intelligent design how nah nah nah
0 because and it simmered not since
essentially and so we can be taking a
look at the evolution
of various animal
some people would have you believe that
we
are the best thats some deities him
man Balaban Spaghetti Monster want
whatever you choose
we're the best that they could come up
with ans
animals go we we are now we have really
past I me with crap
these pic splashy creatures which the
strange appendages coming of us
when you think a beautiful amps really
amazing animals
you think things like the Siberian tiger
a majestic wandering through the snow
you might think if
a bird of paradise which to these
amazing Tarsus
moving their wings around it icon
accompanied us we suspect that the
the best we can with Christmas just
working it's just embarrassing compared
to something like this
kitchens you can't go wrong with a happy
kitten
and I need though
no I cut no I cut to it there's no way I
can compare to something
as cute as last tropical fishes Apsley
peace with all these
vibrant colors that are there even some
insects you be considered peaceful this
is a spider
its how cold is bad how funky is back
Wii
resemble something little more like this
this
his the naked mole rap which basically
just looks like a wrinkly sausage with
legs and teeth
and again just that spasm
much closer resemblance that than huh
done with the kitten
so if we wanted to take
the best bits all these different
animals to make and design
are own all I wonder what it would look
like a wonder
what pic bits and pieces that we could
use we have free rein
to just completely start from scratch
because
it's not just our looks that might lead
to stand in the animal kingdom
we have absolutely terrible memories we
forget things all the time
a did you know for example that
six-percent
all skydiving fatalities because of
people who forgets to pull the ripcord
justice the parsing we have a man
s shakes spine which is very good for
supporting about seventy percent of our
body weight allows us to walk around and
Stratton stages like this
because this terrible back pain our eyes
are essentially stop installed inside
out with that nerves
from the retin-a coming onto the inside
of the eye instead of
back towards our brains the gonna come
act and then in like that
because this this brady pointless behind
spartan each of our highest
so let's think about some credits
so who want to look at some of the most
powerful and credible Hamels
let's see if we can make a predator
gonna start of with the fastest
animal appall the show oh yes this is
all going to be thinking about today so
inspired by the sci-fi channel we're
gonna be combining all of these various
things
we just saw the cheater to the cheater
can go from
not 269 three seconds it reaches a top
speed of 75 miles an hour which is much
much faster
the new same ball to can do 27 miles an
hour
it's much faster I can do about four
miles an hour has my top speed
so this could easily catch me out there
in the world
so this is going to be our starting
point the majestic cheater we're going
to move on
to sure us not think you've shocks
trolls or something like that I'm
thinking of
the Nile crocodile because this guy
has one of the most powerful chose the
animal kingdom
our up bike forced if you match in
biting the trunk
iPhone app that's about a 120
pounds per square inch 120 PSI this guy
could do five thousand-page PSI
its incredibly powerful so as soon
as a cheater has caught you connect now
crop down using the trolls
a saltwater crocodile where we going to
go to next well
this is demand Sri
and this is actually my favorite animal
in the collection
his this guy lives in all sorts of
briefs down at the
bottom of the sea underneath the water
mysis shrimp
but it looks like it was made in the 70
just got this wonderful tie-dye affect
all over it and
one of the most remarkable things about
this animal as its on ice
let's zoom in sick closer looks at these
response now
each one of these can move independently
and and i'd
any direction seventy degrees all around
to see them both moving around
in different directions now we can see
that there's
3 areas and the third middle one kind of
goes across the Middle like abante
so we have to ice which covers
binoculars vision allow us to
perceive depth in church how far way
things are each
one of the mantis shrimp size has try
not kill a vision our ice
also contain things called Color
receptors
so there are brought switched attacked
and movements in
cunt blacks and whites and grays and
things like that when you're in a dark
room 218
height in a dark room I slowly start
with just using the Broads
in your eyes another cone cells which
helps to detect color
we have three types account south so
we've got
red blue angry and using all of those we
can see
every single covering for thousands and
thousands of colors everything from
beige to top but
the mantis shrimp has not three
can cells not four not five but 6
gene different kinds have come cells
this guy
can see colors we can't even imagine
enter ultraviolet
an infrared lights this guy can see all
hopes
dreams even though internet history this
absolutely
terrifying so this is what we're going
to be using to see
are prey then we move on
to the grizzly bear now the scariest
thing about the grizzly bears night
strike and sexy
that we can see here it snows has one of
the most powerful noses in the
animal kingdom help bloodhound consume
any pretty well
but the grisly pear has a nose the
seven-time shrunk a
and millions and millions of times
stronger than ours we can text back
10,000
different kinds of smell but the grisly
back it smell you
from 18 miles away CPB eighty miles away
from this guy and he would still be able
to smell you
and not only that beacon smell you
across
time this is just insane can you imagine
that
soak if it picks up your scent it can
tell
how far away the you've been where you
where and exactly how it's going to
track you a hunt to Janie's in the
census now so even
if you can't see you it snows is going
to drop
tracking your this
is the crates gray al also known as The
Phantom of the notes
school name this is silent death
on wearing his because it has
the best yes of the animal kingdom in
fact
its into higher face axe
like a gigantic here so we have our ites
which help to you pick up the sand and
diverted into RNAs
butts his entire face is shaped like a
parabolic dish
that focuses that sent and all the Fed
has that covered space known
as a rough now focuses the sound
to it each miss yes so we have two years
on either side of her head
and this allows us to pick up what
direction sound is coming from
so depending on if the sound is coming
from over there is gonna hit
my left ear before hits while right my
brain is pretty clever it's able to
figure X
timing between those two things in tel
me a brief idea of where its
but it's useless if something's coming
at you from
dead-on what they're behind because it
hurts but your years at the same time
to the Owls overcome this by having
asymmetrical years what is
ever so slightly higher in Fort it
always has a slightly lower
so how effective is
the ES a great gray owl well it can
detect the beetle
hidden in the grass
about a hundred yards wager scurrying
around it can hear the squeak
a mouse hoff a mile away
that's just incredible and then it's
swoops down
from the trees landing on its prey
catching it with its talents
to the next time you see an alcove Bobby
gets hurt
ran like this looks very cute what it's
doing theirs
honing in on its prey to get exact
mock to a concert with Dan I get a meal
this
hasten star nosed mole and
it looks kind of a cross between
Wolverine with some clothes here
and a plushie toy that's just been
squeeze really hard so
you so we called it insights coming out
of its face
but its nose is absolutely
incredible switch able to kinda it's a
combination of touch
and tastes similar painlessly and it's
the fastest
eating animal in the world his this
knows has a back twenty
of these tentacles all around it and
that covered in these tiny tiny little
dots called
I miss organs and using these I miss
organs its freely around underneath the
ground
its I size incredibly poor sprint
replied it just uses
his nose stuffy around underneath the
grant miss looking
for a meal but as it feel something
in 10th a second it decides whether to
eat it
or not is going on mad mad mad mad mad
mad mad mad mad mad world mad mad mad
mad mad what
it does incredibly quickly even as as
underwater it's so fast that edge X is
little apples into the water
so that can taste what underneath the
water
before then borrow Smackdown underneath
the ground
absolutely incredible I'm going over 10
to the mantis shrimp because this has
another feature
just even cooler minutes ice because
once are predators smelled your head
you're so you act
we to give it a weapon and this creature
has
the best weapon in the entire animal
kingdom
see might be able to see just around
here is got these ok back to real
appendages go a little bit like this his
even though
this guy looks very peaceful very
harmonious
like I said it's like he's been design
in the seventies so
you might imagine him car coming along
and splitting up some fun snowman
who just want to live in peace just be
like me just embrace the conner is still
around
not known in another this I aquariums
dome half use because
they Cahill everything else
in the czech so it goes along and
instead of breaking up the fight
just goes what if we just what a
three-time
and he's back to morial appendages fling
acts smashing
whatever's in front of it they
accelerate 23
meters per second that's the same speed
as a bullet coming from a .22-caliber
rifle
and it hits its target with 1500
Newton's a force to give you some idea
of just
how much that is if we were able to
throw a ball at a baseball
with one 10th of that force
we could throw that ball into orbit
ass it moves these back to real
appendages forwards
it's going so fast but it instantly
boils the water in front of it creating
a shockwave
nah shockwave is powerful enough to kill
its prey anyway
2x celebrates forward to the shock wave
then it creates something called a
cavitation bubble
she's a bit like a vacuum as the water
gets pushed guys in front of it
as the vacuuming collapses back down one
of these tiny bubbles
it creates temperatures up thousands of
degrees Kelvin
his much hotter than even purse
surface of the Sun as the bubbles then
collapse the and Mitch
lights in a strange process that no one
really understands we call it saw no
luminescence has pretty terrifying
so we've learned about all of these
different ways that animal skin catch
their prey or
even Beach up when it finds it but would
you guys like to see
the perfect animal if we combined all of
these different things
into a single creature to terrify s
for the rest of our lives because let's
see it every game
settlement if there was such a thing as
intelligent design we would live in a
world that would be
dominated by creatures like this and it
would be
absolutely terrified thank you
I've been ross thank you very much
sex in today's it's just so yeah
the jolts have nightmares
at those if you've enjoyed the show
we're gonna be back 8:30 tonight
doing another key show of where I will
be for all Harley hammered by the time
it starts
so that's going to be quite exciting
thank you you've been an amazing journey
it's collateral calls for everyone the
scene so hard
the say
the