hello everybody my name is Eileen
Donahoe and Nico asked me to come speak
to you about the united nations or the
UN
and I i guess my personal connection let
me start their my personal connection to
the united nations which I will tell you
about the entity itself with that I was
the you s ambassador to the UN Human
Rights Council in Geneva for four years
from 2010 through 2013 and I now work at
a human rights organization called human
rights watch as the director of global
affairs and we basically try to put
pressure and scrutiny on the governments
throughout the world to live up to their
commitments that they've made through
the UN system that's my connection I
went out and talked a little bit about
the connection between routes and the UN
and let me let me first half of the kids
who are here in the audience anybody you
know 15 16 or younger have you heard of
the United Nations has anybody heard of
the united nations they've heard of one
person who was actually sixteen year old
and said I think I've heard of the
United Nations so let me start by saying
the united nations have some one
important thing very much in common with
roots roots was founded with this idea
that you're trying to make the world a
better place and create a better world
and I thought I understand it this whole
project is to try to empower all of you
to understand your power and
responsibility to make the world a
better place and in many ways that's
what the UN was also founded for and
interestingly the reason I decided to
put this slide back up which was
something that sci-fi and Christina head
up at the very top of the program
these are these are they actually this
is
it's the way it's the one before this is
these are the rules but you don't have
to drive the changes lied I will tell
you I'm interested in the principles the
principles behind the founding those are
the values you get it even before the
rules values are laughing at the first
that's it ok if you look at those by
Principal the same principles apply at
the UN in fact the united nation was
founded on the concept that the world is
one we're all connected these
connections are growing stronger and
faster every day and that has been true
since the founding of the UN chaos
control the connection focus control the
chaos and you control the focus so I'm
gonna tell you how these things apply to
the UN now so the UN United Nations was
founded seventy years ago way before the
internet existed and it was founded in
the aftermath of World War Two where you
know over 60 countries around the world
hadn't been engaged in a multiple year
war that covered much of the globe
millions of people were killed and much
of the planet experienced physical
devastation and that devastation was
enough to get the leaders of the world
to say ok this is not acceptable
we've gotta figure out a way to solve
problems without going to war so the
original idea was that each government
in the world would come together at the
united nations they would send a
representative and that those
representatives of their governments
would sit down and and and solve
problems without you know fighting in a
physical military way today there are a
hundred and ninety three government
that are part of the UN and the original
organization of the UN had three parts
one part was the protection of
international peace and security
basically preventing war second part was
economic development and alleviating
poverty because everybody understood
poverty was a big driver of conflict
third part this is part I really care
about is the protection of human rights
and the idea that individual individual
people by virtue of being a human being
have certain inalienable rights the
rights don't come because the government
gave you the rights you've got them
government's job is to protect and
promote the freedoms and rights of their
own citizens so those were the founding
ideas
the other very interesting piece of this
is that at the time they were the
understanding that governments
controlled physical territory and that
each government was responsible for the
security inside the geographic physical
boundaries of that territory and they
responsible to the people within that
territory citizens so what happened the
internet came and have completely
disrupted this entire system in certain
very challenging ways the internet
doesn't really recognized geographical
boundaries as particularly important you
can communicate with people anywhere on
the planet and governments don't really
control that ability necessarily part of
what's happened is that a lot of power
has been distributed from government to
private sector technology companies as
well as to individual hackers are
incredibly empowered be the be all kinds
of entities in the world in particular
other
events and there is this sort of new
power dynamic
what we call a symmetry it used to be
you have one government against another
government or multiple governments
fighting against each other but at least
you sort of knew who your enemies were
and what their abilities were and you
knew how to think about protection and
when you do you know make a deal
currently governments are so much more
vulnerable because individual hackers or
peak people anywhere can disrupt their
societies and caused massive damage so
and I want to connect what you what you
guys are all doing with the three big
project that the us- was formed for the
let you start with that first one
international peace and security people
being trained here could play an amazing
role in helping government as well as
private sector entities as well as
individual citizens around the globe to
protect themselves in terms of their
digital security and in particular
protection of critical infrastructure
because now the concept of war but
everybody's focused on now and the
biggest threat everybody's worried about
is cyber warfare and what's really
challenging about cyber warfare is it's
difficult it's called an attribution
problem it's difficult to know who your
attacker is and so the importance of
protection of your critical
infrastructure becomes so important
because you you you can't necessarily
deter the bad actors with your own
physical overwhelming power as you could
have in the in the previous age you can
be attacked from anywhere and it's
difficult to know even who go after so
cybersecurity for critical
infrastructure is something you up you
all could be working on the second big
pillar of the UN
is the one about economic development
and want you to think about this there
are 7 billion people in the world of
those seven billion four billion more
than half do not have connection to the
Internet
they do not have access to information
communication technology digital
technology and therefore all of the
resources and information that you
experience in your life because of those
connections are completely lacking for
just try to imagine what would it be
like to live if you didn't have access
to digital technology and the internet
so that the second big bucket where you
could put your skills to work if it is
enhancing or or exponentially expanding
the access to information communication
technology that's the second big UN
project you could really help the third
one that I really care about is the
protection and promotion of human rights
and hear the Internet has in some ways
been incredible boon to the exercise of
human rights in effect the Internet has
become the landscape on which people
actually exercise all their freedoms
freedom to access information people
freedom to share information
freedom to communicate what they think
form their opinions
share their opinions and communicate
with people around the world also that
means by which people organize
themselves for any kind of project that
they're engaged in for social good it's
done via the internet and that's called
freedom of assembly and association but
access to information
ability to communicate that's freedom of
expression fundamental right
freedom of assembly and association how
you organize yourselves is done
essentially on the Internet at this
point and it's done globally people can
connect with each other all over the
world so that that's the upside down
side of the internet or digital
technology and information communication
technology is that it's also empowered
government in certain ways that
completely undermines human rights so on
the one hand you have a repressive
government that basically monitor and
track everything their citizens do and I
can tell you that if you knew that
everything you were doing at every
minute ago said you know cameras in your
hotel room
everywhere you win by your government it
would obviously have massively what we
think chilling effect on your exercise
of your freedom would be less likely to
say what you think out loud you'd be
less likely to meet with people who you
thought you might put at risk
you just constrained by virtue of not
having their privacy enhance the ability
to do mass surveillance of everybody
with the digitization of everything so
what I would say is that the part of
human rights protection and promotion
that you all could really help with is a
digital security for individuals and
helping governments understand that the
way they actually protect their national
security is my understanding the digital
security of all of their citizens as
individuals the digital security of
everybody's data their health data their
banking records you know there's search
records all of it is that is an aspect
of security that is not antithetical or
against national security it's actually
the means through which you achieve
leave your national security the other
thing and I think you all work in this
space and you're enhancing digital
security
gotta advocate for the importance of
that digital security to your
government's the other big piece of it
is just plain advancing the idea that
privacy itself is a right it's a human
right its international universal human
rights that every individual should have
and in many places in many government
conversations it's not well understood
and it's not valued adequately but the
basic idea is that you you cannot
exercise any of your other rights or
other fundamental freedom freedom to
form opinions to collect information to
share your opinions expressed yourself
to have meetings freedom of movement
freedom of assembly and association none
of those things are really possible or
fully possible if you have no zone of
privacy because as I said every if
everything you do is being tracked and
monitored and watch your not gonna feel
empowered to exercise what you would
your right to do what you would
otherwise do and I believe your
generation and all of you in this
program are so far ahead of the curve in
understanding the value of privacy and
part of your job is not just the
technical dimension it as advocates out
in the world for the importance of
privacy to all of your freedom and and
by the way to your security to the
security of your country to national
security
to international peace and security
we've got to start with the protection
of privacy so let me stop there though
those are the basics about the UN and
how closely
it relates to the work of love you all
of you were doing and there's a space
for you to help with
in the international peace and security
cyber protecting critical infrastructure
with cybersecurity helping connect the
world to the internet but most
importantly advocating for privacy as
the core the essential piece of being
able to exercise human rights anywhere
so I don't have any questions you want
to ask anything
ok that's it