talk on capitol of play and who's gonna
do quickly what is capture the flag and
talk about how you can compete in what
the challenges are like my name's jet
lag security robots track cross country
and
and minecraft netbook and what is
capture the flag capture the flag is a
unique series security contests where
you try to bring things I think Lee and
you get a flag so an example would be
breaking into a website to get a
password is usually two different styles
of jeopardy style where they give you a
board and you select different
categories and then you exploit those
programs or codes or websites and
they'll give you a flag if you do it
correctly there's attacking the facts
where you're given a system and they're
even a system and the same system and so
you try and find exploits in your system
and then you can exploit them on the
other system kind of like you try and
find the holes in your fence and so you
know where the holes in their fans are
many competitors are financed and
breaking theirs
capture the flag a lot of fun you can
learn a lot and you kind of learn in the
sink or swim situation where you get it
or you don't and you don't have a lot of
help around yourself and your TV and
your ability to Google and learn to
speak on behalf of others without
breaking the law
the nice thing about capture the flag is
that they're giving you permission to
break these things so I capital is a
year-round event so you can do it almost
whenever they usually last 48 hours some
of them last week or two weeks though
which is nice but can also a
time-consuming you want to do other
things a good place to work with BCG
have time they have postings for
upcoming events and previously been so
you can look at how challenges result
peco CCF is a really good one for middle
school and high school they have a
really good program and they also if you
sign up the mailing list the late you
know about other high school middle
school dance that are coming out which I
like getting into the competition
there's usually four main categories
which forensics and exploitation those
already breaking codes usually do that
through ways either using math and logic
like in a substitution cipher where you
do
quincy analysis you look at how common
letters are and he's walking out of the
way would be working really really hard
by crystallography where things are just
plain sight so so am i right
invisible message like writing in lemon
juice
you hold under a black light and it
shows up being examples in order to see
where things are hit last we use brute
force
usually in a competition you want to try
and avoid this one because it's time
consuming and processor intense but it's
used to bring shoes and break the
password hashes example would be as they
give you like a Windows password hash
you might have to crack that it's just
to try every possibility until I get
something that looks passable this is an
example of the fee where someone's
hitting on that file so I had enough
water and it's like bookends so anything
that's after the Porter is this regard
about the image processor so the image
looks normal but when you scroll down to
the bottom
it is to find a new biography you just
use sorry like being dirty X or X at it
and you can look through that is usually
three kinds of challenges that it'll be
like find the password or break into a
database or fake a cookie and so on your
password can be as easy as looking at
the source code for comments or for jobs
before they've done client-side
authentication so where the codes
authenticate that your real is running
in your browser is a really bad idea
because then you can change that and
attackers to change it and breaking into
a database sometimes you'll have to use
SQL injection to break in and steal
passwords or get access to it and this
is usually done through SQL injection
SQL injections kinda like a Trojan horse
you send the website your code and it
looks normal but then once it gets to
the database is interpreted and it turns
out to be something that executes its so
once that execute that it'll return
database information to the user
database information can be anything
from username password email to
credit card number phone number house
and social security number so depending
on what your story it's a bad idea so
here's an example of how client-side
authentication works this is how you can
find a password if they're often the
case in your browser using javascript
code for the web page and let the
comment
we find the JavaScript source or going
to the page and this is the jobs bill
that's being executed when you press the
button to try and login to the web page
so that it's reading through each
character of the user's input so it
starts at zero on it counsel the way
through it and checking if each
character matters what it thinks it
should be and so Jas 20 mins the first
character should be gay and then the
next character CBS and i underscore so
I'm just typing that out and then a CNN
and you win and will try and find
passwords or look at what website they
went to or who's trying to attack the
website and then there's recovering
files where the view an image a snapshot
of someone's hard drive and you have to
look through that snapshot and find
files or passwords or virus that
infected the computer and then find
whoever installed
this is an example of packet capture
that's not working but the way you solve
a problem like this would be you opening
wider short and you can just search for
strings so if you hit ctrl alt you can
search by a string or search and then
you can change it to be by string and
then you can look through all the
details in the packet and you can look
for password so that might bring up the
password for him or that can bring up
the actual passwords mission part this
brings us to exploitation exploitation
is all about breaking things that's what
is possible because of coding mistakes
where the person who wrote the program
do a sufficient job securing it and so
as the attacker you're able to break the
program this is in CT outs that I do
most two most common are close to where
it's like a bucket and as you pour more
and more water into it fills up and
after fills up it'll start to overflow
and the overflow gets executed by the
machine organs returned to the machine
which allows you to do things like take
over the process where you can run your
own code and then there's format strings
which is where the programmer didn't
specify what kind of output you should
it should give so the attacker can
change that they can say instead of
returning a string return integer
Lawrence ever attorney an integer return
a memory address and then in that
address you can see what's happening and
you can look at the code below
example where you don't overflow
oh yeah sorry what's your question
so he found a bunker overflow in his
game where he could tell it is it tell
us how much money something else and
then you can get the money from it so
number and then it gives you the item is
not merely simple version it's not as
complicated as a video game but the same
principle where you give it something
that's too big it will execute or so the
code for this is actually just saying
check if this variable is and if not do
something else
prints you win so variable is stored
right above the buffer so once you over
for the buffer but next thing gets
written to that variable so you want to
have that exact exact amount of water to
fill the bucket and so she is generating
a pattern so I can tell how big the
bucket is so I can find how many letters
I have to send to the program for it'll
change the variable so you're find that
it's
gonna be 70 76 bytes 76 characters then
in Python I'll print 8276 times and then
whatever it needs to be in this case I
think it needed to be da so that's how
you would go about it a lot of them
though the source code but then they
won't give you the source code so
sometimes it's just a matter of trying
things and looking at the code that's
why does anyone have any questions
ok I'm doing a workshop on capture the
flag now this is the URL for the
workshop there's some practice problems
like in the talk here
cryptography is by gloira now waving his
hand