hey guys my name is Julian and I'm lucky
enough to work on the facebook security
team we gotta go to work day in and day
out and protect that 1.5 billion people
that use our product everyday connected
family friends new and old and like
mines across the world this is pretty
daunting task but helping our people
shrink the physical boundaries of the
globe and catching all the bad guys in
the process is a pretty rewarding
endeavor I'm you today to remind you
about how important information security
really is to talk a little bit about
what a career in the field looks like
and to finally give you some creer
pointers on how to best prepare yourself
for really impactful job history but
first a couple questions raise your hand
if this is your first year at DEFCON
raise your hand if you get excited by
technology and everybody yeah raise your
hand if you use the internet everyday
all right now raise your hand if you've
heard of a major breach or attacking the
last year for some scary things are ok
so as you already are no information
security is incredibly incredibly
important more important than ever we're
putting more and more of our lives
online and in return we getting services
that we love to use online banking be
able to pay our bills shopping connected
to people in ways we never thought
before possible and it's amazing power
there that gives each and every one of
us but it also means that there's a huge
spotlight on security right now because
with these opportunities and convince
his connectivity there's increasing
risks and additional opportunity for
those with less than good intentions and
thanks to some very large hats and tax
the last couple years we've seen how
catastrophic destructive these can be in
the last year alone hundreds of millions
of people across the world have become
victim to data breaches fraud intrusive
malware in 2014 alone there's a 46%
increase in data breaches mus 46 percent
one year so our jobs defenders
protectors gets more challenging as it
must be faster more flexible on
prevention detection response
capabilities attackers are getting
smarter motivated by financial gain
media fame and a new word has been
introduced into our vocabulary
cyberterrorism with all this the
complexity of threats increases and to
handle this
to address what is really in my mind the
defining challenge the 21st century by
building a safer now everybody we the
very best and brightest tackling issues
at all levels
unfortunately the curry out in this
regard it's very very worrying with the
astronomic rising importance information
security but demand for InfoSec talent
from that town has grown three and a
half times faster than the overall I T
job market and 12 times fasten a total
labor market and our current pace over
two-thirds of the jobs go unfilled due
to insufficient pool of talent did this
last year alone there are 200,000
national postings and took recruiters 36
percent longer to fill those in all
other job postings combined so for
example at Facebook it takes us about 15
to 20 times longer to fight to find and
hire really did InfoSec engineer as
opposed to normal software engineer and
that's really really difficult it's it's
it's really scary so in other words
everyone scrambling to find this really
high-quality InfoSec talent to meet the
growing demands of the industry and
luckily for you people in the room you
guys are exactly who are looking for so
if you're worried about a job
information are you worried about
longevity animation security you really
need not be you you guys are you were
looking for
so you all know information security is
incredibly an increasingly important to
the future of technology and national
security like so then what is it clear
to both cyclic like even myself I had a
really difficult time conceptualising
all the different teams and security or
do before I started Facebook at the it's
really invaluable County take a deep
dive and look at where different teams
doing a different career possibilities
out there are are out there so bear with
me for a second I'm gonna use this the
team that Facebook as a kind of model
I'm used it seems the model is how it
happened Facebook each department's
little bit different but you get the
general options out there so we have a
product security team are private
security team runs our bug bounty
program where we have white house
researchers across the world
world's meeting both phones and bugs
this team repose them and it works well
across functional partners to push
patches and we have a computer emergency
response team these the guys responsible
for detecting and responding to
technical threats that ames compromised
our infrastructure these our nation
states looking for protester information
these are individuals looking for user
data we have a software and team
responsible for building software to
protect our infrastructure a lot of its
log monitoring and and
anomaly detection we have an open source
security team that worked most closely
with our team is focused on developing
open source security products that
empower Facebook their goal is to
re-imagine how modern information
security problems are solved in Crete
free reliable software that allows
Facebook and other organizations to
improve their security really if the
industry as a whole doesn't just improve
our security posture we're kind of all
in trouble we have a safety protections
team these guys that are out there
catching the really really bad people
that use our site people with incredibly
nefarious intention we have a sturdy
operations team that you wrote mapping
budgeting project management technical
project management there goes to really
scale the organization in a way possible
that allows us to meet our goals so we
have a broad range of teams and what's
really interesting is when an incident
comes up with a we have a breach every
single one of these teams in one way or
the other is affected everything from an
open-source team they start looking at
ways to kind of patch a bigger problem
everything on his team gets pulled in
cross-functional manner and it's it's
really exciting to see so now you have a
better understanding of what the
different careers look like in the field
what can you do to best prepare yourself
for career earlier so first you use to
capture the flag competition before
awesome awesome ok perfect so we at
Facebook grand one here a couple of days
ago and it's kind of the perfect first
recommendation get as much hands-on
experience as you possibly can
nothing is more important than getting
hands on keyboards for every lesson you
learn a text book online do everything
you can to apply to recreate that lesson
on your own even at the college level
companies like mine have a really
difficult time finding students who
actually have the ability to do
themselves what they've learned InfoSec
town as you'll
InfoSec trickle imagine learn is far too
often
conceptual and there's very little time
to actually apply the concepts of
students are learning many colleges are
very against allowing students to hang
around and kind of implement what
they've learned and so any opportunity
to get hands-on experience is incredibly
incredibly valuable one at your level
I'd recommend participate in Pico CTS
Carnegie Mellon it's great for students
ages 13 to 15 after that their cyber
pitcher at the high school level of
course CCDC at the college level
Facebook sponsors all of them and we we
run competitions each one of them if
they're absolutely incredible I can't I
can't recommend it enough doing these
types of challenges lets you apply that
the aryan demonstrate your credentials
to someone who can actually code and
solve problems it gives you a proving
that you understand the best way to
apply what you've learned CTS in our
estimation are truly the missing
resource of the core curriculum out
there
ucts do as many extracurriculars
possibly can separate yourself from the
pack as you'll find when you study
information security there's thousands
and thousands of other students doing
the same thing so just like in any field
you separate yourself do as much the too
much experience as you can outside the
classroom leverage the huge repository
of online resources to increase your
knowledge of info second CES across the
board and we're totally build a
portfolio of your code to show people my
final recommendation here is
specialization so you guys are young
enough to have to worry about
specialization you need a color as much
as you can this point but companies such
as mine don't really look for very
well-rounded people from a technical
standpoint rather we look for
specializations so you folks have a long
way to go before you need to settle on
specific field but you're getting the
necessary understanding baseline in
those that try to identify and build
upon the things you get most excited
about is your learning now actually i
find some areas that excites you more
than everything else
dig into that and make sure that you are
the best person in the world at whatever
you like right so when the company is
looking for someone to really good at
reverse engineering or malware analysis
or crypto that we can call on you and
you will be indispensable
specialization to channel Mark
Zuckerberg safety and trusted internet
or more important today than ever the
Internet is our shared space
it helps us connect it spreads
opportunity it gives us a voice it makes
us stronger and safer together to keep
internet strong we need to keep it
secure so in closing I request for all
of you each and every one of you have
risen the challenge come to DEFCON at
your age and you're you're taking the
steps that most evenings down to learn
that's fantastic keep doing it
keep doing it you clearly have we really
need more of you to stay passionate they
really curious never back down for a
challenge because you fear the unknown
that's what's juries all about we don't
know what the unknown this we don't know
what we need to know so literally the
only way to find out is to try take
risks and blazer on path as generic as
that sounds legitimate a candidate this
the safety and security of the Internet
in the future of the Internet depends on
you so keep studying keep learning and
apply everything you learn we will hire
you once you graduate thank you