alright so I'm Nick McKenna and today
I'm going to talk about using the NSA
toolkit which basically means using mass
surveillance tools for yourself by and
what that entails is basically two
different schools of tactics and those
are dragonettes which are things that
just sit there passively and either
collect or inject packets so they change
what you see when you browse the web or
they will just collect what you see when
you browse the web the next set is
called TOA which is a tailored actions
and operations and tailored access
operations which is basically just
hacking into things that they that
government deems high-value targets and
those are done through methods like
social engineering using zero days or
more advertising and i'll talk about
what all those mean later but for now
i'm going to start with dragnets so as I
mentioned dragnets or anything that sit
there and collect what you're doing on
the web so they just sit there and they
see you're going here you go in here and
they see everything about you and they
kind of build a dossier on you and God
because of this because of the position
that is be there in which we'll talk
about in a moment
ISPs are very important to attacks like
this and because of that governments
like to have very strong relationships
with ISPs so what is a nice p is p is a
is your internet service provider so
they take you send I want to go to
google.com and it figures out where that
is and it takes you there and it returns
everything and it gets all your requests
as well so why do they do this they do
this because ISPs are in a very
interesting position because they are
between you and where you want to go and
illustrate this i have what i have an
example so now back to my original demo
so say that I go and I open itunes it
will as you can see it will see all the
feeds it will see everything that I
listened to and that's somewhat
interesting information for government
like and they there and governments to
click this from time to time and use it
to learn about people and as you could
imagine if you watch all of someone's
traffic for days or even years you can
learn a tremendous amount of information
about them
additionally you can also see everywhere
they go on the internet so that I go to
my website as you can see ok
it shows my traffic but anyways you can
inject things into the browser and
that's that's one of the reasons that
the position of an isp is very important
to someone that wants to do mass
surveillance
so anyways moving on so just to recap
the position of an isp is important
because you can see everything that
someone does and you can inject stuff
into what they see you can both see what
they see and you can change what they
see ID so one example of this happening
is something that done by GCHQ which is
a British intelligence agency and that
program was called squeaky dolphin it
was where the government recorded
everything that users did try to figure
out who they were and what they did
which is somewhat scary arm and
summarized here the quote from Kristin
going about it and that quote is the UK
government's monitoring Facebook likes
and youtube video views arguably
impacted huge number of people who the
government knew were doing nothing wrong
they've collected both data and saw this
as a way of getting useful analytics so
how they do it is two words and they're
not back two words are zero days so 0
days
your days are experts for which there is
no fixed so you can infect anyone
running a service if you want to UM so
it
infections happen generally on a mass
scale and generally only by very corrupt
government so Syria and other people
that are trying to maintain control
their citizens so this and it becomes
very scary what they will use them for
so generally it's used for more enhanced
data gathering so things like how you
can you can take off someone's passwords
with something called the keychain dumb
so what that does on OS X is it allows
for an attacker to get all the users
passwords and this is a backdoor left
God was put in by its own which
government but it is it was put in by a
government now here we go
ok so right here I have something called
metasploit which allows me to attack a
target which i'm about to do so this is
the target
and right now i'm going to i'm going to
run that light so right now I'm telling
it just will look for the X plate so I
want to look in
but yeah um and then so these are a
number of exploits for older versions of
OS x
and then when i run it will show a page
on Fred the system was not working on
but basically what it would do is it
would allow me to when it that machine
access to the page it would allow me to
control that computer and make it do
whatever I wanted to and that is
something the government have been known
to do but usually only for high-value
targets so if you want to learn this is
kind of just a quick recap of what
government can do and if you want to
learn how to do these texts i'm doing a
demo over there a now we thank you