hi there everybody i'm carole mcsweeney
and I'm whenever federal government
officials that at DEFCON this year and I
know that sounds kind of probably
unusual for people last year ago
actually spotted me as the Fed which is
pretty fun and I wanted to just take a
minute to talk about why the federal
trade commission is here at DEFCON
between a couple of things when we're
running a competition in the contest
area which is designed to help us get
better tools and used technologists to
defeat robo calls which are those
annoying phone calls that you get even
if your mobile number if you still have
one landline numbers registered on the
Do Not Call list we did a contest here
last year that was really successful and
we're doing one again this year so we're
really excited about that but we're also
the part of the federal government that
really i think is aligned with the white
hat mission and the honor code here in
truth how to protect consumers and make
sure that they are getting information
about both the security of the
technology that they're using but also
what's happening to their information
and things like that in absence and
other technology as they're using it so
we're expanding our reach and research
and harnessing the power of
technologists and the research community
and hackers to help us protect consumers
in the marketplace and we're really
excited about that mission so our chief
technologist Ashkan Soltani and I are
here this week also giving a talk about
how technologists and hack for
government and we really are excited
about the valuable research and
information that we get out of this
community because it helps us bring the
cases that we bring that help protect
consumers in the marketplace and as
consumers are growing increasingly
connected and we have all these great
new innovations and devices and
everything else that is wired up in our
lives we're finding that we need a lot
more help from the technology community
in order to understand exactly what's
happening to consumers and whether they
are being deceived by promises that are
being made about their privacy whether
their information it's been adequately
secured and I'm super excited as a
parent five and seven year old who will
probably be he retreats next year that
route is starting from a really young
age to talk about the really valuable
mission that we can bring as researchers
and people understand technology to
protecting consumers I love the Honor
Code out front I think it's terrific and
I think this program is so incredibly
important and inspiring young people to
take their talent and know-how and use
it use it for good so I invite you to be
a part of our mission at the Federal
Trade Commission always happy to answer
any questions we're wandering around
this weekend I would love it if people
visit us in the contest area as well
to find out how we are trying to create
new tools for consumers to help deal
with some of the underlying problems
that come up from members and Robo
colors and things like back thanks for
having me and will be around so I invite
you to come ask questions and thanks for
participating in this terrific program