my situation report on the trip because
they aren't over there will never be oh
we are in a stage of human history what
we doing something that hasn't been done
in five or seven thousand years seven
thousand years ago we began to move into
city and for the first time people could
really good fraction of their lives amid
you omit things built by human beings we
get to the point of modern city you
could not actually walk on on the ground
you could not go very long time slot
being outdoors you can be an air
conditioning etc
things that will matter of natural law
became matters of human policy
convenience decision and now we're doing
it again we are moving our culture as
rapidly as the venture capitalists will
lend us the money we are moving it into
into cyberspace and who controls
cyberspace is going to be a major aspect
of
of the next so what are the crypt awards
as they stand at the moment it's allowed
by the FBI various other people that
they should have a right maybe with a
court order to get access to any
information that you that you have
outside of your head and so they get
your cell phone
they want to be sure that they can so to
speak pry it open and see what senate
get your communications they want to be
sure that they can't be gripped it in
such a way that they can and they have
been lobbying for something that we on
the other side of this considered very
dangerous which is a set of back doors
cracked or sometimes the ball towards
the formal formal garden at the moment
this exceptional access
I mean I think we're clearing out right
now but the most pleasing thing for me
at this moment they wouldn't something
like pieces doesn't go week without some
major organization that we depend on
whether some piece of the government or
some some chain of stores some banks
being broken into and the basic problem
but security system
complicated we don't really know how we
don't know how to persuade ourselves
that anything was secure except for the
very simple and if you all for this
exceptional access you make them more
powerful and so that's exactly the wrong
thing at this moment when it seemed very
secure in these people want to make
everything less secure by adding
mechanisms that they did you just
incidentally I think that basic
sentiment explains a lot of insecurity
in the Internet to that because the
government on the only people who are
the most effective filled with doing
everybody
which I mean who will Apple Microsoft
etcetera one should be secure everyone
but then so if you have automatic
updates on your computer for example
that a certain ways makes you more
secure but it makes you utterly ballroom
the Apple and Microsoft or whoever is
provided and it is just basically you
big words the fact is what companies
want they want to dominate the customers
they want fundamentally that control of
their customers computers they don't
want what I would also which means I can
run any version of the software that I
like all open source code I can copy
anything I like I noticed incidentally
earlier said the Internet is gravure
important to note yeah anything you say
may be kept forever by somebody with it
isn't likely to be available to you and
a lot of people don't want that also
would like the same to Ruby and not let
to copy so they can have whatever
marketing strategy that like about
creating an emergency so
my view of security is least I don't
know how widespread it is but it isn't
affected me widespread nobody knows how
to make money and therefore get lots of
products out so forth
out doing the kind of centralizing
controlling things that all of the
successful operations are doing and you
can look at the cold war with the
government case is just well let me so
that I wasn't told my title until
I was given some suggestions about what
I like to do with just about like I hope
you're bored
I have at least awful one reason I don't
believe it is generally over arts
believe the Young scored think they're
going to live forever quite simply no
better than the unpredictable up and you
know get old and die with everybody else
and I believe you know I'm old I'm going
to die I don't believe all of you know I
don't literally mean you think you're
going to live forever I doubt anybody
will live long enough to see the
collision with the Andromeda galaxy
vibrant I don't know what that would
mean but I think there are probably
people sitting here who me alive
hundred to 500,000 now we will track
meet people I don't know I used to be
designed human being for the end of the
first century and now I think we in the
first quarter and the first sort of
simple cases are already seen you know
didn't get the right mitochondrial
mother they can replace the mitochondria
when you are just a few of conceived and
give you a better mitochondrial so they
don't suffer
so we're going to world writing
something very long and by which I mean
when you talk like that
twenty years ago about time because you
studying and you can talk intelligently
about that person take they lose track
you can gain
possible the old and gain all the
virtues of you but you can be young and
gained a lot of the virtues of a I
recommend that's all I had in my hand
somebody once asked questions ferris
wheel
asking questions
somebody else over