this conference will now be recorded
Henry or Sam was gonna go first you
wanna do the shorter presentation first
or the longer Sam I think you're up
first
ready all right so everybody Sam is the
it's a well known in the house and he's
an awesome guy and he knows a lot about
a lot of stuff so looking forward for it
free stalk and take your waiter put this
slides because people now ask about the
slides in the chat channel so I'm
sharing a show you see the presentation
now yep looks like GoToMeeting picked up
on it all right
Samuel Greenfeld I'm Steven CISSP
certified for ten years recently one for
the software variant specialize and sell
for quality assurance especially on this
security sides blackhat scholarship
recipients what their last year as a
result also have done many of the
conference recordings for hack Miami
that you see on the YouTube as well as
recorded the first year of specific
hackers conference and the reason I'm
giving this talk is I'm a licensed
amateur radio operator for the past 30
years see sure I'm on the right screen
with the cursor so the agenda what does
that matter radio what can you do what
you cannot do
operating practice how to get your
license in the conclusion I guess I was
hoping to do this in person so he'd show
off toys unfortunately we're not at the
library so we cannot really go off into
showing twice today so the top service
what is that mature radio technically is
defined radio communication service with
purpose to self training if occasionally
carried out by amateurs that is
duly authorized versus interested in
rich Serino techniques le foot with a
person like me without a canary or
really a financial interest its
regulated by the Federal Communications
Commission United States and it's I
would say it's not really a single hobby
it's a range of possibilities that said
the reason it's a it's a lot like using
a car I mean you can just drive around
the car casually to where you need to go
you may want to build a car from scratch
you can do that amateur radio you may
want to pimp out your car and make it
all fancy and or you may want to do try
to race it or something and those are
all sorts of things you can do with
amateur radio as well again you can do
conversation locally around states to
the world it's a concept of directed
nets where one operator controls the
flow of traffic and who should talk when
these are difficult done to exchange
message traffic we also use it to manage
an event such as a marathon or incident
such as a hurricane its concept of D
expeditions where people are actually
going traveling internationally to
locations to run amateur radio usually
they choose a nice-lookin location in
the rear which is rarely causing me to
have very many amateur radio operators
to be you can said you can contest there
people try to work all stage four
continents work fifty hundred countries
who can make most contacts in it a
certain amount of time maybe bogus
multipliers for using certain techniques
and stuff field day is your general
merging a practice emergency whatever
run which is done every year truly just
crowds of the bands it's your fourth
weekend in June presume thing that still
happens there's lots of local events you
might be able to see someone doing stuff
alternatively there's where field day
which is done in January but it's not
done by the same organization and you've
concept of sending or I'm qsl or
response cards saying little
postcards say
I talked to this person or nowadays why
our equipment is the logbook of the
world which is an online system and you
can experiment with amateur radio
different operating modes different
designs internet lengths so though
that's pretty common nowadays so not
really as experimental may want to try
how far can you go in low powers are
very commonly done satellites or earth
moon earth bouncing has also done a bit
and I just gave an example of FG agents
weak signal communications here they're
repurposing a protocol used actually to
talk to deep-space probes and and it's
basically a very automated communication
that can be done to transfer things back
and forth
volunteer emergency services are also
done you may just doofus it volunteer
for like a marathon or rock or run or
other event you have to cost Aires which
is every emergency service it's warmer
private-sector things more official ease
you have raised these which is gringo
amateur civil emergency service which is
explicitly defined in the rules that
define amateur radio the practice these
are usually the same groups often have
other groups out there you have
hurricane watch groups Saturn there's a
Salvation all army so why are purple
patrol military amateur radio service to
treatment tropics might be needed to
maybe health and welfare there's all
there may be a lot of site traffic which
may just be people trying to confirm
that people are still alive or people
passing along messages confirming
someone stole alive one thing I will
note especially since September 11th
these groups often require explicit
training registration and background
checks all done before the emergency
actually happens if you're doing
anything that involves the government
chances are you going to need to take
FEMA's incident command service ICS
courses I like one hundred two hundred
and seven hundred this is not this is a
federal requirement this is not
something can easily be bypassed some
groups also like for amateur radio 800 a
are out like they are on come level one
for areas groups and if you're working
with the Red Cross or something they may
also want you to have their
certifications as well so now we've gone
through what's allowed and what's not
allowed generally having a financial
interest in the conversation public
broadcast music foul language commercial
all that legal usage encryption
you can't encrypt things on amateur
radio sadly you can do like iMessage
hash though using more than the Midland
power required generally also is frowned
upon that said is that these are
generally speaking there are kinds of
exclusions like if for example you had
an agreement with NASA to rebroadcast
the audio from a space station
well and they happen to play music to
wake up the astronauts well that's okay
or if you were you to schedule time to
talk to the space station with your
class and you were the teacher and you
were being paid to be their teacher
that's also okay too
and there's a said there's a some gray
areas with this one talk is offering how
much of the process of can you order of
a pizza over amateur radio and the
interpretations of that actually have
varied a bit over time here's just a
picture of some of my stuff I just put
together the Kenwood little radio in the
middle here let's see this is turning
along a little pointer this little radio
here is 20 years old it still works it's
just an am/fm mobile ring I just decided
to show mobile rigs here because I know
you see a lot of you carrying around
Bell phones so these are a bit more
powerful that's oh that's just an FM ray
dual-band typically dual BAM you mean 2
meter 440 ring on top here we have an
ancient also 20 years old roughly
speaking packet radio set extends dated
about 1200 baud and down below here I
have a modern radio which is the Cieza
thing here that comes with a that one
has a USB that has a built-in sound card
that is upgradeable firmware that has
all your modern fixings
so radio like that nowadays
it also does hf b hf so it covers a lot
more bands it can do a lot o MF animal
digital modes a lot more on its own
Lorraine you like that if you've got it
pre-made that's only it that one's about
$1,200 or the modern equivalent to
something like this probably is 300 400
for the middle for the mobile ring and
that one probably nowadays would include
bluetooth and conclude include the
digital radio that's sitting on top of
it it could include GPS and a whole
bunch of other things so where you have
evolved in general so
I'll get him into operating practice
because I know we don't have so much
time Kurt there are currently three
classes of licenses you can get for
amateur radio you start out as the
technician I'll go up to the general and
now you the amateur extra or extra class
a licensing is cumulative you have to
pass the lower exams to get the higher
license some also some discontinued
license classes but there's still people
licensed under them such as the novice
the technician plus a maid advanced
class these at all Point had their own
fury exams but main difference you could
say is they required more various
different levels of Morse code knowledge
than deal current ones did ever since
the early 2000s Morse code is no longer
required one thing I will note because
some people are paranoid here is license
records are public information they no
longer include information like your
date of birth but the basic record that
you have an amateur radio license and
your address will be public along with
your call sign that said you do not need
a license to receive amateur radio this
is primarily a license to transmit
technical enable license historically
would be also argued to be a a license
to be the control operator of an amateur
radio stations as well as the license to
have an amateur radio station but that's
all most technical distinction here's
the little bit of math as as not to get
only math they want a pointing chair is
that you have the concept of a
wavelength is equal the speed of light
divided by the frequency so basically
well I'm going to why is the Miss giving
is an example here why is the amateur
radio band here between 144 and one for
a roughly 150 megahertz known as 2
meters it's because if you divide 300 by
150 you get 2 and the reason that
matters is was when you're treating an
antenna
they're often cut to fractions or
multiples of the base wavelength and and
if necessary I mean I can pass placed a
link to this here
just a band short and I'm also I just
pointed out it's just pointer on a
blazer so care about various amateur
radio bands you can see they break it
down by what license class can do what
where in terms of frequency this reason
I'm also kind of mentioning this is you
can see that there are a lot of bands
they vary in frequency the bandwidth
they said again three meters in
frequency and you can see the name but
they notice how big some of these bands
are and it's they're not very big if you
think about it because if you look
historically I want to just compare it
to Wi-Fi for a second here because if
you know you're two gigahertz Wi-Fi
bands you have three independent 20
megahertz channels most of these bands
here are not 20 megahertz light at all I
mean two meters is only four megahertz
wide you go down to 30 meters at slight
point zero five megahertz wide so we're
talking a lot less than with then you
have with your Wi-Fi especially once you
get to five Hertz Wi-Fi you got two
meters
you got your 40 megahertz channels which
are now 80 and now what's with Wi-Fi six
one 60 megahertz channels and while you
can do that at higher frequencies you
don't necessarily have access to that at
lower frequencies and most for most of
the amateur radio bands which are in
common use you're all sharing less batt
much less bandwidth in your typical
Wi-Fi connection but that doesn't mean
you can't do voice and stuff it just
moves that the radios use a lot of more
historical techniques for audio for
example with you know your basic here
you got what would you call a just
borrowing from Wikipedia this video you
have this baseband signal which is
basically used speaking that gets
shifted up in frequency Jen you're
talking over here I mean if you
but if you're a young you make am signal
historically had a copy and another copy
over here just of it of you speaking
along with this carrier share which if
you were just doing CW all you really
need is this carrier which is very
little bandwidth but if you're smart
what you can do is you can just we'd
only have to really transmit this state
si you know you can don't need to
transmit this large carrier which means
you can also increase the power of this
and use regardless of what you're using
like very little bandwidth same
alternatively you could just transmit
this bottom piece here and you still are
getting here a point across and that's
basically how it's done with the various
at least at the lower frequencies as you
just aren't very conservative of how you
use bandwidth it complicates the radios
a bit but it makes them it's much more
efficient use of the bandwidth so yeah
the high level basically the
international to automation using which
had defines the world into three regions
region to defines what the FCC can
allocate and the FCC then turns around
says given an amateur radio license of a
given class this is where you can
operate a more gradual levels there are
best practices recommendations that the
organization such as the ARL put out but
they are not necessarily where you were
required by law repeaters and beacons
should be coordinated if they're so
there are organizations that will try
and coordinate what frequencies used by
what for repeaters within the best
practice regions for where a repeater
should be located if you are coordinated
you are actually have have a bet you are
considered more important than someone
who do not get coordination should there
be a problem I said because lower
frequency bands have less data your loud
symbol rate varies by band however
modern coding is more inefficient but
they have to update the rules but still
you're not going to lower frequencies
you're not going to get Wi-Fi bandwidth
and
50 megabits a second just not
theoretically possible some allocations
are in the secondary basis amateur radio
shares their frequencies and others and
they make some Caucasians actually have
been lost like you may have noticed
there was a gap in a band on the
previous slide that was because ups at
one point thought about using that for
tracking packages eventually it did not
happen but the band section was lost
anyway these bands also very near
country borders as well if you travel
internationally so if you go close to
Canada there there may be frequent seas
which are used in Canada for different
purposes so if you get too close to the
border you can't use them for amateur
radio uh that said we have the concept
to call signs like and just like you
hear call signs for TVs whatever you
have call signs for you for amateur
radio operators just like radio station
also and everything else that said
amateur radio call signs all have a
number and typically refer to them in
like like one by two format would be one
letter a number than two more letters
after it with in Florida you're going to
have all half a call sign which begins
with four if you start out by getting
your callsign down here if you go if
you're in California or you're gonna
have your call signs always starting
with six it used to be decades ago that
if you traveled around the country and
moved you would have to change your
callsign to match the new region that is
no longer the case said they vary by
class by default they're issued
sequentially if the higher the class
license you get them longer you the
shorter of a call sign you qualify for
but they're no longer changed when you
moved around the US or change your
license class that used to be automatic
just gave some examples like there's
four blg Richland was a person I
actually worked under K 2 RF somehow k4f
a use at Florida Atlanta
University and they've had that since
1964 but more a more recent development
is if you don't like the callsign they
gave you automatically there are a
vanity call signs you can pay for just
like getting a vanity license plate so
you got there you for wdw is that Walt
Disney World if it ends in MOT it's
often a Motorola line W explore any
cheese the National Hurricane Center and
is an example here of an inheritance
10th floor BG the original person who
helped Bo G which is a club in the brown
can he died but since but because
there's an inheritance preference they
were able to retain the call-sign salsa
say the concept of clubs all signed
which are very much
a lot of the use of the Bandung eco
signs often if it's an individual game
event any call sign they just want
something shorter they used to be
concept of Gracie's call signs for those
emergency groups but they no longer
exist the race these groups have tried
to grab their old call signs back to his
club call signs if it's a super short
call sign it's typically a foreign
special event and you have to use your
callsign regularly during conversation
there are ID requirements I'm not going
to go too much into to the zoo stuff but
during this is hack Miami and possibly
Pacific characters we're going to get
things are the technical stuff in the
terms of the operating stuff I want to
get into the stuff really mostly that
you're not going to cover in the guides
obviously the power supplies you need to
have proper voltage connectors whatever
as you had obviously she also considers
surge currents because my big little
radio tip wants a 30 amp power supply
but even if you turn the power down all
the way on it it may accidentally blow
like me accidentally trip a smaller
power supply because the strum needs a
strong currents to start transmitting
even at a lower power my older radio
doesn't have that issue but getting back
to this slide you have Anderson power
poles
especially since
September 11th they've been looking to
standardize how everyone connects so you
can just borrow someone else's power
sources so Anderson power troubles are
your very common power bus so you have I
get here at the top picture of a power
supply with Anderson power poles there
my picture of this rig runner thing
which has power poles and connectors for
power poles genderless so you can take a
cable so this 50 jacket is the same as
the plug
you just plug right into each other
there are something now there are some
various sizes over connectors for power
poles but it turns out the 320 the 15 25
and 30 amp connectors all share the same
external power size so they vary on the
back as to what why are you connect to
but it gives you an easy way to create a
a power bus at 12 volts that everyone
else can connect to may also have
started seeing this kind of stuff these
kind of connectors appear another 12
volt supplies online Amazon and stuff
antennas I this could be a talking
itself can be be homemade they can be
achieved expensive as Purdue's operating
frequencies control their size may
require Brenton playing or something
traps techniques maybe and use band
they're gonna very obviously new a power
you can stand like this tiny little
antenna here they can stick on top the
car it's gonna take a lot less power and
stuff than this big one here then I can
just stick in a car when you're putting
an antenna out of car consider one load
one thing I will note if you have a
special antenna like this if you're
putting a car on top of antenna like be
sure to consider extra functionality you
like if you can fold it over like this
one can be folded over
connectors again very widely
that's amazing reversed estimators you
typically see on on higher frequency
devices that needs less power
cell phones are a prime example if using
reverse SMA well the radio you see
there's using a regular SMA connector
just means they swap which part is
supposed to have the male and female
parts a UHF connectors a historical
popular connector used at HF and VHF
frequencies when we're talking hf b hf
UHF there are some general ranges for
what frequencies are and those ranked
very high or ultra high or things like
that but there's some room to play BNC
connectors maybe on stuff in the 1990s
but I haven't seen them that popular now
and is more microwave and NMOS another
type of antenna mount you may find on
cars cables again cables obviously vary
in size and that the super tiny thing
obviously the I here which was so tiny I
don't know who didn't want to know how
much loss it has but then you get
thicker connectors like you think RJ a
NEX cable in the middle there and then
RG 8 you said twice the thickness so
that one meant that thicker one has
twice half the loss per foot bin the one
in the middle you have to consent when
you're making a cable one you have to
consider how loss of ADR at the
frequency you want to operate the map
also have an antenna over here made out
of LMR 400 which is a super ultra luffy
non a lossy cable which is about the
thickness of that one but even half half
that loss of that so the other thing is
cable quality varies widely you need to
be aware of that so you can get a cheap
chinese cable or something or maybe a
expensive cable and putting it on where
you get it and the quality of the cable
just because they call it RG aid x or 8u
a lot of these know historically had no
specs standards but a lot of companies
are not really making them to those
standards anymore so if you have a
poorly soldered on connector or
something you may have an issue where
your cable may be more lucky than it
otherwise could be it's also perfectly
possible for you to go out and buy your
own cable and then use that ground
ground planes be sure to properly ground
everything show me a single pass to
ground who do not want to ground loops
it's the same thing with water meal
electricity in your house do not want
you transmitting to be hot on some of
these have metal cases if there's a
floating ground you could have a risk of
RF burn or something if you touch the
case of your radio what was running and
since this is obviously Florida if
you're in concerning outdoor antennas
installation consider lightning
protection vehicle installations
depending on your regular said my big
guy does not like would not like a
cigarette lighter or Jack it's just that
I like cheddar Jack just only 10 15 amps
so even if I turn them all the way down
just starting I mean I might
accidentally blow the fuse so if you
have a radio like that you may need to
consider using the fuse box wiring
attack there I'm doing a direct wire to
the battery most cars in the US should
be negative ground it's possible that
it's positive ground and you have to
consider that if that happens newer cars
you miss aluminum ins steel why is this
important because if you touch two types
of metals together they start reacting
with each other and there's some risks
of one destroying the other it's like
the anode inside of your water heater
getting eaten slowly so you make if you
have a car that uses a mix of these you
may need to consider if you need to use
dielectric reads fast fasteners or
things like that one hooking up the
radio if you have to bypass the normal
fuse box or other circuits you also may
not be able to put a magnetic mount
easily on the aluminum surface also in
newer cars they often have a battery
monitor and the negative terminal
especially if they have an insta-star
system so they turn off the motor of
every start light if you bypass that
you're going to be drawing crewmen away
from the battery and battery money is
going to get very confused as to why the
battery seems to be in poor condition
than it is because it thinks it should
know how much currents going through the
battery and
you there's some current going through
the battery that it doesn't know about
if this happens usually these are in the
negative terminal you can use them
challenge to ground to the chassis set
the car if it's negative or otherwise
have to do it again
always fuse your power lines you just
I've even seen a negative line fused as
confusing as that is so you want to make
sure that there's no risk of if if
something happens you want to also fuse
as close as possible reasonably possible
to the battery so you don't accidentally
cause damage to the vehicle if you want
to do computer stuff there's plenty of
computer software whatever you want to
do many things are now controllable by
USB or serial ports sound modems are the
art of using the radios you're a
computer is a radio you may use an
isolated audio interfaces and get that
into the radio without risking having a
problem back just like you have TTC IEP
was derived from X 25 X 25 is a
renewable protocol which which amateur
radio and and it's Linux incidentally
has a kernel module for it so Linux on
its own can route X 25 just as natively
as it knows tcp/ip or ipv6 there was
there historically also his on an entire
eight subnet on the internet which is
just dedicated to amateur amateur radio
that said they realized that subnet in
today's day and age was a bit big and
there was this sale of roughly a quarter
of it to supposedly to believe Wikipedia
for Amazon for over fifty million
dollars so if you wanted not much an
ipv4 address is worth it's worth a lot
the actual details of that sale they'll
have been somewhat obscured but that's
what's believed to have happened if your
s is just logging is logging physicians
all sorts of web interfaces you may just
log log your contacts or software to do
that
if you want to send messages you can
just solve where'd you do that to a
concept that is covered in the course a
bit and it is it kind of standing wave
ratio which is ratio of your fuller to
your reflected power you want when
you're transmitting not all your if you
had a perfect message in China all your
power would go into the antenna should
be a 1:1 scenario which is ideal but in
practice you're not going to get that
there's always going to be some sort of
reflected power because antenna isn't
perfectly tuned or your cable isn't or a
connector in the middle has a tiny lower
fraction off of that on your radios can
tolerate this a bit if your your your
basic HF FM radio for higher frequencies
isn't necessarily going to let you play
with it
but at the lower frequencies you can
have an antenna tuner compensate for
minor errors ideally you don't want to
exceed 2:1 or 3:1 on this radio ratio
because you can damage is the antenna
here I have some examples of stuff of
two STR meters you also have a digital
meter one here just uses a single line
if I show you here this one just uses a
single line to measure SWR here's an
example of a dual fancy air of meter
it's just on one meter it's showing you
the forward power and the other leaders
shown you the reflected power and where
they intersect them these two lines
cross over here you can see where your
SWR lies if you're testing I do not
transmit in to your antenna you can test
your transmitter using a dummy load
which basically is a big resistor they
do not have to be very big I have a 300
watt daily load I'm just hold in my hand
here but if you're looking for something
which needs to handle a longer term we
need to transmit for an extended period
of time or a higher wattage you can get
an oilfield paint can basically these
are the size of paint cans and those are
dummy loads that you can transmit high
power on for an extremely long
period of time RF exposure limits by
government regulations on you you do
have to limit the RF exposures caused by
your station
that's say there are two sets of limits
it was involved with operating those
with the public it's up to operators to
prove that they're in compliance in
general it's and there are this is
probably the most calculating thing you
could possibly done do with your station
fortunately there are variety of people
put calculators on the web which can
help you try and do this there's also a
lot of things can come to consideration
that will help you such as the fact that
uh you don't have to worry about if
you're below certain power limit at
least at the moment and if there's also
factors that come into play such as
you're not transmitting all the time see
most of the time you're receiving and
also depending on what type of
transmission you're making you may also
get a little reducing factor as well but
however the FCC has looked to harmonize
these regulations across all of their
services so there will be generic
exemptions replacing the amateur radio
specific ones however I cannot tell you
what's going to happen with that because
that's still going to happen for the
next several months while they're
working on it if there's an emergency
anything you say is there any questions
because no one's said anything yet
good good emergency use anything goes if
there's an emergency but you have a bet
better to have a good reason for doing
it realize empty radios unencrypted this
does not mean that you talk to the nice
police dispatcher who asks you to
quietly get off their frequency
I have heard a story of that happening
outside of an emergency situation
someone casually transmitting the
something when they should not be but
the FCC may alternatively limit amateur
radio operations as they see fit during
an emergency third party traffic
you can't let an unlicensed person
operate your supers your station if
you're supervising them your stall to
mately responsible you can relay a
message on behalf of someone else then
you received in the past so long as it
doesn't break any other rules that's it
if you're going internationally you do
have to have a third party operating
agreement to send traffic initially
there's also an additional
identification requirement you have to
identify at the end who you are talking
to this also gets a bit complicated with
Internet services because if you're
you're triggering a transmitter remotely
over the Internet into another country
then that kind of falls into their third
party rules and I've once watched
somebody using service called echo link
traced off of an international Mountain
remote they weren't allowed to remotely
do that internationally it's hard to say
without knowing the rules of the other
country if that was actually the case
alternatively you can go internationally
with amateur radio there's three I'd say
three main agreements for amateur radio
going internationally some of these
arguments are automatic some require you
to apply ahead at a time be sure to take
a copy of your license and the
appropriate paperwork
I mean FCC for one of the agreements if
she just gives you a three page print
out in three languages that you take
with you copy your licence and you're
good you go up to Canada you just bring
your license and you're certain
identifications and it works but there's
other cases where you have to formally
apply and the allowed frequencies will
be those under the treaty and allowed in
the visited country one thing I will
note is if some of these agreements were
written back in the age of Morse code so
if you don't know Morse code and can't
copy Morse code at set rate if they
haven't modified those agreements you
may actually be knocked down a class in
terms of what you're allowed to do
internationally harmonics images I'm
just bringing it basically you read your
body Ringo was in a simple crystal radio
then that works for AM C this is concept
of bringing down the frequency like you
sell from higher frequencies
lower frequency just like in here your
CPU may run in at 3 gigahertz but the
rest of your PC may only run at 400 or
800 megahertz because it's a lot easier
to take those frequencies further than
the 3 your heart's you just inside of
your CPU the downside to this this is
just an example I took from Wikipedia of
a heterodyne receiver superheterodyne
receiver which is a very common design
you can make multiple stages of this if
you get into the SDR talk next week they
just lost out where that demodulator is
and that's where your str starts hooking
in the problem with this is that uh when
you have a local oscillator you're
actually can receive two frequencies
it's one you're trying to receive and
then there's a other one you're not
trying to get there's also as I said
harmonics just like are just multiples
of your frequency so when you're
transmitting it like 20 megahertz
although you would never actually say
there's 25 - that's more closer to
amateur radio this you're also we have
multiples of that frequency it's going
to be technically transmitting at 50
you're going to be transmitting at 100
and also a half of 12.5 and stuff
but ideally you want to keep those two
minimum and your receivers also have
those kinds of risk sensitivities as
well this comes into place so when you
look up a radio spec you don't they'll
give you my image rejection and things
like that to tell you how sensitive the
receiver is and how much it can avoid
getting confused if there's an
additional signal there by this
especially comes into play with the
Chinese radios I know a lot of you guys
have been picking up on those Bao phones
I have one too and general amateur radio
operators are able to modify your other
radios for use in their bands and this
is generally not allowed for other
services malfunction similar in a great
area there was one FCC cease and desist
against a baffling employer cheap where
you guys are not necessarily as good
transmitters are selectively receiving
as expensive ones yes you can that's it
there are putting a lot of downward
pressure on the pricing and possibly the
all of the fancier radios as well so
it's hard to see where this is going
save because you can buy as people
pointed out you can buy one valve you
can buy two or three columns for the
price of a more expensive radio and yes
that more expensive radio may have
Bluetooth and GPS and other stuff
built-in but it makes it a very hard
sell and you can just get a regular you
can toss aside even if the manual isn't
the best one stuff
interference amateur radio is greater
than part 15 devices generally part 15
being those devices you have which which
you buy all this devices you in elements
a may not cause interference but may not
cause generate it caused any offense but
if they get interfered what if they have
to accept it that's that's pretty much
all your home to buy little devices with
computers and stuff in them so if a
maturity is interfering technically
you're being you're not causing me
anything illegal there but you're gonna
very much set your neighbor's other
their services are greater than amateur
aid you know if you're interfering with
aircraft or something you're in trouble
on general though it's best to be nice
this does not mean intentionally
transmit that full power to try and blow
someone else's stereo I have heard every
case where someone actually did that and
it worked but I don't recommend doing
manage that you probably would get a
trawler the trouble of someone actually
found out but we have interference
ideally do you want to try and eliminate
it at the source with your like a
low-pass filter or a high-pass or
bandpass if you're trying to get it you
seem like also a choke on a USB or power
cable or something coming also it's an
attempt also to keep power from either
getting into or out of the device you
may have purchased where the system is
having issues rules enforcement it's
primarily self of hopefully Singh one
thing I will note which is a recent
development
the official observer program can may
reach right about is replaced with
volunteer monitoring I still get if you
can if you get too bad the only they'll
just tell you politely please fix this
out there but if not they may refer to
the FCC FCC in general doesn't really
have the budget that they'd like to have
now as much as they used to in terms of
enforcement but if you are and if you're
something like commercial radio station
or something
you didn't get to the lovely you know
where the FCC you're they're going to
make you pay for it
very I've rarely read a finds ten twenty
thirty thousand dollars so but ideally
you don't want to get to that point
buddy I didn't think it's very rare for
it to get to the point I can think of
one example in Broward County where
someone is constantly interfering with
things and jamming for the fun of it
where it probably will get to that point
but that's generally not the rule that's
it how are you in your house like here's
an example of a lovely cut caused from a
declaration for a condominium somewhere
in Palm Beach County no I am radios
without permission of the board this Cup
it also comes from an interesting errand
in nineteen nineties where I think the
HOA lawyers thought they were more
powerful than the government I had a few
people tell me a clause like this
probably is not legally enforceable but
how much do you really want to try and
prove that is always the case
over-the-air reception device Act is
another in law out there is law it's not
an HOA rule it's actually a law which
allows is what allows you to have a TV
dish antenna within the quote unquote
area of exclusive use of your house it
overrides some HOA missile restrictions
for these this does not mean I I can
think of another Association who has a
clause which attempts to say that all
the little things in the hotel are still
requires you to go through there's there
committee and have your have your
satellite dish approved even if it's
fully inside your house and as they
still go through all your liberals and
their little beautification committees
and stuff I can also read an FCC opinion
which line by line strap down one of
those clauses that said overall taller
does not cover amateur radio so you
cannot use that as the basis for having
having an antenna inside of your booth
fully enclosed patio even if it's not
poking outside of your house PR b1 is
the closest thing to a now
- radio : but only applies to new
colonies basically says municipality
can't deny you having a reasonably sized
antennas stuff but does not override
certain concerns so we're still writing
for illiterates legislation to cover
amateur radio an HOA is amateur radio
carried yeah to the people you proposed
it's passed Congress general it's
probably Don't Ask Don't Tell but if
you're causing problems like someone's
DSL modem starts going nuts every time
you try and transmit you may have to try
and work with them it's probably just
best to be polite and proactive you may
have to find yourself buying little RF
church and stuff to put on their stuff
if you absolutely have to but it's
probably on you just in general because
they're not going to the other person
who's having interference isn't
necessarily going to know what to do
getting a license who can get a license
in the u.s. anyone pretty much who's not
an agent of a foreign government that
said if you were convicted of a felony
there's a more recent requirement if
you're doing anything with the FCC where
you have to discuss provide an exhibit
explaining why giving you a license is
in the public interest notwithstanding
the conduct uh there was a steady I saw
right about this it does not it does not
look like the FCC is really denied to
anyone for the most part if they had a
felony for provided they provided this
exhibit and that exhibit though is
public information usually though that
some of them have been filed privately
there is no age limit on amateur radio
how old you have to be to be licensed my
family it was before cellphones amateur
radio was the daddy color to see how
close daddy was to being home and
licenses are generally valid for 10
years that said you have to hear some
online systems to get your license the
FCC has a system called cores which
currently has two versions online one is
what's referred to as the FCC
registration number as your user name
there's a newer system out there which
can handle multiple FCC registration
numbers
uh you want to get your FCC registration
number before testing why do I say that
it's because as part of the frm
registration process you have to give
the FCC your social security number and
other information that is not set public
but it you will have to give it to them
what part of the stuff the FCC does with
the application is a so-called red light
review where they make sure you don't
owe them and possibly other divisions of
the government and money
the u.s. is this other system which is
what refers to is the is so basically
you think of course as their equivalent
of Active Directory or their sam'l
authentication provider whether it's
their authentication system the OLS is a
separate system which focuses on
licensing that said when you finally get
your license you do not want to download
the public reference copy of your
license you just look your name up
search in the public we're gonna say
logging download my reference copy the
license that's not the one you want you
want to log into you LS currently using
your upper run password FD support email
password login form and download your
electronic authorization to get the
official copy of your license to post
around your house or wherever your carry
with you all operating this is that
license of this public but you put your
phone number or your social security
number something the course registration
that is not public information if you
had a business registration you you
would have to worry about it and you
only need one fo ID number even though
the newer system can support multiple
SETI guys there's lots of ways to study
if you get an AR L study guide it's
going to probably focus on the theory
then tell you to read the test questions
at the end of each chapter you can also
get study guides which focus on the test
questions with furious commentary as you
go through them the w5y group tends to
use those questions peers themselves are
updated every four years but they're
fully public information you can find
all sorts of websites where you can play
with the question pool some one will
require you to log in see them some
won't some will just let you download
the entire question pool and you can
just read it yourself and all if unless
you're going for the flowing high class
license you don't have to worry about
any upcoming explorations taking the
exam all non exams are in person there
was there's some talk
possibilities while grouping and last I
looked into the feasibility if you could
do this online but as far as I know no
one has come up with the ability
volunteer exam coordinator groups
administer it decades ago you had to go
to the F
see to take the exam that has not been
the case for a very long time these are
often done monthly large events such as
Def Con have their own exam inventions
smaller events as well what to bring
photo ID F remember pencils calculator I
probably non-programmable is best
photocopy of anything I don't think a
certificate of successful completions
really are relevant because you can't
really get one license it's getting a
previous I doubt most examiner's will
let you take a higher level thing
without taking the lower level one first
I think this is exam there's an exam fee
that's me often done this is the only
time you have to pay a third party to do
anything with your license I mentioned
this because once you get your license
you'll get say congratulations
please join this group please join this
I do what please here here's our catalog
please buy from amateur radio equipment
from us and twenty other things but you
also have groups periodically saying I
need to renew your amateur radio license
you can pay us to do it for you you
don't have to do that you don't have to
go through a the EC's for anything after
this point you can just do it with the
FCC directly unless you really want to
use a VEC to on various national
societies that promote amateur radio us
this amateur radio relay League they'll
obviously send you something once you
get your license but membership is not
required it's also lots of local amateur
radio groups I could refer you to
there's also like national other
national groups out there like tapper
Luther stood for a Tuscan area pocket
radio but now there are national new a
lot of other stuff it's amateur radio
growing fortunately my favorite site
fool keenest information out what
doesn't have stopped updating for some
reason but there's probably or this
point probably around 800,000 amateur
radio operators also the average length
of the license is more than the
half-life for the license so in terms of
raw numbers amateur radio is still
growing the licenses that are not
expiring is fad
they're being added this does not
necessarily mean that your people are
very active unfortunately either a lot
of people are just got their license in
our Idol I tend to be pretty idle myself
I know if you look at an actual amateur
radio club a lot of them tend to be
older than to hack my enemy groups just
on average on conclusion it's amateur
radio I'm not quite sure I was hoping
maybe someone would have had questions
or wanting to go into a topic but that's
basically everything I had to say on the
subject and you get so many questions
the things um if you want I can hop in
here just to let a couple of quick
things and mind you I'm not licensed for
a ham radio operator but let's go clean
more and I've actually been kind of
studying a bit honest topic over the
last year or so we both purchased from
Mike's electronics which is over by Fort
Lauderdale Executive Airport he's not
open all the time but he is still open
and you can get the a I'm sorry the ARL
ham radio license manual from there
which is really good it's got a lot of
great stuff in it and one of the things
that I also purchased a little while
back was there's a book called pastor
amateur radio technician class the easy
way and what this guy basically did was
he's been an ally since radio guy for a
long time and he did something that I
ultimately did earlier he basically took
downloaded all the questions the entire
pool set from ARR l's website which
anybody can do and what I did was I went
and basically deleted all the wrong
answers so if you look in the events on
slack I've basically posted a PDF that I
created that is the entire test pool of
questions but what I've done was I've
eliminated all the wrong answers so it
makes the book a lot smaller easier to
go through and should help you out as
far as memorization and random if you
still probably want to go through them a
full licence book as far as like I just
don't understand really what is you're
talking about but for just purposes of
passing the test this PDF file that I've
up there it's a stupid easy way to get
actually get there and like I said that
easy way by Craig buck k4 ia is also a
good very good book it's a bathroom book
if you will anyways yeah that's an
extent I'd say take doing an exam like
that is kind of you should you should
know the theory at least behind all the
basic math question them the theories
stuff but I I can understand your
wanting to memorize like questions on
I'm like what is this frequency range
that I'm allowed to use on this band if
they're giving very similar examples but
I would say it's best to understand the
theory not just why specific answer is
color right and that's what I said I
also advocate getting the full big red
the big red book the ham radio license
manual from ARRL which fool is going one
more infest use sources as far as co big
19 and Mike's electronics Mike's is an
example the local store were very
fortunate to have one in South Florida
that's stroll around because a lot of
those don't exist anymore
there's also a lot of national change if
you had he gets equipment internet that
will provide ship it from elsewhere in
the country we have to get stuff Mike's
electronics no for covert nineteen I
think he's only open in the mornings and
you have to call it advance and possibly
see what he's doing but his stuff okay
that might be possible cuz last time
claymore and I went there it was
actually like goes before the whole
coronavirus thing so he does have coded
19 hours and restrictions but you'd have
to call them I think you have to call
them in advance hey Sam I got a question
for you this is a Phil I'm actually
going to be doing the SDR talk in a few
weeks here do you have any
recommendations for booked not
necessarily related to the test in
particular but more as you're saying the
theory and fundamentals a lot of the
books focus on if you have a license a
book problem they are all probably the
book that's probably
the most common one out there though
it's a very very very thick book is if
you wanted to go into all sorts of
details have lots of things is the ARL
handbook which they update yearly which
is just a whole book full of articles
and how do you do all sorts of crazy RF
in other things
anybody who wants like manual stuff for
that I've got a crap ton of PDFs hit me
up and I can definitely send them over
to you I got everything from antenna
theory to radio theory so excellent I
got a question yes okay I thought that
Danielle was speaking so I went and got
my technician license uh kind of on a
whim so what's a good starting radio to
get I'm not eager to drop 1200 bucks or
even you know 300 bucks what are you
trying to do what you're just trying to
talk locally um I don't know just good
introduction radio right I mean I got
the license they don't know what to do
with it so I just wonder I don't know
good decent doctor said I guess I mean
well you could start with like handheld
handheld Stone tend to be very expensive
radios if you have a local like repeater
to talk to you should also like us to be
looking to getting involved with your
local amateur radio groups some of them
like it's a group in Palm Beach County
has its own Shack sitting in the park
and that's a good possibly a good issue
should look around and see what they
recommend I would say this room so I
don't know it's very it's a very open
question if you're just looking to
casually talk to someone locally then
you just need a little handheld might be
sufficient for your use but if you're
looking to Talk Talk internationally
then you're probably you look and you're
probably looking at plus if you have
room putting a dipole outside of your
house or something which is just a lot
big long line of wire then you might be
looking which that's very cheap to do
but then even used you might be looking
like for like a five foot maybe a $500
HF radio the HF stuff is
probably a lot more expensive than the
FM radios could they do a lot more bands
and stuff and even older HF radios tend
to hold a lot of their value for
whatever reason primarily because you
basic radio theory has not changed much
two years even if you
they don't have built-in fancy digital
signal processors and things waterfall
diagrams and stuff that an SDR what
radio can do yeah there are a lot of
good STRs out there you can find on
Amazon and on the web is also there is a
couple of good backpack radios I was
trying to actually put the link in this
go me Channel it's not letting me for
some reason but like for 200 bucks you
can get a pretty decent powerful
backpack radio with a 10 hour battery
life I mean I mentioned that the bow
Fung is getting one that play with a
good idea or not and if so which one
they seem to have quite a few models
that roughly the same price range
I think the bow things are actually OK
for a starter radio just don't admit
that your ATS what you're actually
talking on because they a lot of the
amateur radio guys blast the the bow
thanks another good resource to look at
also for those of you guys who actually
are on Facebook there's plenty of ham
radio groups that actually can share a
lot of information as well I've done a
lot with those guys yes it is possible
to walk down a bow phone so just
transmits on the amateur radio bands
I've done it but it's you have budded
that sends to be aware of something else
with a bow phone I'll be sure to set the
alarm mode to local otherwise you may
find yourself accidentally transmitting
the siren over the all over the place
alright guys any other questions for Sam
will or claim on or so actually I'm a
couple people joined in on that
all right well fine one of the guys
mentioned the book that eliminates all
the wrong answers I just I didn't quite
catch that if you can maybe I don't know
maybe put in a chat or
it's the events it's called ham dot PDF
yes just like channel those also on the
slack Channel / system for the % 27
slack they don't call it the channel ham
radio but there's the channel radio
frequencies yeah all right
are you part of the black I'm sorry are
you in black with us no I am NOT I just
I saw that I saw this event on my own
app and I just join if you would kindly
give me your if you want to and being
invited to our channel give me your
address and I'll send it on to the
Edmonton cool organizing you can direct
message me in a be GoToMeeting chat okay
all right or if you just want to
directly from hit me up it's it's not
something that's not even a full neck is
any William knit okay let's make will
net at gmail.com
all right Henry is up next well did you
want to do any kind of introduction or
are we just going to turn it on and ring
no I think Henry should go for it all
right Henry are you ready to go yep
perfect I am making you the presenter
please you are the presenter dang it cat
all right take it away Thanks
so we're going to talk about mini cats
just a quick run-through about what it
is its uses and how it's been integrated
into other tools so you'll have a lot of
flexibility now in order to understand
we will have to briefly go through
Active Directory authentication I'll try
to cover that part faster than the rest
so what is mini cats it's an open source
tool that allows to view and save
authentication credentials so you're
you're in a workstation you can use
mimic ads to dump it credentials you can
see clear text passwords you can see
password hashes stuff like that with
that you can just copy the credentials
you can if you don't have the clearances
clear text password or plain text
password George's and you have a hash
you can actually dispatch the hash of
the password to authenticate you can use
Kerberos golden and silver tickets and
pass those tickets there's also a
technique called pass a key or over pass
a hash we're gonna talk about that but
basically basically a bunch of different
attacks open up
once you use mimikatz and obtain this
information from the workstation so it
looks kind of like this it does require
admin rights so basically you run the
tool
you're gonna type privileged debug in
order to escalate privileges and then
you'll you'll be able to just dump the
password
as you can see in the picture you're
gonna see that it says down here and TLM
that's the password hash and the
plaintext password that will come from
it now with that you can do whatever you
need with those credentials either login
into a particular account or like I said
if it's common to be in a corporate
environment where you were gonna have
Active Directory so let's try to quickly
cover Active Directory authentication
which basically just falls into two
different categories either ntlm and
Kerberos they're technically not
mutually exclusive you can find a domain
controller that would allow you to
authenticate through ntlm well while
it's actually using Kerberos with other
devices so it's not necessarily mutually
exclusive but normally you will see it
in a way that it's somewhat is like
basically just focusing on Kerberos or
it has a bunch of legacy stuff so it's
basically stuff with ntlm the difference
between them one is basically a
challenge response style of
authentication we're gonna see it in
detail in a little bit but it uses
password hashes that are easier to crack
where the rest Kurvers uses tickets and
uses AES encryption and this is using
again some legacy system with DES but if
it's using AES it's gonna be harder to
crack so let's so just a quick overview
on ntlm and how it works
it's super easy basically the user
authenticates with an application server
and says hey this is my user the user
will repair the application server will
reply with a challenge which is also
called a nun's it's just a random value
and then this nonce gets encrypted with
the password hash and is sent back as a
response now the application servers
grab the response is going to grab the
nonce is going to talked with the domain
controller and say hey this guy is
trying to authenticate with me this is
the number that I gave him this is his
response because the domain controller
also has the same password hash for that
user it will be able to also encrypt the
nonce compare it with the result that
the user encrypted and if it is the same
then the authentication is a success and
the user will be allowed to access
whatever they were trying to access on
that particular service or server now
for Kerberos I try to simplified it I'm
not entirely sure if I actually managed
to do that but I'm gonna try to go
through it a little bit faster this one
I truly an easy way to see it is that it
works the other way around instead of
asking the server hey I need to access
something and then that server
communicating with a domain controller
in this case you're authenticated
directly with the domain controller
you're gonna get a ticket granting
ticket that basically allows you to come
back with that and say hey now I want to
use a particular resource so in order to
get that resource from the domain
controller you say hey remember that
I've already authenticated here's my
ticket granting ticket now I need a
service ticket to be able to go and talk
with whatever service or server you're
trying to access whatever resource
within the network you're trying to
access you'll have to follow those steps
you're gonna see actually that pretty
much encryption it's at every single
step of the process so at first you are
encrypting occurrence time timestamp
that's to avoid replay attacks with the
hash derived from the username and
password you send that to the domain
controller the domain controller sends
back a ticket granting ticket that it's
encrypted with a password only known to
the authentication server once you get
that ticket you can communicate back
with the domain controller and start
asking for service tickets which
in turn are encrypted but with a
different password that is known to both
the domain controller and the
application server that you're trying to
access now why is this important because
if we go back here remember that we
talked about Kerberos golden and silver
tickets okay so now that we understand
the concept of how all of this ticket
works back and forth basically a generic
ticket from the domain controller a
particular service ticket for each
service that you need to access so now
I'm going to talk about mimikatz
within other tools performing these
different types of attacks that is over
pass the hash golden tickets silver
tickets but at the same time I wanted to
show you how you can do this with mini
cuts actually within other tools so you
can expand on what you can do with
another engagement you're gonna have a
bunch of different tools such as the USB
rubber ducky
which is basically if it's mostly known
for the physical social engineering that
will allow you to get an initial
foothold or you can steal credentials
with it if you plug it in with memeing
cuts
it will run me me cuts real quick copy
their credentials back to the USB unplug
it and let's say you have the
credentials stored on the USB Drive
another tool that we're gonna see is
PowerShell Empire which actually mini
cuts benefits a lot if you manage to run
it from PowerShell instead of on its
standalone version or or or through the
command so a combination between
PowerShell Empire which actually has a
module for me that's already embedded in
it will benefit a lot mutually benefit a
lot from being able to get into a device
escalating privileges and dumping a
bunch of credentials and then navigating
around into other devices in the network
pivoting stuff like that and then the
Metasploit framework
similarly known for it for the
exploitation and post exploitation
face in particular meterpreter will have
also a module for mimic that's already
embedded in it so as soon as you are
exploiting or running through the post
exploitation steps one of the things
that you will be able to do is run mimic
ads and obtain credentials authenticate
pass the hash ticket etc so we'll see
how that looks
starting off with the USB rubber ducky I
also wanted to add a couple of other
devices one of them is the G spark 80
tiny as the one that you see on the
right it doesn't come with a case unlike
the rubber ducky and it doesn't come
with an SD card reader you can probably
attach one to it but it's kind of wide
to actually put it inside a case unlike
the Wi-Fi dock which also does think
with an S car SD card reader but it does
come with an ESP so it has Wi-Fi it's
basically the same thing as a wife the
USB rubber ducky but you can plug it in
leave it in there and then control it
remotely through Wi-Fi whichever the
case may be
with all of them you will be able to do
an attack that basically you plug it in
you request mini cuts from the internet
I'll show that in a bit you request me
me cuts either from another computer in
the network from mimic ads website in
github stuff like that
but only with a rubber ducky because of
the SD card you'll be able to make the
SD card show as a USB mass storage
device and you will be able to run mini
cuts from there now whichever route you
choose in both cases you'll be able to
run mini cuts obtain credentials dump a
bunch of stuff that you need for that
for further attacks so the top example
this is just a piece of a script in the
top example you see that it's running
PowerShell and that it's basically
downloading the mini cuts executable
into a local computer you can like I say
you can do this either by just going to
github or just opening up an Apache
server let's say you have Kali or within
the network
you open up Apache server you copy
mimikatz in it and then you go with a
rubber ducky to another computer and
you'll be able to load it the cool thing
about the rubber ducky like I say you
can share the SD card just put mini cuts
inside and then you'll be able to take
the rubber duck you plug it in it will
automatically run me me cuts run what it
needs in order to dump the credentials
save it to the USB and you unplug it and
keep working and that's gonna happen
super fast with the rubber ducky now
with PowerShell Empire I wanted to start
talking about past a hash and overpass
ahead if you're using PowerShell Empire
which you might be using to let's say
for the initial social engineering
attack you're doing spearfishing you
grab a file a Word document you embed it
with a PowerShell Empire you send it and
once it opens you start you need to
start gaining a little bit of
information about the device that you're
in other devices in the network and then
eventually move to those devices or try
to obtain information from it so in
order to do this you can use of course
mini cuts so once PowerShell Empire is
running you can just type mini cuts or
you can actually load different modules
from it once you load them you'll be
able to just obtain the same just like
we saw at the beginning when you obtain
the just the password hat and then if
you're in a situation where you have
ntlm authentication you'll be able to
just pass the hash and do regular ntlm
authentication or mini cuts allows you
to do something really cool that it's
called over pass the hash and basically
it allows you to get full Kerberos
ticket with just a password hash in
order to
do that you'll see the command that is
in the picture you see the command in
order to obtain the hash but on the top
of the slide you're gonna see the
command that it requires a lot more than
the other one that just is like you're
just specifying logon passwords to just
dump the credentials in this case you're
gonna add a bunch of different things
like the the username that you just
found the domain in which you're in the
ntlm hash that you're the judges got
with mini cards and then an app to run
again you can run PowerShell ideally and
you leverage it a lot more than your
regular command prompt once you do that
mimikatz is gonna create or basically
prepare a ticket for you but remember
the way that Kerberos works you actually
need to go to the domain controller and
authenticate with it so what you can do
is just use whatever network research
either shared storage or whatever you
need in order to obtain something that
will require authentication and now that
that information is there thanks to
mimic at you'll be you will be able to
authenticate with Kerberos and you will
be able to generate a ticket for it so
now let's talk about the next tool which
is the Metasploit framework and let's
talk about now with Kerberos we silver
and golden tickets with which would
basically be if you're an apprentice
engagement this would probably be one of
the coolest things to get because it
translates into a lot of access either
to a bunch of servers with a silver
ticket or to the domain controller as an
admin with the golden ticket so first
let's talk a little bit about the
Metasploit framework in a similar
fashion then PowerShell
Empire it's gonna have a tool it's gonna
have a bunch of different modules in it
you can leverage a lot of them and use a
bunch of different elements included in
them in order to pay would move around
gather information etc etc one thing to
note though even though the mimikatz is
included within the Metasploit framework
you're gonna see that it's called kiwi i
would guess it has something to do with
the fact that the username of the person
who created me me cut this gentle kiwi
so whoever wrote that plug-in from
meterpreter probably was referencing
that not entirely sure though but
whatever the case may be
you just put load kiwi he will load your
regular mimikatz module and then you'll
be able to start using your
old-fashioned minicab commands in order
to create either a golden or a silver
ticket basically if we go back to our
talk about Kerberos and we said that you
first authenticate with a domain
controller in order to obtain a ticket
granting ticket it's basically a ticket
that allows you to get other tickets the
service tickets which you in turn use in
order to access different services or
servers around the network if you were
to by using mimikatz obtain any of the
password hashes for either one of the
servers or better yet for the domain
controller you can craft your own ticket
granting ticket or your own service
ticket if you create your own service
ticket that is to access one particular
server and you managed to obtain that
password hash now you'll be able to
create a silver ticket using the
password hash for that particular server
and with it you can give you permissions
in order to access everything on that
particular service when you create your
own service ticket that allows you to
access one particular
server in whichever way you deem
necessary that's what's called a silver
ticket because it allows you to access
only one device but with as much access
as you need now the same thing but
happening with the domain controller now
it's the domain controller password
hatch that you have obtained then you
can use that to create your own ticket
granting ticket basically the ticket
that allows you to get all the other
tickets that one is called a golden
ticket and one of the cool things it has
similar to the service ticket the
service ticket has basically hey what
does this guy if what is this guy
allowed to do within the server in a
similar fashion your golden ticket is
gonna say what groups does this user
belong to and since you created it you
can make yourself the domain admin so by
simply running mimikatz you can see on
the lower screenshot to the right the
command golden ticket create is actually
used to create both the silver and the
golden ticket it just depends like I
said on on which password hash and you
obtain is it just a service account or
is it domain account depending on
whether you are on the domain controller
or one of the servers you create that
you give yourself the appropriate
permissions or specify that you belong
to the appropriate groups and you'll
have basically unlimited access to
either one particular server with a
silver ticket or choose them in
controller and to anything else that you
need to with a golden ticket now I
didn't want to make this talk too long
so I will be doing another talk that
will be a Red Team intro and one of the
things that we're going to talk about in
it is how to use mini cuts but bypassing
antivirus on different detection
software
because the tool is very well known you
can imagine that a lot of antivirus
software he's gonna try to pick it up
try to stop it and there's different
techniques in order to try to bypass AV
since there's different techniques in
order to actually run mimi cuts you can
run the executable alone you can get a
powershell script that will invoke it so
depending on which technique you're
gonna use there will be different
techniques in order to bypass the
antivirus if it's just a powershell
script you may just replace a couple of
the keywords and you'll be able to run
the powershell script in other cases
you'll want to obfuscate the powershell
script so even the the stuff that is
readable before now won't be able to
whatever antivirus or end point security
solution won't be able to read it
because you can actually encrypt it with
AES and of course last but not least
actually encoding and executable and and
trying to run it in a way that doesn't
use anything suspicious for the
antivirus now all of that is actually
just too much content so I'm gonna let
that I'm gonna leave that for the red
team intro and I wanted to leave a
little bit of time about for questions
because I know that until M and Kerberos
it might raise some questions as to
where or how you would actually use
mimikatz to obtain that information move
forward stuff like that if any of that
wasn't clear enough now
Oh beyond excellent moment for those
questions if you guys have questions for
this go ahead and ask them you can
unmute yourself you know if you have any
issues is there any type of cheat sheet
that you draw recommend that you've seen
out there that we can go right ahead
take a look and really start using it
specifically with the rubber duckie
you
yeah so let me go back real quick to
here in so the last line at the bottom
is the source for all of the rubber
ducky stuff that's actually from the guy
who made the rubber ducky you can go
over there and actually explains him in
in detail how both attacks would be
performed one of the cool things about
the rubber duckies that you can put it
in I believe they call it like twin duck
mode in which it can act as both a
keyboard and USB mass-storage
so you should be able to do all of the
automation all over typing down all of
the putting the commands that you need
in order to Remy cuts down the
credentials copy them to a file inside
that basically second partition that is
the shared SD card and then just unplug
the rubber ducky and you'll have all of
the credentials in there
you
somebody had mentioned in the chat that
there are payload generators online for
both the rubber ducky and the digi spark
last year I did a talk on how to make a
I think was a four dollar rubber ducky
by using a did you start Ford so Dave
and I had fun with that and Dave is
reminding everybody that there are those
payload generators out there for both of
them and Dave is reminding us that the
Digi spark has a much cheaper version
like I said and we did the talk on I'd
make a $4 rubber ducky with that did you
start yeah you can get like ten no five
for ten bucks so we'll be like two
dollars each and in my case what I do is
because speaking of the rubber ducky and
even the wife I got even though it's a
bit cheaper they're still too expensive
to be like dropping around in an
engagement let's say that you go to the
client go to the parking lot and you
want to drop about a bunch of this USB
so somebody will pick it up on plug it
in that's probably not something that
you'll want to do with a $50 rubber
ducky
but you can buy a pack of five of these
digi sports for 10 bucks and then in my
case I used 3d printer to just print
that really cheap case because they're
too wide to actually fit on the regular
USB case so I just ended up doing my own
with a really printer which is super
cheap if you consider the price of a
filament and I was it a cheap way of
making a rubber ducky that I won mine if
I if I loose after the engagement you
mentioned there's a red team event that
you're going to be presenting are you
also planning on doing a presentation of
the blue team perspective or is that
something you've done in the past that I
can look up somewhere blue team the demo
specific to that at least not that what
one that I've gone to I do know that
they recently did a couple of monitoring
ones that would help but at least I am
NOT planning on uncovering this kind of
stuff from a blue team perspective if I
could do that I I don't think it should
be I think yeah I think it would be a
good idea to present both both sides of
it we recently had an issue with a
client which is a client from another
department so we had we had like no idea
of all of the cyber side and recently we
had to do a couple of incident response
and one of the things that we saw is a
lot of people using PowerShell Empire
mimikatz
for for their own attacks a lot of
hackers even at a more advanced level
like saying full apt groups just using
PowerShell Empire mini cut and a couple
of things like that so I think will be a
very good idea to do a talk on about the
blue side of that and how do how to
respond analyze detect these kind of
attacks great thank you
any other questions for this talk or the
other
all right thank you very much Henry
really appreciate it lots of good
information there assuming you'll give
us the slides for that as well is that
correct yeah I'm gonna share them
through just like the last time okay and
then we've got the session recorded so
once that's been across something else
is that control and and you can assume
that we're which is going to float it or
may walk I'll post that in the observe
panel I believe that animals an item
Elysion remember Susan things and then
rod I wanted to do an opinion yeah
yes thank you very much for for
attending keep in touch with us at the
slack the the social media and obviously
this online meetups and we will continue
updating depending on how things go
there is more to come today in around 10
minutes we'll have the meeting for all
last top 10 API at Pacific hackers which
which is the West Coast group of percent
when t7 so join us in a little bit and
we'll continue learning and
participating thank you very much I
think guys have a great day some great
weekend you too bye thanks dojo
you