should start the recording right about
now
[Laughter]
all right recording has started thank
you very much rod uh go ahead and then
i'll go after rod so
all right good afternoon and uh thanks
for coming again uh
today uh it seems like things are
somehow
leveling and then we're starting to hear
about hybrid events uh
we probably are not gonna do anything in
person yet
um maybe we would look at
the last part of the year and see how
things go
if we don't get a twindemic or a uh
something worse and see how things are
going it seems like for the most part
most of us that
have either managed to stay employee and
and and do okay or soon we'll get
another job that the ones that
that lost jobs had for the most part
being
finding jobs too there are jobs uh if
you need uh
help please go on the jobs channel
paying some of us there might be
the positions that are not advertised or
why we might be able to
push you in or help you um today we're
going to have two
uh presenters that i know very well
uh one of those phil berlo he's going to
talk about gnu radio
and then we have tony which is an old
schooler
i work with tony already we work with
tonya jask and
tony is an awesome researcher and uh
he's very passionate about that
intelligence and uh he's going to talk
to us about this
and i'll suggest you to pay a lot of
attention because you can use this
and you can use it for your own
investigations
um before we get started uh again i'll
thank you
if you have any feedback i read
somewhere in the
slack that somehow discord kill our
channel that's very sad to read
i know honestly i don't know what to do
about it i don't know if
if we should go back or what or we were
using a bot
and the bot seems to be patching up
things a little bit
but uh i do feel like the
momentum has decreased with the adoption
of uh
discord you know we had all this
expectations about this score
and it turned out to be an absolute
disaster um
so there's something that i'm i'm gonna
put this out there for you guys to try
to figure out how well we do should we
go back to slack and
stick to it or because i feel like in
between both
we're losing communication i myself
sometimes i log in and i'm like oh my
god i lost this huge threat that was
incredibly interesting i could have
i could have got some of it i could have
uh collaborated with it so i'm a little
concerned about the whole discord thing
i know the kids like it
um and they all do their dj and their
stuff and that's pretty cool but
it seems like the majority of the people
are not getting it i'm sorry and i
include myself
in in that group but i i'm so what
lost in this discord thing and
after deathcore you know honestly i got
a pretty bad flavor out of it
like a defcon had to do support sessions
and
it was not good it was it was convoluted
and i don't mind using it and keeping it
as a backup but
uh um i feel like we we don't have what
we used to have
that's my perception as of today i'm not
sure if you guys agree with me or not
but
but definitely i'm not the only one like
there's been people posting
and saying hey this is not this is sort
of lost
momentum so i'm gonna put this out there
um
we are gonna continue meeting online
until we make a decision
uh the next big event uh which i will
let
um danielle announce it uh is
the south florida issa and she will give
you the details we also have b-sides
orlando at one point
uh which is our friends in uh and and
orlando which usually put up a great
conference
uh other than that i'll um keep
participating
come up with ideas so we can fix this uh
discord slack thing and uh
um i leave you guys with uh danielle
so thank you everyone now that he has um
told you all about uh discord so uh
we're gonna circle back to that in a
second so uh
south florida issa uh chili cook-off
hack the flag which would normally be
uh but we can't really figure out a way
to do the chili cook-off so
uh you're certainly welcome to make your
chili at home make two batches
enlist your spouse and list your kids
you know battle it out amongst
each other that's fine however more
importantly um
we will be holding we will be holding
the conference in a hybrid situation a
different hybrid than what rod's talking
about
but we're actually going to have the
lobbies and everything in discord
now that has rod has hyped all that up
and gotten everybody excited about
discord
uh so discord will be the uh common
meeting place uh for
chatting uh finding your teams and
everything
uh we are not going to be say i don't
like to set myself up for failure i set
myself
up for success so we're not actually
going to be presenting the sessions
uh via discord it will just be the place
for everybody to mill and talk
um i will be doing my thing i will be
using zoom to present the talk so we're
not gonna have those issues
um and uh i will handle that uh we will
also have the ctfs there's going to be a
beginner ctf and advanced ctf
and our very own rod is in charge of the
advanced obviously
so we'll have some fun working on that
like i said everybody will mill around
inside discord you can find your teams
there we're going to create team
channels so everyone can
uh you know get together and talk and
share your um
clues and experiences and everything so
it'll be similar to what we did in
person where everybody sat at the table
um however what i need is
i need help so i'm in charge of this
discord thing and rod just told you
how difficult it is i need help so um i
need help with
information booth gooms basically um you
will be my evil minions
um so i need people to say this is where
we're going this is how you get to the
ctf you know this is you know the room
you need to be in go check the
links over here uh just helping me out
um uh
corral the people so i would be ever so
thankful if i got some volunteers bill
phil even offered to help me in the
morning he is going to join the ctf in
the afternoon but he's going to help me
out in the morning as well
i really can use the help however if you
choose to volunteer and help me
if you do it in the afternoon love to
have the help but you probably won't be
able to participate in the ctf so
choose wisely red pill blue pill up to
you um
but uh i need all the pills and i need
all the help i can get so
dm me everybody knows where to find me
miss gizmo find me in discord find me in
slack
i don't care where you call me just
volunteer and help me out here guys
so it will be october 3rd i will put the
south florida issa conference link
in the in the meetup in the chat today
and without further ado now that i've
begged and pleaded and i had your own
venti here i appreciate it
um i will offer up phil uh as our first
uh
speaker and he is going to
uh be talking about the um radio uh
the gnu radio and uh
various other things in here i saw a
little bit of his presentation earlier
so i will let him set it up i will let
him introduce himself because he can do
it even better
thank you very much rod i know you had
to drop off but thank you for coming
and uh i need you 15 minutes soon okay
all right thanks have a good day
everybody have a great conference i am
recording
phil it's up you're up go ahead and
share your screen
and uh tony will be up next all right
danielle thank you very much
let me go ahead and share my screen and
pull up the presentation
so this is an introduction to gnu radio
um
for those of you who are at my last
presentation on
uh software-defined radio this is
basically a
direct sequel to that um a follow-up to
what was covered there
there is a lot of overlap with that in
fact i
just straight up stole a bunch of the
slides from my last one
um so hopefully we'll be reviewing some
of the concepts
so who am i uh my name is philip borlau
i am a senior security engineer at
vigilant security
i'm also a licensed technician class ham
operator since 2018
um but really my only real qualification
for this is that i'm a hobbyist
um been interested in radio wi-fi
bluetooth
software-defined radio in general for
about 10-15 years now
given a few talks here at hack miami
related to radio as i said one on sdr
a few others on bluetooth um but really
i'm not an expert in this field
and this talk is really just to give you
a sample
of sdr radio
and these concepts from a hobbyist
perspective
so a little agenda for what we're going
to be talking about today
um i'm going to be starting off by
talking about some just basic radio
concepts to give us some some foundation
then be going into some digital signal
processing and software-defined radio
concepts again just the basics just the
foundation level stuff
and then talk about the foundational
aspects of gnu radio
and where that fits into the picture and
then in the last about 15 minutes
i'm gonna transition to a demo and cover
all the concepts that we covered up to
there
and show you a demonstration of what it
looks like in gnu radio to see like an
am radio an fm radio
or even to demodulate digital signals
like on off king
important note though is i there's a lot
of stuff i'm not going to be covering
today
software defined radio and digital
signal processing is a
pretty deep field uh you know it's got a
you have to have a background in
electrical engineering
to to really understand a lot of these
concepts deep
so i'm going to be skipping over a ton
of stuff i would recommend though that
you guys
kind of follow up a lot of this talk is
based on this three volume series
field expedient sdr um all of the
examples i'm giving today are pulled
exactly from
their site fieldxp.com it's free you
don't have to buy the book to get
the examples so uh if anything i show
here interests you
i recommend you go on there and download
the samples and just play around with it
and the second thing is uh michael
osmond the creator of the hack
rf put out a great 11 part video series
again free at their site that walks
through basically everything we're going
to be covering here today
in gnu radio so i recommend you guys go
check that out
so let's start with the real basics and
i assume
um a lot of you guys i'll
i'll show you guys uh the book titles at
the end but basically
um just answer a question in chat it's
an introduction to
software defined radio field expedient
sdr it's a three volume series you can
find it on
amazon and i will be linking to it after
the talk
so some radio basics um
you know the basic ideas of a sine wave
you have your amplitude
um when that comes to sound that's how
loud you're speaking you can see that
uh here the amplitude is shown by the
y-axis
you have your frequency right um the
shorter the period the higher the
frequency
um these are some pretty basic concepts
and then one that might be
unfamiliar to some of you are as phase
um and so
two different waves of the same
frequency and amplitude can have a
different phase and that just means that
basically they're different places in
the wave so if you were to take these
two lines as being like second markers
the red wave would be at a value of zero
at three seconds where
the blue wave would be at a value of
zero at four seconds
right so just where upon that wave that
is and these are the basic
aspects of a wave that we'll see
another really important concept here is
uh called the fourier transform and this
is really a foundational concept to
digital signal processing and
signals in general um and it's the idea
that any complex waveform that you have
like up here this might be an audio
waveform or radio signal
it looks complicated but you can break
that down
into a series of simple waveforms
and this is a really important concepts
in radio
this chart down here at the bottom left
is what we call an fft
plot a fast fourier transform plot and
instead of showing you know the
amplitude over time what it shows us is
the amplitude versus frequency
and this allows us to see which
frequencies
are the largest component of this
complex wave and so to read this chart
we would see these two big spikes
indicate that those two frequencies uh
make up the largest portion of this
wave but we also see you know there are
a bunch of other frequencies all
throughout here that make it up
and this is just a fundamental concept
of signal processing
the last thing here is i want to show
you is a waterfall graph so
whereas this shows us amplitude over
time this graph shows us amplitude over
frequency
the waterfall kind of gives us the best
of both worlds so we can see
the intensity shows us the amplitude the
frequency is shown by the x-axis and the
y-axis is time so we kind of see all
three of them at once
and these are just three different ways
that we can visualize waves and they'll
come up throughout the rest of the talk
so let's talk about a few radio
components and components we're going to
be seeing coming up in basically any
radio system you're going to see you're
going to see
a mix of these components so the first
one is pretty straightforward it's an
amplifier a lot of you are probably
familiar with it
doesn't change the frequency doesn't
change the phase it simply just
amplifies the amplitude of the wave
pretty straightforward
filters um you know as the name implies
filters out frequencies
so if we imagine these images here um
are a fast a fourier transform
you can see these lines as being which
frequencies would be allowed through
and and that's just basic concepts so a
low pass would allow any frequencies
below a certain frequency through
high pass the opposite any frequencies
above a certain frequency are allowed
through
band pass allows a certain frequency
range allowed through and a band reject
or band stop
rejects a certain range of frequencies
and then the third concept is a mixer
and this simply is a way of combining
two signals so
this is the first place that i'm going
to kind of brush over but what i want
you to get out of the mixer is you can
combine two signals
and the output is either going to be
it's used for two things one is
amplitude modulation which we'll talk
about in a second
and the other is for shifting
frequencies so you can have a frequency
come in
put another frequency and it will shift
that frequency over
and that concept will also come up in a
little bit
so let's actually talk about how this
might come into use how waves are used
uh let's talk about a speaker and a
microphone
right so when you talk you are producing
uh vibrations in
air air uh air pressure waves and human
hearing occurs at around 20 hertz to
around 20 kilohertz
middle c is around 261 hertz
right so let's say you want to play uh
record that and play that into a speaker
you take a microphone you sing middle c
that's going to vibrate a
diaphragm back and forth that has a
magnet on it next to a wire
and that's going to vibrate back at 261
hertz and cause an electrical impulse to
go down that wire
at 261 hertz right
to play that back you just play that
into a speaker which is an electromagnet
and a magnet and it's going to push that
diaphragm
at 261 hertz and cause the air to
vibrate
pretty straightforward but let's say you
want to play this over radio
um well 261 hertz is is extremely
extremely low for radio that's the kind
of frequencies that they communicate
with like submarines with
you need an antenna that's miles long
and you know
extreme power drops that's not going to
work for us right so we need to
encode the information that we have the
audio at around 261 hertz
onto another wave that's going to carry
our
our um our information at a frequency
that we can actually work with
right so we're working at 261 hertz
but we're going to be using a frequency
for am which is around
500 kilohertz to 1500 kilohertz or 1600
kilohertz
right so how do we do that well this
brings back up um our idea of a mixer
and you can see this little animation
here we have our carrier wave
this am uh frequency and we have our
modulated signal this is our
our audio signal and we're putting in
through a mixer and you see it doesn't
actually change the frequency at least
in the same modulation it doesn't change
the frequency
of our carrier it changes the amplitude
and so we can see there are multiple
ways of encoding information here and
this is how this is just the basic idea
of modulation of how we can take a
carrier wave and take information and
put it on top and this works not just
for analog signals but we see how
down here it works for digital signals
too
um and so let's let's actually talk
about a few different ways that you can
encode information on waves
right so we talked about amplitude
modulation you know you can
have your carrier you have your input
and it comes out varying the amplitude
well we can do the same thing with
frequency um we bring in the same
input same carrier but now instead of
changing the amplitude we're changing
the frequency of the wave
right um and then this also works and
this last picture just shows that this
also works for digital
signals so let's let's actually go
through these we're familiar with am
amplitude modulation
when you do this for a digital signal
this is called amplitude shift keying
um and there are multiple forms of it
one that we'll see later in this
presentation is called on off keying and
it's just a
very simple form of digital amplitude
modulation
um you're probably also familiar with fm
radio um
in terms of digital that would be called
frequency shift king
mfsk is multiple frequency shift king
you can use more than two frequencies it
doesn't just have to be binary and this
kind of brings up the idea that
uh you can encode a lot more information
if you use more steps
um but in it sometimes brings in an
additional complexity or additional
error rate so there's balances there
and then the third one which might be
less obvious is uh phase modulation so
the phase is the third attribute of the
wave that we talked about and you can
use that to encode information so phase
modulation and phase shift king
and then the fourth one again i am
completely skipping over this uh
quadratures
in phase and quadratures is kind of a an
artifact of digital signal processing
completely leaving it out i touched on
it a bit in my last talk
the only reason i'm bringing it up here
is if you look into things like how
wi-fi
works and how modulated there it tends
to use quadrature type modulation
just bring it up in case you run into
that
so we've talked about how we can encode
information on waves
but we don't want to be stuck to one one
radio station the radio is not great if
it can only tune into one station so you
want to be able to
tune it around and go to multiple
stations so how do we do that well
um we can broadcast information on
multiple different frequencies or
channels in this case probably familiar
with that
and use filters to you know filter only
the channel you want and filter and get
rid of everything else
great the problem is that that filters
making a filter that you can tune that
you can change which frequencies work
for while possible is
really complicated really expensive it's
not the way we want to do it
they figured out a long time ago that
the way to do this is to
make a fixed filter that works for a
single frequency a single range of
frequencies
and then shift around the frequencies we
brought this up earlier a mixer can
actually change the frequency
and shift it around and so that's that's
the way we're going to do this we're
going to
use a local oscillator to shift the
incoming frequency
to to meet the filter that we have um
and this is a concept called heterodyne
uh and it's a concept here called
superheterodyne receiver
um and so when you tune that dial on
your radio what you're changing is not
the filter you're changing the
the the waveform of a local oscillator
that you're mixing into the incoming
frequency that's going to move it around
right now this introduces a few kind of
uh
issues uh one being an image again this
is one of these
aspects i'm kind of kind of brushed
right over um but it does
introduce kind of like artifacts like
mirages uh harmonics of the frequency
that we have to be aware of and it kind
of produces some
limitations of this in terms of how how
broad we can make these filters
but this is a basic concept that is
basically at the the foundation of all
radios since the 30s um right
so as i said most of what we've covered
is is basic radio concepts have been
true since like the 30s um so
what about software-defined radio well
it's the idea of radio where we
implement some of the components we've
been talking about like mixers and
amplifiers we're doing some of that in
software
now i say some of that because the
majority of it
is still being done in in hardware um i
have a hack rf i guess i don't have it
around me right now but
um we talk about like the first and
second stage here are still
being done in hardware it's really only
the modulation that did the demodulation
of the signal
that's being done in software why is
this important um in your car radio your
car radio can really only do fm and a i
mean those are
two different components in that radio
but it can't decode tv signals it can't
decode you know xm radio software
defined radio as long as the antenna and
the receivers are tuned for those
frequencies it can just change how it
demodulates so it's a lot more flexible
it does introduce some drawbacks and the
main one being it's limited by the
sample rate
um so let's actually get into that what
is
sampling um this is this conversion from
the analog to digital domain analog
signals are continuous it means they're
they have a defined value at every point
in time
right digital on the other hand it is as
it's it's discrete
it exists as discrete ones and zeros uh
which means
that the resolution is a factor here
the the rate at which you sample the
signal is going to determine the
resolution of the signal
and we can see here up top an analog
signal and it's digital representation
these bars are you know
an estimation why is this important well
if you're sampling at a rate that
doesn't match your signal you're going
to see a signal
that isn't true this top rate is is
based on these dots this is
you know a pretty good guess at what the
signal probably looked like but
the sample below is showing you that if
you had a really fast signal
that that was much faster than your
sampling rate you're going to get a
mirage you're going to get this this
false signal it looks like it's much
larger and it's just because it happened
to coincide if you've ever seen like a
rolling shutter with a
with you know propeller blades where you
you snap shots at different times
that's this effect so it introduces this
idea that you have to be cognizant of
what's the frequency you're sampling and
how fast are you sampling it
um and it's going to introduce some
artifacts
so that's software to find radio let's
talk about gnu radio specifically
um so gnu radio is a software
development toolkit for signal
processing
um it's written in in python and c so
it's basically
a set of libraries that you can do a lot
of what we're talking about implementing
you know mixers and filters and
amplifiers you can do that in software
and it allows you to do that
it's cross-platform but what i'm going
to be showing you today is gnu radio
companion
and that's a wysiwyg interface that's
built on top of it so you don't have to
traditionally go to radio you would be
you know programming in python
this allows you to do everything
completely without touching code
which is nice especially it reduces the
barrier to entry
um i do want to make it clear though for
those getting
into software-defined radio you probably
aren't going to want to touch gnu radio
um for most applications like receiving
tv broadcasts decoding images
speaking am there are purpose-built
applications it's probably what you want
to use
um gnu radio is is like you know the raw
tools so this is useful for if you're
building new applications
or um if you're learning digital signal
processing or reverse engineering a new
signal
um it will allow you to break it down
every step along the way
visualize it and kind of debug what's
going on
um i just want to tell you most of you
guys if you want to get into you know
radio and sdr
you probably don't need to touch gnu
radio or you'll find people save
files who have already implemented it
who really understand digital signal
processing
and you'll use it but it's fun to be
able to play around and see what's going
on
and then the last one i'll put up here
and i'll just throw this out to save you
guys some headache
don't run it on a vm when we come to
sample rates and and frequencies
uh the latency introduced with
um the latency introduced with a vm
just causes all sorts of issues so try
and install on bear hardware
i'll go over a few of the kind of basic
components of gnu radio here before we
get into some of the demos
so the first few are variables and gnu
and gui entries
um the idea being that throughout your
entire uh schematic
you're going to have amplifiers and
mixes that are set to certain
frequencies or sample rates and it's
annoying to have to update those
all over the place right um
so having variables in good entry box
gui entry boxes allows you to just
implement it once reference it
throughout your code and just update in
one place and it'll allow you to
actually like implement tuners like when
you make an am radio we can have just
a slider to to move what radio stations
return to uh sources as the name
suggests is the source of information
this can be things like a file source uh
it can be you know a wav file it can be
a hardware source
such as a an sdr um or it can be
like an array i'll show you in the on
off keying section it should we'll just
have an array of zeros and ones that we
feed into our
um flowchart syncs are the opposite it's
it's where we're putting our information
so just like we can read from a file we
can save to a file um
when it comes to audio like a am radio
afm radio we can
put it out to an audio sync and put it
out to our speakers or
um you know any sorts of uh types of the
really important ones
are the gui sinks these are visual
outputs that allow us to see
uh we talked earlier about things like
the um fast fourier transform plot that
allows to see the frequency over time
um and it'll just be able to allow us to
visualize what's going on that's
probably the most
important tool in all of this um
radio components as we talked about
mixers amplifiers filters those are all
uh implemented as components um
obviously i'm not going to get
too much into it we can you know i'll
show a little
a few of them off in the demo um
type converters this is an important
idea in gnu radio
um there are different forms of
information
um they come in different formats and
you have to be cognizant of them as
you're moving them around your system
complex numbers floats integers binary
representations um they are all
are all color coded within gnu radio and
you will be having to convert from one
to another
and it just adds a little bit of
complexity to
just some of these flowcharts uh sample
rate related
um again we were talking about how
sample rate comes into digital signal
processing
as you go throughout your flow chart
there are going to be a lot of
components that
um either decimate or interpolate either
fill in data where there wasn't any or
get
throw away data where it's not necessary
as you're transitioning from one sample
rate to another
again another topic i'm going to be
completely skipping over since i don't
have the time
and then stuff like math some of the
basic ones like multiply or how you
implement mixers
but you can do all sorts of mathematical
functions in gnu radio
that is the presentation portion so with
that uh that should give us the
foundation to actually start jumping
into some demos
um so this is gonna radio companion uh
this
is i i modified a few of the examples
that came out of this field expedient
sdr
uh book and it will walk you through
most of these examples
um and you can see here a few of what we
were talking about so we have things
like a file source and this is a source
uh from the radio example so i didn't
have to hook it up to a radio these are
you know a capture
um of an am broadcast you have things
like
text boxes and frequent variables to
keep track of our sample rate and what
frequency we want to attune to and what
the center frequency of the filter is
and stuff like that
and then we can actually see you know uh
we talked about the heterodyne radio
and and we have things like
a mixer here and a low-pass filter
and uh an am modulator and what this
allows us to do is we can see we have
things like
gui syncs here that allow us to
visualize these signals as it works its
way through our system so let's go ahead
and actually boot this up we'll we'll go
ahead and run it
and we'll pop up is our signal so let's
go through this here's our here's our
ama
input right here's the signal that is
coming out of our file
and here's what's coming out of our
multiplier they look very similar and if
if you notice
look at this peak it's been shifted over
well that's that's exactly what we were
talking about our mixer was doing we
input
a sine wave a cosine wave in this case
uh what is that 20 kilohertz
cosine wave and we're shifting this
frequency over
so this is an example of what's going on
in a super heterodyne
receiver where we're shifting it over to
from its you know what is this
running at around 900 kilohertz
right a radio frequency around 880
here though it's around zero this zero
is shifting it over for our filter our
filter is built around zero
right so this is one of the ways you can
kind of
visualize this as it's going through so
let's actually pull out and and see
disable these outputs now guys i know
you guys are answering a lot of
questions i will look at those at the
end of the talk and
uh cover all of them um
so there's our output let's actually
look as it goes from our multiply output
to our filtered output after our low
pass filter
all right so let's run it again here's
all our filters and we can see all these
spikes are likely other
radio stations they're on other channels
we've shifted this to zero and as we see
we've now removed everything around it
um so we've isolated just the am station
that we want to talk about and that's
what that low-pass filter is doing so
we're able to very easily visualize what
these components are doing
let's keep going let's disable that guy
and let's
um enable the final output and
a uh audio sync
and there we go look at that so here's
the radio station the channel
and here's the actual audio waveform as
it's coming out at the end
um and so in in a really quick way we've
demonstrated uh that super heterodyne
receiver with an am radio station and
broken it down and
and this shows how gnu radio can be used
as a really good tool
for sean for showing what's going on in
each step in the process
um so now jumping over let me show you a
quick example
of a um
of an fm broadcaster and receiver so
in in in our last example i was showing
pulling from a file
right so someone received a file um in
probably a software defined radio and
then and throw it just directly into a
file for processing later
and that's actually what sdr is great
for pulling from files and and you know
analyzing signals after the fact
but in this case we're actually drawing
from a wav file this is just an audio
source so we are going to be
going through broadcasting and then
receiving
in the same diagram so what comes out at
the end
you know this is basically just a fancy
way
of playing a wav file but we're
we're simulating it going through um an
fm broadcast
so this is a little bit more complicated
um am is much more straightforward to
implement than fm
uh so i'm not going to go through what
each one of these blocks does but we can
see here we have things like
um a transmitter um
this uh excellating fr filter is just a
fancy way of doing
shifting with a mixer and filtering all
in one which is just something that we
do often
um so let's actually you know let me
disable the audios
oh no i can't disable the audio sync
it's going to yell at me
when in the course of human events so we
can see the audio
in the course let me turn that down
so here it's it's a similar
implementation as we saw before now in
this case we're using a different gui
implementation and this allows us to
switch
how we visualize this so instead of just
a frequency display we see okay this is
at 98
98 uh what is that probably megahertz
okay
we can also see it as a waterfall
display and uh we start to see
some of the issues that come up
like aliasing these are uh filters that
we need to
now uh filter out right so
just interesting that we can see um
these different visualizations and it
allows us to just
identify the type of modulation from a
distance and what's going on very
quickly so
i'm not going to spend too much time on
an fm sample
i think what's a little bit more
interesting is this um
this is an implementation of an on
off king so our source here instead of
being a file is literally just an array
of ones and zeros that we want to
transmit
and we are going to see what this looks
like
um so let's start off we see what our
digital input is it's a digital waveform
you know
one one zero one zero one zero one zero
zero blah blah blah
cool let's see what that looks like
after we have you know modulated it
so we go from a digital signal out to
now this
okay so we're getting spikes at this one
frequency let's let's change the
visualization here
okay there's something over here let's
change the contrast to make it a little
bit more
okay okay we got something now let's uh
let's zoom in
so there's our digital signal um on off
king it's turning on and off
um at this one frequency right so this
is amplitude shift keying
it's one frequency but the amplitude is
going from nothing from off to on and
showing as a spike here
um and oh this is interesting a time
domain display so we can actually see
um it's pulsing you know on off on off
okay
cool let's now go back
um to the end here and turn off the last
sink
and play
am i yelling me why is it yelling at me
right now
it can be a little temperamental
what's it want from me
do i have one running
oh that's annoying
yeah so as i said it can be a little bit
temperamental sometimes let me see if i
can get it to run
generating flow graph okay
and execute
you can do it oh demo gods
all right let me restart it real quick
sorry about this guys
all right we're right back where we were
so let's play this
and here we go so we see our digital
input
uh the frequency uh output and then how
we're receiving it so it's a perfect
replication
um very cool one more example
and then we'll wrap this up so this is a
similar thing but it's showing
a little bit more complicated and in
this case
we're actually using an access code um
so in this case there's a static code
coming across there's ones and zeros
coming across and we're looking for a
preamble
um it's a certain sets of ones and zeros
that always precedes the code that we're
looking for and it tells us that this is
the code we're looking for it's not just
random noise
we can use things like this where we
input what our preamble looks like and
it will inject
two so this is a binary signal we're
talking about
but it will inject a two into there so
that you can identify where the start of
your signal is
so let's look at what that looks like
right so here's the signal it's going to
come across in a second there we go
so the input into the demodulator it's
uh on off king
is the amplitude and what comes in is
this waveform what comes out
looks more like a digital signal cool so
we're making a translation here
let's go a little bit further let's turn
off the input of the modulator
look at the clean baseband all right
so after a few more blocks we're going
to take in what was a little bit of a
rough signal
and we're going to clean it up so this
is the rough signal it's got peaks it's
got overshoots um the timing might not
be perfect and we're going to turn it
into a nice
clean digital signal that we're
expecting cool
let's disable that guy let's uh
turn the time sync on and let's run it
again
so remember this is after the access
code so what are we going to see
all right this digital signal came in
and it rises and then stays up
but what we want is points in time we
want some ones and zeros so we want to
go from a square wave to a triangle wave
so that's what this is because we're
going to be writing this down into a
file as ones and zeros
this this peak two which obviously makes
no sense in a binary
format this is our access code so this
is what that block did to tell us hey
here's the start of your signal
everything after this is the data
cool so let's turn this guy off let's uh
enable the file sync
let's run this one more time
let's wait for the signal to come in
there's our signal okay
cool let's go ahead and open
up our um
a new radio example in here okay
bin let's open this up and so here's our
output
we can see most of the time it's off but
every once in a while we have ones and
zeros here in a file
and if we look carefully there should be
here let me scroll a little bit further
down
here a two so we now have a file that we
can pipe into like
a python script or whatever we want to
start to start taking this apart here's
our data here's ones and zeros here's
our binary of whatever we want to
transmit across our data so this is how
you can take the new radio um and start
taking in an arbitrary signal
something straightforward like a on off
king and actually start playing around
with it in in a system
um you know create applications around
it put it into a python script
um yeah and that's it uh i think that
covers the majority of what i wanted to
get to
so right now i know i told you guys i i
would check the questions so
i will open up the floor and let me look
at chat
all right thank you phil do you have
access to the chat screen all together
do you want to run through them one at a
time or do you want me to
uh read them off i mean if you have
anything i i know there might be some
just conversation back and forth in here
but if you saw any any good
almost all of its questions oh perfect
for the
room uh you guys have the ability to
unmute yourselves
so um happy to have you guys type in the
chat ask a question
um or you can unmute yourself ask a
question
or you can raise your hand and i will
magically unmute you or something i'm
not sure but go ahead phil
yeah okay so let me go through some of
these questions again i do want to say
some of these are pretty technical
questions i am a hobbyist i probably
won't be able to answer a lot of these
these are good questions that i um
uh need to read up a little bit more on
but i'll do my best
so the first question is can you explain
how phase would be measured
um this i believe is done through in
phase and quadrature this is um
in the modulation section i touched just
briefly on
um what i wasn't going to be talking
about
in phase and quadrature is a way of
analyzing signatures that helps
for one thing identify phase of the
signal
um let me see general rule of thumb
someone brought up the norquest sampling
rate it's a basic idea in digital signal
processing again
i am not knowledgeable enough to give a
good explanation of that here
so i would recommend uh they they cover
it in both the
uh the volume that i covered as well as
michael osmond's um
video series or just go on the wikipedia
page it's it's interesting but
that uh nyquist sampling rate um and the
criteria is a very fundamental theory
behind this
yep look look up my question channeling
sampling theory yup absolutely
what the band and sdr can receive um it
depends on what sdr you're talking about
they have different ranges
um i would recommend you you look at my
talk on uh
you know introduction to sdr i cover
some of the major
software defined radios are out there
and the frequencies are out there and
the capabilities
so i'd put you in that direction um
the the quick answer is it's typically
in the low megahertz to about
two and a half you know the two and a
half five gigahertz
range so like you know ham radio
up to to wi-fi is the range you'll
typically see
yep hack graph goes about to get yep
so can you pick up radio cellular and
wi-fi
um in terms of frequencies yes you want
to visualize it go right ahead
demodulate and demodulating it is a
totally different ballgame
when it comes to radio for example
you're talking about the bandwidth
you're covering you start to get into
you know
limitations of the the hardware um
it's much more difficult to do that with
general purpose hardware like a hack rf
you're much better off doing it with
specialized hardware
um so while you can demodulate wi-fi
with a hack rf
just get like a an alpha yeah right
don't do it by yourself um even
satellite yeah you can you can do it all
it's all about um you know the
implementation
um heavily dependent on bit rate
antennas yeah antennas and all of that
are our completely different topic
um that i certainly do not have the
experience on
but that's all implemented in hardware
right
um and that's how did you learn all the
blogs pointers and resources
yes how did i learn it uh the two main
resources and i will go
back up here to the uh in the agenda
page to show you guys
um right here
these are the two major resources i use
for these talks field expedient sdr
uh it's a three volume series i believe
each one is about 20 bucks on amazon
um the the the web page that he has with
all the demos completely free so you can
download the demos and play around with
them on
gnu radio today for absolutely free the
other resources i'll point you to
michael osmond the maker of hack rf has
a really good
um 11 part sdr series where he goes
through
in gnu radio covers all of the topics we
talked about today
and again free check it out
greatscottgadgets.com
sdr um guys i will be posting a link to
this talk
um the links in chat in our discord and
slack and i'm sure
this talk will be available and not too
long on youtube so
if you have any other questions i am
active on the discord and the slack
um i think we have sdr channels in both
so
with that i will turn it over i hope i
didn't go over time on that nope
perfect timing you did not did great
thank you thank you thank you phil
absolutely we're gonna keep you we're
gonna stop your sharing
if i could get to that freaking control
there we go all right
um okay so uh tony is
up next tony are you ready to rock and
roll
sure i am all right may i ask how long
your talk is so i
uh have my uh thing we could we could do
15 minutes 30 minutes or 45 minutes it's
up to you guys
all right i'm going to let you roll um
and i'm going to let you go ahead and
introduce yourself
and do you want questions during your
talk or do you want to save them to the
end do you want to interactive
tell me tell me what you need to make
yeah anybody can jump in and
and um ask a question um
i'll put the chat window on my other
monitor here so i can keep an eye on it
um and also i have some friends here if
they want to chime in with an
answer they're more professional i'm
also a hobbyist like phil so
all right that's fantastic all right you
go for it i can see your screen
thank you awesome yeah so um
you know rod asked me to give a talk on
malware information sharing
platform it's a platform that was
developed i think by nato
and the luxembourg cert and the
belgium area sort of eu financing
uh sort of industry they needed a way to
collect
uh information and and uh indicators of
compromise
for different campaigns and malware and
things they were dealing with and
different threat actors that were
targeting them
so they built a database to do that
so i started using this when i was a
threat researcher at
a endpoint company to categorize the
malware
because we would get new malware samples
every day and if we knew that they were
phoning home
to a known call home or a domain name or
they were using some sort of a registry
key or tactic that we could identify
and store in a database like this uh it
would be a great way to kind of help
quickly
sort of prioritize and route what kind
of malware something was
and also you know train um the malware
engines and the
signatures involved and stuff like that
so that's really
how i got into this platform kind of
built it and stood it up for my team to
be able to
quickly identify uh malware so i'm just
going to go over the basics obviously uh
what an indicator is most of you
probably heard of ip addresses domain
names
and hashes of you know one-way
cryptographic hash of a
file it's like a fingerprint but there's
also things in there like the aba
routing number for a financial scam or
about a bitcoin wallet for a ransomware
or
who is registering for a domain name can
sometimes give a clue
to a campaign being related to another
one
so these are all things that we kind of
want to collect and there's way more
than that but these are just some
examples
um and you know the other question
people might have is well why do we
collect these things and and i put some
examples here
um like i said in europe there was a an
industry isac
sharing information uh that they wanted
to say you know if these guys are
targeting all the banks we want to know
about them and share that information so
we kind of have more of an immune system
around our banking uh here in europe or
something like that
um you know tracking a malware campaign
as a researcher
is the use i used for it but we've also
seen people
automating and validating and enriching
their sim content
they might have written signatures or
gotten vendor information or logs in
and they can compare it to known bad
activity
and maybe enrich the data by giving you
context around
yes the signature fire and it's it's
going to a known you know
bad address or something like that or
just maybe if the sim content is not
working and you see something
you can investigate and find out and fix
it so it gives you some sort of
operational
validation that things are working the
way you intend um it also
gives you a way to communicate with
vendors uh without
you know giving them too much
information so we've seen a lot of
people say hey you didn't catch this to
their vendor
they provide some information some
domain names some ip addresses
then they're able to improve the
products and
you know everyone benefits from that as
well and another thing is
historical searching and review of data
once you do have a identified threat
actor
you can go back into your data and
figure out maybe the dwell time
which is how long have they been
operating in my network uh
and that way you know how much damage or
how many
footholds they might have established in
your network and again
automation is the last thing it's a big
piece of where we're going in this next
decade
we all need to you know learn our python
and our
automation tools to uh to kind of make
the easy stuff happen a little faster
so having data around that makes our our
scripting more intelligent
uh so use cases for miss we've kind of
touched on that in the last slide too
um but here's here's some more use cases
um
but for me it was about collaborating
with the team number five you know
um searching and seeing that this
malware is doing this that this other
malware did kind of tells you right away
that it's related
um you know unless it's just a commonly
compromised
uh public host that is being passed
around by different threat groups but
you know that can happen as well but
it's just a it's a quick way to identify
things and
and collaborate with your team when you
when you have a lot of data to process
um and then the first the first thing
too is is this product has a uh
it's not a product it's open source but
this this platform has
a way to search from you know your sim
or from
uh slack or discord so one of the things
we did
on our discord was we made it just like
a quick way to search
where we could search for a hash for
here for instance and get a
get an example back uh or you could
search for a domain name
and get several examples back or you
know uh
even a thread actor name and like
lazarus which is tied to
a specific nation-state actor um so it's
just kind of a way for your analyst to
be able to quickly query it without
jumping and logging in and doing a bunch
of work
uh just you know having those things
available so
um the main the main thing is getting
data into the platform
uh so some of the sources for data we
have vendor blogs like
um you know palo alto cisco talos
and you have the online threat exchanges
from ibm alienvault uh
threatconnect um there's there's so many
sources but there's also feeds inside of
this platform as well
so you can turn on the feed from the
luxembourg cert circle you can turn on
all sorts of feeds from
the swisscert abuse.ch uh you can bring
in even a tour node list or
or something like that so you can be
aware of that type of activity if it's
if it's in your threat profile
be to do that type of work and
so this this is kind of just uh
some of the sources for the data but
really the most important sources are
going to come from your reverse
engineers on your
your company staff or something like
that to find you know the threat actors
that are specifically targeting you
and having a place to put that data so
that's going to be kind of the
most important data
so here's an example too of once we get
a bunch of data in
some of the correlation we can see from
the data so we see here a bunch of
hashes and domain names
and how they're related so here we have
a palo alto
blog entry called the gorgon group
nation state actor
and we can see here that they have the
same ip address that was related to
another
one of their blog posts called subot and
we can also see that a microsoft hawkeye
keylogger article
shared a lot of indicators with it as
well so we can start to see
um even cisco talos had chimed in that
there was a threat roundup in august
that mentioned one of the
uh hashes involved so it kind of gives
you a unique view of
what different threat actors are being
reported and how and what the different
names are which has kind of been
a bit of an issue in the industry
because
you have fire i might call it apt and
then a number
and then you have crowdstrike might call
it bear fancy bear or something like
that
you have uh microsoft might call it
strontium
and then you know somebody else might
call it spider or something like that
uh so there's kind of a naming problem
as well so this is something that we can
talk about how to address that if that's
of interest to people
as well so uh just kind of having um not
not to depend on your memory for all of
these millions of indicators
for how they relate to each other is a
huge lift uh
for stock analysts and threat
intelligence folks that are doing work
on this type of stuff
so let's talk about also data
enrichments right so we've taken the
effort to put all this data into a
database
and and collect it um what what do we
want to do with
uh with the data so one of the things we
can do is we can enrich the data
by querying against you know different
services as well
not only can we get indicators from
alienvault but if maybe they don't come
from there we can check to see if
they're in alienvault and get more
indicators
or another cool one is the um the risk
iq passive total one
if you have an ip address from a vendor
that's bad and you don't know why it's
bad
well you might get a list of 30 domain
names that are parked on that ip address
and then be able to figure out more
and go a little deeper with your
investigation so these little things
kind of help
and even with showdown where it's more
like well what services is this
ip address hosting you can go and look
and see that maybe
it's hosting a webcam uh security camera
and it got compromised or something
along those lines
you never know what you're going to run
into but having these extra tools to
query and bring in data with
is really helpful and lastly
uh we have here is the mis is part of an
ecosystem called the hive
and the cortex uh ecosystem and then
maltigo is a visualization tool that
takes the relationships a bit further
than what's built into the tool
um so you can actually have a security
incident response platform that
integrates with this
you can have um malware samples actually
available and uploaded through miss and
through these platforms as well
so you have access to them if you want
to reverse engineer them
so there's all sorts of stuff that you
can bolt on to this it's really just a
starting point
and for me it was just about collecting
the data and taking a look to see if it
was worth collecting
but also another thing i think is very
important is
the data when it's published could
change
down the road um so having the data as
it was as it was published to me is very
important
um as as stories change as narratives
change as
as nation states get involved in cyber
uh
and cyber war considerations having a
point of reference is is really
interesting to me so
um that's another reason so um any
questions about
um the platform so far or anything like
that before we jump into a working
platform to show you what it does
all right so again misp is available at
github
the hive is available here the project
and
iproject.org and misproject.org there's
tons of
information there about the platform so
this is my personal server that i've set
up and i've pumped data into about
five years worth and uh the crowds
asking for the demo
so um so this is uh basically the
the event list when you log in
uh so some of the stuff that i think is
really cool is um
you can see here how many attributes or
indicators are in each
um event and you can see how many
different things it correlates with as
well so
you can see that it's related to 12
other things that are in the system
and that's pretty cool for for learning
about stuff so
let's go take a look at um actually
let's do start with emote
so this is a very common mass mailer
that we see week after week it's pretty
relentless
it tends to bundle with trick bot um so
what we can do here is we can actually
tag this
and say um that it's a mass mailer
or maybe trickbot you know it's related
to trickbot or something like that so
there's a tagging functionality here
but there's also a galaxy functionality
where we can say
um you know this is emote
and it'll tell you that it's related to
the giotto
uh family as well so it's already
able to give you context about some of
the malware families and
and the types of stuff they're looking
for um
and from there you can actually look i
think um
one of these guys tells you a lot of
information yeah so
uh this is this is taking you into the
galaxy's piece of the platform
we can see here a bunch of article
references about this malware if you
wanted to learn more about it
um so so having that sort of galaxy that
ties together all the thread actors all
the names
all the terminology and and lingo
uh really helps uh get up to speed on
some of these things very quickly
so down here how we enter these
indicators is you can click here and use
a free text import tool
and just paste a ton of iocs from maybe
pastebin or from a vendor blog or
something like that
and you hit submit and then you can add
a comment to each one
so i can see here that this ip address
was added and it came from
its emote working group cryptolemus uh
his twitter account or their twitter
account
and and so we have a frame of reference
for when you know where it came from and
when it was added to the system
and you can also see the events it's
related to here in red
uh so when we do want to take a look at
all the different things that it's
related to
for instance here's that trickbot
relationship i mentioned um
you can just click here on correlation
graph and you'll get like a
bunch of relationships here so we can
see in july
of you know this year of of uh
probably 2018 here let me see here
yeah so there was a drydex campaign that
they were delivering malware for drydex
as well with emoted
and you can see in november this these
ips were used
you can see over time that it's using
some of the same infrastructure from
week to week month to month year to year
and and see that even though they're not
changing much they're still getting away
with and delivering different malware
so what we what we've termed this is
kind of as access as a service or
um yeah you know compromise as a service
where they're bringing in
whatever dridex or or tripod or whoever
wants to pay them to get access
because they're very efficient at
delivering those payloads even with the
same ip addresses month over month
um so yeah any questions about this
visualization or what we can do
uh with this data
does this seem interesting to anybody at
all would this help you in your security
operations
yeah everything looks good um the the
more i'm seeing the presentation
um i'm wondering whether there's an
integration with security onion where
you can actually take those p
caps um or does
is this more of a replacement to
something like that
or to that type of platform
um that's a good question i haven't
actually used that
security onion there might be an
integration here where you can go in and
add an api key
okay cool yeah and and if they if
security onion has an api
that's a great way to uh to do that um
and also tom hacks is mentioning uh the
export functionality too
so anything any data that's in here can
be exported to snort or bro
or circada you can do this on an event
level or you can
do this on the whole server level um so
that way you're able to uh
even yara as well store data in here
that can be used by other systems and
export it so
uh since this is an open source project
again i'm not familiar with security
onion but maybe you could make an export
sort of function here to bring this data
in uh to them
and and also automate using their api
um all sorts of stuff that you can send
and receive through the api
with other products so so like i said in
the presentation there's a ton of
products they integrate with
i haven't even gotten through them but i
think there's over 150 entries
in the in the import export sort of
area alone of this platform
yeah thanks um as far as the discord bot
goes i don't have discord bot
on this machine but um
we we just built it to query the search
all handler
in here and what it allows you know
allows your analysts to do is they're
seeing a weird domain name they've never
seen before
or they're seeing a weird um you know ip
address they can
search really quickly and get a result
back a hash or something like that
they can also do that against virustotal
or any other service as well
so you can we're going to start to see
more slackbot functions and discord bot
functions like that
um as we go where you know we'll be able
to query a bunch of services at once and
i think misp is a pretty cool one to add
to that especially in a corporate
setting
if you don't already have some internal
tools that are well integrated
it's a great thing they can just drop in
and integrate pretty easily
all right um so yeah are there any
threat actors or campaigns you guys
would be interested in searching for in
here that uh
that would be um interesting to anybody
like
uh the gorgon group was one
too as we can do can we take two or more
missed deployments and connect them to
share data
yes there's actually a sync action here
where you can have servers
that share data directly and you can
also set the publishing level and the
distribution level
of each article
uh does it do ja3 hashing i have not
heard of that let's check
um so when we add an indicator down here
we can just add a single indicator i
think it'll give us a list
and there's md5 shot one
shock 256 j3 fingerprint md5 is that
what you're looking for cisco
all right so we do have that in here um
there's also that
there's also the other one that i can't
think of right now like ssd or something
like that
is in here as well you can manage
instances
or yep yeah so you can you can have um
like an isac that has everybody's
connected below it
and that way you don't send your data up
to the isac until you publish it
um and uh they can send all their data
that they publish to you guys
so you can have an ecosystem of these
servers where uh you're sharing the data
you want to share and publishing what
you want to share
and there um the way the
the servers go is there's like yeah
there's like these communities here
let's see
um
yeah so you can have locally published
you can have it published to your
community
or you can have it published globally so
there's multiple levels that's what i'm
trying to say
uh for where you can have data go and
filter up
and you don't have you can have this
stuff here you know published globally
but if you're not connected to anybody
it won't go anywhere
um it just stays on the system
cool good questions guys um so the other
one i wanted to talk about was the
gorgon group
um the one that i showed you where we
had a palo alto
uh release but that it it was also
mentioning a hawkeye keylogger and it
was also mentioning subot
and you know mentioning in cisco chalice
as well
um so we can see here when we when we
entered when i entered this data i saw
immediately those relationships pop
up here and um you know we're able to
look at that
and see here that it's related to
hawkeye keylogger and
when i read the gorgon group uh blog
publication i didn't see him mention
that at all and i thought that was kind
of weird that they left that out
so if you're even a researcher
at one of these kind of elite threat
intelligence units you should dump your
indicators into one of these things and
make sure you're not missing a
connection here
is kind of what we see and so what we
ended up doing was
we would um we would tweet at the
researchers
from you know unit 42 at palo alto and
say hey
you know there's a connection here with
this article and send them the link to
this
microsoft hawkeye keylogger article here
um that james in the box tweeted out and
i think there was an actual microsoft
yeah
uh article here so yeah it was kind of
interesting
uh to be able to participate in that way
with the researchers and show them those
extra relationships
so we take a ja3 hash collected and
query it
and get the os browser that made the
request
even if it's trying to obfuscate okay
yeah yeah so for example when um
you make a ssl tls connection to a
server
uh you can uh get that fingerprint um
before it encrypts the connection
and because hashing it with ja3
right if you're collecting those um
those fingerprints
um yeah and and we've uh this is an open
source project as well
uh using a rainbow table for it
well um um they already have uh uh
in their database so if for example um
somebody's hitting you with metasploit
but they're saying no i'm firefox um uh
because we already have the fingerprint
fingerprint for metasploit
we already know yeah no you're lying to
us this is an actual attack
that's pretty useful yeah i hadn't run
into that yet i like
all right so uh if anybody has any
questions we can keep going and digging
into the platform but i really just
wanted to share it with you guys
and let you know on discord uh if you
want to reach out on the thread intel
channel
um my name on there is service pack
spp ride and so um
or mia i think at the end sprite mia if
you guys want access
to read only to be able to query this or
if you want to contribute and want to
talk to me about this
feel free to reach out we can we can
always use more folks adding data to
this
uh like i said a lot of it does come in
automated but
i do still add manually a lot of blogs
and stuff like that just to make sure
we have a good coverage of data so this
could we can also make a separate
organization within my server for hack
miami
uh so you guys can have your own working
group and and be able to take all the
data that's in here
plus whatever you guys want to publish
uh and share
and and connect with so uh that's an
option for anybody who's super
interested in that uh let me know and
i'll be happy to set up an account for
you
so that's about all i have for the day
if there's no questions
all right no questions anyone
all right well tony really really
appreciate that that was a lot of uh
good information thank you very much
um i know people usually ask if slide
decks are going to be available
um i know we did a recording in the
meeting we'll put that up in the youtube
channel as soon as we get that
um but tony and phil will you be
um giving me your slide decks i've
already made them available on slack and
discord
so if you go to uh the sdr slash wi-fi
channel in discord or the radio
frequencies channel
in slack you'll find the powerpoint as
well as all the additional resources i
mentioned
yeah i can share mine with rod and he
can send it over to you i don't have
your email personally but
i'll send it to rod okay no problem all
right well
thank you guys very much does anybody
have anything they want to offer up any
kind of quick discussions or anything
like that
announcements of any kind um i will say
i am working on a badge for defcon next
year
so yeah yeah i actually i already bought
an oscilloscope for it so i'm invested
but if anyone is interested seriously
interested in developing a hack miami
badge
um let me know yeah no absolutely
um it's going to be a serious badge so
anyway
pick me pick me yeah oh wait
jumping up and down part
um i'm active on on slack and discord so
just get in touch with me i'm actually
uh posting some pretty regular updates
on the hardware channel on discord if
you guys wanna
if you guys wanna get in touch so i'll
just put it out there
all right thanks guys um have a great
weekend
and uh see you in a couple weeks
sounds good thanks daniel bye guys thank
you