[Music]
hi
i'm worry i'm currently working on
walkway an online arduino simulator
and also on this skull and this is an
hardware city friday
power the 80 tiny 45 chip and while
working on these projects
i learned a lot about the avr
architecture avr is basically what you
have
this chip on the arduino uno board so
hackety and i partnered to bring you
this class
about avr architecture assembly and
reverse engineering
our goal is to help you start your
journey into the fascinating world of
avr internals
by the end of this class you'll be able
to write avr assembly code like
the program that i have here on my
screen and you'll also be able to
reverse engineer
avr code like this code generated by the
arduino compiler
and even more we will get very intimate
with the 80 mega
data sheet so here's like an assembly
code example
and you will be able to read all those
code examples in the data sheet
learn about the registers and all that
stuff and maybe even solve some capture
the flag riddle yourself
now if you want to join this class you
need to know uh some arduino programming
so digital read digital right
pin mode uh bitwise operations and also
have like basic understanding of
electronics what is an
led why do you need a register for and
that kind of stuff
so i hope you will join us and let's
hack some fun together bye