[Music]
hey
great to see everyone even mr nello
um you told me your name today but i
forgot it
so embarrassing anyway uh welcome back
to the
arduino avr uh reverse engineering and
whatever class
and great to have you back um i know
last week has been
uh a little last time has been a little
intense and this time is going to be two
so
um before jumping right into the deep
order
um i just want to say that i hope that
you had a great week
and let me share my screen and just let
me know in the chat
if uh you can if everybody can see my
screen
as soon as i will share it in a moment
so screen shared let's just make sure
that i can see the chat
while i'm sharing the screen and uh
please let me know
if you can see my screen
there are like leds one of them should
be blinking
looks good thanks christina okay so
great
so um last time we uh
walked through a couple of instructions
in assembly
we have met like this uh asm statement
and this horrible syntax with uh
things you want to write to and read
from and they had a few questions
uh in the following uh q and a session
um and uh
i i realized this is an awkward syntax
like it
i still i'm still not used to it and i
make errors every time
it's it doesn't look like c or c plus
plus it's strange
but um anyway it is what it is and
today uh pretty um
in in a few minutes we are going to see
another way to write assembly which is
a bit less awkward in my opinion so um
last time uh we started talking about
our arithmetic instructions
specifically uh i think uh
this is the instruction set and uh you
have the link in this document
and just uh so everybody have the link
i just copied it to the chat so uh the
instruction
manual is linked from here the previous
class documents and resources
and now we are in the third class and
we'll have a few more
resources soon um so last time i think
we stopped on the
inc instruction uh it's the first
instruction that
uh is doing arithmetic before of that we
just
load the data and save data and move
data
between registers um so where is the
ink ink ink
okay increment so um we did it
but let's do it real quick again just as
a refresher
uh so this is the name of the
instruction the description
it's it adds one one not minus one one
to the contents of the register and
places the result in the same register
um and you can see like it can work on
rd so ink rd and d can be between 0 to
31 so it can work on
any of the registers and if you need a
refresher there is like a quick summary
here
about the registers that we have in avr
there is actually one more which we will
probably touch today the stack pointer
but we'll get to that um
so inky's
and all the all the other automatic
instructions
actually uh updates this status and flex
register that we have seen last time
for instance it updates the uh z flag
the zero flag
and that flag is set to one if the
result was zero
and there is like this um
flag and that tells us if it was
negative um
and uh if there was uh an overflow
uh from uh signed integer to answer
from answer like in if it was a side
integer and there was an overflow but
let's not worry about this for now
let's just worry about z because it's
going to be the most useful
um anyway let's just
uh do a quick demo so let's say we have
value actually i want it to be just one
byte
you need eight so uh value
is uh five never mind
uh let's also set up the serial output
so we can see
the output uh and let serial println
value and obviously this will be
one okay why did that happen
uh interesting i didn't expect that to
happen that's strange
[Music]
i don't know why it prints one
something is wrong um anyway let's
try to refresh the page it may or may
not help
and try that again
surely missing out something
okay interesting
oh yeah yeah yeah it should have been
serial.begin.println
uh so it tries to print that number and
then we haven't set up the serial so
uh it doesn't continue printing it just
sends out the first character
um okay so now this
looks more sane so we have this and it
prints five
perfect and now let's just uh increment
it
and we we don't really know which
register
the compiler uses for this variable in
fact it will probably optimize this to
read as
just real println five but um
if we use the read we can actually uh
force it to be copied uh
into a register so we want it to be in a
register
and a value and then we can ink
the first uh opera at the first operand
which is
r and this doesn't work
because the compiler doesn't actually
expect us to update value
so we could use this syntax which tells
its we want
to write back to uh r
but if we wanted to use the same
register for both
we can actually write here um instead of
this r
just the number of the argument so 0
is like the same as this it tells the
compiler
i want you to use the same register or
the same
constraint as i defined here uh in this
uh read so basically it will read uh the
value
from this register and then write it
back to the same register
and if we run it now we can see that we
got six
so um basically that's what ink does
and uh like increment we also have
decrement
which is minus one and um
the uh decrement like uh
is pretty similar uh actually uh we
don't need
even need to uh look at the manual
because it does the same
uh to make it a bit more interesting we
can also see how it affects
the flag the flex
multi-line assembly statement
close the multiline
okay so uh we have this trick where uh
if we have this break it will print out
the registers
and um specifically
when we decremented this value we can
see like there were
a bunch of registers set like the carry
and
the h um if we use
increment again we can see um
yeah yeah we can see like
uh it's basically the same flex that
were set
and if we have here like uh this value
then uh after incrementing it's one byte
so it overflows to zero
and we can see that the z register was
set so
uh just like uh the manual says uh where
is
increment uh that's increment yeah
uh if the result is zero then uh we set
the c
the c flag so uh we can see verify here
that it actually worked it actually said
it's flag when the result was
zero um just like
ink and add we have uh instructions to
shift right and shift left so for
instance
let's say we have this value of
4 and we want to
uh shift it left so basically shifting
left is like
multiplying by 2. so
logical shift left zero uh
the register name that's uh zero uh
percent zero
and uh we can see we got eight so
basically multiplying by two
and then we have shift right which is
the equivalent of dividing by two and uh
just like before
they uh update the flags for example if
we had one here
and we would divide it by two uh we see
that the zero flag has been set
and a bunch of other flags so
um basically these are like the basic
operations
of uh um shifting right and left
incrementing decrementing another useful
one
is uh com which is just a complement
which means
bitwise not so if we have for instance 0
the nut value of 0 is 255
so bitwise not um we can actually see
uh yeah basically bitwise not again
uh you can check out the um
the instruction manual and see
how many uh cycles it takes one cycle
and carry is always set to one after
note and this one is always cleared and
zero is
only if the result is zero and um
basically they all all the instructions
the arithmetic instructions have uh
a similar effect on the flex um
okay and then um the next instruction
um this one is uh i think
uh it's a bit unique i'm not sure if it
uh if there is such extraction on the
x86 or other
architectures it's called swap and what
it does is basically
uh swapping the nibbles of
a byte so instead of 42 hexa once we run
this
we can see that now we have 24 so it
just
swaps the digits uh the hexadecimal
digit
of um the number so another useful
instruction
and uh let's just quickly write down the
instructions that we covered
that so that we won't forget so we had
uh ink and deck we had um
then lsl r shift right left
and then we had uh comp which is bit
while it's not
and swap nibbles
um so these are all uh unary
instructions so they get one value
and or run register and they work on the
value in this register
another instruction which is a binary
instruction
is sbr and there is also cbr
and what they do are they let us um
set a beat on a register so sbr sets bit
in a register
uh basically we give it a constant uh
k some kind of constant and it will set
all the bits in the constants
uh to the on the register so it will do
a bitwise or
logical or between the contents of the
register
and the constant and this way it will
allow us to set some bits in the
uh register uh for instance
uh we can uh we have this value
42 we can set bit number
uh one and then it will be
43 and if we set bit number two which is
already set in this case
uh there won't be any effect we'll get
the same result
so sbr sets a bit um we have
sbr and cbr uh
similarly clears the given bits so
this will actually clear that bit number
two and then we are only left with 40.
and we can also clear this uh this bit
so basically cbr with this mask
will uh clear this bit the uh 40 hexa
that's the uh second most significant
bit
and we will be left with two so cbr is
just uh uh steps and
clear bits uh i'm hearing something in
the audio is there
anyone who okay
probably just an artifact um
cool so uh these are like uh
all the operations the basic operations
that uh work on a single register
there are probably a few more like neg
but
they aren't really interesting right now
and
just like we did here you can you know
find any of them
in the manual if you encounter them or
need them
um and then there are a few um
few operations that uh work on um
two operations or two operands like
adding two numbers so
let's for instance value and value two
so we want to add two and forty hexa
and then we will add it as another
register we get we read from actually
let's give it a name
so it will be easier to follow and then
we add
to the first register this one we add
the
value to actually let's give this one a
name as well let's call it
in one and
here in one
the same one and this will be in two
and then add in one in
two um and
hopefully we'll get here 42 as it will
be adding the two numbers
and it's also uh let's make this a bit
bigger
yep it's also one more
yep it's also updating the flag so in
this case
uh the result uh was not zero but for
instance if we
add two to uh fe
exa then it will overflow and we'll have
zero and carry uh so the result was zero
that's why the zero flag was set and
carry because
f e plus two
actually equals uh
100 extra so this is the result but we
got
an overflow we got uh a carry uh
another bit to the left which was
omitted so it ended up in the
carry flag um and
um just like adding two numbers we can
also
uh subtract two numbers so uh
this will basically do value
uh minus value two so the result is one
or twenty-two minus 1 is 15
that's actually hexa so that's right so
it should be 21 in decimal um
so adding and subtracting and
sub uh
oh thanks for uh for this comment uh
mikhail um yeah
and um i think a few more useful
are like uh bitwise and or
and uh xor
exclusive or one thing to note they
don't
call it xor they call it exclusive or er
um and let's just uh you know do
exclusive or between two numbers and
sir when you sort two numbers that are
the same value you get zero
so let's try that and yeah we can see we
got zero
also the zero flag is set because the
result is zero zero
um and uh and and or
they work similarly get two arguments
and
two registers and update the first
register with the result of the
operation so we have
also and or and er which is
sore which are just bitwise operations
cool thanks for the edition mikhail
okay so that is that's it with
arithmetic instructions
and right now uh we can uh there are a
few more
like multiplying numbers and dividing
numbers and i encourage you to test
check them out like uh mull and
i think there is one for division i'm
not sure actually i think there isn't
uh division in the avr um
as far as i remember i just multiplied
yeah there isn't uh just uh shifting
if you want if you want to divide
numbers you have to write a code for
that yourself
uh isn't that hilarious anyway
so there is uh instruction for
multiplication add width carries
subtract would carry
and all of that but um let's go
what happened here let's go over to the
more interesting stuff
so uh we know how to load data from the
memory how to save data from the memory
and how to uh perform arithmetic
operations on it
um but what about control flow
so the first thing we are going to see
is actually this
useful instruction it's called jump
and it lets you um go to a different
location in the program
just like the go to
the go to keyword in c that you should
never use
so basically the syntax is jump and
where to jump
and um we can give it an offset like uh
100 and it will jump to location 100 in
the program
but we don't really know where we will
end up unless we end up
we write all the instructions and
figure out their uh calculator addresses
uh so we can use labels like uh let's
jump to before and before just uh define
before just
after the jump and that would create an
endless loop so
if i run the program you can see it sort
of
got stuck here it never printed the
value and the break was not executed
or i can jump forward
let's jump to after and
yeah so after the break and you can see
that
the break didn't uh execute so i didn't
get the debugging for the console
so um yeah so
um that's jump and by itself it's
not very useful so how can we
um how can we make some kind of
conditional jump jump if
and the answer for that um
there are like a bunch of instructions
which are called
conditional branches which are just like
jmp but
they jump depending on the value of the
um
the flex so they are defined here in
conditional brands summary
and basically there is a bunch of them
and we'll go
over it in a moment but first of all you
need to
uh you can see here that they all like
look at the flex
and decide based on deflects on this
condition whether they should jump
for instance uh we can jump if
it's zero or jump if not zero
um like if the zero flag is set or if
it's
not set and um
what we can uh do for instance so we
know this uh
e or only x uh will return zero if these
values are equal because that's what
sword has we have just seen that
so for instance we can say instead of
jumping over break we can say that we
want
to jump
to after only if uh it's the result is
not zero so that's
uh brne um so
um let's do that so
um now when i run the program
uh we can see that uh
interesting it
oh yeah it's not zero so it didn't jump
so uh the result is zero so this jump
didn't happen
and we had this output but if the result
would have been different
like 54 and 50 which would not give zero
then uh it would take the branch because
the result is not
zero and we won't get a debug output so
basically
uh once we uh perform some kind of
arithmetic instruction
we can use the result in the flex in
order to conditionally
branch to another place and that's how
we implement
we implement conditional logic
and and also loops and
before we see a more complex example i
will show you one more
useful instruction and it's super useful
with those branch instructions
because usually you want just to compare
two numbers and you don't care about the
result
here the exclusive or actually stores
the result
into in one so there is another
instructions
instruction called cp compare
and it compares to register and none of
the registers are changed
and all conditional branches can be used
after his instruction
so basically this instruction just
checks
uh compares these registers and
updates the flex whether the result was
negative or
positive and the nice thing about it you
don't really have to worry about the
meaning of the flags
uh if you check out the table uh that we
have seen before this
summary um we can just like uh
call compare with two registers and then
uh
choose the condition that we want let's
see how we do that in practice
so we are going to define a new function
uh we'll call it uh max 8 and in
function
this function gets two arguments let's
call it
uh left and right
and uh basically what it's going to do
it's going to compare them
and then um return the maximum
of them so let's have another variable
for
to hold the result and then we can uh
just uh copy this that's what i always
do within my assembly just copy it
instead of writing this from scratch
and uh we can start writing the logic
here first of all
we want to store the result into
result and we want to read from
a register left
and another register
right and let's call them right and left
in assembly as well
so these are the names we'll use inside
the assembly these are the variables we
are reading from or
writing to and then we are going to
compare them
so comparing uh
left and right and uh
i have two rights uh do hi where
uh if you mean here oh here yeah right
thanks uh thanks uh maro
um and if i have
uh so i compare these two numbers and
now i want to decide what to do
so uh basically if left is bigger
store left into result otherwise
store write into result
so the first thing i want to do before i
jump into the table
i want to see if i'm doing this with
signed integers or unsigned integers and
in this case i'm using unsigned integers
so when i'm looking at the table i will
only look at this section
which is talking about unsigned i don't
care about assigned now i'm looking at
the sign section
and now i want to check if um
rd is greater or equal than
rr and uh for that i can use this
instruction
brsh um
yeah funny
so brsh
and so brsh
and we'll go to uh left
is greater is
greater so if left is greater or equal
uh then we will oh s8 stands for same or
higher and i guess if uh we will
check yeah same fire thanks uh mikhail
uh yeah and that's also
and other branches and we also had a cp
compared to registers okay
so uh if this is same or higher
then we are going to this
left is greater than eq otherwise
uh we are just we know that right is uh
greater so we will move uh we'll copy it
into result
right and if left oh and
uh we don't want to execute the code in
leftist greater so we'll need to
use jump here and jump uh to the end
so jumping to the end and
uh if left is greater then we just want
to move
um left into the result
and now hopefully we have a function
that compiles and works we don't need
those comments
um and um
i will compile it and let's actually
print some use the test cases already so
uh max 8 of
10 and 20 and
20 and 10 and some edge cases like
0 and 255 0 and -1 which is
255 because these are unsigned integers
and let's run this and we can see that
uh
it doesn't work maximum of 10 and 20
is not 10. this works
so it seems to always return the
left argument let's try to figure out
what's the reason for that
um yeah um
first of all let's check um
so let's call it only once with
actually here it should return 20.
so let's call it only once and then add
a break here
so we can see what's going on and we can
see that uh it took the branch
interesting
oh it didn't it took the branch left is
greater
even though the right value is greater
in this case um
because if we put a break here we can
oh it doesn't print the debug output
interesting
interesting we don't get any debug
output at all at
all here uh did we
call
um let's see
[Music]
just a sanity check that we get into
this function
yep and let's print left
and right yeah it works so
uh what's happened what happens with the
asm
statement and uh
i have an idea what it might be
no interesting
let's just narrow it down for instance
for a second
to okay that's interesting
uh one more thing to that
oh okay so uh this is
something that sometimes happens the
compiler figures out
that disassembly is not needed for
whatever optimization reasons
and just removes it all together so
using the keyword volatile can actually
help here
and the reason uh the compiler optimized
this
output is this uh code out
is pretty simple uh we um
do the calculation and store it into
result but we do nothing with result
so basically what happened is that uh
the compiler so this code and then okay
it does something
stores the result or introduced variable
but nobody is using this variable
so uh i'm just going to optimize that
out
and that's the reason why when we called
break
we didn't see anything in the console
because this code was
never emitted and then volatile is a
special keyword that tells the compiler
you know what never optimize this code
away
and when we added volatile we can see
that this code is executed and we have
seen the break
and this helped me figure out that
normally this code didn't execute it was
optimized out and then i realized that
this is because we forgot to return
results so let's do that
um and let's return all the test cases
and now let's also remove this print so
it won't confuse that confuse us and now
running it again we get expected results
so
2020 and 255 255 that's the maximum
now um just uh to show you
uh what would happen if we use the
signed instructions uh so that was
signed branches so instead of using
brsh we could have used brge which is
the signed version of this condition
then we would get something different
suddenly zero is greater than 255
because this number is no longer
interpreted as a
positive integer it's interpreted as
minus one
um so yeah so
uh bs is adding in the chat that
volatile is also useful
for the same reason when debugging
because often some parts of the code are
optimized out and no longer match the c
source
that's true and you can also define
variables volatile so if we had this
variable volatile then
assembly would uh the compiler would see
we are referencing
it inside the asm statement and it would
not
optimize it away so i think uh if you
are writing inline assembly it's best to
start
with volatile probably and then remove
it and
as you have seen it it really helps you
catching backs
if you see that the behavior changes
when volatile is not there
um so um
and yeah somebody also mentioned
interrupts so
defining a variable as volatile is also
useful if it's
accessed from interrupts but that's out
of scope right now
so yeah so we implemented our first
logic in assembly
and there is a little problem that you
should be aware of
with those labels so actually
let's say i want to
change this code and call this one end
as well
and i will try to compile it and
actually did compile because i think
this one was
optimized away yep now it
wasn't um
[Music]
again i calculated something and i
didn't print the value i didn't use it
so it was optimized so that way
it wasn't compiled but now it was
compiled and the assembler tell me
and is already defined and that's an
issue with those labels because they are
global
in the entire source file so uh
just like that i couldn't use a label
that matches the name of function like
if i call it setup
for some reason it worked
probably because that's a c plus plus
function we'll talk about it in a moment
but if i called it for instance i think
digitalwrite for instance
is a c function let's check that
no interesting um or maybe start
yep so for some reason uh
i guess the cd plus plus name mangling
doesn't
uh doesn't uh changes the name of the
function so
uh it doesn't make a problem but still
they are global like
i can't use and in two different places
that would fail
so uh there are a few ways around it one
way
is just uh use the name the function
name
in front of each label inside a function
something like that
to sort of guarantee uniqueness that
could work
um and there is also a syntax for local
labels
so instead of calling them names i just
give them numbers so that would be one
and that would be two and then instead
of
branching to one i need to tell it
whether it should branch forward go down
or branch backward go up so in this case
i want it to go down
so one f means one look for the closest
one down
and here i want to branch to two f so
go to uh the closest two tile uh down
and then i can compile it happily and it
works
and if i add another one here
this branch would still go to this
number one because it looks for the
closest
number one so that's why they are sort
of local
and you can have a hub to up to uh nine
of those so from one to nine
um and they are pretty useful for
uh i wanted to remove that one
for shorter code snippets um
and for longer one i usually just break
it down to smaller functions
um there is also another syntax that
lets us add a unique number uh
so let's call it greater uh that's the
syntax
but it only works in inline assembly so
i usually don't use that uh syntax it
just adds some unique
a random number uh that is unique per
each asm statement or something like
that
so it exists but i usually don't advise
using it because
then the code only works in inline
assembly
um cool so um
we had uh max eight and now
um i i i will briefly mention
so uh we had cp oh thank you
i will briefly mention a few more
instructions that are useful
so there is uh for instance uh
cpi comparing with immediate just
compare a register with some value
instead of another register
this is a nice shortcut if you know you
just want to compare
with some value so you don't have to
copy that into a different register
first
and there is also a bunch of
instructions that
are unique
[Music]
there is also a bunch of instructions
that are
unique to avr i think and these
instructions are called
uh skip so we can skip the next
instruction
on in some conditions like if a specific
bit in the register
is set or cleared uh so
if this bit is set or clicked it will
just uh skip
the next instruction um but
they are useful uh i mean you can get
the same thing
you can do the same thing with the
branches and uh
bitwise operations so they are useful
but
i mean you can find them here if you
need them but we are not going to go and
use them right now
um and uh the next topic i want
to the next thing i want to do actually
is
uh to get rid of this asm to stop
writing inline assembly because
when we wanted to test just one or two
instructions
that was fine but now we have a whole
function that is basically assembly but
we have to write
all these fancy syntax just to get it to
work
and uh for that to work we need to
uh we if we want to define our own
functions
in uh assembly we actually need to know
how the compiler uh
expect a function what it expects from a
function
and we can find this information
in uh here yep
in the uh avr gcc wiki
and uh this is a section called abi
application binary interface let's um
put it in this document so
uh that's
the text would be gc avr
gcc application binary
interface and the application binary
interface basically defines
how the uh compiler uses the registers
and how it calls functions how it passes
the arguments
so it's all defined here and we can see
like uh it defines the sizes of types
so in is two bytes long is four bytes
long long is
eight bytes etc um
and there is a bunch of other uh things
regarding types
but then there is this section about
register layouts and
[Music]
there are like a few interesting bits
here first of all values that occupy
uh more than eight bit one eight bit
register so
16 bits or 32 values always start in an
even register so if the compiler needed
needs to store a value
in two registers because it's too big it
will always start with
an even register like r30
r22 r4 and then we have a few registers
that are spatial
so r0 is used as a scratch resistor that
not need not to be restored after it's
used after
its usage so if we want to use some
temporal
register inside inline assembly we can
actually use r0
because uh it's a scratch resistor a
register the compiler doesn't expect it
to preserve its value so um
that's okay the only way uh time we need
to take care of it is
inside an isr um and
if we are using inline assembly we can
use this macro instead of writing r0
and r1 always contains zero so uh
the the um compiler needs the value zero
in
many different cases so it just stores
this value in this register
and whenever it needs a zero like uh to
end something with zero to add
to multiply by zero or whatever um
it just uh uses the value in r1
um so uh you can always
if you are running inside
this c environment you can always assume
that
r1 is equal to 0 and you must never
change its value
and then there are a few other registers
uh these registers are call clobbered
this means that any function can use
them and
it doesn't need to restore the content
so if you write your
if you create your own function uh like
we did here you can basically use these
registers
uh for free um and you know that
uh the compiler doesn't really uh care
about their content
if we had non-assembly con the code here
then that would have
probably been different um but if it's
a pure assembly function then these
registers are free to use
um and then the remaining registers
are called saved so if you change them
you must store them to the memory or to
the stack as you will see
and then before your function returns
you must restore their
original content so uh if you want
to write code that will uh work uh
in harmony with this environment just
like we did here
uh and we had to respect the fact that
we are running uh
inside uh the gc compiled uh
code we have to respect this constraint
in order not to um to
interfere with uh the other code that
gcc compiled for us
and another interesting piece of
information
is the calling convention so uh
i won't go over this uh long text
it's a bit cumbersome but basically
defines
[Music]
how parameters are passed to functions
and i think this
summarizes uh this example summarizes
this
uh pretty good so we have a function
that returns in
and take two arguments a character and
um
a long value and we can see that the
first argument will be pressed in
r24 and then b will be passed in these
four registers so
20 to 33
so in a nutshell if it's uh
one or two bytes then the first argument
will always be in
r24 and if it's two bytes like un16 it
will be also
the high byte will be in r25 and then
the result is stored
r24 lsb and r25 msp
and uh like this example is useful for
most of the functions that you will
create uh
they will probably not take more than
one or two arguments
uh if this argument wasn't long if it
was like a character or
unit 16 it would start in artwork with
in r22 and not r20
but to really understand how to
calculate this just uh
you can go over this and it explains the
algorithm
um so uh
okay so uh julian is asking whether
there is
uh a reference for the
assembler level format
uh as far as i can tell i couldn't
really
find a coherent reference
uh these 1f and 2f i will look for it
for the next time if i can find
something better but
uh basically everything is global except
for those look a little bit
like labels with numbers um
that's what i found um
so cool so uh now that we
uh know how the uh
compiler passes arguments and what it
expects from functions we can actually
create our
first uh pure assembly functions
and um i think we i haven't tried it but
i think we can't really do this
like uh like
here that would probably not work
just emitting assembly code random
assembly code globally
oh it works so uh there might be
uh it might work you may be able to
define functions pure assembly functions
using this asm statement i haven't tried
it
but what i usually do which makes a lot
more sense to me
is just uh to create a new file uh
with assembly code so let's
let's call it uh hackaday
and the extension has to be s so it will
be
uh assembled and not compiled with the c
compiler
and then let's start with a really
simple function
that uh uh basically we don't we want to
create a swap function that
will uh swap the evils just like the
instruction does we don't have that
operator in c so let's create a function
for that
so uh for that we just need to define a
label
like we did here and that would be the
name of the function
and then we remember that
oh somebody asking about the extension
that's an uppercase
s hackaday.uppercase s um
so we said that the first argument will
if it's
uh uh one byte or two will be passed in
r24
and the result in r24 as well so
uh basically we just need to swap r24
because uh arc 1
r24 result in r34 it's the same
register so we can just uh
you know do whatever and then
the other thing we need to do we need to
uh
write red which means there is no syntax
highlighting here
or autocomplete for assembly uh i will
probably fix it
over the next few weeks but for now
we'll have to
imagine it's colored
and then in order to be able to call
this function from other another
module from the main sketch for instance
i need to say to declare that it's
global so
it's sort of a way to say that this
label is actually exported from this
file and that's all we need to do
from the assembly side of thing and
in an idle world we could just say
something like
let's say this let's remove those
actually let's keep them for later so
let's remove all this clutter we don't
need it anymore
um yeah maybe i will just copy this to
uh the document so you will have it as a
reference later
um okay and
um in an idle world we could just say
something like
uh serial println and then
println swap uh let's say
42 and expected to expect it to be 24
but unfortunately uh the compiler said
i don't know about swap what swap
and in order to uh make the compiler
recognize that function we need to
declare it
so just tell it there is a function
called swap
it returns uh unit eight and
um it also takes the you indeed
argument um and
the reason we need to do it is so that
the compiler know
which registers to use because this
depends on the size
of the uh like argument which registers
it should use to pass this value
and if we run it it still doesn't
compile it says
undefined reference to swap and that's
pretty tricky
the reason it's it does it is because it
actually expects a different function
name
uh i don't remember what's the name of
this but c plus plus adds
uh some sort of decoration to the
function name so
it's something like swaps underscore
something i don't
remember the exact syntax uh because
uh the function name also uh the
compiled function name
also includes information about the
types of the uh parameters and the
return value
so uh in order to fix that we can just
uh say this is a c function which is
a bit of a cheating because it's an
assembly function
but basically what this does is tell the
compiler hey
just call it swap don't do any like name
angling
i think that's what it's called um
just uh look for a function called swap
without every addition any additions or
changes
and now if we compile it uh
it actually compiled and we got the
correct result
so that was our first assembly function
and now i want to show you how we take
this uh max 8 and implement it
in inline assembly in assembly
uh how it would look in assembly so
basically
we have max 8 and
just like before let's make it also
global
max eight uh arg1 in r24
r2 in r22 so going
uh down by two for each argument as long
as they are
uh one or two bytes um
and then we just define it and then uh
we don't need all the variables and we
don't need all this clutter
we just need to do something like this
uh we compare part one
with part two uh if it's greater then
jump here otherwise uh we move
uh we copy um
result so r24
and r2 that was r22 so we just copy the
second argument to the result
um but actually uh if
here if we are here if there this is
greater
we have to copy r24 into hardware d4
but we don't really need this right so
basically we can remove it because it
doesn't do anything
and now we can see that uh jumping 2f
actually does nothing because uh it just
jumps to the next instruction so we can
uh
remove it as well and then a lot and the
label as well
and then the last thing we need is just
the return the red
to tell it to go back to the function
that uh called us
so uh just changing this
lowercase so basically now compare this
with this and i think you understand why
you want to avoid inline assembly
whenever you can like if you can just
write a function
uh straight in assembly then it's much
shorter easier
um and you don't have to work very hard
to
cooperate with the compiler and now
let's just
make sure that it still works we still
need a function
signature though like we had for uh
swap and let's have all these test cases
again and we can see it still works
uh i don't know if you remember but we
are getting here
uh zero instead of this because this is
uh
sign we we change it to be
a signed comparison if we go back to
brsh then
it will be unsigned comparison and this
one will be greater than
zero so yeah that's how we are going to
write assembly for the rest of the
course
no more having to fiddle with those uh
with this awkward syntax
um and
uh one more thing uh
about function calls so
whenever you uh call a function like uh
here where was that yeah like here
or calling swap it's actually uh
pushing the address of the return
address like the address of the next
instruction into the stack
and this stack is like a data structure
that starts at the end of the memory
and it goes down so whenever we are
calling a function
uh there is a new value at the bottom of
the stack
and then the stack pointer goes uh
decrements to point to the uh next
location in the stack which is uh
down in the memory and then
what ret does it basically takes the
instruction
from uh the top of the stack so
basically
uh it's the instruction that the the
address that was pushed when we
call this function and it jumps to that
instruction so it removes the top value
from the stack
and uh go sets the
pc the program counter to that value and
that's how calling function works
functions work and we have a few utility
functions so
in this utility instructions so in this
case
we had really simple functions and we
didn't really need to
use any temporal registers
if we needed some temporary registers we
could have used
all of those
scratch regis clobbered registers
without worrying too much
because this c doesn't the compiler
doesn't expect us to save them
but in the next lesson we are going to
implement fibonacci
which is a recursive function and then
we'll have to
have some temporary space to
[Music]
store the registers while
we call the function recursively
and then we'll see how we use uh the
stack for that with the push and pop
instructions
but i think that would be for uh the
next time
um so let's do a quick review of what we
had today
um so we learned about a bunch of new
arithmetic instructions
and now we have also red and then
we saw how to compare numbers and
how to define functions in pure assembly
and
how to uh return from functions but
more importantly i think we'll learn
about
uh thanks for the reminder
we learned about the avr gcc abi which
lets us call
our assembly functions from c
and we can also do the opposite like we
could also
call uh some of the uh actually we have
one one in it so
we can do that let's make swap also uh
turn this uh
led on so basically we want to call
digital write that's a c library
function
and we know it gets p number
and a high or low so uh that's pin
13 first argument hold the ir2413
ldir22 um
r321 because it's high
and now our um yeah it won't swap
anymore because now
we are destroying the value in r24 but
now our swap function uh actually should
actually turn on this
built-in led let's see that yep it
worked so
uh we we can now that we know the api we
we can define functions in uh avr
in pure avr assembly not the inline
assembly
and we can also use that to uh call c or
c plus plus functions
from our assembly code which lets us
basically uh integrate the two pieces
so uh yeah we can also add call to the
list
you now know how to use it and the
the really important piece here is the
abi
so um that's it for today um
i hope it was uh intense but not too
intense
and um yeah i will take questions
in a moment before that uh last week we
announced that
uh we will have a final project in
the course and i've put together a
description of the project
it's basically building a pong game
in avr uh assembly like
we have here but from scratch uh without
using any of the library functions
and uh right now i guess
you still don't have all the information
you need in order to
create this game um but after lesson
number five
you should have it so we still have a
long way to go
in the next two lessons but uh
this is just to give you a general sense
of uh the final project
and uh if you want to get a certificate
from hackaday then
you would have to uh do that
and if you have any questions about
instructions just
or about anything here we learned today
i just hit me on the hackaday chat or
the discord channel of walkway i'm
always there waiting for you um
i'll also add this link even though it's
uh i will probably add some more
information
over the next couple of days uh that
would be
final project oh i love this uh
this responses challenge accepted
intense but no the intense
perfect thanks uh project description
i'm looking forward to see what kind of
punks you will make