[Music]
hi there my name is alexander rousell
i'm a canadian hacker specializing in
embedded systems prototyping and
development
i partnered with hackaday to bring you a
hackaday u course about serial buses
in this course we're going to be looking
at two of the more popular serial buses
used in embedded development which are
i squared c and one wire they're used to
communicate with memories and
sensors and peripherals of all kinds
we're going to be looking at both of
these protocols from the
software hardware and protocol levels
and we're going to be actually
looking at practical implementations of
these protocols
so we can actually gather some data
process it and then do something with it
like send it to the cloud or display it
to an
end user i'm really excited to be
presenting this course and i hope that
you sign up
if you want more information about this
course or about any of the hackaday u
courses you can go to hackaday.io
you or you can check out the hackaday i
o page for this course if you want more
details
on what we're going to be learning thank
you so much and i look forward to having
you as part of this course