[Music]
hi
i'm maribel jones and i'm an interactive
artist working with new technology
i'm also a software developer and
educator previously i worked as a senior
designer developer at meow wolf
building room scale interactive art
installations i'm partnering with
hackaday to bring you all this class on
developing your own interactive artwork
using tools like arduino and fast led in
this class students will learn how to
work with sensors including motion
sensors
light sensors temperature sensors and
microphones as well as other input to
create their own interactive
programs using the circuit playground
microcontroller
we'll also learn about leds sound
components and how to make robotics
projects with moving parts
using servos this course is suitable for
complete beginners
as well as experienced developers and
makers who are familiar with
microcontroller programming
but want to learn more about designing
and developing for interactive art
we hope you'll join us for this exciting
course in interactive technology
using sensors