[Music]
welcome back to interactive art using
sensors in light
in our first class we looked at how to
use capacitive touch sensing to trigger
sound output in the second class we'll
learn how to use leds to output light
we'll get some inspiration for wearables
and installations and learn how to
create beautiful lighting animations
moving patterns of light we'll also
learn how to use the three sensors that
come onboard the circuit playground
express
the temperature light and sound sensors
to trigger interactive events
we'll continue to develop our c plus
programming skills as we learn about
float variables
if else if statements and while loops
we've got a lot to cover today so let's
get started
if you're jumping into this course for
the first time please visit
mirabellejones.com
forward slash hackaday hyphen sensors
here you'll find links to the github
that will have all of the course
source code and also links to the
slideshows
which have links in turn
and if you need help getting set up you
can find the slides for class 1
which will walk you through how to
install the adafruit circuit playground
board
and library and also how to install
arduino
if you don't have your environment set
up yet
an led is a light emitting diode
when current passes through the led
it causes the led to light up
to get to our example sketches we want
to go to file
examples and then down to adafruit
circuit playground
here you'll see a whole bunch of
sketches that you can use
you can really dig into these to learn
how to use the microphone
the light sensor and more but for
starters
let's just blink this led to get to the
blink sketch we want to go to
hello circuit playground underneath
hello circuit playground there are some
introductory sketches that should get
you started using some of the onboard
sensors of the circuit playground
let's start with blink
in this sketch we see that we're
including the adafruit circuit
playground library
this is the first line of our sketch
then we have a setup function and a loop
function
these are the two main functions in
arduino
in our setup we're initializing the
circuit playground
circuit playground.begin we'll need to
do this
every time we want to use any function
that's in the circuit playground library
then in our loop we're saying circuit
playground
dot red led high
then we have a delay of 500 milliseconds
or half
of the second then we're saying circuit
playground.red led
low and then have another delay for half
a second
what this sketch is doing is it's
targeting the red led
which is d13 on the circuit playground
express
this is an indicator led that's a single
color led
just like the one i showed in the video
this led will light up when current
passes through
again just like i showed in the video so
what we're doing is we're saying
hi which is sending the maximum voltage
that we can to this led 255
then we're setting it to low meaning
that we're setting it to zero
the lowest amount that we can send it
and we have a delay in between
so when we upload this we should see the
led blink
let's give it a try to upload a sketch
you want to go to the arrow at the top
if you hover over this it'll say upload
you also want to make sure that you have
the correct
board and port selected
once you know that this is the case
click the arrow to upload your sketch
you'll see the leds on the circuit
playground go from red
then to green when they've gone to green
you know that it's been
uploaded correctly
now we can see the red indicator led d13
blinking
if you encounter any problems uploading
your sketch you can press the reset
button twice
and reset your controller for your first
challenge try going back to the sketch
and trying to get the led to blink at a
different rate as a hint
try using a different delay value what
is a neopixel
each rgb led or neopixel is actually
made up of three smaller leds
one red one green and one blue the
combination of these three color
channels creates the visible color of
the led
when all three colors are turned on
you'll see white and when none of them
are that's black so black is always
equivalent to off
other colors are created by mixing the
three color values
you can try this out for yourself by
using the hello neopixel sketch
try changing the last three numbers in
the parentheses to mix the red green
and blue color values let's give this a
try
we see our leds light up with various
rainbow colors
and then they go black
this happens at a half second cycle
it's nice having source code to use but
we learn best by trying things ourselves
let's try changing the values in circuit
playground.set pixel color
to make our own colors can you try
changing
the pixel number and also the rgb values
in the first challenge just try making
your own colors have fun and experiment
for the second challenge try turning all
of them to purple
for the third challenge try turning them
all to white
and then all off and then all white
again
for advanced users try using a for loop
to set the color of all the leds at the
same time
or try making your own animations
this principle of finding an example or
demo sketch
and then experimenting with the
functions and also the variable values
in order to see what they do will serve
you well when learning arduino
programmable rgb leds use an onboard
driver chip to turn the electrical
signals on your data wire
into programmable colors by setting the
red green and blue channels accordingly
the library we'll be using fast led can
handle most programmable led drivers
the most commonly used are ws-2811 2812
and 2813
adafruit's neopixel line are some of our
favorites due to the wide variety of
products they offer
but you can also find more affordable
products online
individual leds you can get surface
mount through-hole and even sewable leds
online
these can be great for embedding subtle
lights into projects or wearables
without ending up with an overt
light strip look
led strip the led workhorse
strip comes in densities from 30 leds
per meter to 144
higher density strips require more power
note the led strip is easily damaged if
you don't take care when installing it
it's best to not bend or crease led
strip
so if you take it around a corner it's
best to cut the strip and solder some
jumper wires between the two strips
led modules these are individual rgb
leds
each sealed into its own waterproof
module with a diffuser
short wires typically four inches
separate each module from the next
great for a light bright look or for
embedding individual pixels into the
surface of complex outdoor artworks
led matrixes these come in square or
rectangular formats
larger matrixes require more power
the leds in your matrix can either be
wired across like a typewriter
or back and forth like a snake fast led
can address both
as long as you tell it which type you
have if your matrix doesn't say
then don't worry experimenting is an
easy way to find out
led rings these come in sizes from about
12 leds up to 60.
the larger rings require two power
injections we'll talk about those later
the smalls can be powered off in arduino
as is
these look cool as they are but they're
also fun to embed inside round objects
they can make cool eyes if you install
them in pairs and are careful with the
programming
side emitting led strip these are
powerful when you want to use led strips
but you need to attach the lights to the
inside of a solid shape
such as a tube or half dome or need them
to shine
out rather than up unlike regular flat
strips these strips can bend to an
extent without damage
led neon these leds are embedded inside
a thick neon look diffuser
they're quite flexible making them
perfect for lining complex surfaces
using as recessed lighting in a room or
making neon art
now it's time to make our own animations
using the fast led library
vast led is a powerful library that
allows us to make many patterns and
animations
pretty easily if you haven't already you
can download the fast led library
to do so go to manage libraries and then
click add fast led
you'll find example sketches from the
fast led library
under file examples fast led
we can use any of the sketches in the
fast led library
with our circuit playground express all
we have to do
is change the data pin to 8. the data
pin
8 is where all the leds are wired to
here's how to install the fast led
library go to manage libraries
and then in the search bar
type in fast led it should be one word
there may be a few options that come up
but we want to grab the first one that's
just called fast led
select the most recent version and then
click install
once it's installed open up fast led's
blink sketch
this can be found under examples fast
led
and blink
you'll notice that this sketch looks
very different from our other blink
sketch
this is because fast led programs
lighting a little differently
first what we'll want to do is comment
out clock pin
we can do this with two forward slashes
then we want to change the define for
data pin to eight
eight is the pin that all of our leds on
board the circuit playground
are connected to then we want to change
the number of leds to 10
there are 10 on-board leds
double check your values then hit upload
hmm only one led is blinking we change
numb leds to 10 so why don't all of them
work
here's why leds within fast led
are treated as elements in an array you
can see the array declaration
on or around line 14. if you don't have
line numbers turned on
you can go to preferences
and then check displaying line numbers
so on line 13 we see crgb
leds num leds as an array
this tells fast led we would like to
reserve space for an array
of 10 crgb objects aka
rgb pixels note that this line
always goes at the top outside of the
setup and loop functions
below you'll see the following line in
setup
fast led add leds neopixel data pin
and then in parentheses leds comma num
leds
this tells fastlady that you have
neopixels on data pin
they're to be stored in the leds array
and there are num leds of them
you always need a fast led to add leds
call and setup when working with fast
led
there are many options for this line
since there are many kinds of leds in
the world
check out the other entries for some
possibilities
anyway scroll down to the loop function
and we'll see why our leds aren't
lighting up
in loop our code says the following leds
0 equals crgb red
then there's a call to fast led show
which is a function of fast led
then we have a delay of half a second
what this says
is light leds number zero to red
then call fast leds show then wait half
a second before continuing
then the code does the exact thing to
set the led at zero back to black
completing our blink cycle these three
lines represent the fundamentals of any
fast led sketch
code that changes the values in the leds
array a fast led dot show call
and some timing code at its ordinary
speed the arduino operates much
too fast for humans to perceive so we
need a way to change our lights more
slowly
note that delay is not the way you
should do this in non-demo code
we'll explain a better way in the next
class the only confusing thing here
is fastly d.show use this call whenever
you want the strip to update
it'll cause fast led to write the
contents of the led array
out to the actual lights often you'll
use just
one fast led show call at the end of
your animation loop
after you've made all the color changes
you want to make this is important
because fastled.show can be an expensive
call
in terms of time if you can call it just
once per timing cycle
you'll improve the efficiency of your
code in the case of this demo however
we have two show calls inside the loop
one for the red color change
and one for the black
and this also happens to answer our
question from earlier
only one led is blinking because we're
only changing leds
zero which is the first led in our array
note that arrays always count from zero
and stop at
one minus num leds in this case zero
through nine
it might seem intuitive to copy and
paste
in order to get all of the leds to show
but this takes a long time
maybe there's a better way to do this
when you have this many pixels
it's not really practical to copy and
paste thus we're going to use a control
structure called a for loop to do the
work for us
change your code to look like so first
we're going to write
4 opening parentheses
int which stands for integer and number
i which is a variable and we're going to
start at zero
while i is less than
num leds which we already set earlier to
then we want to increase it i plus plus
now what we want to do is instead of
changing
0 to red we want to change any led
that is i to red then we're still going
to do fast led show
and then a delay now we want to do the
same thing
for turning the leds off
you can type this out again or you can
copy and paste
again we're going to have this for loop
and then instead of changing it to red
we want to turn them off
which remember is black
let's give this a try
now let's try an experiment what if in
our for loop instead of having
i as less than num leds we had
i less than num leds divided by
let's try this for both of our for loops
what do you think will happen can you
guess
we'll see the first half of our leds
light up
let's make another change to our sketch
what if instead of dividing the number
of leds by 2
for our up to in our array what if we
changed int
i to equal the number of leds divided by
2.
let's try doing this in both of our for
loops
can you guess what will happen now we
see the other half of our leds light up
by this point you may have worked out
how for loops work
you give them a starting point and
ending point and instructions to execute
at each step of the loop
in most cases i plus plus which is a
shorthand way of writing the most common
iterator
i equals i plus one aka do this for
every entry in the array let's go back
to our basic for loop
what if instead of having i plus plus
since this means
i equals i plus 1 we had i
equals i plus 2. let's try making this
change for both of our for loops
can you guess what will happen
now we see every other pixel blank i bet
you get the picture
you'll use for loops later on to develop
more complex lighting patterns
to read more about for loops see the
reference here
one important thing to remember when
experimenting with for loops is that
trying to write to an array element
which is beyond the end of your array
as defined in num leds may cause crashes
freezes and other undesirable effects
likewise reading beyond the end of an
array will return unexpected values
because you're actually reading them
from whatever happens to be stored right
after your array
these off by one errors are an extremely
common cause of bugs
even for seasoned programmers so always
check your code to ensure that you don't
access any pixels beyond the end of your
num
leds array when you're finished save the
file
we'll call it basic led playground you
can use it as an example later on
now let's go further with fast led
sketches there are lots of ways to
animate your leds instead of just
turning them to one color
a good place to start is with the fastly
sketches in arduino
to access them go to file examples and
down to fast led
there you'll see lots of sketches that
you can play with but let's start with
cylon
here we see a very similar setup to what
we had before
to use cylon or any fast led sketch with
our onboard leds for the circuit
playground we want to change the number
of leds to 10
and the data pin to 8. we can ignore
clock pin
then we see we're creating an array a
crgb array of leds
we've added our leds and we've set the
brightness to 84
you can change this to any value up to
255.
then we see a function called fade all
and a for loop
in this for loop we see we're starting
at zero
we're going up to the number of leds and
then we're iterating
and then as we're doing so we're scaling
something
let's have a look and see if we can
figure out what that is once we animate
it
then we see a loop that stores a hue
value we have a serial print line
statement of x and then
for int i equals 0 and i is less than
the number of leds we're going to
iterate through
the leds and we're going to turn the led
to a chsv value that is hue plus plus
so we're iterating through hues then
we're showing
the strip and then we're fading all
and then we see that this goes in the
other direction so what do you think
will happen when we upload the sketch
can you guess what the animation might
be let's give it a try
we see our leds fade through a rainbow
pattern
this is happening because we're
iterating through hues and then fading
fast led is a very involved library to
learn more
you can go to the facility github page
which has an excellent reference
but we won't be covering everything in
this class
if you want to know more about leds
kathy and i have a separate class on
fast led at hackaday u
see the hackadayu website to sign up
anukoprect is a dutch fashion designer
who creates robotic dresses
many of them use sensor systems as input
in either servos
leds smoke or other outputs
the pangolin dress is a 1024
channel vci brain computer interface
dress that visualizes brain activity
by changing 32 different 3d printed
panels
or scales with 32 implanted leds
in this way the movement and light of
the dress visualizes brain activity
benaz farahi is a designer and creative
technologist
working at the intersection of fashion
architecture and interactivity design
she's trained as an architect and
explores the potential of interactive
environments
in their relationship to the body body
escape
is an interactive 3d printed fashion
item that's inspired by the movement of
the human body
as the wearer moves a gyroscope
communicates the gestures to an led
lighting control system
and the lighting is visualized as a part
of the movement
benaz uses 3d printing to create
delicate diffusers
for the led lighting that can contour to
the body
this research is based on langer lines
which are the topological lines of skin
tension
bodyscape is an investigation of our
relationship
between anatomy and materiality
based in tokyo team lab is one of the
most impressive interactive arts
collectives on the planet
they create enormous large-scale
exhibitions
in museums as well as pop-up exhibitions
this installation features tens of
thousands of led strips
that hang from a ceiling in an enormous
mirrored room
as the viewer walks throughout the space
it's as if they're within a crystalline
forest
and different lighting animations
activate the space
creating mystical environments
here's another team lab piece where
inflatable sculptures
contain tilt sensors so that when
they're touched and tilted
the led lighting responds this creates a
reactive
environment using sculpture
yaya kusuma is an artist from japan
one of her most famous projects is the
infiniti mirror room
in which visitors are invited into a
small
closet sized space that's lined in
mirrors
strands of leds hang down from the
ceiling
and when replicated throughout the
mirror create this infinity effect
the effect is to create a large
installation in a small space
a sensor is an electronic device that
detects and responds to some type of
input from a physical environment
there are lots of different types of
sensors that can measure and respond to
all kinds of input
and this in turn can be used in many
ways for example we might use proximity
or
ultrasonic sensors to detect the
distance of obstructions for visually
impaired persons
or we might use environmental sensors
which can determine air or water quality
to make suggestions for city planning
we can also use sensors in our artworks
installations and wearables
to explore and visualize sensor data
making interactive works
last class we explored using capacitive
touch as a touch sensor
and in the following section of this
class we'll have a look at three
on-board sensors of the circuit
playground express
sound light and temperature we'll also
explore how we might trigger lighting
and sound output
using these sensors let's get started
the circuit playground comes with a thin
mems microphone that can be used to
detect audio levels
you can read the analog voltage on pin
a4
but in most cases we're actually going
to want to detect the sound
pressure level which is a pressure level
that's taken over time
this will range from 50 decibels to 100
decibels
in terms of if it's loud or if it's
quiet
open the sketch to hello sound sensor
you can find this both in your course
materials and in the examples
but an annotated version is in the
course files in this sketch
we see a new kind of variable which is
called a float
a float is a variable that has a decimal
this allows us to store more specific
data than if we are using an integer
which does not have a decimal this will
make more sense once we see the value
here we see that we're we're using our
float sound value
to store some data the data we're
storing
is coming from the circuit playground's
mic and it's for the function
sound pressure level we then see a
number that's in
parentheses this is because in order to
calculate the sound pressure level
the circuit playground has to take a
specific piece of data
and then calculate the result the kind
of data that it's taking
is a recording over a period of time so
this is a recording of 10 milliseconds
so it will use these 10 milliseconds in
order to calculate the sound pressure
level
we can change this if desired but for
now let's leave it at 10. then we're
seeing a serial print statement
that's printing out the sound sensor
sound pressure level
and then also printing the exact value
then we see a short delay of 90
milliseconds
let's upload this and then try making
some sounds
if we open serial monitor under tools
we'll see the sound pressure level
as i'm speaking you can see that the
sound level increases
the baseline looks like it's about 58.89
this might be a little different for you
depending on what kind of environment
you're in
when i'm speaking it goes up to about
62.41
to see this increase more clearly we can
look at the serial plotter
this is next to serial monitor under
tools
if you open this up and then try
speaking
you'll see that the value increases when
i'm speaking
clapping yelling and talking
and making other sounds to see how the
sound pressure level changes
to learn more about the sound sensor and
how it works see the adafruit website's
reference for sound sensor
to add interactivity let's use the
if-else statement we used in the last
session
open up if-else.ino in the sketch we
still have a float for our sound value
but we also have a float for a threshold
value
this is the value at which we are
triggering our interactivity
meaning we've decided it's the right
volume level to trigger our lighting
or our text or whatever our output is
i've set it to 65 but this will change
depending on what your specific sound
environment is
next i'm storing the sound value and
taking a reading of 10 milliseconds
on line 18 i have an if else statement
this is what will be responsible for
triggering our interactivity
the first part of the if statement says
if the sound value
is greater than our threshold meaning if
it's above
65 decibels then we want to do something
in this case we're saying serial print
line sound detected
serial print statements can be really
useful for holding interactivity
later we can change this code to
actually trigger our output
be that led lighting sound etc
then we have an else statement so this
means
that if the sound value is not above the
threshold
then it will print silence as golden
so one of two things will be happening
all the time
if we didn't want anything else to
happen we could also comment out this
line
and then it would only print sound
detected when a sound was detected
let's try this out
if we open up serial monitor we can see
the statement
silence is golden then when i speak over
the mic
and make a loud sound it says sound is
detected
you'll notice that sometimes it'll
detect the sound continuously
and sometimes it'll have silence as
golden between the print statements
this might mean that our threshold is
too high or too low
to make sure that our threshold is at
the correct value
we can uncomment the lines 15 and 16
to print out the sound value that way we
can make sure that our threshold is set
correctly
let's try uploading this and seeing if
we can adjust the threshold
now when i go to serial monitor i can
see what the value is when i'm speaking
it looks like when i'm speaking the
value is about
62 or so so if i adjust my threshold
to be 62
and then re-upload my code now i should
get a more faithful result
i could also lower the threshold so that
it's more sensitive
i think you get the idea now it's time
for two challenges
first see if you can adjust the
threshold to trigger sound detected only
when you're speaking
if you have trouble doing this see the
last video
for a second challenge can you change
the code
so that instead of saying sound detected
it lights up the leds as a hint try
copying and pasting the for loop from
two for loop
or using two hello neil pixel
for advanced students try triggering a
fast led animation
to solve this challenge i'm going to
look and see
what i need to replace from the led for
loop sketch
within my if-else sketch
so right now i see that when the sound
value is over a threshold
it prints sound detected this is a
placeholder for my interactivity
so i know that this is where i want to
put in the for loop that'll turn on my
leds
i can even write pseudocode to remind
myself
that this is where i should put it then
i can either decide to just leave them
on but maybe i want to turn them off
when i'm not speaking
in that case i want to use the else
statement so instead of printing
silences golden i want to turn off the
leds
now that i have my pseudo code i can
find the code that will actually make
this happen
in my for loop code here we find the for
loop for turning on
our leds by setting the pixel color to
purple
i'm going to want to copy and paste the
entire thing
and put it where it says turn on leds
now i want to find the code to turn off
the leds
and i know that it's circuit
playground.clearpixels
i'm going to copy that line and i'm
going to put it in where it says turn
off
leds let's upload this and give it a try
now i see that if i'm speaking the leds
light up
otherwise they're off
the circuit playground express has an
on-board light sensor that's connected
to analog pin
5. you can use analog read or you can
use the light sensor function
from the library in order to read the
value
the value will be between 0 and 123
with higher values corresponding to
brighter light levels
the range is approximately 0 lux to 1500
lux maximum
because average daylight is 10 000 lux
or so
this sensor is best suited for indoor
lighting
an average indoor light level will be
about 300
we'll use the following sketch in order
to tell what the average light level is
for your environment
as well as what is dark or bright for
your environment
open the sketch hello light sensor from
either your course files or from the
adafruit circuit playground library
upload the sketch and try putting your
hand over the circuit playground
then taking it away to see changes in
the data in serial monitor
so in this sketch we're storing the
light sensor value
as a integer into value
and then we're updating that in the loop
by calling circuitplayground.lightsensor
we're then printing out the light sensor
and the value
and then we have a delay of one second
so it's taking readings pretty slow we
could update this if we want to take the
readings
faster let's have a look at serial
monitor and see
what the default reading is for this
room
so you can see that the reading is
pretty stable it's either
197 to 199
so it's a today is an overcast day which
is typical in copenhagen
not a lot of light in the room pretty
dim if your room is brighter
you probably have a light reading of
about 300 or so
and if it's very bright it's probably
above that
if it's lower than that i'm guessing
that it's night time where you are at or
it's very dim lighting now when i put my
hand over the sensor
you can see that it drops down to about
40.
this is with my hand completely covering
the sensor
if i put my hand on the circuit
playground it drops down even further
and now i'm just getting a single digit
reading
if i hold my hand over the sensor
i get a reading of about 100 or so
so you can see how you might start to
play with these values
as thresholds in order to trigger
different kinds of interactivity
depending on how
light or dark something is you can also
in this way
use a light sensor as a proximity sensor
because if light isn't shining on the
sensor then you know that something is
blocking it
so in this way it can kind of be used to
detect motion or an obstruction
there are other sensors that do this
more efficiently but
unfortunately the circuit playground
doesn't have any other proximity sensors
on board
so the light sensor is a good candidate
if you're trying to see if something is
in the way of the sensor
from your course files open the sketch
to light sensor
if else
in this sketch we have three different
variables
we have a light value and this is the
variable
that will store our light sensor value
then we have a variable for average
light
and a variable for bright light so these
are two different threshold values
so we've decided that average light is
anything
between 150 to 550
and then bright light is 550 or above
anything that's under average light
would be low lighting
so let's take a look at how this might
work if we wanted to have three
different thresholds
first we still want to update the
variable for light value
every loop and that is taking the
reading from the light sensor and
storing it as
light value then we're going to print
the value
and then we have an if else if else
statement
so we've seen if and else before
but now we're seeing else if which is a
third condition and this is a program
so it's going to be computing this in
order
so it's first going to check the if
statement then it's going to check the
else if statement and then it's
going to check the else statement so
first it checks
is the light value which again is our
reading from the sensor
is that greater than or equal to the
value for bright light
which again is 550
if it is then we're going to have it
print bright light
and then we're also going to have a for
loop where we set the pixel color
to red
and that's for each led
then we want to check if it's medium
light so we have this else if statement
that says
else if the light value is less than
bright light
and the light value is above average
light
so this is checking to make sure both of
these conditions are true
and this is how this double ampersand is
how you do an
and you can't use a plus because a plus
is a mathematical
operation so if you used a plus it would
try to add these two
together so we have to use this
combination of two ampersands to make an
and
statement but it's basically saying
if this is true and if this is true
so if both those things are true then we
want to print medium light
and then we want to set all the pixels
to green
lastly we want to see if it's low light
and we don't have to check that because
we know if these two things aren't true
then it's going to be low light because
it's the only option that's remaining
so if it's low light it'll print low
light and then it'll set
all the pixels to blue and then we have
a delay
of half of a second and that's between
every check
of this whole loop so let's try it out
and try to put our hand over the sensor
at varying distances and see if we can
get those three thresholds to work
you might have to adjust these numbers
so that they're more accurate to your
lighting environment
but the goal should be that when your
hand is not on the sensor
and there's bright light then it should
have its own
threshold and there should also be a
threshold for average light so if your
hand is hovering above the sensor
it should be whatever this value is and
then low light would be if you have your
hand covering the sensor completely
so let's give it a try
the circuit playground also comes with a
temperature sensor
it is a thermistor which is
a resistor that changes its resistance
based on the temperature
it's easy to calculate the temperature
based on the analog voltage on analog
pin
a0 there's a 10k one percent resistor
connected to it as a pull down
and you can read the analog value and
calculate the temperature
with the beta constant or just use the
circuit playground library
the circuit playground library has a
built-in circuitplayground.temperature
function which will give you a floating
point number in centigrade
also if you need to use fahrenheit they
have a built-in function for that as
well
which is circuit playground.temperature
f
we'll have a look at both of these
open up the sketch hello temperature
in this sketch we have float variables
for both the temperature and celsius
and the temperature in fahrenheit temp c
and temp f
accordingly in our loop function we're
updating the values for each variable
then we're printing out the data there's
a one second delay between readings
we upload the sketch and then open
serial monitor
we can see the temperature readings for
both celsius and fahrenheit
up until now we've been using sensors
that are pretty easy to adjust
like light and sound but how do you
change the temperature
try to get your temperature sensor to
display a different value
here a few potential solutions to this
challenge but there are probably many
more
one is to use fans or heaters to heat or
cool
the sensor another solution would be to
take your circuit playground express
outside
and get a temperature reading from there
you could also bring your circuit
playground into different rooms in your
house
you might also put your circuit
playground between your hands
lastly you can try breathing on the
sensor
give this a try and see if it will
detect a difference
in this way you could use the sensor as
a breath sensor
have a look at the birthday candles
example under microphone demos
in the circuit playground library to see
how this might be used
the circuit playground express has eight
general input output pads that are
available
for us to attach our own sensors and our
own
outputs such as servos which we'll get
to in the next class
inputs and outputs are at the heart of
interactive design
with interactive design we take in some
data
or stimulus usually from a sensor
or a button or a switch
then we output a response this could be
lighting
sound or smoke as seen here in a new
quiprex smoke dress
so far we've used a few inputs to
trigger a few outputs
can you think of all the inputs we've
used so far we've used the capacitive
touch
the microphone as a sound sensor the
temperature sensor
and the light sensor for outputs we've
been able to trigger print statements
led lighting and sound from the onboard
speaker
but this is just a handful of options
can you think what other
inputs and outputs there are which
inputs might you want to use in your
project
what about outputs in the next class
we'll look at developing more complex
interactivity using an interactivity
matrix
but for now feel free to explore places
like adafruit and sparkfun
to see what sensors there are and what
you might want to use in your projects
you can also consider different outputs
you might trigger and look for tutorials
that cover how to use them
so far we've looked at a few kinds of
loops
there's the setup loop and loop function
for our main arduino sketch
there's also a for loop there's also a
while loop
open up two while loop
this sketch looks very familiar to our
if else sketch
we're still storing the value of our
light sensor
in an integer into value we also have a
threshold value
over which we will trigger our
interactivity
then we see that in our loop we're
updating our value variable
to store the reading of the light sensor
this is followed by a delay of a tenth
of a second
then we have a while loop while
our value meaning the value from our
light sensor
is greater than our threshold in this
case 100
we want to print the line trigger
interactivity
then have a short delay of 200
milliseconds
while this is true this will continue to
run
when it is not true it will exit the
loop
and then go back to a delay of a tenth
of a second
then it will check once again the value
of light sensor and update it
let's give this a try so i'm going to
start with my hand
over the sensor because i know that when
it's light it will trigger the
interactivity
so right now my hand is on the sensor
but if i take it off
i'll see that it triggers the
interactivity
if i put it on again it will stop if i
take it off again it'll start
again as a challenge try changing the
threshold
to trigger the interactivity only when
it's a certain temperature
as a second challenge try replacing the
serial print line statement with code
that will turn on leds
or play a sound to solve this challenge
i'm going to open up both my while loop
sketch and also my hello temperature
sketch
because i'm going to want to combine
elements of each of them
and before i get started i've decided
that what i want to do
is i want to trigger my while loop
while the temperature sensor is at or
above my body temperature
and so i'm going to first figure out
what that is
by running the hello temperature sketch
and then
looking at what the read is for
temperature in fahrenheit when i blow on
the sensor versus when i don't blow on
the sensor
once it's uploaded if i open up serial
monitor
i can see the reading
now when i blow in my temperature sensor
i see that the temperature goes up to
about 80.64
so there it was 80.82
and that time it went up to 83 almost
so it looks like what i'm going to want
as a baseline
is any value that's less than 80
and then if it's over 80 i'll consider
that to be triggered
another way to look at this would be to
use the serial plotter
and the serial plotter i see the data
coming in this is without
me doing anything
and then we see a spike when i blow on
the sensor
and you'll see that there's two graphs
there's one
for temperature and fahrenheit and one
for temperature in celsius
so if i wanted to see just one of these
values say for example
fahrenheit i could upload this again
and now when i go to serial monitor
i just see the temperature for
fahrenheit
and then when i go to serial plotter
i just see the value for fahrenheit and
i can see that
a normal baseline is somewhere below
81.
and that when i breathe on the sensor it
goes above 81.
so i might if i want to make the
instrument really
sensitive and and if i want to reduce
the incidence of false positives meaning
results
that say that the sensor has been
triggered or is above the threshold when
it isn't
i might want to set my threshold to
something like
81. i'll do this test a couple more
times just to make sure that that's
accurate
and sensors are very obviously sensitive
to the environment that they're in
so the value may change a little bit
depending on where you're at
so that's something to keep in mind you
might have to reset
your threshold now that i know that my
threshold for my temperature is about 80
i can save this sketch as while loop
challenge before making changes to it
and then i can change my threshold and
we'll say
and instead of having int value
as my variable i need to store float
because the temperature data is stored
as a float
so i'm going to store it in fahrenheit
and steal this float
temp f and copy float temp f in place of
where our
value was previously now i need to make
sure that that
is changed throughout my sketch so to
start with i'm also not getting data
from
my light sensor i want to update the
variable for temp
f with the temperature so i'm going to
go
and take the line that says temp f
equals circuit playground
dot temperature f and i'll take that
and place that where value was
so now i'm updating the temperature
variable every time
and then i'm not comparing a value
anymore and comparing
a temperature rating and then
i also want to update it
while we're in the while loop so i'm
going to replace this line
as well and this is important because
the while loop
won't exit until it has a condition for
exiting
so the condition here is if the
temperature
is not greater than the threshold then
it exits the loop
but how will it know that unless it
takes the reading so you have to take
the reading within the while loop
as well as outside of the while loop
that's why it's written twice
and then here we have a serial print
line statement to trigger interactivity
and let's just test this before we put
in lighting or sound
i can see that it's saying to trigger
the interactivity
constantly so i know that
maybe my threshold is too low
so let's try setting this to 82.
and there i see that it isn't triggered
but when i blow on the sensor
you'll see that it prints trigger
interactivity with a small delay
to solve the other part of this
challenge which is to replace serial
print line
with either lighting or sound i can
either put in a for loop for lights
or i can play a tone so if i can't
remember how to do that
i can open up my
class files and i can open up my led for
loop
i can also open up hello speaker
and to play a tone what i'd want to do
is copy
the line circuitplayground.playtone
and i want to paste that where
interactivity is
and i'm going to make this a fairly low
tone that plays for
two seconds and then i also
want to put in
a for loop for changing my lighting
so i'm going to copy that from our led
for loop sketch
and i'm gonna i'm thinking of the
sequence here so
first it will print trigger
interactivity
then i want it to set all the pixels to
this color
and then i want to play the tone for two
seconds
the order does matter here because this
is a compiled language
and so whatever is written first
will get executed first so if i put
serial print line trigger interactivity
at the bottom here
that will be the last thing that gets
executed and it will happen
after playtone feel free to copy and
paste these and put them in different
locations
to see that happening but for now let's
upload this and see if it works for
homework and as a final challenge
try making changes to your while or if
else sketch
to create your own interactive events
for the light or sound sensor
you might also use the temperature
sensor or capacitive touch
then start to plan how you might install
your circuit playground
would you put it in a wearable or a
sculpture
how might that affect your data
grab materials and start rapid
prototyping
materials could be things like fabric
paper hollow toys
clothing and so on try installing the
circuit playground
using these materials and see how it
affects the data
see if you can write a program that uses
your input
and produces an output the output could
be lighting
sound or pseudocode for some other form
of interactivity
if you're out of ideas try creating a
lamp that does different animations at
different times of the day
we've covered a lot in this second class
we've learned all about leds and how to
create responsive lighting
we've even learned how to create
animations using the fast led library
we've also learned about inputs and
outputs as well as how to use three new
inputs
the temperature sensor the light sensor
and the microphone as a sound sensor
we've expanded upon our growing
knowledge of c plus plus by using if
else if
while loops and float variables we now
have all the tools we need to create a
simple input and output program
which takes in data from a sensor and
triggers lighting sound or print
statements
in the next class we'll go even further
with inputs and outputs
by looking into using buttons and
switches for control
and servos to make projects with moving
parts we'll also look at multiple inputs
and outputs
using more complicated logic and
programming see you next time
you