[Music]
all right hello everyone
welcome to our last class we're um
going to talk today about a lot of the
things we've done previously
and then add to that by talking about
how to export files from rhino
to useful applications
and most of what i use it for is
creating rhino files for fabrication for
illustration
for rendering and then less so for
virtual reality and gaming but you could
do that if you want so
the first thing about exporting is to
know some file types
rhino files are.3dm and
grasshopperfiles.gh which we've used
already
i guess we could divide files into ones
associated with software that are
private and ones that are kind of a bit
more open
generally compatibility with lots of
softwares
is like
dxf which is more of the open file
created by autocad
is going to be a lot more compatible
with smaller softwares and
able to get files around easier than
some of the more private
files then some of the
file types are sort of updates or
upgrades that
increase the capability of certain types
of files so a dot step file dot
stp is a sort of successor of a
igis file iges and
um some of these have some interesting
histories i just files
go back to the us military and um
object files are like stl files but they
allow
materials and textures and things like
that so
dot stl files is the main 3d printing
file that
does not allow textures and color
and then with success or the successors
that dot amf
which is the additive manufacturing file
but generally with file types
if i'm going between different softwares
i just like to trial an error
see if it works sometimes the geometry
doesn't go through on a certain file
type and then just try a different file
type and it probably will work
um in the pep cure example that i'll
show you guys later
that i went through on a few file types
and it didn't work and then dot stl
works
so sometimes it's just whatever
works so when we're looking at
file types they're going to transfer
different types of information and not
transfer others
so the questions are can it store
nurbs curves can it store nerve surfaces
can it serve poly surfaces can it store
meshes subdivisions does it have
textures materials lights animation
rigging
object properties groups layers low file
size so for rhino files
that animation and rigging is not really
a rhino thing that's more of a
sort of maya or 3d max thing so
that won't save from the other soft
person come into rhino
if we look at illustrator at least the
way i use illustrator
that it's mainly just for putting curves
across
that you don't really bring full 3d
models into illustrator
and luckily groups and layers stay
intact when moving
to a aai file and if they didn't that
would be
really problematic because i'll show you
on some examples later
so to start back to this building casa
de musica
in porto and portugal and i created a 3d
model
of that building and
i want to just mention that if we look
at this
3d model in any of the 2d views
it's still 3d geometry that if i click
on any of those points
uh to snap to them they're very much
three-dimensional
they are not on the same plane but
sometimes i want to export
a two-dimensional drawing um
so i'm make 2d is is a very very useful
uh command and when looking at any view
it will project what i see to a
two-dimensional curved
drawing sometimes these curves are
grouped in strange ways
so they sometimes need some editing but
make 2d is how i go from a 3d model
to to say give me the two-dimensional
projection of that
and it always sort of ends up at the
origin point
zero zero zero so that there's my two
dimensional
uh front view that's a that's sort of
the 3d model
and then if i make 2d now i have
a two-dimensional projection of that
that's curves and i can
save that as a a file and export that to
illustrator
or somewhere else and then in
illustrator i can do stroke widths a lot
better
and start um coloring it in and
i like uh illustrator models with zero
stroke with
with the uh the colors filled in so
that's just
me with a fill command just filling
each color manually that's not a render
and there's a three-dimensional model
so make 2d is great for diagrams here's
an
example of gary ingalls and they want to
propose
a big space that goes on the roof so
each one of these would have been drawn
in rhino possibly on different layers
and then that's the the proposal to
take over the rooftops of this famous um
shopping
store and then here's another example
that i did for a t-shirt
where um you can do any font in rhino
drag in custom fonts so this is a rubik
from google fonts collection
and if you explode a font it turns to
curves so that now they're they're just
nurbs curves
and then i just extruded those curves
drew some roads between and
messed around with the camera settings
that i'm going to talk about later
to to sort of create this
perspective view with a wide angle lens
and then that was brought into
illustrator
[Music]
did some fill on the top and then
that was ready to go for a t-shirt which
was my local running club when i lived
in new york city
so another um fantastic software is
pedicura it's a
less than forty dollars to buy and it's
you can drag any 3d model from rhino
and i used a stl file which wouldn't
transfer over textures but it just
unfolds the geometry and gives you
a very precise um
[Music]
thing to cut with flaps so that you can
cut it out
and assemble it as a sort of paper model
these lines if you bring them into laser
cutting is are really really accurate
and you can make very very precise
models
by taking your 3d geometry into pepakura
then bringing it to a laser cutter
afterwards so this is textures on top to
create this dice it's one of their
pre-loaded files
so i did the um the casa de musica model
did the unfold that's what it would look
like in papakura
did the unfold and this is the geometry
uh here and
that would be great for laser cutting
and i'm just going to get out of
this uh pdf and to show you in pepura
so this is their animation showing how
this 3d would unfold you can see it kind
of
unfolding
and i've seen some people use um
very very detailed grasshopper models
with the most intricate parts
bring it into pepakura and then laser
cut them and have these
really really precise models that
would be impossible just to figure out
the unfolding patterns otherwise
and you can kind of drag and drop if you
want a different uh
unfolding pattern it just sort of moves
across
the page so winter craft is a company
that makes um
different animals as masks you can
download them for a couple dollars each
but if you wanted to make your own you
would make the 3d model and then use
peptura to make the unfolding pattern
of these kind of masks
so this is a standing desk i designed
and this is a
make 2d on the side view and the sort of
perspective view
and there's make 2d colored in from
illustrator
and i kind of went back and forth
using a nesting software to make
the most efficient standing desk i could
possibly think of so i wanted
two of these to a eight foot by four
foot sheet
and this is an example of what
rhino nest which is a quite pricey
plug-in
for rhino it's about a thousand dollars
but
there are openness that i haven't tried
but i might try soon
as a free alternative and you can kind
of see that
you select any curves that you have
drawn that can be anywhere in the model
and you first set your stock
size so i'd set it to a eight foot by
four foot or two four four zero by one
two two zero millimeters
and then in millimeters uh in
millimeters
um distance item to item so it's it's
going to do that
distance item to sheet that's the border
on the edge in case i've got some
screws or some holes down to hold that
material down that i don't want the
router bit to go anywhere near the
screw because that would damage the
router
freedom do i want the curves that are
going to be
put into this nest to stay their
orientation
or they can rotate 180 degrees or they
can be free
and rotate any direction
and some of these nesting cartons to
minimize
x because you might use the rest of the
sheet
and you can kind of do different um
settings on nesting so this is uh
the desk this is the shorter desk which
is three desks to the sheet
and um you probably know the the famous
story of the
uh chess player kasparov who
lost to big blue the the computer by ibm
and a couple years later that they did
the experiment again but
allowed the computer to play against
the computer and human beings i think
they call that a centaur and the
centaurs one so the
the the humans do what they do best the
computers do what they
do best and as a team they beat
computers pretty easily
so with nesting there's sort of
sometimes a mix
of human and automated process
for this i kind of changed the design to
sort of maximize the desk size
based on filling the void of this sheet
so i get three
desks to the sheet and then this is the
bigger desk with the top piece
two desks to the sheet
and then for cnc files or
laser cut files that a lot of the time
you're just dealing at least from a
rhino perspective as flat
2d curves so this is a bear shape
and i have them as different colors
so that when i export them they will the
different colors represent different
layers
and when i export them they'll be on
different layers and
i just for the cnc file i want to say
that this
inner blue line i'm going to pocket cut
on the inside which means i'm going to
cut
all the material in the middle and you
set a height for that on the machining
so i set two thirds of the
the stop the 18 millimeters and then
um next up cut uh
on the outside of this red line and cut
again
one third into the material and then
afterwards cut on the oh sorry cut
pocket cut this green area and then
column outside of the red line
which is a profile cut which is going to
cut out the shape and you always kind of
leave to cut the material loose from the
bigger sheet as the last step so that
the material doesn't move around
and then this was the other side of my
little bear shape
which cut on the outside of the profile
cut and pocket cut
this whole interior two thirds on the
material and this is
uh what i've made this was a sort of
um i wanted a place to put my cufflinks
into this as my wedding favors since my
wedding
reception was in a zoo and there's sort
of a zoomed in
uh thing of this bottom part and the top
part just
snapped friction fitted on to have this
little
cute storage space inside and i made
lots of different animals mainly because
my wife asked me to do small animals
first
made a hundred of them and then she's
like no no i prefer big animals so then
i made
another chance we'll get tons left over
and this is where nesting comes into
really useful so
they're all on different layers which if
i had to manage
manually select those curves in a cam
software which
in my opinion is not the most user
friendly it would take forever and i
probably made
a thousand errors where as long as
they're on different layers
i'm saying pocket cut the purple layer
do the profile cut two thirds the way
down the sheet on
the red layer and so on um and then
these shapes are obviously rotated
because i allowed them to be free rather
than fixed on the nesting settings
and i set a a rather wide distance
item to item and a distance on the edge
so that
i've uh hold down screws on the edge
and there is an example of the crack is
left behind
and if you guys see the camera here's
real bear
so for laser cutting a lot of the time
you're looking for the same thing you're
looking for two-dimensional
geometry and most laser cutters are not
the most sophisticated interface and
you're just going to set the
the speed of the laser and the power of
the laser
and if you set a um
a high speed and a low power you're
going to just etch
the material and if you set a high power
and a low speed you'll cut all the way
through
and you kind of learn off different
power and speed settings for different
materials
and that's how you can operate a laser
cutter so you really just need
two dimensional curves and you're either
cutting uh
the raster inside of the curve kind of
like a pocket cut on cnc
or you're cutting along the profile
um and this is a really cool project
where it's called there's no place like
home because these
shoes they don't have a screen but they
have gps built in
and on one shoe they've got four led
lights
in a line and on the other shoe they've
got like eight led lights in a circle
and you tell the shoes beforehand where
your home is
and you click your heels together and it
says one mile two mile three miles and
four miles and in that direction
and sort of guides you home with this
really
low tech interface but i just love the
laser cutting on the bottom
of these little drawings and they've
just drawn
i think the laser there you go and
here's an example of a laser cutter
and um just need these as curves
and then set the cut speed
and the or the speed and the power
to cut through this material and i'm
going to get lazy better
also important with laser cutters or any
of these machines is what the maximum
dimensions are
because you're obviously going to need
to to make your files to fit within
the machine's size
for 3d printing there's lots of types of
3d printing
these are machines by formlamps which
was
came out at mit's media lab and they
used a process called
inverted stereo lithography and better
known as sla
and when they did this project on
kickstarter they did i can't remember
exactly what it was but it was a couple
million
that the process was still underpatent
and they had to wait two
years at least before they could ship to
backers waiting for the patent to expire
but now they've done the second machine
and third machine
and are doing really really well stereo
photography is a very
precise type of 3d printing generally
considered
very expensive um historically these
machines by formlabs make it still not
cheap but a lot more affordable than it
used to be
and this is a project that makes
extensive use of grasshopper
by arthur manning manny who was my
teacher of grasshopper
a decade ago when i first learned the
software and this is a 3d print
done on a formlabs printer i think um
and you can see how thin some of the
profiles are
and hopefully you kind of don't know all
the grasshopper commands to
to make this but you can kind of see the
grasshopper grasshopper like
logic to how it's created and with any
3d printing process you're looking at
what is the maximum dimensions of
the print area what is the layer
thickness
and the more layers you have in 3d
printing
the better resolution that 3d print is
going to be
but the longer it's going to take to 3d
print because the machine is
going to make a two-dimensional print of
every single layer
and if you want quarter the thickness to
be more accurate that's four times the
print time
and um that's the decision one needs to
make
minimum wall thickness is really
important when you're 3d modeling
fast 3d printed that's the thinnest
size that a solid object can be
for this particular method and the
thinnest
it can be changes depending on the
method
and they're doing it with uh
somebody who's 3d printing the things
for you they might be a little bit more
conservative and want
slightly thicker uh wall thicknesses so
the models definitely don't break
if you're on your own machines you can
do a little bit more trial and error and
see how thin you can get and
and learn um how to be kind of more of a
craftsman of a 3d printer
this is um an image from a makerbot and
you can see just
layer thickness is thicker on the right
here
and they've done these cats thinner and
thinner and thinner
so this cat would take probably four
times the amount of time to print as
this dab
different processes have a different
profile on the layers
so makerbots are fdm
deposition modeling where the first
printer i showed you is
an sla printer you can see the layers
have this different profile which this
gives a much smoother edge
another type of 3d printing is the zed
court machines which are powder-based
and they work by this is sort of a
gypsum or plaster
and they one of these drums is empty and
one of it
is uh full and the printer will
basically transfer the powder
layer by layer from one to the other and
every time it prints a layer it will
also print
a glue or a binder and when you
do your 3d model it's going to slice it
up by the layer thickness kind of like
we did the contour command
and it's going to be 0.1 millimeter
layers or really thin layers
and then that's going to be a layer of
powder a layer of glue and go to the
next layer into the next layer
and then at the end you're going to dig
out the 3d model kind of like an
archaeologist
which is basically glue powder from
non-glue powder
and what you pay for is the amount of
powder you remove from the machine
and then as well as that the amount of
glue so it's for the
combo price these are some examples
of 3d models made with zed core uh
free prints they generally have a
thicker wall thickness
and are kind of more fragile
um if if if you kind of don't want too
much glue because if
if the more glue you put on these models
the stronger they will be but it kind of
gets a bit tacky looking so you kind of
want
a happy medium but if you don't put
enough on they kind of crumble
um so they are
shorter lifespan than a plastic model
which is just gonna
um not um they're gonna have many
problems
long term with that um the powder
this these are three prints by the way
um they don't really look it but
um this is powder 3d printed with ink
going in so every time it does a layer
of 3d print it's going to
have ink go in there as well this is
again a zed corp
machine now owned by shapeways
and sometimes people do experimentation
with 3d printing
and this is a cool project by bowling
green state university
where they um so that the zed court
machines
are um kind of like a your packard
business model where
the ink is expensive for the zed coat
machines the powder is expensive and
you're meant to buy the powder from them
and not use any other
third-party powder so bowling green
state wanted to just
try any kind of powder it wanted and did
ceramics
and glass and just started pushing
powders through and coming up with its
own
um binders and these were shrink tests
of 3d prints
from a ceramic material that they fired
in the kiln
and uh i think they got in trouble at
first and then
zed corp asked to collaborate and
sponsor them so i
you know that kind of sort of break the
rules and then get invited to the party
afterwards so
uh and they've sort of filing patents on
uh they also want to compress
every time it does a layer inside the
machine to then compress
each layer because that's better for um
if you want to do
a cup and then
same kind of idea powder plus binder
this is a stone which is crushed into a
powder and then on a
massive 3d printer built up layer by
later um
with a binder that sort of makes the
stem part
and then you dig it out the same way so
when it comes to 3d printing
um in rhino this is a 50 millimeter by
50 millimeter box
if i 3d printed a solid box that would
3d print fine but it would be a lot of
material
and in a z port machine that would just
be a solid box so every single layer is
going to be
a square an open box um
which is each side of surfaces i just
exploded this box and deleted the top
surface
that won't print at all because as i
said surfaces
have no thickness whatsoever they so
this is a thickness of
zero and it will just appear invisible
to a 3d printer
if i do an offset surface i give it a
thickness so i've given that a 1.5
millimeter
thickness using offset surface
and i i just did um rhinos
p-type volume and you'll get the volume
on shape this is 14
the volume of this cube which means it's
of the price and um that could be
25 versus 250 and it's gonna look the
same no matter what
so uh if you turn upside down and it
will look the same
so if we go back to this slide
here if this was an offset surface
with nothing underneath it would be 14
the price of
if i just made that solid
so a very important command with rhino
especially
um to check your precision is
show edges and then do the naked edges
and naked edges are just any surface
edge that is not part of a solid
so in this case all of these
these are exploded surfaces they're not
connected
and therefore all of these are naked
edges where all the edges on the other
two
cubes are part of a solid poly surface
and if i was to explode the box
and um redraw the top square where i
i'm deliberately off by one millimeter
that
uh if the surfaces are not joined so
these are all separate surfaces
and i do the show edges naked edges
analysis
that i'll get pink edges on all the
edges but if i join them i just get pink
edges on this
open part here and that's very important
because that box currently would not 3d
print because it is
an open poly surface and only closed
solid
poly surfaces will print so you kind of
depending on how you create geometry but
if there's any risk that there is any
imprecise parts you want to do this test
of show edges
naked edges before any 3d print
especially sometimes that if there are a
bunch of parts that are stacked on each
other
and let's say there's five parts the
middle part is
um got a problem and there's there's a
little hole in it
then they will just 3d print without
that
object in the model and you'll have
whatever where it was meant to be one
piece
you now have two separate parts because
the middle part was just invisible
this is super advanced but back to
adam holloway who i showed you that um
colorful minimal surface
um and arthur who did the burning man
temple project
and carl they created this plug-in for
grasshopper
that changed how you do 3d printing and
so it's
very difficult to understand plug-in but
it's normally
uh 3d printing is done in horizontal
layers
called slicing and um
a 3d printer needs to go through that
whole horizontal layer before it moves
up and does the next horizontal layer
in this model they've sort of gone
directly to the g-code
the the underlying code of 3d printing
and said that you can just move the 3d
printer turn the extruder on
and then move up vertically to create
this um kind of twirl piece
and then this side that to create that
geometry that
that's not going to work by horizontal
layers it's going to need to sort of
move up and down and up and down and up
and down to sort of create this weaving
effect
which is quite an interesting uh hack on
3d printing so setting materials which
i'm going to show you when we open
software
that materials are properties for
any object or a surface or polysurface
and there are a lot of preset materials
that are included so you can just select
plastic wood and there's a ton of ranges
of wood
or paint and then set to color and then
you can alter the settings for
transparency if you wanted it for glass
or glossiness which would be turned up
to max for metals
and change around the settings that way
separately there are textures which are
um image files that you scale and you
bring in to the material so this is wood
which has the texture
included in that we're not going to
cover much on
setting materials and rendering because
it's like a whole horse in itself
then lighting we can turn on i'll show
you lights when we open rhino
which then shadows will appear in your
render view which
normally there wouldn't be shadows and
you can set environment settings
set what location this model is in the
world what day it is what time it is and
the shadows will
uh sort of match that sort of timing
and then there's just multiple lines
with multiple shadows the lens length
in perspective view can be altered so
this is a 10 millimeter lens
which when i did that harlem round
t-shirt i
had a very small lens length which from
the top which created that sort of
geometry and if the lens length is
very large that you get this more
flat sort of 3d
you can also go to isometric which has
no perspective points
and change your view and then do make 2d
on any of these views
to capture that 2d geometry
and now i'm going to start drawing soon
with the final project so the final
project
which you guys can all create and get
your certificate when you submit
is to do either a furniture piece or
some object
maybe related to things you're
interested in that
has something from each week that we
learned so it has
something from nurbs curves something
from
maybe solid geometry something that's
subdivision based
something that's grasshopper based
and then maybe set a material and do a
make 2d
or have the files ready to see and see
so you've kind of done something from
each of the five weeks
and i'm going to show you an example of
something that meets that criteria
and it's going to be a sort of refresher
on
the trading geometry in each of the
different types
so as um one just type of geometry that
um was very popular in the 90s and i
still think it's really really cool is
um voronoi and that's where you just get
a bunch of points
and this is just a randomly organized
set of points and
if those points find their nearest
points and create curves between
all their nearest points and then you
will find the perpendicular bisectors of
the midpoints of all those curves
and then trim them all and
then delete the the purple lines
that we get this sort of uh shell
pattern
and uh let's turn off the lights so this
is a
voronoi uh pattern and it's controlled
by those
underlying points and i'm gonna do um
use a voronoi pattern which is just a a
ready-to-go
grasshopper component but when people
were doing this for the first time
in the 90s this was there wasn't a
grasshopper and this was coded from
scratch
so in this case this is um a voronoi
pattern
and then an offset from one of the or
every one of the cells
and then rebuilds the curve from a first
degree curve to a third degree curve
um creating this nerve's curve in the
middle and then a planar surface between
those two
and slightly creates these triangles of
various format patterns as well and then
sends that to a laser cutter and makes
this as a full
wall in the architecture school at
columbus ohio possible
and one of the tools i'm going to
sort of indicate of use in my design
is a bullnose
router bit so in controlling any router
bits from rhino i'm just going to have
profile curves and when you export it
you would
sort of assign this router bit
to go along that curve so i just really
need
the the mid curves this is an example of
using
a write a bit like that
[Music]
there and this is kind of what i'm going
to draw so
let's draw the same guys so we switch to
grasshopper and oh sorry switch to right
now
so the first thing i'm going to do is um
start with nerves curves and draw a
rectangle
um with let's say 250
[Music]
so i'm going to create the the legs
first using curves
and i'm going to snap to the midpoint my
snaps are on
and i want a circle exactly that length
and that will snap to that point and
i'll just drag that down
i'm going to use the trim command and
trim both sides and
that's right and then i'll just explode
this curve and delete this bottom line
and then i'm going to join that together
and
offset it let's say 15 mil each side
i'll just take any point on the side
um
and just move these two points up uh
let's say 50ml
and there will be a
seat here
so
let's say um
so i'm just drawing one of the two sides
[Music]
and
i'm going to use a mirror command to
bring them over the other side
[Music]
so now i'm just selecting this and
trimming
various curves
add some curds to the bottom
and i'm going to join that to make one
curve
i'm just going to join that one and then
type close curve which will fix the
other one
so there's kind of a stool
leg made out of nerve curves and
um i made a lot of cnc furniture i kind
of
know my way
i'm going to basically offset this
[Music]
i'm offsetting that nine millimeter each
side creating an 18 millimeter
[Music]
gap here and then
copy this to make a second one
again just trim more sides delete those
might point to the midpoint
and then i'm going to trim
top side on one and the bottom side of
the other and they will
they will lock together and see and see
so join all those so they're
peace i'm just gonna move
this morning to my origin point since i
like it
[Music]
and just so i need them for 3d is
extrude
curve and both sides needs to be off
and 18 millimeter which is this
thickness of plywood
and then if i just select the extrusions
which are close quality surfaces
[Music]
and
i can do rotate 3d
and then we'll take this one 90 degrees
and then i'm going to move them and snap
to place
so
if i was just to see and see these
curves and do
a profile cut on the outside of those
curves
i would get from cnc that geometry there
in 3d and now i'm going to create
a top using um
grasshopper and subdivision so
um i want a circular top
and i want it to be
[Music]
snaps so it should be 280 so it's a
radius of 140
i'll just that up out of the way
and voronois are quite interesting when
the like you kind of really
if you mess around with different
underlying shapes you realize how
drawing nature um you just use different
uh curves and um
it creates this very biogeometry so i'm
going to use a spiral
and i want the spiral to be flat if i
didn't type flat here or didn't click
flat
it would be a three-dimensional spiral
it's not to the center point
the edge of the spiral is going to be
the edge of the
seat and its default is set to 10
turns if i wanted to increase the turns
i could increase it there
that's fine and i could do that in
grasshopper
if i wanted to do more in grasshopper
but i'll just
do a little bit of it so um
i'm going to open my grasshopper window
which currently has nothing in it
and i want to bring that curve in so i
type
curve and take this basic curve with
it's just going to ask me to set one
curve and i want to set
the spiral and i want to divide
the spiral and
so that's going to create division
points and currently the number
is 10 but i will make that a slider
and set the slider to integers
and change the limits from
a minimum of one and let's say a maximum
of
a thousand
and plug that into the number of
versions
so now our spiral
if i move this oh didn't say it
[Music]
so i get a thousand up to a thousand uh
division points on that spiral
and i want to do a voronoi which i can
just type
uh born away
and i want those division points where
the example i showed you on pdf was
randomly
assigned points but um
those points
and then i want to bring in another
curve and this time i want to bring in
uh the circle from the edge
and i'm going to set the circle for the
edge as the boundary of the boron eye so
it doesn't go out
like the rising sun here
so now my my voronoi is
um just so i can see what's going on i
want to turn off the preview of the
points
uh i'm going to hide the
um edge circle i'm going to hide
the spiral
and i might do this in the top view so i
can see it better
okay so as i move
this division points now
that's basically dividing our spiral and
automatically creating a voronoi of
the points that it creates
so i could even um
[Music]
turn off the spiral
okay so what should i do um
let's do it about there
and then i'm going to bake that geometry
so i'll put on a different layer there's
a layer one
and now i'm essentially done with the
grasshopper
and
so when i have my layers open i can
actually right click
on layer one and uh
select select objects and that's just a
nice way of selecting just what's on
there and i'll drag this over
100 okay
maybe i didn't rotate that properly and
just fix that later
so it doesn't many degrees um
and i want to um show
because i want this edge circle to go
with it and i moved it
uh exactly 400 it's good to move things
by precise dimensions so that if you
forget something you can just
move copy 400 millimeter
so each one of these cells
is a closed curve
and if you remember the multi-pipe from
the kettle exercise
i'm going to do a multi-pipe on all of
these curves
but i don't want um
i want to basically one curve in each
position where currently
in this one position is this cell and
this cell
so i can explode and select all this
geometry
i don't need the circle and i can
explode it all
and that you can read from up here it
exploded 142 curves which were the
closed cells
into 823 segments which are just
individual curves
i want to click off and i can type
select duplicate or select dp
which is quite useful in numerous
situations
and it's selected 396 duplicates and i
can just delete
so now when i click on each of these
it's just one curve in each one of these
positions so then
um i want to use the circle
to trim these
outer parts
and i guess if i wanted to spend the
time i could do the whole thing
in grassroots but i'm just doing a
little bit in grasshopper based on what
we already know
so
you'll probably get away without being
so accurate but
i'm just gonna take the time to probably
follow this geometry
all right that's close enough and um
[Music]
so now i can select all these curves and
um
probably the best ideas in perspective
i'm going to do a multi-pipe on
the whole thing
so multiply i'm going to do a pipe
radius all
let's try three um
tap ends off and
one is fine and there we go
okay so i'm going to extrude my circle
by um the thickness of plywood that i'm
going to use a quarter
inch which should be 18 millimeter
and
[Music]
my subdivision had messed up
let's try it again
so um
i'm gonna do a bounding box on the curve
and a bounding box
on that so i can drag this subdivision
across
i could snap to that point and then the
top point
of this bounding box
and now i'm going to use solid geometry
to boolean
[Music]
separate
that subdivision geometry so i'm going
to do boolean split
and
there's the towel on to turn this on and
hopefully this will
separate
but from controlling a cnc machine
perspective we actually just need these
curves and then to assign
a ball nose router bit which is the one
i showed you at the end of the slideshow
to those curves and then it will move
on the line uh profile cut these curves
and this would be the end result
so for c c and c machining you actually
just need the curves
and um it's going to take a bit too big
and that's most of it um done as far as
modeling
goes i'm going to then set some
materials
and make 2d
[Music]
works very well with simple geometry
sometimes it kind of gets a bit messed
up with more complex geometry needs to
be tidied up
there are a lot of sub settings that
weren't there in previous versions so it
might be better
in mind seven
this might be better on a faster
computer but my laptop's a little slow
if anyone has any questions um
so i can just delete this top part
there is my boolean.geometry
so my hope is to create that as a stool
top and um
it's got enough points on the stool that
should still be comfortable
and we can
move this to the top so before i make
sure that this is not perfectly straight
[Music]
so
so now that's better and i can snap
[Music]
two
and then uh
[Music]
i'm just creating bounding boxes so i
can snap from one to the other
[Music]
and then i want to move that down again
i said it was
let's say six millimeter
so that's our stool um when creating the
cnc
file we would need to pocket cut
the parts underneath for these which
um one way of creating that geometry is
to just boolean out from this
and it'll be i don't know if it will
slow down my computer again but
james do you do everything line to line
for your
your uh cnc work or do you leave a
little bit of
gap a little bit of tolerance or
clearance in those
um i need a little bit of clearance
um how much huh
how much would you leave it depends i
mean i usually
like a millimeter oh sorry
do you mean on sorry vertically a
millimeter definitely not on the other
side
um it takes a lot of i mean wood
obviously
plywood can expand um depending on the
season
and um it's kind of a trial and error
process
sometimes the cnc especially since i use
the shotbot
is some of the machines are more
accurate
sometimes they're a little off so you
kind of i do like a few tests and then
see how that goes
and then apply that tolerance to the
rest of the geometry and then we cut
i wouldn't sort of take a file and cut
it directly without
doing a tolerance check
and i like i guess when i first did it
um
[Music]
i just made like
15 different uh slots and
like made it in wood and then with the
wood put it in each of the 15 slots and
and check
which fit i like the best and
i guess did it in the real world for
trial and error and just this one works
the best
that's cool thanks
so um just as a last step in the last
few minutes we have
um if i just uh
grab this and let this be
um so this is properties that we've done
before layers
rendering and then the fourth one is
materials
if we add a new material and
kind of see these set materials already
here i don't think they have wood
so i need to just go they're still
in the downloaded file but um they have
lots of
more options here so i can select wood
they have
all these types of wood
i want birch but i don't want polished
birch
and that adds to my material file
and then there's a few different ways i
can do it i can select all the geometry
right click on the material and go
assign to objects or i can just drag it
across
and in ghosted view i'm going to have a
material but
if i bring it into rendered view
there we go so there is
a object that uses
some subdivision geometry through the
multi-pipe tool some grasshopper
geometry through
voronoi um it's on a spiral
divided points some nerves curves for
the legs
and then kind of sets it up which i
guess i haven't totally finished but
sets it up for a cnc file
um and we could do make
2d on this and hopefully in your final
project file
you're doing one something from each
week uh hopefully that makes sense and
then there should be a place to upload
your file which i'll send info i'm not
sure exactly where we're doing it
but you can send your 3dm file
or we might just do an image i'll let
you know
and maybe just describe some of your
steps there's a
google spreadsheet actually a google
quiz that i created already and i just
you just take a checkbox and say
my model has nerves my model has
grasshopper and so um that's kind of the
conclusion to the course hopefully
everyone
if they wanted to create a this
stool and
lots of other cool projects and if
there's any questions now i'm going to
stay around
and if you have any questions in the
following days i'll be happy to answer
them
on the hackaday page