[Music]
let's get started
okay so a little bit laggy but
we should be okay and welcome to
session seven so again
for people who who know just bear with
me for a sec
this is where we have everything and
brian has already also posted a link to
hackaday projects
before i get started with today's topic
again congrats to the people who
submitted the katas
to get the first certificate and i got a
couple
really nice results tweeted
and just for people who missed it last
time
we are doing a certificate give out
which is this vector graphic where you
can use to
print out anything you want and is kind
of
a hacked schrodinger's cat
and all you need to do is to find a
quantum catalyst and then do a
screenshot
that you finished a whole set of
cards then post it on either twitter or
linkedin you will get this
of course you need to tag these accounts
and hashtags so that i will know
so today's topic is on algorithms
we start with the simplest the
earliest one of the earliest algorithm
which is deutsche's algorithm
so these are a set of algorithms that
are really class classically taught
in academics so in academia
they were developed in the past
couple decades and there were
early algorithms that
scientists were able to show the
specific
improvement compared to classical
algorithm for
specific tasks so the
deutsche aurism what it's trying to
solve is
to figure out if a function is balanced
or constant balance just means that
[Music]
is not a two to one
function is one to one so one input
gives out
one output and there's no
repeated ambiguous result
when a function is constant is a two to
one so
here is saying no matter what input you
give
you get the same value so either your
function output one or either is zero
so don't worry that uh right now i'm
just giving a short intro
if anything sounds confusing we're gonna
answer that later
and deutsche hosa is a expanded
deutsche algorithm for n-qubits
and later on you also see some of the
more complex
algorithms that also tend to be more
useful so gruver's algorithm is
a search algorithm for
ordered list and then also the
schwarz algorithm you would use to
factorize really large
numbers so
there are not a lot of quantum
algorithms
that are distinctly different these are
some of the examples that are doing
different things
and most of the later algorithms
are developed based on those here is a
link where you can find
all kinds of other algorithms and i hope
that by
your self-study of quantum computing
you will be able to come up with more
useful algorithms in the future
and also a lot of these are academic
and we need a lot more large-scale
industry
solutions so keep that in mind
while you learn these historic
algorithms
but also the industry really needs more
interesting and useful ones
before we go to the algorithm there's a
concept called
articles i i very perplexed
why are we called why do we call these
things oracles
like i was trying to look up um the
definition of oracles
so there's also there's the theological
definition uh so that's what is
cartoon is trying to show but also in
quantum computing we have
this uh quantum oracles
that basically a black box
and there are also a lot of different
ways to define it
is sometimes people say it's an
operation that is used as
input to another algorithm sometimes
people say
represent classical functions that
return real numbers
instead of only a single bit there's
also definitions saying quantum
operations
which implement certain classical
functions
these are just words and is not
that useful so let's turn them
into more intuitive pictures
a classical algorithm looks like this
where it takes
some inputs and then you apply a
function to
the input and you get an output y
a quantum algorithm cannot use
this kind of setup because this has no
guarantee that
this function f of x is reversible
and we introduced reversibility when we
were talking about gates when you're
applying an
operation onto your qubits you need to
make sure that they can reverse back
so this algorithm setup
wouldn't be useful for
quantum so instead in quantum algorithms
we
build a setup like this where your
inputs
are encoded into these qubits
and also this output qubit y also goes
through this
black box you will get
your input cubits out through the box
and also your y qubit would become
this y with a control
knot with f of x
what does that also show
this is trying to give
you a proof that you cannot
set up a quantum algorithm like this
for example in this case
if y is your f of x
and you can have all these inputs of x
but it has
a period it goes from zero one two three
and then repeats
so in this case you can get a f
of x but then you cannot reverse back if
you say
you have a value of three
you don't know if your eggs start to
with a three or
a seven so here is just trying to show
you
that instead if you write your
oracle black box in this way then you
can get a reverse
i wouldn't spend too much time showing
you the derivation but i'm
keeping these slides here for you to
look at later
so this is just trying to show you that
if you set up your
circuit like this it would work and it
would be able to reverse back
if you do two of them in series you get
your initial
inputs back to before
so don't worry about this too much this
is just showing you that
um in quantum algorithms uh a lot of
them
so i've showed you like teleportation
algorithm before we didn't
need oracle but a lot of those
future later articles later
algorithms that they need oracles
and this f of x is this classical
function that we can
get out of this
black box and it is also used to
construct
this black box so let's just
look at an actual example this deutsch
hosa
algorithm then and that's constructed by
physicist david deutsch and
mathematician
richard hosa at first sight it seemed to
be a very complex
circuit you have a bunch of input qubits
and you apply hardama gates onto all of
them
and also when you input those qubits
they all initialize to zero
so even including your your
input of the oracle which is your
classical output y
is encoded into this qubit and it
is also starting at zero but then you do
a
flip this x gate that
change it to one and do again a hard
omega
then you throw all of these into this
black box
when it comes out you
do a measurement of
those input x cubits
and then you would know what your
function f of
x would be so what deutsche holzer
algorithm does
is to find out if a function
f of x is constant which means
f of x is either 0 or 1
for any given x so
constant 0 or constant 1. or
f of x could be balanced which means
half of the time
f of x gives you output of 0 and half of
the time
it gives you output one this is the
setup
for this algorithms it does nothing else
it just
tells us if a con if a function is
constant or balance it doesn't even tell
you exactly what f of x
is but what this algorithm does is to
tell you
uh the nature of f of x
if you want to do this classically you
will have to
test every single output
given every single input so you need to
run your algorithm n times
if you have n numbers but in this
case with even with n qubits you just
need to run your algorithm
once and do the measurement for all
these qubits you will get
the answer so this is what it does
much better than classically
a recap what is each gate
in case you forgot the h
gate brings a 0 or 1
to this intermediate state that is a
superposition of 0 and 1.
what is a c not gate it's
i haven't shown you a c not gate in
deutsche hoser
black box yet but there is a c naught
and what it does
is to change the second qubit
based on the first qubit and what does
h and the c naught together do
remember we discussed entanglement
before
you would build a entanglement
between these two cubes when you have a
h
and a c naught so intuitively what
deutsche hauser auxin is doing
you are starting with some pure zero
zero qubit state
and each gate will change
all of them into a superposition of zero
and once and then this last qubit comes
in
it started with zero but then when you
do a axe gate
on it it would bring this negative sign
into your system because each
gate applied to a
1 state is the minus state
and then this black box is set up
so that if f of x
is constant your oracle actually does
nothing to your
input qubits these qubits here
so if that's the case then when it goes
out of the black box nothing is changed
so applying a h gate to them
will bring them back to where they
started so all of the outputs will be
zero
however if you want your black box
to have this balanced function
then what it is doing is it actually
entangles this qubit
this state with any of the
the other state so this then
entanglement allows you to carry this
negative sign
over to your
output of the oracle
and turns out that because this negative
sign brought by this last qubit here
half of the time you would have
a positive amplitude for
all of the states being zero but half of
the time it will have a negative
amplitude
so in fact what this
black box did if the
function is balanced is that it creates
this
destructive interference for
these states preserving
so the output if you measure
zero zero zero zero and if they are all
zero
that tells you your cons your function
is constant
but if you measure any of those qubits
being one
if there's just you will
one one state
you will know that your function is
balanced um i know
this is usually quite confusing
to fir when people first see it
let's take another example just
because we have so many qubits here
the mathematics can get very lengthy
let's
reduce it down to the deutsche algorithm
where we only have one input qubit
so this is
what deutsche algorithm does is trying
to find
there are only two options now only two
qubits involved
if a function is balanced
it's either when x is 0
it gets f of x to 0
1 to 1 or 0 becomes 1
1 becomes 0. this is balance this is a
one to one
function but if it is constant
say is always becoming zero
no matter your input or it always
becomes one
both cases are telling you the
function is constant yes
is there a question yeah i said you are
frozen
or you were proven a second ago for the
whole
oh we usually yeah i would present for
half an hour and then
we can have discussions and questions
after is that okay
yeah i was just saying your screen was
frozen oh it is
yeah which oh it's fine okay thank you
yeah yeah it's a little laggy i think
next time i probably won't you
won't use this again let's see
so if you want to figure this out
classically you have to test
each step you need to do one
run of your classical algorithm and then
see what your
end result is if it is in this case
what happens next
you have to evaluate all of your
possibilities
but as i mentioned earlier if we turn it
into a quantum algorithm
they would not need to be measured
they will not need to be run n times
so the deutsche algorithm is just a two
qubit version of deutsch hosa algorithm
so we would reduce this circuit into
this below circuit only
two qubits involved so that's much
easier to
follow and see what happens with the
math
okay so the deutsche algorithm
is trying to find out if the function f
of x
is constant or balanced and in fact
in here you would replace it with a
quantum algorithm that has
oracle in it so you need to build a
oracle
based on the different possibilities of
f of x
let's see step by step
you can construct these four
possibilities so classically you have
um constant zero so f of x is zero
constant one f of x
is one if it's balanced but same
is f of x will equal to x
but if it is balance reverse you will
have a reverse of
x so these are the four
probabilities and you can
write a truth table this is how a
constant
with x would look like but then now
we're dealing with
quantum algorithm you need to even
expand it
to further
your truth table will have all these
pros
possibilities written out so if your
x is zero your y could be zero or one
and similarly with x is one
you have two possible y values
and then you just write out okay
constant is constant zero then all of
the x is zero
and then you calculate what y
c naught or control y is the control and
f of x
is target you will know that
if y is zero
f of x this
overall is zero if y is one
this result is one so you just do this
calculation so
you see that this here is exactly the
same as
as y so then in this quantum
article here we do nothing we just let
the
the cubits pass through without doing
making any gates
but if you had a constant one you will
notice that
is the opposite to y so all of these
cubits got flipped for for y then you
know okay i'm gonna
put a x gate to
this second qubit to get this kind of
truth table but if it's balanced
which means half of the time it will
have
zero and half of time is one
you you see that you would be able to
get
this value if you had a c
naught in between these qubits so you
can just
try to construct this truth table
and you will see that this is what you
need to do
with balance reverse you is
same there but then you need to flip the
qubit
so you put an x there
the significance here is that
you see that if the function is
if they were constant either constant
zero are one
there's no interaction between the two
qubits inside the oracle
but if your function is balanced
you have this uh c naught
in between them you you connect it to
the
two qubits inside the black box
you can for sure write all of the
steps out in mathematics and i will
highly recommend you do that at home
to realize it looks difficult
but turnout is very very easy so
you should try going through the math
and try to reproduce it
on your own to realize how this is done
mathematically
so one way to study quantum computing
is that people say shut up and calculate
so you will get
you understand mathematically how it
works
and that is my language and i i like
doing this but it's not always the same
for everyone
and intuitively this is intimidating
so what we can do
is just intuitively looking at
those gates as i mentioned for deutsche
holzer earlier
is that all you are doing
is to make your state
into a superposition and then introduce
a negative sign then based on
your oracle setup you will either get
your output 0 or your 0 will be
cancelled out
so you will get 1 as your output and
those two cases correspond to function
being constant
or balanced and i can even write this
out
more for you here i made a note here
for myself to not forget is
[Music]
try to write out the steps
so this x
plus one is this here when your
first qubit got h gate on it
and now you are combining your system
with
a a minus state
which is from your y here
and then what happens uh through this
black box
so first you need to expand this you
will get
a positive zero zero
and then a negative
0 1 positive 1 0
and negative 1 1.
okay is i'm writing with my finger here
it's not very pretty
stop uh my computer stopped recognizing
my pen
um so then what happens
after you go through say
i pick a balance state just to prove the
point
and what that truth table
earlier told me if i used
this balanced
same truth table
then what is doing is based on
my x i would change y
accordingly so this would then becomes
0 0 nothing changes
minus 0 1 nothing changes because
the first cube is 0 but then your second
one will become
1 1 so this amplitude becomes
positive and then the last one is
one zero
then what's happening is that
you have these interference negative
amplitudes here so it will bring
destructive interference so
if you want your first qubit to be
zero
and then your first qubit
to be one
oh actually it doesn't really
matter so
because the first qubits you want to put
it into a state where it is a
superposition
so that you can uh do a h
to it to figure out if it is zero or one
so you would actually want to look at
your first qubit being 0 and 1 there
so this gives you a
positive state
and
this one will give you
a negative state
and then similarly looking at this qubit
here
this will give you a negative
state and this will give you
a minus positive state
so what's happening here is this the
amplitude for the positive states
are destructively interfering so
as a result they would cancel each other
out
and all you're left with is this
minus state and then when you do a
h to it you would then obtain
your state one so
turns out that there's no
possibility of obtaining zero when you
measure your first
state if your
function is balanced so this is the
exercise you should try to do at home
to try the other cases
the intuition i want people to establish
here is
to understand that when this
negative sign gets introduced if it
interacts with your other
one of the other qubits and because of
the h
here and the c knot here you are
essentially entangling
the two qubits inside this article then
your output
would cancel you will have half of the
time that
the zero amp zeroes amplitude would be
positive and half the time negative so
you canceled
you destructively interfere them
but then if you don't mix those two
cubits you don't
make them interact then the
top qubit will just come out without
being ordered
so in both constant case you will get
your output being zero this is what
deutsch
and deutsche hosa algorithms do that's
all he's
trying to figure out is the nature of
the function
so it's not a super useful
algorithm we don't use it anywhere
however it
is a very cool demonstration to show you
this
powerful effect when you have both
superposition interference
and entanglement involved in your
algorithm so
classically you will have to run your
system
multiple times but then quantum
you know quantum wise you just need to
run your algorithm once
so there are a couple of exercises
that's related to today's topic
you should look up on the
um quantum cutters
and cutters also has two options
it has its own deutsche hosa algorithm
cadas but it also has a tutorial
option where it shows you
some of the details so there's the
deutsche hosa you should try
out there's also the
tutorials which has a more
explained step by step sorry
previous so
i would recommend people go back and try
these
which will help you understand what we
discussed today
and another place you can look up
is in the documentation page
the microsoft's documentation site
we have the samples
inside the documentation and you can
download
the code from github and try those out
so there are three three exercises you
can choose and pick
to run and then
if you just look at the tutorial how to
set up
the deutsche hosa algorithm is actually
very straightforward
all it is asking you to do is to
use code to set up this circuit
and the usefulness of the code is that
as you grow your qubit
number of qubits you wouldn't want to
draw
all of your qubits out but you can just
use the q-sharp language use code to
directly write out
you have n-cubits and you can apply
h and x gates and you can apply
oracle this is exactly step by step
trying to set up this q v
here so you should go back and try to
run this catas that's it
um to finish off i'm announcing another
certificate this wednesday
the questions are as follows this is
this is less technical
quiz uh it's more of like a historic fun
entertainment so here i wonder who came
up with
the term quantum oracle because it
really
kind of created this
barrier for me to learn what this term
is about
that's not in my culture that's not in
my vocab vocabulary before so
if you are curious like me please
search around and see who came up with
the term
and then i have embedded some
characters in the comics so
on page six who is this person and on
page 26
who is this so you can you can
pick any of this and then tag me on
social media
as i mentioned earlier and you will get
another certificate which i would
announce on wednesday
okay so that's it
time for questions
you