[Music]
hi
um so i'm going to teach this course
mainly about geometry and then about
rhino
as well i like to kind of bounce around
to all the different parts of rhino
rather than
going deep and learning every single
tool in one part
because i think if you know a little bit
about everything
in this youtube google era if you
understand what can be done
and a little bit about how to do one or
two things it's quite easy to search
your way or to find
all those extra tools so the five weeks
of this course
are going to jump between the major
areas of rhino
different types of geometry that i kind
of cover in this introduction
uh and then we'll i'll do some slides at
the beginning of this
lecture today and introduce the kind of
3d design
as a sort of whole and then onto rhino
and we'll like learn how to use the
software
um if you haven't downloaded the
software i presume you have at this
stage but there's a 90 day free trial
um of rhino7 some of you may be using
905 or
6 or mac version um
the mac version is slightly different in
terms of its layout same tools but just
slightly different layout
um and that's that
so i love this project
um which kind of gets a little bit
started about me i was in
london in 2008 working at a sort of
large corporate architecture practice
that does
many of the world's tallest buildings
and they had
extra budget i guess to do cool projects
and they had within the office this
group
people call the smart geometry unit that
were also in other of the sort of large
big skyscraper architects and
one of them was sort of a had just
finished his phd from mit and others
had studied in london at the
architecture association or aaa
in the drl program and the drl is the
design research lab
and this was a sort of a project they
did in 2008
just to show what they had learned in
this sort of second masters program
in london and it kind of differentiates
how i think about design software and
geometry
because my undergraduate degree was
uh hand-drawn we we did drawings for
architecture by hand if we did
perspectives we set up
um sort of fading points and did lots of
lines and lots of measurements on the
paper
and when i went to london i was sort of
immersed in this world of digital
geometry
and i think when many of the people from
my undergrad learned
autocad they were doing the exact same
things
people done for decades in that they
weren't using the software to do
anything new and i think that gave them
a lot of frustration because
some of the professors liked drawing by
hand because they weren't
really doing anything on the computer
that you couldn't do by hand
rhino and other softwares that we'll
cover or kind of introduce
really do do new things and that sort of
sets up
this change from what you can do on pen
and paper and what you can do
with mathematics and algorithms and
that's sort of an old and then new
and i think many people know autocad or
other drafting softwares and they aren't
really doing anything new with it
so in this course we're going to sort of
cover what's new in geometry and
why you would need this software or can
use the software to do those new things
so as a basic introduction starting at
the very beginning of all
computer graphics i just like to um
explain the sort of origin story
um if on the left we have a grid of 30
by 30 squares and we label some black
and some white
we can kind of draw a circle or
something that's recognizable as a
circle
this is sort of a pixel model of drawing
and on the right hand side we have
a precise measurement with a center
point at 15
and 15 and a radius of eight
[Music]
on the left hand side we call this
raster graphics and all photographs
many of you are probably familiar with
this stuff but all photographs are
raster graphics where each of those
squares is colored a different color and
three thousand by three thousand squares
would be nine
million pixels or nine megapixels
when you zoom in on the master graphics
it will always fade to this grid the
grid is sort of always there it might be
just really really small
on the right hand side vector graphics
are mathematically defined
uh therefore if you zoom in on it it
will always be a crisp
edge the major two softwares for
2d drawing for graphic designers and
because i've done
use them a lot but our photoshop and
illustrator and they they create them as
separate softwares because they really
are
two different giants two different sort
of
underlying ways they work
when we look at 3d the same is true
voxels are pixels volumetric pixels
and they're sort of 3d pixels and on the
right we have
mathematically defined uh shapes
that can be more accurate they
contain a lot on all sort of vector
drawing compared to raster drawing
vector drawings are far more efficient
when it comes to a file type as well
there's a lot less polygonal points
defined in the model therefore there's
just a lot less geometry
there's a lot less
tiny file sizes as a relative comparison
the
major foxhole program that you may know
or game is
minecraft in this the whole world is
defined by
physical blocks and transparent blocks
that you can walk through and
some of them are textured as grass and
some are wood and some are stone but
they are all
just an entire grid of cubes and you can
kind of manipulate them as you want and
it's sort of
because you're able to manipulate them
in the game it is in a way a 3d design
software if you were to
kind of use it to create geometry uh
another form of voxel geometry is mri
scans
they take uh images through the body at
sort of set intervals and then you can
make 3d models out of the geometry that
you do through an mri scan
this is a project i did just on ornament
and
voxels where we this is human
body made through symmetry and tidied up
in rhino
taught by tobias klein but it shows sort
of
learning about other types of geometry
for vector geometry mathematical
geometry we might split
them again subdivide them into two and
come up with surface and solids we can
make a sphere in
both types of geometry but in one
it is hollow and then the other one it's
solid and that's quite different for
if we were to take a bite out of each of
those what the resulting geometry would
be
if we were to bite out of them solid
programs generally are popular with
engineers
um particularly a program called
solidworks another one called creo they
tend to be
really really expensive 5000 plus or
4000 plus dollars
to buy they do things
that surface geometry can't do um
and then some of the surface geometry
sort of fakes that way to be solid when
you want it to be which we'll cover in
this course but
rhino is a surface geometry software
therefore
all geometry you create it thinks is
hollow
that's its back end uh one of the big
problems with solid geometry
um or people who are very used to using
solid geometry sulfur
is filleting solids or kind of cutting
away solids so
if you were to do the uh digital
equivalent
of using a router bit to cut away the
edge as you would do with this wood
that's quite easy and solid works in
rhino it just becomes a bit of a hassle
but you can kind of do it okay
surface geometry is then further
self-split
into a couple of different types and
nerves non-uniform rational beast lines
not something you need to know but
is a type of mathematical modeling and
i'll come to that one last
mesh modeling or polygonal modeling is
where we have
points defined in 3d space and we have
flat geometry
straight lines between the points so we
can do a quad
mesh or a triangular mesh um that's more
of a mathematical problem to which type
of mesh we want to do
but um there is no curved
geometry in that sphere therefore that
sphere will never truly be
round we can simulate it as round but
its underlying geometry will always be
these flat
faceted pieces and on the right
we have subdivision geometry and that's
a sort of variant
kind of between the two but more
polygonal model mesh model
where we have points in 3d space we have
flat planes between those
uh points we need sort of less points
and when we smooth it in the software
you end up with
this tab in rhino's tab on tab off
but you end up with these patches so
in all forms of 3d software having too
much geometry
is really hard to edit because we just
want one point and to pull it and the
things to happen if we have 100 points
which point do we grab and it becomes
really hard so you're always looking to
have
as little geometry to control the shape
that you want and
not really much more so meshes are kind
of a little harder to work with they
have
different kind of tools that are a
little like sculpture where you push on
them and it pushes all the points in
slightly but more towards the center
they tend to be more around gaming
so low poly is gaming high poly is more
animation
subdivision modeling is also associated
with animation nerves modeling
kind of like the factor circles is
efficient from a file size perspective
but more importantly
between the polygonal points there can
be curves
a mathematical model does not need the
shapes between each of the points to be
flat they can be curved and as a result
we can be far more precise
with the type of geometries we create
and if we're going to engineer these
products or build them in the real world
um we really want to be accurate with
the shapes that we're creating
so i would or kind of generally thought
of as polygonal modeling
is fast and very useful for animation
uh but nurbs is where all
or solid or surface mathematical
modeling is where all engineering
architecture
jewelry anything that's going to be made
physical because you want what you draw
on the screen to be at least somewhat
accurate
in the product that you finally make
so um one of the offices i work for oma
uh quite a fan's office and they
work a lot with blue foam models and
blue foam is cut using a hot wire cutter
so you just sort of
that's hot wire and you push the phone
through it
and i really think the tools that you
use
uh the final geometries you create are
dependent on those tools so the blue
foam models you can almost recognize the
buildings even though
this is not a building made from blue
foam it's still the geometry that was
created using
a blue phone prototyping method when you
look at this final
project by zahadeed in azerbaijan
um it was very clearly kind of a
subdivision model
uh on a on a computer and
i kind of knowing all the tools and a
range of softwares
start to look at buildings or any
physical product and i'll kind of
have a fairly good guess what software
they use to design it and have a fairly
good guess what
specific tools they might use to get
there so it and hopefully it will become
kind of obvious to
all of you as well um
the first uh 3d model uh ever created
was using bezier curves and we'll cover
different types of curves next week but
this was the utah teapot where
martin newell was doing his phd in utah
and they created this mathematical
modeling remodeling
and they didn't know what uh model
they'd send around the world to say we
did it they were
instead of pyramid or cube and his wife
said why don't you send our teapot
and they model this teapot and it's the
first file ever since so it's kind of
the hello world of 3d
and when people are testing their
rendering settings they still use this
teapot as a sort of
uh it appears as references in a lot of
uh
3d things there was a music video that
did it and simpsons did it when homer
went into 3d
toy story you see it here um also andy
the character
in toy story is possibly named after
andy van dam on andy's bookshelf is
visual programming by andy van dam which
no kid that age would have he's a
professor famous professor at brown
university
on computer graphics and toy story
used the first toy story which is 1995.
this is scud the dog and the first toy
story was done in mathematical modeling
it was done in nurbs
and as a result it's it's not uh great
for these kind of
very fluid and flexible and smooth
shapes
because scud has no fur um
some of the zoomed up shots look pretty
bad uh and
as you kind of see pixar evolve every
single
film they made their sort of giant leaps
in sort of the geometry
uh for each one um fur is possible
by the time of uh monsters inc
and this is sort of
um the animation process for
uh pixar just found something online it
may or may not be accurate it's just
from the core
post but they used autodesk maya for 3d
modeling
geometry then they probably set the
materials in maya
i gas and they do the rigging in model
maya
so rigging is uh this process that
you'll see here where the face
as i said before you want the least
amount of geometry to do all of your
control
so you have these uh kind of rigs that
you can
move the eyebrows up and down and when
they're setting the animation
they're just really moving the character
rigs which all the
hundreds of thousands of legal points
are controlled by the rates so in that
way you're controlling the whole process
and pixar use a whole range of other
softwares presto being
their in-house software that doesn't get
outside their office and
can apply commercially
in sort of an architecture process you
might do the modeling in rhino
material lighting rendering are usually
done out of house if you're
if you do professional stuff with firms
like lexicon
or haze davidson where sort of 5000
pounds per image or some price like that
and um but ultimately you can do 3d
modeling draw the geometry
then kind of like setting meta
information you're going to set those
materials
which is sort of setting the color the
texture maybe with the jpeg
then setting the glossiness
the opacity the um if it's water or
glass the refractive index and kind of
you just draw
any shapes you want and then you set
these settings and it becomes that
material
then they would somebody else would do
the lighting for the model
rendering takes up to a day or two days
on a computer to really get the high
quality renders out
and in architecture they might insert
that back into a photograph a sort of
aerial photograph taken by drone
to make it really photorealistic another
thing you could do is do 3d modeling and
then just
export the line work uh to
a sort of illustrator um rhino one of
the best things about rhino is it has
tons of files types that you can import
into it and tons of file types that you
can export from it
so this would this is big architects in
copenhagen and
i know they're processed very well
worked in this other office
um in copenhagen it used to be the same
office and that would be
3d models in rhino exported and brought
into adobe illustrator
and that's just making the line work
nice maybe coloring it a little bit
adding arrows
and this is a proposal for a really fun
hotel that was you could ski on the roof
to learn how to ski and then go up the
slope
which is that green slope or red slope
depending on what side
you wanted to ski down on the roof
another thing to use a 3d geometry for
is you would model something in rhino
when i was in college we learned a
program called ecotect which was bought
by autodesk but i've never used this
ladybug honeybee but it's a plug-in for
a rhino
that does looks like it does the same
thing where you 3d modeled the geometry
um these sulfurs generally know you
input the city it knows where the sun is
at every single time of the year
and it shows you exactly how much light
is going to get in through each window
in each direction
if you model all the surrounding
buildings it will take account for
shadows and you can see the shadows
throughout the year
and really plan the size of your windows
based on the feedback that you would
make in these kind of models
and just on plug-ins right now has tons
of plugins
a lot of a very strong online community
for
asking questions to in the form of
forums or
sometimes the software developers
themselves get involved and answer your
questions
there's a lot of youtube videos so that
there's really a great community to
learn new skills
beyond the introduction uh this is uh
my own uh machine which is this tnc
machine
and on this you're kind of drawing
furniture in as a line work and then
bringing it into a cam software and
telling the tool path to follow
the paths that were created in mino and
press go and
furniture so
all these softwares will have xyz
coordinates and in rhino and
in solidworks and anything that we're
making physical products the z-axis is
vertical
in film software they think of x and y
as the screen where y is vertical
and z is off the screen so if you are
ever using any of those softwares
you might need to reset it you can
always reset the xyz
to anything you want it to be the
origin point or zero zero zero is
um uh uh
on minor where we're going to sort of
insert the units when we open the model
so we don't need any units after we tell
the program what units we're going to
use um they can be light years
they can be millimeters they can be
nanometers they can be whatever you want
or inches
um but after that point the software is
just going to think in 0
10 100 000 it it just wants numbers it
doesn't want to know
those dimensions afterwards if you're
going to print a page
or uh export a 3d print it might be
useful to know whether you're in
millimeters or light years because
that's
potentially going to have problems but
um we're going to
sort of insert coordinates in in the
format of
x comma y comma z
uh and no punctuation at the end
so if we want to point and we're asked
the position of the point
we're gonna put three comma three comma
three
um all geometry i'm just gonna go
through the types of geometry in rhino
and then we'll jump into the software
um so points is the smallest
unit of rhino and everything in rhino
whether you draw it or draw something
more complicated is composed of points
so it's sort of the electron or the
the smallest unit in the sulfur
a curve oh also just note that a point
is pt
uh and knowing the shorthand
abbreviations of each of these
is particularly useful for using the
software efficiently
uh a curve is any line whether it is
curved or not curved
just all lines are called curves and
their shorthand is c or v
um there are a few different types of
curves but we're going to cover them
next week um a curve can be
open which just means it's open and
it's selection uh shorthand is is open
curve
uh if you're going to get into coding
the the capital letters matter but
otherwise it's not so important
and then you can have a closed curve
a closed curve can become a surface an
open curve cannot because it doesn't
can't finish off the geometry um and
a surface can be planar if it is flat
it's called planar if it's flat
or it can be um sort of curvy
then if you were to extrude that up it
would be a poly surface
that could be open or closed a closed
poly surface means that it's airtight
that means for 3d printing you can only
print closed poly surfaces
and if there is some bad geometry that
somebody
left a nanometer open that would be open
geometry and 3d printer just wouldn't
see it so
knowing that closed geometry is
perfectly airtight closed is quite
important
and there's close poly surface and
abbreviation
plus plugs so everything
when you're drawing is some version of
points curves or surfaces
um when rhino thinks about solids it's
really just thinking about
closed poly surfaces um
there's no true solid in rhino there's
just
closed voice and most of the tools
are going from one of these types
up or down to another one so if you
extrude a curve it becomes a surface
if you extrude surface it becomes a poly
surface if you
want to duplicate edges on the
surface or the polysurface it becomes a
curve
if you divide a curve it becomes a point
so you're just moving up and down
this ladder of geometry
and um just to cover some tools scale
when
d is uh what you can type into rhino and
and you'll
sort of scale it in one direction uh
rhino has
a lot of time if you type what you think
it might be
a lot of the time that is the name of
the command and it just
works so if you just can't remember the
name of something just type it and
i'll show you when we open software and
it'll probably work and then a lot of
time there's
more than one command or that does the
exact same thing so stretch
and scale 1d will do the exact same
thing at least in this example
scale 2d will move into two dimensions
and scale 3d will
move it in three dimensions so we're
going to
open software now and i'm going to draw
this model
it's it's quite a simple geometry but
i'm just going to show you how to draw
it
and there is my contact information that
if you need to contact me you can ask
questions
so this is the rhino interface
so you see these four windows maybe you
might be able to start there top
front right and perspective
at the very top of the page is the file
menu and you can see
the names of the weeks that i'm going to
cover curves surfaces sub d
solid each of those has various menus
of every tool in the curve menu
there are each of the tools available as
icons which is repeating the information
but if you want to use icons as opposed
to the file menu
you can do it that way so we have curve
tools here surface tools
and changing that changes both the
sidebar and this top bar
and solids subteas standard
and down the bottom is all about
accuracy
um so here we have uh
the snaps which are currently grayed out
because i need to click
the o snap is turned on i know snap
should almost always be turned on
planar should almost always be turned on
um when you download the software for
the first time they're off so i
turn them on ortho we're going to turn
on as well now so planar is just
uh if i'm in any view and i draw a line
that it will be at the same height
in all views if that's not on sometimes
the second point can be
a thousand meters higher than the first
point and it really messes things up so
planar should
say almost always be on ortho just means
i will be
locked to go
vertical or horizontal in each view
if you want to make really curvy
geometry you need orthodoxy off
but for now let's just leave that on and
then oh snap
is our various snaps and i'm going to
cover them when i
when i open up some geometry the command
line is the third option for how you
could
input commands into rhino um it's by far
my favorite and pretty much the only
thing i use which i type in the commands
and
if you just type box box will be a
command
and you get a box
and if you type sphere it goes here if
you type
curve from there so um
the first thing we're going to do
is change perspective view um the
viewport menus
so it's quite normal to have top
front and right which are kind of like
plan section elevation
um as wireframe which
just means you can just see the lines
but for
perspective view we have the option of
shaded rendered or ghosted
and a whole load more but ghosted just
means
that if there are surfaces that we see
them as
shaded and rendered means we will see it
as a solid
so ghosted is generally what perspective
would be set to for modeling and i'm
going to
delete this box and draw one more time
so
from the menu on the left here you can
select a box by left clicking it
some of the commands if you see this
tool
tip that it shows that the if i left
click this one i get hide objects and if
i right click
i get show objects um so sometimes left
and right click
might react differently with some of the
tools that doesn't that's not true for
all tools
and then if i hold down and left click
and i just hold it down for like four
four seconds
this menu pops up with lots of types of
solids
and if i click off that disappears but
if i hold it down again
and i drag it out it becomes a sort of
menu that states there
and similarly there's lots of different
types of boxes and
that generally is if i wanted to draw a
box
um let's say if i wanted to draw a
sphere do i want to
enter the center first and then the
radius or do i want to enter
three points on the surface and just
create the sphere to fit those three
points
or some other variant of them so there's
different starting points for how you
want to
what kind of inputs you want to give it
in order to get the geometry you want
so if i start by creating a box and
from the command point it will sort of
ask me questions
and you always kind of want to look to
that top left
part of the screen to see what is it
asking for
um so in this case it's asking for the
first corner of the base
if i was to left click on model that
would place
the first corner of the base but it
would be a
highly inaccurate way of doing it it
would just be like placing it randomly
where i feel like it to be if i type
zero zero
comma zero comma zero
now the first corner is exactly on the
origin point
then it asks me a second question other
corner of base or length
so if i enter a number that would be the
length
if i enter another number comma number
comma number that would be where the
point in space
so i'm just going to put 100. when you
open the model you'll be asked
millimeters or light years or
kilometers or whatever the hundred is
those units but it really doesn't matter
for this lecture what units you entered
and then with uh press enter to use
length
so i enter the number 100 and you guys
hopefully can see that 100 is entered
there i press enter
and that's that and then height one more
number
100. so now i've created the cube but i
can't see it because i'm
far too zoomed in and you can select
the cube and type
zoom and it's going to give you a bunch
of options
these options that are kind of being
highlighted
are i can click on them or i can type
them or i can type the first letter
or the underlined letter so i want to
say extense
that only did perspective so i can type
zoom and click all
which is all views and extents and now
all
four of my views zoom to the box that i
just
created
so if i double click
on any of these views they become
[Music]
they take over the whole screen and if i
double click on them again
they go back to the the for menu
so if i uh zoom out
and um if you have a three-point mouse
wheel that's
particularly useful when modeling um if
not you
can use i mean if you get used to it you
can use a computer mouse
but um if you move the mouse wheel up
and down
that's going to zoom in and out of your
model um
if you have a laptop mouse two fingers
up down will zoom in and out of a model
so that's
uh important to do right click
and hold will
orbit around the model
and right click
and holding shift and holding right
click
and moving it will pan the model so kind
of like just pushing across like this
they are different if i double click on
perspective and i go to any of these
views
i'm not going to orbit in a top view or
front view but i would need to pan so
right click
in this case would be pan and just kind
of drag the model left or right
two fingers up down or the click wheel
will zoom in and out of the model
like that and again i can just click the
model assume all
and i could type selected or extensively
have it selected
so if i try to create another shape um
let's do a pyramid so we have this menu
that we
sort of lifted earlier and
it's gonna number all sides is one of
the options it's currently set to five
if i click that it says how many
one and four for a pyramid
and it wants the center of the pyramid
um if i do this method um so if i draw a
line
quickly across there
which is left click for each one and
right click
to complete the command so it's like
left click to
insert the geometry right click to
complete the command
and then right click when i'm not uh
doing anything it's going to repeat the
command so that's repeat the last
command
so i can go that way as well so now i
have the center of this box if i
need it for this pyramid so i'm going to
left click
the pyramid it's once the center we have
the number of sides set to four
here we could change a whole bunch of
other options as well for some other
and we can select that midpoint
and since it wants us to select a corner
and then select the end which is the
height
which i just want to enter 100 so it's
sort of balanced
so now we have a pyramid on top of the
sheep
um i want to talk about these uh snaps
now
uh which are the o snaps um if you don't
have snaps on
uh it means that you might think you're
clicking the corner or the top of a
pyramid
but you're actually just one millionth
of an inch to the left
left or you're just slightly off
when i was working in big architecture
firms that had
a lot of younger members of staff um
a lot of them did not have snaps on a
lot of the geometry was
almost perfect but if you zoomed in was
actually all over the place the
the squares weren't perfectly square and
it was really annoying so having snaps
on and having the right snaps on is
really important so there are several
types
and near point mid center intersect
perspective are the big ones after that
they kind of fade off in their relevance
if endpoint is on any type of geometry
will snap to the endpoint of any
geometry if that endpoint is
not selected it will not get there see
it says
near which is telling us what snap it's
doing and that would be an example if
i was to start that but that is not
perfectly
on that corner only if end is on will it
snap to an
end point near means it will snap to a
a curve just on the curve but not the
end point
so if that was off now i'm not even
snapping
snapping to the line and just snapping
anywhere in space
near there so my new geometry would be
quite
random so that will snap to a center
point of a pyramid or circle
center zone and midpoint
as well point is
if there are any points in the model or
um yeah just if there's any points in
the model which you kind of create at
times
um if you have two curves and you're
intersecting and want to meet at the
intersection
that's that can be on um and
perpendicular is
useful as well but i believe most of
them on most of the time
and then i'll snap uh down the bottom
will either turn all snaps off or
all snaps on there are times when you
kind of
want to create very organic geometry and
you want snaps to get out of your way
so um
if i have this pyramid i can zoom in
on different views this is the right
view in the front view
um mirror is a regular command and in
rhino
i just type mirror and it works so it
asks me for the start of
the mirror reflection and it's going to
snap to the end
point and it tells me that it's both an
end point and an intersection point
um that's fine i wanted to snap to that
point and because i have ortho on it's
only going to go horizontal
and it's going to mirror the geometry
creating another pyramid
exact same size
if i went from that side it would create
that way
so now i have this facing pyramid
and um
i can't remember what this uh sculpture
thing is
and i'm just gonna create anything but
um
[Music]
so now we can just create other types of
geometry
that we can center so let's do a
cylinder
uh we don't have a midpoint but we do
actually
have a center point that we can snap to
so you're always kind of looking to get
a
center point so left click to begin then
ask me for the radius if i get a
midpoint here i can just snap to that
and then it asks me for end of cylinder
which is the height
and i just got 100
from matching side
so i hope you'll be able to follow along
this video when it gets uploaded or
um you can't follow along as i'm
doing this talk but um follow along and
then
ask any questions and i'll be available
to answer questions anytime you want
during the week
i have to figure out where we're going
to ask them
so now that we have our kind of geometry
we can orbit around it we can zoom in
and out of it
we want to sort of keep our model
organized
so when the software is open by default
it does not have layers
and
layers and properties on
so it sort of initially creates them as
this sort of pop-up menu
if you sort of drag it and kind of needs
to be dragged from the left side of it
it will snap to the um
left hand side of the screen you may
need to sort of pull it out by just
hovering over these lines and left click
drag
it to make it wider and you can left
click drag any of these
as well just if you wanted
so everything is on this current layer
called default
um this little file here creates new
layers
and we can move or create take five new
and having layers uh on helps
sort of put different objects on
different layers to
hide them or to lock them so that
they're not snappable
if you have thousands of objects in your
model
it really helps to be able to just work
on a tiny part of it at any given time
and not have uh thousands of polygonal
points that are all going to
be snappable because if i have if you
see if i'm trying to
even just with a small amount of
geometry that i'm trying to snap to that
bottom corner
it's kind of snapping to all these
points near there so i want as little
geometry in the model
so that my snap goes to the exact point
i want it to
because if it goes to the wrong point my
geometry is going to be all wrong and
i'm going to have to go back
and recreate it so
um left click selects
any object we want and this
colorful circle is the layer properties
so this shows us
that this all the details of this object
shows us that this is currently on the
default layer
and we can move that to layer one
and then move this
bottom pyramid to layer two the top
pyramid two
layer three cancel
clicking this i don't know what this is
actually meant to be it looks like kind
of a
pie with a blue white and red layer a
slice of pie or something
um we have the option of the light bulbs
beside each layer
and the lock symbol and this black
square the black square is the color of
the layer
and this is just for modeling purposes
only if
i render this model it looks red here
but it's still
uh not it has no material it does not
have a red material this is just for
modeling
um so if i click the lock layer that
locks layer one which is our red one
and if i click a line uh it still will
snap to that layer but i can select it
i can't move it i it just sort of stays
in the background
and if i turn the light off it
disappears
oh it comes back so hiding geometry
that's still in the model it's not
deleted is
one way of focusing on exactly what you
want
um and if i click this uh pyramid
i if i wanted to just work on this or
select just the two pyramids
um i would click i could type
isolate and it isolates
everything that's not locked but okay so
isolate again
and now i just have the other stuff is
still very much in my 3d model space
it's just currently disappeared
control z in rhino has an enormous
memory it can be
manually edited in the settings but
you can click it many many times and it
will
undo the hide if we type unhide
it will unhide all objects
or show sorry yeah showing three hidden
objects
and those menus are this light bulb you
can see the left
click is hide the right click is show
and if i left click and hold it i get
the menu i can drag that out
the third one shows selected objects and
the fourth one is
isolated isolate object so that that
isolate button
is this fourth one if we wanted to click
it
and then we can just close this and
close this
so i'm just going to show all
and let's just
so um
[Music]
when um
when dragging or to move an object and
to rotate an object
and to scale an object um they are done
by just typing in
move rotate scale um there's always
multiple ways so they are
i'm not sure even where they are because
i never find them in the menus because
it's a very slow process
but you can find move rotate scale over
here it's probably here somewhere as
well but
um if i
if i left click an object and type move
and then it says point where do i want
to move it from and i like
left click this bottom corner and point
i want to move it to and i
left click this other corner it will
precisely move it
by that distance
if i was to have it selected and type
move
and select the point to move from and
then type it
distance but i'm just going to like hold
or kind of move it either slightly along
the x or slightly along the y and as
long as it's sort of in that direction
and then type 100
and sort of set in that direction and
type enter
uh it's sort of locked there and
one left click to finish and it's done
so that's one another way of doing it
in rhino and i just want to sort of make
this point that in many cases it doesn't
matter what order you do things which
makes the software really nice to use
because
um some softwares that are order
specific
don't work when you try to get them to
do it so if i was to type move
without having anything selected it
would then just ask me on the top left
corner select objects to move
then i select the object and i press
enter and then i'm back to the point
that i move it on from so
you can have the object selected first
or you can select it later it really
doesn't matter
but you're always looking to this top
left menu for what kind of instructions
does it
does the software want me to do
so um i normally i haven't done online
teaching before but i've normally sort
of
set these tasks for you to do and then
see how you're doing and then just add
more
tools later but we're just going to
cover a few more tools
for the last 10 minutes so if you want
to know the distance of something
type distance and that will work also
kind of like
google's prediction when you type a
search thing if you
just type a few letters it will show you
every command
in rhino that it thinks you're trying to
find and
sometimes if you kind of half remember a
command
you can kind of just type a few letters
and see what's available
also so if we type distance
type the first point and then type the
second point
it says that distance is 100 millimeters
which everything i'm doing right now
is 100 millimeters because i use this uh
top area a lot
i'd usually drag this down so i can see
more of it this is the history of
everything i've done so i can just
sort of see the last few commands and
there's a
scroll thing here so i can actually
scroll up the full history of every
single
thing that i've done it does remember a
lot of history
uh again that can be manually edited in
settings
so um you can kind of see on this left
hand menu
the curves different types of curves and
different types of surfaces
and different types of solids
and then join and explode so if i type
explode to a poly surface that would
turn it into
all of the surfaces that made it up so
you can see
that that is now
all these different surfaces and
selecting them
if i'm selecting multiple objects from a
distance
it gives me a pop-up menu for the
different surfaces and if they were
surfaces curves it would say surface
curve
point whatever and if there were
different layers it would show
what layer they're on it kind of makes
it slightly easier to select but if
you're too much geometry it's near
impossible
but it does add um and how much it helps
you sort of select this
and then if i select them all again um
and type join
it join surfaces and makes them back
into
polysurface
and then since we're going to do move
rotate and scale
rotate and make sure your rotate and not
rotate 3d i'll show you both but
rotate is a sort of flat rotation if i
set a point
in the top menu and you kind of see that
if if i select any point
it's going to select that point in all
the views so
that top top of the cube the selected
cube
point in perspective it's selected in
the top view
but i wouldn't know if it's that point
from that point so you kind of need to
look at multiple views to see
which point is being selected and that's
why snaps and
everything is important selecting the
right points um
[Music]
so if i want to rotate around the origin
point i can select this bottom corner
because that's the origin point uh and
then i just need to left click it's
asking for the sort of first reference
point
and then it's going to ask me the second
breakfast point and it's going to rotate
90 degrees uh again if i left click
the first corner and i sort of set the
second corner and then i just type
30 it would go 30 degrees
and i don't make some very accurate
rotations that way
rotate 3d um is going to have an
extra step in it so it wants to select
the object to rotate
i left like the object and i press enter
when done
the rotational axis and this time in
this case i'm going to select
this line here as the rotational axis
then the first reference point i'm going
to select
this point here and now it's going that
way around
so i can um and if i'm
selecting very um
obscure accesses i can sort of rotate um
beyond the orthogonal geometry but
that would be that one and ctrl c will
undo that
duplicate is another
important command so dup is the
shorthand for duplicate
and duplicate edge is the command of how
i would go
from a surface back to a curve so
that just selects that one curve and if
i press enter
and then i move it out
you can see that that's now the curve
and then if sel is the other used one
i'm going to give you guys
uh um grammar uh or vocabulary
a sheet that has all of these shorthands
for these commands
um so it's just just i mean there's not
that many when you get used to them
just duplicate select explode join
[Music]
so on so you can select all objects with
scl
all you could select just the curves in
the model by
select sel crv um
just the curves in the model and if i
had the curves and i didn't want them i
could do
sel crv and then delete which i'm going
to do because
so that is um most of what i want to
cover today
um
[Music]
one other just little trick that's kind
of important is if i am moving
stuff um
you can't just left click and drag but
this is a sort of inaccurate drag that
now
i've nowhere to reference that to say
it's precisely on the origin point or a
hundred millimeters north point it's
just
a random distance now because i just
dragged it but
if i was to do move
uh which i can type m enter or move
enter
and i select this bottom corner point
and then once the point that i can move
to
but i control click on any point
that's not going to select the final
point it's going to select
that point in 3d and then lock it to
that vertical axis
and then i can type a height above that
point
so that's sort of move
select object bottom corner
and then control click this bottom
corner
so left click control and then okay
that's locked and then i could type 50
and it would be exactly 50 meters
50 ml for whatever my units are um
so the aim of this lecture is really
just to create the shape
in
something delete that copy
enter and
drag that one up and then left click
copy
enter okay
and lastly we haven't created a sphere
but we can sort of left click
drop out this menu and say
sphere no one wants to know the center
of the sphere
and this is where this control click i
don't know if this is too complicated
too early but
if i control click on top of this uh
pyramid
now i'm locked that distance and it's
asking me
for i think it's going to ask me for the
radius so if i want a 100 millimeter on
the diameter
i'm going to do 50
and once the radius is
that's mainly just what we want to cover
today
a lot of these tools as i repeat them
throughout the
various weeks will become obvious the
idea of layers
snaps turning the snaps on at the bottom
corner here
and just creating geometry and putting
in the model um the left click and the
right clicking
of rhino just takes a while to get used
to it but just
um left click is to sort of create
geometry right click is to sort out
finish command to to orbit um
it sort of depends what you're doing
what the left and right clicking
is at that time but hopefully you'll be
able to follow this video
and draw that gentleman