[Music]
hi folks my name is ayan and i work as a
merit systems engineer here in new delhi
india
some of you might already know me from
articles featuring my project on
hackaday
or my youtube channel where i talk about
their electronics now over the past many
years i've been building programming and
flying
unmanned aerial vehicle especially
high-speed racing drones meant for fpv
drone racing and freestyle
that's the like one sitting here
now today i'm really excited to partner
with hacker day and bring you all
a fresh new class on introduction to
drones only on hacker to you
in this class i'm going to talk about
different paths that goes inside
building these drones
the physics behind it the electronics
and also the software component
that helps keeping this flying camera in
air we also want to touch upon different
applications of the drone
and how they are being used around the
world from saving wildlife
to fpv drone racing sports and also
fighting corona wireless these days
i am extremely excited to have you all
as a part of my class and looking
forward to meet you personally during
the office hours so sign up today
and let's build and fly together