[Music]
hi everyone welcome back to the
introduction to fpv drone
course on hacker u my name is ayan and
i'm going to be your course instructor
this is the class 2 and i
already hope that you have attended the
class 1 where we talk about
the physics of drones physics of flying
and different components that goes
inside building a drone and
specifically we discussed about the star
of the class that was the propellers and
in today's
class we're going to talk about the
drone frames transmitters and receiver
which are the very vital components
so if you haven't already watched the
class one i would
highly recommend you go and watch that
first and then come back to this class
so
uh because this class has some
prerequisite from class to uh class one
uh but anyways without further ado let's
start uh with today's
agenda so today we're going to be
talking about the frame selection
and how different things comes into the
picture when you are deciding uh frame
for your drone application
uh we'll also be talking about if your
there are different materials available
uh in the market there are different
options if you should diy the frame if
you should buy someone else designed
frame already off the what shelf the
number of propulsion system which are
available in a frame and what materials
are they made up of for the shape of the
frame the geometry and how to assemble
it
so that about the frame selection then
we will be talking about the
transmitters
and the receivers will talk about
frequency uh the communication link and
how the communication happens
when you send some data from your
transmitter and how the receiver
receives it and it translates to the
drone motion
of your desire uh we'll talk about
frequency
will demystify some of the myths behind
frequency power
transmission losses and latency and so
on there would be some maps involved in
it so
that would be there then we'll talk
about receiver compatibility we'll talk
about
lrs and uhf and we'll talk what they are
so for now let's deal with the short
forms here
uh then we will also talk about
telemetry and how data
is sent back to the ground station to
where the drone is
being controlled uh we'll talk about
antennas and that is a very interesting
topic
uh we'll see how we'll talk about what
is failsafe and that's
the agenda of class two uh that is a
today's class so
let's talk about the drone frame variety
and
uh when uh in the last class i mentioned
that
when i'm talking about drone i want you
to think about a quadcopter because uh
drones can be of various type as it is
in the last class it could be fixed wing
it could be helis it could be even the
military drone but
uh to be on the same page to be uh on
the same understanding level i want you
to
think of a quadcopter that is a drone
with the four
uh four rotors on the top uh so
we'll talk about drone frames and we'll
see how different drone frames are
available
for you to choose from so on the on the
screen you can see a very small
tiny drone frame which is also known as
tiny whoop
uh this is a great beginner drone it is
meant to be fly indoors
it is uh using coreless dc motor which
are really cheap and
this also support fpv as you can see
there is an fpv camera and a transmitter
so
uh there are variety of drone drone
frame available and i'll show you in the
overhead cam
of different frames i have with me but
uh what are the frame options available
let's see so this is
one of the quadcopter frame which you
might have seen uh
the most because it's uh like a standard
size frame standard shape that is the x
shape a very
common geometry when we talk about the
quadcopters we have
four motors we have landing gears this
frame seems to be made up of wood
uh we'll also discuss what are the
advantages of having
a frame made up of wood as in this photo
versus the one which is made up of
plastic as the tiny whoop here uh
you also might have seen these kinds of
frame and these kind of frame are
especially
very common in a in cinema industry
where
they meant to carry some big cameras
like dslr or even some
cinema class cameras like alexa mini
alexa
the standard one or the alexa re even
the red cameras and black magic design
studios if you
know some cameras from the film industry
you might know you might have seen these
kinds of drone
uh the landing gear which you are seeing
are quite elongated
uh they are actually being folded these
landing gears fold up
when the drones take off and this
landing gear comes back to this position
when it's landing
this is also used so it can be
it can be picked up by someone on the
ground it can be hand launched if needed
at certain areas so that is why this
elongated landing uh
gears proves importance and they they
keep the operator very safe compared to
the one on the
on the right side because you can see
there is a quite a long gap in the
landing gear and where the
the motors of the drones are so it's
it's comparatively safe
and uh we'll see about different frames
so
these uh this is a small uh dji tele
drone which you can buy off the market
and you can see
there's a small camera maybe you can see
there are coreless motors so
comparatively these two drones are
almost same they have almost same
kind of motors the brushless sorry the
coreless
dc motor they both have cameras i think
this can do hd transmission i believe
and this is a normal one but
these both are quite same but you can
see that the design it's everything is
enclosed because it's a commercial
proprietary product
uh the company don't want to reveal all
their electronics which are inside
and this is comparatively easy to get
inside so
i'm just showing you the different drone
frames so you get the idea of different
quadcopter frames available in the
market here is
another one which is used by the fpv
pilots like me for
freestyle and drone racing we'll talk
about how
these frames are different in
construction different in geometry and
what all
flight characteristics so it changes as
the frame changes
there's also this funny one i i think
it's funny
i'm not sure about you but this looks
funny it's like a very minimal
drone and this is meant for fpv racing
by the way this uh the
arms are very small the weight is very
less
because it has very less of parts
involved but it has a very high speed it
can
probably go up to 150
miles per hour or something like that
because it's very small and very
lightweight
but yes these are all the drone frames
the quadcopter frames commonly available
in the market as you can see
everyone has different application so
that is the motive of showing you this
slide
that there is not one frame which is the
best for you there is not
one frame which i can recommend you uh
to use there are
thousands of different frames uh in
terms of geometry in terms of material
in terms of how they mount the
electronics
like for example here you can see all
the electronics are exposed here it's
inside then
why someone choose to expose their
electronics versus someone choose to
hide the electronics so things like that
we're going to be discussing in today's
chapter so uh let me switch to the
overhead camera
and show you different type of drone
frames that i have so this is uh
my go-to fpv drone freestyle frame as
you can see
so this is a frame by a company called
armatan
chameleon so this is a frame from them
and
i have modified it to suit my needs and
we'll talk about modification in future
chapter so this is my go to frame
as you can see i have some other frames
with me as well as
like this so this is a tiny loop as i
showed in the ppt
here so this is the same frame but it's
disassembled right now
uh there are also a smaller one so this
is uh
almost like a fpv racing but this is a
smaller one meant for
very tight gaps and you know mostly of
the fun flying it cannot carry a gopro
or hd camera but it's
it has its own application it has its
own needs uh so yes
we'll be talking about frames more in
today's chapter so let's continue
okay so the very first thing that you
need to keep in mind when
buying a frame is the frame size so what
size you're looking for and uh
if you remember in the last chapter we
talked about the propellers and how
frames and propellers uh form a very big
constraint that you need to clear
on the very early on when you are
deciding on what application you need to
use your drone
uh so in the last uh chapter in the in
the last
class i showed that you cannot use any
size of propeller on any drone frame
because
the frame has some constraint the frame
construction in such a way that it
may not be able to spin one bigger
propeller because of space constraint
because of some other constraints so
that is why if you have chosen the
propellers already you need to choose
the drone
frame and when you're choosing a drone
frame the first thing you need to keep
in mind is the size so how do you
calculate
the size of a drone frame so the size of
a drone frame is
calculated diagonally motor to motor so
you you take any diagonal you
uh calculate the distance between these
two motors so the center of this motor
sand
uh this distance is in millimeters so uh
if you if you if you take a scale if you
uh measure the diagonal motors
in millimeter you'll get the size of the
frame so talking about uh
my frame so this is diagonally 130
millimeter frame so from one motor to
another motor diagram it's 130
millimeter
if you talk about this one this is more
like a 220
millimeter size frame from motor to
motor is 220 millimeter so
uh this is how the frame is calculated
the size of the frame is calculated and
that's
how the frame are being designed so it's
called
the drone frame classes so a very common
class is 450 size frame and when i say
450 size
frame or 450 size class frame uh what i
really mean is that
the distance from center of motor to
other diagonal motor is 450 millimeters
and that is a very common frame that is
a very common size uh more common before
the introduction of fpv drones in the
industry
uh because that is uh like the only
frame which was
easily available so if
this is like a 450 size drone you are
saying this is also somewhat like
500 class frames so yes that's how the
drone frames are being uh
sizes being decided so if you talk about
the fpv drone racing and freestyle the
the class which we use it's called 250
size frame
uh which can rotate a propeller of five
or six inches and
uh when we when we say 250 class it it
has anywhere between 210 millimeter to
270 or 280 millimeter of frame sizes
so the frame which i'm using here it is
a 220 millimeter
uh diagonally motor to motor so it comes
under 250 class
and 250 class frames are meant to rotate
propellers from let's say
four inches five inches and six inches
and so on
so that's how you decide the frame if
you have already know that you want to
have a drone which is running a
propeller of let's say five inches then
or 250 class is a good class to go if
you want a drone which can rotate let's
say 8 inches of propeller then you might
need to
go for a bigger size of frame like 450
class and so on
okay so moving ahead the second factor
that
is a deciding factor when you are going
for a drone frame is number of
propulsion system and this is a very
interesting uh
thing to know that uh why i would want
my drone to have
three motors or four motors or six
motors and what are different
characteristics of each motor so
right now i want you to forget that
thing where i talk about that drone is a
quadcopter and uh
just uh let's come back to that after
this
particular slide or or this particular
set of slides so
what is the propulsion system so a motor
and a propeller together from a
propulsion system which is actually
uh producing thrust for a drone so if
you talk about a tricopter it has a
three propulsion system that is it has
three motors so
you can see a tricopter by the name it
has three motors and
each motors on one arm so these motors
can speed up and speed down uh to give
its role and pitch access but but
what about the u-axis so we have seen in
the last uh
in the last class that to have a yaw
motion you need to
vary the speed of a diagonal motor but
this is having an odd number of motors
so how the
tricopter is able to your on on the
degree of freedom of your axis so the
answer lies in its tail so the design of
the tail is such that this
motor is mounted on a servo motor and
that servo motor rotates to give
its thrust in a particular direction and
we discuss about thrust vectoring in the
last
class so that is exactly how a tricopter
uh do its
your motion so let me find a quick video
for you
and where you can see that how tricopter
does the yaw motion and it's very
interesting to see
if you have not seen tricopter before so
let's see
so i am not having the top-notch
workstation so there might be some frame
drops i believe in the last video i've
seen some frame drops so
i'll try to mention these videos in the
hackaday uh project page so you can
refer it later so
let's see if we can find so tricopter
tail servo your motion
i just need to show you a couple of
seconds so you'll get the idea of how a
tricopter do
your so i'm
i'm getting some frame drops already so
apologies for that
but this is the best we can do so let's
see if we can find that video
okay so i think this is the one so you
can see that the
tail of the tricopter motor is mounted
on a yaw
mechanism on a servo mechanism where a
servo motor controls the direction
i'll mute this one so this is how
the assembly is being done and apologies
for the frame drop so
this is showing this entire assembly and
we are more interested in the working
so let's skip here i think this should
wait so yes that's the servo motor and
that is how the brushless dc motor the
bldc motors are used on drones are being
mounted
so now you can see that the servo has a
property that it can rotate from 0 to
180 degree and using that
it will do some thrust vectoring so how
tricopter servo works so
this video will clear the doubt how the
tricopter even though having odd number
of motors
is still able to yaw
so this is a tricopter frame and yes
there you can see
okay there you can see that how the
motor is continuously being changing the
direction
with the help of servo motor to keep it
stable even though having an odd number
of motors so that's exactly how a
tricopter
do your degree of freedom in 3d space
so engineering is fantastic and
tricopters are really good
so the question arises then why
do someone would want to build a
tricopter so
i wanted to see here so see this angle
between these two motors at the back so
this angle is so
much that there is no obstruction you
can mount anything here you can mount a
spray you can mount a camera
and there will be no obstruction from
this propellers because this is a very
very wide angle if you look here it's
more than 100 degrees so
this motor goes here this motor goes
there and still you have a lot of
angle you have a lot of clearance here
because of this clearance you can mount
a camera here
no propellers will come into into the
into the picture
you can mount a jet spray here and even
in the in in the last
last class i show you one video of a
drone ambulance
made by some university in netherlands
they're also using a version of
tricopter it's basically y6 which will
also come to but they are using a
version of tricopter
because of very same reason because this
space they are using to mount a screen
and a camera to talk to
someone who is assisting the patient so
that is why tricopter are very uh very
much used in these kinds of applications
where you need this
big clearance and you will not find this
clearance in quadcopter
as we'll see in the next slide another
reason one would want to
want to build a tricopter is a cost
because
motors are expensive propellers and
esc's are expensive
so when you are having more number of
motors you might also want to
have more chances of failure so that is
why to
reduce the cost uh you can build a
tricopter
another reason that is i know a lot of
people have built tricopter in the past
is
the yaw authority as they used to call
it because
the your mechanism is not dependent on
the speeding up and speeding down of the
motors and it depends on
a mechanical assembly a servo assembly
which is a good servo motor a metal gear
servo motor so it gives a tricopter a
very good yaw control a very
very good your authority and you can do
very quick
your maneuvers and those who have
already fly drone they know that
yaw is one of the access which is really
important
in terms of flying in terms of handling
so that is why there could be another
reason to build a tricopter so
yes uh that is a reason if you want to
build a tricopter
and yes we spend a lot of time talking
about tricopters let's move to the next
slide and we'll talk about quadcopter so
the very first thing i want you to
notice is the angle which i'm talking
about so see how this angle reduces
compared to the tricopter it has this
uh very obtuse angle and in case of
quadcopter this angle is reduces so
uh the first disadvantage of quadcopter
is a very less clearance between
two arms or two propellers so if you are
about to mount a camera here
high chances these propellers will come
into the picture
and if you have not mounted it below or
up there are high chances if you have
mounted on the center line that
propellers will come into the picture
and again if you want to mount
something else like display or camera to
talk to
someone like the drone ambulance then
that may hinder
that decision okay but talking about
quadcopters
uh one thing which you can notice is
these two motors are marked blue because
these two motors spin clockwise and
these two motors spin anti-clockwise
which you already discussed in the in
the last uh
last class
so because of that it provides a very
good stability a very
uh very stable uh performance in the air
so quadcopter
really stable drones they are
not aerodynamically stable because they
don't have some airfoil or something
which are reducing drag which we have
already discussed
but because of these two anti-clockwise
and two clockwise spinning motors they
cancel each other out and they can be
very much stable and
if you have programmed it right if you
have tuned it right then quadcopter is
one of the most stable
drone frame which you can build so yes
uh another thing which you want to build
quadcopter compared to tricopter is uh
one motor will give you more one extra
motor will give you more power and we
talked about thrusters to waitress and
it's important so
obviously you will get more stability
than the tricopter
uh next let's talk about hexacopter and
as a name today it has six
motors so the question is we already
have tricopter we already have
quadcopter
most of the problems can be solved with
it then why someone would need to
build a hexacopter one of the major
reason people
in film industry are building hexacopter
is
uh so yes before that i'll let me tell
you that hexacopters are mainly being
used in film industry where people
wants to mount big cameras where people
want to
mount expensive cinema class cameras
there you'll find hexacopter
the very first reason they want to build
hexacopter is
more power so obviously you'll have two
extra motors that will give you
uh 2x more thrust compared to the
quadcopter
uh number three is redundancy and uh
hear me out and try to understand this
concept so
you can see there are three motors which
are rotating uh clockwise and three
motor which are rotating anti-clockwise
compared to quadcopter where there are
only two sets of one set of each
so if one of the motor or is two of the
motor fails
in a hexacopter you still have a
quadcopter uh setup and it
is still very stable so what i mean by
that is if you
let's say is mounting a fifty thousand
dollars camera which is uh
not uh which is uh like the cost of a
cinema camera
you want some kind of redundancy you
want some kind of fail safe you want
some kind of feature that protects its
uh if
one motor fails or two motor fields and
that is exactly what hexacopter provides
it provides redundancy if one of your
motor or two of your motor fails you
will still be able to land it without
any problem you will still
still be able to control it in the air
so that is
one of the major reason people who want
to
want to mount expensive gears on their
drones they prefer hexacopter over
quadcopter
similarly more redundancy more power so
yes if you're still not able to have
your
payload lifted with hexacopter then you
can add two more motors to get
octocopter and you'll get
another level another layer of
redundancy so
uh let's talk about some weird shapes
and it's y6 the same
we saw in the last class in the drone
ambulance so what exactly is happening
here so
you want you don't want to uh you don't
want to change your frame you don't want
to
add keep adding motors because at one
time you will
you will exhaust the available space and
you will not have enough clearance
between the propeller so if you talk
about hexacopter see there is very less
clearance between the propellers and
uh you are pro you are basically
exhausted the
space available to you and your
propellers cannot spin so what you will
do
so engineers have come up with great
ideas that instead of mount keep
mounting motors on one axis let's mount
motor on
the below axis so you have three motors
on the up and three motors
on the below so that is how our y6 work
it is basically
two tricopter uh attached back to back
one on the top and one on the bottom uh
when you have a y6
you'll see in the tricopter all motors
spinning in the same direction but in
the y6 there are
two sets of different motors spinning on
different direction which cancel out
each other and you don't need a servo
mechanism as a tricopter did
so in the similar way uh if you can
mount a motor downwards
why not mount four motors downwards and
get an x8 that is basically two
quadcopters
and similarly you can mix and match a
number of propulsion system
and you can get these kinds of frame
configuration so so far we talked about
the drone
size and the different shapes in which
you can make the drone okay now let's
move ahead and talk about
different materials that you can use to
build drone frames so
basically no one is stopping you to use
any kind of material to build the drone
you want
but there are certain materials that are
being used already by different
drone frame manufacturers by different
people around the world and
there are certain factors that are kept
into consideration while building or
buying a drone frame and i have listed
there in a table it's a cost durability
weight and signal interference so
as i already mentioned in the last class
that when you are
talking about drones everything is a
trade-off
you will gain something but you will
lose a couple of things and vice versa
that is why you need to find a sweet
spot you need to know on what particular
ground you want to compromise on and on
what particular ground you don't want to
compromise on
and i'll give you a very uh sweet
example what i meant by that so
let's suppose i am a drone racing pilot
and uh
i am flying drone at a very high speed
so what uh
can i give up there and what i cannot
give up there so
definitely i cannot give up on the
weight i want my weight to be as
low as possible that is the only way i
will
i will be able to attain higher speeds
i can give on the cost because i know
that if i'm participating in a drone uh
races uh people will come uh there as my
competitor with all kind of
uh drone frames with all uh best kind of
material and we
are basically competing for a price
money so cost is not
a factor there uh i cannot give up on
durability because
when you are racing uh you want your
frame to be durable uh
even if there are lighter crashes you
are able to make repairs and you are
ready for the next heat and so on so
this is a
an example i want to give and talk about
the sweet finding the sweet spot
so let's compare different materials so
on the left you can see that these are
the common materials which are being
used for making drones it's a wood uh
plastic composite
g10 or fiberglass or carbon fiber so
let's talk about wood so uh wood
basically cost very less
so there are different woods material
which are being used in making drones
i am not sure but i think pinewood is
one of them i have built
of a single or a couple of wood frames
in the past
mainly for tricopter and there i only
want
it to carry a gopro and don't do any
fast maneuvers like i do with my fpv
free cell drone
so that is why i am not concerned about
the durability so wood can break easily
but because it is so cheap you can
replace it with a new part so you can
carry extra extra parts with you you can
make replaces on the go so that is why
the cost of the wood is
very low and also the durability is also
very low you crash you
uh you'll break an arm or something uh i
also want to mention here that when i
talk about durability it's not only the
frame durability but
also the protection frame provided your
electronics so
uh basically what is a drone frame it is
nothing it is a house of all your drone
electronic components and if
the frame is not durable it will break
very easily
there are high chances that it will also
break your components so for example if
your drone arms break on the arms you
have mounted your esc there may be esc
wire breakage and because the battery is
connected there may be short circuit and
your entire electronics fry and the
magic white smoke comes out
and the possibilities are endless so do
also keep that in mind that durability
is not just the frame durability but
also
the the housing the shell it provides to
other components
uh talking about the weight that is a
big uh
factor for not choosing wood as an fpv
racing or a fe freestyle drone because
the wood is very heavy
and the heaviness of wood is not
suitable for such kind of application
but on uh one good uh end there is no
signal interference
with the wood wood is not conductive so
there is no signal interference and i
will talk about signal interference when
we will talk
about the other materials now let's talk
about plastic composite so
some drone manufacturers what they did
they are using some plastic polymers
which are very durable which are also
very lightweight i think abs is one of
them
uh there is a tpu which is also flexible
so it will
never break it's like flexible materials
you can never break them
so talking about plastic composite the
cost is it depends uh
on uh different frame manufacturers and
different
polymers which are being used in cost so
cannot really come in so if it's a high
quality plastic
composite it would cost more if it's a
low grade plastic polymer it will
cost less there are some plastic which
are mixed with
resin and something i i don't know i'm
not the best uh
best guy to comment on that but yes i'm
not
really sure the cost of the plastic it
would totally depend on the material
durability wise they are good so i have
seen
some plastic frames floating in the
market and even in drone racing
we are using plastics to enforce the
frame and the plastic i'm talking about
is
tpu it's a flexible plastic so it
doesn't break and
yes they are being used and they are
quite durable so that is a good uh
thing with the plastic composite on the
weight side i cannot really comment it
depends on the density so
these frames are generally injection
molded uh
you may also find some 3d printable
frames but i'm not talking about them
particularly here i'm talking about
injection molded frame
so how much dense they are the density
of the material that
will totally uh dictate the weight of
this frame so i
uh so i've left that particular section
on the signal interference again
plastics are not
conductive so there is no signal
interference so that is a good thing
i have marked data red cross but that is
actually a good thing there is no signal
interference
that's what i mean by the red cross okay
so
moving ahead there is another material
which uh
is being used in making drone frame it's
quite
popular a couple of years back because
it's relatively cheaper than carbon
fiber and it's
g10 so compared to wood and plastic
composite it definitely
uh expensive than that but it is far
less expensive than carbon fiber
durability wise it totally depends on
the manufacturing process so what a g10
is it basically a sheet of fiberglass
and they are
sandwiched together and they are
they are pasted using epoxy and the
density of epoxy the quality of
resins used to make that epoxy and so on
uh that detects a durability so i've
left that one
uh the weight is uh very high it's so
it's
quite heavy compared to the carbon fiber
so that is a downside of it
signal interference again fiber glass is
not
conductive out of the box so there is no
much signal interference
now let's talk about carbon fiber the
most
famous the most favorite material of
building drones these days the cost is
extremely high
carbon fiber is really expensive and to
make to find good carbon fiber it's also
not an easy task and
what is basically a carbon fiber is it's
the fibers of
graphite and some other carbon composite
material and they are
made in a sheet sandwiched together
again again
stacked together and paste using epoxy
on the durability side they are very
very durable carbon fiber is one of the
most
durable component sorry durable material
which you can use to build drones and
depending on how you post process or how
you
do some kind of things before making
drone it can be more durable
for example uh what we as a drone
builder as a drone pilot do is we
chamfer the edges using a very
uh very high grade file and then we put
some
super glue on the edges and that gives
extreme durability even in crashes so
carbon fiber is extremely durable
a weight side is also good it's not very
heavy compared to g10
and wood it's a quite lightweight so
that is why it's also
another favorable thing so everything is
good in carbon fiber so what's wrong so
the wrong part is signal interference
because the carbon the graphite
is a conductive material and when you
are talking about
frequency we on the drone we have 2.4
gigahertz for our ceiling we have 5.8
gigahertz for video link
so carbon fiber if
so basically uh consider it like this so
carbon fiber is conductive but
uh the epoxy and the the coating of
the layer on the top and the bottom that
is non-conductive so
out of the box the frame you will get
that will not conduct electricity
but after some time when you are
crashing when you are
getting rid of that particular coating
on the top and on the bottom
the conductive parts the fiber of the
carbons they start appearing up and that
is
conductive in nature that can that can
do some short circuit if there is some
voltage leaking on the drone and that is
the major part which is
responsible for signal interference so
signal interference happens in the
carbon fiber if
the frame is not maintained uh so
what could be the best of this both
worlds so in the engineering everywhere
we are seeing that uh the engineers the
manufacturer
they take some good part of this world
they say some good part of this world
and they come together
so i'll show you my drone frame so i'll
quickly
uh go to this overhead camera and you
can see this is the drone frame which
i'm using so
carbon fiber very lightweight very
durable there is signal interference but
that's okay unless uh you are
maintaining a frame there is no problem
but carbon fiber is also soft at some
points and they can break
they can uh they can they can get
they can get worn out over the period of
time and what these manufacturers are
doing they are they are using metal
parts
so you can see here this is a 70 75
aerospace grid alumin aluminum and this
is being used to enforce the carbon so
this is the best of the both world
i'm getting a metal where it is
necessary
and carbon fiber on the rest of this
place so why we cannot make the frame of
this metal and why there is no metal on
my slide
that is because the metal is quite heavy
and that is not a suitable thing and
metal is conductive as well
so any leakage can cause short circuit
so but the best of the both world is
carbon fiber
uh with aerospace aluminum which will
give its
durability where it is necessary so
there is a front end collision
the aluminum will protect it otherwise
the lightweight of carbon fiber is
a goodness so that is how the frame
manufacturers are coming up with the
best of the both world and
i think that is a way ahead all right so
let's talk about
uh the quadcopter variants in drone
frame and i want you to come back to
that
same thought process that whenever
whenever i'm saying drone
you think about quadcopter the drone
frame with four motors
so before that let's talk about
different thing that changed the flying
characteristics and the first thing is
center of gravity so
uh the center of gravity is the
balancing point of
any body and the drones are no different
uh they balance at a particular point
where
uh they have equal amount of balance
in all uh direction in 3d space so uh
center of gravity
if it changes because of external part
like
battery is one of the uh one of the
component of drone which carries
most of the weight so you can change the
center of gravity of point by changing
the position of gravity uh changing the
position of battery
uh in the drone so that changes the
flying characteristics how your drone
is flying so other thing is uh if
uh your drone frame has less material
overall compared to
another frame which has uh thicker arms
if your if your drone frame has thinner
arms and so on
that would have less drag and we
discussed that in the last class
that uh the shape of the uh the shape
of the material and the amount of the
material which is exposed to a fluid
that contributes to the drag so
uh less material your drone frame have
less drag it would have
uh this is the most important part that
is the better balance is
less work for flight controller so uh in
the last class we discussed that
aerodynamically drones are unstable they
rely on sensors they rely on
on-board computers to maintain a balance
to maintain a stable flight
so if your center of gravity is off if
your drone frame is not perfectly
balanced
so more work has to be done by flight
controller to keep it balanced so
let's say if i move to the overhead
camera to show you
let's say this is your drone frame
and your center of gravity needs to be
at the center so all the motors are
doing equal part
but for some reason the frame
manufacturer was incompetent and they
designed the
frame such that the balance is at the
back so
uh ideally your drone would always be
flying tilted this way
so what your flight control have to do
is always instruct this motor to spin
relatively at higher rpm than these two
motors
so that the drone can stay at balance so
what is happening here your flight
controller have to do more work
uh your one set of motor needs to do
more work and that is a lot of work and
that is a lot of computation so overall
you will get
a very less adequate performance from
your drone so that is also
uh an intuitive unsaid thing
that goes inside when choosing a drone
frame so
better balance a better center of
gravity less material that all accounts
to a good quadcopter frame
so these are all the variants of where
you can find different quadcopter frames
so i have listed that
on the left and on the right you can see
their photos so we have
a x type quadcopter also known as
true x then we have h type then we have
hybrid x i'm sorry it's not hybrid c
it's hybrid x
then we have stretched x and then we
have dead cat so this is the true
x frame which is in the shape of x or
across
uh this is a h where it's in the shape
of the edge
so you can see there are four motors on
all these but the arrangement is quite
different
it's x here it's h here uh this
is a stretched x where you can see this
angle is more compared to this angle
while on the true x these are the
distance between these two motors and
these two motors are same
whereas in stressed extra distance
between these two motors is higher
compared to these two motors
then you you take the h you take the x
and you'll get you'll end up with hybrid
x and square is also another kind of
frame
uh another special kind of quadcopter
is a dead cat as you can see here where
the angle uh
in the front two arms is greater than
compared to the back two arms so
uh let's talk about all these frames so
again
center of gravity uh on all these frames
the x type the edge type
is different and we have discussed that
because of center of gravity there is a
different in flying characteristics and
we'll talk about that
in a bit uh less material is equal to
less drag and that is why you can see
this small quadcopter here it's called a
toothpick drone because it has very very
thin
arms a very very thin surface area
exposed to the air
and this can go up to very high speed
because of lesser drag so
this point holds valid in these kinds of
frame uh better balance is equal to less
work of flight control as we already
discussed so
uh in in the x there is a very good
balance because so the distance between
these two motors and these two motors
are same
so there is very less computation this
flat node will have to do
whereas in something like h or the
hybrid x it's it's
it's quite different and the center of
gravity and balance is a bit off
especially in the in the dead cat as you
can see there is a
shift in the center of gravity because
of different angles of back and the
front arms
so flat controller has to do more work
but the question is uh
why would anyone wants to choose these
kinds of uh different
different quadcopters all these are
quadcopters all these are four motors
we discussed that they are a tricopter
hexacopter but now uh
why quadcopters in different
configuration so
consider the truex that is one of the
most stable quadcopter the
most balanced quadcopter so that is why
if you're looking for stability you can
go with that but the downside is look at
the space in the center there is very
less space you will get to mount your
electronics
uh you cannot fit everything in the x
frame that is why
the drone manufacturers the frame
manufacturers they go for the edge
configuration there you can see you get
this bus
like structure in the center where you
can put your gps your flight controller
your video transmitter and antennas and
so on
uh when you want uh the stability of an
x and you want the space like h then you
go for the hybrid x where
the balance is like the x the stability
is like the x but you also
get more space to put all your
electronics but the downside is
then this will have more area exposed
and it will have more
drag so again i mentioned that
everything is a trade-off for when you
are building such things so you need to
find your sweet spot
uh the uh the need for stretch x is
uh so when we are racing so stretch x
are recently uh very common
these days because of drone racing uh so
because of this
weird distance between uh two set of
motor uh this stressed x kind of drones
are
very very agile very very maneuverable
in uh
in close turns and and in any proximity
flying kind of situation
uh so remember in the last uh in the in
the last
video we talked about the uh how jet
jet airplanes are using instability
design
as as their advantage for their
advantage
similarly stretched eggs because the
balance is off
the air the air will not compensate for
its stability they will not provide for
stability so it can use this instability
for its advantage and get high
uh maneuverability high agility and it's
very easy
uh in the in the shop turns for pilot
and the turns are very hard
when you're drone racing so stretched x
frame especially
are used by drone racers for the agility
purposes
uh now similarly uh if you if you see
the dead cat configuration of quadcopter
see how the arms are in different angles
so 70 degree
of uh angle between the front two arms
and almost
50 50 degree in the back to arm so why
is that uh
do you notice the small camera here so
that is the reason remember when i
talked about the quadcopter i mentioned
that
the quadcopter is not like tricopter
where you will get a very
uh very very good angle in the front so
you can mount oreo all your cameras and
the propellers will not come into
picture
uh well guess someone has a solution so
what they did they
they make the front front angle a bit
more steeper so you can mount this gopro
like cameras and still not get
propellers into picture
but the downside is you will lose some
stability it's not a perfectly x
the center of gravity is way off and the
flight controller will have to do more
work
you it's it's very you will have a very
hard time tuning it or
making it stable so that is overall
trade-off so you need to decide
uh talking about me i i fly uh this kind
of configuration hybrid x or
edge kind of for quadcopters more uh but
these days
people are shifting to truex and stretch
because of stability and
uh the components are getting smaller
and smaller
uh the receivers were used to be very
big a couple of years back
they are comparatively smaller these
days so
you can fit a lot of parts in this small
area so
people are making a shift but again you
need to decide for your own particular
application
okay so here is another table which i
created so on the left you can see
uh different drone configuration and on
the right on the columns you'll see
space
stability agility durability and field
of view
so talking about a true x frame there is
very less space
but the stability is very high agility
is also high
durability again uh depends on how good
the frame
uh manufacturer has provided to keep the
electronics safe
field of view you don't get a good field
of view because the propellers are
very close to each other each other in
the true edge everything is good except
for agility
uh because its center of gravity is
again off so
more work has to be done by flight
controllers and motors to keep it stable
and there you lose the agility uh hybrid
x
uh uh this one the frame which i use
the fpv drone pilots and freestyle
pilots and race pilot use it's
good in every department uh stretched x
again there's a space issue but
again it's good that cat you will you
get a very good field of view but uh
you have to compromise with stability
and agility
uh so a small a word about drone frame
assembly so every drone has
a different uh structure every drone has
a different structural component and
different
physical components and you need to
consult the manufacturer you need to
consult
some documentation which comes with it
to assemble it and
if you are diying your own drone frame
then you know what to do but uh
let's uh shift to an overhead camera and
i'll
show you what i'm talking about so this
frame particularly comes with a single
bottom plate and a top plate and this
particular part
you need to assemble using the screw
this frame is comparatively very easy to
assemble it just one bottom
part and a top part there are some
another unassembled frames i have
which are mostly used for drone racing
so this is one frame designed by my
friend
so this has a dual arms like structure
so you will get two arms in one
body you have a bottom plate and then
you
put some standoff and then you have a
top plate so what i'm trying to
say is that every frame is different and
when assembling a frame you need to
consult the manufacturer documentation
and if any chance if you are building
your own frame like a lot of people do
then you know what you are doing so
that concludes the drone frame selection
uh
part of this particular class and as i
already mentioned the first class i'm
i'm not going to recommend one
particular kind of frame or any part
so you know what best your application
is but i can surely show you what i
use so i use this armeton chameleon
frame which is a very good frame
and our milton is a good frame
manufacturer this comes with a lifetime
warranty
uh i'm not sponsored by admittance or
anything but that is just what i use so
if you are interested
into that okay so now moving to the next
part of this class and this is very
interesting and
a lot of things we need to discuss so
let's quickly talk about transmitters
and receivers and
let me show you how that looks so here
is my
transmitter and transmitter is your best
friend in the hobby and
when i say best friend it i mean that
this is the one thing where
i will not recommend anyone to
compromise uh you can compromise on
drone frame you can compromise on other
components you can buy cheap one but
never buy a cheap transmitter never
compromise on the transmitter please go
for
at least a good transmitter like this
one this is the fr squared
on s9d plus a bit expensive transmitter
but there are also some cheaper version
from the same company like
f sky q x7 there are also some
more cheaper one by other cheap
companies but i will not recommend that
because this is the something which is
going to be your best friend you are
using this to control your drone
this is where the signal is coming from
and if you lose the signal you will lose
the drone
you will put people life into danger so
that is why never compromise with
transmitter
so let's talk about the communication
link so transmitter
is the remote of your drone uh
transmitter is
the part which you are keeping in your
hand to control the drone
of course if you are trying to make an
autonomous drone then you don't need a
transmitter but again
there are some cases even in autonomous
zone where you need transmitter to feed
one time information or so
so transmitter is the remote which you
keep in hand which you use to control
your drone
receiver on the other hand is the
component which stays on your drone
which
receives the command the input from the
transmitter
about uh the roll pitch your access the
throttle and
how you wanted drone to react so this
stays in the drone
and they communicate together over a
radio frequency link so they work on
radio frequency
uh rf channel if you are not familiar
with the rf
frequency it's basically electromagnetic
electromagnetic carrier waves which
carry information
what kind of information so it carries
in this case it carries inform
information of a role pitch yaw and
throttle
how much yaw you want how much a degree
per second of roll you want
how much throttle you want your drone
and what's the
overall attitude you want your drone to
behave
so uh talking about the communication
link the uh transmitters and receivers
generally work on ism band that is a 2.4
gigahertz so
there is a frequency band available
which are free to use around the world
it's called ism band
your routers work on that wi-fi or
bluetooth works on that and a lot of
different
uh things which uh do not require any
license work on that
so again uh 2.4 gigahertz is a ism band
and if you are using the ism band in a
in a restrict power levels then you are
free to use without any license
uh for example uh in india where i come
from if you are using
other frequencies which are not a part
of ism band then you need a ham license
then you need a
special permission from communication
ministry of the government to do
any uh any communication on that
frequency but 2.4 gigahertz under a
certain
uh power range is free to use and yes
these transmitters have uh
have a power on which this transmits the
signal
if i talk about the uh radio transmitter
which are used in drones and
rc hobby the general uh transmitting
power it's around 10 to 15 milliwatt and
that gives you a range of around one
kilometers in a good
line of sight open space which is good
enough and we'll also talk about how to
increase that and stuff like that in
later slides
okay so uh one question which could
arise is uh
uh i want uh to fly with my friends we
have 10 friends and we all have drones
we want to fly together
will there be any interference and that
is a really good question
and to answer that it it's it's not uh
there will be no interference
but how is that possible when everyone
is flying on the same frequency
so the answers lies in a thing called
frequency hopping and what
frequency hopping means that the
transmitter and receiver
they decide that we will be keep on
changing frequencies uh
every a certain time and we will know uh
we are hopping from one frequency to
another at the same time so we can
communicate and this
uh frequency hopping allows a lot of
pilots to fly together they allow
a lot of people to use fame same
frequency without interfere interfering
one another
and there is a very very very steep very
less chances that you will end up
interfering with some other but that is
not really the case that i have seen uh
in big rc events around 200 people
flying together without any problem
and that is how frequency hopping work
so frequency hopping
is uh built into the transmitter and
receiver and when you bind the receiver
with your transmitter
they agree on the algorithm used for
frequency hopping
and that allows a lot of pilots to fly
together
so 2.4 gigahertz i told you is the ism
bandwidth this uh
radio uses but you can also use 900
megahertz and 423 megahertz depending on
where you are in the world
or if you are allowed to do that you can
also extend the
capabilities of this transmitter which
we'll also talk about in later slides
frequency limits as per local
transmission loss so that holds true for
everywhere in this world so government
controls
what frequencies you can use what
frequencies you cannot use what power
levels you use so
please consult your local radio
transmission laws before
doing anything which may land you in
problem like illegal transmission on
illegal frequencies
uh might need a ham license to transmit
certain frequencies that holds again
true if you want to do some
frequency related stuff you want to
transmit in some certain frequencies
you might need to apply for a ham
license and generally you need to give a
test you need to
give a test on electronics and antennas
and
radio frequency to get this ham license
so uh if you are serious in this hobby
and you want to continue pursuing it
it's also a good idea to take that
license as well
power of transmission is also limited by
local laws as i mentioned that these
transmitter they work on 10 to 25
milliwatt
which is good enough it will give you a
range of around one kilometer on or one
mile depending on what is the power
level
and that is a good enough range
range depends on a lot of different
factors which we will also
be talking about in great details but
one such factor is
like uh how dense uh in an area you are
flying so
if you are flying in an area with a lot
of buildings lot of concrete walls then
you will obviously have less range
compared to if you are flying in open
space where you have good line of sight
for your drone and such kind of things
and also where your antenna is facing at
a particular time and what is the
direction of receiver antenna that also
matters a lot so we'll talk about that
in coming slides now let's talk about
the frequency
uh rf power data rate and range so
uh when i when i was teaching uh about
drones in my
in my local area to my students
there is a common misconception and that
misconception is that
more the frequency more is the range so
they think that 2.4 gigahertz frequency
will give them more range compared to
900 megahertz and
that is a misconception and that is not
true in fact
at same power level and at same
modulation
lower frequencies will give you more
range example 900 megahertz will give
you more range
as compared to 2.4 gigahertz but that is
one when you are comparing apples to
apples and not apple 2 orange
make sure that when you are comparing
any frequencies
they are transmitting on same power
levels obviously
obviously if 2.4 gigahertz radio is
transmitting at higher power level you
will get more range but
if they are on same power level they are
on same they are using same modulation
technique
then lower frequencies will give you
more range also lower frequencies
wavelength are bigger and therefore they
have better penetration
so it's a simple formula c is equal to
mu lambda
c is the speed of light constant uh that
is 3 into 10 raised to the power 8 meter
per second
mu is the frequency and lambda is the
wavelength so by this formula
frequency is inversely proportional to
wavelength so more the frequency
less is the wavelength less the
frequency more is the wavelength so
obviously 900 megahertz uh
signal will have more wavelength a
bigger wavelength and
it will give better penetration
capability so it can penetrate better
through walls and
concrete structures and whatnot compared
to higher wavelengths
also more data rate is equal to less
range so uh
what i mean by that if you're
transmitting 2 megabytes 2 megabits per
second you will get
less range compared to if you're
transmitting let's say 2 kilobytes per
second so
you need to make sure that you are only
transmitting the
minimum amount of data and not
excessively using the channel
because there are certain concepts which
are involved and which
reduces the range these are out of
scope for this particular class but i'll
i'll just throw some of
the some of the dragons that you some
you may
google out if you want out of your
interest so there is a channel limit
there
is a channel bandwidth and then there is
a
link budget which hampers this
data rate and ranges so feel free to
google this out and
uh let's bring bring question to
officers if you want but
for this particular session you just
need to know that
more data rate means less range
okay so moving ahead one might ask that
if
lower frequencies are providing more
range they have better penetration
capabilities then why
are we using high frequencies then the
answer is simple so
higher frequencies that is a 2.4
gigahertz or 5 gigahertz or 5.8
gigahertz they comes under the ism band
and they are widely accepted as free to
use
band around the world so if you want to
buy one transmitter and take it anywhere
in into the world
you don't want 900 megahertz maybe you
are allowed 900 megahertz in asia but if
you are moving to us
you cannot use it because it's used by
some other cellular communication and
lower frequencies are generally used by
cellular communication that is the last
point
in india i think there is 800 megahertz
which is reserved for cellular
communication that is a mobile
communication so
obviously you cannot use that that is
a link which is uh assigned to that
particular task and you are you don't
want to
uh jump into that and and and and
jam that signals or or populate that
particular band
other reason which you might want to use
high frequency is more bandwidth
so higher frequencies gives you a more
bandwidth there are more channels
in in the bandwidth in the same
frequency range so i'll give you a
simple example if you have ever seen
the wi-fi router there are wi-fi uh
channels it says you want to transmit on
channel 11 channel 7
so if you don't you just need to log
into your router and see on what
what channel it is transmitting it is
transmitting in 2.4 gigahertz but that
is not exactly 2.4 gigahertz it can
be 2.40 gigahertz it can be 2.44
gigahertz
or it can also be 2.6 gigahertz so this
is the entire bandwidth the entire range
uh on which the frequency is divided so
more the higher frequencies gives you
more bandwidth so you have more number
of channels
it also helps in uh frequency hopping so
more number of channels you have
better you can hop these channels so
that is another reason to use high
frequencies
uh another thing is small antenna size
so lower the frequencies is the bigger
antenna size it gets and will uh will
will understand that in
in in a bit in later slides but for now
just understand that lower frequencies
need bigger and bigger for transmission
higher frequencies need smaller antenna
for transmission and you do not
want to go on a field and take a massive
three feet antenna with you
for flying a small fpv drone so that is
why you need
to have high frequencies uh and again
the last one i already mentioned at
lower frequencies are generally used for
cellular communication and you are not
allowed to transmit in that
another thing which someone may ask is
uh so this
uh radio on the left is transmitting at
10 milliwatt
so we need more range how about we
increase the power we make it let's say
one watt
so we will get more range so that is
true but you can do that so but
uh it's not uh uh it's not uh
as simple as it seems there are legal
aspects involved there are
uh authorities which are responsible to
see that you are under limit and you are
not
transmitting at very high power uh
increasing the power increases the range
but
uh there is something called inverse
square law so
it doesn't means that every signal which
you are transmitting is
receiving to your receiver uh some
signal goes to the open space
uh and they get lost so if you are
doubling uh the
if you are doubling the power you do not
double the range and that never happens
it's called inverse square law and we
will discuss some more about that in the
fpv chapter
which is due to come there is something
called antenna gains
antenna also has gain it is not an
active component antenna don't have
batteries but they have gains
something we will also discuss in the
fpv chapter not now uh
but for a rule of thumb uh just know
that
uh twice the increase in power is equal
to
3 dbi of gain of isotropic antenna
so uh so so to get uh
so to so to get 3 dbi increase of gain
you need to increase the power by 2
so that is a small match there again you
do not need to stress on that we will
talk about that later in the fpv chapter
but for now
uh these are the answer of why uh we
cannot uh
why uh we are using high frequencies and
why we cannot just simply increase the
power to get more range
uh last thing i want to talk about in
this particular site is antenna dead
zone and that is uh one topic that i
want to
take on the ipad uh that is my
whiteboard
so let me switch to that and
let me show you what i mean by antenna
dead zone
okay so i am on uh my whiteboard and i
hope i am able to draw
yes you can see so uh in a schematic an
antenna is generally
represented like this so this is an
antenna and
if you if you look on my overhead camera
and if you look on this transmitter so
this is the antenna this is also known
as a linear antenna or rubber duck
antenna
so this kind of antenna it transmits in
two direction
and this transmit in this direction
this is called a lobe and this
transmitted in this direction this is
called another lobe
so this is my antenna and this is
transmitting in this direction and this
is transmitting in this direction
and there is no transmission in this
direction
so these two direction are also known as
the dead zone
so you always want to face your antenna
uh this way if you are flying your drone
over over here or if you are flying a
drone over here
but as soon as your antenna of your
drone comes in this particular direction
or this particular direction
it will receive no signal and it will
do uh something called fail safe which
we will also be discussing in another
slide
but just for now understand that every
antenna has dead zone
and every antenna is having a particular
shape
uh the antenna which we are using on our
transmitter it's called
uh linear antenna and the property of
linear antenna is
uh it only transmits in this particular
lobes so there is no transmission
in this direction and it's like a cone
so the far you go
the far uh the cone gets bigger the far
the transmission is but as soon as
the receiver comes in these particular
directions then it may
lost the signal so make sure to always
keep your antenna
facing these this way and your drone in
this way
uh so this particular property can be
changed by changing the type of antenna
and there are more antennas like
circular polarized antennas or direction
antenna so moving on let's talk about
the number of channels so every
transmitter has some channels every
receiver has some channels so this
transmitter which i have
has 16 channels and let me move to the
overhead camera to
show you what are different channels so
so uh this uh so this one has
one channel for throttle one channel for
roll one channel for pitch one
channel for your so these are four
channels
apart from that every switch is one
channel so
these switch are also like channels
these joysticks
are also like channels these ports on
the sides on the back
so all these are channels which means
every
particular channel is sending one uh
one value of data so this is sending one
value of data data pitch
this is sending even value data that is
a role and you can program this to send
different
values for example i have programmed
this one uh to change the mode of my
drone
and we will discuss more of the drones
in software uh
class where we'll talk about what are
different modes you can fly on drone so
from for going to mode 1 to mode 2 to
mode 3 i have used this channel
so this is also sending data to my
receiver and the data will be passed to
the flight controller to do
some calculation and on the base of that
calculation the mode of the antenna will
change
also these joysticks can send some data
for example uh
this can send if i want to ascend my
drone or i want to descend my drone
in in particular intervals and whatnot
so uh
generally speaking for a drone or for
any rc hobby for planes or something you
need at least six channels so
roll pitch your throttle r4 channels and
two channels more are good to have
so information is transmitted over the
channels so every channel contain
particular type of information
for example throttle your pitch and roll
these are information which
is transmitted there are auxiliary
channels which we talked about so these
are auxiliary channels which
you can use to program what value you
want to send
these channels are multiplex and what i
mean by that is so you have one
frequency and all the information from
this channel is going to that one
particular
frequency one particular radio frequency
channel so you need to do some kind of
multiplexing so
generally it's time division
multiplexing that is all the channels
are separated by a small time interval
so it is easier for receiver to
interpret uh
what is the value of throttle what is
the value of your and so on
so receiver and transmitter can have
different number of channels for example
this
transmitter has 16 channels but this
receiver only has six channels so
you can send maximum six channels only
to this receiver if you try to send more
than six channels it will
discard the channels which are coming
after the sixth channel so that's how it
works
number of channels at rx site matters so
obviously because this is
the receiver which is going to be
mounted on the drone so this receiver is
sending data to your flight controller
so
the channels on your receiver that is
the only thing that matters you can have
16 channels here but you can only use
six channels because your receiver has a
limitation
uh now let's talk about transmitter and
receiver protocols and to understand
that
see this one diagram so this is your
radio transmitter
this is your receiver and this is your
flight controller so your receiver talks
to your flight controller
and your transmitter talks to your
receiver so on the transmitter side
you have a transmitter protocol that
means the protocol on which the receiver
and transmitter talks
and on the flight controller side you
have the receiver protocol that means
how your receiver talks to your flight
controller
so talking about the tx protocol that
defines the channel multiplexing that
defines modulation that defines uh
defines frequency hopping and error
check
so basically in a nutshell what happens
is
your transmitter and your receiver both
uses a radio frequency chip a 2.4
gigahertz
chipset and uh on the on the top of that
chipset they make their own protocol
that
how we are sending each channel we are
sending throttle first or we are sending
your first
and uh how frequently we are sending
what is uh what is the modulation we are
using what is the frequency hopping
algorithm we are using
and what is the error check we are doing
so this is mostly a digital signal
uh coming from transmitter to receiver
and this is a proprietary so these are
not
open source these are not protocols
defined by the community the
transmitter and the receiver
manufacturer they decide that protocol
so generally speaking you can find the
protocol such as d8 and d16 for
fr sky transmitters and
you can find protocols like fast if
you're using a futaba transmitter so
these are
transmitter companies which make
transmitters if you're using a spectrum
transmitter then the protocol they are
using is called dsm-2 or dsm-x
so your receiver and your transmitter
both should understand same protocol so
that is
why the compatibility comes into the
picture you cannot use any receiver with
any transmitter
they both need to understand each other
language they both need to understand
each of the protocols
that is where tx protocols are important
and
again these are propriety protocols the
manufacturer design them as they want
however on the rx side the receiver
communicates to the flight controller
and this communication link
we will see in more details in the
flight controller chapter
but for uh but for now you can you can
understand that
uh these protocol can be generic they
cannot be they cannot they cannot be
proprietary so generally speaking like
it can be generic like pulse with
modulation
pulse position modulation pulse coded
so these are kind of modulation
techniques used in signal process
using signal and digital signal
transmissions and whatnot
uh we will talk about that in fact
control chapter so don't worry
uh if if if the term scares you for now
uh it can also be proprietary like s bus
was developed by futaba and crsf is
developed by team black sheep so these
are drone manufacturers
uh it can also talk on an analog signal
like pwm and ppm are analog in nature
they are not digital signals they are
not zeros and one they are actually
analog waves which are sent out and
interpreted by the flight controller
they but it can also be digital like s
bus and i bus these are the protocols
which are
based on zeros and ones so digital is of
course
a better more reliable signal
also receiver can send data to a data to
fat controller
in a parallel fashion like for example
if this receiver has four channels
throttle pitch
yaw and roll so each channel can have
one wire of itself
throttle can have one wire going to the
flight controller from receiver
your can have another wire so each wire
carries one channel
uh that is called parallel communication
so example of parallel communication is
pwm protocol
but this receiver can also send all the
data in single wire like i have seen
here so
red is red and black are the power for
receiver and yellow is a single wire on
which
all the data of throttle your pitch roll
and auxiliary channels are transmitted
so example of serial protocols are s bus
where only one wire is used
for every for all the all the channels
while on the parallel each channel will
get
one wire of its own uh
so a few takeaways so one transmitter
can offer multiple protocols for example
there could be one transmitter in the
market which can do d8 d16 and also do
dsm ii
uh tx and rx protocol are entered are
not interdependent that means tx
protocol can be different rx protocol
can be different
uh you may have rx that speaks uh
d8 and that speaks pwm and also s bus
but they are not uh mutually dependent
and
they don't defines if you are restricted
by particularly one kind of protocols
that is not the case
uh end of the day it's all about latency
so all these protocols so
the question is why do we need all kind
of protocols why do we need d8 d16 here
why do we need pw and s bus here so it's
all about latency so as
as the demand for fast and flashed
drones fast and fast signal processing
comes into picture as more research are
happening in these areas the latency is
going down
and these new protocols they are they
provide
more real-time communication and less
latency okay so in the
uh last slide i told you that uh the
transmitter which
we are having out of the box they can
transmit at 2.4 gigahertz and 10
milliwatt
but that doesn't mean you need to
restrict on that frequencies on that
power
level uh some good transmitters like the
one i'm having here they have
something called jrb which is exactly
like an extension port
where you can put external modules and
increases its capability
so for example you can add something
called lrs which is known as long range
system or
a uhf called ultra high frequencies so
this is the kind of module i'm talking
about you can see on the photo this one
is
easy uhf by a company called immersion
rc it's an ultra high frequency
module and this is a team flagship
crossfire
an lrs module or long range system
module as it called
so on the back of the transmitter i'll
show you on my transmitter so on the
back
you you have a port which
you can open up and you can see there
are some pins on which
uh the external modules can be connected
and this uh
this increases the range and it
increases the capability
so what you are doing here is
basically uh you are increasing the
capability of a transmitter you
are changing the frequency because this
module runs on different frequency
if i remember correctly it works on 900
megahertz and it can change power level
up to 1 watt
so you can increase the power level if
you if you already have permissions to
do that
and if you have programmed the model
correctly
there are some programming might be
required some configuration might be
required but
uh basically you can change the
frequency you can change the protocol so
by default
this transmitter works on d8 protocol as
i uh told you in the last in the next
slide
but this uh module has its protocol on
its own it's called csrf
so you can do that so not every
transmitter has that so
only the good a bit expensive
transmitter provide you these
capabilities but again
it's very flexible and one of the good
thing which you can do is you can also
make some diy modules
like on the left you can see a picture
of nrf24 model which is a very common
module rf used with arduino and you can
control your own
uh homemade drones home homemade
transmitters or a small drone if you
have made using these kinds of radio so
uh overall uh these
transmitters run some open source
firmware
so if i talk about my transmitter it
runs on open source formula called open
tx
and you can change the code you can you
can you can program your own external
modules you can take uh
the advantage of this jr bay where you
can plug external modules
so basically what you are doing is you
are disabling the internal
uh radio chip and you are enabling the
external radio chip which you have
plugged
and basic uh you and based on that you
can
you can attach these modules to
different receiver different uh
antennas and you can get different
frequencies and protocol so that is
entire idea
of making it modular and extended
extending its capabilities
uh so this is a transmitter and it talks
to a receiver
but this receiver can also talk back to
transmitter and this concept is known as
telemetry
a very powerful concept and let's
understand why you want your receiver to
talk back to your transmitter so
receiver is mounting
mounted on your drone transmitter is in
your hand so why do you want your
receiver to talk to the
talk to your transmitter so it's it's
very simple you want your
you want to have the knowledge of your
drone current gps coordinates you want
to know the current battery status you
want to know the current speed
so this can be done with the receiver
but the question is so this is a small
receiver this
does not have a gps inbuilt this does
not have a
a voltage sensor or a speed sensor then
how this receiver is uh
passing this data to a transmitter back
the answer is very simple this receiver
is talking to the flight controller the
flight controller knows all these
the flight controller can send this data
to receiver and receiver can send back
to the
transmitter so basically this is not a
receiver this is a trans receiver it can
also transmit so that is a powerful
concept and this is known as telemetry
we will see in the greater details and
if i
if i go to the overhead camera
welcome to open tx you might heard that
my transmitter speaks to me so when i'm
flying with the goggles on
and i want to know my battery status i
can flick a switch like this
so for that i need to program it so i
can flick a switch like this and it will
speak the current battery to me i can
flick a switch like this and it can tell
me the current flight time so
this is the powerful concept called
telemetry that is sending data back to
the ground station and
uh receivers like this uh can do that so
you'll see two antennas
uh that is not for redundancy one
antenna is to receive and another
antenna has to transfer back to the
ground station
okay so let's
move ahead and talk about the antenna
so basically on the receiver side the
length of antenna or the shape of
antenna that doesn't really matter
uh it does matter but not at that extent
at
as it mattered to a transmitter because
a transmitter is a
sending signal out at a power and if the
receiver is
not good there is uh sorry the antenna
is not good the antenna is catchy or
the antenna is not designed properly the
there is no
impedance matching there is a concept
called impedance matching that is used
everywhere in electronics so if antenna
is not particularly matched for that
frequency
and because the transmitter is sending
signal out in some power
it can burn the transmitter because
there is no way the signal is going out
the transmitter wants the signal
to go out via an antenna but the antenna
is crappy
it will burn the transmitter so the
design of antenna is
very crucial there uh so uh you
you might be you might be thinking that
diane you told us that
on higher frequencies the antenna length
is very small that is why we use higher
frequencies
we are using 2.4 gigahertz which is very
high frequencies then why we are having
such a
big antenna and if i if i take you to
an overhead camera you can see the
length of antenna is quite big so this
is my receiver
and this is the antenna it's it's it's
quite big
as you can see here so this is my
receiver and this is the overall length
of the antenna which is quite
significant big
so you might be thinking that why is
that even though we're using high
frequencies
so i'll say that this is not a big
antenna
you just need this small length the
exposed length it is also known as the
active element of this antenna so this
is very small you can see
so only this uh exposed length matter
and this length which is covered does
not matter uh
this is just there to provide you with
some extra length so in case
you crash your drone the antenna breaks
you can peel off
this length back and you get back the
active element so this is
nothing but a co axial wire which is
having uh uh
having a wire inside it a coaxial wire
inside it
and only this exposed length matter so
you can see how small is that
only that length is better for the
transmission and this is just
to have some extra length in case you
you break this you can peel off back and
you can
get your get the good range back so
range is very sensitive to length of the
antenna and
if you cut a small piece here let's say
even one millimeter
you will get very bad range you will
start having signal losses so
uh make sure to have a proper range
uh so again the same point when i say
that uh
my transmitter and receiver works on 2.4
gigahertz i mean the 2.4 gigahertz band
and this is an entire frequency band
which may range from 2.4 to 2.8
gigahertz and so on
so uh how do we calculate this length of
this exposed antenna
how do i know what should be the length
of my exposed antenna so it's a simple
formula
so the wavelength can be calculated by
uh dividing frequency in gigahertz by
300 so
the band is 2.4 gigahertz which range
from 2.40 to 2.8
so let's take 2.44 gigahertz as the
middle band so if we divide
300 by 2.44 we will get 122.95
millimeter of wavelength and the length
of antenna is wavelength divided by 4
so 122.95 divided by 4 is equal to 31
millimeter
so 31 millimeter or 3.1 centi centimeter
is the only antenna
of active element you need on your
receiver so that's how small it is
receiver connection with the flight
controller we will discuss that in
flight controller but
i've already mentioned that there are
two kind of connection you can do
between the receiver and the flight
controller
one is the parallel where each channel
have its own
uh connection throttle has its own
connection roll has its own
uh on wire which has its own wire and so
on
in the serial there is only one wire and
all the data of all channels is
transmitted to that particular wire
there is one thing that i need to
mention that is called failsafe that i
already showed you on the whiteboard
that there that this antenna transmits
in two lobes on the left and the side
because it's designed that way
so on the center there is a dead zone
and
that is where the fails have happened so
what is the fail safe so
uh this transmitter and receiver had a
particular range let's say it has one
kilometer range and if you exceed that
range if you take a drone below
uh beyond one kilometer you will lose
the signal or you will lose the signal
if you come into the dead zone
so one thing in the drone which will
trigger
uh when you lose the signal to your
transmitter it's called fail safe so
what is a space if
failsafe is a situation which happens
when uh the transmitter and receiver can
no longer communicate
maybe they are out of range maybe there
is some interference whatever
they are not able to communicate and a
situation of failsafe happen
as a drone builder as a drone pilot you
have
the liberty to choose what you want to
do when the situation happen
so one thing which you want to do is cut
off the motor and let the drone fall
as a rock one thing you can do is let
the drone fly
as the same altitude is flying
one thing you can do is let the drone
ascend very slowly
so depending on that you can program in
your flight controller what you want to
do when the situation of fails have
happen
uh the last thing i want to show we need
to go to the overhead camera
so i have i have done a small setup here
so this is my transmitter
and i have one receiver here uh which is
connected to two motors
uh one servo motor and one brushless dc
motor
so how do my transmitter know
so how do my transmitter know that it
needs to talk to this receiver so we
need to do something called binding of
receiver
so i need to bind my receiver to my
transmitter and every receiver has
different process to bind it
in this particular one i don't remember
but there is one button or you need to
short some
some pins and connect to the battery for
example in this receiver there is one
button here
you need to you need to put your
transmitter in binding mode you need to
press the button and you need to power
it on and it will bind together
uh so you need to consult the
documentation of your particular
transmitter and your receiver
and you can able to bind that but over
here i am already
bounded these two so this receiver is
this receiver is bounded to my
transmitter and i want to show how it
rotates this motor so i need to give
power to this
okay so i have bounded this receiver to
my transmitter already
uh this is the receiver and this is
bounded to my transmitter already you
can see the green light
and i have connected the servo motor to
the roll uh
access so if i happen if i do roll
you can see the servo is moving
on the roll axis there will be no
another movement on any other axis
because
it is on the role access so i have
connected my role access to the servo
and i have connected throttle to this
motor
you can see as i give throttle the motor
signal
now i want to show you the situation
where what i will do i will
power up the motor and i will switch off
the transmitter and see what will happen
so i'll power up the motor
and i switch and i switch off my
transmitter
and you see as soon as the transmission
signal is lost the trans the motor
stopped
that was all for today's class i hope
you
get to know a lot of different things
about frequency
and transmitters and frame selection and
there are some myths
you would be having before that that is
now solved so
thank you very much for joining and i
look forward to seeing you all in the
office hours
thank you very much and see you in the
next class