[Music]
hello everybody
thanks for coming to the third quantum
computing session and hackaday
we do this every sunday this time for 30
minutes
today i know it's easter a lot of people
are off
but everyone's staying at home anyways
so
uh i hope this is fun so people wouldn't
consider this as work
the class today will talk about
entanglement but this is an overview of
what happens in this sunday classes
we have 30 minutes each day
talking about one topic and that topic
is based on
my comics of the week if you have
already
followed my project on hackaday or on
social media you
know that today we're going to talk
about entanglement
because this is the third class
we have already covered a few
basic concepts and if you miss them
don't worry there's the link to the
hackaday
project also brian has posted it
in the chat you can follow and find
the links to the recordings from before
in the files section and i also
include a couple links useful links that
you can look up
for self learning and we also gonna use
these later
did someone want to ask a question just
now
okay let's put questions in the chat and
i will
go through the materials on the slides
with you
uh remember that we talked about
superposition before
this is from last week we had
some examples showing we can
have different numbers of qubits and
then
that would determine how many
configurations we will have
so remember if we have one qubit
it can have two states in superposition
if we
have two qubits then we will have
four configurations in superposition
if we have three that would be eight so
n qubits will have 2 to the n possible
configurations it scales
exponentially
so that gives us a
degree of freedom to manipulate our
system
remember when we talked about
interference
last time when we have a
superposition enabled interference that
was
one of the strange things about quantum
mechanics
now because of superposition is
possible in quantum mechanics there's
yet another strange thing today
is entanglement so what is it
if we have a two qubit
system we would have four different
types of configurations that also means
that we could
have defined certain configurations to
be
in superposition so
there are two very interesting special
states that we can put the system in
if we have the
two qubits in the same
either zero or one we have this option
to have these two in superposition so
your first qubit could be zero second
cubit could be zero
or plus the superposition of
the first qubit being one and the second
cubit being one
so this is one possibility and another
possibility is that
they are different so first qubit and
second
qubit are opposite then you could have a
zero one plus one zero state
so it's basically this four but then
you can assign
b and c to be zero or a and b to be zero
so you get these two and why is it
special so look at this then if you want
to do an experiment
you just look at one qubit say the first
qubit if you measure it to be
zero then you don't have to do a
measurement of
the second qubit you already know your
second qubit would be zero
because each of this is
represented with a amplitude
we remember is squared is the
probability
if your first qubit is already zero you
know there's no
possibility that you will have this
configuration so you would know that
your second qubit is
must be zero you could do the same thing
with your second qubit you just measure
the second qubit you would know what
your first cubit would be
and in this case similarly if you have
you know
you have entangled set
then if you measure your qubit to be
zero
first one then you know your second one
will be one
and vice versa this is
called entanglement basically means the
qubits are correlated
when you do the measurements their
results will be correlated
and we have two special entangled
oh sorry four special entangled states
when you have two
qubits these are called the bowel states
it's showing you that so plus
or minus of the 0 1 and
1 0 combination or a plus
or minus zero zero one one so the
special
thing about it is that the amplitude
here now is equal
so it's equally likely to get um
the either outcome
so if you take these as an example
if your first qubit when you do the
measurement is zero
just pick pick one of the states
for example this one with a plus
then you know you would definitely get
a second qubit to be zero
with the probability of half and oh
and remember why do we have a square
root here
because of the normalization condition
we have to
make sure that all the probability add
up to
one so while you have
two super two states in superposition
that would be a square root of two
and if you measure your first qubit to
be
one then it's not possible to be this
one
it will be this one here so
your probability will be
half to get one one state out
so again this is
a repeat to say that if
you measure one qubit you would know the
other qubit without even looking at it
and mathematically what does
entanglement mean
we can write everything out nicely
into this vector which we introduced
in the first class so
remember that if we had two independent
qubits how you represent the system
is to do a tensor product so
these could be your two qubits and you
do a tensor product to write out
your resulted vector four by one vector
and that is to say if you have two
separate qubits and you put them
together
they could form a system
using a tensor product but if
you already have two qubits that's
entangled
it's impossible to break them apart into
two
independent qubits so if you try to
equate
this four by one qubit this is
uh the one of the bell states
and then equate it to a representation
this way
you will never get a solution
it is impossible to write this state
the bell state into a
individually separated two qubits
so that's how you can also test
if something is in entanglement is that
once they are entangled they cannot be
separated
into two independent cupids anymore
there is a very common mistake when
people talk about
entanglement it always sounds very
strange
when people say if we have cubits
entangled
you can separate them infinitely far
away
and if you change one of them the other
one would automatically
change that's not right that's not true
that cannot happen that would imply that
information can transfer
faster than light you have two
cubits infinitely far away and if this
one
changes and the other one immediately
feels the change and change itself
that's a information transfer that's
prohibited we know that
information cannot travel faster than
like
but so many people talked about this
when they mention entanglement so next
time if they
say this then you know that they don't
actually understand
quantum mechanics or quantum computing
so the picture of
measurement has the concept of
measurement has to be
in the picture or at least you know that
what entanglement
implies is a correlation between your
qubits
so
what happens is when you have two
entangled qubits
you if you poke this one i that's what i
was trying to show
is the other one doesn't feel anything
and if you separate them far apart
nothing is changing if because
the two cubits are still correlated
the correlation entanglement is not
a function of distance so
if you do a measurement of your qubits
infinitely
far away you would know the answer to
the other one
without looking at it that that's what
it is that's all it is
there's no spooky interaction as people
say
in popular science there's just no
interaction there if they are entangled
and separated
then nothing is changing
so we can use this to make
useful things you
if you can prepare a pair of
entangled qubits and separate them
to two different people one of them
if they take a measurement of their
qubit
they can know what the other person will
get when they make a measurement
so here alice and bob prepared
a pair of bell states they separated
them
and added if she measures and gets
zero she knows if bob measures he will
get a 1
because the state will be
in this one
now if she wants him to obtain 0
instead she will just ask him to flip
his cupid
and there are ways to flip cupid's which
we'll talk later
so this is basically
what entanglement implies is very very
useful we actually use it in every
single
algorithm
so this is repeating the idea there
you start with one of the entangled
pair alice makes a measurement
and she will know bob has a particular
one
and if bob measures his
he would know what alice has and if we
can entangle two cubits there's no
reason we cannot entangle
more more qubits so a bell state
counterpart for multiple qubits
is the gh set states
when you have three this is the simplest
form of g h flat states
is these one one one and zero zero zero
in superposition and if you have n
qubits you can just have
many many many of them and put them into
this
particular state to entangle them so
this is a shorthand
mathematical way to write this
you can imagine even though it cannot
communicate it cannot
be used to communicate information
faster than like it can still be
useful for example in encryption
you would know if you establish a key
using entangled qubits you know what the
other person will have
so you can encrypt your message and
decrypt your message
using a specific sequence
and some other examples also include
teleportation
this is one of the ways to demonstrate
uh if you have entanglement between your
qubits
but it also is a way of communication
so i just said that they cannot be used
to
communicate communicate faster than
light
so there needs to be some information
that's transferred
using classical ways of communicating
so i'm not showing you any details of
the
this algorithm yet i'm just using this
to tell a story with cartoon we'll go
into this
to see this step by step once we learn
how to manipulate cubits
so just look at this picture here what
is happening is when alice and bob they
pre-prepare
the bell state they separate them and
they go as far
away as they want
then alice now
has one cupid but if she wants bob to
know about
some unknown qubit that she later
obtains
she can actually entangle her now
two qubits and then she can do a
measurement of
her qubits and she finds out
the answer and call bob
not directly telling him what she has
but telling him what to do with his
cupid
when bob does the measurement he will
get
the same new qubit that alice
obtained using his only cubit
so that's what teleportation is about
it's basically because with
a starting point any of the ball states
you would be able to build out
a table or grid of what to do to bob's
qubit you know everything
in between in this grid and
you can just do a manipulation to bob's
qubit to obtain
what alice wants him to know we'll go
into this x
and z later these are gates that's
the way to apply a change to a qubit
so that would be our next few sessions
is about
how you can manipulate qubits
another similar algorithm
is the super dense coding it's kind of
the opposite so what just now
alice and bob did was they
exchanged classical information in order
to exchange quantum information so they
did not directly send qubits
they send classical information by
calling bob or
sending him a letter but in effect
bob gets the quantum information alice
wants him to know
super dense coding is kind of the
opposite where
they were sending quantum information
but what alice wants bobs to note is
a classical piece of information so
again you have to know
what type of gate you have to establish
a table of possible outcomes
when they prepare a
entangled pair alice
can then come up with a way to
let bob obtain her classical information
by sending him uh her
her cubit after she does a
manipulation on her qubit so
bob can obtain like classical
informations like zero zero
zero one one zero one one uh it
is cost super dense because they are
sending one qubit but then
it contains information of two classical
bits
so this is another place where
entanglement is used
so i'm just showing some of these
simple kind of toy models
to show that they are useful
if you can come up with clever
algorithms
and entanglement is used in every
algorithm we're going to talk about
and coming back to this multiple qubits
i just want people to absorb this here
if you have n
qubits you can entangle them all
and if n equals to 5 that would be
2 to the power of sorry if n equals to
500 that would be 2 to the power of 500
possible states your system could be in
that's
the total is more than the number of
atoms in the universe
yet only
500 qubits are needed to
contain all these information if you
entangle all of them
and that's what nature has been doing
that's
what our universe is having a lot of
fundamental quantum particles that are
in entanglement and they are just doing
this
calculation behind our back with
when we do a observation it
we use the term collapse last week but
it's really a
result of interference we are making
a observation to find out what's the
most possible
outcome but that at the same time all
these
particles are doing their own thing
without us looking so that's
really cool and then the last
piece is a word of caution here
is that entanglement can be can be
very useful if we know what we're doing
if we establish our organism that
we know each step what the qubits
would do then we will get the
results very efficiently if we do one
measurement
you will know what the rest of your
system will be at
but entanglement can be also very
dangerous
because your qubit your system has to be
perfectly isolated
if you prepare this very nice entangled
system you want them to be
totally uninterfered with your
environment
if there is any uh imperfection
it could very easily entangle with its
environment
and the environment is also made up of
all those quantum
particles so there's
you have to have prevention but then
measurement is an act
of destroying your
system so because
all of the measurement devices are made
of physical things
and they're all at the fundamental level
of quantum
then when you approach your system with
your measurement device
it would be entangled with your system
as well
so you have to build in this mess up
in your measurement in order to get
the correct information you need so
there's a huge
field about error correction when you do
measurement or you have unintended
errors when the cube is entangled with
its environment you have to be very very
careful
and have additional circuitry building
to correct the errors that could be
caused by the environment
so we will also talk a bit more about
this
in the hardware sessions because
different types of hardware will have a
different tendency
to is
entanglement with its environment
so that's what we're gonna show today