[Music]
hey everyone
uh welcome back week five the final week
right here prototyping mechanical
engineering i am will fisher and i
am your guide through the world of
mechanical engineering here
um today we're going to be talking about
uh motion and gears and
moving stuff and all that sort of thing
uh which should be really fun i just
want to remind everyone before we hop
in um that there are some quizzes and so
you if you if you wish to take them i
believe hackaday will give you like a
certification that you've completed the
course
if you can pass those quizzes i realize
given how quickly we move through all
this material it may be helpful to go
and watch youtube uh of the these
classes afterwards so you can kind of
get everything um
but uh but those you can get that
certification going
so um without further ado uh we're gonna
jump right on in just
uh to introduce myself again my name is
will fisher i am
a mechanical engineer i've been doing
engineering for more than a decade now
in a variety of different fields
i'm a freelancer so if you have a
project you can hire me um
and i also teach so i can do that as
well
uh let's jump in it's movie break time
because we're only
a bit in uh this one i like a lot
hopefully i've got my audio shared so i
want to make sure that i've got my
audio shared on this
um yeah sorry i was not sharing computer
sound
because this one is a beautiful thing
the missile knows where it is at all
times
it knows this because it knows where it
isn't by subtracting where it is from
where it isn't
or where it isn't from where it is
whichever is greater
it obtains a difference or deviation
okay
so i have this in there because i think
it's really funny um
and uh i just figure um it's a good way
to think about motion you know
and a lot of times you're thinking about
where you are but sometimes you think
about where you're not
and how to get there and it's an
interesting frame of reference to use i
mean this is clearly
kind of comical uh comical ish um
uh but it's good to have that kind of
reference so we'll move right on in
to a motion and then after that we'll
look at power transmission and what i
mean by that is how you get power from
one thing to another
like a motor into a propeller something
like that
um then we'll talk about linear
actuation so that's
the kind of where your power comes from
and rotary actuation as well so that's
stuff moving in a line as compared to
stuff rotating around
um cool let's go into the intro stuff
today is going to be um pretty heavy on
math but it's all
algebra um and so it will be difficult
math just a lot of it
um so we'll jump in on that um
first of all i want to define motion
motion is just
stuff with mass and that's important
moving from one place to another and
mass
uh follows newton's laws specifically
inertia
um and that is a body at rest will stay
at rest unless
acted upon otherwise and a body in
motion will stay in motion unless acted
upon otherwise and
that's a pretty important thing that uh
that inertia is kind of the
mechanical and physical space equivalent
of
induction in the electrical world and
it's just this idea that once you're
doing something it's going to stay doing
that thing whether it's still
or motion the second one is one newton's
second law is one we're going to spend a
lot of time with today
and that is uh force is equal to the
mass times the acceleration
um and so that you can play either
direction you can either start with an
acceleration of mass and figure out how
much force went in
or you start with a force and play it
the other direction we'll spend a lot
more time there um and the final one is
every action has an equal but opposing
reaction so example
for example you exert a force on the
floor uh
assuming you're on a floor um and it
exerts an equal force
back up in the other direction and in
the case that those
forces were not equal there would be
motion that f equals m a
so so that's an important way to think
about things though the map we're
working on today won't go too far
into that um and
today's class will be a warming blend of
practical and theoretical a lot of
theoretical is going to be the
mathematical side of things
um and as we jump in i do want to take a
quick note here of this
image over here on the right side that's
what we mechanical engineers call a free
body diagram
and that's where you take something by
the center of mass so here you have
a block on a inclined plane with pulley
and so these are the two masses that you
see and you can look at all of the
different forces that are at play here
and how they
how they balance out and that's a really
important way to think about
uh whether or not stuff is going to move
around on you and so you'll see those a
couple of times
further on in the presentation but just
give you an idea of what it is you're
looking at that's what those
are okay newton's second law like i said
we're going to get
right into the depth of this so it's
that force equals mass times
acceleration
um acceleration is uh the
the movement of something increasing in
speed
um so you have distance and then
distance per time
is rate or velocity if it has a
direction to it and
velocity per time is acceleration so
it's the
second time derivative of the position
mass is the material that is a property
that
all material has which is it weighs
something and
by in this case its weight is the force
of gravity on it i'll
talk about that a little bit more in a
second just to kind of clarify i realize
a lot of these
things kind of uh get confused
anyway so what we look at the unit of
force in in the si world is the newton
it's abbreviated n um and that's a
kilogram uh times a meter per second
squared
and that's just a very standard unit and
we're going to look at units as a way of
explaining phenomena and that kind of
helps us all
get get through it um
so um torque is uh
with the same exact principle but taken
into a rotational frame so we as
mechanical engineers
oftentimes things spin and find things
spinning around and so
it's helpful to just multiply that stuff
by the radius it is away
so and that happens for angular velocity
as well
um and it turns out that that radius
component drops away but if it doesn't
drop away you have different forces
acting at different radiuses away from a
thing
then that's a really important thing to
calculate in the way that you rotate
something so a torque very close to the
shaft
um can be counteracted by a relatively
minor force far away from the shaft
of large torque i'm not going to talk
too much about
torque and the rotational frame simply
because we just don't have time for that
so i'm going to do everything pretty
much in a linear and translational thing
frame and you can extrapolate that to
your rotational frame on your own
work is an important component of this
as well and that's the product of force
which is mass times acceleration
times the distance over which it
operates and so um
normally this would be you would get
into the calculus of this and it would
be integrated over the distance
but in the case of something that is
constant the integration comes out to
just be multiplication which is really
convenient for us so we're not going to
do anything more complicated than that
we'll just give you an idea of what's
deeper under the hood here
um and that unit is a joule a joule is a
newton times a meter
and so um oddly enough
that newton times the meter is the same
as you would get from a
torque over here which is also a newton
meter
but in the case of work you're thinking
about it the force
operating over that entire thing so so
while they look like the same unit they
are in fact
not the same unit so here you have
you've added that meter into the top so
if you look closely there you'll see
that i've squared my m
so it's kilogram times a meter squared
per second squared
cool moving right along
energy is in the same units
as work in joules and it can be used to
do work though it isn't necessarily
the same thing because it can be a lot
of different things
energy can also measure losses to heat
and it is always conserved and what that
is
is that in a system that you have the
amount of energy that goes into it will
always come out
in some form eventually um
and so that's a really important thing
but if you think about
uh about this if i'm doing work i'm
putting some work
in maybe it's electrical energy and it's
coming out as rotational energy there
will always be
some loss there towards you nothing has
what we call perfect efficiency so
efficiency is down there at the bottom
efficiency
is commonly used with that kind of loopy
end
shape which is cool and that is
a ratio of the useful energy out from
your system so whether that's you're
compressing a spring or
you've rotated the thing a certain
number of revolutions or something
divided by that energy and so it's
always going to be a number
between zero and one it'll never be
above one
if it is come find me we got patents to
file
um but if it's if it's not it should be
in that range now it can get very very
very close to one
and sometimes you find things when
something is quote
ideal then you just assume it has an
energy
an efficiency of one but in reality
nothing has perfect efficiency because
reality is
not what theory tells it it should be
okay so let's think about uh
what we've got to to calculate here so
there's a lot of different types of
energy do i
skip a slide somehow no i guess not
there are there are several different
types of
uh energy here um the first is that
we're going to talk about is kinetic
energy and so that is
uh like how how much energy you have in
a moving object so if you have a car
moving at a specific speed
the the kinetic energy in the car is
modeled as one-half times the mass of
the car
times the square of the velocity of the
car
if you have that car go off an ideal
ramp a perfectly efficient ramp
goes straight up it will you can guess
the height of it
based on the mass times the acceleration
of gravity times the height that's
potential energy
gravitational potential energy it's
going to then fall right back down and
assuming it hits its ramp
and there's no friction it will end up
going the other direction at the same
speed which is kind of a comical thing
uh we call this the roadrunner effect um
but that is actually
and you can calculate the height it goes
up to and you know that it was it comes
back down assuming that everything comes
back down the right way
and there's no friction in the system so
no energy lost heat
um then it will end up moving back out
of the ramp at the same velocity that
came
into the ramp wild okay that's the
conservation of energy at work
you can also store potential energy in a
whole bunch of other different ways
for example uh mechanical energy can be
stored in springs
so you can press compress compress
compress compress and then
when it releases it can create this fast
moving
object uh so that would be something
like if you have a spring-loaded
catapult
or like a trebuchet uses the
gravitational potential energy
counterbalances it and then it converts
all that pretty efficiently into
velocity of a much smaller
mass which is cool that's how it can
launch so far um
you can do the same thing with like um
like a bow and arrow you have this kind
of spring potential
as you draw it and then as you release
it out it goes
into that kinetic energy so this can be
a really convenient way to calculate
stuff
um there's other convey potential energy
stored in other places
the potential energy inside of a bullet
is stored chemically
for instance and then it explodes and
that creates a large amount of energy
which then you convert through to be
kinetic energy in the case of a firearm
and there's other ways out there as well
i won't get into
so let's take a look at an example here
so let's say we've got a spring we're
going to
crank it all the way down we're going to
put a mass on top of it
and then we're going to release it and
we're going to see how high our mass
goes
okay so throughout this entire thing
we're going to assume
that everything is operating with
perfect efficiency so that we can serve
energy throughout the entire
uh the entire entire
example so we're going to start with our
potential energy from a spring
that k is a spring constant and you can
that is a listed property when you
purchase a spring it'll tell you
the spring constant um so we're just
going to choose i chose here arbitrarily
a spring constant of 12.
um and then we're going to see what
happens as it just goes through
the system um so we have this thing
we're going to see what happens if we
put a one kilo object
on top of this spring that we've now
compressed half of a meter
um and then we're going to see how high
it goes when it comes out the top so you
can see there that i've taken this
this value here um 12 times
point point five squared so that's uh
what 1.5
joules is my unit here and then
i'm going to see what 1.5 joules of
energy will do in terms of the launch
velocity that is the velocity that's
moving right as it leaves the spring
and then i'm going to convert that
velocity into height i could convert
straight from the spring energy to
height but i'm curious to know how fast
my object
is leaving uh the thing so it turns out
to be the square root of three so if we
if we multiply that two on through
that's uh and then we
take the square root so our velocity is
the square root of three which is about
1.73 meters per second
which is pretty quick when you think
about that that's fast
um so we want to see how high this one
kilo mass is going to go
so the gravitation uh like the
acceleration of gravity
at sea level on earth is 9.81 meters per
second squared that's just how it is
you can look that up in a table um
[Music]
but uh but then we can figure out our
height so we now have an object that's
moving
that we know has 1.5 joules it's moving
at 1.73 meters per second
so we divide that 1.5 joules by our
acceleration
to get our height which is 0.15 meters
so this thing's pretty heavy so it's not
actually going to go all that high it's
going to launch really fast and then
it's going to
kind of ground right back into the earth
there
cool so
moving along power is kind of the next
thing
here that we want to that we want to
look at
and so power is what happens when you
look at work over a period of time
and so when i say over a period of time
um
i'm dividing by my time so it's an
average amount of power
it's an of work per time and you would
do this with calculus normally just like
the other things
but we're not getting into that today so
the unit of power is the watt named
after james watt who refined the steam
engine into a usable form and
spurred the industrial revolution
interesting dude look him up
and it's a joule per second so what that
means is we now have
kilograms times meters squared over
seconds to the third
and uh that is kind of a useful measure
for us
uh in terms of measuring the amount of
power in a system over a long period of
time
um we'll come back to that i think i
should have reviewed my slides a little
more closely this afternoon
um so gravity is an acceleration
it's not it's it creates a force based
on the mass
um and the gravity at sea level is this
9.81 meters per second squared
so the force of gravity is that 9.81
times our mass that's why heavy object
applies more force if i put a feather on
my finger it doesn't weigh much
um so the weight the force that it
creates is not very high but if i
increase that mass
to a 20 kilo boat anchor
then it's going to create quite a lot of
force on my hand also
so we can look at the work done to raise
that
a 10 kilo object one meter so we
multiply that out
the work of gravity is 9.81
that acceleration we had times
the 10 kilo weight
times 1 which is our 1 meter and that's
98.1 joules so that gives you an idea of
how much power
there and let's say we wanted to raise
that in 30 seconds we're now going to
take that 98.1 joules
and divide it by our 30 seconds and that
would require
uh 3.27 watts and you think that's not
very much and it doesn't sound like much
but
a 10 kilo object is pretty heavy 30
seconds is a long time
like i've spent less than 30 seconds so
far on this slide
it is creeping up there right so
so you can use a relatively small motor
to move a lot of weight
um potentially and that's why i'm
talking about this stuff now is when we
think about how we size our motors later
on
we'll want to think about that in terms
of watts and so you want to figure out
the job you have to do and then spec
your motor accordingly
so that's why we're talking about all
this math now
okay so let's check and do a sanity
check on this and see if our units make
sense
so we have all of these things we're
going to take a look at the units so
we have uh we can take our 9.81 meters
per second squared
kilogram our meter our second we could
we can take all of our numbers out
and we can say okay so there's a meters
per meter squared kilograms and seconds
cubed here oh look our there's our watts
out there at the end kilogram meters
squared per second cubed
voila we have our watts right there
beautiful that's a nice way to check and
make sure all your units are working out
um to make sure you haven't accidentally
multiplied by 10 use centimeters instead
of meters so on and so forth
this is a really convenient way to make
sure you're doing it right
power comes with trade-offs as always um
as we know from our formula
um we have this kind of
this divisor in the middle so we can
start with a medium amount of power
and do a medium amount of work in a
medium amount of time if we want to do a
lot more work
we can increase the amount of time the
same amount
so we can spend five watts to do you
know
five joules in one second or
we can do 50 joules in 10 seconds we
just the same
amount of power going in
is used over a longer duration to do
more work same thing goes exactly in the
other direction that's that third line
there
we want to do a little tiny bit of work
in a little tiny time
we can do the same thing but if we want
to do if we want to decrease the time in
which it takes us to do our
work without reducing the amount of work
we do we have to
increase our power and the same thing
goes the other direction right this kind
of makes sense
uh intuitively but the nice thing is
there's a mathematical relationship here
that allows us to model it and it's it's
relatively easy to
to use moving along to something else
okay so i realize i am moving through
this material really quickly and that's
because i want to get to
uh some of the really exciting stuff in
the power transmission parts
stability and control this is a
trade-off also we'll talk about that in
a slide or two
and i want to say you know you use
control systems to
to move things where you want them to be
stability is the tendency to stay where
you are
it works a lot like inertia right um
if you want something to fly straight
you want it to be pretty stable so
like in big cargo aircraft they put the
fuselage below the wings and then the
weight
the force of weight keeps that plane
very steady as it's flying
you don't want that for a fighter
because you want to be able to move very
quickly those cargo
planes don't roll over very quickly and
they certainly don't bank very quickly
so with a fighter you you put everything
pretty close to the center of mass
so that you can rotate and and pitch
really quickly
the result of that is that you have very
good control but very low stability
um and in fact these are f-18s shown
here
when they initially rolled these out the
pilots would get unnerved because
there's an electronic control system
that would control the
ailerons the flaps on the back of the
planes and they would look outside at
certain speeds and they would be
fluttering in the wind and it wasn't
actually that they were fluttering is
that the computer control system was
moving them to maintain that stability
artificially
even on a straight flight so that they
could have that really high level of
control later on when they need to be
doing
extremely uh nimble acro aerobatics
as they're as they're called um and just
uh kind of as you think about this you
can think about the as a pendulum right
um if i want to be able to move that
pendulum with a motor
i can shorten my length or lower my mass
and i can move it more quickly but the
thing is it's then much stable if the
wind comes along it'll blow that much
more easily than it would
if i have a big weight on the end
cool so here's the same thing you can
think about
and control instability that we talked
about earlier kind of with power
if you want to increase your stability
you're going to by default for the same
amount of power decrease your control
so these are inversely correlated um
and so same thing goes the other
direction or you can crank up your power
get a lot of stability and the same
amount of control or a lot of control
the same amount of stability right it's
all kind of
intuitively makes sense i hope now
cool let's take a look at some control
systems here
uh we'll move along here this is a
control system uh that has one of the
classic
things called an inverted pendulum so
we're going to watch it here
as it moves it's going to try and swing
the pendulum up to the upright position
just by moving back and forth
this is really hard to do as a human
look at that ah
so nice but that
that pivot that you see is actually a
free pivot and that's one of the classic
problems of control systems is how
efficiently can you do this thing
turns out that's a really difficult
mathematical question we're not gonna
um we're not gonna get to it but it
requires uh
some knowledge about control systems i'm
just going to touch briefly on this
and this is one of those slides that's
like an entire phd
entire phds are done this is an entire
field control theory is an entire field
that people spend their lives
researching and i'm doing it in a slide
so i'm sorry to those people who do that
stuff because you are working real hard
so this is uh hopefully an answer to the
fundamental question of how do i get
something to where i want it to be and
this is a fundamental
part of robotics also because as you try
to have an arm grab a thing
you need to know where the arm is and
you want to get to that location
and so you you can do this one of two
ways
if you don't have information about your
system you could kind of dead reckon and
that's called open loop control
and so that's if i like close my eyes
and i just reach out for a thing
and try to grab it and i don't know
where it is at all that's open loop
control that can work
sometimes you can count how long a motor
is on
and get it pretty consistent um
particularly with something like a
stepper motor which tends to be pretty
consistent in
the distance it goes um but if you do
that 100
200 5000 times you're not going to get
necessarily repeatable results and that
is not ideal right
and the way to solve that is by plopping
in some state information to your system
and you do that with sensors um you can
do that with a simple sensor like a
switch that you bump into
every third time on your motor you swing
back and you swing until you hit a
switch and then you know where you are
and you can go and
you can calibrate it and that's still
not
exactly closed loop control ideally you
have something
like a rotational encoder on there that
tells you exactly where you are at all
times
so as you try to move to a specific
location you know
when you're getting close and you can
slow down before you get there because
remember
inertia is kind of the enemy of your
control system
it's going to try to to keep moving even
after you stop moving so if you move to
the location
and then stop your motor it's too late
your inertia is going to swing you a
little bit past
so you need to just start slowing down
your motor effort before you get there
and there's a large amount of control
systems out there that will do this
some of them that are very very very
complicated and very efficient
some of them that are pretty darn
efficient and not that complicated like
the pid
controller which is kind of like the
bread and butter of your control systems
it was invented back in
i don't know maybe the 30s or 40s i'm
not exactly sure um
but uh but it's still used today because
it's so simple to implement
and so that's the one i would recommend
to most people who are trying to do a
control system
you can get more elegant than that you
can dive much deeper into control theory
if you choose to um so
uh yeah so that's kind of control
systems
uh in a very very very short nutshell
and basically this idea of open loop
versus closed loop is pretty
important um and as you try to have
higher and higher precision
you're going to need that closed loop or
else to just no way you can hit it with
an overloop system
cool i want to talk about degrees of
freedom also degrees of freedom are a
really interesting thing
um so uh
mechanical systems are designed are
defined as their
uh by their degrees of freedom and and
what i mean by degree of freedom is is
the way in which you can make them so
a motor has a single rotational degree
of freedom assuming the motor body is
fixed
there's only one thing and it's a degree
of freedom that's rotational
a slider on the other hand has one
degree of freedom and it's translational
a free body that means something just
floating there
has six total degrees of freedom it can
translate
in any of your cartesian directions and
it can rotate
along any of those axes right and so
when you are designing something that
you want to move you want to think about
what your degrees of freedom are
some of them you would like to constrain
so that you get just simple rotation
means you've constrained five of six
and left one free or sometimes you want
something that's going
to to have multiple degrees of freedom
operating simultaneously
and so if you're building something like
a robotic arm those can be
five six seven degrees of freedom at the
end effector
so you have a thing kind of moving
around but even
human arm usually is modeled as kind of
seven degrees of freedom
so you have three rotational here one
rotational your elbow
and three rotational at your wrist and
that's a reasonable mathematical
approximation though it turns out that
it's a lot more complicated than that
and we're really good at using them but
if you have multiple motors linked up
in a row you might have a multi-degree
of freedom
system even though each one is only
operating on a single degree of freedom
and that allows you to get to where you
want to be because you're going to
control all of those things
uh in your software and your electronics
independently
and so to try and get smooth motion out
of them eventually you need to think
about that like
okay if i need to be able to move to
rotate this thing
and translate this thing okay those are
two different degrees of freedom i'm
going to need two different actuators
because you need an actuator per degree
of freedom in order to get them to
operate independently
if they don't operate independently
maybe you've synced them together with
gears then it's only a one degree of
freedom system
and that's actually really convenient
that can be a really nice way to do it
um
and you see this sometimes out in the
field where uh
you know gearing or linkages create a
single degree of freedom system so i'll
show you a really cool
single degree of freedom system when we
get to the linkages stuff later on
but i do want to show you this which is
a really really neat example of a
486 degree of freedom system so far as i
know it it's one of the most complicated
things
this is a piece of artwork that some of
my friends made it's called morph it's
uh
it's a kinetic art piece each one of
those panels is independently operating
and they are those led panels kind of do
this it is mesmerizing to watch for
hours fortunately this video is only 12
seconds long
so and it's going to leave no let's not
do that
so that's a lot of degrees of freedom
and each of them is translational so
they're all kind of moving
in and out and they use these uh nclas
which i'll talk about
to do that later okay
we're done intro nailed it we're only
half an hour and
so power transmission let's just jump
through this
all right uh there are a whole bunch of
different types of power transmission
i'm gonna go over
uh three of them and then we're gonna
look at the math and then the types of
gear trains
and how that works because my hunch is
that the most useful stuff to you guys
is this uh is the kind of math of power
transmission
and uh so onwards we go so here's some
linkages
i'm just gonna spend one slide in one
movie on linkages
um but you see them out in in nature all
the time not nature in mechanical nature
in the case of this right here this is a
engine crankshaft
for an adjustable compression ratio
engine
which is super cool and
so you see that there are connecting
rods and things these are linkages so
you have
rotational degrees of freedom between
them but then they don't translate so
you can
fix them in places so this is a one
degree of freedom system
in that you have uh you've constrained
it such that the rotation of this
element
it becomes the translation of this
element assuming that you're not
threading in
and out adjusting this thing similarly
this is a one degree of freedom system
these are
mechanically tied so even though you
have multiple things all moving together
that little thing crawling over there
it's actually a single degree of freedom
system which is super cool
um they are excellent for things like
odd trajectories as you see
uh with the moving legs down there in
the right um they're also really nice
for converting between linear movement
and rotation as you see from the
crankshaft there
and they are great because they give you
reliably synchronous movement and what i
mean by that is if you need things
moving together
linkages are really nice for that so
they're a good tool to think about when
you're designing stuff
for those things they they tend to be
difficult for some things like vibration
um and because you're using a lot of
physical elements they can have higher
inertia and they can be kind of heavy
so they're not great for some
applications where you need it to be
light or where you need it to not
generate
vibration which can become acoustic uh
noise which is unfortunate okay let's
take a look at another movie here um
this is a buddy of mine who works in
this co-working space named flo
and he creates these incredible linkages
in kinetic artwork that's him
demonstrating it but you can see this
thing as it goes around you've got a
whole bunch of languages but this is
still a one degree of freedom system
that degree of freedom starts out with a
rotational actuator and then it becomes
all of these different really cool
translational elements
as it goes which i just think is the
neatest stuff um
i would definitely recommend following
him on instagram he's great one of my
favorite instagram accounts
okay let's talk about build some pulleys
we're gonna do this in uh
in i think one slide one slide um
so uh flexible linkages uh covers a lot
of different things it can be belt it
can be rope
uh it can be like steel braided cable
and it can be chained kind of so chain
usually has
one one degree of freedom in which it's
really flexible
and a degree of freedom that it's not so
it's not particularly flexible in the
other but it's not strong enough that
you could really rely on it
to move um in that direction i guess you
could also think of a tank threat as a
flexible linkage
and the fundamental of this is
that they they operate great in tension
but as you compress them they buckle
basically immediately if you think about
trying to compress
a rope you pull it taut it stays great
in tension the moment you go like this
it's already buckled under the force of
gravity
it's sagging like that and that's what
defines these things
so you can use pulleys to redirect that
tensile force pulleys don't
do not redirect compressive forces
and if you think about this it's kind of
evident if you think about that guy
standing in the thing if he starts
pushing on this to try and get the block
to move down
uh it's not ever going to move faster
than like you know he sets it down on
the thing keeps pushing to try and push
it into the object it's not going to
work the rope is just going to buckle
immediately because it's flexible
um so you can use these things
uh to create mechanical advantages by
doubling and by doubling what i mean
here is that
he's pulling on the load but actually
the load is being distributed between
this one line here
the the right line and the left line
on those and that allows him to move
twice as far
but distribute the load between those
two so that block and tackle that's a
simple block and tackle
that's how you get the mechanical
advantage out of that the pulley itself
just redirects the forces and it allows
you to redirect them in such a way that
you can double them
or more um so that's
a super cool thing uh if you need your
belts not to slip
which is a major thing if you're using
say steppers to drive something which
you use commonly in like 3d printer
applications
timing belt is nice because it locks
into
uh it locks into your pulley or or your
pulley wheel
um and chains also because they
synchronize onto sprockets they don't
slip
um if they do you have done some
terrible damage to your system
and i'm impressed really more than
anything else um
so what you can always know is the
direction of rotation in this particular
so the example that i've got down here
on the bottom you know the rotation is
going to be
in the same direction so they're always
going to rotate in that same direction
and the effective gear ratio which i'm
going to talk about as we get to gears
is the drive over driven and so
you can kind of see that here if i
shrink my radius my
um i'm going to have uh a let's see
higher gear ratio and if i increase it
i'm gonna have a lower gear ratio which
gets me
more torque out um and similarly
my work in is equal to my workout times
my
my efficiency and so i can say hey like
my smaller gear is going to move more
quickly my larger gear is going to
move more slowly and this
works the same way the gears do which is
why i'm not going into it too
deep right now
[Applause]
we made it to gears 35 minutes past the
hour and here we are
okay so these are spur gears and i'm
going to talk about the different types
of gears in a second but this is the
the cleanest example of kind of how
gears and gear design works
where you have this line of action as it
showed right here
that angle with respect to the tangent
is what's called your pressure angle and
so when you design you choose your
pressure angle
and that shows you here's some examples
of what different pressure angles look
like
you can't really go much below 14.5
which is a really conventional pressure
angle
because the teeth get too thin and they
start to snap off
you can go to these really high pressure
angles but you start to lose efficiency
at the higher
at the higher pressure angles you also
module is commonly used for tier
for gear size um and that is
represented in millimeters or inches
um and so you would choose like a module
one gear
is in millimeters um and then your
manufacturer will know and then they'll
guess they'll know the size of the gear
based on the total number of teeth you
could also give them a pitch diameter
and they'll figure out how many teeth go
in there
but the problem is if you specify that
wrong you could end up with a fractional
number of teeth which of course doesn't
work as a gear
so it's easier to specify tooth count
module pressure angle
uh when you're when you're specifying a
gear in a mechanical schematic
and uh and you would also always uh
specify the material
when you're getting this made by someone
else um
cool and and i've got this image on here
um
so that you guys can go back and look at
it if you need to
um you mount with the center distance
which is
uh this this pitch diameter the pitch
circle
halved the diameter plus the pitch
circle half
half of the pitch diameter from the from
the other gear and that tells you your
mounting distance
when you have gears operating together
you end up with
a backlash and what this is is if you're
rotating one direction you get this
perfect synchronous motion as you rotate
back the other direction it takes
a fraction to move and that's something
to pay attention to as you get more and
more gears together
the backlash adds up between them so if
you have only two gears operating you
have
some backlash but if you run that same
gear system back to back to back to back
to back
you now have five times that much
backlash so you're gonna start
spinning in one direction when you go to
reverse it you're gonna spin for
you know maybe a quarter of a rotation
before you actually start moving the
other direction
and if you're using something where
you're where your um
your sensor is on your your motor then
you may have
very very peculiar outcomes um
on the the kind of the end effector of
your thing
um it's difficult to prevent but it can
definitely be minimized based on your
gearing selections and i'll talk about
that in a second
um but basically it is a massive
headache for your roboticists um because
uh you need precision in your movement
and this is just the killer of precision
which is a bummer
okay we're going to talk about gear
ratio and i'm going to take a swig of
water
so that i don't lose my voice
sorry for the wasting time
um conveniently
the ratio of radius diameter and tooth
number
always mix the same way so your radius
of drive
over driven your diameter of drive
overdriven
and your tooth number of drive
overdriven will always be
your gear ratio and this is really nice
for your design
um and and this is really convenient
because oftentimes gears are specified
by tooth counter
and so when you're thinking about
designing yourself a gear system
um that is a really nice way
uh to do it um and so um
yeah so so uh
you do it with those numbers if i have
multiple gears
moving along i take the output from one
shaft and put it into the input of the
next shaft then i can multiply the gear
ratios
from drive to driven drive to driven
drive to driven
so on so forth so let's take a look at a
quick example i start with a
two start worm gear and i'll talk about
this in worm gears but that's
effectively a two tooth
here pushing a 24 tooth spur gear
the shaft of that spur gear drives a 42
spur
which then itself drives a 60
spur so now i can multiply that gear
ratio together
so i take my 2 over 24 let's drive to
driven
like 40 over 60 drive to driven i
multiply those together that's 0.083
times
0.66 i get .055 as my
total gear ratio and so what that gear
ratio effectively means
is that my output shaft moves .055
rotations for every rotation of my input
shaft so i'm really cranking around on
my input shaft
and my output shaft is just barely
moving why would i do this
well my output shaft is going to have a
way greater torque
than my input shaft which is really
awesome so my torque ratio
is my gear ratio lives in the
denominator of my torque ratio and then
my efficiency
live up top so i'm going to multiply out
all my efficiencies that's what that big
capital pi is so the product of all of
my efficiencies
i'm going to then divide that by my gear
ratio so
i'm going to be having generating 12
times as much torque on that output gear
as i had on my input gear
because of this worm gear plus my plus
my spur gears which are geared in the
right
direction so i would note
that my rotation is 18 times slower so
i'm losing a ton of power to this
inefficiency
right like i'm getting a 12x torque
multiplier
but my uh but my rotation is
now my speed is 18 times slower so it's
a bummer of a trade-off but
that is the loss of heat what i get for
that is worm gears are extremely high
ratio to their
uh they're extremely efficient in terms
of their packaging size
and i'll talk about those when i talk
about worm here specifically
okay practical example is going to take
me a second to pull this up because i'm
pulling up calculations from my
previous company and uh
so it's gonna take me a second i'm sorry
i should have had this a little bit
better prepared
oh sorry
so sorry i'll go wait for this i promise
um
[Music]
loading
nope okay
cool so this is going to load on up this
is a design calculator that i use for a
project that i was working on
so the project that i was working on
over here is a bed that lifts from the
bottom to the top so i
my goal was to specify uh a system that
i could use
to move a 60 kilogram bed to a height of
2 meters in less than 30 seconds
and that sounds really fast but actually
30 seconds is pretty slow
so as we look at this i've got my um
my calculator over here and i'll show
you how i've laid this out so you guys
can get an idea of how all of this stuff
works
so true to form like a consultant all of
my variables that i can change i have in
blue and all of my static or calculated
variables i have here
in black so i can go through and i can
change the different diameters of
the things that i'm using so i'm careful
to make sure that i use my units
here so that i can keep track of
everything so i know my revolutions
millimeters minutes and that way when it
comes time for me to look at
my actual lift time um i can do all of
that sort of stuff i'm also looking at a
variety of other things like the torque
required to move things
and whether or not the motor that i
currently have specified will actually
work so the motor that i have specified
in this particular system is a 775 just
kind of a standard dc motor here
um and this is how i went through and
looked at it so here's my two meter
travel distance in centimeters
here's my motor rpms which i'm pulling
off of a
crud i don't know where i am um off of
a motor
data sheet um
and uh and so that's that tells me all
of the things i need to know so i'm
looking at my 60 kilogram
uh total frame weight here and that
shows me that i'm not able to do it so i
also in the same one i go down and talk
about all my electrical
and then i'm also looking at cost and
the same thing so this is showing all of
the different things
my structural numbers all of these
things so i recommend this is the way
that i do it but
uh you can you can go ahead and build
your own one of these so this is just a
normal spreadsheet and most of the
things in here
that are calculated are just
multiplication and additional stuff
right here's a lot of multiplication
addition but that's all there is to it
um so that gives you an idea of how i go
about solving this problem
when i'm doing this in an actual
engineering way
okay gear mounting here we are taking a
look
at um at mcmaster data sheets and they
will show you the mounting distance for
all of these things
so over here in the spur gears you'll
notice that it gives you a pitch
diameter this is an american part so
it's in
inches and then i if i'm meshing that
with one of the same then i know that
that's my mounting distance
uh access to axis and if i'm doing
uh a different sized uh gear then i have
that number and added to half this
number and that gives my
my mounting distance between the two
that's
how you do simple spur gears if i'm
doing bevel gears you'll notice that it
shows
from the uh from the gear throat down
here
to the center of rotation here and if i
look
on this gear as well so they're showing
two of the same gear
then it would be the same the other
direction but i may want to be using
this to drive
a different system so if i have a
different gear ratio two with different
numbers of teeth
um then uh then i would i would use
those those schematics respectively
okay cool um and you notice if i'm
looking here
i am showing my my tooth pitch here
and my number of teeth tooth pitch
number of teeth
right those are absolutely necessary um
and it'll show
it should show module in there somewhere
so i don't see where it is
cool let's talk about uh types of gears
i'm showing you one here on the screen
which i really love this thing is called
a harmonic drive it's a zero backlash
drive system
it's extremely high gear ratios in
extremely low
uh form factor um they're really neat
but it's kind of a specialty gear so i'm
not going to get too far into them but
there's tons of cool stuff on youtube
about how
harmonic drives work uh they are really
really neat
uh the other one here that i'm showing
is what's called a joyce dayton jack
um and this is a combination of multiple
gears working together
doing interesting stuff so it's a worm
drive driving this
this gear here the spur gear that drives
a threaded rod
for linear movement out of a rotational
thing in an extremely compact way
they're able to produce an incredible
amount of force it's super cool and you
see these sometimes in car jacks but
also they're
they're powered frequently to move stuff
like stages around
which is really really neat because you
can put a bunch of these all over the
place
and you get that kind of balance i am
going to talk about the gears over here
spur gears bevels worms
differentials planetaries um and well my
others are right here on screen
um i want to talk a little bit about
efficiencies um because those
are really important when you're
thinking about your gear training spur
gears are really high efficiency
same thing with uh helical and double
helical which i'll talk about
in spur gears bevel gears are also
really high efficiency
where your efficiency starts to drop is
when you're starting to move things
kind of uh in in weird ways and so your
worm gears have very high ratios so you
can see the normal ratio range goes up
to 75
to one which is crazy um but its
efficiency could drop as low as 20
percent so
there's so much power out of there oh
it's a bummer
um but uh but yeah
so uh but you could still maybe use it
because it's very compact
single set of uh there's two gears
measuring against each other
i'm not going to talk about crosstelical
uh really even though
they're in this i guess i am a little
bit in the worm section
spur gears are what you think of when
you think of gears
they are like the most conventional uh
gears you can 3d print these maybe not
super well but they can be done
um they're simple they're cheap they're
super easy to manufacture
they tend to be kind of bulky
particularly if you start chaining them
together and getting these really long
gear trains
um they're a little bulky um and they
always have parallel axes
but you can get really big gear ratios
range off of them
so you can do one to one or you can do
like you know
uh 10 to 100 and get that 10 to 1 ratio
which is crazy
um helical gears work a lot like spur
gears but as you can see
because i'm i'm spiraling the tooth
around the outside they're a little more
difficult to manufacture
but the tooth is longer even in the same
form factor and what that lets me do is
have much higher torque
and quieter movement because i'm
engaging multiple teeth more teeth at
the same time
but they're more expensive to make um
cool bevel gears are what happens when
you want to change the um
the direction of rotation um and not
that you're rotating
against each other but that you're
you're changing the axes of rotation
so your your shafts are always going to
be coplanar so like here the plane is
now
like that um and they're pretty high
efficiency they're as high efficiency as
a spur gear
typically and they're really common um
and they're useful for things like
drivetrains and that sort of stuff as
you have to make your movement go around
a bend and that bend is most commonly 90
degrees but it doesn't necessarily
have to be 90 degrees you can get bevel
gears custom made
that do them at weird angles those are a
pain in the butt to design and i
recommend against it if you can
you can get them in uh straight tooth
gears like you see on the top here
and you can also get them in spiral
tooth which has a lot of the same
advantages you get out of the helical
gears from the previous one
and that you have the more uh tooth in
contact
with time so you can get more torque out
of them and quieter movement but they're
just a
bigger pain to make and so they tend to
be more expensive um crown gears
are a type of uh bevel gear
um and that's where you have a spur gear
over here um hitting a 90 degree thing
so it's a subset of bevel gears and the
calculations are all the same
conveniently bevel gears and spur gears
calculate exactly the same way
it's tooth to tooth ratio super duper
easy on the calculations there
worm gears are able to get these really
really really high
uh gear ratios because a worm gear is
effectively
like this one which is a one star worm
gear winds the same tooth around the
shaft a bunch of times
that makes it a one tooth gear and what
that means is that here where i've got i
don't know what is that 18 teeth
i would guess on the outside there where
i've got that 18 tooth i now have a
ratio of 18 to 1.
which if i need to do that with spur
gears means i you know like the smallest
spur gear you can realistically have is
about 80.
really tan is better so that means i
need 182 gear over here and this thing
is going to be huge
it's going to be massive so there's just
not an efficient way to do it from a
from a from a material space
you can't fit it all in there this is
worm gear super little efficient it's
tiny
um and uh and you know you can get
pretty high efficiencies but like i
would say a
normal one start worm here like this is
probably going to be in an efficiency
range around 70
so that's not great um but it's not
terrible
and they're not super duper expensive to
create
um the kind of the a similar thing here
this is kind of like
uh these crossed helical gears are like
a worm gear but with many more teeth on
them
um so you know i can go from one tooth
to a multi start thread
to a four star once i get above four
it's not really a worm gear anymore
and it starts to become these crossed
helical but as you can see it's just
kind of a continuum from one to the next
differential is one of my very very
favorite uh gear trains and what it lets
you do is
typically a five gear system working
together
and it diverts power between from one
input shaft between two output shafts
and this is really really cool because
it lets you
drive around corners while one wheel on
the inside
needs to move slower the one on the
outside needs to move more quickly
because you're kind of going around
this curve you need to be able to do
that and so i have
a video for that that i will show but
before i move on to that i want to talk
a little bit about this thing that i've
got in the bottom left there
which is what's called a south facing
chariot and this was a device
using differentials in the middle there
you can see that schematic
it was invented in ancient china and and
this takes the output from the two
wheels
and measures them against each other so
instead of driving the wheels a horse is
driving the carriage
but i'm checking this these wheels as
they move with respect to each other
to make sure that i have a gear system
that always points
south so before you leave the stables
you set this thing to be south
by shifting your wheels with respect to
each other and then no matter what turns
and
over the course you go bumps and stuff
this thing always points out
it's just such an elegant gear system
and uh
proof of really really brilliant
engineering in ancient times
so neat so so so neat um so let's take a
quick look
um at a differential video
um and i just want to show this so you
can kind of get an idea
um this one does a little bit better job
of showing that thing
rotate so you can see that i'm still
getting a little rotation here
on my right hand side but i'm getting a
lot out of my left hand side
stop that there and head back to our
thing
planetary gears are another really cool
one there you've got that animated thing
showing up there and they're sometimes
called epic
epi cyclic gears um the planetary gears
is the common name
you have a sun gear in the middle you
have planet gears that travel around
here and you have what's called an
annular ring around the outside which is
just a bunch of tubes on the inside of a
thing
they're extremely compact which is cool
um and you can get
um kind of medium and high gear ratios
out of them by changing the ratio of
your sun gear size
to your uh your planet gear size and you
can do this with tooth ratio
as well the cool thing is because
they're compact they can be chained
easily coaxially
this is how a lot of transmissions work
is that they chain these things
coaxially and then they shift what's
changing
uh or what's what's the driven and drive
gear out of there
so you can understand if i keep this
same drive here
but i now fix my planet gears my annular
ring will start to
rotate as well and i can do this by by
breaking
different things to get different
rotations out of them
okay there are some other ways you can
trans transmit
power um right here i've got a racking
pinion
um and that allows me to
take rotational energy and convert it
into linear energy and it's a very
efficient way to do it
but i have kind of a limited range to do
it it's also important to know about
clutches
clutches are a method that allow you to
engage and disengage
rotational movement so if i have a shaft
that's rotating and i want to have a
shaft that i can either rotate or not
um a clutch is kind of that it's
basically a switch for power
and what it basically does is basically
two plates one rotating and then
when i put the other one in contact with
it friction
overrides and it starts to it starts to
to rotate alongside
and this is neat if you want to be able
to have something free rotate for a
while and then engage to
to another thing where you're having an
output of the thing you do this a lot of
times if you have an internal combustion
engine and you need your wheels to be
able to stop um and that's because
uh your internal combustion engine will
stall if you stop it completely
so when you're driving a manual
transmission you just engage the clutch
and it allows your motor to continue to
free rotate
but your wheels can be stationary and
that's good because you don't want to
continuously drive all the time because
stop lights are important
bearings are a really really important
part of rotational and linear movement
um because they allow you to constrain
your motion
in your degrees of freedom on some axes
so this is a plane bearing you can see
it right up here
hopefully it does it and you can see
i've got a picture of it there and that
allows
rotation and translation along my shaft
um
and that's nice if i want to constrain
things to move in a specific way
they're cheap they're compact they can't
get to super high rpms
um and they do require lubricant you can
get what's called self-lubricating
uh bearings and that's because they put
lubricant into the bearing already and
it's slightly porous
and it seeps back out it's super useful
you can use them
to hold a radial load and what i mean by
that is
i've got my shaft and i've got my load
going
on the radius to that shaft okay
or an axial load which means i have a
load pushing
along the axis of my shaft
and and you can get both depending on
the shape of the bearing
you can get slightly more expensive ball
bearings this is you can see down there
an unshielded ball bearing on the image
but you can see
what i've got here is a shielded ball
bearing that just means they put a
little piece of plastic in there to make
sure dust doesn't get in there in case
i'm operating it outdoors
um ball bearings are also really cheap
they're not quite as cheap as plane
bearings but they're still pretty cheap
they have much higher max rpms so if
you're going to be spending something
really really fast
your ball bearings can go pretty dang
quick
um and they are typically rated for
radial loads
not axial loads but you can get ones
that are rated for
axial specifically or both
um needle roller needle and roller
bearings are a little more expensive
i've got one here you can see as i take
it apart
i've got my rollers on the inside there
and it spins
this does both for ax radial load and
axial load
so i can load the crap out of it in this
direction i mean i could probably put
100 kilos on this bearing
and still have it free rotate really
nicely and i could probably do the same
radially so you can see that it kind of
falls apart if i don't have it in a
thing i'd probably put 100 kilos of load
radially and it'll still rotate freely
so that's really cool that i can do it
it only does axial load in one direction
right like it literally falls apart the
other direction um these are
these are pretty expensive so this
bearing i think was about 15 euros
so they're awesome but they're expensive
air bearings are where you have a gap
between two very precisely made
materials and you pipe air into it
and then that air prevents things from
touching and you can get extremely high
max rpms like hundreds of thousands of
rpms
but they tend to be really expensive
because the manufacturing tolerances are
so tight
you can also get these things called
recirculating uh
linear bearings they look like this they
slide back and forth and you can see a
cutaway diagram of it there that allows
you to have that nice
translational movement without getting
rotation on any other axis
so if you have something that's moving
along a system
these are a really nice way to do it and
they're not super expensive i think this
one was about 15 miles
or dollars euros and dollars about the
same these days
um yeah and so you can see over there on
the right hand what the inside of a
roller bearing looks like
threaded rods are a really nice way to
to convert from rotational to
translational
motion what you can see down at the top
is this
rod with just kind of a fixed thread on
it you can also get what's called
ball screws and ball screws use an
internal channel where they move
balls around so it operates like a ball
bearing and they have almost no backlash
they're really really really cool for
that so in very high precision
things you often see ball screws use
because they minimize that backlash but
they work the same way that a threaded
rod does
and there's some math that uh that
operates out and i wish i had time to go
into it but i'm
already over time oops we still have a
long way to go because we haven't hit
actuation at all
we're gonna pick up the pace here i'm so
sorry
linear actuation this is a steam engine
um and it's
showing you linear actuation that's then
turning using linkages into rotation
i do want to talk about solenoids
pneumatics hydraulics and electrical
actuators i'm not going to talk about
steam
solenoids are just a magnet moving in a
magnetic field
so you you have an electrically
controlled an electric coil and it moves
a magnet
it usually is linear movement between
two points it can be spring return that
means while it's energized it goes one
direction and it returns when you
de-energize it
or latching means you energize it and
goes one way and you energize it with
the opposite voltage and it goes back
the other direction
they have extremely high power draw when
active and a huge inductive load so you
want to use a flyback diode
google ad otherwise you're gonna roast
whatever power supply you have
i have learned this the hard way um
speakers are really really similar to
solenoids but they allow you to have
movement within a range based on the
voltage
um and a spring that's going against it
technically you can do that with
solenoids but it's a little hard to do
and they're built to displace a fluid in
waves to create sound
and a microphone works exactly the same
way the speaker does but in opposite
so it uses sound waves coming in to look
at an electrical signal coming on you
have to amplify that
in order to get a useful signal out of
it but that is uh
don't have time for that pneumatics and
hydraulics
are really really cool and really useful
um i use them for a lot of my stuff i
tend to stray away from hydraulics
because you have to have
high pressure pumps typically to do them
and so a 10 they tend to be pretty
expensive
but and but they have extremely high
force
operation within a range
pneumatics don't really do ranges very
well they operate really between two
points
but they are really they can be
extremely fast like scary fast
with relatively high force uh which is
really exciting the forces
correlate to the pressure that you put
into them
and i would absolutely for obvious
purposes use a speed controller
and that's a little needle valve you put
on the inlet and that allows you to dial
the speed
down which is important if you open
those all the way up pneumatic cylinders
move scary fast and you can hurt
yourself
um and you typically control them using
solenoid valves that i talked about last
week
for easy electrical integration um
hydraulics tend to use very high
pressure so you need to have a very
robust system that adds a bunch of
weight the nice thing about pneumatics
is that they're very light
you can use electrical linear actuators
so there is such a thing as a linear
stepper motor
which is basically this thing i have up
here in the top and it alternates
electrical fields to move it across from
north to south to north south north
south and that gives you pretty precise
motion they're extremely easy to
implement but they're really expensive
so what i recommend doing instead is to
use
a rotational to linear system
to drive to drive your linear motion you
can buy those off the shelf like this
ball screw sliding table which i
pulled the image straight off aliexpress
or you can do
that you can you can use a system so
this is a threaded nut that fits on a
rod that's turned by a stepper
and that'll get linear motion provided
you prevent it from rotating around
which you can do with one of these handy
dandy linear rails
um you can also get these things called
down here non-captive linear actuators
nclas
i have one right here and what this is a
stepper body that's hollow
but with a thread on the inside so when
the stepper rotates
it moves the threaded rod in and out
they're really beautiful elegant
machines and i hadn't seen them until a
couple of years ago
um but they're really really neat and
they move things really well
we actually use those in our beds for
the first generation and they did not
work very well
they do a lot of force but just not
enough to move the bed
cool that's linear actuation let's do
rotate rotary actuation
even though we're already a little over
time
uh so rotary actuation i'm going to talk
about this you need to actuate stuff
it's often useful to have
sensors you can get those in rotary
encoders which i show here and those
have a digital output where you're
looking at the signal coming in off of
them to figure out where you are
and the number of counts dictates how
much precision you get
out of that you can also just do it
within switches where you bump into
something
and then you know you're there because
you bumped all the way into it those are
really cheap
and really useful and i have a drawer of
them over there you can also use hall
effect sensors those measure magnetic
fields
and you can make your own rotary
encoders by having a magnet pass by a
hall effect sensor
and waiting for that hall effect sensor
to blip um hall effects give a digital
output so you could just measure high or
low on that
on that signal which is really nice cool
i'm going to talk about those actuators
coming right up that's now
dc motors there you go the 775 right
here
on the camera and the 525 555 whatever
it is 575
up there on the screen this is a very
conventional off-the-shelf motor and the
way that these work
brushed dc motors are extremely cheap i
mean you can get them for less than a
dollar
less than the euro they do require
what's called an h bridge which is this
thing right here
to operate and an age bridge just to get
control speed and direction otherwise
you could just power them and they just
spin
it's magical they're terrible for open
loop control and the reason for that is
that they
are each motor is slightly different um
they rotate differently under load
they so so if you need if you need to
get any precision out of them you need
to have them with closed loop control
um and that's really important i've got
a schematic over here about how they
work
they use these brushes to alternate the
polarity so all you have to do is apply
dc
current to them and they start to rotate
super cool stuff
you can also get what's called brushless
dc motors and these work
slightly differently where you're
pulsing between different coils to get
these things to move around
so you can see one deconstructed right
here all the different coils and they
require an electronic speed controller
they tend to have very high rpms and so
they're often used in drone applications
because you can control the speed of
them
really really quickly which helps with
that stability and control that i was
talking about
before they have a lot of the same
problems with precise positioning that
you would get out of
um a dc motor because they uh they vary
based on them
so so i wouldn't use them for precision
applications so much as i would use them
for
high speed applications they are really
cool
uh you can also get dc motors that have
been geared down for you
um you can get these ones these are
originally like i think they were used
for
uh washing uh windshield wipers on cars
they're extremely high torque you can
see they're a worm drive hidden away
underneath there um and they are just
super duper high torque
which is great if you have something
that like you need to
move at low rpm but high torque and they
tend to be pretty cheap
and pretty compact they're still not
great for control though the slower rpm
makes position tracking a little bit
easier
servo motors are motors with integrative
feedback whether they're doing that with
their own rotational encoders or whether
they're doing it kind of the cheap way
with a potentiometer
um it depends so micro servos are the
ones that i think are most
accessible for most humans and so they
have their internal
closed loop control in the form of a
potentiometer that lives inside of here
and they have some gearing to give them
much higher torque but at the end of the
day it's really just a dc motor
with a potentiometer that it drives and
it uses a pulse signal
to guide where that goes there's a lot
of youtube videos
on how to do servo control but the
really nice they
tend to have a limited range of motion
they don't usually go full
uh 360 degrees and getting them to run
full rotations
can be difficult um you can buy those
but
those are less common and they tend to
be a little bit more expensive to get
full rotation servos and even so
a lot of times they'll limit themselves
to like five rotations so it's not a
continuous rotation thing
you can get continuous rotation servos
but i would
recommend doing stepper motors instead
hey a segway
um so these use alternating coils to
advance
uh incrementally so you alternate
between coil one
and coil two to advance one step
and the step uh and so electrically
um this is pretty easy to do you use a
stepper driver which i'll talk about
in the next slide but you can advance um
by your typical ones are 1.8 degrees you
can get high precision steppers that are
0.9 degrees
um you sacrifice a little bit of torque
for those at that higher precision
they tend to be pretty low rpm they max
out 1200 is a really fast moving stepper
i would never really want to push one
past about 800 rpm
they tend to have pretty high torque
given their body size um which is nice
and you can get very precise movement
out of them uh which
means you can do open loop control on
them
with some reliability they're not
terrible for it um you can also use the
coils to break
where you apply a lot of juice to them
and they they hold everything in there
which you can't do with dc motors um but
you do need to have a stepper driver in
order to use them
so uh you have a couple of different
options on stepper drivers they kind of
look like this i've got some images up
there
um they're uh current limiting but you
can the torque in your stepper is
voltage-based you can put a lot of
voltage into your stepper driver and
then
limit the current back down so your
steppers don't overheat and that's a
really good way to do it
also most stepper drivers will allow you
to do what's called micro stepping
and that uses pulse width and modulation
to uh control how much is going into
each coil so instead of going
directly from one coil to the next which
is the highest torque way of moving
uh you can do you can kind of phase in
and out and that lets you get much
higher precision so if you're 32x micro
stepping
on a 0.9 degree stepper you get that
really really fine
movement around at .028 degrees
per input now you sacrifice torque by
doing that
so there's always that trade-off you're
sacrificing torque to do that
but you can use them easily with open
loop control and uh
you still need sensors for closed loop
control so you may need a
encoder for closed loop control but we
talked about that already
cool that's everything i'm 10 minutes
over so dreadfully sorry
um but uh
let's uh oh let's let's end on a nice
note engineering is all about
persistence um stuff is gonna break
but the rule of the rule of thumbs is if
you can build it you can fix it
so uh when someone knocks your thing off
the table don't get too sad it's just an
opportunity to rebuild it better this
time
all right i'm gonna start looking in
chat for uh
some q a it's you thought i got rid of
that picture but i didn't
sometimes i troll even myself that was
me when i could still get haircuts