hey folks my name is Matthew ol and I'm
here to talk to you about a course that
I'm doing together with hackaday
designed to teach you the fundamentals
of software versus engineering using
Deidre I currently work for Cedar Creek
software as a security researcher and
also offered training and consultation
through voiced our security you may have
seen some of my previous work on
hackaday and on my github pages where I
reverse engineer various embedded
devices and have to explain the concepts
behind hardly reverse engineering but
enough about me why bother to learn
about software reverse engineering well
maybe you want to learn more about how a
proprietary binary blob works the you
have source for or you want to start
participating and capture-the-flag
competitions and learn more about
information security industries through
solving these kinds of puzzles and
shadows throughout this course we plan
to teach you the fundamentals needed to
start your journey with reverse
engineering so forth and after going
through this course we will teach you
the fundamentals of using this tool to
reverse engineer software with a focus
on x86 Linux executables each session is
going to be focused around practical
exercises and have additional exercises
for you to perform outside of class and
then review later during the office
hours where you'll be able to ask
questions and kind of expand upon the
things you talked about during the class
sessions regarding prerequisites we ask
that you have experience writing C and a
familiar with the concept of assembly
language before the class begins we
provide links to materials to get you up
to speed so that everybody's on the same
page one of the class begins thanks for
watching I look forward to learning and
working
[Music]