well welcome back from lunch
everyone who's come into this room thank
you for joining the vendor stream
um we've skipped on slides you're right
so we've got ricky calder here to talk
to us
about lessons or lessons as the slide
says
lessons learned around active directory
uh
if you have any questions please lodge
them through the app
so we can keep everyone on both on the
virtual stream and in the physical room
aligned
i'll be moderating those questions and
asking them as appropriate
so welcome ricky i'll leave you to do it
thank you
thank you okay so today's discussion is
going to be
more of a broad discussion around what
we're seeing
with the customers that we're actually
engaging with so
we're going to actually talk about um
active directory of
defense in the real world so you know
aed defense is more than a detect
and respond you know there's a lot more
to active directory events to protect
your credentials your data
and goes into the last result which is
you know we've detected that we've been
compromised
we need to respond you want to be
actually interrupting that train
way before you can get to that point so
i come across this quote actually in a
actually another vendor slide that we
deal with
i thought it was actually painted a very
doom and gloom picture
of actually the i.t space and to
security you know
if you're not hacked you're going to be
hacked and if you've been hacked once
you're going to get hacked again i was
like well
yes but you know if you do all the right
things
and actually understand the attack
pathways
um you can interrupt those attacks from
happening and have a stronger chance of
actually
stopping them from happening again so
you know a few years ago microsoft had
the guidance you know assume breach
the problem can't be solved by a single
strategy which is true
and you actually want to look at more of
kind of
identity parameters you know restrict
where your privileged accounts should be
logged into
in order for them to not be compromised
big problem with that it's very very
difficult to harden active directory
from an infrastructure point of view you
know you have network boundaries you
have
uh domain segregation you know accounts
unknowns service accounts doing certain
privileges that you just don't know
about banking applications that require
privileges
you know um organizational buyspoke
applications that you just don't know
about
so obviously microsoft and i've dealt
with some very large organizations in
the finance industry
over the last six to 12 months that had
tried to actually implement what they
call the red forest approach
the tiered approach to i suppose
privileged segmentation
problem with the actual privileged
segmentation of the red forest approach
it's very difficult to implement it's
very
hard to maintain and operate from both a
financial and
a headcount point of view and it becomes
disruptive actually to day-to-day work
in
um for your actual operations team
so what happens there is that you know
they find ways to actually
go around that particular security kind
of perimeter
and then you know it's all for nothing
this cost you an absolute fortune
and it only really works if you're on
premise
a lot of organizations now have hybrid
environments they move a lot of
infrastructure up to cloud
azure google workspace aws
um the ramp up of devops and
infrastructure as code has added a lot
of complexities to actually try and
actually do this kind of identity
perimeter
so when we're talking active directory
defense what do we know
no privilege compromise is key
if you haven't got privilege you can't
move laterally you can't move laterally
you can't gain king city kingdom so if
you gain access to privilege you can
turn a small breach
into essentially a big breach and you
know
lose control over what access to your
systems
um even more so if you've got
your domain admins or those kind of
sensitive accounts they will have access
to data
across your environment also you know
which leads to obviously data theft
ransomware tax compression we've seen it
recently
um where big organizations are actually
paying out
ransomware attacks because you know
they've got no choice
so when we're talking about attack
patterns
what we're seeing you know what we
understand
and you know these are these are real
world attack patterns these are actually
methods that bad actors insider threats
are actually utilizing
um in most organizations when they try
to breach
most recently in a large finance
institution
we was engaged from an ad protection
and a response kind of
engagement and we went up against the
red team and what we're seeing here is
exactly what i did
you know they've compromised an account
that count then
compromised a credential uh that had
privileged
that then used that privilege to
escalate move laterally
gain access to a domain controller and
then
try to do things like dc sync gain
access to more credentials so
no this is an attack chain it has to
have a starting point it has an end goal
so a starting point is always a
compromise
you need a compromise a credential in
order to actually do something
someone needs to be able to click on a
link for ransomware
attack but you know they can click on
that ring if they don't have access
you know they can't get anywhere anyway
so anywhere along this chain we can
actually interrupt you know a chain can
be broken
you know it has many links many kinks we
can interrupt
that at any stage to prevent that
precision attack
so that's kind of what we have we've
discussed what we're talking about
um with our customers and it kind of
leads on to some interesting
conversations around you know
do you actually understand your
environment you know
it's not all about the main evidence
yeah yeah we know we've got we've got a
pam solution
you know we've got all of our privileged
accounts in there they have to check out
uh you know it's not all about your
domain admins you know you could have
as simple as a help desk person that has
the ability to reset a password
that help this person can reset a
password of a user account
that has the ability to modify the
modified group member
that group could actually be applied to
something like your admin sd card and
have actually seen this
in customers environments um this
particular report we see here is
actually through stealth bits
um it's a shadow access report we've
actually shown this in customers
environments and had
you could hear a pin drop in the room
hey guys this account that you said yeah
there's no we don't worry about it if
that's compromise it has
the risk of actually compromising a lot
more than
what you believe it can so it leads the
conversation down to
you know what can we do red forest is
too difficult it's too expensive
the new thing now is zero standing
privilege which is essentially where you
want to get to
unfortunately to get to zero standing
privilege you need to understand where
you've got privilege
um and that's not just by um through
domain admins or schemer admins or these
horrible security groups that shouldn't
have anyone
but you know it could be by delegate
rights by
nested groups circling nested groups you
know you could be getting access without
even knowing you're getting access
so it boils down to essentially a kind
of
um approach that you need to take so
with least
least privilege also you're a standing
privilege you know you're reducing your
take better that's great
you know reducing the risk of your
actual if an account was to be
compromised
doesn't matter you can't actually do
anything that's going to be dangerous to
your environment
but you've still got to get to that
point
and with that comes ad hygiene
unfortunately
when i talk to customers about ad
hygiene it's like
you know yeah we do it we do it you know
we've got pam we've got
you know we have processes in place to
do stuff in the background automatically
for our hr systems and
stuff like that and so okay cool let's
have a conversation about that
you know we'll go in and essentially
this is the
approach we need to take right we'll go
in and we'll infantry your environment
and we'll generate you some reports
we'll show you
conditions in your environment that you
think you've got control of
but actually no you haven't now
as little as i think four weeks ago at
this exact same
exercise a very very large organizing
we're talking about 200 to 250
000 users seats and they were purely
focused on
what can you detect can you detect
golden tickets can you detect past hash
silver tickets and that it's like great
why do you need to detect that
oh you know because we need to be able
to respond to instances and it's like
okay but what are the chances
do you understand the chances of that
actually happening in your environment
and what what protections have you
actually got in place before it even
gets that point it's like yeah yeah you
know we're really really confident about
our
user accounts and you know the controls
and the
access rights that we've got in place
okay great i generated one report which
was a sensitive security group report
basically this report shows you everyone
that's in your out of the box sensitive
groups you domain admin scheme admins
enterprise admins and within that report
we'll actually show you some detail
around
the accounts of those members so one
they had
15 accounts in the enterprise managers
group
uh no sorry the schema admins group
which was like okay
guys already a bad idea
we then run a report to actually
identify where they've got weak password
utilization in their environment
so essentially compared against the
dictionary of passwords that were used
in known breaches globally like 600
million passwords whatever it was
um we showed them everywhere where they
actually had we password utilization in
the organization
we also showed you of all those accounts
which ones were admins
this is where the penny dropped again
you could hear the pin drop
the one of the admin guys that were on
the call was in the list
of them in a weak password we then delve
deeper into that and you said okay well
you've got weak password utilization is
quite bad you've got
historical weak password utilization but
more concerning you've also got shared
password utilization
so again okay you want to be able to
detect things like
advanced persistent attacks passwords
brain attacks
if you have an account that's compromise
or a password spray on attack that's
successful
and you've got shared password
utilization in your environment you've
now
compromised several accounts
unnecessarily so what does that tell us
that tell us basically your password
policy is not secure enough you know
you don't need to reduce the increase
the frequency of password resets
but you do need to consider the actual
complexities and utilization of
passwords in your environment
so again the conversation has swiftly
kind of gone from
i want to detect and respond to okay i
need to build stronger foundations i
need to
secure my uh my active virtual
environment i need to reduce
the attack pathway and that's really
where these conversations
we'll have in these sort of
conversations five years ago you know 80
hygiene here's your report
you know microsoft or some third party
company will come in and go this
this needs to be done we've done this
poor configuration active directory
we're still seeing exactly the same
issues so
we kind of when we talk about that story
of you know id defense you know
things you need to do to better your
security posture
always start with the conversation about
ad hygiene the reason is that's where
your credentials are stored
that's where your accounts are that's
where typically you get
the rights to authenticate against your
file systems which
as well your corporate data which is
your sensitive information so
it's not something that we should be
taking lightly you know i know it's
fancy these days to talk about saws and
instant sponsor and machine learning but
unless you get the basic rights it
doesn't really matter
so the five five-step approach that we
typically take you know infantry and
analyze
it doesn't take much to actually
understand
what your active directory environment
looks like you know 80's been around for
20 years or not so now lots of mergers
lots of migrations
lots of changes have happened in
environment you know in source and
outsourcing all this adds to
complexities in active directory
where no one actually knows what is
going on
so infantry and analyzer information
find out where you've got toxic
conditions
poor conditions such as you know circle
and nested groups you know
style users users that haven't logged in
for x amount of months you know do they
need to be in the environment no well if
they're not being utilized
get rid of them stripping them out of
their group membership
put them into a disabled ou no one still
wants them
delete them for a period of time so
these are basic things that any
operation teams can actually do and you
can automate
quite simply um so that's that kind of
clean up phase let's
reduce the amount of mess we have in
active directory let's make it cleaner
let's make it easier
to find where we have issues now we can
actually monitor so we've cleaned up all
the stuff that's now relevant
now we know what stuff is relevant
what's privileged accounts
um what user accounts are not
necessarily highly privileged but we
need to actually monitor for
so we can actually look for monitor
changes for those particular accounts
any unusual behavior once we understand
that then you can protect those you can
put blocking policies in place you can
remove privilege altogether with these
kind of five steps
you know this is how we're actually
getting um
to that point where we can go you know
what we can actually safely now look
at that zero standing privilege so
with zero standing privileges you know
people already they go yeah but you know
i've got a pam solution
i went into a customer uh last year
um just to do some sort of true up and
we kind of did a health check
and was like okay great we actually see
that their user account went up by 2 000
users
we analyzed those users there were 2 000
pound accounts
so great you've got the accounts under
control
but they still have privilege they still
have privilege at rest they're still
subject to compromise um and if i don't
know if anyone has actually looked at
some of the passwords or even curated
the dictionary um to
passwords that have been used more than
once in the breaches
there's some complex passwords in there
that are actually from those kind of
faults within those pam solutions so
if we need to get to that zero standard
approach well what can actually we do
um you know
what can we do yes don't panic for one
don't ignore it and turn away i'll
actually get to some stories about
real life scenarios where customers have
actually done that
and i've come back and seen it they've
done that um but what can we do
with um zero standing privilege well a
modern pound solution
should have the ability to create
privileged accounts
on the flyer what that gives you the
ability to do is
create those accounts give the right
just when they need the rights when
you're done with it
revert the change delete the account
there is no count that rest there's no
privilege at rest
apart from the account that you utilize
in which you will have monitor
you'll have control you'll have
protected one account is a lot
more one to five accounts is a lot
easier to control than 2 000 accounts
so that's kind of some of the
recommendations and how our
conversations actually steer
so why do we want that
kind of you know the mitigation the risk
reduction
um understand and reduce the uh the
attack pathway
at the moment if you speak to any sock
you know there's death by dashboard
they've got millions of different
dashboards through their scene platform
showing them all statistics that they're
not really pretty paying attention to
if you're sending everything up it gets
harder to actually identify
where you do have a problem where you
have been breached someone could try and
slip under there with
what looks like usual you usual user
behavior but you don't know because
you've got a million events
so what you actually want to try and do
is actually reduce the events that are
actually going up to your sync platform
you want to do that obviously for a
number reasons one operational cost
seems ain't cheap the storage
utilization from a lot of these things
platforms
then they talk about data retention yeah
you know minimum 12 month day retention
the same platform
storage becomes a big big concern than a
big cost you know
you don't necessarily need to do that
you're not seeing all noise events up
there
so reduce that noise to event ratio it's
keeps for actually a successful
you know sock being able to do their job
the other thing is is if you've got too
much information
you just might be overwhelmed and just
ignore it
i'll say that because i've experienced
it actually our customer
had a customer recall saying hey what do
these alerts mean
i jumped on them i go okay we'd only
enabled analytics and these were
basically these were threshold based on
leaks they weren't even machine learning
or anything
smart every one of them had triggered
and i mean like a christmas tree trigger
so
i reviewed the data and i was like guys
you're actually generally
been breached you're actually under
attack so we said
this is the ip address where it's coming
from it's an external app address
these are the accounts that have been
compromised you've got concurrent logins
from the same account across 20 machines
within the last
three minutes that's not useful
behaviour so this is what you need to do
so we actually gave them
an action plan just for their network
team to
prevent that happy address from getting
into the environment we told them these
are the accounts that you need to
reset maybe remove privilege temporarily
until you understand what the actual
damage is done
and it was like okay great great you
know we'll get back to you until then so
a week's past
haven't heard anything let me contact
this customer and find out what's going
on jumped on a cordless customer they'd
switched all the analytics off
i was like did you manage to do it's
like no because that was just too much
noise we were getting too much
you know too much feedback from our
management so we just switched it off
these guys had all the right tools
they just got too overwhelmed because
they didn't utilize the tools that they
had
effectively they didn't utilize the
actual ad hygiene so they had a lot of
privileged accounts that they didn't
even know they had
um and essentially they just they kind
of just gave up
so it's um it is a real world scenario
it does happen and it's quite
frightening
this particular company was a utilities
company as well and considering
what's recently happened in the us it's
quite frightening to actually understand
that's the case so
the problem then becomes well where does
it sit
it's an operational task is there a
security task
that's you know that's debatable but
really this is where
that uh that team segmentation needs to
kind of
needs to be dropped you know your
security team should be working with
your operational team
to understand that pathway so both teams
can act and um be proactive
and not reactive to actually when it
comes to active directory uh defense
um there was another one recently
where um
we actually did a just a quick poc
um we did it in a cloud lab and the
customer was like this is really really
good because it was all that fancy
threat detection stuff
it was like we'd like to poc it in our
environment so sure
sure we'll get on the call with them we
installed
20 minutes inventory their environment
showed them some of the key reports
so again um sensiem security group
membership was incredibly high and
really really stupid
they had accounts in there that were
clearly generic accounts with password
ages over a three years um passwords
were set to never expire
you know you're just asking for trouble
when you've got conditions in your
environment
they're that bad right so
we recommended okay your first approach
you need to clean up you need to reduce
your
uh your freight uh front pathways so
you've got
a better indication when it comes to
that detection response
um we talked about um
breaking that attack chain how can we
break that attack chain
you know um i think a lot of the
conversation at the beginning
was around you know detection of stolen
tickets they were obsessed with stolen
tickets
it's like great to get us that to
actually steal a ticket you need
privilege
you know in order for you to gain
privilege you need to go and compromise
your account
the conversation comes back to the root
cause ad hygiene
you know reduced amount of
over-production access you've got
reduce the the chance or you know you
don't want to give the keys
to an attacker and make it easy for them
you know if you put up enough hurdles
they will give up
that's you know i mean there was some
studies recently to actually act
um that pointed to the fact that you
know with enough kinks in a chain or
enough breaks in that chain
and a bad actor will just give up and
move on to its next target
you know so now you can start looking at
well what controls can i do
you know everyone wants to be a domain
admin when you're talking to operation
teams i need to i know i used to work in
an operational team
so i'm speaking from experience when
we'll get an order in and the high life
team
members go oh but i need i need the main
admin to do my job
what rights within the main open do you
actually need to do i need to log into a
server
you don't need domain names to do that
oh i i need to do
this web server application and stuff
you don't need the main evidence to do
that
so it starts to become the cleanup of
essentially lazy it
you know i know from getting up at four
in the morning for a
a call that's because i'm on call
evening and a server has gone down and
you're trying to find your credentials
you're trying to wake up and remember
what it is you actually need to be doing
so if you're putting too many obstacles
in place
and over complicate your security um
policies
your admins will work around those
policies it's
it's an unfortunate fact whether that's
the case um
so it's definitely focus should always
your initial focus should always be
understanding of my attack pathways
and that applies to not just you know
your privilege you know you can when
you're looking at things like
patch management patch management's easy
if you've got a small fleet of endpoints
but when you're talking
hundreds and thousands of endpoints
where do you do your patch management
understanding just because it's a
critical patch
understanding well if i don't apply this
patch
how can i be compromised how hard is it
to be compromised
and if that patch is compromised well
what can i do once they've compromised
it can they move laterally
if they can move laterally what service
can they con service can they get
and then you can start going well i
understand this attack path right now
these are the servers that i will
actually patch first the other rest of
the fleet
minimal risk doesn't matter we'll patch
those on a
tight skirt not such a tight schedule
and then that way it actually allows you
to get in front of your patch management
again all about understanding your risk
reducing that risk pathway
um to enable you to actually be able to
detect and respond
be react don't be reactive be proactive
is what is the message there really
so um so with that i just if anyone got
any questions
do we have any we certainly do um
so we've got simon asks how often should
an organization
undergo your type of ad assessments
the type of reporting we actually talk
about here
you know they take minutes to run
you could do them once a week in fact
the the bulk of the work for any sort of
clean up
you know once you get the bulk of the
work done and then you move on to that
monitor and protect
you shouldn't see those conditions
reappear you're protecting those objects
you're preventing
those types of changes from occurring
again
you're preventing weak passwords to be
set so you won't have any passwords
so typically when we actually set these
things up we run these reports once a
week
once a week any changes no you know once
you've done the remediation
those reports should be looking pretty
blank fair enough
another question here from scott how
many companies
actually implement red forest approach
in my experience i have
seen two one still in trying to do it
and one didn't actually do true red
forest they just did segmentation of
active directory
and was it effective no it was too hard
for them to maintain
when we used to talk to them about okay
so what you're actually doing to put
those controls in is
the first thing that you could hear it's
a big sign saying it's an administrative
nightmare
and it's a financial headache so that's
where
um where microsoft themselves have now
changed shift and said you know
that zero standard privilege is the best
approach you know
it's it's actually a lot easier to
achieve
than most people think if you have a
right pam solution for one
they can actually give that just in time
access
and then remove that privilege at rest
and you've done that id hygiene you
clean up then you're actually
your security posture is going to be
greatly greatly
increased fair enough where's the
majority of the cost
in you know you come in you see the
state it is
is the majority in the cleaner or is it
in the licensing to run this
over time the licensing
yeah so the licensing is actually not
that
expensive when you consider what would
happen if you're breached
um i think that recent ransomware attack
saying like
75 bitcoins have five million dollars
you're not spending five million dollars
software licensing to actually do the
right thing
so operationally
i think that first three to six months
to actually
go through change control understand
what you've got going on
um and do the cleanup but once you've
got there the cost of running the actual
software itself once everything's in
place
you know you might have to you might
have initial outlay for professional
services or something like that to
actually get you into a
point where it's configured and you're
ready to go and it's just minor tweaks
operationally then that operational cost
drops obviously you then have the
reduction in infrastructure required
and yeah i don't know um just one that i
thought of
what would be the way you would sell
this
and very simplistically up to sort of
board level what are the
what's the key risk or two that you're
really mitigating at that
so in my experience um i've been sitting
with sale guys for three days so
i've got a green glow you understand why
um
my experience is present an executive
report of
high low medium risk we'll do
we can go in and actually run a
different sets of jobs from these
reports and actually give you an
executive summary ago this is your
top ten risk and then we you can
actually associate um a financial
implication to those risks
whether it be compliance um
whether it be what would be the cost if
you were breached
um what's the cost of your reputation
and that dependent on the industry so
reputation within the industry
especially when you're
dealing with customer information is
everything you can't pull price on that
have an anonymous question here which is
what additional value can you bring if
we already have an ad
audit plus well we can come in and
actually
review so this really is more of an
agnostic approach this is you know this
is what we're seeing guys if you've got
an auditing platform that gives you this
information already
you know we're happy to come in and
actually review and assist
to say okay this is the areas that you
should be looking at
um do you have that information if you
don't okay this is how you can get that
information
any more questions coming in anyone
typing at the moment
no no well that's good
thank you ricky cool excellent thanks
everyone thanks everyone
guys
[Music]
but i might be somebody you might not
even
i'm going through changes
[Music]
strangers
but i might be somebody you might not
even know
i'm going through changes it's a roller
coaster but i might be somebody
you might not even know
[Music]
so funny
[Applause]
[Music]
you can take this level
we're gonna take it
i could watch you for a lifetime
you're my favorite movie
a thousand endings
you mean everything to pay