right apparently we're now live
good afternoon welcome to the final
breakout session of 2021
my name is valdemar jacobson from brook
security and i'm your chair this
afternoon
for our final session the breakout
stream we have the
mike ish and leon show mike's apparently
not going to be saying an awful lot
today
giving us a review of the bdo and
ozzer's 2020 cyber security survey
results
for anybody here who wishes to follow
along or anybody who should follow along
at home if you have a look in the q a
section
i've already dropped the link to the
registration page so you can download
the full survey results and have a look
there
but um we'll be getting the most
interesting highlights uh
from leon and uh and mike this afternoon
please make them feel welcome
good afternoon uh i think we've got a
great deal shift so between uh
between now and coffee break so we'll
try to keep it entertained
um
so this is actually the sixth year mark
that we've done the survey so we got a
lot of good
good insights and data so what we want
to talk through today is
um i think just take a bit of a step
back we've been through covet
um when i prepared this i wanted to sort
of look through what
bid organizations the journey they've
gone on during
preparation and response to gobit look
at some of the threats that
the profile has changed and then looking
at our data
again going through the life cycle of
what organizations have sort of gone
through
during covet what are some of the stats
that we've seen coming out
and then we're going to leave you guys
with um and girls with some
um some thoughts around how to manage
risk going forward
so in preparing for for this
presentation um
i was sort of doing a bit of research
trying to get some other data on
um how investments have actually gone
into covert
because if i reflect our own
organization in consultancy so we're
well prepared
it's easy to sort of send us back home
but i was actually calling the bank
um probably four or five months into
working from home
and it dawned on me there's a call
center and that person at a call center
was actually sitting at home
so that then sort of dropped a penny to
me is
look we prepared we're going home but
typically someone sitting in a call
center
did they get issued a company laptop
when they started
probably not but they're also working
from home
and if you look at the stats um sort of
the growth
of digital adoption and what normally
would have taken
um a year to sort of implement
technology is now fast track and if you
look at in
apac regions specifically it's sort of
four years of
digital implementations
sort of done within a year and i think
what's probably
reason for that is a lot of call centers
service centers are sitting in our
region
and that's that to me is admit i don't
haven't validated that but i think
that's the only sort of analogy that i
can draw on on that adoption
now that those because a few of you that
i remember
each year coming to the session each
time we sort of put up what is a
world economic forum um saying about uh
cyber risk and where does it sit
so unsurprising this year um
we got the crisis around um
infectious diseases as opposed to
sitting now top there we've got that as
a most likely a risk
what we've seen is cyber has actually
dropped off from a likelihood
perspective
but if you look at what's sort of still
sitting around those it's difficult
risk that you can actually manage the
likelihood of that happening so
really it's about addressing the impact
now this year's survey and i really
encourage you to sort of go and read
that report from the world economic
forum
i think it's a section that's dedicated
on yes if you take out
covet and what are the risks then from a
what are the concerns for people and
organizations over the next couple of
years
and then cyber is back and within the
top five
um and the other one is sort of popping
up that's quite interesting
is um sort of the adoption of digital
technologies or the lack thereof
and i think specifically in
underdeveloped countries
it's probably going to be difficult to
keep on working remotely so it's
interesting to see
how that's going to pan out over the
next couple of years
now if you look at the sources of
threats and i was really
looking forward to sort of get the stats
from this year's survey or last year's
survey
and what we've seen is that there's
still a big concern
and has been an uptake of reported and
this is not
attributed attacks it's basically asking
the respondents to
sort of give their own view of where the
threats and risks were coming from
so there's an increase in foreign
activity and we've seen that a steadily
increase
what is interesting there's a decrease
in concern around
service providers or data center
providers but then there's a steady
uptake in concern around supply chain
as well as insiders on employees
the next one i want to talk to you about
is basically if you look at
um the types of security incidents that
has happened and the the graph there is
basically the the bar chart on the left
hand side is saying it's the incidence
that actually was
that we that was reported last year the
line that's sort of through there is to
show the same question we asked the year
before
is what are your concerns that you
expect in the coming year
and this is a keep on a trend coming up
that phishing
when you ask the question what's your
concern for the next year it's not a
bigger concern but if you look at the
data coming through
it's still fairly high data loss and
concern around
that is a is a major concern so
organizations are really concerned about
data loss but if you look at the results
coming through
it's not really that big
mike thanks leon um oh you can hang on
to that i guess
so what we've actually done obviously
with this survey
is because this goes out to all of our
members and it goes out to all of bdo's
clients
you've got quite a good reach across the
nation to gather those statistics
and of course that's great you've got
statistics that tell a story and they
really do tell a story
what really rams that home i suppose for
me at least
is when you then compare that to actual
incident data that's been collected
uh by us by the analysts that work in
osset because these are the ones that
are actually dealing with those
incidents as they're coming through
from all of our members in this country
and new zealand
so what we actually ended up doing and
this this only came up
literally in the last couple of days in
fact there was a conversation between
uh one of the uh senior security people
at one of the universities
and one of the analysts here at this
conference actually one of uh assets
analysts
and the conversation went around well
what can we actually learn
from the information that we have
available to us now what can we actually
do with that
and someone suggested look
i think phishing actually increases
whenever there is exam blocks at the
university
so it makes sense right so you look at
this graph
you can actually see um and you'll have
to excuse the format
we've done this in iso weeks not not
dates so just use your imagination
count the number of weeks you can
literally see the four
distinct exam blocks so obviously the
attackers understand
students are distracted there's other
things they're doing they're more likely
to just click through the phishing link
and give their credentials
so here's a real life example of
effectively
know your enemy but what then can you do
about it well obviously that's where you
go to things like education programs
user education more fishing training
never victim victim blaming of course
but certainly giving some kind of
training at targeted times to combat
those
those threats we might just go to the
next slide please
leon and from here you can actually see
the wider picture so i showed you a very
very small
piece of statistics before just the
fishing
spread out across the iso weeks this is
all of the incidents that
assert um faces and uh guess what the
biggest one is
it's fishing again so that correlates
exactly with the the data that we saw
come through the survey
and it actually inspired um we saw this
coming obviously
you can see in statistics you can see
whenever there's a ramp up
and we saw this coming quite a long time
ago and one of our senior analysts
um that works in offset actually uh sort
of threw out all of our old processes
and
systems and said we can do this better
and decided that there was a way that
you could workflow
taking a phishing site understanding
what the
the tools techniques and practices were
of that particular example
catalog it put it into a system and then
track the incident through to completion
incidentally i was just in nick
pratley's talk
next door this way i think and part of
the saw
process is actually to build those
playbooks up over time
we might not have necessarily been
calling it saw when we were doing it but
we were actually following that process
what we now have is a fully automated
system that can take a url
go and examine that site collect the the
image of what what's happening on that
thing
uh gather information about the site how
long it's been up when was the domain
registered
all of that sort of stuff and then
obviously bring that to a closure and
that's something that we're really good
at because we've got those contacts from
uh you know 20 something 27 years of
being assert
so uh you can use like statistics uh you
know sounds like a boring topic but you
can actually use it
to do real life improvements to your saw
examples
back to you leon uh just interesting you
see the
the sort of a looks like a cycle any
comments on
any insights on that we incidentally we
changed between the 2019 calendar year
and the 2020 calendar year we completely
changed our
incident tracking system and ergo all of
the classification schemes
so as we did that we we obviously
reclassified all the different
categories and everything
but what you'll see is distinct trends
towards certain points of the year
now past life i was in banking what
happens in
march into march is usually easter
now at easter time believe it or not the
banks actually see
more transaction flows because it's a
short period of time everyone's on
holidays
they see a higher transaction flow there
than christmas even
so that's my suggestion why the march
one might actually be an increase in
incidents because there's more activity
then you go further throughout the year
what happened last year well we all got
locked down in maine brisbane
covert took in and then in september a
lot of us were then back
out so there were obviously new threats
and new things that we were doing
that was our take on this but you may
have a different idea and feel free to
send that through in the app and we'll
discuss it thanks mike
so if you now look at we've really
looked at typical
where we've gone through in in the
covert journey so we started off
really responding to um to covet so we
we send people home
want to make sure that they're
productive a lot of organizations then
realize that look they're not
really ready to um to work from home
so we started there's a bit of
investment going in and you can talk to
any of the software
vendors and hardware vendors there's a
big sales coming in
then it started to okay well we've now
invested let's start
adopting the way we we we work through
this
and then it's about starting assess how
well are we working we've now started
adopting
and i think we're now in a phase where
we start looking at
trying to sustain us and a good example
one of our government clients approached
us and saying
we go it's happened we've been sort of
not operational
it's a court system we want to actually
keep on running
courts so we wanted to just you to come
into the risk assessment not a technical
assessment
a risk assessment of the video
conferencing environment making sure
that
it's okay and sustainable and i would
say that was probably sitting in
during the um the invest phase
they wanted to before they roll it out
just to have a bit of a rapid risk
assessment
and then six months later because it was
going to be a short-term solution
um they just wanted to get get it
running and then towards the end of last
year they contact us again
saying you know what this is actually
working well why don't you just come and
do a penetration test now and making
sure that
actually we've plucked all the holes and
the point i'm making there is that we're
starting to see organizations now
it was just about responding sending
people home they've changed the whole
business operation
and this is something we're going to
keep on uh having to um
to be aware of so then what i wanted to
do is actually
looking at each of those phases and
looking at the type of results we're
getting through
and so from my adapt and assess sorry
from a respondent invest is really
we're sending people home and
interesting um what we're seeing is that
there was a lot more reports going to
the board so there's a lot more
communication
happening between the head of security
and sort of checking in to see are we
seeing more incidents so that's a great
thing
seeing that that investment's been there
interestingly
although most organizations saying they
they invested in additional
technology what we see coming through
was
there wasn't really something that's
standing out
the only one sort of stood out as
patching started to increase
i think just the security teams probably
had to apply
new technology and which is why they
started to apply new patches
but nothing else sort of stood out as
really um
we started investing in that so now
we're in the
you adapt and assess so that's the face
where we've done the investment
um and now let's just take a step back
making sure that we
sort of understand the risk where we're
sitting
and again what's coming out there is
that there's more risk assessments
that's undertaken which is actually a
great thing
but it's one thing to do a risk
assessment if you've got a good baseline
and if you look at they're still not
really great baselines to find and you
would expect that at least
now that the business environment's
changed your risk posture has changed so
your requirements
should have changed to do those
assessments
and then the other one is a fairly
minor step up in getting capability for
instant response because now your team
your work for sitting at home um so
there's more capability that
sort of acquired i don't know mike did
you you guys see more members coming on
board
um during the covert period actually we
did leon the
um our membership team obviously uh work
all year round and you know last year
was no different
and we were sort of thinking um you know
obviously
there'll be a downturn in business
because like everything
um you know cyber security funds in
organizations may be cut
but we actually saw not only a
continuation
but a slight spike as well so there was
definitely an investment at least
towards
offset services
so now we're looking at we're in the
sustain phase and what we
looked at is um we've sort of defined
and identified
the top five controls or areas of um
of where we've seen investment it's gone
into from a preparedness perspective so
what they looked at is that those
organizations that
were not prepared before and those that
are now um
have gone well and they responded well
to covet
what were the things that they actually
had in place and we identified that
having a sizo in place having a security
operations capability to actually
respond to something that should happen
it's doing those regular risk
assessments investing in
awareness training and then the last one
is really around
having that instant response plan and
capability in place
so if you look at we don't really have a
lot of data
to sort of try to align back to the
theme there's a few questions around
threat intelligence and we just looked
at
those organizations that had threat
intelligence capability
how well were they aligned to the
business objectives and we seen that
there's definitely a trend there um
then we also looked at those
organizations that had
threat intelligence capability in
receiving that
what were the quantum of the
preparedness when
you look at data breaches and cyber
incidents
and i was actually a bit surprised to
see that i expected
if you have got ctr you should be better
prepared but that's not really coming
out in in our statistics um i don't know
my minor thinking around that is that i
think there's a lot more
intelligence out there or in freight
information i'm not sure if it's
actionable
um but it's probably something we'll
look at in incoming surveys i don't know
mike you've got any thoughts on that
absolutely leon the the thing that we've
discovered over the last couple of years
is you can have all of the threat
intelligence in the world
it's obviously what you then can do with
that in terms of your own internal
capability
and uh you know look as an employer of
analysts um
who are motivated more by seeing
advancement in cyber security and seeing
threats mitigated in our members
they really appreciate when they can
actually do some good with our members
so imagine our dismay when we
you know we started operating the the
court at isaac if anyone's familiar with
the university sector the higher
education sector here we're running a
information sharing and analysis center
in there there's a couple of
uh you know really key players in that
area a couple of universities are
contributing intelligence back into that
assert obviously is doing a lot of the
analysis and
threat correlation and curation of the
data that's in there and that's great
but in terms of actually getting that
actionable
cyber threat intelligence out of that
system or out of that repository
and into your institution in a form that
you can use
that was where you know we we sort of we
almost ran up against a brick wall in
some regards because
the capability just simply wasn't there
in a lot of institutions
sure that you know the top end of town
the group of eight universities not a
problem
um but some of them literally had you
know one person
doing cyber security uh for the whole
university
and actually being able to then process
that into something that will defend
against threats was difficult
so we had to shift gear in terms of what
are we actually going to do for those
organizations
and that's where of course your training
and maturity uplift
kicks in so it's it's not as easy as it
seems
yeah i think i mean if you look last
year's 2020 cyber strategy one of the
components in there was to actually
really
up and build up our threat intelligence
capability
i was talking to the queensland
government qd
cdg folks oscillator stand
out in in the vendor area and it was
actually quite interesting a lot of
startups there is really working around
threat intelligence
open source intelligence collection so i
think it's great to see that
um the government's actually really
putting the effort into supporting the
strategy
and we're definitely seeing that there's
a lot of activity in that space so
um hopefully we can talk more about that
in in the next session
so sort of just to then step back and
say um
what are what are sort of my key
takeaways looking at
go with the last um 12 months looking at
the survey results coming through
and we don't want to really use the word
new norm because
i think it's overused but really there's
four things for me that that stood out
that
i think we need to keep in mind the
first one is uh
around we're sending the workforce been
sent home
we communicate remotely so i think it's
important that we
as practitioners and and owners of
organizations understanding
what is the risk to actually working
remotely
looking at that mckinsey report that
sort of showed the adoption of
technology that would normally would
have taken a year
takes has now been sorry would have
taken three to four years
it's been done in a year i don't think
enough
analysis and assessment was done around
that the next one is around actually
storage of
information and data in the cloud a lot
of organizations that
weren't prepared necessarily to work
remotely have started adopting
cloud technologies are we sure that we
understand what's going in there
are we classifying the information are
we monitoring that
i think the other one is really the
human firewall
um i've been thinking about this is
we've almost think about it as
um you created your workforce is your
army you send them
home you're prepared to give them all
the technology
and tools to sort of be ready to be
sitting in the trenches
but have we provided enough training to
them because that's the first barrier
of activity i mean if we look at
ourselves myself
i'm getting probably three to four times
more emails a day than what i got
a year ago now i'm a security
practitioner so i can sort of
work through that but if you look at
that call center
individual that didn't get issued a
laptop
but they know working from home um
probably on their own technology
see i think it's important that we need
to make sure our own staff but also our
supplier staff are probably educated
and then i think the last one is really
if it all goes wrong at least have a
plan in place to respond to that
because if i look at all the
investigations that we've been
involved in where there's been a data
breach
one of the main things that's sort of
standing out is there was not a plan
we were trying to make it up yes we had
a plan but no one followed the plan
um and it wasn't really that touch
points on checking to see are we doing
the right thing
indeed we see exactly the same thing and
one of the most
um i guess i'm not going to use the word
disappointing but
one of the things that just makes you
want to cry is when one of our own
members doesn't have in their incident
response plan
the phone number for the oscert analyst
team
it's a 24x7 number that is is
uh looked after by a team of analysts
all year round
and you know during an incident they'll
have to you know you know what what do i
do
so just having that information there is
the best place to
to be prepared now interestingly i've
just
made a mental connection in my mind just
as i'm standing here
everything that leon has put on this
slide here
was summed up extremely well in jess
dodson's speak
a speech yesterday morning girl james on
twitter if you if you don't know her
um she's actually written almost
effectively this exact
sequence in a checklist and i i said
afterwards to her i said for a small
business that doesn't have a capability
like
you know being able to reach out to leon
or or even
a not-for-profit organization like us
that checklist that she's put up
takes you through these sorts of things
in
a language that a small business would
be able to understand and cope with
um if not hand out to an msp or
something like that to actually
implement
so the tools are definitely there for
any range of business
top end of town all the way down to
small to medium enterprise
so yeah um if you look at those four
there it's not
technology is not going to solve that
problem um and i think if that's the
the message there is around it's all
about the people in the process not
saying technology is not important but
it's the people and process side
that's us
thanks mike and leon we do have a couple
of questions from the audience
um first of all is um can you give us
any insights
on the uptake of cyber insurance
especially over the last year
that one's for you leon um
we we did focus a lot of energy in
previous
surveys but to be honest it's not
something we specifically looked at
but in reflection on a few presentations
here and
just some of the the incidents that we
helped investigate it
um insurance companies definitely is
starting to to get more involved in that
i think insurance providers are getting
better at actually providing
insurance cover for that so yeah
definitely there's been a small uptake
but unfortunately i don't have the
statistics
we can we can provide that data to you
i think just another uh brain
um synapses flop fired i remember
thinking when i was working through an
incident
um with with one of our members i
remember thinking
i'm actually surprised what cyber
insurance covers
so in terms of i mean obviously the um
the damages but also in the cleanup
operation
there are a lot of aspects there that
you may not know are actually covered
so i guess if you do have cyber
insurance you like any insurance policy
you better read it
make sure you know what you're getting
good
good so that question does it come from
your audience here or someone online
uh it's from anonymous so i'm afraid i
can't uh tell you that
do you work for an insurance company
here oh just i mean if
that person is around just grab me
afterwards we can get the statistics and
share it with you
otherwise they can now get your contact
information from the report or
i don't think we actually got anything
in the report this year i mean it's in
the data so happy to provide that
separately um does the survey survey
highlight which sector has better threat
intelligence and sharing
which sectors sorry does the survey
information or the full data set are you
able to draw conclusions or does it
highlight which
sectors or groups actually um more use
threat intelligence and which ones are
actually sharing intelligence between
themselves
um we got the data but um i we didn't
this year specifically look at that
um i think banking traditionally has
been more actively in sharing that
um so i don't know from your side mike
have you seen more active more members
coming in
um because i know higher education is is
by far the
the biggest members of europe struggling
to find in my mind and a sector that is
doing it better than higher education at
the moment
and it's higher education been
increasing their information yeah oh
yeah
very much so it's a coordinated approach
now
um unique in that sector we heard some
of that last night um with uh
of course awarding simon the cyber
security professional of the year so
he's obviously been helping advance that
which is fantastic to see
um and yeah yes yes simon of course
um and the last question i've actually
got here at the moment um which is a
good one
given the trending information you've
actually been gathering over the last
few years
and given what's happened over the past
18 months
are we still able to use past and
current survey information to actually
give a reasonable prediction of the
future
or did covert 19 in the entire upset to
the business practices of pretty much
every company
throw trust banner in the works i think
that's a really good question
i was looking forward to look at this
year's data given the
um the change in the threat profile
wanted to see
how we've changed investing in security
and
it was surprising to see that there
wasn't that many different changes um
i think you're still you're spending
technology but the technology was still
investing in the same areas
i still think that and this is sort of
the the slide that i showed on
where were we thinking the incident is
going to come from
where do we experience it and what are
our concerns so the concerns is around
supply chain
concerns is around data loss but if you
look at the threats on
all the incidents are not coming through
there so if organizations are concerned
about that
i i personally think that i don't think
we are we've got a handle on
what's the threat in the supply chain
and also then
how much data would you really lose
because we don't classify information if
you look at the investment in data loss
prevention
it is sitting on the order of 70 of
organizations fields they've got in
place
so overall the similar trends you
expected it to be
different but that didn't come through
in the survey results
and we ran it towards the end of last
year so
what is asia's had at least nine months
off covet
okay i don't know whether we want to
take any more questions but we do
still have another few minutes otherwise
people can head off to morning too
early well on behalf of ulcert
thank you leon for your continued work
in this space and mike of course
enjoy afternoon tea everybody we'll be
back here i think it is uh
3 40 3 45 for the speed debate
and so make sure if you haven't been
using the app you do you'll need that to
actually contribute
you