okay ladies and gentlemen welcome back
trust you enjoyed
the many parallel sessions running
through the day a couple of morning and
afternoon tea breaks as well we've now
got two presentations
to get us up to the end of day one here
at ulcer 2021 please keep those social
media
postings going great to see some of the
stuff that people
are sharing uh in a tribute to the new
normal we're now about to take
a speaker zooming in from the other side
of the world before our
ask me anything session with troy hunt
for both of these and in particular the
one for troy
if you've got any questions you want to
ask please hit the q and a
icon in the app this speaker
the founding ceo of the national cyber
security center and now a professor at
the university of oxford
now of course the national cyber
security center you don't need me to
tell you was the uk's world
leading uh institute headed for the
first four years
by this gentleman who now holds a
position of professor of practice in the
management of public organizations at
oxford university's
blavatnik school of government and
advises
nato and a number of private sector
organizations on
cyber strategies i'm hoping that we're
about to see on a big screen
behind me give a round of applause
please for professor kieran martin
all yours take it away um yeah excellent
well i'm really sorry i'm not there in
person it's not entirely my fault
um we just leave the slides down for the
moment if that's all right i think we'll
call them up in about 10 minutes or so
um well
it's fantastic to be here um uh uh
virtually i hope to be back in person i
want to start with one word of
congratulations and two words of
thanks my first word of congratulations
is to also
an organization ahead of its time on
your 20th anniversary
conference i know you've been going for
longer than that but crucial work that
i've long
admired with the business community with
higher education and with
a local government and secondly uh two
words of thanks one is to the next
speaker
i'm slightly i think i'm pleased that
i'm going before him because he's
amazing
and but troy hunt is a global cyber
security treasurer
as a teacher now at a university who
teaches cyber security all i really have
to do
is tell students including world leaders
students in executive education programs
to type in their email to have i've been
pummed and then suddenly i've got their
attention
and the other genuinely is to um
australians
um particularly those in government in
um
in government service at the asd and the
australian cyber security center but
many
other partners as well i had no better
partner i ran uk cyber security for six
and a half years two and a half setting
up the national cyber security center
the other four running it and it was
brilliant
um as part of the five eyes learning so
much from australia's
um expertise and energy
we had our moments i think the uk and
australia are designed to have sometimes
a combustible relationship through time
zones somebody's going to be grumpy
because it's too early or it's too
late or somebody's flown a long way but
we couldn't have any
um better um partner so in the next 25
minutes or so i'm just going to take you
through
the theme of what is an organization
that doesn't exist to do cyber security
supposed to do about it how do we cope
with
all the fear and all the doubt and
the growing um but manageable threat
when we want to be doing something else
we want to be running healthcare we want
to be running businesses
um we want to be running at schools we
just want to be living our lives and the
way we are
and we can't afford always either the
time
or the money just to to make our
organizations about
um cyber security at a time when there's
so much
concern about cyber harm around i mean
look where we are at the minute i doubt
i haven't been obviously because it's
seven in the morning here
i haven't been at the rest of the
conference but i suspect the colonial
pipeline uh case has
um has come up look where we are now in
the united states
we have official government advice in
force today
asking people not to panic by gasoline
or petrol as we call it over here
and put it in plastic bags so if you
wanted
an illustration of the impact of cyber
harms
it would be hard to think of a better
one and in a sense this feeds
all those warnings over years over
decades about
about really difficult cyber impacts
cyber wars cybergeddon and all the rest
of it
the fact that these unstoppable what my
technical director of the national cyber
security center called
winged cyber ninja monkeys um
who were just sitting there in bedrooms
in suburban england suburban australia
teenagers unstoppable hacking everything
and there was nothing we could do to
stop them
and in a sense the panic on the east
coast of the us at the moment seems to
be fueling that narrative
except it's wrong it's absolutely wrong
let's take a look at what's actually
happening in in
in that case we have a bunch of
criminals
they're in over their heads operating
out of russia they've even issued a
partial apology for what they've done
because what they were trying to do
yet again is exploit basic weaknesses in
corporate security all over the world to
make money
and they've gone too far because what
they didn't realize was that by hacking
the it system
of a pipeline company
that that would then cause the company
for whatever reason to shut down um
the pipeline so you have yet again
an accidental spiraling out of control
just as we've had in the past i'll come
to this
where the um where a series of
structural weaknesses in the way we do
cyber security and the way the market
structure the way our organizations are
incentivized
has led to a public impact which is very
very
serious that's the bad news the good
news is when you look at the details of
this
and other cases there are things we can
do
about it we need absolutely to demystify
cybersecurity we have to treat it as an
ordinary um
as an ordinary business um risk
so in a sense what i want to get across
today is that any organization
however big or small whatever it does
has got a bunch of risks that it needs
to manage
the key messages i've got for you today
are
cyber cyber threats cyber risks
they're not catastrophes cyber harms are
the aggregation of small harms
hype fear uncertainty doubt that is our
enemy
what we need to do instead is understand
the who
the why what and the house
of cyber security we need to identify
the risk in each organization
and manage it accordingly it will differ
between risks
and between organizations and finally
smaller organizations any organizations
can do this so if we could just call up
the
first slide and just put it through what
i've done
here is because
in my time in government i was so
frustrated with
the whole fear uncertainty and doubt of
cyber security
um i don't know if we're getting the
slides up i can't i i i can't see
and because i was so um annoyed with the
fear and certainty and back to cyber
security as soon as i left what i did
was
i drew up a chart
of harm and this wasn't scientific
this wasn't meant to be um
saying this is all the harm in cyber
security
i was saying in six and a half years
running
cyber security for a major economy this
is what i saw
and it's absolutely based on the reality
of everyday cyber security so i don't
know if you can see
a nine box grid a taxonomy of cyber
uh of of of of cyber horn
what you will see in the bottom right is
catastrophic cyber harm
and by that and there's an asterisk
beside that and that's because
that is the one thing that has not
happened
there have been all sorts of cyber
attacks having many many of them
and the one thing that we can still say
thankfully is that the official death
toll caused by
cyber harms is zero there was a very sad
case
in germany last year where an um
where a patient on a heroic hospital and
had to be diverted to a different
hospital because of ransomware attack
but the german authorities couldn't
uh causely link to criminal justice
standards
the um um
the death of this patient to this cyber
attack so what we haven't had is the
catastrophic sort of attack what we've
had instead
is this whole state of sight of
categories of harm
caused and these are the ones that i uh
saw in my time
in uh government so what
uh what have we seen instead we've seen
three categories of harm they're called
getting robbed getting weakened and
getting
hurt i'll just walk you through them
quickly pausing on some of them and then
we'll walk through some case studies
because these are the sorts of things
that happen to real organizations
all the time people get cash stolen from
them
everyone's after cash as they can get
that can range from
first insulin i dealt with as head of
the national cyber security center was
an attempt
to brute force attack our national
lottery here in the uk
in order to get some uh in order to get
some cash
thankfully we managed to stop the attack
i'd like to be able to say they didn't
get away with any money
they actually go away with 13 pounds 50
so in one respect we failed on the other
hand
given that cyber security is about the
reduction of harm i'm reasonably happy
uh with that at the other end of the
scale
some north korean hackers in 2016
uh hacked the bank of bangladesh through
its um
the end point of the swift into bank
clearance system and they made off with
81 million dollars and had it not been
for a mistake in the english language
which alerted um regulators in new york
it would have been 850 million
you get into the more sophisticated
getting rolled you get into ip theft the
chinese state as we'll see in a minute
voraciously seeks the intellectual
property of other countries as part of
its getting rich
um strategy you get into data theft at
an
industrial scale and we need to
understand the different gradations of
data theft
because there's a huge criminal
underworld that sells and monetizes this
data
so it can match my email all the stuff
on how i've been honed and so forth
with other data sets and seemingly
innocuous innocuous data sets
in that way can get um can become
that valuable but sometimes data theft
is so significant it becomes
strategically
important and that gets into getting
weakened so you look at
in getting weakened this is where
societies as a whole as opposed to
individuals losing bits of money or
valuable property or data
societies as a whole get weakened by
strategic
um attacks
so on espionage one of the most
strategically impactful hacks of all
time
was against the united states in 2015
where
the chinese are believed to have stolen
the entire federal government database
of everyone who applied for
a u.s federal government security
clearance this
century 21 and a half million people and
if you've ever filled out your
government security clearance form and i
have you will know it's not just your
name and email address and maybe a
password in the last four digits of a
bank
card it's absolutely everything about
you
how did they do that they did some
social engineering they found the
systems administrator
on presumably on linkedin cultivated
that person
guessed some passwords and then spent
more than 24 hours copying the database
without the organization noticing this
massive use
of computing power so you can see
all sorts of red flags here this wasn't
an irresistible attack this is something
where there are various times you can
stop it but look at the strategic harm
that will do
to the us the chilling effect it will
have public servants knowing that a
potentially hostile state has this data
and you see how people can get
weakened we have seen societies
undermined
in the west by interference in elections
through fairly basic cyber attacks and i
know given
the important role that local government
plays in all cert
and the important role that local
government plays in
[Music]
in um election administration that's a
huge interest but of course these are
small organizations that need to know
how to protect themselves
we see pre-positioning that's when
states just menacingly put down
intrusions into energy companies
telecoms companies why are they there we
don't know
but it's a useful bridgehead if there's
a time of tension
so you go from getting robbed you go
from getting weakened
and then there are times where societies
get hurt they suffer disruptive
um damage and destructive um attacks
many of these like colonial pipelines
are seemingly
accidental in the summer of 2017 in fact
four years ago today
um on the uh um towards the end of the
week
i was traveling home or called to go
back to london
because our hospital booking systems
weren't working why
seemingly they were being extorted by
unknown
actors i remember thinking why is anyone
trying to extort the british national
health service it's what the one
organization that famously
is frequently short of um money and
isn't the light and it's one of the most
scrutinized organizations in the world
it turns out it was the north koreans
trying to steal more money as they've
done from bangladesh
at the bank of bangladesh but their
ransomware attack had gone out of
control it had gone viral
and had disrupted not just the booking
systems in the british
national health service but had taken
out the um
the notifications of german railway
platforms the following month the
russians attacked a professional
services firm
in ukraine and ended up disrupting and
i'm not making this up you can check it
given it's close
given it's in no run disrupting
production
for a while at a chocolate factory in
tasmania which i'm sure was not central
to the russia ukraine
tensions so these destructive um
attacks happen and they're often linked
to the scourge of ransomware
so let's just look at this in the round
what do we have
we this is the reality of cyber harms
it's not glamorous it's not
individual catastrophes it's all sorts
of
nebulous pernicious nasty little
incidents exploiting basic weaknesses to
add up to a big
big social problem so that's the what's
happening let's have a look at the next
slide very quickly
who's doing it well if you're a western
country
and like us um we face four nation-state
attackers and it's easy to put the flags
up there of china
russia iran and north korea but they all
are very different
i'm not telling you this just because i
think it's interesting although
i hope it is um it's because
we need to think about how to manage
risk
and to manage risk you need to think
about who might be attacking
you so let's take china and russia to
very
often malevolent actors on the global
internet um but they have very different
motivations
so the history of china's um
cyber attack capability has been
primarily not exclusively but primarily
economic
get rich quick rapid economic
development to steal other people's ip
of course global espionage is also of
interest to them and increasingly as
we've seen with
um all the debates about supply chains
and so forth increasingly china's moving
beyond
cyber um intrusions and towards actual
technological dominance of tech markets
which is a different
um problem so that's the way you think
about china have i got something
valuable
am i strategically important in terms of
intellectual property
or even you know well i will a chinese
state bank company want to buy me up
because i'm strategically
important russia is different russia is
trying to gain traditional geopolitical
advantage so it's much more interested
in political interference
much more it's much more interested in
for example
russian distance abroad it's much more
interested in intrusions into
strategically important sectors like
energy and
and so forth and so for example if
you're a big global law firm
and you're looking at the states
managing the state's threats from china
and russia
we say well i have lots of mergers and
acquisitions and intellectual property
well that's what china will be
interested in um but i don't have any
russian oligarchs who have tensions with
president putin on my books
well if you do russia will be interested
in that and that's a different way of
defending so we need to work out
understanding what you've got
and what a state actor might be
interested in iran and north korea
have both got rudimentary capabilities
but high risk appetite so
there are numerous examples of
organizations or countries
annoying the iranians and then
retaliating with cyber intrusions
including destructive
ones like um ddos attacks on american
banks or attacks on saudi oil companies
which go beyond what they'd be prepared
to do in the
physical world similarly with north
um and korea who famously hacked sony
and embarrassed george clooney and other
celebrities but also caused real
problems to the
um real problems to the company but are
now
actually become the world's first in the
words of the us department of justice
state sponsored cyber criminal because
they're desperate for money so they're
trying to disrupt financial systems in
australia in the uk
and everywhere else so those are the
state attackers there are others who are
trying to get into that
but the biggest biggest biggest threat
to everyone is on the next slide
which is international that's organized
cyber crime and the colonial pipeline
intrusion has shown this
to be um has shown the way this works
this is a service these are not terribly
sophisticated technically although
they're not bad
but they're well organized and they're
not single monolithic
beasts they pay other people they pay on
this slide they pay data miners
intrusion specialists money launderers
people who've got something to do
with um with cyber security now what you
don't have
on this slide are terrorist groups they
haven't developed cyber um
capabilities you don't have all powerful
hackers sitting
in their um in their bedrooms
what you have basically is two sets of
things
you have state attackers and you have um
criminals who are causing all of this
problem and again they're doing it
through largely
basic exploitation so if you look at the
next slide in one of the examples
this is one of the most impactful
economic espionage cases of all time so
you look at the top
wanted by the fbi in the top 10 at the
time very sort of glamorous
hack by the chinese into the managed
service providers the i.t services
company on whom most of the western
world's
um i.t services um uh depend
the fbi director uh christopher wray
called this the a to z
of american business where among the
victims there's a huge global campaign
of corporate espionage
damage is incalculable and
i'm worthy of an fbi poster let's look
how it was done
the bottom left you've got the melissa
virus it's from the year 2000
and the way that this intrusion um
started in japan it may not be the start
of the whole intrusion
was that um some word attachments
running macros with the melissa virus in
them were sent and opened by some
japanese business executives
it's not their fault any version any
modern version of windows would have
stopped it but it wasn't there
and then on the right we've got the quiz
our remote access trojan which sounds
very glamorous but you can buy that off
the internet
you can buy that for 700 pounds or 700
sorry us dollars
you can get a training manual for it but
it was able to
roam across from japan on unsegmented
networks
freely for months undetected
so a very very strategically impactful
um
hack worked off very very basic
capabilities
similarly on the next slide two big
intrusions
into um us and british politics the us
one being much bigger and much more
famous against secretary clinton
in 2016. below secretary clinton is one
of her aides john podesta and the way
the russians did that
firstly they hacked into the server of
the democratic national committee that's
a small
organization and then they hacked into
the gmail of mr podesta and then they
just did a data dump
similarly in the 2019 general election
these are two british politicians liam
fox conservative
trade minister at the time and jeremy
corbyn then the leader of the labour
party
and someone in mr dr fox's department
sent an email to a gmail so they could
work on it offline because they didn't
like this
safe remote working stuff and that ended
up um
being a very controversial election uh
leak uh where um documents about the
relationship between
um the apart the alleged privatization
of health care and post brexit trade
deals became a big
uh talking point so very very basic
security lapses
leading to quite high impact and stuff
in the next slide we see some of the um
interesting points about critical
infrastructure and we're going to be
talking about this more and more
after the pipeline i hear i think we
have to think about getting
getting security right as well as safety
english is a very interesting language
because it's got separate words for
security and safety and most european
languages have the same words of urad
and
spanish security and french and so forth
and we're actually quite good at safety
so look at colonial pipelines
everything's been switched off safely
it's just because of insecurity major
disruptions happening but if you look at
the left
this is this fascinating case from only
january this year
in a small town called oldsmar in
florida where
somebody believed to be a disgruntled
employee
actually hacked into the remote working
facility
for a water treatment plant in the city
of wolves morgan
and somehow managed to use that
compromise to start
changing the chemical composition of the
drinking water
so this is disastrous that that can
happen the good
news is that there were multiple checks
on um the water going out ph checks
uh other uh checks so it didn't come
close
to affecting anybody and that's so
that's an example of bad practice in
that in the first instance
the water should never have allowed to
be altered through remote
and access but good practice and there's
that resilience that non-cyber
resilience which gets us through and
that is why
if you look at the book title on the
right about click here to kill everybody
we're actually containing some cyber
threats
into disruption rather than real harm
so in understanding these harms and
understanding how our systems work and
the relationship between cyber and
non-cyber we get to the positive stories
which is the last sort of
war story um if you go to the next slide
about how we can try to contain this
so everyone's talking about ransomware
and it's a disaster and it is
we need to do more but let's be
optimistic there's some really really
good examples
of good practice here so this is a
polish company called project red
they got ransomware but they had good
backups
they had a good incident response plan
so what they did was they kept going and
they announced they'd been ransomward
and they announced they weren't going to
pay it they wrote to the customer saying
look apologies if these
criminals leak the data but we will do
everything we can to contain
the harm and they publish the technical
details of the attack so security
researchers could have a go with these
people
so it's not all bad and it's not all
doom
and gloom we need to think about
protections and we need to think about
getting protections right so i'm going
to give you a quick example
before we finish about how to get
protections wrong
and then right so if we look at the next
slide
so much of this and so much of what
we've been talking about has been about
passwords sorry has been about basics
and basic accesses and one of those
things has been about password
compromises it's come up with various
points including
the chinese attack on the american
database
so here's some mathematical
approximations about how to
um compromise a password so if you have
something very basic just a few letters
it can be done instantly by a hacker
then if you do something very
sophisticated as in the bottom right
where you've got your special characters
letters numbers uppercase store cases
will take you sort of
quadrillion years so everybody goes
great we're going to have long complex
passwords
unfortunately um when you have to have
separate ones for every uh account
then um and they all have to meet that
um
[Music]
that sort of gold standard criteria what
happens is
the next slide and in the next slide
that is 600
digits i have the uk sorry just go to
the previous one just to 600 digits
at the previous slide uh sorry i um
and at my previous job at the national
cyber security center
and we got a professor of psychology
to compute what we were asking the
average person to do with passwords and
she came back and said we're asking
people to do the mathematical to do the
mental equivalent of learning
a new 600 digit number every month it's
crazy and people count
people can't do it so by looking at
too narrow an aspect of the problem what
makes for a strong password we're asking
people to do the impossible
when people are asked to do the
impossible they take shortcuts when
people take shortcuts
hacks happen so look instead and if we
go to the next slide
this is now what the national cyber
security center in the uk
by australia um uh uh similar in
australia similar in the us
now he's saying use sensible password
policy use password managers
organization should allow people to
paste
passwords into um websites
through password managers because that
is sensible risk management i have one
master password
that you can sensibly um
learn and protect because that is the
keys to
the kingdom this is why
just as i begin to conclude the overall
approach if we go to the next slide has
to be one
of risk management so homework
don't just tell people that when they
work from home
they have to um make sure they don't
click on links
give them good equipment give them vpns
make sure they know bring your own
device and all the rest of it
so you don't have crazy outcomes such as
the one in the water plant
and an aggregate if we go to the next
slide
which is crucial i'll probably um uh
finish on this um manage risk well
at organizational level board
leaderships whether that's
a charity a university a local
government
national government small business big
business boards
need to understand a little bit about
cyber security now
they need to get a little bit technical
they need to know the sorts of hacks
that happen as in that nine box grid
that i showed everywhere
that i showed earlier and they need to
be able
to have an informed conversation about
that
i used to when i was in government i
used to enjoy teasing
oil company executives when they'd say
the cyber security stuff it's very scary
and i don't really
understand it might take them you can
extract
fossil fuels from the seabed safely and
economically
and get them transported although not
this week in america
get them transported um to consumers and
businesses
all over all over the world you can
manage enormously complicated health and
safety risks you can manage enormously
complicated financial risks
but if i mention computer network
security too easy it's too complicated
you wouldn't have a board member of
sitting out of discussion on pension
liability saying well i'm afraid i have
nothing to say here i don't really
understand that the same has to be true
at cyber security and so in this
this is a summary of the national cyber
security center's board toolkit which is
the sort of conversation organizations
need to be having
and as we know have we done a cyber
security risk assessment oh good
an expensive company has done that
before us it's
it's conversations like this
assuming that somebody's going to click
on a dodgy link because we can't expect
people who are busy with other things to
spot everything
how are we going to manage the fact that
people get into our network
how are we going to manage not being the
next colonial pipeline how are we going
to notice this
are we going to notice this intrusion
it's stuff like that it's who is our
systems administrator
what is how big is their team
and how are we protecting those people
who are more important strategically
in cyber security than the chief
executive or the
chair so i would encourage people have a
look at the australian government's
guidance british government's guidance
all freely available
and just manage risk well enough
you don't need to have nation state
defenses so we just lose the slides for
the last minute or two
it's very easy to be terrified of cyber
security
it's very easy to be infantilized
by cyber risks and the hype around
cyber security but there are
good news stories firstly no one is
asking small organizations universities
local government no one's asking them to
be able to take on
the best of a hostile nation state the
best of the chinese state
on their own if you get
targeted and not many do but some do by
one of those elite actors
then you're entitled to government and
help that's what national security is
so for example where i now work in the
university of oxford
a small research institute called the
general institute suddenly became the
center of world attention because it
turned out they've got quite
quite a few good people who were
excellent at making cheap coronavirus
vaccines
and that became the subject of the
world's um
tension including the attention of some
of the most hostile actors
so the uk government helped that
organization protect itself because it
was too small
to do it and it's a small medical
research facility not a cyber security
facility
but the final story because i've given
you all these stories of things going
wrong
i would like to pay tribute to them to
our american friends
in what they did to protect the election
of 2020 from outside cyber interference
look at the legacy of 2016 and how toxic
that proved
look what they did in 2020 they got
the state and local governments together
they got all the major agencies together
they got all the businesses together
and it meant that tiny organizations in
rural states like nebraska and the
dakotas and so forth
actually knew how to manage cyber risk
effectively
knew how their systems work knew how
resilient
um to be and how to achieve that
resilience knew how to share
that information and they did that
through a well-informed partnership
between government federal government
local government
businesses ngos and so forth and the
sort of partnerships that all certainly
have been fermenting over the last 20
years
are ideally suited to meet these
challenges
so understand the harms
have a risk-based approach a realistic
approach
and work with partners and we can get on
top of this problem
thank you very much for listening to me
this afternoon and enjoy the rest of
this great event
professor kieran professor kieran martin
thank you so much for that karen can i
just ask you one
quick question and ask this as a
conference mc who's a bit of an outsider
to this space
but i hear about the um the the you know
the big events you're talking about of
recent times there's seem to have been
four or five really
high profile hack events recently but
then again you take us back to 2015
for that massive case of cyber espionage
so
is it a particularly hot patch at the
moment or is this
just business as usual
we've had a number of reminders we've
had a big spying intrusion in the us
from so-called solarwinds case and
another one from chinese on
microsoft again in the us we've had the
water plant incident and now we've had
the colonial
pipelines disruption and the good news
for people like us is that they're all
in the united states
it reminds me of uh when i sent my
deputy to a
conference i don't think it was all cert
but i sent him to a conference in
australia
and he was um saying the same thing this
will often he was saying the same thing
as i was saying about
you to manage risk be good enough you
don't have to see off every attack
um and he said my job is not to send
them
is not to stop all cyber crimes to send
it to france
unfortunately um you know this being the
global internet age this got back to my
french counterpart
and is it getting worse i think it's
actually steady but i think we're
becoming more aware of the impact
um and i think it's variable so i
think that um we the lesson
of the last while and the lesson of the
last six months is that it's glaringly
exposed to a much bigger audience the
fundamental weaknesses and things like
supply chains
you know why is one company which turns
out was
its updates were poisoned by russian
state actors why is one company
supplying half of the most important
federal governments in the world
without checks and supply chains and
that's why president by michigan
executive order
trying to solve that problem last night
so i think what we've had
um are a series of more visible
exposures of non-existing problems
so don't despair and there's stuff we
can do
fantastic please give professor kiran
mutton another big round of applause
thank you so much for presenting
live into our time today kieran martin
there you go what a wonderful
presentation that was