[Music]
i'll wait for
20 seconds after you guys good to go
[Music]
awesome steps on this side
i'm glad this is a virtual talk there's
no stairs
well welcome to the stream for those of
us in the room and those of us on
virtual
reality i'll move over to the lectern
for you sorry
um thanks for coming to this stream
we've just got some quick housekeeping
issues
first of all due to the time constraints
with the virtual stream which will cut
off
at the end of the uh allotted time
please make sure you put your questions
through the app
i will moderate those and put them up at
the end
now we have dave lewis who's the global
advisory siso from duo
security to talk to us about jet packs
and other nice historical
things from the security industry thank
you
dave you're up on screen great
excellent thank you very much and thank
you everyone for being here this morning
i really do appreciate it even though
it's night time over here in canada
wish i could be with you i really really
do and hopefully we'll get to that some
point some point real soon
so today i'm here to talk to you about
uh i was promised a jet pack
back in the day we had all sorts of
different promises of all this different
technology flying cars and all the rest
of it
and when we take that we line it up with
trust and security
and it really is an interesting
conversation to have on how we are
establishing trust overall
um next slide please
there we go so i have been okay
something wrong here that's not me could
we go to the next slide please
all right so i've been in security now
for the better part of about 30 years
um and along the lines i've had all
sorts of different roles
and i've learned a lot from all of this
as i've been going through
um sorry could i go to the next slide
please
and there we go okay so wait that's the
wrong picture again all right so
could we go one more there we go okay
good now we're talking
um i've been doing security one forward
over about 30 years now and i've had
all sorts of different roles from being
a firewall admin right through to being
a cso for a power company
and all points in between and i've made
a lot of mistakes in my career but it's
been very
interesting in what i have been able to
learn
and one of the things i learned is that
sometimes people that see themselves as
rock stars really need to have a proper
writer
go to the next slide please and so
in this particular case the rockstar
being my cat loki who
put on quite a show last year he was
really tired from hunting
rabbits through the window all day so he
will not be joining us today but
oh well uh if we could go to the next
slide please
so early on him you know when i was a
kid you know back in the 1970s
um in back of comic books they would
have these adverts
that would say you know if you send in
your money we'd send you these
x-ray specs and i was absolutely fat
like just
thought this was the most amazing idea i
was six
um and so i figured out how to get an
envelope and get to stamp and everything
and i wrote
my address on it and sent it on to the
company
and quite literally put a bunch of
change in the envelope because i was
absolutely wanted to have these x-ray
specs
imagine my disappointment when i got
them and it was just a piece of
cardboard with a hole in it
so right there we had an erosion of
trust right out of the gate
if we go to the next slide please and
then as i got older i thought
okay you know this would be a really
cool idea because you know i watch happy
days one too many times and grease and
all the rest of it
and i figured you know a switchblade
comb would be really really kind of neat
to have
so i sent away for that this time you
know my parents were good enough to help
me by sending a check
a little less painful than sending a
bunch of change but when i got it you
know it did one comb
two oh and it broke and again we had a
further erosion of trust
so we go to the next slide please
so promises were made back then you know
we were told that we would be all
living on the moon we'd have jet packs
we'd have flying cars
and it's really unfortunate that
this was how things were built up didn't
really align with where we are today
and we seem to be you know
really content to deal with what we have
as opposed to what we were promised next
slide please
and as a result we tend to battle with
ourselves about you know how we're going
to get things done and what
is you know the best way to get trust in
an organization build it from there
but we have to do better overall next
slide please
and i apologize to the person who's
doing the slide so there's a lot of them
so we never have to do a much better job
and you know around the world because of
the state of where we are now
we are dealing with remote workers as
far as the eye can see
there was a time where remote workers
were seen as
you know a convenience so a nice to have
you know something to
reward your employees with and now it
has become
really an effective tool in order to
make sure that business can continue
and as we transition back into the
office which you know a great deal of
that's happening in australia now
we have to realize that we have to be
able to have
resilience built in that we're prepared
for this in the future and we have to
foster trust with our end users
so that they understand how to do this
in the future you know they're very good
at what they're very good at they may be
in finance they may be in hr whatever it
happens to be
but they're not necessarily technically
savvy and we have to make sure that we
are giving them tools to help
democratize security
and you know that really does mean
making it as easy as possible for them
to do their job safely and securely
because you know we didn't give them the
jet pack
but we can give them the tools to make
sure they get the job done
that being said next slide please
my co-worker was good enough to point
out that yes there are jet packs now but
for some reason my boss wendy nather who
just got indicted indicted
inducted into the hall of fame for in uk
um pointed out that um yeah i can't
expense one of those yet
i'll say yeah that's my go-to all right
next slide please
so tools of the trade you know we want
to look at how we can do things better
and you know ways to authenticate users
is a great example of this because
we tend to rely on some controls that
are essentially deprecated like the
password
now the password has served its purpose
since about 1962
it has really done its job but so has
the house key to get in the front of our
you know abode a house key has limited
utility
the person who has it has the ability to
access the house
it doesn't mean that's the right person
that's supposed to be coming through the
front door
so we have to be really cognizant of
this that when we're dealing with
computer systems
that we understand that this is a bit of
a misstep and we've got to do a better
job
be it multi-factor authentication
biometrics or you know in the future
passwordless
there is a open standard called webauthn
that was penned by the w3c
which is a great example of
how we can get to past this is it to be
and all no but it's a great step forward
so
if you take nothing else away from this
talk today besides you know visiting my
colleagues in their booth today make
sure that you go find this document and
read it this is a
open standard this is not any sort of
vendor thing this is a
something that is freely available
so when we have the tools and we
understand that you know there are
better ways to do things we have to also
be aware
that the attackers are looking for ways
to cause trouble
next slide please
thank you so dark patterns in user
interface design
are one example of this so when we're
talking about that sort of thing it's
sort of
how they manipulate the interface so you
go to click the x in the top right
corner which you know most people say oh
that's how i close the window
meanwhile if it clicks it it pops up
another box saying are you sure you want
to do this yes or no and both of those
are the wrong answer
this is one of those issues that we have
to understand that
when that happens that is helping to
erode the trust of the user
because they don't know what to trust
and as security practitioners we have to
put the tools in place so they can
learn how to you know better trust uh
next slide please
so this is a great example from my
friend corey doctorow's twitter feed
where he took a screenshot of an ad that
popped up in his feed
and if you look there in the yellow
circle you'll see a little what looks
like a smudge
and he went to wipe it and thought it
was on his screen it turned out that was
actually
in the image itself which erroneously
got the individual to click
on the ad which is not something they
would have otherwise
done next slide please
so the attackers know this and they know
how to prey on what
would other our sensibilities you know
what we would
normally do they can mess with us in
many ways
they can do bait and switch they do
confirm shaming like the box that pops
up saying are you really sure you want
to do that
uh misdirection you know and trick
questions and things like that
where you're causing them to make
choices that
you know by all rights they wouldn't
normally make
next slide please
another example of this is messing with
colors on or tick boxes and things like
that
there was one application that i was
working on just two days ago
and when i went to click on the button
to enable a particular function the
application
because there was a bug in it it would
actually move the little check box to
the left
i was like okay that's different so i go
over to click
the box again and it would go back to
the right and this was most insidious
pain in the
posterior that i could think of and it
really caused me a great deal of
frustration but this was
just a mistake in the code and i was
able to figure out what
was going on but that sort of behavior
is something the attackers will use in
their malicious attempts to
gain access to your system to steal your
data
and this really does create anxiety for
the user because
let's be honest the vast majority of
users that are working remotely
or on computers in general are not
necessarily technically savvy
they know how to open excel they know
how to open their email they know how to
get things done
for their job but if you ask them to you
know switch from
an ethernet cable to a wi-fi or whatever
it happens to be something very what we
would take as being simple
this could cause them a great deal of
angst and we have to always be cognizant
of this that we are there
to enable them to get their jobs done
the goal really is quite simple we want
to make sure that security is done in a
way
that doesn't fracture their best
interest
next slide please so malicious design
is something that comes up a lot and
unfortunately a lot of times only a
designer will actually be able to spot
this sort of behavior
and when we have things like that and
then we contrast that
against you know applications are
written by engineers for engineers
this makes it very very difficult for
the end user to be able to
use their applications um
sorry flash back to my earlier days and
when they can't
figure out something because it is far
too difficult to use
they may make mistakes and the same can
be said a malicious design
in that people will make mistakes that
they wouldn't be able to
discern what was going on next slide
please
what it fundamentally boils down to is
we aren't able to trust ourselves
to make the right decisions many times
and that's not because we don't get it
it's because we are built to trust
we are expecting things to work a
certain way and unfortunately nefarious
types we'll prey on that
next slide is because we all have
some sort of bias no matter how we put
it we all have
our individual biases and we have to
make sure that
those biases are not causing us or
others undo harm
we always have to be cognizant of this
because not only does that affect the
individuals
who are interacting with their systems
but we also have to look at how bias
negatively impacts technology next slide
please
so here is an absolute fantastic example
amateur elizari
was talking about creating a bug bounty
for bad algorithms
that's an excellent idea and this is the
kind of thing that we have to start
looking at
you know i was you know very fortunate
to see a talk by mikko heppenen
and sorry mikko if i got your name
pronounced wrong um
who gave a talk a couple years ago when
we were able to you know
go out in public and he was talking
about
applications that were writing other
applications
and this was really amazing but if the
initial application has
a negative bias built into it that can
then replicate and
change in various nefarious ways as it
goes along
we need to be able to better understand
how we are affecting our environments
around us and this very much extends to
algorithms
uh next slide please
so we have to really pray on pray on
pay attention to the capabilities that
we are trying to do
because we don't want to have negative
impacts as we go along because
yes we do security but imagine we put on
a different hat
imagine we went into a different role
next slide please
now here's a story from 2011 about a
former security
expert that became or secure security
expert
who went in to become a developer and
started his own application
and one of the things that he found out
rather short order that
everything he had been talking about
from a security perspective when it came
down to writing his own application
he ended up you know making the same
mistakes
next slide please and there's other
things that we have to look at on how
attackers can cause us trouble
and one is the you know the subtlety of
corrupting data
now we always worry about data being
stolen or data being you know
compromised in some fashion
but we don't tend to spend a lot of time
on data being altered
now this is a great example here where
emails that were leaked
ostensibly were tied back to this
particular journalist and it's made it
look like he was a
you know talking to the cia as an
example in the united states
this wasn't the case but this is an
example of what
looked like a data breach turned out to
be actually just absolutely false flag
and these are the kind of things that we
always have to be on the lookout because
this could really change the narrative
with just a few short words
next line please here's another example
here
where you know a story was changed where
it
absolutely altered the meaning by just
changing a few words in the text
this is the kind of thing where trust
again is further eroded
next slide please sorry
we have to be able to defend against
denial of trust attacks
and these are attacks against things
that we expect to be
correct be it a user interface be it
data
be it how an application should be
behaving
we have to be always aware of this
because we have a fiduciary
responsibility to protect our
organizations to protect our staff and
our data and if we are not there to
enable them to do things safely and
securely
then unfortunately this is going to have
you know unfortunate consequences
next up so in order for us to trust
in ourselves we have to learn how to
earn trust from others
now there's been a lot of conversation
over the years about what exactly trust
is and a lot of times it is like oh i
just trust them
well have you earned it have you
verified it have you gone through and
said yes this is okay
if you log into an application with the
username and password does that mean you
are trusted to use that application
that just means you had the house key so
we have to look at doing a more
you know concerted effort to secure
those devices secure those applications
and protect the data
next slide please and we're able to do
that by earning trust through various
steps you know being
honest with folks when things go wrong
coming out and saying clearly that this
is what happened our particular system
was breached for x y and z
and this is what happened and these are
the steps we're taking to remediate it
trying to pretend something didn't
happen or being disingenuous with the
information
again further erodes the trust in your
customers and whatever it happens to be
we have to be transparent we have to
make sure
that we are the adults in the room as
security practitioners as security
professionals
because we need to establish that trust
you know in the past we may have had the
concept of yes we are the flaming sword
of justice how do we get to the answer
of no
that's a deprecated notion we have to
show
predictability we have to show
capability and a willingness to
correct mistakes when we make them i
built a career on making mistakes as
i've gone along
and i've learned from them so the key is
mistakes are okay
as long as you learn from them as long
as you're able to share those stories
with others
so that they won't make the same
mistakes as well
because we have an accountability not
only to ourselves to our organizations
but the security community at large and
by extension
everybody else next slide please
remember when microsoft said they were
going to do trustworthy computing and
everybody sort of jumped up and down
said nah it's not going to happen
they did it they did a really good job
security for that particular
organization has
absolutely improved but how do we extend
that beyond that to the wider audience
next slide please is zero trust one of
those answers
now this is a term that usually gets a
lot of
blowback as it were because of negative
connotations
because people say oh it's just a
marketing term all right let's flip it
on his head let's call it continuous
trusted access
makes sense um same thing the whole idea
here is about
reducing risk in the organization
next slide please
so is it the right choice yes no
there is a case to be made for the
maturity of the organization to
understand what it is they're trying to
protect
also understand where they are on the
roadmap for talking about continuous
trusted access and how they're going to
get to a better place
because they're working very hard to
protect the workplace the workforce and
the workload
and when we're doing this we have to
realize that
while we may have have erosion of trust
with the users
that we can help establish that at
moving forward and is it easy
no is it for everybody in certain
respects yeah
because this is about reducing risk it's
really that simple
uh we can go into talking about micro
zone segmentation talking about all
these different aspects of it
but the reality is it's really about
getting back to core fundamentals
and tackling things that we should have
been doing a long time ago user
management device management
application control as well as network
zone segmentation
these are just some of the examples next
slide please
because when we're born into this world
we
are you know crying we're hungry we're
scared we're looking for
to be safe we're looking for shelter
we're looking to eat
and you know malcolm gladwell talked
about this in his
book talking to strangers about how we
default to trust
unfortunately that does not translate as
we grow up
as we get into computer systems computer
networks and all the rest of it
because it just isn't something that
translates one to one there is no lift
and shift for trust
we have to make sure that we are working
very hard to establish controls and put
in place
that will enable people to get their
business done safely and securely and
establish that trust and maintain it
next slide please
always got to work in the breaks next
slide please
we have to move away from some of our
deprecated notions of how we saw
security overall
so in the past you know it was like oh
it's uh we have a firewall everything's
fine
nothing to see here i actually worked in
one organization many many years ago i
think
over 15 years ago where the cio looked
at me and said it's okay we trust
everyone's here we have a firewall
um after that particular meeting which
was reviewing the findings for a
penetration test
we realized very quickly that that was
not something that was going to hold up
next slide please
now when we're talking about trust when
about you know we could say granting
access without verifying you
say username and password that isn't
really trust
we could say trust is granted because
you've been verified one of those makes
more sense
we need to be able to be sure that the
people that are connecting to our
systems are the ones that are in fact
supposed to be there
another company i worked at years ago we
had various programmers
in a country overseas that were doing
code for us
and they would come into our network and
they would do their stuff and
nothing ever bad happened but my
co-worker said you know have we ever you
know checked to see how things are going
there
i'd been on the job for four days i said
i had no idea but i'll check
so we found out in rather short order
that people were coming in from this
country all over the different parts of
the country
accessing our network and doing their
jobs which was fine
the problem was they were using the same
key fob for all these people that were
separated by
you know very long drives so there was
no way that they were you know
sharing that particular token other than
calling in and getting something to read
the next number off to them to access
the system
they weren't doing this out of a sense
of malice
they were doing this to get their job
done and when we dug
into it we found out that our mistake
was ours because at no point in our
contractual language had we spelled out
that they needed to do various security
steps that we were
specifying because we didn't specify
them and that was a real problem so we
have to make sure that we're building in
an understanding as to what our
requirements are across the board
because
you know things are going to cause
trouble if they are not
clearly defined and that trust will tend
to erode over time next slide please
and there's different types of attacks
like i was talking about earlier you
know the
fake news i hate that term but it's here
to stay
um and various types of forms there are
people that are putting it out there
just to make their point
or putting it out there to further a
conspiracy theory
or governments trying to influence a
populist to vote a certain way
data misuse is another example and data
breaches are something that constantly
causes trouble
i i started paying attention these back
in about 2012 and i started tracking
these
and nowhere near to what troy does now
kudos to him um but when we're going
through and looking at those data
breaches they were pretty small back
then
now they're in the order of magnitude of
billions of records and they're
happening over and over again
and this doesn't have to be this way
next slide
so how can all of this become an attack
against the system
next slide please one great example of
this
is integrity attacks you know subtler or
or
or overt uh corruption of data you know
i talked about that a little bit earlier
with those
particular stories but if somebody's
able to go in and
change the spreadsheet for a financial
report to say
you know their accounts receivable were
x instead of y
and then they had their earnings
announcement the next day
i could have a real horrible effect
we're accusing somebody of a data breach
by dumping a whole lot of passwords on
the internet and saying they were
hacked and it turns out that it was just
a whole bunch of different data breaches
that were all stitched together and made
to look that way
in the meantime it had negatively
impacted the stock price of that
particular company
there's many different ways to look at
this
so when we're talking about securing all
of this we have to tackle you know three
core tenants
next slide please we have to look at
securing the users
the devices and the applications really
is the core fundamentals next slide
please
because our ecosystem has spread you
know the idea of the castle wall and the
moat we've all seen the castle
image on network diagrams over the years
this is something we need to do away
with because
that really isn't the way things are
anymore the perimeter is anywhere an
access decision is being made
and we have you know third-party
contractors coming in we have partner
systems we have various applications
that are facing the internet that may or
may not have been through proper
security vetting
these are all different things that
really have to have
a framework overlaid to reduce the risk
next slide please
so zero trust or continuous trusted
access is a great example of this
here's a quick five-step walk-through on
how we could tackle this first of all
you want to establish trust in the users
do you know the users that are in your
environment are they the ones that are
supposed to be there
do you have a manual staff ad remove
process or is it automated
um then the next step from there is you
want to gain visibility into the devices
and activity of what is it they're doing
you know is this dave sitting at a tim
hortons in toronto canada
or am i sitting on the beach in the gold
coast and
causing trouble from there like these
are the kind of things we really
really have to have some method to
verify
next up you want to ensure the
trustworthiness of the devices so is it
patched to current is it
past current or n minus one you know
what is the risk appetite for your
organization that you've set out in
advance
if it hasn't been patched in 30 days do
you have the ability to say okay
you can't come in until you address
these particular issues
and then being able to place you know
adaptive policies over top of that
saying oh you're in finance you get
these systems
you're in i.t you get access to these
systems and near the twain shall meet or
whatever your
issues are within your own organization
and then fundamentally you'll take us
to talking about a zero trust or
continuous trusted access framework
which is all about reducing risk and
this is definitely something that we can
do
because we have to implement best
practices next slide please
we have to look at verifying the users
verifying their devices
and protecting every application that
means same overly simplistic but
it really does tackle the lion's share
of what we have to contend with
next slide please because
if you've seen the dbir report that came
out today
there is a great example of you know a
higher
80 plus percent of the attacks were
involving you know
human interaction or stolen credentials
there was a high
number of organized crime uh statistics
in there as well
and when we're looking at this and
looking at stolen credentials this is
the stock and trade
of the attackers if they're able to get
user names and passwords from a
third-party website
and use that to attack another website
and then escalate their access
that's a problem so if we can remove
that by adding in another factor having
multi-factor authentication is a great
example of this
we can remove the attacker's ability to
really cause harm yes there would be
reputational risk of having username and
password exposed but they wouldn't be
able to do any real damage beyond that
next slide please and we have to be able
to enforce
the systems that have you know poor
security hygiene in a way that
they are not going to get in like in the
past when i used to be able to travel i
would be in a hotel and i hadn't been on
the road for a month
i go to log in it's like oh you have to
patch this before you can get in it's
like all right cool
a victim of my own design here but
these are the things we have to
constantly be vigilant about
because next slide please we are always
constantly trying to make sure we're
protecting the workplace the workforce
and the workload
that really does take all the aspects of
our business
into a different buckets next slide
please
so user trust see some repetition here
user trust we need to make sure we know
who the people are that are attaching to
our systems
who are the ones that are in our network
does somebody just happen to have a
password
or somebody that we truly know who they
are next slide please we have to be able
to do discovery of our network discovery
over assets and applications to
understand
what it is that we're taking the time to
protect next slide please
want to be able to verify is it a
trusted endpoint is it something that we
know is part of our corporate asset
inventory
um or is it a byod device that we have
previously seen or we've approved
to gain access to the network these are
things that we need to be able to check
or is it something that's untrusted like
in a previous job that i did years ago
i was able to vpn into our company using
a a web browser on an old first gen xbox
one
or xbox rather and i was able to check
my email
i did that only because i wanted to see
if it was possible this happened on a
sunday
i got into work on monday and nobody
said anything that was extremely
troubling nobody had noticed that i had
done this
so i came clean and they were very upset
about it and they wanted my head on a
stick but
this really spoke more to the fact that
we needed that endpoint visibility to
understand what it was that was
attaching to our systems
next slide please we have to be sure
that those devices that are coming in
are the ones that are supposed to be
there
we don't need old xboxes or we don't
need systems running windows me
which for whatever reason i saw one go
to my own personal website about a month
ago
i don't know if somebody was trolling me
or they really were using that system
next slide please
oh sorry there's uh and security debt is
a great example of things we have to be
aware of
because when we're dealing with you know
establishing trust in the users and the
systems
and the data if we are using systems
that have not been patched in years
like you have an os2 warp system that's
running your hvac system and it hasn't
been rebooted in seven years
i've seen that before these are the kind
of things we have to be aware of because
the attackers will
look for these sort of really weird
systems or if it's something that hasn't
been patched in you know several months
but there's a known vulnerability in the
wild we're really doing ourselves a
disservice by not
addressing that a timely fashion
next slide please adaptive policies we
need to be able to go through and apply
policies that make sense
are you from business unit a b or c you
get the policy that works for you
so when they try to access systems that
they should have no
business going into then you're able to
control that
and be able to alert on that as well
next slide please now from a policy
perspective you can do all manner of
things
i mean there is you know geo-blocking
which only has limited utility because
you know the attackers can then move
through another system
you know you can't get me on behind
seven proxies um but you can also set
what level of hygiene you're expecting
systems to come in that are going to
have
what sort of flexibility for the hours
of work or where they're coming from
and grace period so if they're able to
get
into the system or there's something
wrong and they lock themselves out
you say okay you're locked out for this
amount of time then we'll try again
um and this gives the responders a
chance to look at the system and say
okay
maybe not everything is entirely uh up
to snuff here
next slide please
we want to be able to protect every
application in our organization
are you using office 365 or using g
suite or whatever it happens to be
there's no reason that somebody in new
zealand
or thailand or canada should be
accessing your network if they don't
work for you
so why would you not have them go
through a reverse proxy in order for
them to access the system so you have
them go to reverse proxy
authenticate and then be able to access
the systems
rather than going to them directly this
is again about limiting risk in your
organization
we can do better next slide please
and when we look at this we realize that
as we move towards a risk reduction
framework as we move to continuous
trusted access
we're verifying all the users the
devices and the applications in our
environment
and we're ostensibly getting a little
bit closer to having
that jet pack that has really
eluded us for a very long time or at
least me anyway
um next slide please we have to talk
about the ephemeral nature of trust
it's neither binary it's neither
permanent but it has to be constantly
revisited and constantly verified
when we're doing this we have to do it
in a way that's enabling the users to
get their jobs done
to understand the process and
democratize security by making it easy
easy as possible for them to do things
without negatively impacting them
now what conditions need to be true in
order for them to gain access to the
system
and how long are they allowed to be able
to come in how long are you allowing
that trust to be in effect
you say yes you're good for the next
hour you're good for the next 18 hours
that's really something that is germane
to the conversation about risk within
your own organization
next slide please
so what happens in a community without
trust i think we all know that
if we don't have trust the community
falls apart
what happens about a society without
trust
the society falls apart it's not a good
place to be
next slide please revisiting this from
earlier
we established trust with honesty
transparency parenthesis
predictability capability willingness to
correct the mistakes we've made
and accountability to ourselves as well
as to our organizations and the wider
audience overall
next slide please we're able to do this
by having prevention detection and
correction
having the right tools in place after
you've done your homework
you've looked at all the assets in your
environment
the users the devices the applications
the systems the networks
once you understand that then you can
have the conversation about tools
next slide please
we have to make sure that we are able to
have trustworthy data and trustworthy
systems and we have to make it in such a
way that they cannot be separated from
trustworthy people
we don't want to negatively influence
how things are going to do
happen how they're going to roll out
because we missed a step
because we didn't do our job because we
missed a patch
it's a constant battle but we have to
understand that mistakes are going to
may be made
next slide please and you know
mistakes happen all the time we have to
understand that what may seem like a
small mistake could have a horrible
knock-on effect
next slide please so as we're getting
further along the conversation of
talking about continuous trust taxes and
talking about reducing risk on our
environments
we realize that we're getting a little
bit closer to that dream
of having a personal jet pack maybe i'll
be able to expense one one day
and be able to have that future that we
were promised all those many moons ago
i would like to thank everyone for being
here today i really do appreciate the
chance to be here if only as a giant
floating head on your screen
and thank you once again i really
appreciate your time today next slide
please
thank you very much if you want drop me
an email or follow me on the twitters
and i hope you have a great rest of your
conference today
hopefully you can hear the clapping
thank you very much um
anyone else lodged any questions on the
app
if you have let me know because i can
only see the one that i lodged on the
app
uh and i just thought i'd throw this one
at you as a sort of side
issue how do you feel about one identity
to sort of rule them all
i'm talking about identity not directory
here
so based on real world id or something
because governments like you to have
one id um so that feeling of one
identity versus having many identities
like a government one a corporate one a
social one you know do you see that one
b
is safer than many or do you see it the
other way
or is there some other ground in there
okay so
we here in canada we do have something
similar about that sort of subject
where they're talking about creating
this sort of digital identification
where i lean more to it is if that is
going to be created it should be
controlled by the user themselves
i don't believe that the government
should be the ones controlling that
particular identification
okay oh that's my echo um so we want to
make sure that
we are giving them the ability to
control that and i you know i wrote a
paper about it at school where i was
using dna as part of the marker for the
key
you know there are different ways to do
it and that's just it we want to make
sure that the key
belongs to that person could not be
cannot be taken from that person
and they have the ability to revoke it
if they need to
that's just my personal event yeah cool
well that makes sense
i like the dna comment you made there i
mean that one you can change but it just
takes lots of time and
uh mutation that you don't necessarily
want yeah
well true thank you very much for your
talk um and we'll see you some another
time thank you
thank you very much for having me
[Music]
you