good thing
no one had fruits on them i think
thanks
all righty cool well enough for that
right
geez tough crowd radio so
the next presentation we have oh did my
slides didn't update
my apologies know who you are i just
want to talk about your presentation so
i'll wait for this to update and there
we go
so we have we have mark um
okay gary smith uh he has an information
security he
has been an information security
professional for approximately 20 years
we also have alex webling who's the
director of resilience
outcomes australia a consultancy helping
business businesses
and governments meet their strategic
challenges in organize
in organizational resilience security
governance privacy and information
security
so mark also has worked in operational
and architecture infosec roles
as well as lecturing his current focus
is governance risk
and compliance with particular passion
on cyber security education
awareness and cultural improvement right
so
i was fortunate enough to be part of the
training session yesterday
where when mark and alex were talking
through leading cyber security assurance
so
this is a fantastic course that's been
like squished down into a very short
presentation in the very
last minute of sorts so i'm very much
looking forward to
revisiting some of the information so
maybe some things things that i missed
so thank you very much
give them a warm round of applause thank
you
thank you very much lucas so um sorry
for anybody who was actually expecting a
different presentation
is stuck with alex and i and while we're
on apologies
i'd like to apologize to anybody who
attended our workshop yesterday and is
expecting to hear
anything different today because that's
not going to happen
we're going to speak faster sorry yes
we're just going to convince the
condensed about six hours of the
material into 35 minutes
no problem if someone could shut that
door for me that would be super duper
awesome
thank you if you haven't had a chance to
do
that to go to menchie.com
and enter that code could you please
do that really quickly
so to begin with we'd like to pay our
respects
to the traditional owners of the country
on which we
are meeting today we pay our respects to
elders past
present and emerging and just would like
to acknowledge the fact that these
lands have always been places of
education and sharing and sharing
information
so what is assurance from a cyber
security perspective
let's take a look at our word cloud that
you've all had
so long to fill in
you could go you could go a little bit
quicker it'll be it'll be good
so the great thing about it maybe the
wi-fi
it could be it could be
the code one three three six zero four
six three
please look the thing i really love
about word clouds
is that you can get immediate input from
your audience and you can see what the
different perspectives are
in the room mentee meter is what we're
using today this is the free version it
still gives you
good functionality it's a really good
way to engage with your audience
whatever kind of training or engagement
you're doing especially
good with executive stakeholders because
they get to play with their devices
and you get to see what their opinions
are in an anonymous
ish kind of fashion
and it looks cool as it resizes itself
obviously the bigger fonts are words in
common
um so that's great that's that's
that's good to hear thank you mark as a
legend is particularly
um observant comment
well done lucas i'll give you that money
later on
all right let's go back to
the actual prezzo so
look there's lots of different
definitions about assurance but
here's a good one information security
assurance provides
objective assessment as to the security
of
information
the institute of internal auditors the
i i a revised their three lines of
defense model a few years ago you might
be familiar with the previous one this
is the updated one
it's now just called the three lions
model
the previous one was seen as being too
narrowly focused
on just defense and stopping bad things
from occurring
so the updated model is a little bit
more flexible
and it more accurately reflects the the
way that roles and responsibilities of
the different parties
associated with assurance need to work
together and communicate
and understand responsibilities and
accountabilities
um so this this is definitely an
improvement
particularly around role clarity and the
way that responsibility and
accountability should be
should be clearly communicated because
that's so critical to assurance
and it's flexible enough for people to
customize it in a way that's going to
suit their individual
context
so how much assurance is enough
assurance well
ultimately you'd want assurance to be
commensurate with the business impacts
of whatever information asset
or system we're talking about that needs
assurance
this is an example from a queensland
government document
about assurance and information security
classification
um these are just examples right the
whole point of this document
and these kinds of documents is that
this needs to be correct for the context
in which it's going to be used
especially
within the context of the risk appetite
of the risk owners
ultimately they're the people that are
accountable for risk
the management of risk so they should
have good input
into how much assurance is enough
assurance
of course sometimes some stakeholders
may want more assurance than information
security professionals might think is
warranted or perhaps sometimes they
might not want as much assurance as you
might think is a good idea
either way you have to adapt yourself to
suit the required circumstances
you know managing up is an important
skill
um and you have to adapt it to suit
suit the circumstances suit the context
alex thank you sir
all right where are we oh yeah so
allowing
aligning on the ground um i suppose
uh from what lucas said you know i spend
a lot of my time
going into organizations as the virtual
siso
for six to twelve months um
and trying to help them with improve
their governance
and and then ideally let go
or and let them stand up on their own
two feet and
and keep on going and improve what
they're doing
it's really important to have a clear
plan
when you are walking in to a new
organization
whether you're going to be there for the
long term or as i tend to be
there for a shorter term because you
only have a very short amount of time to
make change
and you want to make change stick
as much as you can and to make the
organization that you are
responsible for as as deciso or cso
increasingly in in organizations uh
as good as it can be for its
organization
so a couple of things um
the first six months uh plan is really
important as i said
you're going to be bombarded with lots
of ideas from many
stakeholders including malcolm tents
some of your information that you
receive in your first
weeks uh days weeks months is going to
be crap
some of it is going to be brilliant it's
going to be really difficult to filter
that
out be cautious with
with how you do it there's pressure to
perform of course
and and so how do you succeed in the in
in your new organization that you're
that you're trying to help
and uh the the big idea is uh ultimately
trying to
trying to build the airplane whilst
flying you're trying to get
do your strategic changes in the
organization
over your over your time but you've also
got to do all your tactical stuff at the
same time as well you've got to keep
keep everything flying everything
running and it and quite often it's ugly
in the first few weeks
these are some things that i think are
really useful in your first weeks and
months
to think about from my perspective
and this is in no particular order and
other people
do things slightly differently as well
um
so some of the questions you need to be
asking yourself who has
organizational power within your
organization
um there's formally informal power
usually an organization will have a
structural chart and you'll know who
your boss is
and your boss's boss and that's really
obvious but you should also
like uh start being curious about who
the other bosses are
and who the who who your cohort are that
you're going to be talking to
but also really really importantly
particularly in
in smaller organizations is what you
might call information
informal power um you know
who are the people who have a lot of the
knowledge within the organization
on what's done and how is it done
particularly if it's a smaller
organization and they don't document
anything
i'm sure there are none of those here
that you know of
around the place it's important to get
to know those people
the price of a coffee can i suggest is
super valuable
on on people around the place talking to
those people
talking to hr starting to talk to order
starting to talk to people who are doing
phys
sec and uh and persec if those people
exist
that's a big question to answer um
talking to the people who are
who are in charge of finance um
uh of course the other question that you
have to ask is
why what is the incident response
capability
and you have to start doing one-on-ones
if you don't know what one-on-ones are
ask that question
and we'll answer it at the end of the
preso
so does anybody know what that number is
207 days is the average time according
to poneman in the
2020 report you know
your experience may vary it's around
eight months
um between an organization discovering
that it's been owned and
and uh day zero so that means when the
moment that you
turn up at an organization you've got a
clock ticking backwards for eight months
um so that's why ir is a really
important thing to start as soon as you
absolutely can
so big questions what incident response
capability plans exist why as i said
you're accountable if not responsible
for from day one it's a sad story
but that's why they pay you the big
bucks you may already be breached
my approach is always simple dumb direct
questions
i know all a lot of you look a lot
smarter
and but just play dumb is my advice
and again use coffee tea whatever
beverage of choice you know questions
like i'm new here tell me how you do
this
tell me about tell me when you last
questions like cyber exercise when you
last detected something when you last
scanned
how do you do vulnerability scan just
really dumb
you know open-ended questions let's have
a conversation
not you know show us this you know hard
hard stuff you can get to that if you
need to later
just start soft
okay stakeholders and now
stakeholder analysis um in the talk
yesterday we spent quite a bit of time
talking about stakeholder
analysis in larger organizations
particularly when you're going to
when you know that you're going to go
through a big change process
say you're starting to work in an
organization like defense or
a really big multinational or so for
that you're going to have to go through
a change
management program now there will be
experts that can help you
but uh it it helps to actually start
thinking about
what which stakeholders matter we
started talking about
informal and formal power well you need
to start working out who
who are the stakeholders who matter if
you're going to make a change you're
going to have to make some
changes whichever way you want either
because the organization needs to
respond to the changing threat
environment
because it's a perfect organization but
it needs to keep on being
a perfect resilient organization or
because
it's a substandard organization and you
want to improve it
as much as it can be so that it can
respond to the changing threat
environment
so which stakeholders matter and you can
you can categorize those people as
people
broadly who who can help you who can
hinder you
who don't care and such like and there's
a lot of science in there
um and and there are a lot of people who
can help you with that sort of stuff but
you should be asking those sorts of
questions
this is important uh
mark talked about uh risk uh
appetite and risk tolerance you need to
be starting to align your organizational
security objectives to whatever the risk
tolerance
is within the organization that's really
really important because you need to
sort of
at least say well this is the direction
we want to take
the the security approach that you're
going to take
as an organization i know let's use an
example i always
like using the fish and chip shop is not
the same as if you are a defense
establishment
so um and and of course there are
advantages and disadvantages in both
so you need to actually sort of cut your
cloth
so and also in terms of your discussion
with which stakeholders matter
this is about part of getting
organizational support
for the inevitable change that changes
that you're going to have to make
at that cyso level don't ever go into
one of these organizations and say
we're not going to ever have to change
because you'll be left behind
and of course lots of people have talked
about identifying
meaningful measures and metrics
they tend to be different for different
organizations
and both qualitative and quantitative
measures and metrics are really useful
building the case
for change this is all part of that
and again still over the six months you
still have to keep that airplane flying
you still have to keep on doing all that
tactical stuff
so you have to then start thinking about
well your team needs to be better so
that you can give them all the jobs that
that that they can do so that you can
have the headspace to be doing all the
stuff at the top of those
top those points because the better your
team is
the better you can be so delegation and
coaching
passing on those tasks making sure that
people are doing stuff
so that you are free to have the
headspace to do that strategic thinking
that strategic approach
okay those of you who know me
uh know that i like talking about
goldilocks security
not too much not too little just right
incredibly hard to do to achieve
um but it's a nice little sort of
thing to talk about and again this is
very much
uh the shorthand of aligning
organizational objectives to what your
tolerance
and your risk appetite is within the
organization
this is what is the scope of security
within your organization
and the point that has to be made is
that security
as a function as an entity doesn't
decide what that is
it should be an expert advice it should
provide its view but ultimately
the risk owner i the ceo the minister
the director general whoever it is
and his or her leadership team
however that's described in the
organization has to do that
of course they need to be advised of
course they need to
to be you know given as much
good guidance as you can you as
almost the translator for security
of what the the implications of their
decisions are likely to be
but the ultimate decision maker has to
be the risk owner
and if it goes wrong they have to wear
it
so and somehow in in some ways i'm
repeating what i'm saying here but
it's worth saying it in a slightly
different way that the security at risk
appetite varies by the organization
of course it's very similar across
industries
so the appetite will be very similar in
banks of a similar size in
insurance agencies of a different of a
similar size in
intelligence agencies of a similar size
and and type and such like
and of course it's not fixed because you
we all know
that the threat environment continues to
change so that risk appetite is going to
change
and you have to keep on top of it
so your risk tolerance also has to
reflect the
acceptable variation in the outcomes
related to specific performance
uh measures linked to objectives this
entity
seeks to achieve so there is a
difference
and and i i think that sometimes we
forget that there is quite a big
difference
between what appetite is and tolerance
and hopefully this diagram actually sort
of gives you some idea of
of uh what that difference is so the
the appetite is the amount of risk that
the organization
is willing to take on a particular you
know
er in pursuit of of its particular
business aims
so this might be reflected in an
organization willing to
invest and take a 100 million dollar
risk
on a particular project the risk
tolerance is the variance in that
effectively to bear the risk if it
if it goes wrong and the risk capacity
that's the overall risk that
risks that can be taken by the
organization so
as an example a government may have
uh a budget
of three billion dollars so
in a year potentially its risk capacity
could be as
large as that but of course it doesn't
want to take that much risk
if it doesn't have to
sorry okay
risk appetite statement traps um
we've all seen bad risk appetite
statements um
i have a real bug bear for
certain things one of my biggest one is
the statement we have zero tolerance for
something
right um if you ever see this in a risk
appetite statement
um you know that whoever wrote it
doesn't know what they're talking about
because effectively if somebody says
that they have zero appetite to do
something
they won't do it right so if an
organization has zero appetite for fraud
then it shouldn't be dealing with
finances
so let's just
okay rant mode off okay um
you know that risk risk is simple in
theory
there are only four options effectively
that you can do you can mitigate
control you can accept and or transfer
and share right and i suppose if there
is
zero tolerance you can avoid the risk
you can stop doing an activity and that
is
that is effectively your choice of zero
tolerance that's the only time you have
zero tolerance to do something
um if you you know so
you have very few options as a as a risk
manager for what you what you
can do and there's always some element
of risk in anything you do
in crossing the road in walking up the
stairs or whatever
you might have zero tolerance for
tripping but that doesn't matter if you
decide to go up the stairs
of course the other thing is risk
appetite statements that don't tell it
like it is
that in some way tell some sort of
fanciful fairy story about about the
organization that's not good for them
it's not good for you
as a as a as a security executive within
the organization
because what it does is it holds you to
unreal expectations
it's sort of like the zero tolerance
statement
and the last one which happens an awful
lot is ones that are too vague
and not practically applicable a risk
appetite statement should be really
difficult to do
it should take the board of executives
a lot of argument to come at um
and well done
it should be quite fine-grained in terms
of saying well
you know we as an organization are
willing to take a particular risk in a
particular way
the other point is uh the lack of
degradation of
of risk or risk tolerance within the
organization
um by that i mean that obviously in some
organizations
you know they might they decide that
they're going to take a particular
the easy ones are probably financial
risk
maybe that organization says that the
board can sign off on a hundred million
dollar
financial risk and we're all familiar i
think with financial delegations we're
quite
comfortable with that and that's the
embodiment of a risk appetite
but we rarely see that in broader
security risk
you know that that the
a certain level is able to take a
certain security risk
a certain a higher level is able to take
a certain higher list
you do see it in the military
you know in dspf it actually allows
certain ranks to be responsible for
classification
of of documents who and that reflects
both the over classification of
information and the underclassification
of information
but it's rare to see it in in many other
contexts within the organizations
okay
defining and mean and implementing
meaningful metrics
um there is probably no one
perfect metric for any one organization
it's usually the best advice is what is
being used
within the industry within the field
and within the organization itself
if your organization is using
exclusively missed
frameworks then try and use them because
then you can speak the same languages
as as them if your organization is using
iso standards then
use the iso standards in the end
they're all trying to come at the same
thing
and in the end none of them are perfect
and we don't want the enem the perfect
to be the enemy of the good
be cautious about quantitative
or only using quantitative metrics
what i have seen personally is people
arguing
the point difference on quantitative
metrics
and what that means is you know
one person saying it's a 4.5 and the
other person's saying it's a five
and that might mean the difference
between two completely different actions
when what you're actually saying is on a
scale they're pretty close
and one's a little bit left of the other
one
um and that's where often qualitative
metrics can be useful
in terms of actually having a look at at
some of these things
but both um done well
uh can help
baselining is helpful as well because it
gives you a line in the sand it allows
you to celebrate your achievements
particularly if i go back to where i was
talking about
you have to implement change as a saiso
one of the big things
uh for those of you who came yesterday
we talked about kota
kotter is my favorite change management
hero
of how you do change management one of
the big things
is create wins along the way for your
change management if you can actually
find ways of celebrating wins in your
change process
even if you're not quite finished or
close to that's really good because it
you know it gives that psychological
impetus for people to go and you know do
that final
lift over the top or to the top of the
everest or what
however you want to use that description
um as i said there's lots of maturity
assessment frameworks uh
uh mark made the point that some of
these are
probably not technically maturity
assessment frameworks
but really use them but don't
think that they are necessarily the you
know
the perfection they are useful tools
they are not necessarily the be all and
end all
one thing that's really useful is
keeping an eye on trending
figures to trending metrics rather than
absolute metrics
is the organization improving rather
than
is it you know x number
this is worth just emphasizing in terms
of
when you are working uh at this iso
level
um biases we all have them
uh anchoring confirmation on
overconfidence if you go into this
into the literature there are hundreds
of biases
unfortunately we're human we're just
above uh bonobos
um so you know uh live with it
the problem is that in crises they can
be accentuated
we have effectively two brains um
we have a brain that works mostly in
crisis
you might call that type one 1 thinking
brain
and that is reactive fear-based and such
like
that is the brain that takes over in a
crisis
if security is being done of course it
is boring repetitive
and and just day to day and everything's
calm
but of course it never is and the
problem is that you can have make
critical errors of judgment if you are
not aware
of your biases don't be afraid of them
we all have them we're chimpanzees
this document here which you can find
site
colon.gov dot a u decision making during
crisis practical guide
is really good it talks a lot about that
don't know how much
running our time this
this comes from that document it talks
about
the processes for decision making during
a crisis
talks about psychological safety making
sure that you are
removing biases as much as you can in
your decision making
managing expectations and
and making sure that you're confirming
authority and direction and such like
really useful recommend it use it
please all yours
um yeah that document that alex is just
referring to it's extremely well written
and it's so nice to see a federal
government document that
actually talks about the way that people
behave
in reality rather than a nice perfect
process where we're all
we're all rational consumers which
doesn't actually exist in
in practice so um for the next couple of
slides let's have a quick chat about
diversity so look personally
i think it's a bit of a debate about
whether there really is a cyber security
skills shortage but
i know for sure that there definitely is
a diversity shortage in cyber security
so what is diversity diversity
is broadly speaking broken up into two
areas your social identity and your
professional identity
and it's all sorts of things this is a
really nice diagram to
to to summarize it
and part of a diversity is
how you perceive yourself and how you
perceive how other people perceive you
so what is inclusion well
inclusion is how we get the mix of
diversity in organizations to work
effectively together diversity on its
own
is a laudable goal but it won't
get the outcomes that we really want
and need as a society and as an industry
without effective inclusivity
so inclusion is
all the ways that people can feel
respected
for who they are and able to be
themselves
how they feel connected to their
colleagues and their sense of belonging
in an organization
how they perceive that they're
contributing their perspectives and
talents to their workplace
and how they're progressing in their
careers that is
how if if they're having equal access to
opportunities
and resources
diversity well before i go into that i
think this this
this is a great phrase that really sums
up the difference between diversity
and inclusion the diversity in cyber
security it's not just a moral issue
it's an issue of team success diverse
teams are
more innovative generally perform better
during crises
and are less likely to suffer from group
think
and that in its own should be a good
reason for people to be thinking
carefully
about they can harness the benefits of
diversity in their workplace because
groupthink can be particularly
corrosive to any kind of true innovation
the only way to realize these potential
benefits
is through effective inclusivity rather
than tokenism
if diversity is only a check box it
doesn't deliver good results
for anybody not for individuals not for
organizations
in fact you're very likely to result in
a large number of dis benefits
both for individuals and for
organizations
and that's all we had prepared in terms
of our
presentation proper so if anyone's got
any questions
you can ask them via the app or you can
just sing out
am i allowed to say that lucas because i
already did you can sing if you want
thank you uh there are a couple of
questions
and i thought one of them's going to be
answered judging
on what we discussed yesterday but it's
an abrupt stops a bit thank you
actually can we get a warm round of
applause because
six hours of content into 35 minutes
and how long did you have to prepare
about 24 hours
there we go so it was lack of sleep last
night most likely
well done uh there are a couple
questions on the q a
app so what questions would you suggest
during the one-on-one
look i suppose it uh we had a long
discussion yesterday about one once
the the purpose let's just go back to
the purpose
and then we can talk about the sorts of
questions one might ask the purpose of
one-on-ones
is several-fold right you are trying to
get to know as
the as the manager as the leader who
your
people are and you know what their wants
needs desires
are as as as workers right
so it should be mostly in their hands
um if you are if you're coming to them
with
you know here's 15 questions i want to
ask you
maybe the one-on-ones is not the right
forum for that because
what you're trying to do is get to know
them as individuals
and to build up trust your trust
of them and their trust of you and
that's
done through human interaction it's much
more difficult in covert times when
you're having to do this over zoom
and and i acknowledge that if you can go
and buy somebody a coffee
you know on a regular basis once a week
and have a quick half hour discussion
you know and you might be just talking
about the footy
you know if that's what they're what
they're into
yeah um
you know from a national security
perspective the reason why
why you do that is to try and get to
know your staff because you're worried
because you need as a as a manager in a
national security area
to make sure that you're dealing with
insider risk
insider threat that to a lesser extent
in
all workplaces but certainly from a
you know if you if you're working in a
in a secure area in a sensitive area
you're trying to work out are there's
people other things stressing this
person
you know are they are there kids pissing
them off
you know never happen husband wife you
know whatever
you know how can you help
that's what you're trying to do because
you're trying to humanize that
relationship
because um and i've said this previously
if you look you know if you're an
obsessive nerd about some of these
things like i am
um and you go and read the the the
report on warwick's
warren snowden warwick snowden anyway
the guy the spy who went to russia
edward edward snowden that's the one
edward snowden his brother was warren
anyway his his bosses
had never met him you know so
so and this is a guy who had tssci
clearance
and then they're surprised that this guy
is disgruntled
so you know i'll leave it to you
so one-on-ones are about grunties and
not disgruntleism do we have another
question
there was yes uh so queensland
government have mandated the
implementation of isms
in your experience what are the biggest
challenges we are likely to face
sorry suppose the government had
implemented
the the isms uh
queensland government have mandated we
implement
isms yes so is 18
which is the queensland government
information security policy and
note that i am not a queensland
government employee so this is
personal views not not the views of
queensland government
um what are the challenges in
implementing an isms
so the big the big challenges
are trying to get alignment between
your information security management and
your risk
appetite within the organization how do
you do that
by making sure that your most senior
members of
in this case your department are
involved
in actually determining what your risk
appetite is
and what the actual tolerance to risk is
within the organization
because that then should determine
how much money they're willing to spend
because effectively
you know it's the pareto principle 80 20
80 percent of of of costs of
mitigating a risk can be
mitigated with 20 percent cost the last
20 percent
costs 80 that's a principle it's an
overall big
arching thing so again it's a matter of
how much
how much the ceo stroke border
management actually cares
and so i think that that it's actually
getting them to focus
and to own that they that they have
information security risk and to make
those hard decisions
they are accountable uh you know
in the end for for uh for
making sure that the information within
the organization is secure
now i know that there are a few uh
queensland government people here and if
you want to jump up and disagree with me
please do but uh
yeah um
no one's jumped up and disagreed how are
we going for time lakers
uh we are over but we're going into a
break
so we may have no we're cutting it i'm
getting that
get off get off so uh i had a question
but i think i'll ask
after so if anyone does have questions
please feel free to
grab them in the hallway yep not
physically because covert social
distancing and all that
um could have a warm round of applause
for dr mark smith thank you very much
foreign