hello everyone um all right coming up
now we have dr dan kims associate
professor at the university of
queensland
i'm a uq alumni myself
and he's here to talk about moving
target defenses
recent advances and challenges
thank you
uh it's very my great honor to give a
talk at all search conference
2021. uh today i'm going to talk about
moving target differences and
some recent events and some challenges
and before i'm going to talk about
moving target defense let me introduce
myself a little bit i'm an editor board
member of elsevier computers and
security
which is one of the top journal in cyber
security area
also i started serving the ieee
communications and surveys and tutorials
it's the number one impact
in the all italy journals
there are about 220 ipp journals and i
served as general chair and co-chair for
the conferences
acisp and pldc
and so on and my publication
according to the google scholar is more
than
and i have published more than 130
papers
in journals and conferencing workshops
over the years
i have done some research in
and development uh in regard to moving
target defense
uh sponsored by new zealand governments
and also u.s
army research lab
and i got
fundings from u.s army's lab three times
i'm also working on that now
and this is the list of projects i've
done with the u.s omg lab in
regards to moving target differences
and this is a talk line line first i'm
going to talk about the
background of mtd
and then three-dimensional
aspect of mtd
and
uh what type of mtds are existing
and then some empty related mattresses
then i'm going to talk about some
of my work
in
mtd techniques for the cloud computing
in vehicle networks and iot
and
other areas and then i'm going to
introduce some other activities going on
in academia and also industry
and finally i'm going to introduce some
challenges and future directions
before i'm going to talk about mtd let
me summarize some terms the system so we
can think of the asset as it can be any
system resources including hardware
software and data and communication
facilities and some examples of iot
assets are infrastructure
applications endpoints and iot
cloud and supply chain
and
in
in the sys in a system or a network
there is a proven ability
vulnerabilities of flow or weakness that
could be
exploited by
attackers and to violate system
securities goals like cia
and there are tech surfaces attack
surface is a uh
a collection of reachable and explorable
vulnerabilities in a system and network
in the maybe the i.t assets
and then there are mitigation strategy
in terms of
prevention detection and tolerance and
sometimes resiliency
and then why we need an mtd
first reason is that is it possible to
make a perfectly secure system
yeah no it's not possible so there are
always a way to find vulnerability in
the system and networks
and how about this traditional defense
techniques are very passive mostly and
aesthetic
so once you apply it then you use it for
a long time
but attacker has advantage of a defender
because they have developed advanced
techniques
in penter writing systems and networks
developing new exploits
new ways to find the vulnerabilities and
then they exploit them continuously and
try to compromise systems and networks
then how then this call calls that uh
this generates a symmetry between
attacker and defender so attacker has
advantage over
defender
this way attackers are bigger than
and defender so can you change this
landscape
how
right that's my question that's why
their mtd is required so can you change
the situation like this way or maybe
a great uh
dependent has much more power than
attackers
so one way to do this one is to
apply
moving target defense
so moving target defense technique uh
continuously change
the attack surface
uh to twerk attacks
and uh
it's like a
trading or cyber or slash digital shell
game have you done initial game before
so you have a ball
right
and then you mix the cups
then
ask that where is that right so if a
system can be dynamically changed
right in a regular basis or maybe by uh
triggering events
then
uh attacker will be uh not easier to
attack that one so mtd
is trying to make it
much harder
for attacker to their dirty work by
consistently change
the attack surface
and also the
defenders environments
and
also it try to increase the urgent t
and also includes the complexity for
attackers
right
that's the main goal and there are three
dimensions in mtd first dimension is
what to move
so how you can change system
configurations
from the static configuration to the
dynamic
so what elements
we can
use to do that
that's the first
uh dimension
what to move so it's about moving
elements so it can be a single element
there can be a multiple elements
so and the second uh uh dimension is how
to move it's about techniques
so
how
you can choose an element or more
and how you can move that elements
right that's the second one technique
the third one is when to move
so it's about adaption strategy
uh
so first the
moving elements so i i listed
the potential layers we can think about
from the hardware
virtual machine monitor this is called
hypervisor
and virtual machine
instance
in a cloud or a virtualized system
an operating system
an application and so on so this can be
applied in many different areas so i
will show you
what are the albumin elements you can
think about
in a minute
and then second one is about how to move
uh i classify them into three different
categories
including diversity
redundancy and shuffle
okay
and for the uh when to move
we can divide them into three cases time
based
event based
and hybrid type
so now i'm going to talk about one by
one
the first one is what to move it's
moving elements
so we published this one you know a acm
ccs workshop mtd workshop there is a mtd
workshop annual workshop at
international with a acmccs conference
and we listed all the uh some of the
existing uh elements
that you could think about if you take a
look at this table
uh if you see the diversity
so what kind of
different
hardware we can use
to increase
the complexity of attacks
so from the hardware point of view we
can use different cpu and their
hardware architecture
and so on and for the virtual machine
monitor hypervisor level uh there can be
a you can choose a zen or a vmware or an
exi server right and so on then maybe
there are more than that
and the virtual machine uh we may use uh
same as os
or maybe different version and then os
level we can use different versions of
os and different version of kernels and
so on
and then for the application
for the same application we can use
different
software version right for example
web we can use iis or
apache and the different version as well
and for the redundancy we can think
about how we can use different uh type
of replicas
so that uh this this can increase the
availability and reliability of uh
systems we want to protect
the last one the shuffle
we can change some values
uh you know timely based or event based
so some of them can be the port number
can be changed where virtual ip can be
changed
and personal ip and port number can be
on a regular basis that's all the
possible elements you can think of
course there are much more than that
but we summarize that into this table
and if i give an example for each
techniques shuffle can be
we uh can keep the real ip address as
they are
but we can change virtual ip address
every x period time so every one minute
birch life pictures can be changed and
then
uh
attacker is trying to scan
the network
then either change already right so what
is the typical the port scanning ip
scanning time it may takes maybe a few
seconds to the minutes
then if the ip address is being changed
then even though attack can find the
data ip address during that period of
time it's gone in the next pace
right that's why this is very efficient
so pressure shuffling can be applied how
we can realize that one we may use uh
scn technology uh software department
networking technology is easy to
configure that at the software switch
level or some some researchers use a
middleware or a proxy solver to do that
work
so real ip address does not change but
only the virtual ip address are located
to the real ip address is changing every
uh time interval right that's the idea
of shuffling a sharpening can be
happened in many different ways
based on what elements
a security designer can choose
the second one is a redundancy rather
than having one single solver but you
can think about having two solver
especially this redundancy is not very
new technique but
in the full tones design is very
commonly used
so if you increase number of replica or
a number of servers it's good for uh
availability perspective of systems
right so that's the redundancy can be
used and this redundancy can be
same replica or it can be a diversely
picked as well so they so
redundancy can be combined with other
techniques also this redundancy can be
combined with shuffle as well
so each
server may have different virtual life
addresses located rather than having the
same ip address
and the last one is the diversity we can
use different
version of software
this can be done at the os level
application level or compiler level or
different
program languages
so that's different implementations
and and this uh summarized
some benefits when uh diversity
redundancy supplies use shuffle is very
efficient
and uh
because it's you don't have to change
much thing but only ip address virtual
port number it's very efficient to
implement the redundancy can can help to
increase the reliability and
availability of systems
and the diversity can
enhance
resiliency and robustness of
the systems and networks that's the
benefits also they have a drawbacks i'm
going to talk about that too
soon
and the last
d is about when to move
so this can be done and when system
starts
time based one every
time interval for example 300 second
you can change the ip address
and move can happen right the average
another 300 seconds elapsed then
a move can be
happening and another move or this can
be done based on events or
uh
maybe all multiple events for example
on intrusion detection
alert is generated
then it may
uh trigger a move
right rather than waiting until the next
interval that's the idea of that so this
event can be any many different things
right so this event can be user-driven
so i want to do it uh randomly
because to to protect the system against
much more intelligent attackers
and this can be combined together so
this is called hybrid triggering
so event based and time-based mtd can be
used same time
and that there is some delay for this
one right of course in intrusion
directions alert is
uh
generated then you need to check that
whether this event is actually
a correct one or not and it takes some
time to check that
and so stretch-wise there's some delay
as well
and
now let me introduce some mtd related
mattresses so we can think about
security matrices
and the performability mattress and
economy matrices
so when we think about uh
to adopt mtd techniques
to uh our uh some system we want to
protect
first one security there are many so
many different types of security
matrices
some examples are system risk
system risk can be computed by
multiplying the probability and the
impact value
and
and also
attack cost
and attack path
and the vulnerability level and the
probability of the success and many
other mattresses can be used to
show that different aspects of mtd so
let's say that we have a static system
and also we have a stack system which is
adopting some part of some uh of the mtd
techniques
so can we compare that how efficient or
effective
uh the system adopting mtd technique
right so it may show that there's some
improvement in the system risk
but
it may uh
lower some
all right at that cost but
it may interest another problems one of
the problem can be performance so for
example
uh users are using a system
then they want to connect to the system
which is adopting mtd
then there's end-to-end connections
suddenly empty is triggered what
happened
the connection will be lost right so
especially that the
the tcp connection is long tail then it
may cause
maybe some performance drop
degradation right and this can be a
critical problem so we also measure not
only the security aspect of the mtd
but also performance so that it may
cause some blocking of
connections also dropping of existing
connections
and also it may
downgrade the qos level right throughput
can be dropped and so on right
so we we try to
develop mtd techniques which can satisfy
the secure level
also performance also
also this has some trade-off if you want
to increase the security
then we may need to
sacrifice this performance right so
let's say the attacker can
uh find the virtual ip address within uh
an order of seconds
then we have to trigger mtdg very
frequently right i think i can find the
virtual ip address being used
within uh order of minutes then we can
less frequently trigger mtd in terms of
the time-based mtd techniques
so that we we're going to lose less
connections of the estimated users right
that's the idea of that also when you
think about the cost
economic way so when mtd is adopted in
the system
uh does roi is improved a lot a lot
right return on investment or return on
security investment increases or not
that's that should be considered also
when we have a static system then
adopted mtd techniques then that
anti-technique uh may need some capital
expansion investment also operational
costs
so so with this all the compressive
consideration of security
econo uh probability and recurring
mattresses we can think about this mtd
technique is effective and efficient or
maybe considered ineffective or
efficient this is the idea of mtd
technique and mattresses
this
clutch
summarizes what i've done over the last
nine years
or so
so this paper published
first one and then over there i
published a lot of papers in mtd area
so start with the how we can evaluate
the effectiveness of mtd techniques
and then develop the neural
anti-technique
and scalable mtd techniques
and
develop anti-technique for uh
iot
and sdn
and also cloud computing
the domain and also develop some dynamic
matrices for mtd techniques
and this is a summary of that uh
and then uh
i have a
supervised four graduate and they worked
on these different topics
and first one
mostly focus on effectiveness evaluation
of mtd techniques
so let's say uh if you
if a network is
adopting mtd technique does it improve
the security or not right how effective
or ineffective that mtv technique so we
need to evaluate that before we adopt
that one or maybe deploy that mtd
technique so this uh this ph student at
the time was focusing on uh how to use a
graphical model to evaluate
effectiveness of mtd techniques second
phd
she was working on the mtd and the cyber
session technology for iot domain and
third one developed uh high virtual ip
shuffling and virtual port shuffling for
uh scn networks and we also have a test
bed for that
the last one
here was interesting combination of
empty techniques for cloud computing so
i'll show some demo for that
so let me show you some uh
the technique applied to the cloud
some some sort real domain first one is
mtd for the cloud and the second mtd in
the uh sdn
and third is mtd for the in vehicle
networks
and the last one is uh mtd folder iot
this is a real implementation so we use
a unitec cloud
and we also made a graphical user
interface
to trigger mtd in the cloud environments
and
let me show you some demo hopefully it
should work i just use a usb stick so
let me click that one
ah yeah
yeah it works
so this shows a shuffle so for the mtd
we use a virtual machine migration as a
shuffling technique
so you can see that uh some of the nodes
the virtual machine uh is moving from
one
logical host to the other
so we can change the configuration of uh
cloud computing so that uh uh it's not
dynamic anymore so a
virtual machine in the cloud virtualized
environment can move from one
to the other way so
on a regular basis or event based that's
the first demo the second one is um
diversity so we use different or virtual
machine version
so very slow
yeah
so you can see that the the os version
of course this can be implemented at
different way so application level or
other level but we we choose that one so
you can see that different version of
os's
and that that can be deployed uh
based on uh
our policy and the rules and then your
implementation so we use the api
provided by the
private cloud
and you can see that
we can apply different types of
os version in the cloud
and the last one is a redundancy and
this this one you can see that the sum
of virtual machine uh
have multiple replicas
so you can look at look at them in the
middle so some node
so you can see that the
new circle will be generated can you see
that yeah it's quickly happened so that
uh
we can generate redundancy uh in real
time of in the cloud environments so
that uh it can increase the availability
of uh
a cloud system
and the next one is that how we can
implement mtd in the sdn
so we have
tested this one in the stochastic
modeling
using petri net modeling and also use a
simulation also we have or our own test
bed so using a soft switch
and
the idea is this
when attacker is trying to penetrate the
system and then make a later movement to
reach a target and exfoliate the data
we assume that attacker can follow the
cyber key chain so located by team one
so from data collection right so the
first step is to collect data about that
so
very typically
attacker use port scanning or ip
scanning then if the
virtual ip address and
real ip address mapping is changing
every unit time
how effect
effective this one
against
port scanning ip scanning so we
tested that in the our scene test bed
and also measure that uh how long it
takes
to
find a virtual address address being
located to on end host right for a given
period of time
and this shows very effective way so
this is one of the example of that it's
called the flexible
random virtual ip multiplexing in short
flvm
as you can see that
one real ip address
is mapped with the multiple virtual ip
address and port number here port number
is a real port number the virtual ip
address is a different prototype address
so we can use 24
or 16 depending on how well uh this uh
system want to use right so 16 then if
you use a 16 sider then it's a 2 to the
16 right it can be used for the virtual
life address this is really hard to find
within a minute or three minutes that's
attacker so sometimes it's lucky enough
then i can find it then next one is
attacker can
find some vulnerability
in the end host
then scan that then they take another
time then uh attacker is successful to
find the vulnerability then attacker can
exploit that balloon ability then
entities triggered right then attackers
template is gone
something like that so attacker can
achieve all the steps from the data
collection
to the
backdoor installation
if it takes maybe
order of
between the
empty interval maybe during the second
then attacker will
maybe have that access to the internal
system right so we want to
reduce the time interval if there are
frequent
attack attempts
if there's less attempts then we can uh
increase the time interval right that's
the main idea of that and this is
implemented and tested as well
and a lot next one is that in vehicle
networks one of the the project uh i'm
currently currently working on uh with
the arl is that how to apply moving
target defense techniques to the
in-vehicle network this can be used to
the autonomous vehicle as well right so
in beacon network they have many ecu's
electric computer unit and then they the
ecu's are communicating
uh by our canvas
it's a chi area network
and
that uh if a attacker outside of the
vehicle can connect to the uh the car
then they can compromise some of the
ecu's then they can shut down the
function of the ecu how we can
make this difficult right
the one of the ideas use mtd technique
for
in vehicle networks so we started with
them and there was we also have an ids
module so it can detect ongoing attack
we are using ai technique to detect it
and also use a misused detection engine
as well so by detecting some ongoing
attacks we can adjust the trigger uh
interval
okay so that if you see a lot of alerts
generated from the
uh in vehicle network then we trigger
more mtd and also how we can develop the
empty techniques in this work we change
the address shuffling of a packet header
so that the attacker can get some of the
the canvas messages
but it's invalid after
uh after some minutes that's the idea of
in vehicle network mtd techniques
uh this is one of the state-of-the-art
work uh we have been working on
and the last one i want to introduce is
that how we can apply that to mtd for
the iot so here we combine the mtd
technique with a cyber deception
so this shows a very simple iot network
and you can see that there are multiple
subnets uh
represented as a dotted rectangular
and then we can put some
uh deception nodes
this decoy node reception node can be
low interaction decoy nodes or maybe
high interruption decoy knots low
interaction decoy node is cheap and
attacker can find out this is a low one
right it's easily figured out high
direction is a expensive but it mimics
real behavior of iot nodes and those
servers so when attackers trying to get
to the
deception nodes
then uh
it's forward to the uh decoy server then
attacker cannot get anything
and
also we can shuffle the network topology
so that the reachability from the entry
point to the target server can be
changed
uh based on the time-based mtd or
uh event-based mtd so this can be used
for their iot networks so we've been
doing this one also with the arl but not
not the same team with different team so
we publish some papers in this domain as
well
and i have listed some
activities uh being carried out in
academia
so arizona state university they are
interested in the mtd and sdn and they
try to apply the game theoretical
approaches to the mtd how attackers
behave and how defend they behave this
can be formulated as a game so that
that's what was done and the carnegie
mellon university and uh
sci the software engineering institute
in the canada university they want to
develop middleware for mtd techniques so
they do not want to change any legacy
system
also
but they want to provide empty technique
how what's the way they can build a
middleware which can understand
the static systems
configuration and the messages and then
the attackers right on the lessman user
so they want to develop middleware which
can provide mtd technique and the george
mason university they are interested in
mtd quantification also performance
model for mtd and penn state university
they are interested in how to use all
reinforcement learning uh to
decide which mtd actions are the best
and uh universal south florida they are
interested in empty theory and mtd for
the scn uh university queensland i'm
called
we're interested in how
can the model attack
attack model based mtd also we want to
develop mtd data metrics and also i
already introduced some of my research
outputs
and in the companies
uh i cannot interest every company but i
i want to highlight some of them so many
people ask about this mtd is actually
practical
yeah the answer is yes so you may know
that uh as a uh
asrl is already implemented in the linux
kernel right it's it's a long time back
so from 2020 so you can regard this as a
mtd technique it's a type of shuffling
technique
and also in the open bs bsd and the
window vista and what now windows 10 has
this one aslr and also kernel
aslr is applied in ibm research hi far
they they want to develop uh mtd
technique uh against rop so rp is a
return oriented programming right this
is a more advanced memory
uh based attacks uh in the systems so
they want to use mtd technique and by
shuffling the
uh the sequence of uh program executions
yeah so this is the ongoing work and
morphe sac is one company they want to
develop the cybersecurity solution based
on mtd
for and host protection so they want to
protect the virtual desktop
infrastructure and this is funded by
the usdod and dhs
there's several millions of project
and the next ie they are they are
focusing on the entity for the data
storage uh area
and the crypto next next one there they
want to develop hardware device it's
like a proxy between
uh
users and static systems right they want
to protect the system but rather than
changing the system they want to develop
a device like a secure box so they can
put them in the middle so this can
provide some shuttling techniques in
between so that they can protect the
legacy and static systems that's just a
long way to work of course i haven't
listed all the companies i cannot find
all of them but this is a somewhat
example that how the companies and
the products are being developed
okay last one is uh the challenge of the
mtd techniques
so i have listed four of them the first
one is the security and performance and
cost tradeoff so you can see that
if you trigger mtd a lot
then it introduced downtime
or maybe performance degradation and
also that downtime calls the
uh penalty of their services right
so how we can adjust this one it's a
trade-off second one is that can you
develop hybrid mtd
for that that can be optimized right so
how often mtd is triggered
and how often we can trigger event based
mtd
for a certain system so can you optimize
that that's the second challenge the
third challenge is about uh so i
introduced some practical services
but there are still some more
improvements right that needed to be
needed and testing as well so i
developed my own
purpose techniques and
and not doing research but we need more
tests and then deployment and and so on
that's that's the challenges and the
last one is that
can we advance
the mtd technique itself
against ai based attacks
so we assume that the dummy attackers
maybe a little a little intelligent
attacker not very smart smartest
attacker right smartest attacker will
use very sophisticated techniques to
from the data collection to the
achieving the goal
so can we develop empty techniques
which is adaptive and also
very intelligent about airbase attacks
that's the challenge as well and then
the last one is the future direction is
of how you can do these things right
that i list the same thing for that uh
fish interaction
okay that's it uh for uh today's talk
yeah thank you
all right um we've got one question in
there so far but if you have any
questions feel free to chucking me up
really quick
um so our first one is many
organizations struggle to do
basic bcp and dr
are there bite size mtd recommendations
that could be used to implement for high
risk systems as a first step
so
where can we get started with mtd
yeah so easy adoption could be the
virtual ip shuffling as long as we have
some infrastructure supports
soft switch that could be easy one so
andos have uh this virtual ip shopping
and purchase for shuffling it's easy to
implement and as long as
you can buy some
additional devices yeah that's possible
cool um from andrew great work and
there's many uses
and i wanted to chuck one question out
there myself um in your example for
diversity you had
uh
an example with uh apache servers and
iis servers
um does that end up
you know expanding your threat landscape
in terms of zero day vulnerabilities
yes so that's uh
even though we introduce diversity it
doesn't guarantee that the security will
be improved
yes it may interest more uh
attack factors
also attack surface you can widen that
so for the zero day uh
somewhat that we do not trust anything
then we do not know that what's the new
attack will be coming up by exploring
the vulnerabilities that the one way is
to change things right it may help may
not depending on how quickly attacker
can proceed with the majority
vulnerability let's say that new
generator vulnerability and then
x and later exploit can quickly uh
achieve all the goal from the entry to
the end
within empty interval the mtd will not
be effective
but if not then until entity is still
valid yep
old school
yep so is there value in uh in
disrupting the reconnaissance more than
there is on actually changing the the
architecture of the landscape so how the
things that what what what
infrastructure you might be using so if
you disrupt the if you disrupt the
reconnaissance in the first place
you put the attacker back so far that it
might never ever catch up and you can
slow down the other changes which are
there before you can keep your
availability going and you give up this
service disruption
but you you're holding back the attacker
by just giving them lots of false
information
yes that's possible so um
currently that we if you think about the
reconnaissance as a first step
and then that's the first attempt right
to block it but
uh attacker has already done the the
data collection about the potential
server then we need to think about the
next level mtd so not just a single
layer mtd
when you think about defense in depth
so multiple layer of mtd so i also think
about that too so how we can develop
this um
stronger mtd
with a what-if scenario what if the
first step is done
and uh attacker is already inside of the
network right yeah that's a very good
question yeah yeah that's that should be
more developed
all right it looks like that's all the
questions we have for we're just running
out of time now too so um just another
round of applause and thank you
[Applause]
you