thanks very much mike thank you david
yes this is our moonshot moment as you
said mike we've got some amazing
speakers about to take the stage here
for our first panel session
but this and all sessions over the next
couple of days if you want to ask a
question at any stage
in the app you have a live q a icon so
just click on live q a
send us your question we'll get through
those if time allows mike's about to be
joined on stage to discuss
what does a security transformation
strategy
look like and how can soar help by the
following james
young from splunk jess dodson from
microsoft casey ellis from bug crowd
and anthony kitzelman from air services
australia
give them a big round of applause let's
get our panel discussion underway
live q a icon if you'd like to
contribute
all right you've just listened to me
ranting for i'm not sure how long that
was
so i'm my goal here is to talk as little
as possible because we have some experts
here this time
so let's start by a really quick
introduction to each of our speakers
we're very very pleased to have all four
of you thank you let's start down this
end
so jess with over 15 years of experience
in the management and architecture of
identity and security systems
passion for fixing things and the
stubbornness to push people to get the
basics right
jess wears the title of sec ops which
proudly
though her official title is customer
engineer at microsoft
which is uh way more boring but i don't
know
we've seen girl gems in your internet
travels so
uh maybe check in to twitter for that
twitter yep um and uh you might have
bumped into jess
likely in one of her sweary rants
yeah jess thank you
[Applause]
alright next up we have casey
going down the line chairman and founder
cto of bug crowd i'm sure we've all
heard a bug crowd
a co-founder of the disclosed io project
he's a 20-year plus veteran of
information security as a career
and has been inventing stuff and
generally getting technology to do
things that isn't supposed to
since childhood professionally has worn
a variety of hats
working as a pen tester security and
risk consultant solutions architect cso
and then more recently
as a career entrepreneur and company
leader casey pioneered the crowdsource
security as a service model
launching the first bug bounty programs
on the bug crowd platform in 2012 i
can't believe it's that long ago
that's amazing and co-founded the
disclose.o vulnerability disclosure
standardization
project in 2014 also a long time ago
alrighty uh who else have we got let's
move along
we have tony is the chief information
security officer at air services
australia
and formerly the australian digital
health agency's chief information
security officer
and the general manager for the
australian digital health agency's cyber
security centre
chinese always looking to further his
knowledge through new challenges working
within the cyber security domain and
believes that our role as
leaders in this exciting field is to
challenge the status quo
you must have listened to my opening
speech before and look at ways in which
we can shape the future and security of
our respective organizations here
tony holds numerous industry and
academic qualifications
he's currently studying masters in cyber
security and strategy and
diplomacy at unsw competing university
for university of queensland but that's
okay
all right with that alrighty lucky lucky
last james
with 20 years of experience james has
taken every opportunity to learn more
about
and in turn improve how security can be
done
his current role at splunk as a global
security specialist
it's a fortune of speaking with a broad
range of different people advising
organizations around developing and
maturing their cyber security
capabilities
this work also often involves
collaboration across
a range of internal and external
stakeholders now that's complicated and
tricky so well done
to develop and improve the joint
solutions splunk and their security
ecosystem partners
bring to market to help solve a range of
cyber security challenges
so let's um let's just kick off
and what i'm going to do is i'll go the
opposite direction this time i'll start
up here
if each of you would like to just give
the audience a bit of a flavor a bit of
an overview of what we're thinking
where we're going uh what's the
direction
and obviously we're we're not too short
on time but
if i do the zipper thing that means
you're going too long
okay go for it thanks mike hopefully
that microphone's on but um
yeah look the way i sort of see it is
that we're sort of stuck in this state
from a security perspective of
constantly playing catch up or
constantly having to react
to sort of all the different challenges
that we're faced with um
from a security point of view so if we
look at it from the point of view of
simply just been able to support say
business transformation digital
transformation those types of things or
maybe getting the security basics sort
of right there's lots of fundamentals
that we need to probably do a better job
of getting right
and even looking at the ways that we
sort of deal with sort of
maybe the common metric of say dwell
time for instance and how long it takes
us
to find the important things or the
critical incidents and really sort of
see
uh soar as an opportunity in itself that
can
not only really help us to do things
faster but probably redirect and refocus
our efforts on
improving all of the things that really
matter so i really sort of see the
the the way that we should approach when
we're thinking about building out maybe
a saw capability as well
look at all the things we spend the most
time on work out how we can automate
those in a sensible way and then maybe
look at the resources we have in turn
available now
to maybe focus on some of those more
critical things to help us to improve
and maybe get in front of
what we need to think about from a
security perspective so
certainly said it's a big opportunity to
perhaps change the way that we approach
things so
indeed well said absolutely look it's
the next evolution of where we need to
be if we think back 10 15 years ago we
were dealing with spam and our
i.t people at the time were digging in
setting up spam filters and manually
clearing out
this is the next future for us is how do
we scale rapidly to use the advantages
of automation and orchestration to
actually apply the same logic
we don't think about spam anymore we
deal with three percent imagine if that
was in our security operation centers
we're our analysts who are overwhelmed
at the moment we're dealing 100
000 a million events a day what happens
when we hit a billion when iot really
hits and runs
and these hubs are the future where
technology converges so rapidly
just becomes an overwhelming challenge
the adversary is really good
they're disciplined they're thinking
it's no longer a 15 year old well
actually there are 15 year old kids out
there sitting there with their script
kitties
but the good guys the bad guys that are
out there are actually really good at
their trade craft
and they offer a significant challenge
our analysts are just as good but
they're overwhelmed with the sheer
volume of what they're dealing with
so we need to look at ways to actually
change the culture within the security
operations centers
so that this isn't actually a threat to
what they're doing but more about an
enablement of allowing them to focus on
the really
challenging wicked problems as opposed
to the volume crime that they're trying
to deal with every day
there's some there's some good 15 year
olds kicking around out there trying to
help out too so there is that
um so you know my point of view on this
is that um you know cyber security is
an intractably human problem like the
idea of people making mistakes that
allow
exploitation that predates the internet
by a couple of thousand years
um as does the idea of people taking
advantage of that for for their own for
their own gain so there's this element
of human creativity
that we're never going to fully remove
from
from you know what we're doing and our
work
but the counterpoint to that uh and this
actually it was you know coming from a
gartner conference in 2018
um you know risk-based vulnerability
management which is you know the space
that i
mostly play in uh had been a thing that
the cool kids were talking about for a
really long time
2018 felt like the year where everyone
realized that we're kind of screwed if
we don't
do that we're not going to get around to
all of it um and and where we're at now
i feel
as a kind of progression of that is this
mindset shift in security in general
from capability-based
you know programs and process and
approaches to security to one that's
risk-based
um because we have to and and that
involves the use of automation to
classify the use of automation to be
able to solve to make decisions on
behalf of the user guided by the user
they're really tying it back to the
analogy of the um almost the iron man
suit which is where i think saw comes
into it
the suit without the human is dumb but
the human without the suit is weak and i
think if we can get that pairing right
as we go forward that's how we solve
this problem
and i think it's really interesting
looking at it from the perspective of
being in a
sock team you're not going to be
automated out of a job
the aim of this isn't to automate you
out of a job the aim of this is to make
your job
way more fun you don't want to be
sending emails to users you don't want
to be
resetting passwords you want to be doing
cool stuff and focusing on things that
are actually important rather than
boring day-to-day work
and when it comes to security strategy
one of the big ones for me
is getting the boring things right and
doing that automation for the really
boring things
but also going back and focusing on the
basics
and getting the basics right from the
get-go so doing
proactive work and focusing on our
proactive rather than purely reactive
absolutely amazing couldn't agree more
now um
i did say that i don't want to do a lot
of talking here so
your goal everyone here everyone out in
virtual land
jump into the app and send through your
questions
so what we're going to do obviously is
they'll come through on the app
uh shortly adam's going to start reading
a few of those out
um please you obviously use this
opportunity
but there is a caveat i get in first
because as i said i love coming to this
conference because i get to meet all my
heroes
so i have a couple of questions first so
me first
all righty i've got a question for you
um
okay let's let's talk a little bit about
small business so a lot of enterprises
obviously reported
breaches you know we've had so many um
solar winds we have
ev everything that you could possibly
imagine has been a breach
assuming all of the businesses were
already adopting a saw approach
how could soar help a small to medium
business so the larger organizations
yeah okay they're probably
yeah if hopefully they're okay hasn't
stopped data breaches
in small business though what would you
suggest
uh let's go to who wants to take first
question
go for it it's actually a really good
one and my last job actually
tapped on this challenge quite well
working inside the health sector digital
health we were working with all our
partners out there in the um the health
sector delivering frontline health
services
imagine a small gp clinic that might
have five six doctors
the person who provides its support also
runs the reception and does a whole pile
of back stuff in that
and we sit down and work with them and
try and understand the challenges they
have in delivering their business
where their constraints are real world
they don't have the money to spend on a
security
analyst sitting in the environment and
we were always saying to this to these
people out there
find an msp that you can partner with so
you can actually leverage
the skill and the scale that they bring
to the equation in a cost effective
manner
with the an msp using something like the
sort framework and actually bringing it
all together
it actually means that this becomes a
commodity product that can actually be
delivered into the service
and allows people to move on with their
focus it's just unrealistic to expect
that people are going to be
delivering the specialty service like
healthcare and also being
astute enough to be able to deal with
the cyber challenge that's on the
landscape
right here and now they will get lost in
it and they will be sitting there in the
dark for ages
just getting wrecked on the side of the
road so this is an opportunity that i
think small business can partner with
now i know a lot of people are thinking
oh we're just going to push people
towards an msp
but so what msps are there to provide a
service the more people that consume
those services
drives competitiveness in the market and
then we'll be able to see this becoming
a cost-effective solution
we can't do it on our own and i think
saw inside an msp environment like a
sock as a service
really does move the needle yeah
to add to that um you know i spent a
decent chunk of time talking to
uh you know how do we how do we bake
security and like how do we prioritize
security um as a startup like
getting hacked is not your biggest
threat at that stage like your next
payroll is so
how do we approach this from a rational
standpoint and to your point like
really the idea of like in sourcing the
things that are core and then
outsourcing as much of the context as
you possibly can
actually viewing that as a way to to be
able to double down on value
that you're building into the business
but the benefit of that on this side of
the question is that
you know you're either automating or
leaving some of the security aspects to
the people who actually have
defined expertise around those
particular things so it's it's
a question of economic rationalism as
much as it is you know staying sane i
think
you now i think as an example perhaps of
of something that we see
often from an automation first use case
point of view is um
automation of investigations of phishing
emails so if we think about
i mean phishing is a challenge we're
faced with continually
and small business doesn't matter what
size of organization
you are it's a problem you need to deal
with and if you can actually take that
on board
build an automation use case that's
going to cover investigations
of those phishing emails as a small
business that's one less thing you
potentially need
to worry about and it's certainly
something that
customers large and small they're all
usually starting with something along
those lines as their first use case when
it comes to automation because it's
usually the same process
emails are all traditionally the same
type of thing we can feed into the
automation engine and run through a
standard process to
to investigate and make a determination
is it likely to be fishing or not
and then determine what to do after that
maybe pass it to human for four next
steps or something like that but that's
that's probably a really fantastic place
to start
and i really liked anthony's point about
utilizing
msps and mssps because you get the
benefit then
of their experience not just dealing
with your organization
but with a whole range of other
organizations they're getting threat
intelligence
from so much more than just your org so
you get to leverage that so
while it may look like a large cost
you are getting so much more from that
right i suppose one of the follow-ups on
that
and look there are questions coming
through that's awesome i will
i promise i will shut up in a moment
just one more thing
um obviously and tony you mentioned that
the
drive to msps and you know obviously
that'll bring competitiveness
and price or competitive prices down one
thing that concerns me and having having
known a lot of
people in not cyber security but in pure
i.t
that have not potentially the best
approach to cyber security and a lot of
those obviously sort of hang up their
shingle and say right you know
his bargain bob's pc sales store and you
know
here's your antivirus endpoint product
thingy protection just go
use that you'll be fine and and you know
there's businesses obviously purchasing
these things
so i guess where i'm going with with my
thinking
is the industry probably needs training
programs
or incentives or something to drive
those small operators
towards some of the things that we're
talking about here does anyone have any
thoughts on
are there existing programs uh do you
have any suggestions
i think the the the past providers like
uh you know
the different folks that are basically
trying to enable the cloud
for all sorts of different companies
like ranging
they're scaling vertically so you can
you can procure it as a
you know small business or a startup you
can use it as an enterprise
seeing more and more of these like sore
like features
creep in because they can it's like okay
we've got visibility we've got telemetry
we've got the ability to act
um that's all stuff that we can do as an
organization it's becoming a value added
something that you know we can be
suggestive around if we identify
something really silly that's about to
happen
or we can make it configurable by the by
the user and the owner
yeah i love the concept of make secure
uh
make insecure obvious and secure easy
just as a solution
premise um and looking for the folks
that are really trying to trying to do
that
i don't feel like that's a solved
problem yet by any stretch of the
imagination but there's people that are
really actively trying to approach it in
that way and i think
you know finding those is part of the
answer to the question
all right i actually think that's a good
example too um one of the challenges
back in digital health was working with
these
small healthcare provider organizations
that were trying to run their own team
and picking up commodity services like a
cloud provider who actually
bakes in the foundation stuff that
traditional i.t would always be doing is
a really good way to jumpstart the
thinking
and start to look at how you can take
advantage of it
no one's going to rock up and expect an
azure an aws or a vault out there not to
provide you foundation hygiene products
built into the solution as a minimum
sort of basic requirement
so that's i think the first conversation
about well this is how you can
take advantage of atscale enterprise
technologies to deliver a solution and
then you can have that next conversation
with your technologist
about right the paradigm has shifted
it's no longer about a room full of
blinking lights it's about
a capability that you plug into to
deliver the business outcome
brilliant okay i think we're definitely
going to get somewhere with those
approaches
i'm going to uphold my promise and shut
up now i'll reintroduce the wonderful
adam and we have questions coming in
from from you
so thank you we do indeed we've got some
great questions coming through already
now you can identify a particular person
on the panel you might want to set the
question to or the question goes to the
entire panel
john asks how do state government
departments
with large technical debt reliance on
state id provider and no funding thank
you covert stimulus
get on top of things state government
departments anyone got any insights
how we can help them oh yes i have
worked for a state government department
so i have been there i have been in the
trenches i spent eight years working for
a queensland state government department
um a lot of it comes down to the people
i'm really sorry
there's no quick and easy fix um
you need to fight for it um unless you
have
the drive and the stubbornness and the
snark
to push for the changes that you want to
see in your organization it will not get
done
um you need to make sure you are carving
out time for that proactive work
in order to make sure that you are
making efficiencies and improvements
in your organization because you don't
have the budget and you don't have the
tools and
you do have a lot of legacy that you
need to deal with um
an example of that is a project that i
worked on to try and get rid of
server 2003 from the department that i
work from and it took me
nearly two years by myself i was it
i was the project manager i was the
operations i was the security person i
was everything
if you want to see it done you're the
one that has to do it
i think going back to something i think
casey mentioned before the idea of a
risk based or i like to say risk
prioritized approach you're not going to
be able to do
everything all at once you need to focus
on the most important things first take
them off move forward and maybe
shift your priorities as you move
forward because the landscape's
constantly changing as well too so i
think
getting a list together working on the
most important things forward and then
moving moving on from there
the interesting thing i mean it is we
always love having a laugh at how
you know anachronistic and dinosaur-like
government are but government also is so
big that when government gets something
right or does it well you're looking in
like the covert app in new south wales
and that when that just clicked in
and just removed 25 other different
attempted systems and in just this step
changes so that it's worth encouraging
government to get things right isn't
because they're such big beasts that if
they
deal with a problem it's it's dealt with
does that make sense
yeah it i completely agree i think part
of that
there was a tweet that went out this
morning um colonial is advertising for a
cyber security manager
uh literally that went out today so so
the whole idea of
you know large organizations that have
enormous sprawl
like legacy systems tech debt almost
built into their business model and
they're having to figure out how to
secure that and how to move forward and
then you've got this layer of
you know bureaucracy to handle on top as
all large organizations do but tends to
be more pronounced
in the government sector and places like
oil and gas
you're not alone i think to your point
you know the idea of saying like
our role as an industry is to partner
with you and to actually try to help
that and and frankly you know reward the
wins when
if and when they do happen anthony do
you want that something that's going to
say following onward from that
government's good when the challenges
honor the fires at the door so covert
was a great example of how
we could actually break down those
traditional barriers and get things out
like the covert app and integrate with
um the
uh the vendors out there and get things
done quickly what i find though is that
um
if you sit back and let it coast back
into bau that's when the old thinking
comes into play and um
the tradition of we'll just double down
on our technology debt we'll just do a
windows 2003-2008 upgrade
we won't look at a cloud adoption
strategy that's too hard
we're too complex we can't do that yet i
think also that
they fail to take an opportunity to look
at the business benefits and actually
turn around say
yes it's going to cost money now but in
three years we're going to pick up a 30
our 30 productivity improvement we've
got to wear the heat now to get the
benefits in the future
jeff asks a question that touches on
something i was going to mention as well
in this the whole automation space
when i was growing up one of my best
mates dads worked for the roadside
assistance
that they have in in nrma they have it
at all the different state things
excuse me alright so your car breaks
down
he's the expert and this guy was a
superstar with cars he used to rebuild
things in his backyard he was amazing
and 95 98 of his job was
keys locked in car or i've left the
lights on the battery's gone flat
and you had these genius mechanics that
were just driving around
recharging batteries and jimmying
windows that was all they ever did
and i had a crap oh my first car was a
total box
and it would break down in the most
innovative ways
and so the nrma guys and girls loved me
because they come to my car go
oh wow so you haven't locked the key oh
wow
i think that's actually melted onto that
oh i get to do i get to do some stuff so
jeff asked is human creativity something
that's going to be harder to cultivate
in an automated environment the way i
was going to ask it is
what is it that humans do best what is
the creativity what is the one of you
use the phrase
the wicked problems anthony what's the
sweet spot that humans do
so much better than automation at the
moment and how do we make sure that
creativity
and human side remains active in the
system
look my view on this one's quite simple
the saw framework so if you look at the
automation and you get the volume crime
off the table
and the wicked problems all the analysts
are dealing with the human mind with
orchestration tools will actually allow
them to move quickly and more agilely
through
but it'll also give them the ability to
look at the lessons learned from
previous ways that orchestration was
brought to bear look at for example
who is the person who solved this
particular type of challenge out of the
sock team
and how can i go and leverage from them
and what did that person have in unique
skills
i see the linkage there is where the
ability for humans to start to take a
real leading edge
because yes ai is around the corner and
business machine learning is
sorry machine learning is there all day
every day but it's
never going to truly take it out of the
equation of actually needing a smart
analyst
who can look at the problem and the
trade craft that the individual brings
to beer
and say right what is this adversary
doing differently why am i
seeing two nation states working
together bringing two distinct sets of
trade craft into an equation
and how do i build a profile for the
future attack
because that's what we need to think
about we can deal with today's problem
but it's the next attack and the next
tradecraft evolution that we need to be
working towards
yeah this is a kind of a you know a
created
category on the thesis that we need to
scale access to human creativity in in
our domain that's
kind of why i'm on stage right now so i
clearly believe in the importance of
this question
um i think to characterize it
you know there's a there's a concept in
in machine learning called supervised
ml um where and i think it actually
characterizes what machine learning and
some of those different kind of
next generation call it approaches to
automation
actually do the supervision part is the
human
so so there's this feedback loop and
there's human creativity that's being
applied in order to train the machine
in a way that you know it can then
extract the things that are repeatable
and that's where you get your leverage
right
so you know there's already um i think
constructs that exist i feel like
they've been oversold to some degree
um you know i was literally in in the
bay area in 2015
which to me was like the peak of the
hype cycle around ai is going to solve
everything
it didn't um and that's because it was a
shiny thing that we could we could talk
about and sell
but we didn't necessarily know how to
you know apply it to the user's problem
in the same way and kind of got called
out in that process
and we didn't do that but that was the
thing that collected league ways in the
industry i feel did at that point in
time
so you know there's this idea of like
this is already how it's meant to work
these systems have been built to do this
in the first place i think jess made an
excellent point around you know trying
to remove as much of the intimidation
factor
and the replacement factor from the
operators and from the users as possible
because it's a real concern
but then on a practical level it really
is about the interface you know for the
human to understand that this is not
here
to you know replace your job or it's not
even here to replace
aspects of your thoughtfulness that you
apply to your job this is here to give
you leverage like your creativity and
your ability to problem solve ahead of
the problem
that's what you can do computers are
there to repeat what you've come up with
am i right it goes one step further in
an industry that i often hear every year
i hear this
you want to get more people into this
industry you want to get more young
people considering this as a career
well the more they can look and go
actually this is a place where your
creativity is vital and it's an industry
where more and more you're going to be
doing
the creative fun sexy iron man suit
stuff
not just churning out emails and telling
people have you turned it on
can you turn it off again and turn it
back on that's that's an enticement to
get people into this career isn't it
but not only that from my perspective as
well it the creativity is really
important
and the information that you have in
your head is really important we can't
we are not very good at being able to
teach computers everything that we have
in our heads
and your organizational knowledge your
knowledge of your infrastructures
it's ai and machine learning can help
with that
but it can't replace you it can't
replace the knowledge you have about
your users and your systems so we still
need
really talented sock operators and
analysts to be able to be that human
interface to be able to spot those
things that
the computer doesn't realize are weird
yeah so automation
and ai ml are ways to give humans better
information and make
better decisions at the end of the day
so i think simon asks a question about
exactly this simon says what risks do
you see with the push to ai
mlis saw capabilities and the push to
sell the
shiny over the real benefits of
automation
yeah look it's it's an interesting one
and i mean even if you go back before
aiml saw there was always that sort of
idea of the silver bullet we'll buy a
piece of technology and it's going to
solve all of our problems but i think
it's a case of
before we even get to those points of
using those advanced
you may say advanced technologies like
aiml we better get the basics right
otherwise the outcomes are just not
going to be what we need to have and i
think saw
itself offers a pathway to help get
those basics right
and in the sense of what i was saying at
the start where we can take the
resources that we have
the limited resources that we have and
focus on getting the basics or the
foundations right to look at things like
ai and ml
and make sure we can get the best out of
those as well so i think
it's hard it's a challenge in the sense
that everyone is naturally attracted to
the idea that we're going to be able to
quickly and easily solve a problem with
very very little effort but the reality
unfortunately is
not necessarily always the same as that
so i think in terms of
making sure we're able to get the basics
or the foundations right before we start
to move to those things is critically
important
go on one step further from that the
real risk is here that
if we don't bring an orchestration
automation process into our thinking
around managing stocks and security
intelligence centers
we run the bigger risk of losing our
good people because they're going to be
dealing with rubbish day in and day out
and smart people do not stay where
organizations where they can't actually
grow and evolve
this gives us an ability to actually
take the workforce to the next level
we're never going to fix the background
problem of trying to fill a
shortfall on cyber across the armed
sector we need to teach our
technologists to deliver better
technology we need to take advantage of
tooling orchestration
bringing all of the technologies
together average
console operators must probably sitting
in front of six or seven interfaces
jumping from one environment to another
to work out what's going on
so will bring that together and give an
ability to see the data
in a systematic approach that's where
they get to grow and evolve and we can
actually keep our people
focused by giving them things that are
challenging wicked not going to work for
you because you pay me 10
more and go across the vendor you're
going to work for me because i give you
a challenge that
forces you to evolve and i can give you
a career pathway that actually allows
you to be something that's the risk i
think we're truly running
as individual business operators casey
then a couple more quick questions yeah
for sure
um i think we've already seen this in
terms of risk this is a great question
so
you know i was around doing solution
stuff when when waff
became a thing um and prior to that when
ids ips
became a thing it was sold in a way like
here's this magical new
automation that you just plug in and it
blocks all the bad guys and great and
all of a sudden you've got you know
irish people unable to log into your
website because they've got an
apostrophe
in their name right so we've seen this
movie before
um in terms of it being undersold or
mischaracterized
in its nature so the whole idea of saw
coming in and just yep
we're going to replace everything we're
just going to know everything's going on
in your network
you can you can go over rest now the
risk is that there's either unintended
consequences or it fails to deliver
in a way that the business you know
basically takes as a cue to rip it all
out and just abandon the whole idea in
the first place i think that's a real
risk
in this space because you know no one
really knows and
the the definition of ai like get three
people in the in a room and ask them all
to define it and all say different
things
joe asks a question that was touched on
slightly with your example of the small
doctor surgery where i loved it the
receptionist is also
the i.t expert joe asks is there a base
level of maturity
that an organization needs to be able to
effectively implement
soar no
i don't think so i think you're better
off doing something than nothing
um you're not going to get it perfect to
start with you're not going to have it
perfected straight away and
saw and any of the automation pieces
they're not going to be set and forget
you are going to be constantly tuning
them and constantly monitoring them
and making tweaks so doing something and
getting started with something
is going to put you in a better position
straight away rather than just going
it's too hard i can't deal with it
i can't get it perfect straight away so
i'm not going to bother yeah look it's a
common thing that i've seen anyway in
the sense that customers i speak to uh
talking well i'm not ready i'm not
mature enough
to look at technologies like that where
i think it's it's the opposite it could
be a tool that can help you to
build maturity faster and one of the
first things when you're looking at
building out a saw capability is
understanding the process and quite
often we don't understand the process we
haven't defined what that process needs
to be
and the first step if you're looking to
automate something is building a mind
map of what that process looks like and
understanding how it works
looking for the opportunities to build
that automation and plenty of the sore
tools out there
a part of that is is if you like what
could be called a case template so watch
other steps that i should follow for a
particular type of incident that i might
need to investigate or respond
defining that and all the the saw tools
i've seen
offer that capability so defining that
as the first step and then
looking for avenues or areas that you
can automate as part of
what that process is once you understand
what that process so i think it's the
opposite it offers the opportunity to
build maturity
an anonymous question here many
organizations are investing heavily in
recruiting technical experts and socks
are we investing enough in digital
literacy cultural change
managing our data better now as i said
i'm a conference mc
so i know for a fact whenever a question
says are we investing enough in
dot dot dot the answer is no we're not
we should be investing a lot more
don't give me that actually
drill down here a little bit
what do what what can we realistically
do here to bring about
significant changes in digital literacy
or cultural change what's the
low hanging fruit there i think with
within an organization
um something that i've seen be really
successful that i think anyone can pick
up and use is the idea of security
champions
so you know identify the people within
whatever realm
of the organization they might they may
not work for the security team but
they've got
an inclination and a mental model that's
going to actually make them effective in
teaching others
so it's like how can you get leverage
from from folks that are going to be
natural champions within the
organization just starting the process
of identifying who those people could be
um that to me is is a is a pretty quick
win as a step zero
gotta jump in agree on that um my last
job we actually kicked off a little
program where we spent about twenty two
thousand dollars
got ten people through their sis and
they were out of the workforce and they
weren't allowed to have a cyber
background
they weren't allowed to come from
technology and we got the advocacy
working there
one of the other things that i've seen
really working well in the health sector
was
get in early with the new workforce
coming on and help them understand the
literal
literacy so they can become the
advocates we're seeing doctors now
emerging into the actual workforce who
are digitally literate who understand
the challenges
and can communicate that in a meaningful
way to their peers what actually changes
the paradigm
it's no longer a tech head with his
rotors spinning on the top of his head
trying to sell them something it's
actually the business saying
this is going to bite us we need to
actually look at this for the future and
it talks to how we handle their
data better fantastic i'm mindful of
time because we're switching to the
virtual event role everybody kept saying
a couple of questions i'm going to go
through get quick
short sharp answers from you gauche asks
when a company gets hit with ransomware
do you advise pay the ransom or try and
fix the data to get it back just one
word each from the four of you either
pay
or fix starting here going along the
line pay off fix
i'd have to say fix i don't know fix
tough questions first
fix unanimous on fix okay and there's a
final question here what are the key
factors for a successful saw
implementation and what's stopping
organizations
from making progress in this space so
i'll go down the line just one big
inspirational
if you're trying to sell this message
right for people who want to go and have
this discussion with organizations about
this is why we need to do it
what is the key to this being successful
what's the selling point of this
what really drives it home as we go down
the panel i think
you've got to start with measurement so
measuring
where time is spent measuring then
as you go through the process to build
out your sort of automation capability
what's working where the improvements
are coming from and identifying where
else you need to maybe spend time so i
think i'd say
how you measure what is important what
takes the most time has been
key anthony absolutely 3x to 10x
improvement on stock productivity
just get it simple that's your own
conversation point with your executive
casey uh get your definition right like
soar is a product it's something that
you can buy and put in
but you know before that it's a strategy
it's a decision it's a north star that
you're orienting your organization
around so put time into that get that
right first
jess i like what anthony had to say i
think it's about being able to retain
your staff
if you have them doing boring mindless
bland tasks all the time they are going
to leave
and you're going to lose that
organizational knowledge and sore will
help them
stay motivated and stay interested in
the work that they are doing and they
will stay with your company
what a wonderful way to finish what a
tremendous panel to get us started
please give them a big round of applause
james young from splunk
jess dodson from microsoft casey ellis
from bug crowd and anthony kitzelman
from air service australia
beautifully moderated mike thank you so
much we do have a gift to give you i
think in these cover times we sort of do
that up the back of the room without all
physical contact and all that so give
them a round of applause and say leave
the stage thank you so much guys
[Applause]
and can i say to our audience thank you
so much for the live q a questions they
were just absolutely raining and there
were some tremendous
questions there keep that going
throughout the course of the day and
don't forget this afternoon troy hunt
is doing an ask me anything session here
on the front of the stage i've spoken
with troy extensively
we've planned nothing it could be a very
very awkward 35 or so minutes unless you
really hit us but there must be
questions you want to ask of the guy
who founded have i been pwned
after 4 30 this afternoon