just in case anybody's wondering we've
just got a few technical issues with um
the next speaker so we'll be um going
live in a couple of minutes when we've
got that sorted
good afternoon everybody and uh welcome
to the first afternoon at ulcer 2021
i've been remiss in the past um so i
better introduce myself as opposed to
that guy in the pants my name is
valdemar jacobson and i work for a small
consultancy in brisbane called brook
security
so for our first highly technical
session in this stream this year we've
got um dr weihangol kevin tan and
patrick kang
from project enigma talking about
detecting indicators of compromise
through ram analysis event logs and
malware machine learning
and this is our first stream in this
session
that's completely virtual and we've got
three different speakers on three
different virtual streams so hopefully
everybody remotely and locally can
welcome the next speaker
hi good day to everybody
hi my name is kevin
and today i'll be presenting to you
project anima
an innovation that the team has been
working on
to streamlining and automating some dfir
processor
oh sorry i think i'm hearing double
sound
okay nevermind um
so okay so this presentation will
actually cover the technical aspects of
the tool
as well as a demonstration on how the
usage
is being conducted
okay so
next slide please
so just a brief
in introduction of the presenting team
the first member of the team
which is myself
i'm a second year student
in singapore institute of technology
majoring in information security
secondly we have patrick khan
who is also a second year student
in singapore institute of technology
majoring in information security
next we have assistant professor dr gol
weihan who is also teaching in the
faculty of infocomm technology
everyone next slide
okay uh so here's a brief outline of the
presentation where we will talk about
some of the challenges in dfir
brief landscaping of the ifr tools in
the industry
our integrated solution to this problem
uh pro description and demonstration to
the solution and the road ahead
uh next slide please
okay um so one of the reasons why this
project was actually created is actually
to
uh target two distinct issues faced in
the journal foreign
so firstly we have actually a lack of
integrated uh analysis solution where
there was no automated software for ram
analysis
so even if the use of tools like
volatility uh forensic analyst has to
actually manually type in commands and
actually check
files that are actually being extracted
from volatility manually
so uh secondly there's actually a lag in
data triage hardware so i like uh i like
uh software uh sorry i like hardware
duplicators uh for example duplicators
necessary then she isn't a plug-and-play
data triage hardware solution
currently in the market and
currently geofurizing analysts actually
resorts to using software
data trader solutions
next slide please
okay uh so uh in the dfir community uh
there are actually many tools to serve
their individual purpose very well uh so
we have like volatility and uh
individual tools out there to do certain
tasks for dfir
and each of these tools actually require
a lot of manual work like such as typing
in commands and knowing all the syntax
for each and every com each and every
two
so
in dfir uh some of this work is actually
quite difficult to automate as you
actually requires uh professionals to
actually look at these results and
actually interpret the data to make sure
that uh
the data is actually uh correct and what
it actually makes sense already
so uh here's actually how we come into
the picture so uh we are actually aiming
to provide uh automation for some
processors within the dfir framework so
that we can actually reduce the amount
of manual labor needed
next time please
okay so our team actually has come up
with a solution to actually provide
automation of random analysis malware
analysis and event loss correlation
so this solution will actually consist
of a combination
of a hardware and a software which we
will go in depth in the next few slides
based on the current development of the
project it's only
windows supported at the moment
and this solution can actually be
installed on the host machine or
actually can be placed in the thumb
drive and can be used as a portable
version
next slide please
okay so this is actually the general
architecture of the whole solution
we will use a scenario to describe the
full flow of the solution
so firstly the batch money will actually
be used to collect data
such as random and event logs from the
compromised computer
the forensic analysts will then collect
the data and then pass it through our
software solution
the software will
first execute
automated volatility commands to dump
off the random and extract relevant data
from it
after that
the software will actually
then use an inbuilt portable executable
analyzer
and to actually uh
analyze the pe files that are actually
found within the random
and also to uh and also we have an event
loss correlator module where we'll
further analyze
the event log file and actually
correlate certain activities within the
evtx file
so after the whole analysis is actually
completed
the program will actually generate a
report and
it can be presented to the analyst
itself
so uh next slide please
so i think some of you might ask like
what is the batch money so a batch money
is actually a linux computer built into
a usb drive
and to use it you have to arm it with
script and you automatically execute
the scripts when the flash bunny is
actually plugged into the computer
so the general use of the bash bunny is
actually for retaining purposes however
the team actually utilizes the pros of
the cache funny and tweaked it to use
for blue teaming purposes
next slide please
uh so to talk more on the hardware
configurations uh we actually configured
the batch money to perform uh two sets
of instructions
uh for the first switch uh we actually
developed the powershell script to
actually uh to extract security event
locks
from the computer utilizing robocopy at
the back end to perform data extraction
and
also hashing of the files and
to maintain the data integrity
as as it goes along uh a lot will also
be generated after the extraction is
completed and
for the purpose of audit trail
for the second switch
we use the powershell script to call
upon an open source ram acquisition tool
called dumpbit
due to internal memory of the batch
money
the batch money only has
eight gigabytes of
internal storage uh it's not able to
store ram data above four gigabytes uh
ram down so we will actually use an
external drive
uh to complement this
so uh
the user will actually have to plug in
an external hard disk and plug in the
batch panel and you will perform a ram
acquisition and the output will actually
be placed into the external drive itself
next slide please
so uh to to picture the bash money in
action i actually prepared a simple uh
use case on how
uh the batch running can
stand out from the crop yeah so
uh the current workflow is that
necessary responders will actually use
uh software acquisition tools to
actually extract
data from
each computer and there's there also
might be a risk of human errors
during this process
so by using the best bunny we can
actually just plug in the batch money
into the compromised computer and you
automatically collect the data that is
needed once it's done it will have a
green light and then you can just pull
it out from the computer and then you
can move on to the next computer and so
and so so on and so forth
next slide please
okay so now i'll be talking a bit about
the software uh component of this
project so there are actually a
few key functionalities that we will
have and we'll go into
more details as we go on to the goal in
the presentation
so uh next time please
okay so first we have the automation of
ram analysis with the aid of volatility
so how this works is actually we used uh
python to automate volatility processing
by
implementing
a set of built in volatility commands
which are commonly used for ram analysis
so these inbuilt commands are actually
sorry next slightly
uh so some of the imbue commands are
actually dll dump process dump process 3
and net scan
so
for dll dom and process dom we actually
use these two commands to actually
extract dll files and
uh portable executables which will
actually then be used in the next few
modules
that we have actually developed which is
the key static analyzer to actually look
for indicators to show that it's
actually a malicious program that is
actually running within
the computer
so
next slide please
okay so next we actually have a security
event lots correlated within the
solution
the program will actually take in a
security ebtx file and then it's being
passed through a rule set which is
that we have collateral based on event
ids so how this correlation work is that
it will detect uh event ids within the
ebtx file and look for a sequence of
event ids or or even individual event
ids and alert possible events that might
have taken place
in the computer
so uh next time please
okay so this is just a
a short
list of what uh correlation rule sets
that we have we have in in this program
but we have the more notable
correlations uh such as potential
privilege escalation uh lateral movement
and a lot on brute force
yeah
i'll go into more detail for one of the
for one of the rulesets that we have in
the next slide
uh next time please
thank you uh so over here we have an
example of
correlation by event id or detecting
privilege escalation so first we will
detect it in the event in a sequence
show order of for example six four six
four four six two four or four six four
eight
followed by four six seven two
uh like privilege uh special privilege
assigned to a new log on
four seven zero four uh user rights
assigned and lastly 468 new process is
created so when we see a sequence of
such events we might we will actually
correlate this uh event id
to be a possible privilege escalation
but of course uh the analyst will
actually have to answer uh double check
this on the event log itself
yep
uh next slide please
okay uh now i'll hand my time over to
patrick uh who will be talking about the
other parts of the software component
patrick please
hello
thank you kevin uh can you hear me can
we
yeah i can hear you
okay so now i'll be talking about our p
static analyzer module and how it works
so all dlls and processors previously
extracted by our ram analysis module
will be passed into this module for
feature extraction and analysis
next slide
so
there are two main reasons why we
decided to use only heuristics to
conduct static analysis instead of using
traditional signature based approaches
so firstly singular-based detection can
be easily bypassed as a single change in
string value or variable name will
change the whole hash of the file
and making it ineffective against
zero-day attacks
and the second main reason will be that
our tool
was developed to be tailored for
triage which is part of the incidence
response
framework
in the event where data breach
is uh has occurred time is of the
essence
and therefore we did not include
computational heavy techniques such as
like pattern matching against a
compilation of non-malicious strings as
it will require substantially longer
amount of time to execute
so the pe analysis model works by saving
through files of interest
for investigators and highlighting set
files with high number of
anomalies or suspicious properties
based on several heuristic rule sets
which we have implemented
so next slide please
so over here are several notable
heuristic rule sets we have incorporated
into our
static analysis module
so for example
having inconsistent checksum
size of code
and detecting file having multiple b
headers so when a file is flagged for
having inconsistent checksum
is an indication that a particular file
has been either tampered
or potentially injected with code
without rebuilding the checksum value of
the optional header
a file having multiple p haters is also
a sign that
it has been it has been embedded with
another executable into it
which is also indicated that the program
author had an intent to hide malicious
payloads
so moving on next
apart from heuristics our solutions also
incorporates entropy analysis
where it is being used to evaluate if a
particular file has been either packed
encrypted or obfuscated
knowing if a file is being packed or
encrypted is essential as
it is a common approach for malware
authors to consume their malicious code
by using packers such as upx
dermida and so forth
so moving on next
so how our to evaluate if a particular
file
is being encrypted and so forth are
based on all these values so based on
the entropy value of the executable our
solution will classify each of them to
be either encrypted packed or normal
if if it has an entropy value of more
than 6.926
you'll be classified as encrypted
files with entropy value lesson of 5.25
will be considered to be normal or
rather native and plain text
and for anything between the value of
6.926 and 5.259
you'll be classified as pac
so uh next slide please
so our solution will also be able to
identify the functionality of
of the malware by looking into what win
api functions are being imported and
then classifying them into these
categories as shown here
so the categories shown here are just
some of the categories they are not the
full list
so how do we know if the file has a
function of a keylogger and so forth
let's look at it it's like
looks like this
so over here are three examples of
identify what functions an executable
has based on its imports
so if we find that
if the file
the file will be indicated to have
keylogger capabilities if it contains a
series of win api functions like for
example
get key state
get async key state get focus window and
so forth
as for checking whether it has
anti-debugging capabilities you will
check for functions like
grade create 2 help 32 snapshot and
check remote debugger present
so moving on to the next functionality
of our software component
so now let's talk about how do we
predict if a file a p file is
a is my line burning with the help of
neural networks so we have gone over
heuristics entropy
and imports analysis the next thing we
can do is to predict if a key file is
maligned or benign with help of our
automated neural network module so next
so before we are b we are able to change
our model to predict the file we will
first need to collect data
so for the nine files we have manually
extracted them
from various
multiple clean installation of windows
operating system ranging from xp all the
way to the latest windows 10.
as for malign samples we downloaded them
from
various sources like
such as various total maldivia and other
malware repositories
so next slide please
after the collection process we can then
proceed with extracting features using
our pa static analyzer
and an entropy analyzer and imports
analyzer modules and saving those
features into a csv file
we then proceed with pre-processing the
data and normalizing it before feeding
it into a neural network for training
so after the training process we
evaluate each model's accuracy by using
a t20 chain test split
and currently the best model accuracy we
have is
90 if not
however
we have only trained it against 14 000
samples
so uh next slide please
so after the pre-training phase we can
then use the model with with the highest
accuracy
by integrating it into our portable
software solution to braiding malware to
predict if p files are 9 or burning
and the output of
the output will be a number of between 0
to 1 with 1 being malicious and 0 not
being malicious
for files with a score above 0.5 our two
will flag it out for the investigator to
look into
and now let's look at the neural network
architecture that was used for training
upon com next slide is
so where is the architecture of the
neural network so the input is a vector
of 73 numbers
and is normalized to the range of zero
to one
we then passed it into a shallow neural
network as the data is not super complex
with large dimensions
so we don't need a complicated neural
network with too many layers if not the
model will be over fit
so we drop out we use dropout to prevent
overfitting and we keep it simple with
using sigma activation function for each
of the hidden layers
so moving on to the last component of
our software module next slide please
our software solution has various total
api integrated into it whereby pe files
will automatically be submitted to check
if it has been previously detected or
flagged
an api will be required for this and for
our case sbr students
we requested for an api academic key
where it grants us access to
up to 600 000 requests per month
up from the usual
30 000 requests from normal api keys
so
you have the flexibility of
changing the api key to
your own api keys if you needed
so uh
next slide
please
now we will have a short demo on how our
software solution works
okay so i'll bring a voice
over for this
so this is the bash bunny so when it's
actually plugged into the computer you
will actually see a purple light so it
will show that it's actually starting up
uh then after it will change to a yellow
light a yellow light is actually to show
that the
the screen is actually running
and after it's done it will turn green
so uh this is what will happen on the
screen when the batch money is actually
plugged into
the computer
so it will actually prompt
this
cmd and you can actually see the whole
process
uh but for the purpose of demonstration
uh
i enabled the cmd to be in this way
but actually uh you in the script you
can actually edit
and change it to hide the cmd in the
background
so currently it's actually
collecting window event logs
from the computer using robocopy
and after it's done
so now this is the ram
uh acquisition portion so
as i mentioned just now there's actually
two switch
uh to the batch money so one switch will
actually be used for even locks
dumping and the other one will be used
for ram dumping
so currently now it's actually dumping
the
ram into an external drive
yeah so
now we'll watch the video
for the software demonstration
software solution
so over here the forensic investigator
can see all the functions which are
provided by our solution
so for cage generation you will pass all
the case artifacts which were being
retrieved previously by the bash bunny
and triage analysis
will conduct a full analysis of all the
artifacts
and then provide a report
and in the event where the investigator
doesn't actually want to conduct the
full analysis and use the individual
modules we actually listed them over
here
yeah the investigator can actually
analyze their own files if they want
and on their own secret windows event
locks up
so let me show so now i will be
first i will be passing all the case
artifacts which were previously
extracted by the benchmark
to generate a case so over here we will
keep our name
okay so our then browse to the ram file
which was retrieved by the batch party
which is this
and then just click execute them
and just wait
the time duration will scale depending
on how large the file is
okay well once it's done there will be a
notification popping out the top right
corner to tell you that it's finished
and now the investigator can actually
proceed with the future triage analysis
so when they click on the site tab or
form they can access those functions
from the home page or the site tab it's
the same
so when they click they can just follow
the instructions if it's their first
time using
so over here
is a brief summary of what kind of
functionality it provides what kind of
thing process processes and what kind of
analysis it conducts
so we will
carry it out
so right after generating a case we also
have to
we have to dump two extra files which
will also retrieve by the batch money
mainly the
event loss and some computer metadata
info
so we will be copying
over to our
okay as you can see here this
folder was generated after generating
the keys
so we just have to paste them here
and once we place that here we can
proceed with the full charge analysis
so
okay we browse to the folder
and select it and just click execute
analysis and just wait
this will also
the time duration was scaled based on
how complex or rather how many files
will be extracted also
so yeah let's wait let's see
here once it finishes there'll also be a
notification popping out the top right
corner
and once the results are being passed
when you scroll down to the bottom you
will be able to see this results tab
and
over here all the metadata of the whole
species will also be
installed here
so some interesting thing like what kind
of manufacturer
and model of the compost bc
and the number of processes that was
running at the point of extraction
and how many domains and ips were found
and the summarized number of all the
potential suspicious and malicious files
that have been flagged by our
our individual models
and the flex events are how many
suspicious events that were being
flagged by our windows event logs
correlator
so over here the first table shows what
processors were running
at a point of time
the users can actually search what they
want here also
so
at this the next table we will also
highlight what kind of ip addresses were
being flagged out
now as you can see
there are three suspicious ip callbacks
that were found
all these
they are pointing to united states
and okay uh the next table will
show all the executables that are being
extracted and all the executables will
be passed to our malware analysis module
whereby we
[Music]
were done
we will conduct a hash lookup using
virustotal
and
using our pe analyzer we will extract
any heuristics
okay we will provide a heuristics
indicator score to indicate how
malicious
and for our tens the class field which
is the tensorflow model will indicate
the prediction
that was done by our pre-trade neural
network
so as you can see 1.798
1.79 is actually a very high value with
one being the most
one being suspicious and zero being the
least past subspecies
so we can actually sort it
descending order
see what are the files of interest to
look at
so you can see this this first
executable is actually quite suspicious
he has been
detected he has a very slotted detection
score 42 69 and he has hit eight
heuristics indicators
and the score that was detected by our
new network was actually quite higher
and aside from all the executables we
also analyzed all the dlls
and sometimes malware can be also
injected inside
uh okay as for the last small table
which will display all the events log
all the suspicious events that are being
flagged out by our correlator
so you can see there are actually signs
of
privilege escalation
based on all the event ids and time
stamps
uh yeah and there's actually a calm
brute force that was potentially
they found instances of
brute force attempts
yeah and that's pretty much it and
the investigator can actually save the
results to
look back at a later point of time
the event where they want to view the
resource later and process another case
it will be able to save it as a json
file
they can save in as any extension
okay
once they save it
there'll be a notification
and they can actually review their past
results from their homepage after all
the site
this is the case that was
the demonstration case
yup that pretty much sums up my solvent
now
between
what this tool is we've seen uh that is
actually a combination of a hardware and
software solution if if you look at the
hardware itself uh we talked about batch
money um now batch money like what kevin
have talked about just now is a tool
that's typically used for um
reptiving for attack orchestration um
the scripts are run by the bash money
emulating hrd keyboard and so on so it's
actually a tool that's meant more for
for the attacker's side now
the road ahead for a project like this
for this project essentially is um one
one thing that we've
been thinking about or we've been
looking at is basically how can we
create a purpose-specific device to
replace batch money right because um
we know we by now we know what batch
money is we know what it can do um
it lacks certain features that are
desirable for forensics for example you
know
you you can use a batch money but you
may not know whether it's uh you know
you you can put in the scripts and
everything like that and ensure that
things are for example
um forensically sound on your end but uh
is there a way for example to make
it more
obvious to at least the people who are
you know
who may look at you using this tool
right so things like for example um
log internal logging
um
read-only uh components um you know
right on toggle and so on so could the
road ahead one of them is to actually
build purpose-specific device for this
we have actually had a few ideas on how
to do this um
so far so we're still an explorer three
stage um for example using raspberry pi
uh w and you know with the
with some custom software is built on
top of it right together maybe some
measurement architecture that will
measure everything that's being executed
on the back on the support raspberry pi
itself right um the next uh two things
or next
the other things that we can do um now
if you look at the break as it is right
now um it's still pretty
i would say
it does things but we can improve in
terms of what it can do so like for
example um currently uh we only process
uh the security event logs or i.e you
know the security.evtx um
we can look at um
for example expanding it to support more
kind of events event logs more kind of
logs and correlate
between those kind of logs to see you
know whether certain things actually
happening or not um the third thing that
we can look at is of course to use a
larger data set to train our
neural networks um currently
uh because this is a you know this is a
project that's meant to be exploratory
the
data set that we use um is
i would say sufficient for the purpose
of demonstrating the capability of the
two
but of course with more data
results will definitely be better in
this case right um so these are some
things that we see that we can
potentially do
next slide please
and
the source code for all this has
actually been released all right um the
github repository can be owned with a
documentation available online so if you
want to try it out you can actually go
and try it out right um but more
importantly we're also looking at how to
actually improve this tool how to
actually add in more features uh one of
the things that we can actually do uh
what we mentioned just now for example a
new
hardware that uh
that pairs well with the software like
this and so on so it has to allow same
the same seamless plug and play but at
the same time on more
or more
forensics kind of platform right so uh
if you have any questions you have any
um you know
you have any ideas or which
collaborators are in terms of this feel
free to drop us an email um kevin the
patrick's email
are there right um my set up we have a
go at singapore.edu the sg right so feel
free to drop us an email uh discuss
about project i mean we are open to hear
ideas see where we can what we can work
on what we can improve
and so on right so uh thank you for
listening um there's qr code there if
you want to take a look at the video
demonstration again you can scan it you
can uh you can take a look at it um
or you can just distribute it to you
know to whoever you think might be
actually interesting in a project like
this right so um yeah thank you everyone
um we
open the questions uh
we're pretty much out of time
unfortunately but there are a couple of
questions here i'll try and rip through
them extremely quickly in the last
minute um is there a capability for the
investigator to compromise the event log
correlation and change the thresholds of
the models
um okay so
this one
um there are two ways of looking at it
one is they compromise the event logs
itself if they compromise
i was
customize the event logs that's correct
all right um we're looking at expanding
the capability of the tool right like
what we mentioned just now whether we
can you know include more kind of event
logs um so that we have you know a
better picture of the whole system that
we're actually looking at
and the other really quick one for you
to answer is there any plans to allow
for a remote collection without using
the bash money
um remarkable remote collection without
using without use of batch money um
all right so the the premise of using
batch money is uh is because well a lot
of the work that
goes with collection is typically done
manually right in stock and everything
like that um so the idea is if you have
a batch money loaded with scripts and
this emulates what uh
an analyst would do
right um yeah that that pretty much
automates the whole process um if you
talk about cloud uh collecting
through the clouds
um
if i understand questions correctly
collecting all this data through the
cloud um there
we need to look at it from different
perspectives it may not be a hardware
anymore software module of sorts either
that or it could be for example a remote
uh you know some some kind of a linux
distribution or something like that
the device where we plug it in perhaps
using the same concept of smash you know
this mesh money company plug it in and
this device then establish a connection
over the internet of sorts and somebody
can control it at a remote and to
actually retrieve this data a more
simpler approach will be well plug in
this device data is collected data gets
automatically sent to the cloud which is
something that we actually thought of
as well which and this is actually a
more
quite i would say very straightforward
approach if you
really implement this
great thank you very much very
informative talk
all right thank you
okay we've only got a couple of minutes
everybody so we just need to move
quickly to the next session
um we've got three minutes if you wish
to change rooms
you