[Music]
good morning everybody and welcome to
the second day of ulcer 2021 the 20th
annual cyber security conference
my name is valdemar jacobson from brook
security and i'll be your chair this
morning
um for our first session this morning we
have a session
titled the human firewall a journey into
the unknown
with uh brian haye ex queensland police
now executive director
of cultural cyber security australia and
tracy weeks manager of cyber security at
queensland health
please welcome them
how you feeling tracy so nervous this is
my first time presenting at a conference
so
yay so i know i get to interrogate you
sorry i mean
interview you interrogation was a past
life you know some habits are hard to
break yeah right so we're just going to
have a chat just think if this is a
chat with a friendly soul sitting beside
you i know you too well brian
is that right you know i'm talking
crackers my lips are moving
but look you know from my background
it's very important that i did a bit of
research on you
and i've gotta
i came across this anomaly so
luke could you just share that video
please
well
i know what's going on
[Applause]
hey
okay what the hell was that what
happened
firstly can i just say with a background
in training
i always think every embarrassing moment
we can find some kind of unique learning
experience we've got three we can pull
from this
one social media never forgets anything
so what you put up there or what other
people put up there
can come back to want you number two if
anyone wants to socially engineer me
after today's session
just send me an email the link in it
going how to get revenge on or cert
co-host
that will probably work i'll open that
one probably right now
and actually i think i think three is
that lady that joined me in that dance
she is 70 years old
and so what i'd like to say is when i'm
doing my training awareness programs
um i like to have fun i love to have fun
and i think that you have passion for
something and you're excited about it
um and you try and have fun other people
will come and join that journey with you
um as you could see from beryl getting
up there and doing that dance with me
so thank you brian that's a great way to
start but that actually rotation
the first thing went through my mind is
you know boot scoot and line dancing
then it's sort of like another human
version of mad cow disease
i'm done line dancing tomorrow when i go
home yes and you admitted that in front
of a
thousand people in the audience they
love it
so tell me how did you get into um cyber
safety and cyber security safety and
social security so
um the really interesting thing is i've
been with queensland health for
27 years please don't do the maths i
started when i was 11. that's what i
like to tell everybody because we don't
want to reveal my age right now
but i actually come from a
administration background and then moved
into a training awareness background
so when an opportunity came up to work
with information security i was like
i'll give this a shot and i have no
technical experience so
they brought me on board because of my
training background because i wanted to
start
delivering some security awareness
training at the time to queensland
health staff
and they gave me a go mainly because
they thought i was a bit
bit out there and a bit strange and they
thought i might bring something unique
and different to the team
well in my limited experience i'd
suggest you they've made the right
choice
it's been 10 years on this journey now
so so it is a journey
and and people are a journey and it begs
a question
here i see lots of words going around
about cyber awareness
and i see lots of words around cyber
culture so how do you distinguish
or do you distinguish a difference
between awareness and culture
100 so when we're talking about
awareness especially
in the context we're doing i like to
think of that as what do our staff need
to know to get their job done so
we have policy process governance what
are the rules that they need to follow
to keep our organization safe
and to meet that need we've got our
baseline cyber security awareness
training
but culture is a whole nother thing so
what we want to do is move away from
what they need to know and actually have
them doing
um work that you know they will actually
call out other people and say
that's a bad cyber security behavior
that's a good cyber security behavior
and they're actually bringing those
practices into work yeah probably
one of the things for me and i don't
want to cast any dispersions upon
my previous career but there are you
know the difference between awareness
and culture to me is we see that in
queensland's been a lot of media
recently about
a police officer pulling over a
victorian officer and then there was a
discussion that let them go
that officer was aware of what the
protest processes were
but does the culture reflect they didn't
follow those processes and took another
step
and was there a subculture that played
to neither and to me
awareness is one thing culture is when
you it's more like an instinctive
intuitive behavioral
process that becomes a standard you know
absolutely
um and i think as well an organization
as large as the one that i work in in
the healthcare industry
there are many so different subcultures
as well so some will already be good
there'll be some that aren't so great we
need to look at the organization's
culture towards cyber security as well
so we have a lot of learnings to do on
that environment as well to try and
create a program that's going to be so
multifaceted that we can actually attack
all those different elements
so it is a challenge to try and attack
all those different elements at once or
you you focus on some core issues and
expand out absolutely
it's like adding an elephant one
spoonful of it one spoonful at a time
absolutely
and this is a journey like we've been on
for 10 years so we've started out with
our program
and doing some basic work i was there by
myself in the initial
part of that and would spend a lot of
time cutting out bookmarks
and coasters and doing things like that
so now i've down the back there i've got
kim and devlin who have joined my team
and have
helped us to to create some wonderful
stuff that you'll see throughout the
presentation
so what i've got queensland health's got
about a hundred thousand people here
a complete diverse environment rural
very rural very very remote and so many
different disciplines as well
so so how do you work within making the
priorities on what you're going to focus
on when
and where yeah that's a really great
question too so
when we're starting out obviously like
we have our baseline e-learning program
which is a great way to get
that that standard training where
everyone needs to know
and then we go out and we talk with all
the different areas within our hospital
health services
and actually try and understand their
needs and then try and build some unique
programs around that
a good example of what we're doing at
the moment is working with the research
team
in one of our large hospitals who have
some really unique challenges and we're
actually building specialized programs
around their challenges but isn't it
more complicated for you because you've
got a lot of autonomy which
with each health district so they can
choose to let you in or
choose to hold you out so we have to
sell ourselves
all the time so the internal marketing
program is just as important as the
delivery of what you're trying to
achieve so not only do we have to create
like a really cool and interesting
program that people want to take notice
of
we also have to go out and create a
really cool awareness program and plan
that we can actually then go out and
sell to different areas and say hey look
this is all the cool stuff we've got to
offer
um it's in your best just bringing us on
board so lots of presentations okay so
what's been the fundamental difference
between you embark upon this journey
10 years ago to now and i'm not talking
about the quality of the
and the diversity of the content but
more upon the
the influence and the steps you've had
to take to get an
audience inside a very large beast of an
organization
we really had to sit down and work on an
operational plan that was probably
a good key element so we had to know
where we were going
and then we had to bring other people on
that journey with us we had to go and
talk to executives and board members
and talk to them about why this was so
important to them and why it's so
important to their staff
to to go on this journey so you actually
had to convince them
this was their interest
and have you seen an accelerated change
in their adoption or acceptance what
you're saying
between now and 10 years and you might
say
yes but can you share that the first
three years
this was a key point that we moved on
yeah the first three years was really
just going out and doing really ad hoc
presentations so and some of you may be
there
at the moment so if you're trying to put
a program together you might be going
out just talking to
whoever is willing to listen to you um i
know i've done many presentations where
i've sat in a room with just one or two
people
and then i was like this isn't working
we need to try and
and get more people involved and then we
started
talking to our line managers and doing
presentations for our line managers
because when they saw value in what we
were teaching then they would actually
go
back and encourage that their staff to
come along because none of our stuff in
this respect is mandatory it's a choice
whether they come
so we have to sell this it's really
interesting you you targeted the line
managers because i see one of the
fundamental faults in many organizations
they get the executive and the portal
and then you get the focusing on the
ground zero but the line managers get
left out and if you don't embrace or
suggest all levels of the organization
you're never going to grow and achieve
as much as you want
what was really interesting for me as a
burnout cop well no i'm about outcome
now what was interesting
when i was a cop was the most
influential people as a detective
superintendent and operational commander
fraud and cybercrime i could
you would think have someone authority
to direct certain actions and
certain things to be done but i found it
was the senior constables and the
sergeants
at the lower that line manager position
that were them
absolutely far more influential than i
was absolutely because they're in
control of my people's daily work so
they make the decisions
on what people do and don't do during
the day so obviously they're taking
direction from their executive
scene management why it's so important
to get out there engage with our boards
and our leadership teams
but then again to have those um meetings
and those presentations with the exec
with the senior leadership team so they
can actually go back and say look this
is actually a value
what they're teaching is going to
protect the information in our care and
it's going to make our lives a little
easier as well
and that's a key message that we always
try and push so you find yourself
stalking sorry wrongly doing
intelligence research
on the target audience particular
hospital particular location
find out who's who in the zoo what their
nuances are preferences
doing some sort of intelligence
background work before you go in and say
hey i'm tracy and i'm amazing and i've
got this i've got a story for you
yeah absolutely um we've had some cool
so you just admitted to everyone that
you stalk people across queensland
absolutely it's my favorite thing to do
no no you know i definitely do that yes
um
we've actually had some cool
opportunities where we've actually got
to go and do
physical security audits of different
facilities as well
that's been fantastic to actually learn
about
um the actual issues that are occurring
within different um
hospital health services so we can go
through and see how far we can get into
different places what information we can
find
and then being able to take that
information back and say look this is
actually what's going on in your
facilities and this is how we can create
a talent program to suit
you know i said uh i was at uh i think
was on the the
virtual event last year and this young
man got up
and i i'll claim the fact i'm getting
old
i don't remember his name but he made a
very poignant pitch and was all about
for an organization do you want
compliance to be
your floor or your ceiling and too often
in organizations i see they've got an
online training module they must do once
a year
it ticks the compliance box in terms of
being making a meaningful difference
zero and i've gone into those
organizations and you actually have
questioned and they're
interviewed people about their ability
to recall and understand and know what
they should do
and it's virtually zero and i say to
them looks and if that's all you've got
a mandatory online
training program you've got to head up
your clacker and you need to embrace
your people
because you might take a box but it's
making zero difference and what is it
you really want
so what do you think about an online
training yeah well
look he said i've been doing this for a
long time and i'm not saying always get
it right so our very first training
module was about 40 minutes
and i can i can talk about it because i
created it and um it was
compliance-based and i crammed
everything i thought they had to know
into this 40 minute training session
about 20
very difficult questions because i
wanted them to know everything they
needed to know and come away from it
how do you think that went down not so
good we've got a lot of unhappy staff
going i don't want to do this but i have
to do this for a while
so um we go okay we need to change what
we're doing
and as you saw from the beginning of
this session i like to do things that
are fun
so we went out and did a whole lot of
research and i came across has anyone
out there seen the airbus cyber security
videos before
yeah some have they are fun and i kept
watching them
over and over and over again to the
point where if i'm
willing to sit here and just watch this
over and over again because they have
fun it's all if you haven't seen them
they are um really cool little scenarios
there's no talking
it's just actions and music and
explaining different cyber security um
issues
so i thought let's let's create some of
these of our own um so we created like
five fun little videos
um they have fun i did some research
when you're fun
uh luke do you mind sharing that fun
video please
and then just for the record this is
tracy thank you
delicious
yeah it might look like it comes from
your bank your phone company
the tax office or even australian post
these emails have a sense of urgency
about them and there's always links
that you need to click on but don't be
filmed
clicking on the links or downloading the
files can put
malware on your computer and now it can
do
lots of nasty things when you print all
the information and demand
some payment to get it but you can
easily avoid this happening by knowing
how to
recognize it okay okay so we didn't
actually distribute those but
we did they're not our mentor training
videos but we do like to try different
things all the time and some things are
going to work really really well
so a key takeaway here is that be
willing to try anything
so and it's a bit scary especially if
you're working in like
an area as large as what i do to step
outside that box and step outside that
compliance box
but this stuff works we actually did
those and we um
trialed them with our team and we got
some mixed mixed results on them
but we were still investigating actually
using that was just doing snapchat
filter
because i think that when you're doing
any kind of awareness program you really
need to look at especially
like when we're trying to reach a
hundred thousand people whose ages in
our organization range from
you know 17 to you know
we've got some people in our 70s still
working with us so
we need to try and reach all those
different audience using so many
different
so what you actually did you created
something and you experimented with it
and it
by your own admission it didn't quite
hit the mark well
yeah we haven't fully gone out with that
one yet we want to investigate what do
you guys think did you like it
brody brady's in my team over he's like
going night because he's techy and he's
like no i'm not kidding
so maybe your focus group was wrong you
should have shown it up in the weeper
team or something yeah absolutely
but i think the essence of that you got
to keep trialing and everything we're in
a constant i would suggest
a position of evolving and uh as we
evolve we accept different nuances
challenges and
we become more tolerant certain things
or we get to realize
the light bulb goes off and say hey this
is really important
and so what doesn't work today
may well work tomorrow yeah exactly
right
and you've got to be willing to move
with um
we know that everything we do every day
is changing in this field right
no day's ever the same anyone who works
in cyber security knows every day you
come into work
there is some new challenge that you
have to face um and our awareness
materials
and our programs have to move at that
same pace and that can be a challenge in
itself
so that's why it's great to have your
baseline training but to be able to
to mix it up with all these
communication messages and you've seen
some really cool stuff hopefully
flipping around the back
that um we've done internally through
our my amazing graphics person
one of the big challenges me when i uh
when i looked around was that there was
a there was
ample material out there that getting
those fundamentals should we say
and people were forced to do it and they
did it once a year we know their
attention was
switched off all and one of the issues
you're talking to people was they didn't
understand why it was necessary because
they didn't
see themselves touching the cyber
environment
it's the issue of why it's so important
come up
why is essential i think that was one of
the key things that changed
um our program moving forward so before
we were out there doing our
presentations on
you know what do you need to know here's
the policy here's the process this is
the the key risks that are in clean sun
health
and then we changed it and we actually
moved to why is it important to you
why is it important to your family what
can you do
and what can you do with these
particular very simple principles
because they are very simple principles
that we are sharing with our staff to
protect yourselves and the things that
matter to you most
because i'm a really strong believer and
if we train people up on how to protect
themselves at home
protect the families protect the things
that matter to them they're going to
bring those
those techniques and tools into
queensland yeah because organizations if
it might be important to the
organization but it's not important to
the people it makes no difference and
those fundamentals that you just
mentioned is
make it personal make it relevant and
then you've got a chance of becoming
important and then they may
pull down those in your case not so
boring online learning modules to
actually
need to know about this yeah 100 um
another thing there with that is that
that's where your culture shift comes in
so when we're talking about awareness
versus culture
that's where that shift will start to
happen with us where they will
will start doing these things
automatically and their culture about
how they re
even respond to cyber incidents will
change right now how do you you've got a
small team you've got a massive
uh disparate organization over a massive
state
different sizes priorities and
everything else how are you
addressing trying to replicate what you
do across the state okay so
this is actually what i'm really excited
about and really passionate about
um so we've launched a cyber ambassador
program
um our ambassador program this is
something gosh that
kim and i went to a sans conference
probably about how long ago was that
10 years ago probably right when i
started my career i was like i want to
do this so ambassador program is all
about getting people on board
to help share our messaging so we
actually
have launched our first ambassador
program last year so we've got
about four different hospital health
services involved in this program and we
have about 14 staff
that have come on board and there are a
range of staff we've got some people
that have a communications background
some people that are actual trainers
we have some nurse educators people work
with the
graduate students coming in so we put
them through a three-day
workshop now this was supposed to be
face to face covert then hit and
everything went pear shaped so we did it
virtually
which i was a little concerned about but
it actually went really well so
what we do they actually we trained them
up in all of our key messaging what we
wanted them to know
and talk to them all about cyber
security and then they've actually gone
out and started to
deliver our messages for us which that
is the essential thing because
i have myself i have another staff
member working with my with full-time at
the moment
we cannot reach 100 000 people
at you know that in that really timely
manner that needs to be reached
and one of the most exciting things that
i have actually come out of the
ambassador program
was we have a nurse educator and uh she
had been quite quiet through the program
and then all of a sudden she's gone back
into her work
and she's just she's run about 130
sessions for
me since we launched it that's huge and
also our clinical stuff
which again is huge so it's a cohort we
really struggle to get
traction with because they are busy
obviously because they're on the wards
looking after
patients they're doing their job so is
this an addition to their normal
duties this is an addition to their
normal genius they don't get paid for
this
they have volunteered because it's
something that they have shown an
interest in
so it's great for them to develop their
careers if they're looking at
doing more work in the awareness field
or if they just want a little change
to what they're doing um so yeah um emma
went out to her name's emma she's
fantastic
and she actually emailed me and said hey
tracy i've just had the best win
today and i was like what's that she
said went out and i did a training
session with
some nursing staff and i just got an
email back from the nurse unit manager
who said
we've just stopped a ransom we're
attacking potential ransomware attack on
our hospital
because of the that really timely
session they had
one of their vendors had been
compromised and they had actually gone
through and sent an email back to this
nursing
manager and she was about to click on
the link and open it up
when she went oh some of the things emma
told me
uh they were in this email and so she
stopped
and she got that email assessed and it
was a ransomware email
so and which could have had a massive
impact and then um she got an email from
two other staff members in that team who
had also attended that presentation that
got
the same email and yeah so that for me
is the whole core of of why i do what i
do and why the ambassador program or
something like that if you can implement
something like that in your organization
it's phenomenal we're about to run our
second one in at the end of july
and we've got people from all over not
only different hospital health services
getting involved
we also have people from our service
desk getting involved as well so it's
really exciting so i think you said you
started out with four
hospitals yes have you found that the
the word or the positive messages have
started emanate and
now others want to jump on board
absolutely and some of those key stories
like we're getting from people on the
ground who are now out there delivering
training on our behalf which is
amazing um those stories are going
through our different boards and
executive meetings
they've heard about it and now they're
jumping on board and they said we want
to be part of this program
and they're really willing to support
their staff taking time
out of their work to come and get these
messages across to their staff
i mean do you think the uh i mean
since commencement of covert we know the
attacks upon the healthcare sector have
increased 200
is there a greater deal more awareness
and that we've had some
very recent issues in health in this
state
is that actually bringing more
opportunities for you or more work
don't they go hand in hand well i'm not
i'm asking you are they mutually
exclusive or
no i think they go hand in hand so the
um
i have actually seen in the last six
months probably actually since covert
hit um the the want for people to get
cyber awareness is actually increased
tenfold
um it's also had to flip the way we
deliver our work as well
because we've been very much face to
face doing um virtual i don't know if
there's any trainers in the room today
but before covert here and before we all
started working remotely
i used to really hate delivering
training via
video conference and considering that
you know i have to teach people from
torres strait
to you know um texas down the you know
bottom of our state
and i live in mirabara so i don't even
live in brisbane with the rest of my
team that was a challenge
but i've actually found that um yeah
we've had to flip around and
how did you see mirabara then did i say
maribora
that's all right but i mean you make it
happen right i mean
you just you stand up and you make it
happen yes and then the essence of what
you're doing is you're making a
difference
yes and i said yeah people have have
really embraced cyber awareness at the
moment they recognize the importance of
it
so when you reflect back upon this
10-year journey
and obviously there's many 10 years
periods to come
what have been the greatest dare i say
pitfalls or challenges
so okay let's go with challenges first
and i want to come back to pitfalls and
mistakes or
the lessons you would share with the
audience so to help them
take some things on board challenges are
besides working with some of your fellow
stuff
no no they're fantastic um some of the
challenges i think
are obviously we all face financial
challenges
so especially working in healthcare
environment where do people want to
spend money
that's on health care that's on the on
getting services to our
on that point right you're in the
business of saving lives so
you know yes health care is and i've
heard it before that you know we can't
afford to waste money on cyber security
we've got to save lives but what's
really interesting is the
you know the iomt the internet of
medical things
that's diversity it's so inextricably
interwoven do you think the
the environment realizes now it touches
digital footprint touches everywhere
everywhere i think they're getting more
aware of that and that's through the
work that we've been doing to educate
at all levels but yeah we do have that
challenge of
of just reaching all the people that we
need to
reach in that really timely manner that
is a huge challenge for us like i said
anyone who's got to deal with
having to educate over 100 000 people um
and talk about all the different things
that are relevant to them so
obviously when we're talking with
operational services staff
we have different challenges for them as
to when we're talking to
our medical staff as to when we're
talking to our administration finance
team
so there are so many different programs
that we need to run
and that's a challenge when we have just
a very small team to do that
do you feel you're making progress at
the right pace
oh sometimes no actually i don't always
think we are but i don't think
i think any passion a person here would
admit they're never satisfied
i never think i'm doing the best job
that i can do and maybe that's why i
keep pushing to do more because i never
think that i'm meeting the challenge as
well as we could be meeting the
challenge
um and that again is because of the um
resources that we have to do that on the
subject of challenges
and i want to ask you a sensitive
question i'm not trying to embarrass you
or
any other technical people but
have you found the technical audience
have sometimes been a difficult part of
the group to get on board with the
program yeah absolutely
um but again that could be coming from
myself not being technical as well
so where i need to move in that space is
to get on board people within my team
who i can kind of encourage to get out
and talk to them as well
so we're starting to run tech talks and
things like that from
our subject matter experts within our
team um and we're actually starting to
deliver some really cool presentations
around the state around that more
technical side of things to get them on
board and get them educated
so they understand what you're working
100 and then
uh and then obviously they can then take
that information
and then and put that around and help to
get messages out to their staff as well
and if there are any other barriers or
groups besides a tyranny of distance
budget resourcing um
subcultural differences the uh it's not
a focus we're here to save lives
i think we've done pretty well so far
any other major challenges you'd want to
share at the moment because then
pitfalls is coming up
mistakes mistakes yeah we just go to
mistakes because
no mistakes um i never like to think
i've actually made a mistake
i think everything we do is a learning
opportunity to move forward so
do i look at my very first e-learning
program and go oh maybe that was not the
best one i've ever done
but it was a learning opportunity out of
that came
what um when when staff actually take
the time out of the day
to contact me and go hey just finished
our ministry training
and you know it's the best thing i've
done it's fun i i learn a lot from it
i can see the importance of what you're
doing but i had a good time doing it can
all mental training be delivered in this
way
then i'm going you know what whatever i
did wrong in the first place that was a
learning point to get me where i am now
and i think one of the key things is
don't be afraid to try something
different to step outside that box
well i'd almost argue wouldn't you
you're required to step outside the box
and you're required
to do things differently don't you have
to constantly evolve i mean how
important
is diversity and variety in this space
it's incredibly important but for anyone
who works in a government organization
especially one as old as the one i work
in
it can be hard to to challenge what
needs to be done so it does take courage
i think to go i'm going to try something
a little bit different today and i'm
going to see how far i can get with it
i've thrown some ideas out there that
really felt quite flat so
but you've got to put it out there to
see how it will float and like we said
right at the beginning it may not work
today but it may absolutely work
tomorrow
absolutely exactly because like i said
um the attitudes change
even within our organization the more
comfortable they get with the messages
that we're putting out
the more they're willing to accept from
us so yeah it
our job is going to be here for a very
long time okay so let's get back to the
variety of
uh you've got core messages there are
new messages emerging from what the
crooks are doing and the way they uh
change their methodologies and points
for taking
and the different technologies that
emerge
you started out with the core
fundamental 40-minute
stab me in the eye online training
process
well it's interesting now most of them
are shorter and sharper aren't they yeah
like a minute but you can't i know
organizations repeating the same
module five years in a row
yes so how important is to change that
learning module
and the delivery process on a regular
basis
yeah and that's really important and
that's the thing we developed this
program we invested quite a lot of money
in it
um and it's been uh out about two years
now and they're already looking
so the organization's already come back
saying can you guys this is great
what's next what are you guys going to
do next so
we're ready to move forward and come up
with something new as well one of the
issues that's come up recently is
gamification
i love gamification you love gaming yes
it's much fun how's it going over with
the with the organization
so we've uh we've brought this cool um
like physical cyber security games this
is brand new for us
into service into queensland health um
the fun thing about that was
actually when i first did it to be
perfectly honest i'm like i don't know
how this is going to go down with people
because it was
there's no no no technology involved
really there's only one station where
people actually have to try and hack
into someone's social media account
other than that it is physical hands-on
card kind of playing games and but you
know what
the staff have loved it they've had so
much fun with it
um and i actually recently just did this
session with a group of
tech people and that was really scary
i'm like they're not going to like this
because it's the basics of cyber and
it's games my gosh did they have the
best time of their life and they loved
it and then they've been saying other
people to come along
are you guilty of profiling people
yes because sometimes they scare me
because they're so smart and
absolutely i get really nervous talking
to people so but i also hold them in
such a high regard
and that i'm looking at they're the
experts in this field and if they love
this and they can embrace this and we're
doing a good job as well
yeah but even though the area is getting
so specialized
that you know it's like many of us who
are so focused on
um different aspects uh in policing for
example for me it was financial
cyber and identity crime um you know
i had been in the drug squad 15 years
earlier but
i wasn't up to speed at all with the
latest techniques of drug production
distribution
and the way they're embracing you know
different parts of that process in
australia but
i'd imagine it's the same with with
technology so yeah but you're i see you
sitting in a position where you've got a
more holistic view of the greater
structure of the organization
than someone just purely in a tech role
yeah we can see it from the end user's
point of view
i think one of the the key things is as
well
if you're coming into cyber security
team
and you are not technical you have a
really
um specific skill set that you can bring
so what you can do is that your skill
set is that you can talk to the business
which is key um so i always figure if i
can talk to the tech guys and
learn they can teach me what i need to
know and then i can translate that
out into the everyday speak of our
employees and our staff
then we're winning so if you are not a
technical person and you're working in a
tech team
then embrace that because there is a
particular reason why you're there
and there's a very special reason why
you're there
so how do you know you're making a
difference
how do i know i'm making difference the
fee
i like i love instant feedback and i get
a lot of that
um i think we can see a difference
because i can see a change in people's
behaviors
like we can see an increase in people
actually reporting
phishing emails we can see a
higher engagement in the work that we're
doing so instead of
me going out and selling my wares all
the time i have actually people coming
to me and going hey tracy i've heard
about this from xyz
can you come in and do some work for us
but i think it comes
would it all know it's also not coming
back to the point you've actually
actually had to do a
by the sound of things a damn lot of
work on
establishing communication pathways
across the state across the business
relationship buildings and
yeah basically we do have our awareness
plan which has all of our core elements
and all our core activities that we want
to deliver
so we have all our set stuff and then we
have to
get that out to all the different areas
across the state so how important is it
to stop
pause reflect to see what you've done
everything and then
celebrate that and share that with
everyone
and that's quite funny because we do
have an operational plan that gives us
three years worth of where we are now
where we want to be
um and when you get to the end of each
year it's really important to stop and
actually because you get so
caught up in the work that you're doing
and making sure you're getting your
messaging out
in that really timely consistent fashion
to sit back and go wow
this is all the stuff we've done this
year but this is all the stuff we still
have to do
so having an operational plan is an
absolute key thing and i'm not sure how
many different areas actually have one
of those in place
yeah i see a lot of people um not
putting in the sophisticated
approach to strategy planning execution
review monitor evaluate adjust
because you know this is a crazy
um diverse and constantly evolving
environment that
where change is the norm and the the
speed of change is
um quite extraordinary yes so that's a
challenge for you and
is there anything you would like to do
in the next three years to
take it even more forward and accelerate
the process what you're trying to do
i'd like a bigger channel don't say more
money more team more resources
no expanding that ambassador program is
key i think to getting our messaging out
there in a consistent manner
i also really want to start moving into
looking at educating so the kids in the
children's hospital looking at educate
and cyber awareness
and actually educating um our patients
on how to
to interact with their healthcare data
in a more secure manner so actually
extending outside of
as well our core business and looking at
that makes good sense because i think
you've got the
i'm going to call it the queensland
health 2026 digital transformation
strategy
which in the future looks to how people
can make their own appointments at home
they can get some treatments
telehealth if something's accelerated
since covid
yes and so you're looking at how you
extend your awareness program out into
the community absolutely
because it's inevitable the organization
queensland health will be
you know used as in phishing attacks
against those people absolutely and just
moving out and educating those people
and how to look after themselves
how look after those devices that maybe
attach the person
and how to interact with their own
health information to keep that safe and
secure
because we know that the value
information is in data right so
so do you feel you're making a
difference yeah actually i do
i do um i have my days where it's a bit
of a struggle but on the whole i think
i'm really proud of
the the work my team has done i think
that they have come up with and i i said
i
hope you can have a good look at the
information that's flipping around
behind us but
they've come up with some amazing
campaigns and all of our campaigns
are personal so we've moved away from
the locks we've moved away from the guys
and the hoodies
we've moved away from those really
generic cyber security messaging
and we're trying to come up with some
really creative and unique ways to
engage people
if i can make one person stop in the
lift
and look at our information and get
something out of it
that's an absolute win to me now when
you're trying to win over the regions of
the district
hospitals did you how important was it
to
review their strategic and operational
imperatives and align what you're doing
to try and convince them
we have to do that but you're working
for them yeah that's exactly we have to
do that i have to make everything we do
align with our hospital and health
services deliverables and our
organization symbols and queensland
health levels there's a whole lot of
different plans that have to go into
making
our work relevant and relatable to what
they're trying to achieve especially in
this digital space
right do you think um sometimes that's a
mistake that might get made by people
so if you if you actually said to the
audience
one or two things that they should take
away from today
as we wind up as fancy pants here is
gonna telling us it's time to go
yep so be don't be afraid to step
outside the box
if you're running an awareness program
don't be afraid to try something that is
different
that is an absolute key um and
definitely
start working with your executive
leadership teams your senior leadership
teams
and creating some really cool messaging
that might get out there and cut through
all that noise
tracy weeks queensland health thank you
very much for sharing your insights it's
been brilliant
thank you
thank you brian tracy uh
thank you we're pretty much out of time
but um there are a couple of questions
people uh would like to ask uh if tracy
can take a second oh
sorry i'm not going for you just uh just
a couple
um well there's actually a whole heap
but i'm just gonna pick a couple here
which are quite
interesting um so uh where
was i was there so many i had to have a
look oh yeah um so
the one of the earlier ones and uh um
one of the more challenging ones it
seems to be that um
the program's really kicked off and
working quite well now and you've
actually got people coming forward and
actively volunteering as ambassadors
but how have you been getting people to
volunteer as ambassadors yeah so we've
actually had to engage with
the management teams and say do you have
some people in mind that would be
you know interested in this program or
they're actually people that i've
interacted with when i've gone around
the state delivering face-to-face
training that i've met personally i'm
gone you'd be a great person
to get involved so moving forward though
we're looking at making that more of a
expression of interest and actually
putting it out there and and getting
people from all different facets of the
organization to get involved
we've actually got a director of allied
health that's involved in our ambassador
program
and they use we use that person they can
actually distribute messages through
their meetings and things like that so
that it's a really cool
touch point that we would normally not
have had access to so you've basically
been tapping people on the shoulder and
directly engaging people who you thought
were going to be a really good fit and
actually fantastic okay that's
interesting to see
um so somebody's actually uh going it's
they think it's great making the
messaging really engaging
but um do you think making light of it
downplays it's importance and people
miss some of the criticality
yeah you know what initially i thought
that could be a challenge
but the feedback that's actually coming
back from our employees when they're
actually looking at this information has
been the most positive stuff so we
actually get emails
from people like our nursing people
clinical staff
who've actually just taken the time out
of the day to go just saw your poster on
this just saw your um
little video on on phishing or usb
security whatever it might be
and i loved it so i actually think that
it's
working and i don't think it's down
playing and they've actually made a
statement
where they said i understand the
importance of what you are selling to me
but i really appreciate it being done in
an engaging way
so that's actual feedback has come
through fantastic yeah
um and the last one i'll ask of this
list is i'm given the
um the team you manage and its broad
remit how do you strike that balance of
being both friend and foe given you've
got both audit responsibilities as well
as this training and outreach
capability i do believe that selling so
we are selling a serious message
um and sometimes it can be a scary
message as well
so when i'm going out there and i'm
selling it it's more about
how why is this so important to you so
why is protecting queensland health
information important
to you um it's not about the technology
it's not about that what can you do
so i think making it personable and
let's face it i'm not an overly scary
person
um so i think they take the messages
pretty well from me
but um yeah it's all about just spinning
that message and making it
i'm turning it from that scary message
all that you know you must do x y and z2
why is it important that you do x y and
z and why is it relevant that you do x y
and z
great well thanks again um i'm sure
tracy will be here for a while and
brian's here if you want to actually uh
give him a bit of a rib
pity i didn't get to see you fishing rod
brian i've heard about this but maybe
next year
and yes thanks again very pleased
you