hi bro Martin and I'm going to be
talking to you today about some of the
problems and solutions and fun that
we've had building the data network for
the Athletics parent at the Large Hadron
Collider at CERN in Geneva and the team
is rather hoping that some of our
experiences and solutions will be of
interest to you guys in the real world
here the Atlas experiment itself is very
very large if you look across at the I
can't see whether co sees these small
white dots here these are the hard hats
of people working on the thing for
people over there it's over there ok so
it's very very big and it produces lots
and lots of data it weighs a great deal
and the picture on the top right shows
you the kind of reconstructed image that
the detector produces once the data has
all been sent out and reconstructed in
the data farms that we're looking after
the total output of this beast is about
80 terabytes per second which is quite a
lot actually and they use hardware
triggers to reduce it down to something
slightly more usable which is what we
start to see it ethernet level arrives
at 160 gigabytes per second we look
basically a partial events so that five
gigabytes per second of this goes to
about four or five hundred not 200
processors and then we give the thumbs
up or down as to whether or not they're
interesting and the next level will then
fetch the entire event to come down and
there we've send it out for about 22
thousand processors that again we give
the thumbs up or thumbs down and we cut
it down to a manageable 400 megabytes a
second which goes out the magic number
about that is it's about the limit that
you can actually record onto disk before
sending it out on the grid to the rest
of the world any more than that and
there's just not enough computers left
in the world to do the analysis because
don't forget there's not just us there's
further experiments doing the same thing
in real time around the data flow part
we put the control structure and around
that eventually when the build-out is
finished we'll put our monitoring at the
moment
run it over the control structure but
when things start to get really busy
then will migrate outwards so we're
looking after a total of about 8500
ports in this system we also have a
small problem we have demanding
customers just like you guys do the
network was dimension to meet so-called
requirements so we cunningly built it
larger than we were asked for so that we
would have a maximum average link
occupancy of less than sixty percent
which meant that at least in the plan
that we would go home and sleep
peacefully at night unfortunately this
is actually seen as a challenge by the
physicists because to them sixty percent
occupancy means they got forty percent
for free and so what they will normally
do is just turn up the wick until you
saturate something something breaks and
then they back off just slightly so
you're running permanently at maximum
demand so now we can't distinguish
anymore between what are real problems
because we're oversubscribed somewhere
or rather than to subscribe somewhere
and the self-inflicted injuries and we
need to be able to do this to protect
ourselves and also to help the community
get the best out of the system and the
only way we can accomplish that is
basically by monitoring everything so
what what is out there well we did the
the easy thing we looked around what was
doing in what was being used in the
computer center who used computer
associates spectrum they've used it for
10 20 years now they're quite happy with
it and it really is good for tracking
component failures we discovered very
quickly however that's a very good
system it takes all of the data it
stores it very very very well and then
hides it from you the trouble there is
that even at a fairly low polling
intervals of about five minutes the
report gateway is already a problem if
we have a drop for any time we have to
wait for the system to catch up just to
find out what's been going on and we
discovered to our costs that there's no
support at all if we want to poll at
less than five minute intervals and we
were thinking more like a few seconds
and if a query made a compromise and we
said okay we will do this at 30-second
intervals
and the problem there was we almost
immediately ran into a block because we
discovered that the we were getting
polling drops as you can see in the
graph at the bottom the system would
just sort of give up and go out to lunch
CA did what they could but basically
they said you know when you're running
at that speed you're on your own but but
from our point of view we couldn't
accept five minutes because it's been
used in a feedback loop nobody's going
to change a parameter and then wait five
minutes to see what the hell's going on
okay so he said no we have to have the
speed and in order to find out what the
problem was we essentially ended up
writing our own polling engine so that
we thought it was second guessing what
spectrum was doing in order to find out
what the root of the problem was and we
did in fact find it but by that time we
had a wonderful polling engine which is
fastness reliable it works there's no
drops and the good thing for us our
point of view is that it takes all of
the data and it stores it both in an
inland database and into disc for rrd
files so that all the data we want right
here and right now is in memory which
makes a visualization really easy we
solved the bug it was an interesting one
it may amuse you one of the earliest
speakers talked about some of the first
grade software in the edge switches he's
absolutely right what happened is in
this instance was that SNMP request to
the switches will were provided were
being responded to in some particular
cases by delays and these delays were
coming from switches which had chunks
enabled in the switches and the delays
whether we've been used or not Denari
matter and the delays could be anything
from one up to five seconds now
five-second delay to to an SMP responses
file spectrum concerned was a bit like
mah GERD on it went to sleep and it
would wake up as some time in the future
whenever it felt like it and they never
did find out what that was but at least
HP fix their problem given the fact that
we were over running therefore what the
spectrum support we had to reconsider
our options sorry going the wrong way
and we decided we put spectrum one side
will keep it for what its good at which
is failure alarms we looked at cacti
it's
good for visualizing single plot already
data it says here no plot aggregation
you can actually get in a plug-in which
will do multiple overlays of plots but
it can't handle on our our DS and it
can't handle esflow time series and we
can't use it with an external discovery
so we gave that up buried inside Cathy
in fact his spine which is a very stable
and fast polo and if we'd known that
then we would probably have used this
for our own poll engine and added our
own go faster good ease onto it it's a
very good product but for the to meet
the monitoring everything we also need
to know about the host CPU stats so sis
admins had decided a long time ago they
were going to use nagios they'd looked
at lemon it was fairly it wasn't really
very flexible so my guess was their
choice unfortunately it has poor plot
visualization at least the instance of
it that we have at CERN does pulling
plots out of nagios is a bit like
watching paint dry we also wanted as
fellow collectors you can buy an airflow
collector they're not cheap but the and
the problem is they don't do proper date
data archiving and we wanted archiving
so for post-mortem analysis and we
thought we'd also need something for
environmental stats because there's no
point getting excited about a bunch of
switches dying if it turned out some
clowns turned the power off and
therefore we need to know the
environment starts further for that and
so you see here already we have a large
selection of data sources for monitoring
and how do we pull it all together well
what I want is one-stop shopping because
what I don't want is multiple interfaces
to have to learn it and train people how
to use so how do the pros do it well
this is the spectrum visualization here
and at the top left you've got the auto
discovery which is which is a bit of a
pain because it changes every time
something comes in or drops out you can
in fact we wanted to be able to to
represent to our users the architectures
that they are they're familiar with the
way it laid out and you can in fact as
you can see on the bottom left force
different components to occupy space
that make some kind of visual sense to
them and this works the problem is that
if you actually do an edit of any of
these components the whole thing
collapses and you get the pictures on
the top right if you add to that the
fact that you can't overlay traffic onto
the links basically it's really not
doing what we want and we had to look
elsewhere we pretty soon came back on a
system called guess which is also open
source and this has the big advantages
you can overlay the the traffic volume
as a color code onto the links and in
the bottom left picture there you'll see
the second value added we did because
equipment will always be arriving and
departing as depending on its state of
health but we always wanted to be able
to show the entire system looking like
our architecture so all of the various
classes of devices the edge switches or
the core routers or out on the left the
control structures we offer each of
these instances an origin and a vector
for displacement so that no matter what
is alive or not alive all of the
remaining equipment finds the right
place in the firmament and we can
actually see the entire picture but on
your switches no hosts here because if
we put the hosts in as well the whole
thing just gets far too busy and this is
what it looks like as you every 30
seconds it's updates and you get a very
clear picture where all the traffic is
and you can instantly see as things are
going on if you're happy with what's
happening or not and we already exported
that out to the users so that people on
shift could have a good idea that their
world might be collapsing around their
ears but at least the network was
perfectly happy and so we came to the
architecture of the final system where
at the bottom you see our SNMP polling
engine we have a set of databases which
are central and all of our other systems
feed into these databases and on the top
we have the various visualization
packages which feed off of the databases
and so we look forward to a nice quiet
easy time while we develop this ready
for the
when the machine was going to be ready
but of course you know there's an
advanced clue there nobody has a nice
quiet time we had a very serious wake-up
call and we had a power failure in the
cooling system but we didn't have a
power failure in the computer room so
what happened is things got very hot
very quickly in our in the
infrastructure room that we have
temperatures were rising about one
degree % 1 degree centigrade per minute
and so the idea is when you have a
problem like that is you have a tested
fail-safe plan and clearly we didn't we
dropped the ball on that when everybody
thought somebody else had done it and in
fact the monitoring worked perfectly
it's getting hot it's getting real hot
it's awfully hot in here guys and nobody
noticed for about an hour the
post-mortem was interesting and there's
a word of warning to you guys as well
the very first thing to fail was the
fiber links they go at about 40 to 45
degrees ambient and therefore if you've
got yourself mission-critical links you
better have a copper back up someplace
nobody actually expected that we would
actually hit this kind of this kind of
problem because Intel's got all this
nice thermal management problem and if
things get hot then it skipped cycles
and eventually will stop working
altogether and that's true if the
motherboard that they're living on
allows it to and our vendor had
suppressed all that so these would run
at a hundred percent until he went down
in flames we also got fan controls which
is supposed to speed up and increase the
the cooling as things get one and they
would have if sysadmin hadn't discovered
earlier that if you run the fans at full
speed the vibration on the motherboard
causes the head bounce on the disk which
means that latency goes up and you can't
use it as a file server so they cut the
speed rate really down so that the
latency would be fine routers they've
got a nice cut they've got a nice system
for load shedding when things get hot it
never worked because the power supplies
and the fans went long before that
kicked in beware of ups if you have ups
in your room then you also
need an uninterruptible cooling supply
we didn't have one and the last word
just about sa messes we had a
complicated system of smss put not your
trust in this one guy was asleep the
other guy his inbox was full my machine
was charging in the kitchen and in any
case it didn't matter because the
messages were too long for the buffer
and you couldn't read the magic numbers
that you needed to know we judge we
dodged a bullet on that one because
things did come back to life p I need a
drink here and what you see here is the
opening panel of our network browser
which gives us an overall system summary
this is the first time I'm seeing what I
really want excuse me because here we
have the architecture laid out and I can
see at a glance all the various profiles
are all looking roughly the same except
the one at the bottom which is burst
transmission out to the system
everything is fine and for the first
time I have an overall picture of what
is going on but I go back inside but
again this is just the core I don't see
house what do we want when we looking at
a house well every tool will produce a
single plot it's usually auto scaled and
we're interested in that of course but
we also want to see the load as a
percentage of capacity because as I said
we're running a capacity quite often and
we're also interested in the discards to
see how hard TCP is working and we'd
love to see any of them overlaid
together so we can collect set of peers
and see if they are all pulling the
weight correctly and so we do this we've
integrated this into into our work panel
and I like to spend a few minutes just
looking through this system here with
you I'm going to work on the slide over
here so you have to those are on the
left are going to have to have a problem
here here we have our aggregated overlay
which shows all of the instance of the
particular peer group that we chose from
the menu here and in the mini in the sub
menus here we see many plots which will
display any of the parameters that we
want typically we would put load here
errors there and the auto scaled version
so we see something if anything
is going on the display itself is based
on it on the time slot that we see here
we've chosen the most you the the most
useful peer groups here but if we wanted
to cut things down and filter it even
more than we can put in a regular
expression in here and this is the route
look and feel of our system and in this
particular case we're pulling up the the
traffic polling system but the magic
window is this one up here which tells
us which database will be looking at so
we can now change that and say okay
we're not going to pull up the the s
flow statistics and so we have this
exactly the same look and look and feel
and the s flow of course he's going to
tell us not just a question of how much
traffic there is but who's doing what to
who and why which will help us with
debugging and by again changing this
time we're looking at the statistics for
the CPU system and in the mini plots
here we can pull out any of the usual
cpu one temperature system temperatures
the cpu load the memory usage anything
we want to know about the host cpus and
we can do that for any of the class of
the processes that we see there and it's
the same look and feel and then the we
can also then pull in the environmental
stats just by and again it's the same
here we're looking at the see this it's
the the average temperatures were in the
racks that are being looked at and you
can also see the the water temperatures
and the power or the fan status
temperatures as well we also have
dynamic pages with real-time traffic
everyone does those I'm not going to
discuss it for too much now the guest
display that I told you about earlier is
good for seeing switch to switch traffic
and as I explained do we can't
incorporate the host details the browser
which I've just walked through will give
you all the hoes details but you have to
dig for them you have to know what
you're looking for and you have to be
pretty much of an expert to understand
what it is that you're seeing even then
but i want to see all of the detail when
something goes wrong because what we're
dealing here with is is a process there
is a bit like a factory automation
system if we
garbage out at the bottom I don't want
to spend my time on that because the
odds are that it's come from garbage in
at the top so I want to focus on where
the real problem is and for that I need
to correlate things that are going on
across the entire system and when it is
going wrong I want to see the neighbors
to see if it's an isolated case or if
there's a whole class of devices that
are in a problem and when I look at this
I want to see a different view in a
different different level of detail
depending on my viewpoint how the level
of abstraction that I'm comfortable with
and I want to be able to fly through it
because there's a lot of stuff out there
and I want navigation visible eres it's
all about musics what I want right
because what I really want is Google
Earth in my network right we actually
tried it I built a network the size of
Greenland but it wasn't very practical
because the coordinate system is based
on geography and it's not based on logic
so and in those days I li you couldn't
do dynamic update requirements so we
went looking for some display software
that would do this and the vehicle of
choice is X 3d which is an enhanced vrml
it comes with a freebie viewer and it's
free for a reason it's not very good at
all and we went looking for something
that would handle up to a million
simultaneous instances and we found it
in October player and this is the view
that now we have constructed so the
green circle in the background is our
control plane and brought in the to the
foreground is the the furniture which
are the main architectural structures
it's the farms of processes in the
square boxes and it's the the core
switches in the round boxes and draped
on to the furniture our graphs of what
is going on at the various levels and
the at this top level were your see in
these aggregates of all of the traffic
that's going from one of these building
blocks to another if i was to zoom in at
the for example the center core here
you're starting to see windows here
which are essentially the receive and
transmit traffic in this one is
receiving nothing the transmission is
receiving a lot and underneath there is
bars of weathering
we're in the state of happiness or
there's something wrong and we ought to
worry about it and if i zoom in even
closer then you have this nice little
icon here which is a graphing icon and
this will pull up any of the statistics
about the structure that I want to look
at so i can pull out of the system any
of the particular ports any i can pull
out all of the stats that you've seen
before whether its environmental traffic
or whatever it's all there and i can
look at it in detail if we fly into one
of the inclined to one of the big big
computer rooms the this top-level
picture here is the distance view and we
have an amphitheater of racks of
equipment and i can see instantly the
moment I walk in or fly into this room
that there's one or two or three racks
which are showing some high level of
activity this isn't a simulation by the
way this was done during Saturday
night's run and it was emailed to me
over the while I was here and I can see
that there's some areas here which are a
little bit congested so I can fly in and
this then gives me the second picture
here and now you're seeing the the
detail on all the individual processes
as I'm beginning to see the windows
there and at the bottom I've flown right
in and I can look at one specific
processor and say well are you having a
nice day or not yeah so in conclusion I
would like to show you the video of how
this works if only I could get the thing
to work for us have a look
I may need to resize this no I may need
to kill it
while I'm plane you can think about
questions
okay so this is a screen capture that
was done over the weekends run as well
just a couple of seconds there to see
the view so you just flown in to look at
the core everything is fine there you're
noticing up at the top here there's some
slight congestion there it is yellow
it's not red here we have some
congestion in the xpu farms the rest of
the system seems fine so let's go and
have a look up in here so we fly into
this area there and immediately you can
see that this is the guy that's got the
problem so you fly into him and it's one
of the sub detectors which is putting
out a little bit more data than we would
think of so we pull up the the plots and
we look okay it's nothing terrible it's
that we can ask the guys why they're
putting out more than they normally did
but you know it's it's not fatal data
taking will go on perfectly happy like
this let's go and see what the
repercussions of that are so we fly out
of this room here we have these icons
there we discovered when navigating in
3d it's very easy to get yourself lost
so this so we needed a quick way home to
something that we recognized and this is
flying into the the XP you from the
third level processing farm here's the
here's the area that we're flying into
and then you see how the detail is
increasing as we're getting in towards
it and then we see that essentially
everything is fine because this is the
receive of the top of rack switch and
it's completely and utterly saturated
which means we can't do any better than
we're doing at the moment which is fine
so everybody's happy TCP is working its
guts out keeping up with it but we
cannot do any more than we're doing and
so it's not really a problem at all
thank you very much
thanks Brian we have time for questions
please do announce yourselves so we know
who you are so Tim Brown cisco systems
just to really quick questions for you
first question is on the system side it
seems like you're doing a lot of polling
as opposed to messaging was there a
reason for that decision or are you in
fact doing more messaging based back to
your it's holding its own Leslie going
for that what was your rationale behind
going that approach versus trying to
message the day because it seems like in
more large-scale implementations that
that I tend to see or look at I see a
lot of people kind of shifting to a
messaging based approach where the host
themselves are the elements themselves
kind of message yeah in one of the other
experiments they did this because they
have tighter control over the
applications they've instrumented the
transport layer software and they've
gone that route we are slightly more of
a individualistic shall i say experiment
we are dealing with physicists here not
company men sure huh so there there was
no possibility whatsoever to instrument
the the application level they were
desperately trying to get the thing to
work just to be ready on time let alone
do subtle things like this and so we
were put into a defensive situation and
therefore we polled everything okay and
in fact it's very very useful because
you doing this system we spot anomalous
things that the application guys aren't
aware of for example we see linear
growth intra in in traffic the
application guys completely unaware of
it because he has a bug in his system
he's reporting back statistics to
somebody and instead of instead of
overwriting his record file he's a
pending to it which is fine you know for
him everything is fine the network will
eventually fall over however right the
second question I was looking at your
list of tools that you investigated
earlier in the in the deck and one tool
I didn't see on there and it doesn't
didn't surprise me but I was kind of
surprised that it hasn't received more
attention from the operational community
is a tool called graphite which I
believe portions of it were talked about
at google recently I'm not not sure what
they're using it for if they're using it
but did you look at graphite at all or
no we didn't okay
they seem to solve a lot of problems in
kind of the traditional rd based
approach see the bottom line was we were
up against rock and a hard place this
business with spectrum took a year to
get to the bottom of it right just
trying to we tried every known
combination and eventually we just run
out of time and said look we really have
we have to deliver something yeah and I
hadn't even gotten any press except for
like the past month or so so okay well
this this was all being put together
started about two years ago and the the
data came online about a year ago for
the first time reasonably heavily so we
didn't have a lot of luxury to go tour
the market great thanks very much
occasion morning Wes heard occur Sparta
I'm a big fan of visualization I'm a big
fan of graphs the one thing that I've
had a hard time with over the years is
that I keep falling in and out of
actually using it and I think that comes
from mostly from an operational kind of
sense for you you can spend all of your
time playing around in and zooming in
and out of things and then you had spend
all of your time doing that and you get
nothing else done and then I fall back
into you know working in the real world
and and looking at all the nitty-gritty
all the time and I forget about my
visualization tools and so some of my
question I think is a how long has this
been in production and how much have you
used it and can you give me a real world
feedback for is you know how much of
your day time in fact you've been
looking at this versus you know looking
at other data it's a really cool system
I'm very impressed okay well there's a
number of aspects to this and I
sympathize and agree with it with a
number of your points the workhorse is
the the multi-window browser and that
there's one main user of that needs me
and it sucks up about two hours of my
life every every morning okay and it's
not meant for the for the long haul in
the sense that I intend to do this for
the rest of my life the the database
structure that we have is a platform
onto which we will put an expert system
which will then dig
into there and pull the interesting
stuff out and warn us but to have an
expert system you first need an expert
so I need the visualization tool so it
can be comfortable with knowing what the
system really looks like as it is
operating what they call normally which
is in fact it goes through an order
magnitude every few minutes as things
evolve as for the 3d it's purely in the
prototype stage at the moment and that
is looking forward to the moment when
the developer tool the developing team
has all gone on to better things and
we're left with non-experts looking at
the system now the guys coming up who
will be doing this in the future they've
all grown up with their iPods and their
3d games and they're not going to sit
down in front of a menu-driven menu
drop-down system that requires them to
be expert in everything if it's not made
simple and easy and intuitive they're
not going to touch it and they won't be
able to use it so this is looking
forward rather preparing for that day
yeah I agree you have to train for the
18 year olds the problem is is that
after you've shown them is visualization
you have to teach and what to do next
and the other thing that I run into all
the time as I often look at the same
graphs and said yep that's still read it
was read yesterday we need to add more
fiber and it'll be read for a long time
from now but very cool system thank you
thank you we have time for one more
question hi babak past are about blue I
broke the mic okay I wanted to
understand how you went about setting up
baselines for all the metrics that
you're monitoring application tied to
network usage tied to cpu you know all
of those types of things how did you go
about getting all the different
resources within the organizations that
are using those applications and systems
to give you the kind of data that would
identify to bass lines ah because it's
all in one experimental team all of the
data that goes all of the monitoring
data is is all goes to one control room
and nobody's hiding it from anybody else
the main issue is digging
through it fast enough to understand
what is or is not going correctly so we
don't have any there's no firewalls
between the datas each of these each of
these tools goes to the only the expert
group in of question so the
environmental guys they use their p vs s
and they have their own look and feel
and an interface to it we just plug into
their database and bring it into our
visualization system so we can correlate
with all of the other data that's
flowing at the same time and this makes
it a good selling point because of the
the one-stop shopping if you like so we
don't have a problem there's no
boundaries between the data is as far as
the the rest of the suppliers are
concerned which is not the case for you
guys clearly thanks Ryan