anymore so anyway Celine thanks thanks
very much very pleased to have the
opportunity to speak here to be talking
about something a friend and I have been
working on since about 2004 called
Ireland P and I'm going to kind of give
you a what why how and when of Island P
what it is and why it might be of
interest to people so what is it
Island P stands for the identifier
locator Network protocol much more
information including papers and things
can be found at the URL there and if you
were to try and summarize Island P in
one sentence it's really an enhancement
to the Internet Protocol that tries to
achieve a kind of harmonized
functionality through the use of naming
so rather than add retrofit extra
engineering extensions to to IP we're
kind of trying to go back to look at the
architecture and say how can we change
the way the naming is used my colleague
has been working on this ran Atkinson
has over the last couple years been
discussing this within the IRT F and in
March early this years the IRT F chairs
recommended that an ITF work group is
formed to see if this can be made
workable I'll explain what this is in a
little while it's still pretty much a
work in progress we have one overlay
implementation and hopefully in the next
18 months or so I hope to have a kernel
based at least one kernel based
implementation of this although it's
anarchist a new architectural approach
I'm trying to describe to you of course
we need to build it so we decided to
retrofit the architectural ideas onto
ipv6 and that's why I'll be talking
later about Ireland pv6 not because we
had five versions that were rubbish and
we have to throw them away just because
it's a retrofit on to ipv6 and in fact
some of these that we know these ideas
are pretty good because they're not ours
lots of people have had ideas along
these lines and I'll go through some of
the rationale for Ireland P and some of
the background work
as well in fact I'm gonna do that now so
the intention with island p4 Ferran and
I was really to look at the kind of new
functionality people wanted from IP
networks and think about how they could
be provided in a harmonized way so if we
look at the list of things on that slide
multihoming mobility multipath transport
localized addressing traffic engineering
options packet level security at the IP
layer all those things are available
today there are solutions for them but
they all require some sort of extension
to be added to IP and so when you try to
put them together
the engineering landscape gets a little
complex and we were trying to see from a
research point of view if it was
possible to have something that was
simpler than the current engineering
landscape by going back to the
architecture but still give us all this
functionality so that was our starting
point
however we you know one way we could
have done this was to take a a pretty
clean slate approach and just say okay
we'll just write it from scratch
a totally new network stack but we
thought another challenge that would be
interesting for us was to see if we
could make it backwards compatible and
incrementally deployable and after some
thought and and bear we we decided that
really what we wanted to do was try and
keep the core network from having to
change too much but except that the end
hosts may have to change the the stack
on the end host may have to change in
order to allow the changes we want and
to enable functionality we want in the
way we want so really this set of issues
here that the core network devices
shouldn't change reuse as much of the
existing core core as much as possible
are our two main issues that we wanted
to retain and then we realize that
although we want to try and limit impact
on on existing applications some of them
might work some of them may break and
certainly we will require the the
code on the end hosts change so as I
said we're really looking at naming and
what is a name in the context of this
talk well it's any set of bits that you
can attach to an object in the network
and really the semantics of that name
are defined with respect to the objects
and so here are some examples of what I
would call names in this context of a
protocol name at the application layer a
port number a fully qualified domain
name and in our context and address is
the IP layer is also a name it's a set
of bits which can be used some way to
label an object at the the network layer
so one of the things that we looked at
and as I said other people have looked
at this before is that the use of names
in the Internet the use of the Internet
protocols the use of names is not very
clean there's an overloading of the
semantics of for example especially the
IP address and that's what I'm going to
be focusing on so here's an example of a
URL and in fact the two URLs we have at
the top one with the fully qualified
domain name and the IP address are
equivalent and so here the IP address is
overloaded and it might be used in an
application like this is a session
identifier we move down to the transport
layer and we look at the transport layer
States if you look at how the endpoint
is defined of course you have both the
local and remote IP addresses all the
bits in the local and remote IP address
form part of the transport protocol
States and and so here the IP address is
being used as an identifier for an end
point of a transport layer connection if
we move down to the network layer of
course the IP address is used at the
network layer some of the bits are used
in the core of the network the network
prefix bits of it might be used for
subnetting and so in this case it's been
it has some topological significance and
so it's being used as a locator in order
to make the routing work in the core of
the network so again we have a different
semantics for the same set of bits
locator at the network layer identifier
at the transport layer and perhaps even
used as a session identifier at the
application layer and then if you go
down and look at the physical interfaces
so this is just a screenshot from my
laptop
I'm not sure if you can see it very well
but here we have an interface this
happens to be a wireless interface and
the IP address is actually assigned to
that physical interface so in fact the
IP address bits are bound to an
individual physical interface not just
that the machine but an interface of
that machine
so this overloading of the IP address
the semantics of it has been known
actually for some time people have said
that this is probably a bad thing and we
probably want to try and get away from
it this is some text lifted straight out
of RFC 49 84 which is a report on a
workshop that was in 2006 and it
basically says that this locator
identifier overload of the IP address it
is probably a bad thing and we want to
move away from that but in fact that
wasn't the first time it was mentioned
if you go back about 10 whoops not back
a slight but forward a slight but back
10 years you find RFC 2101 from 1997 and
that says a similar thing it says that
this overloading of the semantics of the
IP address is probably going to be a bad
thing and we need to get away from it
and in fact that that wasn't the first
time it was said if you go back again
not in this light but if you go back
another 20 years 1997 you have Internet
experimental note 1 and I think you can
google for this and find a PDF somewhere
on the on the network and it doesn't use
the same terminology we might use today
so it doesn't talk about mobility as
such and it doesn't talk about
multihoming as such but it's clear what
the intentions are and it discusses
physical versus logical addressing and
it says that if you conflate these
semantics you don't have trouble when
things are when you have n systems that
want to have a change in topology ie
mobility or if they want to be multiply
connected I they want to be multihomed
so this is a problem that's been known
about for a for a long time and the
problems identified in these documents
and others
we see are apparent today there are
problems with the overloading of the
namespace as a summary this is what we
have if we look at the layers that have
just covered in in these separate slides
we see that you know a lot of people
have gone to the trouble of building
this layered architecture and separating
out the functionality but then of course
you use the same set of bits to label
objects in the stack at different points
in the stack and you re entangle the
layers so what this means in terms of
functionality is for example if you were
to use an IP address to identify an
application-level session it means it's
actually tied to the physical interface
on that machine because that's where the
IP address is bound to so if you want
that application to be mobile you want
it to be multiply connected you're going
to have some problems
of course these problems aren't
impossible to get around we have
solutions today for mobility we have
solutions today for for multihoming but
what happens is they each require some
sort of extension set of entities to be
deployed for example mobility requires a
proxy system in a and a set of tunnels
for it to work and so we end up with a
more complex engineering landscape even
though we can implement the
functionality especially if you want to
try and make some of this stuff work
together
the engineering gets even more complex
so the intention with I'll NP was to say
we want all this functionality but we
want the engineering to be simpler and
we want to do that by having an
architecture that's a little bit cleaner
with respect to naming so that was the
rationale behind Ireland P so how we
gone about trying to address this
problem well this is the same table that
I showed a couple of slides ago and on
the right we now have a summary of what
Ireland P tries to do it tries to
separate the layers so disentangle them
by introducing a couple of new
namespaces so first of all of the
application layer we try to encourage
people to use fully qualified domain
names only and in fact this is Keith in
keeping with RFC 1958 which says that
application should normally just use fqd
ends and shouldn't
addresses and then at the transport
layer we have a new namespace which
we're calling an identifier namespace
and at the IP address at the IP layer
instead of having an address we have
something called a locator now the
identifier has no topological
significance at all it's only therefore
identifying the end system and the
locator is topologically significant ok
that's that's the key difference that we
have so as I said the way we chose to
engineer it rather than go cleanslate
was to try and retrofit this onto ipv6
so Island pv6 is what we're working on
now and this can be seen as a set of
extensions to ipv6 and what we've tried
to do is use the same packet format as
ipv6 so the core rooters core network
elements should not here but it does
mean that we do have an incremental
deployment story for Island pv6 and
there is some level of backwards
compatibility with ipv6 and how we've
decided to massage Island P into ipv6 is
to take the 128 bit address space of
ipv6 and only at the end host represent
it in to 64-bit plants so the upper 64
bits we call the locator and that's a
name for a network and the lower 64 bits
we're going to call an identifier and
that names a node not not an interface
but node it is also possible to retrofit
Island P onto ipv4 and we have a kind of
outline design for that but things start
to get a little messy on engineering I'm
not going to have time to cover that in
the talk but I'm very happy to take
questions afterwards and breaks etc so
this is the modification we're making to
the ipv6 address at the top of this
slide is what is the format of the
address as it exists today straight from
RFC 35 87 and what we do in Ireland pv6
is we take that same address structure
and we now change it so here where we
have the ipv6 prefix we now call that
the locator but in il NP that has the
same syntax and semantics as for ipv6 so
the same syntax and semantics and
because that should be the only part
that the core routers look at core
routers should be happy that we haven't
changed the syntax or the meaning of
those bits then for the lower 64 bits we
retain the same syntax that's used for
IP version 6 but we change the meaning
the semantics of those lower 64 bits and
we now say that the low 64 bits is an
identifier for an for a node not for an
interface on that node but for the node
itself
alright so that's the key difference
we've made and what this does is it
separates out the way that end systems
identify endpoints for connections and
for application level sessions and the
bits that are used in the core of the
network for actually deciding which way
a packets going to go so this just for
reference is an ipv6 packet header this
is what the core of the network sees but
this is what scene at the end system so
obviously the end systems have to be
identified - I have to be modified to
add to understand about the identifiers
and know that the address space is split
up into two separate parts a little bit
more about locators and identifies the
locator is topologically Savini
significant and it takes the same syntax
and semantics as today's network prefix
for IP version 6
but the identifier has nothing to do
with routing at all it is only used on
the end systems and this is not
topologically significant and the key
difference between v6 ipv6 and Island
pv6 is that n systems do not bind to the
428 bits they
only bound by into this 64-bits of the
identifier now because that's got
nothing to do with the way the package
ship through the network you can have
dynamic bindings you can have multiple
identify as binding to multiple locators
you can have one identifier binding to
multiple locators at the same time so
you get multihoming you can have the
locator value change on the fly by
e-mobility but the the identifier that's
bound to an end point connection doesn't
change so you maintain the integrity of
the end-to-end connection okay so you're
we're trying to separate out the layers
so a change at one layer doesn't impact
the layers higher up in fact this slide
pretty much says what I've just said
about that the two values during a
particular session and locator value can
change and you can have multiple
locators for a given transport layer
session the identifier has to remain
fixed now in fact a node can use
multiple multiple identifiers
simultaneously but for a given transport
layer session or to ever identify it
uses to start that transport connection
that must remain fixed throughout the
lifetime of that connection so this is
how we're going to implement our various
functions unfortunately I don't have
time to go through how all the functions
are implemented but I'm very happy to
answer questions on those there is a no
free lunch clause on il NP and the no
free lunch clause on Ireland P is we
make more use of DNS because now we're
moving to a system whereby names are
more important somehow when you have a
fully qualified domain name and you want
to contact a host that uses Island pv6
you have to know its current set of
locator values and identifier values and
so that means putting them in the DNS
that when you do a name lookup you get
back a set of identifies and locators
that are currently valid for that for
that node
development of Ireland P where are we up
to well there were a bunch of options
that we had simulation was an option but
we realized that the amount of code we'd
have to write we may as well just try
and build it we have an emulation that's
been done as an overlay and we had a
master student do that in 2009 and that
demonstrated mobility and multihoming
working together quite nicely with a few
constraints it's constrained to a single
lab it wouldn't work in the white area
we also looked at possibly running it
over infrastructures like Planet lab in
one lab but because we need to make
changes to the way that the addressing
works we thought it was going to be too
hard so really what we're working on is
an implementation in an OA stack we're
working on both a Linux port and a
FreeBSD port and hopefully we get those
done sometime next year we start giving
them away for free
as I said Island PE v6 is much more
reliant on DNS in fact you could be
argued it's no more reliant on DNS than
applications and systems are today it's
just in my LNP we make it quite explicit
there's also an interesting feature for
Island P which is in order to support
mobility and work with the DNS you need
to turn down in fact turn off the
caching for some of the locator records
so you've got to have zero TTL for some
DNS records now this sounds a little bit
scary in some cases but in fact I have
some numbers on this we actually ran
zero TTL on an operational DNS
installation at my Institute and we did
it in fact three times over three years
and each time you know we still we lived
nothing really bad happened I have some
numbers on that if people are interested
interested with IP B Island pv6 re
numbering and address management sites
is still an issue it's no better but no
worse than it would be for ipv6 and then
some other things happen which may not
be not make
some applications happy for example
because we no longer have a global
irritable name and IP address tied to an
interface some applications like SNMP
might break and some legacy applications
that ship addresses in application space
like FTP they'll probably need some sort
of gateway mechanism and the other thing
we haven't thought about very very much
into working scenarios what happens when
you want to inter work island pv6 with
ipv6 or ipv4 now I've been asked just to
make a comparison of il NP with list
because list of course also has the
words of locator and identifier
somewhere in the acronym but in fact the
two two things are very different beasts
Lisp is really coming at a very specific
problem whether it was initially as far
as I understand to solve the problem of
growth in the core routing tables for
the internet and try and remove some of
the state that's kept in the core and
island P v6 is really something that ran
and I are tinkering with because we were
we had some research questions we wanted
to investigate nevertheless it is
possible to make a comparison of them
and in fact it shows that they're quite
different in Lisp what changes is the
network so new network entities that are
required for mapping of n system
identifies and routing locators
whereas in island P v6 only their end
host changes sy tree numbering is not
required at all for list but is optional
for island P v6 and of course Island p
v6 requires end host to change which of
course may not be acceptable to some
some customers there are a whole bunch
of other issues where the two differ I
don't think I'm gonna have time to cover
all of them because I've got to leave
some time for questions one main
difference is that there is working code
for list it's out there today and you
can use it and
Filan pv6 it's still pretty much a work
in progress but we hope to have
something available in just over a
year's time also lisp works with v6 and
v4 and although here I say Island P will
work with v4 I suspect the answer really
is no it requires an ipv4 extension
header which for most people means it's
not going to get through the core
network so it's technically possible but
probably not deployable there are a
bunch of other things that of course we
were designing Island P v6 for so we
think it does do them and in fact Lisp
is now starting to address some of those
functionality issues as well right so
that's all I wanted to say about Island
P tried to introduce you to this idea of
changing the way that naming is used and
I hope I've left about five minutes for
questions thank you very much yes this
isn't really a question just a
congratulations I believe this is the
first talk we've had at Nanog on
extensions and work on improving ipv6
rather than just getting it implemented
and up and running and I'm delighted to
hear that we're now looking somebody is
starting to look beyond just doing ipv6
not that I'm suggesting any of those who
are not running ipv6 stopped working on
that
Michael Sinatra over on the side here
Michael Sanchez UC Berkeley I'm
interested in what your thoughts are on
what the best practices will be for
numbering your how you will handle your
authoritative DNS server in an island P
world because you're going to have to
somehow you have to get to that
authoritative DNS server and will you
have L 64 records in as glue records in
your parent and if so how will you
update them when the prefixes change
because you're changing providers or
because you are one of your links goes
down right so I think the question was
that what are the dynamics of changing
locator values have I paraphrase that
correctly
yes but specifically how you handle that
with the authoritative DNS servers which
are the ones presumably which have the
information about the changing locator
values right it's really chicken and egg
thing there right so again yes this talk
was very quick but you we have to assume
that you have DNS ik running and that
when you do make updates updates you
know your authoritative DNS server you
can check its authenticity and then make
the change like my question was sort of
focused on the other side where's I have
a service running like a web server
right that is on an island P enabled
network one of my prefixes goes down
right how do other people know now when
they get when I do a DNS lookup they're
gonna have to say okay I'm ma I've
dropped a prefix here but they're gonna
have to get to that DNS server that's
gonna tell them that information
right okay so let's assume you already
know what your prefixes are there's a
different story if you don't know your
prefixes but let's say you assume you
know what your prefixes are both of
those can remain in DNS together and
there are some preference bits to
indicate which one should be tried first
and if that one doesn't work you then
try the next one at the application
level thanks so Danny McPherson I had
two comments one was actually somewhat
related that question which is basically
just protocol architecture stuff and the
should have circular dependencies and
routing relying on DNS to work in DNS
rely on routing work and you know that
becomes problematic in large distributed
systems I think that was sort of one of
the points um I actually wanted to ask
of you if you would post the the data
that you said you had on TTL you know
basically no caching and you know what
the implications that were on in that
environment that you tested that three
times that would be very useful I would
appreciate so I think approach that
Tanana would maybe or something right
I'm I'm very happy to show you the
graphs but I'm afraid I'm not permitted
to share the data much as I'd like to
so it was collected under the data
protection act which exists in the UK
and the agreement we have says that
we're not allowed to share the data
which I'm unhappy about as well but
that's the way unfortunately it works
because for example I'd like to just
give out sanitized TCP dumps but I am
because they may lead to violation of
individuals privacy UK law that's not
permitted I wasn't looking for the
details just sort of the mathematical
otherwise we you and I have a circular
dependency where you're referencing data
that we can't actually see so we can't
rely on the data to believe what you're
saying all right so anyway yeah if you
could provide a high-level summary of
the findings that would be very much yep
thank you Dave Meyer so I wanted to get
your opinion on one thing um so we have
all this you you kind of uh showed us
all of this wisdom that had been come
that had come down from the stratosphere
issue the internet history
Nowell and all of these guys that and
there's assumption that locator I'd be
split is the way to scale routing and do
a bunch of other things like mobility
and stuff like that but what we're
seeing right now is it's actually
getting built and so we're getting some
pragmatic experience with things like
less than il NP another kind of
approaches to this whole thing and I've
written I don't know if you've looked at
the stuff I've written on locator ID
split and what it means for an
architecture but it introduces some
other kind of really hard problems and
in particular and I will say that
the designers you know the people like
Nolan that these folks who really cook
this up or who realized the overloading
and all of this stuff never really got
to the point where they were
implementing it so the some of the
problems that become apparent when you
try to deploy this stuff weren't
apparent to them and I'll just give you
one example and I just want to get your
opinion on this kind of stuff basically
if you do locator ID split then you have
to maintain the binding between the
locator and the ID and you're doing with
DNS unless does it with you know the
mapping system stuff the problem with
that is that that problem is inherently
N squared and you know if you look at
something like something like the REIT
protocol inside shim six that's
basically N squared problem with a bunch
of heuristics to try to avoid that
scaling property right so now what
you've done is you're trying to
introduce some kind of robustness into
the system with all of this stuff but
you created a fragility and the question
is how bad is that fragility right and
and you know this is kind of like a
dynamic systems question about or you
know complex systems question about you
know robustness complexity trade-offs
but that one it's not been well study I
wrote about it twice I think I think
you've seen the stuff I wrote about it
but it's I'm not convinced quite yet you
know because of this exact issue so I
just wanted to hear your comments on
that so I think is this the right time
State Oh Rick time state is part of the
issue the rate Thanks
sorry the rate times State thing was the
Tony Lee formulation of the problem with
the routing system right this is
different thing I have a binding between
locator and identifier right how do I
know that that locator that's bound to
the identifier is any good right so
there are two there are two situations
you want to look at that once when
you're setting up a session and that's
when you would take a fully qualified
domain name as you didn't now look it up
and you would get back locator and
identifier records from the DNS
yeah the mapping system can work but
that doesn't tell you anything see that
that doesn't tell you about the reach
ability of that locator so the locator
itself might be dead and there might be
quite a Records for it right right but
maybe I haven't understood the question
but is that any different from what we
have today when you look up an address
and you don't know if it's reachable
yeah it's different because the
signaling that the host gets right will
be like I sent a sin and I don't ever
get a Cenac right now I can just bump
down the dns and get the next day record
if there is one and if there isn't one
that thing failed right if it's luck ID
split and the locator ID mapping is
invisible to the host it can't do that
so things like gse had this problem
things like 8 + 8 GS see how this
problem things like Lisp have this
problem where we depend heavily on the
fact that the syn ACK is signalling
liveness of the locator we just didn't
think about it that way when we were
designing it right - and then us can
take action in their locator ID split
case the host can take action right so I
think there is a pathological case which
is an example so for example you have a
client system it's talking to an end
system using Island P it looks up the
locator value sends the the syn and
between the same getting to the remote
host the route hosts move and the syn
ACK coming back the remote host moves so
it's a locator has changed because it's
moved for example and so there's no way
to finish that the TCP handshake and set
up that connection right is that the
kind of acute and worse there's an
external database that's not giving
notification to the people who have
queried that database for information
that it's changed so that that kind of
case is exactly the kind of thing we're
looking at and you're I totally agree
with you that's going to be the kind of
thing that like governs whether this is
going to be deployable and usable in in
various scenarios and the first part of
that has been looking at what's the
behavior of DNS when you have very low
TTL x' for
some of the DNS records and so you
expect them only to be live for that
lookup and then you expect a host to
move now we haven't progressed to the
point where we're testing real
application behavior over a real network
with that but we're trying to gauge the
dynamics of some of the infrastructure
that could support that so we're not
very far progressed along that in the
moment
okay thank you