alright so this is the the more
operational experience side of the ipv6
deployment we were lee and i were trying
to not overlap even though our panelists
could have easily and we have one that
overlaps so our first speaker is John
Rizzo ski I don't know how to say it
he's a cheap ipv6 architect at comcast
he works closely with CableLabs on
docsis and packet cable specs which I'm
sure is just tons of fun anyway come on
John okay good morning folks so what I'd
like to do today is is tell a little bit
about some of our real experiences with
various ip6 related technologies as part
of our trials as I'm sure many of you
are aware and hopefully recall we
announced earlier this year that we were
that we're going to conduct a number of
ipv6 related trials they many of them
are are actively underway we still have
a couple to kind of get underway but
were nonetheless were very close one on
kind of having all these different
activities in flight and I think that's
it's important to note and it's also you
know we feel is very important to to
come back and share some of that those
experiences here with you so real quick
you know you know some some background
information here you know we started the
program of Comcast over five years ago
we've taken a very incremental approach
to enabling v6 today the entire the
entire background is as capable v6 our
back office systems have been fully
upgraded support v6 and an access
network is large and capable of
supporting native ip6 and really the the
piece that remains for us is to kind of
systematically go through and you know
enable it perform any any software
upgrades but from from a hardware point
of view you know we've we you know we
believe we have what we need there to
kind of kind of take v6 to the next
level here
the initial focus of the program which I
believe was actually very important to
how it panned out for us is that we we
actually focused initially on device
management right you know enabling the
networking infrastructure so that we
could manage devices using v6 we found
that after all that work it was really
in at least in our case there's an
incremental opportunity for us to extend
that and now start to take v6 to you
know you guys so that's kind of where we
are now with these trials and I'll tell
you more about them before I do that a
little bit of background it's more
background here so case anybody's wasn't
aware you know when I came back here we
were in San Francisco or Austin we
talked about some of the things that we
had set up from a portal point of view
we added some new sites here and
basically the top two are our portal for
the for our v6 activities and the bottom
was are essentially you know proxied or
translated versions of the content that
resides on the original versions or the
or the origin versions of those sites
one very important point to note we we
recently closed the registrations for
the trials but prior to doing so we had
over 7,000 people sign up to participate
which we were very happy about we
thought that was a very important data
point and hugely relevant to to at work
so again background the little bit more
more background here but uh you know
again the goal for us was to make sure
that our underlying infrastructure was
able to support you know it was parody
we have between v4 and v6 for us you
know really the preference is you know
it for the ipv6 to be native versus you
know other types of techniques I think
we all you know understand or very soon
will understand more about some of the
the pros and cons of the different
approaches are but from our point of
view our you know our preference is to
use to leverage native connectivity to
offer to offer services to folks and
again you know one of the one of the
main goals of what we are
after is to you know enable it you know
again verify that everything is working
as designed and identify gaps to make
sure that you know we don't there are no
surprises right and we think that that
really it's important for everybody who
is deploying v6 to do this sooner rather
than later these findings are there
they're like diamonds in the rough there
are things that you really need to find
out now and not a year from now and of
course you know that extends into the
home you know the goal for us is to make
sure that when we go into you know we
extend services to folks and we'll talk
more about this later that we understand
what the impact into subscriber doing is
going to be right we have to make sure
that that are going to the you know
guiding principles of the program of
comcast is to make sure that we that it
is seamless right so our our goal is
into is to really actively try them you
know disrupt or break things and yeah so
and what's going to go alongside with
that is going to get is to make sure
that in addition to having the
infrastructure ready and available that
we have content and services available
or v6 as well so I'll kind of switch
gears a little bit talk about some of
our Charles 624 was something that we
had added to our activities after our
initial announcement we had done some
preparation work you know in the you
know you know the early spring time
frame that led us to really pay a lot
more attention to 64 I won't bore you
with a lot of details on what 64 is I
think most everybody in this room knows
what it is but essentially it is the
encapsulation of IP six packets over
I've before it's fairly well-known been
around for a while you know often gets a
bum rap for a variety of reasons and
I've been guilty of offering it the bum
rap it's a on occasion as well so the
deal is for us is you know we saw that
there is this you know enormous amount
of opportunity here to really you know
leverage 624 to add to the things that
we want to learn as a relates to a be 60
you know and that's evidence by you know
some home routers that have it on by
default and supported many popular
operating systems etcetera etc the fact
that it's on by default is actually
really the key point here and the real
deal I think for everybody in the room
here is and I think you know Martin
would probably agree with me here is
it's a it's out there whether you're
with you whether you want to acknowledge
it or not it's happening right so you
know you might want to think about
actually doing something to to to handle
that you know we did and I'll tell you a
little about that so we basically
deployed a handful of Linux page 64
relays currently there are four running
they'll be a fifth running here
hopefully in the Atlanta area before the
end of the year and one of the things
that we had learned about the you know
the use of the Linux platform is the
very first time we went to go turn it up
it was about a 15-minute maintenance
window because the kernel panic
basically brought everything to a
screeching halt for that night so once
we get everything squared away you know
and this was a again a linux based
platform the actual turn up of these of
these relays was actually very
straightforward there's definitely some
tweaks to be had to make for you know
different client you know I guess you
know client-side our home gateway side
64 invitations but every day is done it
was very good you know fairly
straightforward and honestly the
reduction in latency was substantial
right it was easily fifty percent so the
message you know from my point of view
is is you know if you're not if you're
not thinking about the point suits for
relays and you have lots of people on
your network that have you know
equipment that supports it you might
want to revisit that and again it is it
is able you know it is enabled by
default in a lot of places and one of
the things that we did observe and you
know this is fairly obvious but as part
of enabling the 64 2.64 relays you know
because they are now on our network we
actually were able to achieve some of
our you know
further achieve some of our objectives
in that now we had native traffic more
native traffic a substantial increase in
native traffic across our across our
network which was which is very
important to us and I think it's these
are things that would be valuable for
everybody to to learn about so sick
sardine a little bit about six rd it's
it's very much you know a lot of folks
may or may not know that it'sit's you
know similar to six to four but it
offers a number of improvements one of
the challenges that we have 64 is you
know the use of the anycast addresses
and the fact that there are like piles
of up and relays out there that yeah
some are some are managed better than
others but after the day is done is part
of the reason why it's it's often
frowned upon but with that with six rd
we have the you know we have a bit more
control you know I price of information
here about you know we could find
information about the draft and you
probably heard about it earlier this
morning again we're encapsulated v6
packets or over over before but the key
benefit the six rd and maybe it doesn't
apply as much to me but it may apply to
other folks here is it's really it was
very fairly straightforward to deploy
for us it's very similar to the 64
relays and for folks who have challenges
and the access network for ipv6 native
it's really something that you know you
ought to take a look at at a bare
minimum test and really consider for
your you know for your v6 deployment
program is uh you know it yielded some
of the same benefits that we had some
the same benefits that we had was 64 and
it helped us to increase the native ipv6
traffic across the backbone but one of
the things that we did have to do is we
had to we had to really do a lot of work
with you know the vendors and the open
source community to to create or have
available to us to see ease the pieces
that reside in your house there's a
couple things that we had to do to get
them out there we have to do some manual
configuration and that's where thing
because in our in our infrastructure and
in a device themselves there are some
DCP bits that were not kind of aligning
but in fairness I
those things are going to very soon work
themselves out the huh ok ok so I'll
kind of quickly jump to the one point
about six rd the deal here is one of the
things that you should note is if you
have if you're going to consider it and
you know the placement in the quantity
of your board of relays very important
right to impacts to g location and
performance and latency are all things
that you need to be aware of i'll kind
of blow through this left side because
i'm running at a time so last but not
least one of the things that we are
actively working to deploy now its kind
of hoping i'd be able to share it here
today is our native ipv6 trial
information this is where you basically
have IP for just like you have IP six
today one thing i won't take a i will
make a note of for you guys here is the
vendor collaboration room is running
exactly some of the components that we
are using as part of our trials so I'd
encourage you to come and check it out
we can tell you more about it the bottom
line for us is we have you know we have
we are actively planning and ready to
execute on enabling the first batch of
native dual-stack subscribers where we
basically take v4 leave it as is and we
enable ipv6 previous delegation into our
trial users homes from a from a bit bit
more technical point of view at a bare
minimum what will offer you as part of
these trials with native dual stack is
they'll be a / 128 allocated to the
Wayne interface and as well and
minimally it'll be a / 64 allocated to
the land interface that's not fixed but
it's it's it's where we're going to
start with it one of the biggest
challenges that we have on this front is
really orchestrating all the you know
the software upgrades and figuration
which is in some cases business usual
but because it is a bit on the on the
bleeding edge here you know where we're
taking a very incremental approach so
last but not least before I get thrown
off here and Catholic is mad at me one
of the biggest things that we see still
where we have some some some gaps is you
know content right yeah we we have to
make sure that everything that we do is
part of enabling v6 to people whether
it's trial and production
that that content gross porcelain and as
a relation SL I was very happy to hear a
lot of the news from folks you know on
the content side and I think we need
more of it and at least I know from our
point of view we you know we need to see
that to make sure that we can continue
to you know achieve the goals and
objectives of our trials and ultimately
do what we need to do to take v6 through
to folks like yourself so I'm going to
wrap up now thank you very much so next
we have Michael Sinatra who's been a
network engineer at UC Berkeley for 13
years including 11 years on the central
campus network and he has some really
interesting experiences and apparently
his current fake title of the month is
ipv6 compliance officer that just
basically means i'm AG people to make
sure that their applications and systems
or v6 compliant so i'm going to talk
about just some experiences that
research and education institutions I'm
gonna call them ed use for sure I
realize that's a little bit glossing
over but we call them Edu's are having
with deploying ipv6 or more
appropriately adopting ipv6 I'm gonna
give an example of the UC Berkeley
wireless network so I did a little
matrix here of ipv6 deployment
preparedness at this point along two
axes of service enablement and client
enablement and one thing that I want to
also point out is a lot of the regional
networks regional are any networks are
sort of down in this area of regional
and national are any networks they're
pretty good well off in terms of ipv6
they can provide ipv6 of their clients
and clients and most of them have
enabled ipv6 on their services so that
includes things like magpie max kalrind
Cameron more net or net and the other
ones like I peds like Internet to nlr
and es net so a lot of what we are
moving for is sort of a native dual
stack type configuration that allows us
to continue to use the ipv4 address
space that we have
and provide a more gradual transition to
ipv6 we do have enough most American ed
use as most people now have enough ipv4
address space we're not in big trouble
with that and we do want to adopt ipv6
we want to move forward with ipv6 for
the reasons you see here i'm going to
divide the rest of the talk into two
pieces one piece is going to talk about
our experiences in adopting ipv6 in a
large-scale Wi-Fi wireless network and
i'm going to talk a little bit about
some of our experiences and maybe give a
little bit of a bum rap 2624 a little
bit here just to help John in in what he
was talking about so what we what we did
in the past year is we abated an old
captive portal system that was end of
life and had some problems it did not
support ipv6 and we actually had a big
problem with rogue arrays in ipv6 um
being announced in our captive portal
system even though it didn't Dino didn't
support ipv6 so I'll talk about that in
a minute but what we did is we decided
to roll our own captive portal system we
had this big problem with ipv4 address
burn rate because what was happening is
people would come onto the network they
would associate with the wireless
network and they would get an ipv4
globally routable address even though
they never used the network and they
never authenticated to it so there was
no reason for them to have that address
they just happen to have a mobile device
that had a wireless antenna and it
happened to be turned on and happened to
get the address so we wanted to get rid
of that and our solution was one-to-one
nat basically you get an RFC 1918
address and then once you authenticate
that gets bound to an ipv4 globally
routable address and based on some of
the presentations this morning you can
see a little bit as to why we did that
it actually allowed us to reclaim a lot
of address space but didn't give us all
of the problems that you heard about
this morning with regard to shared a
dressing and that actually has been very
helpful for us it does still give us the
opportunity the option of going to a
many-to-one nat in case we want to
conserve even more address space it also
once you authenticate it turns on ipv6
as a bridge so basically the captive
portal bridges v6 connectivity to you
you get end-to-end native v6 if you have
dual stack capability we did have this
problem with rogue are a
I call it rogue Ari's is probably not a
good way to call it but basically it is
systems that have connection sharing
turned on some cases unbeknownst to the
actual user of that system and all it
needs is a globally routable ipv4
address or in some cases even a private
ipv4 address it will create its own 624
address whether has connectivity to the
624 network or a six to four real a
router it will still announced a route
saying I have your ipv6 default here
send all your ipv6 traffic through me
and what you end up with is a case where
your ipv6 traffic is effectively blocked
and you have to timeout and then fall
over to ipv4 this happens a lot on
wireless networks in some cases even
happens on conference networks I'll let
you read through this slide but this is
an example of me having to get up at
Erin two years ago and say hey
somebody's breaking all of our ipv6
connectivity please stop so what we
ended up doing with our ipv6
connectivity is not only turning it on
natively which helps to sort of force
out some of that bad rogue 624 the stuff
that gets the bum rap or that causes 6
24 in general to get the bum rap but we
also took the router announcement
priority field which has an incredibly
granular option of low medium and high
and we turned our routers so they would
announce our a's with the priority of
high and that would trump all of the
other ones that are in the default realm
which is medium i don't know why anyone
would ever use low because of mediums
the default there's really no reason
that used low unless you really don't
want people routing through your device
so that actually worked we actually got
the rogue RA some of them still
advertised routes and them still
advertise addresses but we got sort of
rid of them from actually causing a
problem because everyone uses our
default route which is the correct one
it's the n10 native ipv6 route I'm going
to mention a little bit about this later
but the the once you have a 6 24 thing
happening on your network in the best
case scenario you're sending your
traffic off to a six to four real a
router usually being routed through
someone's laptop which is doing connect
sharing and that's out there somewhere
and you may not know where that is a lot
of universities now are setting up their
own 624 relay routers that allows them
to do a little bit more control over the
traffic they know where it's going and
they can also selectively block ipv6
traffic making sure they send back
icmpv6 responses so that the traffic
will stop and failover immediately to
ipv4 since most operating systems will
do that they won't timeout if they see
an IPM icmpv6 unreachable they'll
immediately failover to ipv4 so that's
one way to kind of stop that one or
another way i should say to kind of stop
that 624 stuff from happening if you
don't want it to happen there's some
Edu's out there the block IP protocol 41
which is the ipv4 tunnel side of 624 and
other types of tunnels that's a bad idea
because you're dropping traffic on the
floor and you're giving no signaling
back to the host that their traffic is
being blocked on the floor dropped on
the floor so they have to now timeout
and go back to ipv4 and that just makes
a big mess for the client I'll let you
read through this slide there's not
really much to it other than this is
sort of some of our experiences in
running our own sort of 624 relays
sometimes you've had universities which
try to leap their wraps to their offsite
providers sometimes the offsite provider
happens to be somebody big like Comcast
or someone else and then you end up
sucking in a lot more 624 traffic than
you thought you were so comcast of
course has been very nice and setting up
their own 64 relays and that's helped
out a lot on to give us you know a
little bit more symmetry in the 624
traffic that we are actually sourcing
I'm not going to talk too much about
this part i'm going to try to get
through it so we have time for questions
this is actually wrong it should be
broken aP's not broken Ras and I'll all
say about this is we did have a set of
RA of ApS that had a very very good
implementation of our a guard now a lot
of us here at the edu community we like
something like our a guard because if we
if we have if we have Ras there
maliciously out there which we haven't
yet had they're all misconfigurations
but if we have rogar a announcements
that are maliciously coming in and they
decide to set their route priority too
high that could actually start capturing
some of our traffic so we like our
access points that only
and switches that only allow our a
announcements from a designated port
which is where the upstream router is
that's very similar to DHCP snooping so
it's basically our DHCP snooping for Ras
and there's already an internet draft
out about this these particular devices
who are so robust in there are a guard
capability that they actually blocked
all ipv6 traffic from the client and
they allowed all ipv6 traffic from the
router so that just broke ipv6
connectivity for all the clients but
gave them nice shiny globally routable
ipv6 addresses which they would try to
use some of us are also even putting up
some teredo relays I thought this is
going to be really not very interesting
because you're not going to find much
happening in tirado because tirado is
supposed to be used as an absolute last
resort if there's no ipv4 connectivity
out there well it turns out during
breaks during this meeting I said oh I'm
just going to set up a trade oh right
relay on Berkeley's campus and start
sucking in the trade Oh routes and see
what happens and I'm now seeing with our
native wireless network that we've set
up I'm now seeing a lot of peer-to-peer
what looks like peer-to-peer traffic I
don't really know what it is but I'm
actually seeing a fair amount of traffic
going through trade oh so that's kind of
interesting that's not something I
expect it to happen but it is
interesting the kinds of things you
learn about what's going on in your
network when you have these relays that
you set up the 624 relays and the Teredo
relays so that's basically it in
conclusion dual stack is not dead a lot
of us here in the edu community are
still trying to do dual stack sometimes
with some sort of ipv4 nat augmentation
like we did with our wireless network in
some cases we're just doing straight
native dual stack which is what a lot of
us are doing in our residential networks
at this point and berkeley is hoping to
do that we have some management tools
that we have to fix but we'll get we'll
get v6 in our residential network I hope
this year and for the most part the
transition mechanisms we're actually
trying to sort of keep those out so six
to four and trade oh we're trying to get
a handle on what's happening with them
trying to get some control over them and
trying to get them replaced with native
dual stack thanks
next up we have Tom cuff caffeine I've
never said before he's so self to find
router Lackey and he's been working at
limelight networks since 2006 as a
network engineer hello thanks um I
realized I did not put a background
slide in here so for those that are
familiar with what limelight has
endeavored to do over the last couple
years in the ipv6 space i'll briefly run
over our efforts there our initiative
started in the core of our network and I
guess I should back up and point out for
those that aren't aware limelight is
somewhat unique as a CD in as it has its
own core network modeled very much after
a traditional service provider IP
backbone where you'd expect to see and
do see the traditional elements
architectural elements that are present
in that that's set up so we started out
our initiative with what we consider to
be perhaps the the easiest portion of
the ipv6 adoption process which is
getting ipv6 in the core that started in
around the middle of 2008 and by the end
of 2008 we had v6 in the core and we're
routing ipv6 traffic over the next few
months in the beginning of 2009 we
started bringing up v6 transit sessions
to those transit providers that offered
v6 routes as well as a significant a
relatively significant amount of v6
peering at considering what was
available for the time all of this work
in the core was then followed up by
enough edge work to culminate in a
proof-of-concept demo with Netflix where
we were able to deliver netflix watch it
now traffic over v6 and this is a
service that's still up and running
today so getting to that point we had
what are probably traditional concerns
in the in the in the ipv6 adoption
process for anybody in the room which is
primarily make maintaining stability in
the existing production network and we
endeavor to do that by trying to
carefully select what what routing
protocols we were going to use and
carefully making sure that our existing
edge architecture was primed to support
whatever mechanisms we had to put in
place to deliver v6 traffic we were
mostly successful in that we ran into
some bumps and I've got here on the
first slide a basic breakdown of some of
the architectural and organizational
challenges that we face so I'll talk
about the art of the architectural ones
first one of the bumps that we ran into
is in the process of selecting a routing
protocol at the time our vendor only
offered a single topology mode of is is
because we were using is is and the ipv4
domain there was a lot of interest and
determination to make sure that we
leveraged our knowledge and experience
with is is and the v6 domain as well so
the the trick there is that in single
topology mothers there's a single SPF
calculated for both v4 and v6 so in an
v4 production network you can definitely
run into some turbulence if if you're
addressing schemes aren't correct on
interfaces and SPF recalculations occur
so we got out fairly easy you know
they're a couple of events where there
was some turbulence on the network as a
result of that and now the vendor has
finally caught up to providing dual
topology mode is is which it leaves one
and that you know for myself it's kind
of like well thanks I could have used
that two years ago but you know now that
we're already completely integrated into
single topology is is if it makes a
difficult proposition to think about
transitioning into dual topology and go
through a lot of the same challenges and
struggles that we went through in the
first place with selecting the igp so
and that falls under the general
category of dealing with vendor
readiness
so one thing that we can we continue to
run into issues with vendor readiness on
the network side and on the course ID
one issue in particular that may be of
interest to some folks is line cards
that that have cam space for both ipv4
and ipv6 space ipv4 and ipv6 routes
we've run into an instance where we have
cam space divided up to give us 384 kv4
routes in 128 kv6 routes for a total of
512 k routes and the cam and that's
that's obviously problematic from a core
service provider network stand stand
point if your routing before traffic and
you've got the table which currently is
the before table which currently sit sit
around 330 k routes approximately and
you realize that you've only got
Headroom of about 50 k more routes on
the v4 side and then add to that that
you've got v6 prefix cam allocation for
128 k v6 routes which seems quite like
overkill if if we do v6 correctly and
leverage the the aggregation promise
that it offers so that's something that
we're you know just an example of an
issue that you know we continue to face
even as we go forward with you know with
our vendor of choice where we're trying
to get to let me jump ahead here their
organizational challenges as well and
I'll briefly go over some of the ones
that we faced internally and these are
not unique I'm sure a lot of folks here
who are dealing with the ipv6 adoption
challenge have have run into the same
some of the same issues we're lucky at
limelite we're very forward-leaning we
have to be in the CD in space it's very
focused on on evolution and adapting to
you know the emerging internet
environment to deliver services and to
make money off delivering those services
so you know management by off was never
really the problem i mean i think we had
commitment from from the highest levels
of the organization very early that we
would do v6 and we would you know we
would we would lead in that space but
what we find out is that management by
off and allocation of resources are not
necessarily the same thing and and I
know that you know every organization
struggles with this it's you only have
so many hours in the day and so many
personnel to to tackle tackle
initiatives and so part of the issue is
that you know what we're all witnessing
in terms of the lack of content
available in v6 by virtue of some of the
technical challenges that we face makes
it difficult to make a business case
that would then Alec that within align
resources to in the organization to
deploy b6 in a much more rapid way so
that continues to be a challenge and
that's something that that I'm sure that
you know will continue to see as as a
challenge so for us it's really about
internally in our organization getting
ipv6 you know having in folks in the
organization who are ipv6 evangelists
and getting them to carry the message to
the various parts of the organization
that this challenge is not going to go
away you can't ignore you know the fact
that that we're going to have turbulence
in delivering v4 services based on on
address exhaustion and what we're after
at limelight is quite simply just parity
between everything that we offer in the
vc force base and and being able to make
sure that that functions in a v6
environment a v6 before environment with
you know something like Carrie right now
in the middle or any combination thereof
so
and then finally as part of that it
really what what I'd like to accomplish
this your organizationally at limelight
is to really pin down where the demand
is and isn't from customers I know a lot
of customers know that they should care
about v6 they've been told that they've
read it they've heard it apocryphal E
but they may not necessarily be feeling
the pain yet of not being able to live
or v6 traffic in fact you know we're
pretty much sure that they're not and
when we do get inquiries you know we
definitely try to lead that dance with
customers and make them aware of the the
emerging challenges that are coming from
V for exhaustion if they're not already
aware of them what we'd like to find out
is is what drives their interest and and
or lack of interest in v6 adoption and
and try to try to build a you know a
useful database for extracting we're two
best focus the energies in the
organization to to make v6 happen in the
best and fastest way possible for you
know for our critical customers and for
the services that they want to deliver
so that continues to be a challenge and
I'm sure it's something that will will
continue to work on this year and that's
about all I have so thank you very much
next up we have Lorenzo khleevi from I'm
networking at Google he got to write his
master's thesis on ipv6 and ipv4 tunnel
discovery and the internet sounds pretty
exciting hey so um I'm going to talk a
little bit about what we've done and
what we found to work and what doesn't
so for those who don't know we've been
doing ipv6 for a while we started in
mid-2007 really we started with some
network engineering and software
engineering and in about a year and a
half we brought v62 most of our major
services and they're available in the
Google over ipv6 program so it's it
didn't took it didn't take that much
work to actually do this it was a with a
small team the strategy was to take a
gradual approach the idea is that if you
do it in a hurry it's going to cost you
a lot of money you're going to have you
might actually have to end up folk
lifting hardware and we just didn't want
to do that so we took a very very slow
and measured approach we hadn't you know
handful of people or even less just
slowly chipping away we got v6 ins and
requirements in when we when we changed
our hardware and when vendors approached
are saying oh we have this great new
product that does be sick we said ok not
interested but to vendors that said we
don't support ipv6 we said ok well we're
not going to buy from you unless you do
so so we worked from the outside in and
when we started it was basically nothing
else out there of any size so what we
did was we started with user facing
services and we made them available
starting with ipv6 or google com you
know starting just at the load balancer
and then progressively going up to
software stacks until we reach the
applications and and and that was
essential to actually get some user
traffic and make the software developers
understand this thing was real and that
this traffic was coming in and it gave
us a source of traffic that we could use
to actually run our services on so we
used a shim layer to protect our
applications we basically take the v6
address
rip off the user modifiable bits and
hash it into multicast space which is
something that really enabled us to
advance without having all of our code
all of our applications all our systems
understand v6 this as a few undesirable
properties notably breaks to your
location but it really is one of the key
things that allowed us to make progress
sometimes it's not perfect and one point
gmail was telling you your last login is
from this multicast v4 address so in a
network design what we found to work is
to make it as similar to v4 as possible
that way you don't you don't have to
retrain your NOC you don't have to do
anything and and dual stack everything
you can because if you do a stack it's
going to scale by itself it's
operationally supported so for example
if you're using you know it is probably
best if you use one protocol one NGP and
that's what we chose to do you're using
ice ice and you're using you know single
topology is for everything we use before
to carry before and v6 to carry v6 we
don't want faith sharing between
protocols we want things to blow up
independently if they blow up and we
found this to be very useful and
implementations yes so they mostly kind
of work they mostly kind of say what
they do but they have bugs because
nobody's ever really kick the tires and
so don't expect stuff to work just
because it's supported because it'll not
likely it's likely that nobody else has
used it before you so you know put in a
lab test it and when you find the bug
don't stop testing don't wait for the
vendor code maintenance release to fix
it find the next bug because I guarantee
you that it's there and so repeat rinse
and repeat there are many more bugs to
find and you don't have time to fix them
one by one and what we did what we found
to be useful is that if you can produce
a workaround it's actually acceptable
for production then put it into
production because the bugs are really
hard to find you can only find them at
production so for example I mean these
are a choice examples of bugs if a
firewall filter term has a 1-bit match
in bits 32 to 64 and then a two-bit
matching bit 64 296 on this particular
platform this code
then it's not going to work now I
challenge you to find that in your lap
in a febrile rib get out of sync in
particular race conditions in particular
combinations of its up brute updates
this may be a little bit easier but you
know it's hard to find duplicate address
detection is kind of a you know medium
sized headache on our vendor you
basically have to deactivate the
interface configuration put it back when
you trigger dad and that's that's a
problem right so we ended up disabling
it so again are you going to find this
in lab maybe but maybe not so what's not
working so so our infrastructure is
basically pretty stable at this point we
were able to offer most of the services
now it's in including YouTube now it's
an incremental you know business of
bringing it to the services don't yet
have it and and so if it's a slow slow
progress now but what's broken is the
rest of the Internet in particular we
see a lot of brokenness in in homes what
happens is that typically operating
systems will try pv6 first and then
they'll fall back to v4 but in some
cases the fall back to before will be
slow typically if the host tries v6 and
it doesn't have a default route doesn't
have it a v6 address it'll just fail
instant mean that's fine it will just
fall back try the next address go on
with life that's fast it's not a problem
if there's a network error for example
you know the rooters advertises v6 reach
ability or but doesn't actually forward
the packets or replies with unreachable
what happens is the host just sits there
trying to connect to the v6 advice its
staff of four seconds or 20 seconds on
the windows just sits there saying oh
I'm trying to connect I'm trying to
connect I'm trying to connect and then
the throbber is your spending and
nothing's happening and so now various
failure scenarios learning that on Linux
it's three minutes if you don't send
unreachable it's particularly bad and tu
holds it very bad and a lot of this is
due to home gateway behavior I mean
certain models of home gateways have
been known to turn on 64 with a private
ipv4 address on
on the land side nobody explained to
them that is impossible it's never going
to work but you it's turned on by
default you can't disable it so you know
and even if you have both native and 6
24 in your home your host might end up
using 624 because it's just going to
pick the first River advertisement that
it chooses and this will break things so
another thing hosts may choose to prefer
624 over ipv4 well guess what before is
more reliable because 624 it is at best
as reliable as before and so this was a
known issue in RFC 348 for most
application developers have worked
around it windows worked around it opera
worked around it had never had this
problem the mac is now working around it
we expect those we expect those fixes to
roll very soon and then there's broken
firewalls as those all sorts of things
and basically again it's nobody's ever
really kick the tires there's a very
very low level of background noise this
is my favorite it's um it's um don't
look at the MAC addresses I didn't scrub
them out but it's a home gateway
advertising v6 which ability and telling
the hosts on the local net that they
have a prefix of 0 0 0 0 / 64 that
that's brilliant in itself it's not a
unicast address if I were the OS
implementation it wouldn't accept such a
prefix but the OS accepts the prefix of
0000 and it tries to connect and the
Rooter sends back no you don't have a
root unreachable and the u.s. just keeps
trying and after 4 seconds it it gives
up for the first addressed and there's
five more addresses to try so just you
know waits for 24 seconds and this is
completely broken a normal part in all
parts of it but this is we saw this in
real life and a user had this issue so
we have some numbers of this we use a
variant of the JavaScript experiment the
various other people are using we have a
decently sized data set but there's a
lot of noise in the data and we're not
exactly sure there's there's a lot of
different effects in that may contribute
if you filter out the data and you only
look at stuff that's very clean that we
know exactly what's going on
these are the numbers so for the
internet it's gone down from 0.09
percent to 0.08 to something like that
and so other than other numbers are
similar we have a blind spot for
whitelist ISPs people that are going to
the Google over ipv6 program so for them
if they have broken v6 they can't reach
us and therefore we can't measure that
we plan to fix this by putting
measurements on a host that's not part
of the Google over ipv6 program host
without a v6 address another network so
we can actually measure that as well and
so the good news is if you take away Mac
she sort of excluded from the results
you get into four nines territory which
isn't too bad it's still it's still the
kind of level of reliability that that
the people you know that need to make
this call are kind of uncomfortable with
but it's better than 30 and 39 s or so
you know half that you'd have you know
if you if you cancer the mac and as the
fixes role will see how real fast they
roll out we'll see what the numbers are
looking like over time and but again
there is persistent low level brokenness
the only way to fix this really is is in
the OS stack because the home gateways
never get upgraded you know they often
they're on firmware upgrades available
for them nobody oppressor himoto they
don't know what the problem is and even
you know when they see this problem what
happens is oh google is down that's
funny huh it's down all the time for me
now i wonder what that is but you know
facebook yahoo being they all work so
probably it's a google problem you know
if it did something wrong but i can't
call google because i don't know who
called and so whatever things we were
thinking about with other content
providers is to declare on the quad a
day in which you know major content
providers would get together and agree
to provide cuates to the whole internet
for one day turn it on leave it on and
turn it off and the goal of that would
be to get the user who has such a setup
which is malfunctioning all around which
is broken to call their ISP and their
isp would know who they
our and would say okay you have this
problem turn off v6 and you know that's
fine they turn off v6 the zero point you
know zero five percent of users with
this problem disable v6 fix the problem
and the rest of the internet you know
the other ninety-nine point nine percent
which doesn't have this problem can turn
on v6 or leave it off it doesn't matter
but it doesn't block other people who
want to use these six from using it so
that's what doesn't work hopefully will
you know black fixes in the quad a will
help but you know if you have other
ideas on how to find these people and
once you've found them how to report
them to their SP because our privacy
policy doesn't allow I don't know about
yours if you have any ideas you know no
snow okay now we're going to switch
gears ever so slightly and Jason's going
to come back up there's an internet
draft that he and some other folks wrote
that I thought was particularly
applicable to this community and address
space so I wanted to have him present it
so here's Jason from cox communications
again thanks
alright just so I don't come off as the
NAT guy of of I do wanted to
quickly go over the fact that it since
it says a panel for v6 adoption I mean
in transition just to clear point out
the fact that we are actually doing
transition as well and like II bursa my
job is actually working with the
engineering and operations teams to
actually push native v6 out to the home
user so and just give you a quick
overview there is 2009 we start rolling
on the backbone that's been completed
we're now turning up every peering
session we can this year now pushing out
into the systems hope have every system
online by the end of the year and then
start a cable modem trials obviously
we're a few years behind John so we've
been playing catch-up ever since and I'm
sure he'll hear some nice IM blow up
next few months as we stumble across
some of the challenges that he's already
I run through all right so what we're
doing here is what so one of the
transition technologies already talked
about today was LSN service provider and
a score for theres also 6 rd both of
these including other transition
technologies clearly benefit from a
shared address space so we're doing in
the ITF as asking for a single block of
address space to be used for that
purpose so I'll do a quick history
lesson problem statement solution try to
save some time for questions I'm sure
there'll be a lot of questions for this
whole session here alright so real quick
history lesson NCP to ipv4 happened in
81 basically goal here was a flash cut
which resulted in you know the internet
well the network being broken for for a
few months flash for now never
transition before to be 6 obviously we
can't turn off the network for for a few
months that's not really practical so
hence all the transition mechanisms
we've been talking about all morning
alright so there were view a problem
statement obviously I could be for
exhaustion is imminent
you know it's arguable whether it's
going to happen in q1 q2 q3 this is the
average of the of those the deployment
is obviously ipv6 only deployment it's
not really an option at this point v6
dual stack at least in my view point is
the only option to go and primarily the
things I talked about this morning see
devices aren't aren't v6 enable today
and it's going to take us a few years to
get there so the overall take away there
is providers must do something obviously
we were very talked about today da6 rd
EDS light large scale on that those are
the things we're going to be rolling out
at least to get us through the interim
point while we're doing v6 native as
well and then the other problem that
some of the large providers were having
is we're running out of the 49 th and 19
18 space or we have run out which makes
these transition technologies even more
of a challenge to deploy so Marla a
singer and Leo Vigoda did a good draft I
believe a few ITF Segoe that's going
through last call so hey what is it if
we're if we need shade address space for
multiple transition technologies and get
us through the coexistence period what
are the options available some of the
240 / 4 space the reserve space some of
the challenges there that we've already
ran to or some of the home gateways and
so this is what we're talking about here
is shared address space to be used in
the provider network not not out large
on the internet so it is going to look
like private address space internally to
the service provider or large enterprise
network some of the other options were
redefine a user private space that
hasn't allocated already so that's kind
of what this this draft is seeking to do
another option is for operators to come
together and say hey I got a piece of
this space that I'll dedicate to this
cause and this operator has another
piece and we'll all get together and
come up with you know a couple hundred
maybe a thousand blocks that we can all
use internally to our networks and not
rat out obviously that has some
operational considerations and is not
the best case at least in our viewpoint
and the other option is just do nothing
in squat on space which is another
option that is being talked about in
and some in some networks so the
recommended use is basically the least
crappy of all these approaches is
basically use to just go ahead and take
part of the address space that's out
there that isn't allocated today and
dedicate it for coexistence transition
technology usage benefits a couple of
them are it's the most predictable
outcome we don't have to run through a
lot of the operational challenges we'd
have to with the others it our viewpoint
it does offer the best customer
experience because it's the least amount
of development obviously they're still
development needed but it's it's the one
that we think we can get through most
efficiently and it does allow operators
to focus on ipv6 deployment above all
else because obviously we don't want to
be staying here running before 10 years
from now even though I'm sure it'll be
little pieces of it out there somewhere
but obviously v6 is the way to go for
for native internet usage all right so
what is this real quick this is the
definition is pulled from the draft it's
basically reserved address space that
could be used internally to large
service providers or or large
enterprises for the purpose of
facilitating v6 transition or
coexistence the recommended usage is it
should not be you it should only be used
between the CGN or LSN RSP net whatever
you want to call it and then the CPE
your router and that address space and
it should not be used at home networks
because obviously that would the whole
point of using shared address space is
that you're not overlapping with an
internal private space within the home
networks some of the benefits
flexibility so it's useful for both not
overlapping internally it's also useful
for people that are running out of
artistry 1918 space as well allow us a
transition and my overall view as it
allows you to actually deploy native v4v
64 until v6 catches up so loosen this
isn't this adjacent talking not cox but
if you have native v6 before using
darwin's theory and the fact that
operating systems are skewed to actually
select to visa
over before at some point when all the
content catches up and you'll see
traffic rises to the point of critical
threshold you're going to see that whole
migration take place and then you can
slowly phase out v4 from your from your
network and then the other thing a
security so having one block to apple
from the edge is definitely beneficial
and then this is some supporters we've
had for the drop let's had some
interesting comments within actually
this is the 02 version so it's already
on on the third on the third version so
we've incorporated a lot of the comments
we've already heard good feedback from
operator community as well as vendors
it's interesting most of the vendors are
against us but it seems that most
operators are for so I'm not sure what
would hide read into that but it's kinda
interesting and obviously time is of the
essence if we're talking about q2 is
when I Anna's gone obviously it doesn't
make sense to talk about this in 2013
that'll do it and these are the links to
some of the drafts and this is actually
the third version of this trap there's
also NTT has a giraffe too short sure
sake giraffe that has the address space
just for a nap or for this tries to be
more flexible and say it could be used
for any of the transition technologies
as well as in a year coexistence
technologies that's it
so we have a we have five minutes so
does anyone have any questions I've been
told then we get the big hook go ahead
hooked hey guys party hanigan from mac
my little scratchy i got some allergies
today but I two things I think that I'm
with respect to content networks
catching up I think you just actually
don't know where we are we're kind of in
lockstep whether you know it or not
we're going to talk more about that as
the months progressive and I think
you'll see some thought leadership cup
from us um with respect to V 6
transition second with the customer
perception that customers don't want it
they don't need it I think that so over
the past few weeks I building Cambridge
anam go to Harvard Square a lot like it
around there and every now and then I'll
just kind of walk up to someone to say
are you ready for ipv6 okay go what the
hell are you talking about okay so i
think that from the cable and end-user
network perspective that it's supposed
to be transparent to the users and from
the content perspective I think it's
supposed to be transparent to the users
I don't think that unless we break it
you'll hear a lot from customers and end
users so I'm not waiting around for
customers to ask me for it will be ready
they'll be able to use it the big big
big thing with moving to v6 and this is
a personal opinion and I think it's
probably an industry perspective as well
is that it has to be as good as v4 we
cannot break the internet we cannot make
the service worse we have to make it
equal or better I'm hoping that it's
going to be better um okay we only have
five minutes okay hold on I'm not done
or a big important part of the industry
if you look in the routing table you'll
see that we have lots of e6 space out
there and if I haven't already contacted
you or you can't haven't contacted me
with respect to duel stacking every
single connection that we have see me
after the meeting thanks Marty Suzanne
Suzanne wolf is see I'm looking around
and I see mostly big folks on the UH the
panel's we've done
this morning I just want to reinforce
the point that this is stuff that the
little guys in the medium sized guys
need to care about also sort of the you
guys need to be looking at this if you
want your network to continue to grow
and there's lots of experience beginning
about their there's lots of Technology
obligatory plug is C does open source
implementations of some of these things
we've done a dual stack light check that
out we're doing DNS 64 there are other
open source implementations that don't
cost you anything to try out go kick the
tires talked to Lorenzo and Marty and
everybody else but this is not just
something the words the big guys that's
exactly the point of these panels thanks
Suzanne front Mike just uh who are you
I'm nobody I'm Scott Shepherd who ask
silly questions one in the earlier talks
today someone mentioned something about
law enforcement FBI all that sort of
thing trying to do warrants intercepts
that sort of thing and you're saying you
have to report decent time stamps
datetime source port information has
anyone here actually worked with law
enforcement to deal with some of the
problems associated with carrier-grade
NAT and all this other stuff and saying
FBI you got to give me this information
is there any practical experience
working with these folks standards
bodies any of that sort of thing any
guys want answer me so this is John
brewski the only thing I could offer you
is is from a from a v6 point of view we
recently received the requests first to
this year for legal response for v6
addresses I think you're asking
something a little bit different about
perhaps yes ok this is in the right
track as well yeah I mean I thought that
was I thought that was great a great
sign of things I mean I've the fact that
we were asked the sort of questions and
we had internal people who had to go
respond to this sort of things and I was
huge I was surprised
pleasant surprise so that's cool anybody
else really quick well there is there's
also am Aaron does have a government
working group and we are starting to
work more closely within that group to
try to point out some of these issues as
well on a West George from his friend I
were at the REIT most recent one and
bobby flay mature if he's here but he's
kind of driving that as well thanks a
lot you guys that was great