good morning everyone we're going to
talk about a lot of recent developments
in the ethernet and it kind of ties into
some of the tutorials and other talks
that we've had here so it's almost like
we planned it this way i found this
diagram which I really lie like that Bob
Metcalfe drew in 1972 and so now it's
about 28 years later and it turns out he
was kind of right so we do see Ethernet
almost everywhere you know from the last
mile into wireless and obviously data
center and networks like that so
basically this is going to be a
whirlwind talk we have 58 slides in 28
minutes or 25 minutes but it's okay
we've done this before and no one died
but basically I'm just going to give you
an overview of all the stuff that's
going on with some references and then
you can read about the stuff that's
interesting to you and your spare time
but there is actually a lot of stuff
going on we have 1400 gig Ethernet that
is now the standard is now done we have
Tripoli which is energy-efficient
Ethernet we have a lot of carrier
ethernet and OEM tools that are now
available then we have the old data
center bridging and shortest path
forwarding for layer 2 networks so we're
kind of talk about all those and brief
and go kind of quickly first I wanted to
start out with the slides for all the
standards organizations because I got a
lot of these meetings and I talked to
all these people and I know all these
organizations so I kind of try to draw
this as an OSI model where the the
bottom is sort of the physical layer so
that's the components and interface
standards that's called the oif and then
as you move up the stack you have the
fibre channel yeah the I Triple E which
makes the ethernet standards then you
have the ITU which makes the telecom
standards and you move up higher in the
stack and you get the IETF and then the
Metro Ethernet forum and then at the
very top are you and your customers so
the thing I want to point out is that as
you move higher and higher up the stack
of standards organizations we see more
involvement by service fighters and
internet exchanges so in the Metro
Ethernet form in particular where
they're working on service definitions
and standards for Ethernet services we
see a lot of service' fighters and now a
lot of internet exchange is involved
because of the carrier ethernet
exchanges that people like Equinix
intelex are doing so you can kind of
refer back to the slide
as I throw out the standards acronyms
let's talk about 1400 gig Ethernet at
first so we're done I've been talking
about this for about five years so I'm
very excited that we actually are almost
to the state of shipping product the
standard was pretty much done this
spring and we had to go through some
formalities it was approved in June and
it's a whopping 457 pages long so it's a
massive set of standards for both 14 100
gig Ethernet this is our the sort of the
target applications and just because I
say target applications doesn't mean
that someone won't use the technology
you know in other places we always find
interesting ways to t to be creative
when we design our networks but this is
basically where we think that it'll be
used for t 100 gig 40 gig is basically
targeted towards data center application
so made a data center core especially
towards top of rack and blade server
access as the servers get faster and the
pci bus increases we think that they'll
need 40 gig sometime in the next couple
years also maybe for a small campus core
or something like that on our gig on the
other hand it's really targeted for
large service fighter networks or a
large data center aggregation large
campus cores and things like that here's
a slide that i keep updating and it gets
denser and denser and harder to read so
i hope you can see in the back the thing
that i want to point out here is that i
added a price row so this stuff turns
out it's a little bit more expensive
than we thought it would be especially
as we get into longer reach hunter gig
optics it's just very insanely expensive
and I'll talk about that a little bit
more but this is basically the physical
specifications and the type of media
that we'll be using for 1400 gig so
second generation technology even though
I said the standard was just approved in
June we're already starting to work on
new things and that's good because we
want we want new technology to evolve as
we as it becomes feasible so the
standard is really flexible just like 10
gig where we had I don't know cx4 and
10g bass-t and all this stuff evolve
over time the same thing what happened
with 40 and 100 gig there's already a
new project in the I Triple E to do a 40
gig serial for two kilometer and then we
also expect
there will be two new call for interests
later this year to do a shorter reach
copper cable and a backplane Ethernet
that uses 25 gigs signaling possibly a
low-cost two-kilometre module that would
use for x 25 signaling and then a new
optic called qsfp to which is still
being defined the other thing that's
going on is because the standards-based
optics are so insanely expensive and I
mean list prices of of several tens of
thousands of dollars there is a very
strong interest in the operator
community to support a non-standard
low-cost optic that uses ten-by-ten
signaling that would go up to two to
four kilometers so I think that'll be
something that we're going to
investigate and that could possibly come
out as a multi-source agreement that
would be a non-standard from the I
Triple E so interesting developments
there as far as what's going on beyond
right now what's keeping us from making
cheaper interfaces is the fact that
inside the box for chip-to-chip
communications we basically have three
six or 10 gig Surtees and components
that we can use inside the box what we
really need is faster signaling inside
the box to get rid of all this 10 by 10
conversion that we're doing in 10 by 10
aggregation on electrical interfaces so
the oif that's the standards
organization that those semiconductors
is working on some really fundamental 25
gigs signaling that's going to change
the way that we do things so when we
have that kind of signaling will see a
couple new projects in the I Triple E
that will use a true for by 25 gig
interface from electrical to optical
right now we have a 10 by 10 electrical
that converted into 4 right 25 optical
which adds a lot of costs and components
as far as what's going beyond we'd like
to do terabit Ethernet but it's really
not possible right now as far as
technology and economics i mean we could
build it but people are already having a
hard time affording 100 gig Ethernet and
terribly Ethernet would be pretty much
unfeasible 400 gig Ethernet could be a
choice and say mid 2000s 2015 by using
16 x 25 big signaling but that's just an
idea that's really being kicked around
by now bye
network operators and I think we'll see
you know some some more evolution next
couple years but it's clear that as far
as Ethernet there's a lot of demand for
it in different form factors and
eventually I think we'll see a true
serial hunter gig though it may not be a
couple years just because of our
technology all right what should you
expect this year there's lots of
announcements for companies have started
to announce and/or ship hunter gig
interfaces and there's one company
that's doing 40 gigs so I just want to
leave it at that as far as where we see
the technology going and like I said
it's kind of expensive so here's a chart
that I drew based on the historical
prices of ten and one gig Ethernet and
you can see that in the first couple
years the prices dropped by almost
almost half for over half in some cases
so we think that the same thing is going
to happen with 1400 gig based on the
historical pricing like I said the
optics are really what's the most
expensive right now because there's no
volume I mean the optics manufacturers
are practically making in my hand and we
may sell we meaning the industry may
sell a hundred of these interfaces this
year or next year so when you have that
kind of low volume there's just no no
cost benefit in volume production and
then second generation technology like I
said will allow us to do denser
interfaces and lower the prices too
here's some references I'll just kind of
skip over these all right so energy
efficient Ethernet this is I think a
really interesting new technology that
probably hasn't gotten a whole lot of
you know press or interest in the
operator community I think it's
interesting though because of the power
consumption so what it does basically is
introduced as a mechanism that will
reduce power consumption on the link
during periods when it's not used and
you can see this where I hope you can
see this chart from Intel and you notice
that an idol in a line rate interface
really uses about the same power but if
you run an interface at say ten Meg
versus one gig you actually save a lot
of power so the idea is just like your
CPU scales back when it's kind of idle
is that we're going to scale back the
speed of the network interface to
transmit at the most energy efficient
speed possible so the standard was just
approved last week and I think it'll
take a while because this has to go
actually into the silicon I think it
will
could a while before we see products but
i estimate that we see something in
probably 2011 or or maybe even sooner so
the way that this works like i said is
if you're transmitting say a couple
megabytes then you run the link at 10
meg if you're transmitting a couple
hundred megabytes you run the link at
100 meg and if you're going beyond that
then you run the link at a gig also
there's times when you're actually not
transmitting anything so like on a voice
over IP connection for example you may
only transmit something once every 10 or
20 milliseconds so you can actually idle
the link for several milliseconds when
there's no traffic descent so there's
two things is the speed selection and
then the low power Idol and this is
basically how it works everything looks
like normal obviously we can't flap the
link and things like that so the link is
always up there those frames are dropped
and or corrupted obviously and then the
time has to be transparent so we're
talking about millisecond transition
times between 10 and tunner door even
gig speeds just like your CPU does like
I said and this is the interesting thing
is because if you're already turning off
the network interface then there's also
other components and servers that you
could turn off so for example you could
turn off CPU cores because you know your
network interface is off and there's
nothing to send or receive so you might
as well turn off your CPU you could I
don't know turn down some memories that
you don't have to keep refreshing it or
things like that so I think this will
lead to other areas and server design
that will lead to a lot more efficient
utilization and then the way that this
is done is with ldp extensions and
auto-negotiation so obviously there's
mechanisms to set servers at a
particular speed or there will be
because some servers you may never want
to do this this negotiation so I think
this is really interesting this good
tutorial on the I Triple E web page the
talks about so in the background and
some of the power efficiencies and
savings that we think we can get but you
know if you imagine that large companies
have several hundred thousand servers
and if we start doing this around the
world that could be significant energy
savings ethernet ring protection
switching this is a new standards based
protocol for ethernet rings we've had a
number of vendors i think everyone
probably has their own propriety
technology but this is finally a usable
standard standards based protocol for
rings the good thing about it is unlike
Triple E which we just talked about this
is a protocol so there's no use for
their no need for any hardware changes
or anything like that so it's relatively
easy to implement the first standard was
done a couple years ago and basically
everyone's proprietary implementation
was a lot better so I don't think anyone
actually used it the second version the
standard was done this summer and it
actually has you know it makes networks
usable with multiple instances and
interconnecting rings and things like
that so there's the itu reference if
you're interested in more about it ok
carrier ethernet and we doing on time ok
we're doing well so Carrie Ethan has has
gotten a lot of interest in the recent
couple of years I'd say number one from
just a transport technology and then we
saw these Carrier Ethernet exchanges
coming online where they're actually
trying to exchange circuits over a
switch and we have this organization
called the metra net ethernet forum
which defines the services and
attributes that Kira Ethernet has that
differentiates it from a traditional
sale and Ethernet so there's a couple
things standardized services scalability
obviously you want to sell services in
different increments reliability quality
of service and then service management
is really a big piece and I have a whole
section on the OEM mechanisms because
it's so critical for carriers to provide
that TDM or sonnet like OEM that they're
used to so the MAF to find several
services and as I said before a lot of
the service providers actually involved
in these service definitions and then
you can become certified so it's good
because Carrie Ethernet is sort of a
vague term just like cloud computing is
and it means a lot of things to
different people so the MAF can actually
certify equipment and the MAF will also
certify a network so you can buy
certified equipment go to a certified
network and then you know what you're
getting so customers always get the same
thing the basic unit is called an
Ethernet virtual connection which is
just a point-to-point VC basically and
we can do a couple different things we
can do the e line which is just point to
point elana's multi-point and then e
tree is a rooted multi point where
the root can talk to all the nodes nodes
can talk to the root but they can't talk
to each other and here's some more
slides that will skip that go into more
detail about how that works so we're
going to skip all this stuff and go
straight to the summary an interest of
time here is basically the carrier
ethernet technology that we see on the
market today we have mpls mpls-tp p BB &
p BB te mpls is a very well-established
technology I started do an MPLS
interrupt test I think back in in two
thousand and their deployments even
before that so it's really the Swiss
Army knife of providing services you can
provide IP l2 l3 VPN services the
standards are mature and there's a lot
of development going on mpls-tp is a
carrier ethernet service that's really
focused on transport level mpls so it's
really designed to do sort of just
circuit level mpls and it's a work in
progress in the ITF is getting a lot of
interest by carriers especially for
mobile backhaul applications for example
where they need circuit like emulations
over ethernet but they don't actually
need all the complexity that IP bring so
it's just really just mpls for circuits
and i think it's definitely a market
trend PBB and pbbt e on the other hand
are really just designed to do carrier
ethernet services over ethernet they
don't have the multi service capability
that mpls brings and that's really why
from our perspective we see limited
deployment and and just not really a
market trend and there's no future
development either so if i had someone
ask me I went to do carrier ethernet
what should I use I would definitely say
you want to look at mpls because that's
the mature standard it's very widely
implemented and like I said before
there's a lot going on with mpls so pbte
I think BTW was really interested in
doing that with her 21cn network a
couple years ago and then turned out to
be not such a good idea so i guess
people kind of stopped talking about it
there's a bunch of references so let's
talk about OEM so om is really being
driven by the carrier ethernet services
and we finally have
for many many years a complete protocol
stack of OEM capabilities from layer 2
up to mpls IP and even the VPN layer I
remember when we were first doing mpls
interop tests back in 2001 I guess we
came we all came together with our gear
and we SAT there we plugged it in the
LSP came up for you know a few minutes
or a few hours and we watched the
blinking lights we had no idea of
telling if there was actually traffic
going over the LSP so now we finally
have mechanisms that can do that that
are standards-based and like I said
before this is really trying to emulate
some of the TDM and sonic capabilities
that the carriers are used to and that
they want for their their carrier
ethernet services here's basically how
it works we have a couple different
services if you look at a network a
couple things going on the first is that
we have three h which is a link level 0
am so this is designed just to
troubleshoot and diagnose problems on a
particular link let me move up the stack
and then we have service Oh am so
there's two two standards for this
there's a tour to that one AG and then I
tu y 1713 these provide end-to-end
service OEM so you can do things like
trace routes and pings and the other
thing is that the packets also take the
OEM packets take the same paths that
customer data takes so it's not anything
out of band it's actually an in-band
mechanism to do OEM and troubleshooting
and then the core of course we have IP
and mpls william i'm going to skip
through these because we kind of talked
about them the thing i want to point out
about 1730 one is that it's this
functionality is very similar to 80 to
that one ag and in some senses it's
competing standard the thing that 1731
as on top of that is measurement so you
can actually do SLA is now and you can
actually do end and latency testing to
see exactly what your customers are
seeing and in fact it supports hardware
timestamps so if you're routing
equipment supports that you can actually
get down to millisecond granularity on
round trips and delay so that's really
important for SLA monitoring and also
verification okay talk about data center
bridging so we talked about this already
a lot in the panel yesterday when we
debated trill versus shortest path
bridging so I just kind of summarize but
basically the driver for this is convert
virgins of sand and land fabrics and
there are a couple things you have to do
to make sand storage traffic actually go
over Ethernet and be happy so there's
two things and Donald said the same
thing yesterday there's really two
things there's data center bridging and
then shortest path forwarding which are
going to be combined technologies that
will use for a data center fabric this
is what people would like to do is a
converged network adapter which supports
both Ethernet and Fibre Channel over
Ethernet could be used in a data center
to send both fibre channel traffic and
IP traffic the basic idea of data center
Ethernet is that we have to change it to
make it carry fibre channel traffic and
fibre channel traffic has a couple
characteristics number one it's very
finicky and sensitive to latency and LA
so I was just talking about the ring
protection protocol which has 50
milliseconds failover well fibre channel
people kind of laugh at that because
they need about one or two millisecond
latency and failover and it just can't
tolerate any packet loss for Ethernet we
have tcp and IP which we put on top of
that so people were asking me well does
that mean that we have lost our net
today well no it doesn't i mean if you
put a packet on the wire if the hardware
is working correctly it'll come out on
the other end correctly what we're
saying is that fiber channel doesn't
have any retransmission mechanisms so
from its perspective Ethernet needs to
be lossless what fibre channel does when
the switch comes on the network is that
it negotiates with all the other
switches on the network and then they
actually reserve buffers and credits so
that they know exactly how much data
they can send to the network at one time
we just don't have that with TCP or IP
so we're really trying to make Ethernet
carry fibre channel traffic and that's
that's the the general idea here there's
three new enhancements which we'll talk
about in the next couple slides which
were also mentioned yesterday the first
is priority flow control this is
important because right now if you have
an ethernet pause frame it basically
stops all traffic on the wire so what
fibre channel needs is actually a
priority so PFC introduces a perk you
flow control mechanism so you can have
traffic flowing and say your highest
priority queues and you can
pause frame on the wire for the lower
priority queues and that would allow the
fibre channel traffic to continue to go
in case of congestion the other thing
that's important is intense transmission
selection was I think is a terrible
acronym but this is basically the
ability to group traffic together into a
higher priority group and a certain
bandwidth so like I said before when
fibre channel switches come on the
network they negotiate credits and
buffers and things like that this is
kind of trying to emulate that mechanism
so that fiber channel traffic knows
exactly how much you can send and
receive without losing your over running
any buffers and the last one is called
congestion notification this works
together with priority flow control when
there's congestion so it basically would
put a pause frame on the wire for that
cube and then it sends the congestion
notification to the ingress the ingress
gets it and says okay we're going to
rate limit that flow and then when the
congestion period is over then it goes
full throttle again it was a bunch of
references there that you can read them
out and then the last thing we're going
to talk about is shortest path
forwarding and there's really I think a
great panel and a great set of tutorials
that have already covered most of this
so we'll just kind of be brief but
basically this is the network today with
spanning tree and you notice that
there's a lot of red and we don't really
like that because it's really
inefficient you can do things with
multiple spanning trees to load balanced
traffic but it's really just difficult
to to do that and you know I don't think
anyone likes that and the other thing
too is that there's no no hop count so
with wire speed forwarding when there's
a loop in your network you know it's
going to board really fast the other
thing too is that during convergence
there could be periods of flooding and
when we have storage traffic on the
network that's really a bad idea so
flooding storage traffic not a good
thing and the storage people get really
unhappy when we talk about now this is
what we really want to do we want to
have a layer to multipath network that
has low sharing and also faster
responses to failure so a spanning tree
you have to go through this whole thing
with network recompute we don't really
like them obviously this gives us a lot
of improvements in utilization and
bandwidth efficiency and the good thing
is that is actually backwards compatible
with is exciting infrastructure you
could have a trill cloud that as
connected to a spanning tree cloud and
everything would be half there's two
standards there's true and shortest path
bridging which we both talked about in
detail I want to show this picture there
is ratty a Pearlman doing something very
interesting and then we fast-forward to
the summary this is the last slide I
want to talk about if you look at from a
technology perspective trill is really
being developed for the data center
right now I think we'll see it move into
other areas of the network after the
standard is done but right now it's
really developed as a data center of
fabric application shortest path
bridging has data center applications
but it's also designed since it works on
PBB it's also designed for layer to VPN
and carry Ethernet services the data
plane is a little bit different trill
actually has a trill packet that it uses
to encapsulate layer 2 frames and then
the mac address has changed on each hop
just like a layer 2 or layer 3 IP packet
is routed right now the data plane for
shortest path bridging on the other hand
is encapsulation of the original frame
into a backbone ethernet frame so it
doesn't actually touch the frame as it
goes to the network whereas trill
decrements the hop count and other
things as the frame goes the network the
control plane they're both based on is
is they have both have loot mitigation
trill has the hop count and shortest
path bridging doesn't RPF check they do
the cmp multicast you can use them with
data center ethernet and then really I
don't think that we see shortest path
bridging as a trend huawei and
alcatel-lucent have basically been the
only companies that I've seen talk about
shortest path bridging and I think
that's more for a metro ethernet or
layer two carrier ethernet service
application those two companies aren't
really strong players in the data center
so I think just from a market
perspective there's a lot more people
behind trill in the data center than
there are for shortest path bridging and
I think we'll see definitely trill
implementations as Donald mentioned
yesterday there's already a interrupt
belief event that happened in August at
UNH so that's good i think we'll see the
standard by the end the year standard
for shortest path bridging they just
went through draft 320 in june so it's
making progress but i think the final
standard is going to be middle to late
next year and then we'll see you know in
patient after that here's references and
that was it so that was 59 slides I
going to need a nap after this you can
breed we have time for some questions hi
Greg hey Ted let who ought there's
pushing p BB te know anybody I don't
know if anyone that's pushing it just
from our perspective we don't have any
customers asking us for pbbt and I don't
think we're going to implement it ok I'm
just curious thank you we do have some
customers asking us for pdb but no one
wants the thing about pbte that I kind
of skipped over is that all the
provisioning is manual and so I think
that adds a lot of complexity because
you have to have each so each switch
along the way it has to be provisioned
by the by the management agent so it's I
think open flow is kind of interesting
because it almost has the same kind of
concept where it wants to provision you
know each each flow along the hop so
there could be some interesting
applications but I don't have anyone
that's asking us for it in particular
cool thank you any more questions well
let's thank Greg again