can everybody hear me just to feel a
little bit the audience who here is in
offensive security mostly penetration
testing and red teaming raise your hand
defensive people raise your hand okay
and management I guess the rest well
basically we're going to talk about c2
environment so it's command and control
well
protect yourself against corona virus
one way to look at it so in essence
we're going to talk about c2 systems
what are the building blocks what our
standards let's say or basic c2
environments
advanced it to environments and
something what I call next-gen
environment which is my customized
environment for c2 systems so what are
the building blocks of a command and
control environment you can see that
basically it's a c2 server that has its
own communication protocols they execute
commands on infected hosts and obtain
data and results from these commands
then we have the agents and the implants
basically these are running on your
infected hosts and they have several
modules from persistence to other let's
say capabilities but the most important
one that they need to have is to avoid
detection and how they communicate
towards the c2 environment then we have
gateways and redirect errs basically in
an environment if we compromised an
environment we do not want to have so
many see two agents phoning back into
the c2 server because this will lead to
easier detection of your agents or your
c2 environment sorry okay so when we
talk about persistence we need to know
how to persist and when to persist so
how
a binary persist in your environment is
used through registry keys Windows
servers you can use library injections
like dll or Python libraries or dotnet
libraries if you're using some libraries
in your code or in your app you can
inject yourself in the firmware but also
you can use word templates Excel macros
and so on and so forth and one important
thing is communications so how do these
agents communicate back to your seat to
environment how they communicate with
the Gateway or how they communicate with
each other so the moment we have
persistence we're actually leaving bread
crumbs for the vendors to detect us so
even the blue team's the vendors so
anybody that's basically protecting or
investigating
you will leave bread crumbs so how do we
deal with it we use alpha station and
encoding to protect our binary or our
persistence or our agent so this reduces
the chances of us being detected by
typical endpoint systems so let's see
how a basic c2 environment looks like
you can spin it in a matter of minutes
so basically you can script it yourself
requires 1 c2 server which can be
deployed in the cloud or in your own
environment where your agents will call
back to and you're ready to go so
there's multiple things that you need to
do you need to find out let's say an
appropriate c2 environment in this case
you can use covenant there's a really
good example by a very good friend of
mine Federico he wrote his impressions
of this c2 environment in hack the Box
environment for for offshore and rest
elapsed so have a look at it it's really
good to see how this system works and
how you can move laterally using these
implants so the basic how it looks like
this is you as the sea c2 owner you're
issuing commands to your c2 server that
sends down the commands to the infected
host and the infected hosts return the
information back to the c2 environment
very simple so the problems here is that
your c2 is directly exposed to the
internet and it's easy to develop IOC s
because you have one source address and
basically it can be blocked on the
firewall or the vendor can develop
threat intelligence based on the IP
communication protocol and so on so now
we're going to look at a common
infrastructure what most of us are
actually using so you have your c2
server you have a server for payload
delivery you have your fishing server
that are not exposed to the Internet so
what we are doing in this case we are
using redirect errs to filter your
traffic and send it back to the c2
environment it's a much more effective
way in this case in case one of these
red directors get compromised you can
actually spin it up in a cloud
environment somewhere else you can use
Azure AWS Linode and so on and so forth
so the radio actors basically prevent
direct access to our environment so as I
said everything is happening here we
have our fishing server basically we
need to trick the user into clicking on
our payload for example we use web
servers to deliver this payload you can
use a web server FTP whatever not and
most commonly see to traffic and data
exfiltration traffic is over HTTP or DNS
protocol pretty standard so for redirect
errs you can use Janette's Apache H a
proxy phishing you have Go Fish
Kingfisher and so on and so forth
payload delivery again HTTP FTP DNS and
various c2 platforms so what are the
challenges here and the benefits of
using such an environment you can again
deploy it in minutes you can adjust your
threat vectors in minutes again you need
to write your own redirection rules so
basically you need to know how your c2
environment works once C to traffic
reaches your redirector you need to go
back
send it to the c2 environment if there
is a payload delivery you need to
redirect the traffic to the payload
delivery and so on so core
infrastructure is never directly exposed
this is good we can migrate as I said
initially though the Dirie directors
anywhere we want
it requires system admin maintenance
work and stuff like that so basically
you need to maintain the log files you
need to maintain your binaries every
time you create a new agent you need to
publish it manually so on and so forth
so basically it is a lot of work you
cannot avoid customization so this is
something what Harun said initially you
need to be good at coding to be
successful in your red teaming
engagement or in your penetration
testing because if you're using publicly
available exploits and tools they're
already signatures developed for it so
you need to know a way how to bypass and
customize your own code in order to get
code execution or bypass any edr systems
so and one important thing so once you
have all of these items working together
you don't have a centralized environment
to see what is really happening so if
somebody's clicking on your fishing link
you need to go to the web server search
through the logs if somebody is working
on the c2 environment you need to go to
the c2 server and get the log files and
so on and so forth so it's very
difficult to correlate so as I said
communication is the key so how do the
infected hosts communicate with the c2
infrastructure as I said DNS FTP HTTP
you name it you need to know how the
infrastructure you're targeting is
segmented so basically are there
multiple networks is a single network
are there any firewalls there what are
the protocols allowed between these
subnets so for example most companies do
not even segment their network properly
they allow anything to their firewalls
between the client and the server
environment at the end you will find
other companies that actually filter
surely between the client network and
the server network you need to know are
there any proxies in the network
deployed so basically is the traffic
inspected by HTTP proxy by DNS proxy and
so on what are the other things to look
out for like same systems are there any
logging is there any logging is there
any endpoint system deployed on the
machine and things like that so I would
walk you through a scenario so we are in
theme plankton I apologize I'm a very
big spongebob fan we are looking for the
krabby patty formula the burger it's
located on the application server
spongebob is protecting it and only
thing you need to assume is we
compromised the host so scenario number
one the firewall is blocking all inbound
connection but everything outbound is
allowed so basically we can use any
protocol to send data outside of the
situ environment also we can use any
protocol internally as there is no
filtering between the client and the
server Network you won't find this very
often but there are scenarios like this
and you can actually use anything you
want in this type of an environment
that's why I didn't put any
communication folks so we have the
second scenario basically where the
firewall is blocking everything inbound
but it's also doing outbound filtering
so what do I mean by double filtering
the server's don't have direct access to
the network and you have to move
laterally through a infected host so in
this case we're going to use HTTP to
communicate back to the situ environment
and we can use any protocol internally
in the network so again they will adjust
their security they will upgrade the
infrastructure and we need to do a
different way of communication and data
exfiltration so again we have a firewall
everything is again segmented that
protected only specific traffic can go
between the server environment and the
client environment so in this case we
can use SMB to move laterally through
the infrastructure so again we're going
to use
TPS to communicate back to a single host
and in this case we use SMB to move
laterally because you need to allow SMB
in an Active Directory environment so
your clients need to communicate the
Active Directory server or to the file
server basically SMB is allowed the
fourth scenario is when we have a
firewall that also does web filtering or
HTTP inspection or HTTP so in this case
we fall back only to DNS and everything
else stays the same so now the incident
response team deploys a DNS proxy so in
this case we basically cannot
communicate anymore because we've been
detected and everything stops well we
still need to access the carry patty
formula and the Burger of course so now
we are going into building the next gen
c2 environment so what does next-gen
mean basically we need to go the
environment we are targeting you need to
know your target and you need to know
what they have in their environment but
also you need to keep track of the blue
team's activities so we will speak about
it but also you need to know your
limitations and how to solve it so this
means you need to be good at coding you
need to know what you're doing so the
first step is to develop Deception
capabilities and offensive threat
intelligence so what do I mean by it
everything will come to your redirector
so you will have a lot of data so this
means botnets will access blue teams
will access your infrastructure
there'll be normal traffic c2 traffic
security vendors will access it
malicious users will access it basically
everyone so anyone can download your
code so what do we do basically we
develop an engine X module so I mean I
developed an engine X module that
accommodates me to serve the right
content to the right target so what does
this mean basically I can serve content
false contents to everyone except my own
target so my own target will see
malicious code this means I can redirect
content from security providers and give
them a welcome page or a landing page
while my client will download the
original in payload one other thing is
we connect to threat intelligence
sources so what do we do with these
threat intelligence sources is basically
as every binary that you are going to
send and all of your indicators are
compromised from IP addresses dns names
and everything else you can query I this
data with external partners so you can
use your hashes IP addresses fully
qualified on a domain names and you can
enrich your own data so what do I mean
enrich your own data so as everything
again is coming to your redirect errs
you can basically use shorten to query
the source IP address what it is you can
use gray noise virustotal otx talos IBM
x-force and so on and so forth it's very
very interesting concept so what does
this mean
basically in the module itself I will
tell you what I'm doing here all of my
fake content is on this server in my
environment I'm raising an alert every
time Raytheon or force point tries to
access my environment so these AAS
numbers belong to Raytheon so I know my
client is using let's say Raytheon DLP
and Raytheon firewalls and I'm raising a
separate let's say Alert for another
host so what what's the next thing I do
i define my customer I define the
payload server for this specific
customer and the IP address or network
range of the customer so this means that
I will allow my customer in this case my
target to access the real payload
content but if the same link is used by
anybody else it gets redirected to
another server here asbestos if eclis I
want to target Raytheon because if
Raytheon starts accessing my data that
means that the blue team is on to me and
that they're trying to basically capture
our malware
so very simple we also work on the
working hours of the client so basically
we know they work from 8:30 until 5:30
in UTC minus 8 times own so we know at
what time the client is working anything
happening outside is working our you
mean that they're trying to either
they're doing overtime but mostly maybe
they're going to reverse-engineer our
malware or our agent quite interesting
so what do I mean by it so if you open
the URL the customer a will see the
payload so this is a simple PowerShell
script but what will the others see is
the same URL they will look into nginx
or welcome page of whatever you want
it's very very useful to filter out and
not allow your client or the blue team
to get the hold of your payload so what
can we do we deceive blue team's for a
very long time so any time a blue team
tries to access your resource you're
actually deceiving them they don't see
the real content we can filter based on
IP address network range ASN number and
so on so basically also we can use
browsers time of day and we have
one-time download links so how does this
look we have an alert somebody detected
our IO C on ot X what is the agent
client and what is the hash file so I've
blurted it out so you don't see the
actual hash file so also we have another
visualization in E okay which means I
can track your activity history which
IOC is you've detected and which fishing
links have been clicked on again we are
always query external data sources so
this allows us to basically track the
blue team if they try to reuse
authentication keys so our agents
communicate with authentication key and
they only use it once so if there is a
reuse we will actually see it so this
means again that they're trying to
reverse-engineer our malware and
everything else is very well known
already I said it so I'll just have to
speed up a little bit what I mean by
reuse of keys so we can see again an
alert authentication key reuse detected
which agent source and so on and so
forth so we can see the AAS number the
geographical coordinates and the IP
address for this specific detection
second thing is we modify the agents to
communicate and blend in so what do I
mean by that the c2 framework is
optimized to use DNS and social media
and cloud services so basically we use
applications that you use in your
corporations like slack Microsoft teams
Skype for business Twitter we transfer
you name it and we modify the initial
stager to detect certain items in the
environment so when the stager comes in
it queries if we need persistence or not
or do we need access to that host or not
so this happens basically whenever the
persistence is triggered and it's
triggered by either a macro service or
whatever it's done based on activity so
what do we do we grab the OS type patch
level security software and security
settings of this endpoint and we use the
we detect or audio forensics forensic
tools as well so what do we do we
generate the grunt so this is carbon and
platform and we have specific agents for
slack teams Rob box social media and so
on so we will generate a grunt that will
utilize public services to avoid
detection so here you can see an agent
using slack and going to the slack URL
it's very very helpful so we never keep
the code on the affected host so that
basically means we only keep the small
persistence file we have one-time
download codes we query if we need
access and if we don't basically address
until it's called next time
the most important thing is to have self
destruct embedded in the environment so
what do I mean by self destruct we will
talk about it in a second payload for
every host is different and this means
that we can easily track which host
you're trying to investigate which
malware type you're trying to
investigate which agent which
persistence and so on so we have another
alert in E okay so here is redline so
what does the agent do it tells us here
are detected memory forensic tool I'm
wiping out the data and basically it
raises an alert in ALK we get alerted
about it so we know they're trying to
investigate this host and we do it for
basically a lot of tools from redline
volatility we basically know everything
in this case we have a highly customized
DNS server basically it uses the same
rules as we define in our redirect errs
and our deception we use it to
communicate one-time download keys and
you can see it here so what we do we
just define the deception is true we
have the settings that you will serve
these fake entries to it to the subnets
we wanted to serve the real entries and
the real servers the c2 servers will be
here behind so basically again if anyone
is trying to access our name servers
they will see fake entries so we can
serve whatever we want to serve and to
the Intendant user to the intended agent
we will serve the real content
what is the backbone of this elastic
stack so we use all of these tools so
every single tool is basically sending
log files to a centralized system so
think of it as a seam for red teams okay
so all data from c2 systems
fishing redirect errs everything is
store correlated
we enrich everything by using threat
intelligence from all the vendors so
basically we have paid subscriptions but
we enrich the data why do we do it
it's easier to generate documentation
for your client engagement so I don't
need to think about who moved laterally
when what was the keystroke what was the
password entered by the user where is
this stored all the screenshots are
present there so basically you have a
complete history who has done what in
the environment and I'll just walk you
through a quick engagement what what
what is the scenario we targeted a
software development company so their
management wanted us to test their
systems it was a black box engagement
and a long-term operation so what we've
done is we surveyed the environment for
about three weeks and we stay five
months undetected in their
infrastructure what did you do basically
we use open source intelligence we
gathered enough data about our target
using LinkedIn Facebook reddit github
and so on we found some interesting
let's say posts and we obtained code
execution in a way that we sent them
through the forum basically a fix for
their problem so we fixed their dotnet
issue dotnet library issue but we
introduced a call back so we surveyed
the hosts we deployed custom payload we
surveyed everything else in the network
their behavior we moved laterally and we
got to the corporate data and the source
code what was hosted on their
environment so this is basically how it
looks like so what we did we use we use
slack to send C to information outside
so slack is allowed on their layer seven
firewall you can move through it easily
we used SMB to access the backend data
center and we extracted the data out
they didn't see anything irregular in
their environment so we didn't use a
custom HTTP page or custom protocol we
actually used a protocol that was
allowed in their network and an
application that was allowed
we could have done similarly with teams
with Skype for business SharePoint
onedrive you name it and throughout
every engagement throughout every move
we actually monitored the threat
intelligence so did they upload anything
to two-wire store role with the upload
anything to IBM has IBM accessed our
website or has any other vendor
basically accessed the theory directors
or access our content so at the end we
had long term persistence for about five
months what did the blue team see or the
security provider nothing everything was
normal for them we serve them deception
data fake content false DNS responses
false HTTP data they did not know what
was there so basically throughout five
months of engagement we deceived
everybody in the environment and there
was nothing they could do about it so
what are the lessons learned things are
not always shining so you will find
various different things so everybody
uses different security tools you have
to be careful how you open files that
you find so as Haroon previously stated
if you open a file it's a Word document
he has embedded canneries he can see so
if we use containing containers or
isolated informations or sand boxes to
open this content you cannot see it
getting to note the customer IP is a
painful process for several reasons what
if they're using cloud-based DNS servers
what if they use code base that proxies
okay basically three more minutes
excellent so there are ways to detect
the real IP address of your client but
it can be a painful process always have
one agent to communicate back to the
infrastructure because if we run
multiple c2 agents and they call back
basically the firewall will pick it up
the blue team will get alerted and you
won't do anything
to that we had quite a interesting time
basically identifying security vendors
not only by the a s or a 8 IP prefix but
also if they're using any cloud services
or or other addresses basically to
investigate a security threat so it was
deeply disturbing to identify certain
vendors developers are easy targets
they always need special rights so
basically they're always coding they're
always compiling they need debugging
permissions they need to execute a lot
of binaries and they use a lot of
libraries basically sometimes even from
unverified sources and most importantly
as I said you need to code and you need
to learn how to adapt and solve puzzles
so you will not be successful unless you
can adapt to the environment what can we
say about blue teams we you can get the
seed for a very long time you will not
even know about it look for deviations
in your traffic so basically if you see
an increase in SMB traffic from a host
and in the application for a say in our
case it was slack this should have been
your indicator that something is wrong
in the network always micro segment so
filter out all unwanted traffic
everywhere in your network work with
your developers in the company in in
this case raise awareness for using
libraries you can find research on this
topic as well
red elk is an excellent concept
any questions
[Music]