so okay wait of whom I before I worked
at in in this as security I worked for
eight years as a Java developer after
walking around with those crazy folks I
decided it was his time to dedicate
myself to something something serious I
built the first BMX tricks entered in a
weekend such a fun project as usually
someone calls me and says that has
something that he can't do in I do or we
should do it just because I can
objectives few times some time ago I
read something on a blog saying that I
asked for time girls when you try to
crack passwords from other people you
get better edit it sounds weird so I
decided to test that for myself one of
the issues that i found one up when i
started this was that blind brute force
takes a lot of time it usually goes
around trying use the huge word list
bringing that sign to work on
permutation of stuff and this consumes
time over time I also notice that this
besides efficiency you stop repeating
yourself and usually when you start
thinking about this you want to go the
other way around so less words try not
to repeat yourself remove the duplicates
and as you go on with this you start
noticing that you need more information
about the hashes re or the person that
you're cracking it then the crash within
the hashes itself so when somebody says
that s you I've heard recently that you
don't need an expression they're gonna
password because if it's a strong cost
but nobody want nobody will find it
nobody chooses a strong password not
even we so that's why won't say the red
word so usually people choose passwords
or
on their personal information their
interests their native language blogs
visited websites all this can be
compiled into word lists and your end if
you use restrictions you will reduce
that word list even more so all this
source of information and the source of
the words in the targets information
will compile itself into a word list i
repeated myself are here so my use case
i have google around and I found a
website that was kind enough to publish
all the user information including the
ashes I won't say that it was a
university and yeah it was a fun to find
thing because they have 15 years 15 uses
in there the ashes wall out there I
actually I think they still are and the
some of them were actually professors so
I decided to use this so my first step
was identified the algorithm create the
users create word list based on news and
information and here was my hardware
this tools everyone knows and knows this
one advantage of using the cpu although
by the end of this I've noticed that the
CPU is really something you can get as
it was so to efficiently use the brute
force he can build this I built this
square which is basically lowercase and
uppercase the digits and I've shuffled
around with this try to reduce the
number of permutations with stuff like
this start with the uppercase try the
middle of your lower letters because
it's easier to remember and Edwin end
with numbers because we all know how
people choose their last date something
like that the results were something
like this and you'll notice that some of
these numbers are actually in Social
Security numbers okay so what's keeping
fast
i have i have a two minute long board in
my house so when time once things start
to get tough i usually do this this
small designs what i'm trying to do here
is establish a pattern between the
number of layers in the password and
their components and time and the time
that i need to go over all the
permutations some of the permutations i
have here went from 10 to 10 seconds to
2 hours or in seconds okay so okay
what's not the proximate then this is
last step when you go over all this and
you start all over the brute force yeah
is not the person right magnify show the
last 100 well the last one was actually
the last one was that I managed to crack
all the all the passwords in the the
total number of hours that he's not
included crack all the 15 passwords were
still two hours basically and the last
one had 14 14 karat