every year
so
nomination most
stuff in the US eyes are
things you
use this walk after you basically want
weird so
these locks as you probably already here
really
back amassed locker
three dollars but just the way there
basically
sisters CMOS
world ever you know the more you start
walks notice water everywhere an
important step
or equal version here
so
me going back
we make have March and basically worship
is way that this poll places
spring peace when you dial in
combo long shackle doing is pieces
freedom
back there's many other ways you can
open the shackle
without working this really beat up
with with basically every conference
ever
so what's really funny Sophia actually
just push the peace
way shackle retracted again this is a
block same concept applies to a brand
new one
may be harder to push directly the pic
also monster
again first shames
question is is we want to be able to
display shop
thing that retains the shop essentially
what we're doing dialed allowing these
pieces to disconnect
shop make
shares
alright naturalistic
to mention the reasons why these workers
spring just
knows pulled because it's not a speck
them in the case locks lol
open is a few dollar college again and
field there you go
but users
you up
way to
okay
star up
good
two-inches' very things here
peace picture and eventually good
right sure market
just
16 and you can make
marks
mark Nick
wanna make very edges
used don't route
nice Shea all basically 12
search it Terry here's okay and actually
here
slightly thicker I think this actually
orange juice
a little and
are here
little
or it works the problem is
I mean that's what the mass production
their best right steel
course they're using very big machine
hooker
re: I think the zip
basic like this at all ready black
your wallet where with if the need ever
arises
person matter if the need arises
all just show you turnip
p.m. old
the first step is your fold it down to
that satellite use the lines you drew is
a guide
for legs ramzi
was also helps reinforce the handle
history like world
edges around picture sure parts
yeah
and then what you can do it you just
want to make this round's
it's the curvature shackle you do with
the shackle
you do with hand in everything just
nice rounds
here
now if you look at it now it'll make
more sense why the edges rockers
really flat edges to be easier for this
middle East
care not household
up
so you can view is
ish shocker retainers on the side
obviously you know that beforehand
sometimes each to ship both sides double
word
little other have lost touch these these
once a single
so here
hitch
ours turning around its
in between shackle up
good rip
so happens to be doing wrong care the
shame
obvious you black jail it happens
expect another gonna make
on make so that happens
and of a box have a bunch Shin
second first
up
yeah has been spent
one
something there
up
is that it's also possible to the club
by feel now
with this method you don't get the
combination directly when the shackles
hoping you could actually
figure out published by poking and
prodding inside but
there's also a way to do it just by feel
without making tools
not worried about shames obviously takes
a little bit more time
issue sitting there but I'll but it's
just as effective
Katie pretty quickly one
funny thing is that easier so poorly
made that they actually make it easier
for you
than you might think so there's forty
numbers on a combination 00:02:39
so you know we have three numbers are
combinations
many combinations be a lock brake all
theoretically law but the way it works
is that
when you down your combo to come with
10-20 third
you can probably dial 9
30 11 2013 variations that reach number
between because the way this works is
that has a certain tolerance
so that you don't have to dial exactly
correctly on the line every time to make
it will be easier
more user-friendly so we can use this to
reduce
the key space essentially and these
locks they have a really big tolerance
I think it's something crazy like plus
or minus two the actual number you want
to work
so in actuality it's 240 numbers we have
I'm basically slightly
you know given to some variants but
about ten members for dial
what we can also do is exploit problem
Skype locked let's just figure out what
are the numbers right away
so if we know one another the numbers in
the combination and the other two wheels
lamp 10
possibility each we only have a 100
company to try
reports really quickly and there's some
more advance
mathematical stuff that you can do to
figure out even faster
but the basic idea is that you gonna
pull on the shackle what pulling on the
shackle does is it directly
tries to push the retainer into the
gates inside
we'll talk more about how these work
internally we get to see wats by
such as little wheels with gays when you
can you put the gate
right position we pull the shackle were
pushing against those gates
trying to turn the dial fine or stop
I can't turn the dial more than from
about 26
tours 27 and so
okay we know that we can go from 26 to
27 like go
a little bit all again the next part we
get stuck in
is 29 and a half 230
30 in so you gonna do this all around
the dial
wannabes more gaps different so what
these are
falls gates if you just trying to pull
there were no gates you would just be
able to click install the correct
positions
issue pushing the peace directly wheels
so with this post
try to make it hard to manipulate but it
actually has the effect letting us just
figure out
last number of combinations right way so
again I'm not considered
all the way but you're gonna all Shack
write all this down
and then up these or gaps one of them
will be in how to wire
bigger be smaller it varies depending on
brand
model that in the master locks it
typically a slightly bigger
day and that's because they want to be
easier for you to find you'd
I'm has after you have that lets say are
numbered
is 6 down six all
the the other two numbers we offsets for
from the number six because the way the
mass-produced
so what you know the last number six
you're gonna die I'll 006 046 you're
just gonna run through the 100
combinations really quickly
and ideally find it within 50 and Allen
50 nations
pretty quick and then you would have the
combination
be able to come back so it it takes
patience and practice
the first time you do it will be the
hardest if you do it once
every subsequent be here so there's a
lot of these on the table
you guys wanna practice just start by
pulling on the shackle
finding all these okayed figuring out
which one is different
and therefore yep then you can try the
other
nations up don't care about the
collisions said which basically just
makes them
for us harbors to maintain that pressure
as rotates around inside look and I have
week grip so I use all players I'd
you know stutter when you tried and now
should be pollution do below and yes
try this on the site tried nice
lock yet but ones I have a her little
bit lesbian up
but you know is very easy just you
what i'd can 30 yup
yeah yeah nicely and I think I'm
grosses but if anyone else has been
drinking a coke and what just
wash the sickness away gets me that yep
really good
the other fun stuff
sesame arts or just you know they're
there another for combinations box
but observed
but that's because probably the most
popular
brand in the US law successfully so yeah
previously okay
so these are very similar just
three wheels four wheels number
unlike obviously the dial one yes
individual tiles for individual wheels
in the way these work is that when you
whole the shackle
these discs are physically blocking you
turn on the right positions
it's very similar o'clock it's just a
different way of doing it
I'm I would say that these are
considerably easier to manipulate
I'm just based on their design don't
need to worry about tiling and
making sure you dialed sequence that's a
big problem for
for people who use a fox losses dollar
with this
he said 123 or whatever I'll way this
works
pretty much the same movies here you
put pressure on the shackle some you
have to push down but I think
we own you pull up you pull up
test each wheel so if you
don't fall movies we'll very freely when
you poll
the shackles gonna be pushing against
one or more up wheels
at right now so when you try and turn it
to see this one moves justice really
this one is a little bit harder this was
really hard so what that is
shackle lining up against you should
wheels a different way
and just like when we work with the were
locked each of these wheels
mind in sequence because the way the
shackles pushing up against it can
really
be manufactured against all up same time
so where you could use work each wheel
individuals poll
I found that the first one gives less
resistance an attorney
Hill you looking
place so long as
also important whenever you look at
these urged a magic J shape
especially with the shackles is starts
way up here goes round
just like that and so on havel on this
site shackle
is course to model which is that
possible with little
fluctuations those last for two shins
you know course are being blocked by
these gates just sold smile
but when these are aimed at corrects
number
of course the whole games United
you have this little gates right here at
this flag is trying to
through it care right so tall rotates
there's the gate is exposed and the flag
temperatures will rape
30 really easy
I know I didn't say anything cuz all I'm
doing is just pulling in turning
things like in a place you can all do
this he's
you guys to pass around
as obviously four wheels takes a little
bit more effort
and three wheels but there's actually
the same thing real
such as on the shackle
find which we or this resistance and
Internet
you look like see if the next we'll his
first
and saw next is
saves safe boxer essentially big boy
versions me walk very similar
all and we have a bunch other
matter what a boxer look very different
I
and most to them work on the same
principles to this one you have a dollar
bottom
in a big pot so instead of pulling off a
shock all or persons shackle you push
the button
directly increase you feel you get
here expect skates we have a couple the
you play
for this was actually easier to just
here
dial caliper just squeeze it
well you're manipulating any feel about
lower and lower
until it opens shared test this one in
particular is called national
axis national one different names in
different countries
has urged dictate speed
believed and
social joystick what you do value up
down left right
whatever is actually I in theory heard
fermentations at a certain point you
reset everything given point of 23
movements forest
becomes Nani so you can put whatever you
want was
back up it varies
a randomized sup use this like its four
like down up down down here that's
acting are you see prairie complex
inside its kinda hard to explain
essentially every time you this moving
five different things
so happens that in a bit that front but
not here
all that does is Moo this place and
probably can't see it from there but
this place has many many
little protrusion those projections
go around these
specially shaped dis that pusher
as well and so he's got like a strictly
smell or it
you can kinda see if you move up on us
you know we all knew
up a certain amount and then go down a
move a certain you
up go to that push go down
them inside so these are designed that
has a striptease
going any side of them will move them
pre describing their
all or happen so you can pass that
around your
make Street yep but it's actually really
ingenious cool design if you want to
know more about it there you just restin
yeah ship years they all turn together
wanna know more about you can go to tool
.nl and they're actually little visual
visualization tool just and flashing
can't play with it you can see how the
internals all so
is everything about sex
seats are very similar but also very
different same basic idea
number wheels past
where the ideas you've number wheels
and their brought by the dial positioned
correctly
arm up on top all gates
obviously inside
are several your it's called the wheel
and then on the back
what's known as the drive cam so the
drive cam is directly connected
spindle stacked dial much you
movies wheels to and fro and if you look
to see the big cut out
is the gate very similar to the old
many paradox but obviously made a lot
nicer at a metal
classic young
our world
the basic mechanism by which openness
you start
position all wheels so that their true
gated
harmony arms called the fence that he
said the arms
defense use couple ever and 11 knows
which is the point part as well
interfaces with the track here
started Hills
all all their case here when you read
drive back have rooms
knows lever pollen what's up
retractable with the drive and I believe
the plastic one has come forward
I'll 6
have number ratings typically when you
buy
hardware store usually by
fires so safe sir distinguish between
being
fire resistant or element or
burglary resistant that's what most
people don't nackt
they go sage berkeley well not
necessarily
the Sentry Safe I resisted not burglars
and it's also worth noting is an answer
in the IT field
a fire resistant safe probably is not
require system for electronic media such
tapes that certain things
all the title see old Thursday's likable
a backup tapes
right no fire comes they're still gonna
be hot enough to
Diaz so happen fires the
I did
is material allied see ways
fired
which keeps the papers from reaching
him to: their user
number him electronic
yep
yeah and i'm looking about all the
ratings but there's just a number
group that great saves in the US it's
typically underwriters laboratory
well you well 768 media the standard
for safe walks in this country Europe
its and
yes in a number of organisations product
so it seems can be attacked in a number
of ways
today we're just talk about manipulation
rock
talk about fun stuff like thermal access
even on their
or blowing brother on
up I because that's no fun right
past all fun to watch but
what you do once manipulated however is
quite and
on
no quotes
I will tell you so when you dial
combination
this fence and lever here
are spring loaded down they want to go
into the true gates
but they can only do that when all the
gate sir i want I can only
all the way down when all the gates
underneath the facts
but how can we expect that you'll notice
if you pick up all the wheels by turning
one direction over an overkill
pick up one two or three wheels pick up
all the emails you still hear that noise
what annoys here one sec
click what that is what that is
actually bands next lever knows
falling down camp there you could feel
and right now you here possibly not
all between you and the law you can feel
that
on the dock your that point and visually
you can identify where these two points
are should be each side at the drive cam
K this side is thats
seven and three-quarters
three-quarters to sting decide
that 65 entry missile area
here what happens
is when you take all the
we'll tak just turned into an arbitrary
location you come back
your those points are you probably get
that same reading
back for but when there's a gate
underneath the fence you will be able to
drop just a little bit lower
now there's no material there just like
are other come along just like
somewheres tolerances with all these
wheels with the lever
the picture you have three wheels like
this now they're not all going to be
perfectly level
one could be a little bit higher one of
the desks a little bit over certain
points higher
the offense itself could be a little bit
better offenses like this
think which these things first so all
these at a
just like an lock to this idea
we're gonna be able to identify when a
gay
is under the pants by visual and visual
feedback on the dial dollars tangible be
back with you
field points there's a lot to take
something you really need to sit down
and you it's hard to explain
it's hard to understand but way it works
is that has you
borges defense that
levered is able to go lower and lower
and obviously when all the right
position
all the way down so by picking up all
the wheels
stop 0 when you come back
test that point it
test that point all the way around the
time by taking diagnostics
identifying how hard Oct 14 go
gay here you can identify where the
wheels are
and that's because as you get wheels
under this
lever go lower as it goes lower into
this be shaped
it has less movement back for
think the dynamics of this as you go
lower
back class there's also other ways to
tell for example it's not only
when do you go lower but also the way
that this design
the lower a little higher the bomb
there's a lot of different things with
you to crack say
good hard
are there any questions I know it's hard
to it listen to you
you really should sit down with the
cutaways play with it to learn more
and also who has last piece
no questions there is a master of
so
jonathan is my safe as a lever on it
open
door so what that is either a you have
what's called direct drive safe
where the lever physically pushes into
you the lever on the door
physically pushes into you wheels or
physically pushes into the bolts can't
fully turned into a ball to this type
walk is your check never waste because
sometimes the
the act you might wanna you know most
you're safe really have a lot of walking
points very big balls
and turning this little dial just a
little bit not do it
that's right secondary handle tackle is
it like a sentry safe and
second probably drop which is easier to
manipulate
because you just like these combo locks
physically push yourself in the case
to get the other questions
I am
the question was what are the
differences between different brands
safe locks homes a
Commission yes go to recombination I
so there's differences between the big
boys like sergeant really
Lagarde Diebold Nosler
but for the most part every time you go
like the same kind town you're probably
going to be fine this
exact law just the standard sergeant
Greenlee block and the standard box from
the other companies are all very very
very similar
they very if not almost minuscule like
almost nothing except logo on the back
will be different I am
the real differences when you you wanna
buy high-security say
or lower scores such as century yard
sec or any number of fire seems
which people don't associate with not
being resist
I'm so one example we have this
is surgeon greenleaf the 400
they also 8500 which I think personally
way this works
is that you can see the cam looks
considerably different
shoes AP story here so what that is
arms together to physically block that
little part on the cam
from being accessible by the lever until
you have to practice
nation and so it doesn't stop you from
taking diagnostics
but it does the point is to make it much
longer
so we rate see fire or
terms it terms like you can't
say most saves the their
10 minutes or 15 minutes 30 minutes I'm
all the way up to 20 hours an hour so
could be one guy working hours together
hours I'm this I believe israeli for
tap
its allotted
yes because these
standardized you write you l
or the other standards organizations to
say this is passed
this many hours whatever you lockpick
drilling or fire resistance I now
you may have doubts as to whether or not
standards companies actor
test which is a big thing with box
whether or not
it's really 15 minutes resistance
because
they may not radio as other people
standardized
testing but for the most part
I think all say with this order
law because US Army their hours
well first off there in the door area
that safer another thats
their rating
I'm actually just as quick note sorry if
you're passing it around
make sure not butterfly switch with
upside down because the
then the whole Hartl actually yet don't
put that what's up
just like you have make it the back is
up and then
it the other way of all this used to
having a black
yeah your open up
really
range numbering being yes
ok guys with really yeah
his and he acts loved
yeah he doing yeah the question was
one in the ratings mean those are on
writers say
and they have a code system that'll tell
you really quickly if you understand
when it should be rated
or so Intl stands for tools jack stands
for
explosives I don't know all patients
yep
I think he arched orange an actual
notice of that state law
that's what we call group one are safe
what's the group one refers to them
relations and the are on there actually
if you notice
those discs are not men they're actually
very
or Rep and gathered or so basically what
happens
is if you were to use a x-trail not be
able to see the positions
the dates are saturated for history
lodged I also just be whether or not it
s
against mean on the margins our
apartment
yeah I do what if you were looking
forward to seeing you
yes you don't need whatsoever behind the
same he might be slightly
Osbourne evident during FBI its
considerations nonetheless
this lock
I am that actually is no longer
production their place that would
500 series and actually used to be the
GSA
recommended approval and they've
actually done away with these
if you want to be GSA approved for
much any hi scary top-secret they have
what's called the
hablamos exxon it's basically
your help so basically
its it all electronic its
as a base to happen go up to it you need
to spend first
to generates electricity so it will be a
run
and then there's lots and lots of
different
action safe lock introduces like for
example one thing is
you look at how circle of course work
they're very precise
just being running like that very
very quickly so can detect those motions
okay
servo motor sale he also knows when
you're trying to say
block how teachers think right you turn
it like this
pulitzer about their handwriting these
replace and turn to get
so we'll actually no okay so if this I
was rotating a certain amount
was impossible for him to do so you know
set up this has to be some sort of robot
and it's actually
when I saw this before was kinda
fighters want
oh that's why alike sucks are you
exploit and so what happens is he had
one is on his workplace
course he refused was but every morning
he would go up to it and of course look
at that turned a bit
in order to charge because that's how
you know you induce a chartered
which is nice as you're not lying on
batteries up
what happens every day got block our
owners
to make it really quick to generate that
charge the problem was
every so often shutdown yep week 10
minutes to get in
as the recent this it would
attacked okay this I mean turn way too
much
shut down it also when you turn it you
know to go
27 28 29 and then you can't stop
thinking point
no different action it will go 29-28
it'll star completely randomly and will
just be
yeah sixth for problem well
law yeah there's lots of other
protections it's basically if that's a
flop
on whatever your containers block no
longer
week yep
at the moment track him Obama's
X other fun stuff have for
for Tampa resistance is that relevant
all
p inside lock with party
as you part lock take
you be all particles
arrest there's ever a problem compares
lock also arms
the IC's
have temp
reached up
K the
space X
elsa 07
eights various problems up
yep any other questions about
alarms certainly
actually just released what they
consider
but honestly I don't think it's up
carries
the biggest selling point hey it's made
in the USA
yeah in if viewer concern
frequent really between
walks and normal rhetoric
I no electronic box
3d much stock so I'm working on some
stuff right
have fun like most basic and Muslim
store
like your your all your your
combinations
like the supervisor nation plain text on
the chip
you have all sorts bike trek last
Mike Taylor yep dial
I'll week
buzzing accent you middle said
I'll back on over one nice thing
with blood loggers mechanical
always a little bit various so if you
dial
the combinations 62 you go 62 and
maybe 63 would still kick Center
the same number that you're getting
combination additional saying look
62 there is no there's no
3x your soup
walks have electronic features
don't dollars
the other he's
were military-grade box this once
okay this one step now and they work
much like side force week
are struggled go on at least three
millimeter plate steel
sites actually were most commonly used
if you going back very sick
we're issues plate on the back
sure dial number
fixed dials all number
to be changed after with the dollar
same for the Packers is side and this
one actually a shiny
since meant to kinda give a little
timbre at
behavior so there's a sort of tools that
were made
there's a greater temperature stop
weird
questions walks
up like
still
start
and if you wanna see the how the speed
dial works
I reassemble this onesie as the old
up