okay
up my thoughts on nom is it all just
SMS viruses on and we would not or we
actually seeing real advances in Android
malware
take a look at numbers actually I will
be okay here now I'll
basically exit use to be pretty much
most in our but right now we're seeing a
lot of new things like a
spyware receded pups leader potentially
unwanted programs
a spyware your hacking tools your own
various some Mian Lee actually the
program so we may know one on on device
bench thinking about 50 percent we have
a great how the right now
but look at the actual break down when
we got there %ah
yes SMS premiums in the SMS sending an
hour still there
oh we've got things like from getting to
the good guy X button
using tools and quite a bit of things
and send the information to people
to the attackers so people know what's
on your phone we question how many
people of you have them both times
ok it's no majority rule pretty much has
an Android phone
pretty much all you guys can be infected
by
carjackers you're coming from basically
on russia and China
as long as you're not going to alarm
we're sticking to the official Android a
play market
were play with words alternate Google
Play home
you're pretty much can avoid a lot of
what's out there I'll take a look at it
she's the man the actual tax them
now we know there is not exist there
what what's what's actually attacking
years as in what
getting older what are these guys the
bad guys attackers were the action using
on your system
where you can get a whole is not only do
it once they're there
I'll okay but that's nice
the it PDF yeah alright
okay actual tucker tricks I wanna got
here
are asking to sing before he could get
the simple inscription like Ghana
obfuscation mom we just got like the SMS
number something simple like that or
like this
with simple so positions over three
other configuration file as ago we could
call it something mean that simple very
basic
they got up from nap their really do a
lot more these base using
DS NDS in cambodia traffic
are your command control command I'll
did its Italian
miss your personal data like your IMEI
or would you write an offer for your
phone
I'll you're you're basically you're
you're you're in some cases your Google
what Calgary Alberta Calgary cool
accountant
information gets 14 and equiped allow
this is because the attackers are
worried about
other attackers basic okay you got a
botnet I got a bonnet
he's got a bonnet much like joe said
earlier about the five-wicket on one
machine
if you're infected you don't want some
I'll take your information you want to
basic pushed him outta there
and you can make sure everything to be
going over the network and
within the fun took the minor
I but now the big thing though is the
up-front basically I'll
waterfront happen what do you what you
can do in frogmen a mixer sure it did
your have an application that could be
we'll could be fake
it basically pretend to be fake and
Kenley they have
mostly the code is made up of just the
militia Moshe Katsav not like actual my
county that make you do anything
iomega potentially be an alarm Elena
came out maybe ten to be your man your
security of your bank
i in the case a pic talk in particular
it is it going to be like Windows the
you type in your password and you get
your arm
key code for the next transaction which
works out well for the attacker but it
doesn't do anything
other than that but bush at the end
button which is really close to my page
number
here okay a case in point of a token
this pretends to be a kik illegally the
akiko thing or a key code took in Los of
tokens like an hour say to him
legally the car with a rope you know but
it changes every minute or so
in in this case you in your pure passer
document that cocaine
and insane when it does it to be good
your big number
and it to forward the password needed
activities account over to the attacker
sneaky useful and the course be safe or
any not doing a little work here it all
in Java
it's basically just to put together an
interface for you to see what's going on
and stealing information from them in
your things open more advanced something
like %ah
you want one click fraud family why one
click fraud it did seem a two-piece
email or where you got my car a drive-by
download where you go to a
the or visit the website and boom me
back a girl
%uh dollar-billion the dollar how to
make up the system one could force to
move up
exhibit actually a is an adult
entertainment app
handed pretends to be like I sensed
charging for a observation notes and get
a porn site
and keep asking for money looks like you
know if you've seen top markets like a
lot this monster
350 every five minutes
I am it keeps going up it also is also
won the ones actually goes up your
Google account information what is a
Google account information
your Google Account good ties into your
Gmail ties into your I'll
with Flickr new I figure the David
Picasa possibly I forget exactly what
Google's a initiate
follies are gmail your your Google+
account
arm be with everything that can be
accessed by with a Google account
you're setting up an attacker I don't
begin text includes the bathroom not on
a person's certain
no not the possible does have been like
a unique identifiers which is useful
because they've is still my guess
however a large amount every five
minutes from you
few been put in say but I thought I paid
for them and by nearly forgot you came
again
mom in these are going to happen with
fraud on on phone
can you have your machine
over dumb enough to not pretend to be
something else to turn on/off tubing
could you not love you have an iPhone
comedienne you have ever gonna
propagation
supposed to be something it didn't quite
work a bit not there was a good game
didn't quite work out on you do it away
me tailgaters on a stolen handbook
people have done that occasionally
more likely be wearing pick up anything
because a lot of bad games other
not programmers were not immediately not
bad good in some certain cases though
dues bad programmers or mackey malicious
and they are just giving you a
sorta semi game that isn't quite there
I'll
much is going on we're coming for us is
a good look at the
in checking code I'll get back to the
point where where the applications are
actually
not not quite good be this is a
addicting code is gently when you have a
gym application to me it doesn't
properly
an entity Congress that would be a fun
outings is pure fraud
meaning just designed just for getting
information out of you
these were basically actual obligation
to do something that night
in this case a give USB for a running
through
very nice very useful app a relapse but
it has coded into it emotions got itself
isn't going to sting
I Mauer Android I believe its macabre
got a ezer file infecting virus
mother few 100 bucks to be the only one
hundred action
what is actually do YouTube wheelers
over X files that are Shia
searches your entire arms SD card for
all your your photographs everything
India
basic emigre be all your phone about
their and it basically stamp the picture
of the year
a.m. deceased I talk a meanie on
each year photos basically photo bombing
and all your family photos and fun
pictures and whatnot
with the title communing beautiful right
and didn't bomb it it's kinda buddy I
mean I think he does the code injection
it's mostly the poop do things are based
the old all class files from the
original lineup
%uh investor be up the majority the code
a small percentage does exactly just
listening
adding the ayatollah khamenei to your
your your legal
your photos everything we're photos kind
of annoying
it's also kinda buggy cuz I mean you
figure over the years people have
learned like I did last 20 years a
llamar
if you're suffering from Marseille at
ever
I guess a MS DOS or something it people
knew how to write or already factors you
know
you in fact the file you leave a marker
summers you can tell that the pumping
effectively don't we in fact over and
over again
it can go to bed shop here with this
where the FU
got went in and did something in the
active code like like such
we actually fight over the whole
according to NBC got the following in
this this function within the file
handle each individual with Gabe a file
it's damp together your original file
with the arm it was on the smaller one
it's down together this fall over here
on to whatever phone you have but they
don't need any with Mr Mark output it is
that what happened here original file so
that when they did it again
so we're end up doing is continuing
continue continually
stamping out his this is on top your
pictures and causing damage your files
an increase in the file size there are
multiple multiple times you both place
in SD card
and be keeping very noticeable I
what I don't know if so nervous though
unlike always knows whether
this enough and a diet or something he
titled I'm not sure
is an actual example with the looks like
you see original love me
image of %uh Flickr a big Creative
Commons article at no license says we
can modify do whatever you like we did
so we're at it in our inner Miller's he
wouldn't elaborate we know kinda what
happens but no
basic title for a bomb the bomb and then
because you can check the file
he still does it and will you endorse
the back on its getting lighter in my
delight or not that's good
am this follows the first impression
this is somewhere in the third or fourth
this is sir 56 summer further on
by this time and the fourth one it's now
before time flies
and it's starting to fade away your acct
Obama gonna disappear from a missile
like that seem to bring back a future
where money is disappearing kisses
these guys are going to get okay real
reference okay but nom
the point is he ate
disbelief anybody they are still really
well cuz it's a fresh copy every time
but the original pocketed more more
damage than you see losing a loved this
place
it's kinda kicking it is thank you
because it is
the kinda money that use ticket pictures
guy in a bit when your photos
but I mean it's it's it's gonna be
retained because they didn't do it right
they didn't figure out how to make sure
they're not continue infecting
'em
where am I going with that but you could
be another at Notre basically are
recording audio
recording are you on on on on mom
from the your phone device been with
numbness not by the top but I don't how
that's because you don't have that phone
audio
are getting permission for them this is
the
becoming more and more common it's
basically you recording two things one
is that the team after touchdown to
YouTube on your phone like a
your PIN numbers your credit card
numbers are things like not
om we've seen that initial use only like
in an
no busy approve a concert academic
happen and inspire where
so back to the potential I programs
they're not really wanted their spyware
we've seen all over the place
but known to be seen in malware people
are really attacking your phone is in
Ocala goblet Leo
and he's not back in general the first
academic programs that came out more
deserts and commerce online everything
the other trademark issue
it because some colour art thou colmer
up
basically listen for the audio from your
phone it had like a database uva
all those good I P R Diack invoices
pont's you know where you press 12 TD
see what movie Days Inn best to talk to
a live person or
well your credit card company dial them
up and say okay I've gotta pay my bill
what number i press archive poem I got
it I what number i press all those
things
the other day to be slick a handful a
credit card companies were
a good number there anyway that they
weren't looking and national said
and allow them to say okay we know we're
the ER
I V our system can ask you to please the
say or press your your credit card
number in
and they describe this small thing a
body 0 and it basically a
voice recognition or audio recognition
on for you or your digits like you're
sitting at a number
for credit card you're speaking over
Mount it crackles 129 tickets so
dish 129 in your 16 digit and they just
sent out
know it very few permissions back to the
attacker very nice technique very
annoying
it took about an alarm going to go in an
hour with some generate about
I guess August the same year so called
at about seven months
the lower half a year a long time
consumers are basically open source ID
is how 38 Android
I'll UPC look at the editor Java API for
ongoing say okay
what can you get no can do sorry we're
gonna grab information here
what what do you guys I need to go to
you record audio
I'm it's there exists it took 78 months
which is funny because the
Matheny we going to do this would be
willing to make some money off this
drive slow the traffic like with the
five naps earlier
in like with the are injecting a code is
almost nothing ago that pic you make
anybody any money
it has made the ayatollah infielder
photos I'll
the actual Mauro does this thorough 20
them basically enjoyed mixed by an
Android Golden Eagle
nigga spy got some coverage a couple
months ago for a month or two ago when a
I O security companies I like they're
gonna buy one offer from
by some exploits of a bomb the open
market a black market perhaps in the
next point
it's been about 14 grand worth the time
and money to my next point
%uh did basically silently installed in
a good spot on a bunch of old place
forget the name the company om
summer the racks colleagues I forget
exactly what was behind who they were
um but they had a sort of them I am
a list of press releases but apparently
they were able to tho like a spot on the
phone and record on him
and recording audio is not busy
recording entire way we've already kinda
want to press on it because
one year on a mobile phone on Android
phone Android device
and it's some rare for similar to happen
to me that you take up so much space
unless you're doing
stepping out on top so many picture I'm
you really care about
spaces care about wasting an urgent care
about your data plan like most people
don't have unlimited data plan to
I now with the way it's going now we're
now in the US of A
almost none of us are getting a new
phone getting an unlimited plan
haha so it didn't need it needn't be
whose YouTube AC compressor file so mr.
the compressed audio on a file
and it's a design for a mobile format
allows you to
exports more Monday to is going to have
a picture here why plan works well
they lose by the days are getting number
it should be pretty close together
it serves a purpose that the attack was
able to get know you want to
record audio steal credit card numbers
and pin numbers & trade secrets if it's
not the conversation
at 10:30 a.m. or not you can bring it
into like digits like the
learn the proven Nassau comatose there
are
they were able to gather more
information like Gianna stock tips
things like not
I'll secrets are over whatever early
deals mauna
things like not another nice trick and
I'll know either using are on our
updates
to personal this one is the year update
I guess you look at it this way are
I could be fake %uh people you pretend
to be a legitimate application
like a legitimate Android lemme
and looted accumulated legitimate
Android
system a bit like okay you're a virgin
well %uh three or whatever you like your
what name
the code name for this it's its up my
mind because all like food in mind on an
ice cream in
Ice Cream Sandwich gingerbread and I
don't know
moderation is I'll basically you will
you do is pretend to be an update
because both people say when we come out
they want to pick up the over-the-air
answer
how year after I want you to their
phones
looking at but good personalities or
chose not to the brew their phones
I mean what you get from your phone you
can access to a new firmware is bob is a
cure for my eyes
I like earlier with that knowledge to
call
not go with a call right not color idea
was a carrier IQ
which is basically installed on devices
by the year manufacture
already own carry ahead of time deal
base to go statistics from
-ism individual users but it woulda
it was very difficult to remove it was
because in solar system application you
couldn't
removed from a phone that you had access
so you basically up to reduce acute on
your phone
to clean up your phone because it it was
somewhat accessible and it did because I
believe information
om over the Internet via I guess easy
accessible from a.m.
easily accessible applications which is
also commenting on Android
'em in the case %uh v
pick mello be using Google I want to get
rid of something like that what I do
well I'll tell you but it seems
reasonable
I can't wait for the over-the-air update
on the I'm gonna go and do it so it's
actually quite a bit we've seen a bunch
of different nothing to dent nom
P so now we do that their questions all
packages it's a system update
because no one in its all packages right
and not so much
up and then we'll also how those are the
fake updates which are not nice but the
real nice ones or the ones that will do
updating a themselves now with an update
itself because they want to add new
functionality okay
we've seen on the speaking thing it's
useful to watch TV we can add new X
would get more much like okay
we still love boat with the voice calls
invoice information
now let's deal like their emails or
something like that field earlier text
messages
or proper still have their credit card
information is available
up to what the room our update something
not nice because the
even the bag is beyond okay we got
apocryphal sometime got more things more
features
it's not been a personal girls like
click buy books every five minutes
and and the key is that once you've got
an update and in a basis to manually in
accessing a good connection
why would you want the victim to know
that you're a business owner improving
things and bypass the security or
whatever else
why would you want them nobody wants to
so they did pretending not to be visual
because the only permission because
you're gonna get permission saddam
they're gonna get the installs selling
kinda permission is all packages
to do this is silently very tricky
better
little harder protect been receiving is
dummies are already infected that
doesn't mean you're gonna get phone
installed by a drive-by installs
what we see on the PCR time we're okay
you busy one website you get hit
articles with unit on an iPhone where
you have like jailbreaking dot com
we have the you visit your baby doc
comin they have a a jailbreak exploit
with another chain expert to reduce
security to and disable coating and so
forth
to get you basically a similar kinda
root access on your phone
the job a cactus tearful as you can that
at the Muslims don't love you want on it
got to blow by Tom readers going click
on and we still don't have not
the best we have a sound installs and
and its and once installed actually
that's where they get you
forget the sums of work once the iraqi
on your phone on your device
they've got four lakh issue they've
gotten everything they need you meeting
together
of the film islet took a look at some
academics on the these are all welcome
things you know with abuse the slide 10
all went in things we see out there
already
%ah but they got a mention about some
calmer
odd basically a a malware that does the
records audio from your fault right
my concept took a mere six to seven
months actual unreal our
we know we have to meet a little bit
newer negative academia
it's kinda funny i mean academic
community cutie to the Tiki think okay
how if you got what it has been touched
in a phone up we build a minister to
give us more information on any any
place or not
om what's going to be okay how we do
things like
gotta know how do we read your keyboard
which is another want to sing before
like in a nap call touch longer
touch locker wherever I think I should
know before is are basically two
applications one is the %ah
the bar you install exceeds the cleaning
a it be sweeeeet
records data from your from sensors
attacks or %ah Missy
when you you touch your phone yeah
obviously you'll affect X or a little
bit
and those little variations in and
perturbations become
it baby basically that with the years to
get much better say the 129 okay you got
here that the one you picked over there
that
me and so for the record all those good
overtime all a very secure position
positions and then decide okay that's
what were your
then that data is going to a database
help identify
way you touch it causes they did not
work is the
title texan when you push a button or
whatever you do when you enter your PIN
number
in court on a that was two different
applications that was about
no Butler top floor is a new hearing
from a difference in our different team
they decide put everything into one in
one application basically this one
application
what it is competition i'm back to the
yard the project up like
game they're not that great like saying
I can't imagine game where you're
supposed to match the resulting in a
couple having a sheep
the maybe she'd maybe a little cutie so
you're putting your little cattle sheep
or not
%uh internationally you not a suburb on
screen also
mom is from the actual paper or not om
the that these icons are exactly the
same position as the numbers
so you're matching this one this one in
or near it will use both be pushing
you much into icons in the new roughly
where you are sick
this is one happy going to be a game
tend to be out in a while
like Angry Birds but not as in useful
because it's a lot of the winning the
bird
something simple like this something bad
you might have tried
so I guess what I'm saying is a
be very very wary about up their simple
one of my
much as possible what you want a good
reviews one look at things and
than they have in the play and play
market will be seen on the field on the
first before she got right now
arm because things like this happen this
app is a little bigger than our problem
because i jst training data and
recording
about the sample vid yet from the from
the researchers bill leeson
I believe in a few months I'll basically
one Halfpenny opposite launches and it
doesn't game to record where you're
punching
in two weeks until the a screen like the
unlock screen pops up in 10
oh okay put in your pure your unlock
only deported
I've added 16 digits doesn't matter we
regard to get away pushing
they be the same Centers Inc Salaam earl
or not it is OK it may be
so much in unit of area that's the best
to not reply can you type in
4432 whatever that's your online number
like and pick it up very nice technique
very good for stealing a buchanan is
very good for stealing our credit cards
I'll the other PC should success reading
did some legal different
same can't deal with XO remember but
without the Tom
if you'll you'll notice when you type on
the on the soft keyboard with the actual
letters
name YouTube it like 26-30 letters on
screen or
keys on screen you can touch and type
them or not accessing
you'd be the same mom the same slur on
reading
roughly same sensor many different
meetings to be able to tell where you
were touching on some keyboard
which is the bigger problem and
different accuracy in an alarm or
complications
international numbers in the easier and
also slightly different obligation
basically toploader does it all in one
one piece one simple out
something like that and told me better
than that fake think they are already
modified iranian food
with the year ayatollah coming on board
slight different is
you lose money here they used to
dispense
that's what I got mom use the second
picture how it actually works
the one out basically you got two pieces
works in different modes so into one
point it's learning a new console app
its ok to learn what you doing we're
playing a game in Thursday tinted okay
now you
in the screen has an actual already gone
an actual a touchpad
and inserting something data eventually
send up although that information back
to the attacker
be rainy technique remember useful for
them a.m.
have pretty much not about her not to
attack mom
let's now look at I guess I'll talk
about our meeting exploits since
a lot of the people in this room how
true to their phones
one good thing one good thing com
attackers all actually you know
developing their own experts they're
using same it's what you're using your
phone's
all your phones on devices they're not
we see any effort to do
because it takes a whole yes and reached
base on a link but from yes you can find
dornin reuse exploits from mom
basically think essentially put them
over 22 up are living so make eighty six
innings
you can do it you know what you doing
that takes time but you gotta not over
much of an exploding unknown
understandable in the first place ill
you something with it
so what do we see an interview at the
actual numbers look at look at the deal
okay we've got
nom I'll the first 1i guess is that
appears unreliable person as for
are the new cabinet in Jamaica a body
colour day
exploit we did together 6.0 Fall Break
deciding the volume demand or what not
and there but eighteen different minor
minor variants
89 get their lazy attackers a lazy don't
really want to waste the time
horny also cheap because they don't
spend the money to develop their own
only purpose ago you can use to make
pick up money here and there
I am same thing next wouldn't know Chuck
she has like 20 62 invariant
on this is like a I think that you don't
exploit there were like twenty six minor
variance
but that's a whole lot I think the only
thing they change maybe we packing a bit
mary backing an expert itself is my
tribute to McMahon forget the exact
details
in our region to cater to you get what
very diverse numbers are also
be like them I guess three most common
ones out there any
for various editions allrounder like 2-3
in
three and so forth wanna and its
citizens
attleboro should do they not only
carrying a lot about what's in there and
it's very hard
this is going to go back to against
saddam
how many people are involved I guess in
putting together an individual
firmer look if you if your bank tomorrow
a phone yet have more or publish a TI
a former update if you got like a love
my guess
the because T Mobile has a bit more
effort on the network
for their people abandon funding for
stairs over-the-air taking a look faster
hombres im depends want to get on the
manufacture not just the
via a carrier so depending on who the
man factory phone is a CC is it now
were both GTE in one case are y'all
might have heard about the
the back to uncertainty TV phones at the
with
was MetroPCS or the other said you a
binary
on the on-device lucky to basically axis
the voting booth the phone
good morning because I mean didn't know
there was silence or two it is I'm easy
to
to install an update on the phone
finally he had like a possible with
Donnan been released pretty quickly so
it's like
you guys they left the back door her
phone gym to make things easier for you
other many factors and we're not even in
New Year care seeking solo PTZ oversold
Wyoming almost 2 trouble
do more than a little bit irritating com
anyway I'm once again for the same
reason I guess why we're in your phone's
to get rid of summers but whatever to
somebody that needs by owners are
Picasa or wrist and assault began with a
bit about you guys doing
they also want you to know that nice
things like security software things are
installing previously
like if your carrier said okay we're
going to be sent to your phone with
pre-installed to Ann Arbor Summer
when you do then if you're a bad guy you
root the phone and your move that and
you deleted of the essence the partition
same
by it goes away maybe they they get up
to you
mom then they can they can read your
phone really messes me
week information can be here I me I'm
things like that I mean
this doesn't mean though that you're in
any real danger from rooting your phone
any more than anything else
because basically an Android phone in
anger and it was very very open
likely I'll the PC before with the with
ms-dos in another person dos
wearing with a very open platform and
yes there was a lot of the information
available for the program and whatnot
and yes there was a lot on our other but
compare the actual legitimate operate
there like on the PC
was good long still a very very small
person who knows I may be a couple
percent here and there
community gun large government because
once again there is more money
it when there's like a pretty much the
entire hungrily has the largest some
mcguinness times um
their decision to ponder also has the
most to deny coverage in a landmark
so it's also the biggest target because
almost every word as to go after
ass and gets bigger and I see it more
popular hits our laptops and and now
tablets a lot of tablets are a lot of my
mobile phones
it becomes more and more for threat
saigon
on
rhythm
yet so be it basically as as it now and
are getting more and more me on
established platform or even other
others marveled level become established
no whoever gets the larks the I guess
market share becomes a large target
people continue go
as the money money will keep you coming
in for on robbing stealing money from
people stealing our
account information people Aston
accident data when I think so be
mentioned to me earlier was at phnom
people are you seeing mobile devices for
as
basically tiny botnets for computing
power
like if you working like I collected
baby version norming this in the younger
cousin version out
stealing somebody's keep you to mind
becomes not as much power available on
mobile phones timing is
you're going to be more expensive I mean
been getting an iPhone relatively
cheaply
ombre you want to meet with a quad-core
singing on capitol line is because your
whole much money in front so looks like
the BC I don't know in in China one hour
we see most attacks coming up for job
mind he recent
b2b basically you're when you call and
steal a little from a lot of people
pretty much you get invective million
users and you feel like going car
one dollar for me to them you've got a
million dollars still from firing
thousand getting more reason to work
harder
and in the case of Vegas the China
you're doing a lot more lot more people
lot more over market in a case in
america real solo member found Psalm
and Publix and wal-mart on it depends
because we have so many other markets in
in
other countries where you have for all
you get a localized marketing meaning a
market has nothing to localize in your
language
unita Tom you're more like to go after
them then you are
in america where we have a see the play
market or the one that's provided by %ah
your local carrier look at. a rising
market or something
you're less likely to go outside India
Michael walled garden
to go after individual obligation to
mass
I you're looking at 90 you've been
through your phone is it okay I'm done
with going just one place I want my
Steam you
it's rare so did it's less likely to
come out you for that or
be able to get get you in general and
also as long as you stick with the
application have good good no reviews
and tend to be down by a lot of people
that 10 think twenty coverage but nom
also if you have a Google saw bouncers
offered us a
they're basically monitor for %ah the
Android Market for submission to the
Android Market I am didn't see any real
details on except for what's out there
looks like basically day they scan the
application they look for permission for
us to have a place to look for for
code like like anniversary look because
it battle-ready on the look for things
and that could be trouble
minted slightly built in 2001 arm or
up was in with your sign a bubble has
more shit system protection in place
i in the case about I believe there's a
talk coming up at Black Hat
going any captured coming in the Google
Play market
that is doing some suspicious activity
that is stealing information or
leaking information on and is put up
their buyer researcher
so the literally military please only
count their his own name
but it's it's something similar to that
we're in it
it today lead you to be looking up maybe
like the icon playing out maybe
something else I'm not sure what it is
yet
we'll all find out in
I'm sometime in July you know lately
July we'll all find out and when the
action announced publicly when it is
I'll but they basically min
the they can still be bypassed other
security and
your stall we still gon be better off
going after things that have
good reputations that sucks you look at
them on the counter-attack
it's actually want a more complicated
tax out there that we've seen on nom
on the PC side aren't sure if I
polymorphism
base in the same thing in DC on on the
on the PC where
every time you go to his website maybe
your every time a computer with the
website a new computer
they gonna do in individual customized
version up now
'em our I'm in this case it may seem are
fine for the
a text file so today it didn't break any
I'm simple and my signature
on it look slightly different it's about
team functionally maybe to recompile
basically everybody with get a new
version on the PC side is not a
protection where they say okay
arm the attacker will have like okay tom
we've got like a donnell say the as you
sow dollar wanna
a bonnet dying claimed on order and it
tells you okay
I you installed on and and each
different IP address gets a diversion or
the same person every time
so you can get all other versions you
can't do is say look if you're an
american you can get all the ATM
all example unless you have likes a big
access point or two but I peter is
already setup members is now will have
to find things like that
mean like a melodic machine at your
disposal I came on i guess im incense
it it's very very good year by passing
out so you basing build a custom burger
every person
on Android its recent and very similar
least not one major famine has
we've got like I believe 25 different
directions that the number was gonna
25 different individual texan's for
minor variations on
minor variations and we have somewhat
unique not discharging Eric signatures
for the year
application were it's basically a Street
four-color coach in Mad Men
pretend to be an insulation program it
really is something else entirely
is a.m. could be fake on it it says it
on it so I know I got shut up or
something
something along those lines and it is
not bad at all
and changes are done automatically
making
what up
home 30 so we have prematurity a case
the whole time apparently I forget the
exact number one
there's a few hundred samples you
checked already just what the
the small nothing is out there but
basically you take a standard
a pic a file month played the internal
custom text file
like changing strings or something to
Nick last name and you release
you can you buy today by the hour by
whenever time
former you want it is the world a more
it sounds very faint if your gonna
findings on for each done but it's
really simple
you could be destroyed like a simple
approach might ask up to basically
change text in the source code and then
run your tools to build you a became
send out sign didn't send out to you
to new people is kinda nice and kind of
interesting
but not to leave fancy but it sounds
been in the service I polymorphism
ninety change every single version
London you like
the concept simple the thing is it to do
6:30 mormonism
an efficient activation for like I
University action
which doesn't really work it things they
don't really change functionality we can
basically take on with them
but the function or in general with
possible we can take on on
very minor changes they do like gonna in
a sense strings I mean
their mobile way to be texting someone
isn't there was a was a teen mother
does been disbarred dynamic a person who
if you feel like you're going to leave
I'll deal nice product for for PC an
hour that did not make detection for %ah
Mauer house as there is a network a
texan
so evening like a a private
signature-based of love
the same our like 10 different day uses
gonna individuals think because
you're basically a have a large against
saddam
on to Turkey space not exactly evil or
large species the
basically it take on and NBC things you
can find on your own
so it's possible do without so it is a
nice controversy get now in in phnom
in an hour people keep trying to be made
the detection and we've seen where they
would attack a
their neon so I never saw him so other
things the meaning of securities
offerings okay we're going to cuba is a
first
in this case they're gonna do like what
joe Manchin where basic you doesn't
modify your your your binary into my
kind of people
me how to be a week or two to avoided
or in the case of people like you're
walking down in the apt to Mike
you can if it's Oreo build on the public
side mean you put on a public market
departing market everyone going down i
think im
because available and of course a
million dollars so you're you're
the window of a I guess what's accounted
for
mom sorry
opportunity camp you're popular window
is closing its source or
amenable to Billy still I guess the
person because
you were going out that you think is
good was not I believe the the deed like
to use love
public games like to cut the rope or I
guess so
Angry Birds so things like that to me if
you're if you're getting a popular
application from something that's not
the actual market
the actual play marker one you're better
off not touching
maybe it's not look at Amazon market or
something else and a check
don't go out for devoted entirely on
I think you're going to have to
acknowledge and for the year as you are
chuan bi and central drew for a on the
back on top longer
which is an app that does the detection
and
record if things them dog do you have
any questions on any of these
fixer home
it in an hour or an hour or anything in
general
consent so love you have advanced you'll
feel secure in general
how many people accuse good I just wanna
know
on really really secure could give you
very busy did all the source code on
your phone
hmm you know exactly what's on their you
don knapp your territory
look at it in know them well whether to
your turkey pretty good
people to keep 3 good home
yes yeah okay sir questions are we going
to get more
or bottom analysis tools you mention nom
backup
you can't individually boxed million
that you have you seen nom
degrade om I believe that's the a.m
that's the it basically is a VM that
implemented so it'll tell you all you
very sleepy a cold
but I called love you run to face in
this middle published a mass at a pub
today to send you will see what it does
other things like not touch including
the art museum
the honey net projects are I'll
Eren universe in June 9 p.m. at about
nine gigabyte uncompressed Senate's
and counting up it is actually not at
the start so that's a good seed
IBM the area said if you Google honey
nan
and Erev M you should find an
interesting environment
and else other than a good thing a
Google product reviews up the code as
the name
fix things in the DMZ always have the
updated tumbles I'll
basically a on amino acid I should be
done by a number of different people at
the Madame I think com
a lot of good randomized comparison on I
don't miss because the
it's a pain in the butt to deal with
thousands apples were things like the
tour is I polymorphism
gether lot a summer summer we don't
wanna waste of time
look at every single one is the using
backs Mali on think you're using it BK
tool to basement airport look at all the
code
we like to say okay we see all these
thing before can we
just not come up quickly I we're gonna
see more MORE not come out I'm not
further
I get to do you see other commercial
tools available on the market
home
I create the right now it is a very very
very individual you work with each
individual to litem
big pain in the butt to do in general
his you have to be skipped on yourself
in your angel in the UK allies
log in on half an hour after the fact it
would be nice we have a lot more
integrated tools I mean I like Google
doctor technique it bobby is that their
company making on a mission
I'll a number my mom other other
endeavors comes up on the automation in
general to handle the global
done samples coming in because its very
easy making it now coach in
reasoning Android malware so it's like
%um
there things out there for anecdote into
private sector taken as long you you may
raise a good point
why do we not have a whole lot of choice
in automated the reverse engineering
I'm surprised myself I know I don't have
the ballot for allied
my team is working on stuff like on a
lot of my colleagues or nothing for them
but we don't have been all
out there we figure after between what
four years five years
and with another you figure someone
would have designed an already and put
on the market and Michael I can either
pro or something like that you know
you're signed on XO their tools like ben
dover one on
things like nine we figured to be small
niche players who really something like
that and we haven't seen a
mentioning all anywhere yet hopefully
we'll see that this year now the
like it if you look at it like not
talkin are many as you can see it online
later on
about bypassing downstream there's going
to be called for
for more these advanced home on a
minimalist
to get rid of the people bomb mean you
have to be big help you build a big team
for you to do your cell
meaning by buys into a legacy get it out
there sure
them
mom
High Commissioner article where you if
you take the two top anti-virus
programs for Android combine detection
was assaulted sixty percent
I'm not because I'm 75 person
lesson from the fibers not familiar with
our collections of be back to combine
not individually I'm okay mom
bags are sixty-five this little bit
better than 50 percent
listed recorders are I think probably be
once again because the way the Android
works in general it's a very open market
likened
on the PC side where not always have all
samples is low
well there's some overlap it a lot of
disparity between what the actual
samples or
and there's a a a sample sharing they
are simple sharing between love
an hour companies are we shared ample
time to get them so weird
and there are are are dog or turkey
share more information a lot of us have
a long morning
coverage mean now be nice to happen it's
not there yet
it work it or just like for the
automation the mission om
done a lot of the year the Vipers will
be improving
manual sewing questions
them
makeup thank you ago very much on way