in the boon to it's a community standard
its cross-platform
it each other languages like you can
load PHP and 2.9
you can cross commented on n and
basically
it's starting to consume more and more
languages as time goes on and someday
hopefully all
in offers future compatibility so
whatever platform today is that you're
targeting
you can develop and deploy today and
hopefully your source code might run on
tomorrow's architecture platforms
a 128 bit processors and is
platform-independent
which also offers us the ability to
right now where cracks that
as we've got men are cross-platform so
this talk is focused to hackers in
attackers
whether you're here to learn and enjoy a
in
just mailed other programs are you want
to attack in do vicious things to other
programs
that's what this is about whether you
want a cause damage to someone else you
defend yourself against them
you wanna bend applications for the
system as a whole you need a system to
been to accommodate you
for you happen to be death in you need
slight modifications like this guy your
French in you need just a different way
and
interacting with your programs and then
one said tiny changes made its
entirely good or maybe just need a
one-off solution
and that's what we as technologies can
do weekend and other applications to be
different than they were meant to be
so what's a nap it has our intellectual
property
it has the objects and data that we
consider to be source code
it has a lot since I divers inside a vid
and inherent power that application
controls and that's what we're attacking
we're going after the application itself
where able to infiltrate bended
to whatever means we happen to be one to
accomplish so this isn't
assembly level specifically not IDA Pro
kinda thing
because when you're going to add and all
that ligation thats
assembly code it gives you the power to
drive that application it gives you the
power to been an application we all know
I to pro this is a classic approach and
it was very solid for back in the day
and hide it pro facilitated us doing
what we needed it
gave us the ability to edit modify small
applications
and they look like this literally there
object structure their source code was
quite manageable
you can keep it in your head at one
moment I'm and back then fighting an
application
or attacking it you needed tools that
were comparable to that application
but now today this is more what an
application looks like
its hundreds of objects in memory for
one small frame
and its gigabytes of RAM and thats the
paradigm shift when you're talking about
300 objects are three thousand objects
in 40 threads that
IDA Pro attack and paradigms kinda falls
apart
and that's where this all comes in using
dotnet
and I'll framework which is pretty much
assembly code
up a interpreted level this is I LD
intermediate language a dotnet this is
what Don it truly is
and this is where we attack this is
where we get that same
ability to bend and control applications
that we had an idea pro
and we just uses same power that we've
always had two attacker applications in
the same fundamental did
undeniable way let me walk you quickly
through
quick example be compiling 13 lines a
seizure could
when you compile these 13 lines a
seizure code in Indy compile them
they turned into 15 lines a teacher
could 34 lines if I L
and seventy-seven lines assembly code
and that
is a factor out how much time you're
gonna need to spend to read
so when I say 15 lines as he shared it
comes out barely readable
you can quickly peruse it see what it
did figure out if its malicious
vulnerable the thirty four lines and I L
a little more to read you have to know I
L
and it gets a little more ambiguous and
then once you get to assembly code
even if you know simply coat well it
just gets blown in now you have to
spend a lotta time processing what it
does and does not do any given mom
and so that's why I D Pro just isn't the
tool for this because you don't want to
be
doing seventy seven lines processing for
13 lines have input because if you do
your project will just lead you nowhere
and I'll just be painful
and so that's where I come in attacking
on a marine on disk that's my thing
we're gonna attack an application on dis
when we attacked this application gonna
be using
tool that I wrote called great wealth it
allows us to ended an application and
give it fundamentally different behavior
so let's look at acting on this this is
the old paradigm attacking
and now we're shifting to a more
visceral strong approach
that's what I'm hoping so let's look at
attacking Microsoft Media Center
what does it take what is a bill to and
yep so let me walk you through that damn
no
okay so here's media center
the core fundamental ability 0 reaching
into another application and Mon mining
is that it works again ubiquitous
targets regardless
who made them or what security they were
made
send here
paper
so this is great dragon injects into our
target and
I dragon target or executable it finds
it to 64-bit target
every drop a load in and then it runs in
execute well inside her target
at this point we're able to execute
source code
inside a barred target as if we wear
party we can drag in an arbitrary
payload
and loaded inside and so now
i'd introduced an arbitrary execute will
that she and another one
and we have a couple buttons over here
in Media Center
this payload attacks password sequence
so we can type in any password we want
and
it doesn't let us in I am actually real
quick when I rewired
so there was media center I'm to rewire
drew quick
just so you can see okay
okay so am I figured out we wired so you
can see the passwords and I'm typing in
and that spread with this brings us we
can edit arbitrary things inside her
program is
if they were our own so I can type in
the password and
the password is 111 the password is in
000 right that's where injecting an
attacking comes in
am we inject in
same thing I showed you a second ago
tavern agency the password
drop in our payload inside loaded up
and so now we can come in here and say
let's edit 2000 and
also we can grab the Indy 500 cash in
return but will change
and now the password is your 000 and
that's what it takes you can introduce
new functionality into your target
and just call core functionality and be
like I want years to be 444
and so when you think about attacking
this
what does it take to get into an
application quickly bended
in this model I'm injecting in a paleo
that I wrote in 15 minutes day
overrides a key security feature and
this isn't dead
media centers specifically week which it
is specifically week but
you can go against her targets and I
handle all other
318 so like when this window closes all
the payload center inside any clothes
and take care of all that high level
stuff to make it nice n Easy
you can dish out in any arbitrary void
main you want with these tools
so it doesn't it's not like Metasploit
you have to come up to speed and write
some hardcore think it's just
you packin whatever void main you 1 and
that's attacking media center
I am looking agreeable just did take a
quick aside:
you can take these payloads am writing
drag and drop them over here
and this Israel the Decompiler you can
open it up
and tunnel down into the namespaces so
here's a payload we dropped in weekend
open up
go to Change Password button
and you can book my source code so we
can handle in there
and this is the source code for that
and that's kinda thing
they we're a level higher so getting
source code is slightly easier but
it's pretty much the same thing that we
did was off-base back in the day just
coming back ground in dotnet
and like I said when you're talking
about what does it take to read through
this
here's the IL for this and then here's a
source code is definitely a factor each
year
and same thing when you going at it with
assembly code understand what this
function does
is dramatically easier this way and you
can bet my name
program in C if I put a back door in
which is kinda nice you can trust but
verify
and start reading everything is open
source and verifiable
so to break it down
if you decompile media center and you
start looking in
you find it's checked in it literally
it's a function called checked and it
takes a string in
it looking at the flow you can say okay
comes down here pulls out the currently
existing pin a check to see if it's
equal to no it checks to see if the link
is greater than 0
and then it has a peculiar branch that
if the
0 character in is a call and then it has
an arbitrarily
different sequence for login kinda
interesting when you're brute forcing
you might not notice that
and then it does the
return validation or it does alternative
logic
validation again something slightly
different so there's actually two login
modules
inside this one program and that's
partly what this brings us when you're
doing black box testing its kinda hard
to get that
but everything's white box when you will
indeed
go an important source code and the
course I just go in and put a return
true and I want to get past the password
and so as I showed you the password I
could just as easily put a return trip
and drop it in them so
let's look at it from the other side
instead of attacking applications that
are hardened against us and all that
let's turn it around into
there's entire is not yet seen you gotta
pop up in it said you have an antivirus
are you have a virus so download this
will take your you can drag drop it over
here
and let's do a quick walkthrough you can
go to
find me and then you can find your main
and see where it starts executing
and this is probably now where but
we have no way of proving this you look
through you see
obfuscation and this is the same thing
that anyone defending their program
against you will do
to try and make their program quite
unreadable so that's where
great we'll start to step it up a notch
you can come in here and do an important
bring the same and tires in run it
through at the office Gator
an hour void main has better naming
and now we are starting kid real names
back and what was
arbitrarily hard to read before is now
starting to get significantly easier
and so when you thinking about malware
and they're starting to do office
cations Packers
are sacred go before pulls it out at
memory in the deep accident executed
this on does that anything this done
in a programmatic way can be
programmatically undone and
so both sides of the coin whether you're
defending applications are attacking
applications
this is just one more tool for your
talkback so
let's say you dig into their source code
right and you find something like
but see and I'm okay sure
but say you find maybe a string
and it's like well if the string was
different I might be able to send them
back bad data
forget them to do something arbitrarily
malicious to them very so over here
is a string in IL and here's a string in
code
you can come in here and just delay
I wanted to drop
you can just do whatever you are but
really want to their program and that's
where
I'm going for modified I'm not decompile
and party but in not decompile impaired
I'm
is you can take this back to source code
but you can also just making arbitrary
change
it's a and then save an executable right
out and then fired up
or push it at them or maybe instead of
doing that
we want to do something like I am at a
call
and protocol in there
and then make a call out to some other
functions somewhere else
and so that allows us the ability to
at City find this and so we can put
arbitrary calls in there
we can put in other payloads weekend add
other libraries we can just modify it
like it was pure source code
and this is an executable already lol
thats just deployed on the Internet
and we can start taking that full
control that
like back in the day we all know that
like there is hardcore simply
programmers 2nd just modifying executed
alright
and we lost and no we didn't lose it we
just
forgot about it a little weak and put it
to the side or simply code it's real
hard
and this is assembly code for dotnet in
Java and all the rest in
sup thats on the other side of the fence
when you're going up against malware
the ability to just ripped through an
application quickly modify it
and fired back or pushing back up would
come in handy depending on
what you're doing some
let's look at specifically injection for
just a little bit and applications
running in memory
you coming you deliver your payload
inside a bit and
that your dad women
execute will spend a it fires dll's it
uses also is a verification
this all goes through their ubiquitous
Windows dotnet security systems
and it becomes a process whatever
scanning whitelisting happened to take
place
and then after all that's gone we can
drop in turbulence
and this is the upside I'm injecting and
got net
you can come in at the last moment in a
high-level language either through
Metasploit
or having access to core system you can
come in do that attack
and so let's see what we can do it at
less inject one payload into one
application
let's inject that exact same payload
into another application
and so on and so forth and these are
applications that are
different architecture which one is 32
bit when a 64-bit
this could just as easily be one only
needs one on Windows one on your x-box
you can take the same payload and push
against multiple targets
so here's a
protected and Packer a requires a
password
and once we get the password it unlocks
its features
let's inject in there so this one
payload is attacking
a 64-bit application right so it uses a
64-bit bootstrap
and now we ever 64-bit bootstrap this
bootstrap is compiled into MSIL
which is neither 64-bit or 32-bit that's
why I can work anywhere
we can load in hack dropping in here
and now we're able to add functionality
to their application
where we can in to rate all streams and
just change it or we can change the
locations in values and
any object in memory and so like this
but mimicking click down here
agnosio yeah he can't I can just edit
arbitrarily
any value in memory any object in memory
I can just walk in there and body
snatchers replace it with the
man in the middle object in go to town
pretty much anything you can think of is
a developer
you can now do their arbitrary
applications on the fly
okay so this Taylor that we're gonna
injected right
we can load in as many at these payloads
as we want
and I manage all this reading all that
girly stuff all that
it's managed appear so this payload
looks through the application
and it finds the hash that is validating
against
and then Iran's and reports crack and so
it's like okay here I just brute force
did I used it's arbitrary code for
and checking the hash I got a validation
and that's it
and then I'll type it into the text box
because as a feature
okay so there it is mister
let's kick it up a little bit and again
something that'll take a little bit I'm
to process
so again like I said drag this target in
here
it says okay I see it 64-bit years as
process ID
inject in there drop that
in one more time
and it pulls out a different cash
because this one has a
longer password we start cracking it
again and it uses the functionality
up its target to process the checks so
you're not trying to re code in
emulated your actually using its own
functions in its own hash good values
to check against so this is why one
single payload work against multiple
targets because you identify what you
wanna lock onto
it will just processing brute force
ubiquitously Intel it finds in
and then that's it and that's a 64-bit
application right
so like I said we're gonna go up against
a 32-bit application again
a different application inject into it
with exactly the same tailored
so it's a 32-bit application something
entirely different made by someone
that's completely separate from the
other one right
will inject in and this time
let's drop in one extra pit so like
here's a Kodak says payload
is gonna white through the entire memory
space and then pull out the source code
and number
so as I was doing it on this before this
walks through enriched to remember
anything that you can do is a programmer
you can do here you can
added you can pull out a member you can
push okay so back to the table in
drag and drop the same exact payload and
right in case we have a Palin
we had the hash and we have a brute
force
this is a completely different hashing
see as the previous one was a simple
indy five hash
this is a shot 256 been indy five
and then a proprietary and so it's a
changing
and so as before it was processing tens
of thousands a second
this one's processing tens second
and again we're using the functionality
inherent in them we're not bringing the
functionality with us
so we wait to lock onto a target and
then at that point
choose what functionality we want to
pull out news
where we want to pull the hash value our
and that's why the big winners
proportion
again it finds a password hated into the
box
and then validates and so now instead a
ride in a brute force her to a target
or and brute forcing a single technology
you can read an adaptable fortune that
will work on literally any program that
you can identify here's a hash
here some are sacred do here's may be a
function called keep checking
and why don't you log onto a min
disproportionately in return major
and so let's look at something a little
more real in the real world we wanna go
up against
passwords we wanted pull out free
software you want to
really destroy applications right we
want to critically wound some business
and so we can deploy password before
church we can
am injector own sequences have
communication straight into their stream
we can send things that should never be
sent grain
at this point we can say okay you had a
sequel object that you single clean but
we have the sequel objects weakness
buyer
anything we want edging and now you have
to consider that a high schooler can now
get into your single object and just
start simple injecting you
in a matter of seconds well that's a bad
idea
course we don't do that we wouldn't do
that because
that's not legal and but we have to
consider this is the same tool this is
the same stuff that everyone else has
access to
and so keep that in mind
like this isn't benign threat but also
like I said this isn't new
so we should have been taking care this
twenty years ago every single program
that's on the desktop should be immune
to see more injections
but how many developers for the desktop
you think do sequel cleaning much less
any defensive mechanisms close to
one person so was eating
you connect your target you do cindy
compiling you getting you find out what
technology to have you in fact that you
change the target
you exploit its core vulnerabilities and
take advantage of him
and you re morning and a when
here's their response said I think herb
honorable to go after
can have a top-five so flipping the
check in an application
said in a single value true cutting the
logic returning true in accessing about
you this is because you can come in and
say registered Eagles false
now becomes registry was true or
bullying check for does eight will be
like a password validation
you can simply say 1890 will be and with
a simple change only invalid password
will pass
is registered true
you can just throw it at the top sequel
cleaning
throw it at the top yeah I was simple
clean and now you've negated
all that defensive mechanism with one
single command
so let's look at that let's look at
attacking the login see 17 real
application
same world on this
coming to Settings General security
and put in a password okay so
now we have a secured application anyone
tries to come in they'll be presented
with password challenge
and if they don't know if they can't get
in the application
like I showed you before we could do
brute forcing
or whatever else simply in grey wool
drag and drop in open it up and
at this point we can come down to
in
p.m.
you
so this is the password validation
the password validation is simply taker
in point and compare in plain text
no crypto around it just simply to a
street compares
so at this point we have the plain text
to the password
and the plaintext the stored password
and that's our comparison check for this
program so let's attack that
this is I'll
K so here we get our password will start
adding some new eye on your
okay so this is our guest password
in this is are our people's so kinda
like when we had to learn assembly code
at this point you still can have to know
I'll hopefully I can get past a
but here's the opcode this allows us to
put in
a new instructions here well call it do
and I'm trying to make this easy so down
here tells you the definition
do so it duplicates object on top of the
stack
so now we have are currently stored
password and now we have to understand
open another line to a call put a call
out
put it out to system.windows.forms
library
tunnel down and we put it to show
and so now we have heard password on the
top of the stack showing out
this function returns something a
dialogue result
will put a pop his ass on the cover
stack and now this is what we had
we have get your password
show it and compare that's pretty good
we come down here
and we have this our peoples so
let's pop this of the stack so whatever
our people
up people's did will just destroy and
then we'll put in
LDC I for 1
and so like I said
here's our comparison we do our
comparison and then we
if true and so now this is our
validation sequence
click Save save it up
so now let's go in and try and login
again
gay so put in a password here's our
password netted
those couple instructions have
completely not only negated but given up
the store password
and that's going from a hard application
in this kind of R&D attack is easily
doable
under two hours you can go from scratch
downloading
to a fully deployable attacked in under
two hours if you're still pretty
reliably
if you're unskilled maybe eight hours by
it if you are general programming
knowledge certainly within one day you
should be
able to affect some program in a
fundamental way so let's look at this
we have on the settings in your
and government license
paper in where one
teams 12 and unlock the program
because as a registration key site no as
a registration key
while air one 2012 be a registration key
right
well let's go and fix n
come down here into so
this isn't obfuscated program right we
they went through and they put in bad
names
coming in here core
the static constructor this is where the
initial values at a programmer said
and here's our target variable this
target variable controls
when it's cute against so we come in
here
but this in your change this variable as
I showed you before you can change in
arbitrary string
a change the arbitrary string and now
that arbitrary string
is gonna work both save it out again
and so now we have a second version
we have the original cracked that we
deployed where
it gives us access pass the password
divulges
gets us in
come in setting license
up player one
doesn't welcome
ok dats
home its
open maybe it's absecon USA 2011
okay a closer
I am and that's what it takes to reach
an application seeking consider this to
be like to sign in sequence have an
application
or anything else you when it downloads
updates after the server like this stuff
is completely benign like you can go up
her
thousands of people with this by this is
the benign version of what you can
really do against a protected
application
and so those couple a little changes are
considered hardcore cracks today
like okay give me pass along in sequence
and crack the application
and you can do it in about 20 plates
Lake
that's it it's just a couple lines a
buyer and so
it's dropping at bar what we consider
thread
to be someone that has in nineteen
skills assembly and they had fun team to
some kid in Bangladesh with an extra two
hours between classes
and this is a new threat model so let's
look at your public and private he
signed you simply change the key
and now you can just push out and on the
application
and I Commons validation sequence for
I am she's is you have a unknown value
you put in your name an idea of the
machine and then you happen to know that
known value what is lash be and that's
it and you're able to crack that seems
call the server just tactic all pointed
your own server
ordinary gave that server call whatever
you want you to be phoning home critical
information and say your programs
validated
you can do anything at that point demo
it was true you can send it to anything
you want
and water programs will have this in the
first recalls
have the application right under Boyd
mean is set whether it's
true or false and this is a common
programming standard which is fine
and then there's complex math to try and
defend the application
which is nice and fun because it takes
complex mad
and thinking to unwind its like a
Rubik's Cube that no one won in
jerusalem
and way more than one person at a time
they'll ship you the key generation
sequence inside their program right next
to the
key verification is a key generation
sequence because
they bought an off-the-shelf product
included the DL and shipped in
and that's just part of the market its
trust but verify but on the desktop sign
how many people have really done a
security review their desktop
application like you can testers right
how many you have ever heard a desktop
application
hurting anyone ever had a client say we
have a desktop application were using on
tens of thousands of
terminals and we wanted to be secure and
it can't attack this year
it's just not in the threat matrix so
that's why I'm here
and showing you that if you have a key
sequence instead of trying to be D
you can simply change in when you have a
server call
you can have a point to any server you
on you can send back any information you
want
and then you can complete the sequence
and this is
a fairly ubiquitous tank and we can do
replay attacks
so like here's a sequence you pass in
your name it turns into a
random code string and then we check to
see if the registration code
people's that's nice and then we can
just replay the
same sequence and we can use this
against tens and thousands have
applications in a matter of minutes
and this is just low-hanging fruit
because for the longest time this is a
completely
undefended front and
complex math you simply chop it up you
attacked the weak spot you put in brute
force years
and then you spend the night undoing it
and by the end you've cracked their
complex mad
so and this
program just to talk about it a little
bit like what you see inside an
application
so this application encrypt your data it
stores it
in a static key it uses zero vector
initialization
it stores your text password in the
clear so
if you do in a security review and this
is a product there you they're bringing
in-house or they're producing
you cancer coming back with these
definable things you need to fix this
this and this
and re mediated and then
build that into recycling build a hardon
cycle development so what stops all this
time showing the rain
so what's the security that we have to
go up against white will companies do
to try and stop this they'll try and
protect this with
obfuscation just like that antivirus
program that I showed you where you just
pull off the office cation
they'll do code of Education logic
obfuscation they'll make unmanaged calls
out other languages
bill make shells Packers crypto the same
exact techniques that
your aunt a now where people are coming
up against that if you're trying to
protect your malware from being
reverse-engineered that's the same thing
you're doing when you're trying to stop
here
enterprise application for being
reverse-engineered
and this transition down D compilation
because when you have your secure you
call out to a dongle
you may be phone home in do Twitter in
database calls
you fire off some crypto and these are
the ubiquitous weak points
because each of these points is a single
function part between one library in
another
the search 0.6 can quickly get to in
just intercepted
and say your USB dongle is there I'm in
a fire of those server calls
and think about this if you have an
application that has the right to tunnel
through your firewall
and fire out to the Internet and send
any arbitrary data at once
doesn't that seem like a threat Lake if
you have an application inside your
heart network like a friend 6 PC
software
and you have to open a tunnel to allow
it to get to the key check server
and this is OK why
because we trust that PC software
because there's no way that software
gonna be compromised
and this is just a secure security
vulnerability that we can leverage
because people trust their applications
they trust the guards to protect their
data bases date
trust their programs to protect their
data bases
and we know we should trust but verify
because when you have this model that
it's just secured
and as a beginning in a bit you only
have to worry about the outside
that's just not the model anymore let's
look at it
here's great wealth use this program
that we took out earlier
we drag and drop in its like I don't
know it has no clue about it
and that's because is protected with and
not of the show
packer I love that and like I showed you
before we can
inject into it and do all the same stuff
all their protection falls away we have
like I showed you before we can inject
into it and pop all the code out a bit
and look at its code base and so it's
protected
in memory against
its office created in memory its
unpacked it's coming from multiple
languages
and we can injected and take all that
away weekend injected
and do other things so here's another
Taylor
we can add these buns in there right I'm
take another application way
say the group for sure injected in there
and we can take X number of applications
and just keep injecting all day long in
just keep going right and what is this
all the where does the ability to inject
30 applications together go well this is
where it goes
so like I said I can manipulate objects
in image right these applications this
one
this brew Porcher and this program that
it attacks
at this moment are in the same memory
space and essentially one application
so I can take something like this crack
button remove it off it here
and I can push it over here I can take
the cancel button
what everyone I mean these are
fundamental changes that allow us to
do what everyone to our targets
am actually artist
click that button real quick to show you
up
way okay
home
I'm a little chip
said
I am okay
com okay so that's a sequence you drag
and drop drag-and-drop drag-and-drop
you inject into your target you click
this
iterates all windows and as these
buttons to in
and these buttons do the same thing to
its target local values
which can come in handy such as well as
is pregnant due
right this means you can right click on
this crack but now
and it'll divulge what that crack button
fires and so you can just say hey give
me the code that's right there
right under your fingertips here it is
and you can jump straight to their code
and here it is the pass cracker its
object its function
and you can pull that right now they're
doing like I said
you can pop it off if one application
and pop it on the other
and then fired and it still functions
these this is safe I'm handling the
treading on handling the objects
and it's pretty easy these payloads are
between 25
and fifty lines ago they're written in a
couple hours max
and you can just churning out all day
long and so you can make fairly fun
practice like you can just make
everything run away
you can say okay I want everything to
dodge this and it's like there you go
into lines echo you can just say okay
well you can never click on anything
again
and think about it like what does this
mean like if you come in here
and I can had a right click to this I
can come in and say okay
well this is a 7.84 well
I have a blind individual in this needs
to be a 48 on right
how long will that take
if I said this needs to be ADA compliant
this means to be a
48 fond I what your def time and if I
can say oh it's two lines echoed
and you can do this to in a ubiquitous
program it opens up the doors like I
said if you want to do a one-off
solution for someone you wanna say okay
it's in French will now it's an Italian
internet Allen will now it's in Farsi
you can just go all day long and make
ubiquitous converters
ubiquitous brute force yours with a few
lines ago and that's what my tools are
bringing you
it's not that this is new it's just 83
and targeted at the new platforms and
when I say new platforms
whatever exactly mean right so I keep
saying oh
I'm going up against these programs
there not necessarily below normal in
some fundamental way
but what does make
dotnet slightly different it is a
runtime language
so we have things like reflection we
have there
we have reflection we had
object-oriented all that and this
where one so here's Java dotnet
I KBM I KVM
is a general conversion from Java 2.9
it's open and it's free will come in
here
take this to the main line because have
been
got around to making a nice interface
but is written by a
people guy that has fitzco so that's I
KBM
so KK the
MC for compile so I K bien can run
at runtime working run at compile well
targeted
armitage jar and it'll go through and
produce
armitage dokie exceed best canonize rain
like here's armitage da txt I don't have
the Java Runtime installed on this
machine
will boot it up this is booting the JVM
on topic dotnet
it's basically handling Java on top a
dotnet
and then armitage on top of that and so
this is armitage
converted in a couple seconds over 2.9
right a check this out this is our
injector that works against anything
right and now we can target armitage
we can say okay inject and a
ubiquitous brew forsure now happens to
work and all over pay work
payloads that we're looking at happened
at work so on and so forth
and so we can take something like yeah
make this button thing drop it on their
loaded up
and now we can add buttons weekend edit
and manipulate that Java application as
though it were done an application
which is something new win I'm same okay
if it's in PHP Python
jobber whatever you can bring it over
did on it interface with it roll it into
one application
and deployed on the dotnet framework on
roughly any platform that you want
that's kinda what mr.
so when I say
this is a dotnet executing you can drag
and drop it over here
into grateful and open it up
as though it work and it is so here we
can opener
armitage armitage main and come to the
main on
armitage and so here it is here's the
main
here's the gummi and this is armitage
and so to go from in arbitrary job
application to adopt an application
and then be able to have that same
editing capability in 12 months n
that's kinda nice it opens a few doors
and so when you take something like this
we can start injecting other payloads we
can start
editing in combining it and you can now
use Armitage's though it was just a
bootstrap
but you can write a pale around whatever
you want
and so thats armitage in dotnet
so back to the office cation it really
doesn't make a difference
you can pull it off you can read it
anyways it just hides the code
so obfuscation am
I just wanna talk about it for real
quick second it's not a terribly
important topic
but the downside 7 is it only works
against
your privates so if you have public's
it still allows it through we can import
a puppet of but
that's okay I am
I really don't care obfuscation paid
and okay so this is a slide from a
company that protect your applications
this provides you a platform for
intrusion detection tampered still and
isn't your application
and so when we're talking about going up
against now where this is also what
they're going to be using
and these tools allow us to a edit them
and compromise those core protection
mechanisms
and accomplish the same undeniable
attack that we're going for
and I hope that's where you're getting
from this I hope that these tools looked
fairly easy that you can go to a hardon
programmer fairly
protected program or an easy programming
get that ubiquitous control
and that's look at that for a second
like
what is it what is it that I'm really
looking at
so take web inspector a it's a fairly
large in hard program
what do you think it's protected with
office cation
all sorts a key validation calling home
to the server
we can drag and drop in find a we can
now know anything about our target that
we want
we can just are looking through and say
okay how did they protect themselves
what standards that they adhere to
and all that you can do something like
here's their package scanner
you can come into their Pakistan Air and
look for
what technology they use
white standards that they adhere to and
all that what code the Daily News
here's our package scanner
it okay
I run a whole bunch a different versions
I have to get up in a different version
so am the package gainers a pretty large
payload
8.28 megabytes
source coding resources so
we can come in here and we can go
think it's from and their package
scanner
and do a quick search it
reaches through the entire program
looking for frowns on this program
and a return to some and so at this
point
you reach into their program
Titanic but search its
yeah
so
your so we have a database session we
have a creek wearing
we have a from call and we have some
parameters feeding into it
and so you can now jump straight to
in a couple of clicks having deep
knowledge of the application
and then doing whatever you think you
can do from there and
think about this this is a database
session we can grab a hole that they
have a session in fire
anything we want we could leverage at on
other machines and fired
whatever we want to push in there we
could
put something out there to cause data to
flow up to this
so on and so forth and it takes a couple
seconds to dig through an application
that should be incredibly hard
that's a feature so what do you think
do you think you could go but against a
hard application with the stuff doesn't
look pretty easy
I mean that's what I'm going for like
even if you're not a hardware developer
it's like an OK
I think I can go in and i cant do
something and
so let's look at that what can you do so
this attack that I did against their
program where we got through the air
it was P and then you
was the password validation its okay
here's that
double people's okay here's the first
branch branch on false kick that down
branch on true and there you go you
thrown outside before
and so this is what I'm going for
Lake it's not assembly code it's not a
advanced persistent threat it some high
schooler with a half hour an hour
time and he can this report your program
surefire ensure that your server
and
a course we all know the best defense is
good sniper and
it's an offense and defense in game are
you going up against
web inspecting you're trying to attack
in China men are you going up against
malware pretending to be a
me and it's trying to defend against you
and
whatever side you're on great will tips
the scales towards the attacker
and then the defense's can build up
and just like we saw a skater the entire
point in this
is we can't wait twenty five years and
then say oh we should have been
defending our applications for last 25
years
we can start saying okay you have
protecting your web front
now let's protect your software
development from the talks in the same
exact servers
from the inside from your terms and
you can use Packers in crypto but in the
end
it comes down to architecture so what's
a security we can just bashing a crossed
we can just reverberate through most
security features
but if you bake in security that's
better because eventually they're going
to be able to take out your client
they're gonna be able to compromise
every single one of your security
mechanisms but
if you've built a secure architecture
you should be able to handle this
you should be able to have someone
malicious on the inside attacking
and you should be able to withstand
let's talk about that
like what we call inside and outside
right so
Tom
we talked about inside and outside
threats by
its we all know that we can pivot across
different points
we can get inside the internal workings
have the
enterprise and then we can take
advantage of it from the inside out so
it stayed
here's what are the demos that
I like to push just because I like to
encourage security through fear
so
say you decompile my application and I
don't want you to
here it is here some ubiquitous
application
it doesn't do much but I want to protect
this application
you come in here this is
reflect or there's I'll spire there's
like 5d compilers they're pretty solid
for dotnet at this moment you come in
here you export it to do this
will save it out and so now we have its
eighteen out to this
we've accomplished the
round trip in we got your source code
haha right come in here
go to where it came out to booted up
Visual Studios
are needed
beaded and
this is a up into payloads I wanted it
okay its interactive a a sandbox 00 get
my system
okay so we booted up come in here
looking to form the form doesn't render
because the objects
in memory having been built to render
them we go through quick build cycle
and now you can open up this logo and
it's just some
image you can come in and you can look
at their program source code
however when you come in look at this
about books
and
it renders we get arbitrary code
execution because this
is arbitrarily running source code on
our system
this arbitrary code execution
fires from within Visual Studios as
Visual Studio
from its memory space on its own threads
in a red
normal standard firing mechanism like
this isn't reaching out
running some assembly code or doing
something complex it could repay be
doing books
it's just read running source code into
it
we have arbitrary source code and we
have
a small malicious payload running
there's a course runs in the background
silently
either taking developer keys whatever
you want right we install this
come in here and this reach my parachute
and here's really much harsher
because power shells and Annette
and we can just simply really thin easy
aftershock Taylor and it still works
wages simply reading the front in and so
that her show
is now infected if you have a keylogger
and it's an application-level
keylogger it's not a system-level
keylogger so blows great hasher AB
and maybe it's an application that has
legitimate rights to the internet so we
can to start firing off to the Internet
legitimate
and we can hopefully
defend against this but when you're not
acker this is a fairly normal attack
vector
and Visual Studios has this in their
how do I do it right so let's look at
here's the code:
this is the code that fires this is the
logo button
and when this logo button is rendered
its constructors fired when the
constructors fired
we see are you in the process that is
this application
no okay then attacked the shit outta and
that's it that's that's the code put a
thread in their checked to see who you
are and then go malicious
and it simply here we add this on the
about box
and there it is and now anyone looking
at this form gets attacked
and Microsoft is not going to fix it
this is a feature is is unknown features
since 2004
and so I can push a good project up
there you look at my source code and now
you're infected
you compile wanna my applications and
now you're infected and so this is why
talk about the
going for in 10-20 years with dotnet
weekends are defending against these
things one at a time and start bringing
up vulnerabilities
and Medicaid because if Microsoft can
run Visual Studios in a secure manner
Lake they should have their shit
together right like they put all these
documents okay if your gonna run
arbitrary code
be do it inside a better protected
thread with minimal rights and all this
other stuff
when it comes to actually doing it no
one checks there is no trust but verify
when you come to desktop application to
simply trusted
you trusted not to divulge your password
and so
and its see what else
I'm about one more just for
heading out to do this very many times
and
I think it's kind have had a lot of
questions about how are you
like bake in your own attacks inside a
few targets
so will take this windows 7 USB
DVD creation tool it creates USB sticks
for Windows
to install we can then come down
go to our fine name and here's our main
and so at this point we have
are application started
and these coupled lines are important
just because a set some other context
but after these lines are pretty much
good to go for adding your own payloads
but scroll down to these lines in
I am which years said compatibility text
rendering
and so here we are this returns avoid
onto the stack
so at this point we can put in our own
code in the stack is pretty much clean
at this point it put in a call
and so I'm trying to make this easy
here's where we choose who won a call to
you take your shown that we've been
using to inject
you drag and drop it and there it is and
so now we're linking to an external
library
this could easily be a packet access
inside her target we open it up
retail King fire off point me at said
and now we have avoid mean firing in
someone else
inside or a target in a couple clicks
and that's how you develop your own
payloads
injected into a home and then save it
outright but say that I am
yeah run as admin Jer Andrea because we
trust that store
we downloaded off the internet its gonna
do what we want we're gonna
needed okay after why when I trust you
and so
we close this window the trend continues
because this blocks that read
its thing but so here we go we have this
ubiquitous payload that we've been
running all day long hidden inside
appear
some and other stuff just to
kinda do some tool dropping knowledge
no it
here this is
a course all up on my website for free
am I put in an aim pipe communication
module between all the payloads
so we can come back to you this act
buttons
deployer you can say but see
run anything send the command to run it
and now we can reopen
this inside ever target and so you can
do
a sustained communication with it and
it stays live inside the process it
opens up communication portals
on my website I rolled it into a mess
way payload as well
you can then proxy that do communication
over named pipes over Metasploit what
everyone
pretty much anything you want let's look
and drag and drop in some source code in
here a source code viewing in here
and now we can say okay show me love
your source code or change your core
variables or whatever you want
and this is all from that initial 34
clicks to put that
one Collins had ever target and
you can just are going to like it was
your own application
something else to throw out there dead
is nice but this is say find
I am you want to come to this class
message dialogue and
you see all these private private
private you can come in here
go to access this is just makes
everything public
you come back to this class and its
public public public
and so when you trying to interface with
someone else's API you can just take
control of their API
you can just take control their program
and drive it looked like it was an API
and when you look up to someone else's
program just take control
and you can do this to an entire
application DLL click Save now it's all
public
you can reference it like it's an
internal DLL and just
drive it like it's a rental and that's a
danger
like when we talk about Microsoft
protecting us they're not protecting
themselves
they're not carrying that win they take
over RSP ends from
a single line of source code that that's
a danger
that you can then in there pin it to the
rest in the enterprise through the SPN
you can get developer keys you can get
database keys you can
including bacon malware and this isn't
known for it since 2004
and they have no plans on fixing it
going forwards why not because they're
is no
verification from the community there is
no push from the community hey I'm
getting routed from this all the time
can you please fix it
so that's partly why I'm here so when
you look inside the cert seen what you
shouldn't see
you start seeing the truth and what's
behind their and that's what I'm
bringing you
day ease and knowledge what you really
running deep in your system
you can find out what kinda login check
sir
actually doing what kind of storage
mechanisms are actually using
when they say they're phipps compliant
are they just saying that
Lake are they phipps compliant in like
the past one single test from someone
that they paid off
or are they doing good standards all the
way around you can find out
what kinda crypto they're using whether
it's home big or whether it's of the
show
for proprietary in hardened verified you
can start evaluating what candidate
you're listening
make we just have applications firing
home data all the time
what are they actually sending home
about you do you not want your programs
the fire
information about you back to the server
sure turning off go in there and put a
return sure the top of all the phone
home mechanisms and now you just taking
out the phone home
which is a boner ability to you because
if I'm that server why should I know
where your friends ex lattice
why should I know where you are anytime
you want to use a program it's a boner
billing
someone could use that against you I
could use it against you you can look at
the crypto keys what are they actually
what kinda vector initialization what
kinda randomization what kinda standards
are they actually using deep inside the
program
and now you can not only verify your
programs other people's programs you can
go to a client's a program a secure
program be isn't secure because a
this technology standard and we can
actually start making informed decisions
about our
software that we choose to trust does
anyone have the time and the Restless
Tom Co
I am look at the crypto I am see if its
Big Ten
easy and if there's any questions are
more than happy to answer min
I hope you guys enjoy this talk in the
tools that are free its
way
well I'm burning questions or comments
on the course happy to take more after
but I
and before questions and comments like
how many have you do you think you would
want to like uses when you get home
nights okay I good news and bad news
game
I'm good news my tools are free bad news
is I slow down what's on the Internet by
at least six months
so everything that you saw from office
cation
to Searcy know that is trickling out
slowly and then
good news is I brought a pack and DVD's
with some other newest
agree with on it and a collection of
applications videos demos trainings
everything you need to get off the
ground
and so you can pop this and go straight
to tap
and the course prix I am
when I say attack applications Lake
how many have you want to defend an
application with this tech
I me and you would want to
verifier tak an application with this
decade
I mean when you think about your
competition have your intellectual
property with this kinda stuff
bike isn't that a corner on their
billing
I mean when you come to your clients
like yours all your intellectual
property here's an attack against you
and it's all in 15 minutes questions
comments let's start
yes um
use of my program open the source code
here
if u'd compile my program I will sue you
him
I i mean my program by de facto makes
everything dotnet
open source so if you can figure out the
source cohesion using
my programs are non-commercial they're
not for sale
and you can't buy them and you can't use
in commercial environments
'em
so that being said I am
does anyone want to use in a commercial
environment I mean just to get a feel
now good Singh I did a good thing I stop
people who would want to you from doing
it now with your course wouldn't want
you
I am and so how about
anyone they would actually use it like
why would you use it you have any ideas
yeah ok
your I am burn
sure
yeah
and I mean and so is basically like when
you get to check a desktop applications
to find out if it actually needs a
password to progress
and they're certain standards like when
you talk about backup software
you do not need a password to see what
is in the backup software
you do need a password to uninfected
where you can go through all the backup
singers pull out all the files are
stored in there and what information was
backed up
what dates what size is all that and so
you can look at community standards and
I'm
okay let me put it this way if anyone
has any really good questions they
definitely get one of these DVD's which
is in a limited supply
so any questions ok
me
no
not not in any way this specifically in
only attacks gotten it at this moment
and I don't really have any plans on
expanding it out from there
it's a dotnet specific on
turn some data way
idea ads
354 compatible some other payloads are
42 incompatible
and you have to recompile your payload
to the target I'm
it
no I don't them
yep
oh yeah
and when you talk about like good and
bad coding practices like
the kind the destruction that you can
read give just one airs made
them
yet
and and it's a really so he likes the
line by line inspections which
when you go to a client engagement you
don't have to say hey why don't you
semi-retired environment trust me with
the Kings to your kingdom
you can say okay I'm gonna go to your
website downloader trial in just get all
your source code
and your truck clients don't have to
trust you more than anyone else
they're just giving have their source
code everyone and because that's when
the first thing to get to tell 'em
yep I'll I am
what I'm trying not to attack mono so no
but I mean I'm trying to slow down the
dissemination in this so
like I said ten twenty years will look
back and say oh yeah I don't know it's
much more secure than it would have been
but yet you can it's pretty easy like
it's two clades
had home
I am so when you talk about
irregularities between job in dotnet
conversions
it's the idea that one thing doesn't map
to the other right
and dotnet is a super said
a opcodes compared to Java and Microsoft
Intel version 1.4 develop the Java
Runtime
and then from there there's a little bit
of a split Microsoft went off and it's
something
and where some other also the public
developers have gotten it and gotten it
has fifty more opcodes in job
so you can basically implement anything
in Java straight and done it without
conversion to go from Java to
air from dotnet to Java you have to do a
little shaking but no
dates down I had converted massive
amounts
Java and like that a que bien project
I had to you convert one-line where
it set the growing and I had to take
that out so it didn't use
a unique gooey skin
and its ago
I'm yeah I attack objects are sometimes
when I'm attacking job I have to report
to a different type of object
but nights it's pretty good like you can
and then you can roll it in and use it
like it's a core library and so
when we find a job for libraries in
Psych home and if this was in dotnet to
be so nice
me as I know it is it is flip it over
it's a DLL and you included
and it looks like dattt runs like dot
net and
you don't have to have the JVM in your
deployment cycle in a lot of companies
are starting today
uses when they developed in years a bit
job application they certainly want to
go desktop in dotnet
psycho k drag-and-drop yet
I'm trying to encourage my purse of 212
sandbox the vulnerability
in and I am just going to keep putting
it out there
like if someone went up to code like to
put in the you know I'm a singer I p.m.
hash back
to Twitter when you downloading look at
the source code
Microsoft might start taking answers and
into other
is a security reason there's no
financial reason for them to fix it and
best just unfortunately the paradigm we
live in but no I'm
I'm trying to create social pressure and
market economic probability
other questions go
well I hope you enjoy this talk and on
enjoy the tools and thanks
well
up are
hit you up
okay