[Music]
[Applause]
oh
[Music]
me
[Applause]
bye
[Music]
do
me
[Music]
money
excellent hello uh i just want to do a
quick update it's stu again
uh just do a quick update on the
fundraising activities just before i
uh ed tucker's talk uh which uh mike
will introduce
um so just to give you some updates we
are doing really well we've just reached
7051 pounds
uh which is phenomenal so we're pretty
much almost three-quarters of the way
through our fundraising goal
but we want to push past that if we can
so if you can uh donate
um the mods will be on twitch we'll be
dropping in
uh the the gofundme link is on twitter
as well it's everywhere
if you can donate anything for msf it's
gonna be awesome
and i just want to say thank you to
everyone who's donated anything so far
whether it's five pounds or 50 or 100 or
500 whatever it is it's
absolutely appreciated and you guys are
superb
superstars that's all i wanted to say
bob galdoff bit done
uh over to mike to to kick this off and
i'm just gonna sit here and be quiet
um looking forward to it thank you thank
you stu
uh can't echo everything that steve said
is uh enough
uh give money if you got five quid give
five quid you got
a thousand quid give it right great
super awesome
um here comes ed tucker ed's a great
mate um
super involved in the insect community
uh highly regarded
very very deep knowledge of the thing
right the way from grassroots security
right the way up to the cso level
um over you ed
cheers mate thank you um and just to
kind of echo on is is
donate what you can uh i'm unemployed
now and i'll be donating as soon as i've
finished here
um so just a quick i'm going to kind of
take you through
what i call joining the dots to cyber
security so let's let's draw the picture
to the unicorn and see what we can
achieve
uh firstly who am i uh
so i'm a defender hence i suppose blue
team
for many many many many many years in uk
government
the tax man of all people so positively
despised by everyone
then a consultant and then a vendor so
defender turned vendor and now
unemployed so i'm not trying to sell you
anything so don't worry on that front
uh won a bunch of awards which is really
nice uh generally just know a bunch of
people
like the subject matter like drinking
get along with people
and i've just got a few bits of my
experience to spare with you and
just see where we get to and if there's
anything to learn from that
um so basically kind of say what you see
um there's
there's a common problem that i see in
cyber security
and the industry today um something
that that holds many organizations back
in their maturity their ability to grow
learn and develop into a more effective
organization
certainly when it comes to defense and i
talk about defense as um
everything kind of on the internal side
so i'm not just talking about analysts
in a sock and things like that that's
you know blue team for me goes
way beyond that it's the whole
organization and everything they do
the whole culture and every piece that
sits with it um
there are many many more than a singular
problem to tackle but for me there's a
pivotal piece
that i'm going to focus on in particular
that that really
drives i think a wedge or a blocker or
is a real hamper
um to preventing stopping people
realizing their potential when it comes
to blue team or comes to security
securing the organization
and it goes way beyond just being able
to say kind of we take your security
seriously this is about actually doing
it
um quite simply for me too many
organizations and this is you know from
having been there and done it and also
spoken to my peer groups and i'm sure
most of us would actually if
we looked in the mirror heartily would
own up to it as well
um treat our initiatives our solutions
our activities in isolation
and by that what i mean is that we don't
really give true cognizance we don't
understand or we choose to ignore the
linkage between
each initiative and the overall goals
another pathway is to defining and
achieving that goal
so what i mean there is kind of we've
got dislocated security teams
running dislocated initiatives and
wonder why we're not progressing at the
pace that we should
uh within that as well it's kind of when
we look at our initiatives when we look
at our activities we're not
always conversant or understanding all
the different pieces of the puzzle that
make an effective outcome
you might disagree um you might not
think this is something you do
however if we just take it at a base
level and run
through what i think is a very
straightforward example
and we'll see where people sit so let's
start with security education and
awareness
this is something that was a bug bearer
of mine when i was at hmrc
it's something that i went and did as a
vendor as well and i want to speak about
that from from an example of why
i think as an industry generally it's an
example of how we don't see the dots we
don't join the dots together
and how we can use it to start to build
out this
theme and this changing mentality to
actually understand greater what we need
to do to achieve
um greater outcomes and greater goals so
awareness how many people
have a requirement to run a security
awareness program uh that'll be
absolutely everyone they might include
phishing simulations they might do
once a year 30 minutes of death by
powerpoint because they need to tick the
pci dss box
whatever it happens to be it's a
requirement for everyone um
however when we or when many of those
run through the process of defining the
overall goal
and the various links and dependencies
to make that happen do they actually run
through that
um far too often i hear security experts
or organizations when they're talking
about
awareness that their overall goal is to
raise awareness
and awareness in their organization or
maybe measure preparedness
and when neither really has any meaning
in terms of an actual goal
so awareness is not a goal
awareness in itself gets you little
unless you understand the linkage and
i'm just going to digress slightly um
because for me it feels like as an
industry itself that we're actually it's
designed to push us into a siloed
mentality
it's designed to push us into taking
things in isolation and not seeing the
bigger picture
whether it's crowds waves or insights
it's all looking at isolated components
and at no point you actually see where's
the join where's the linkage where's the
cognizance of people and process
where's the dependencies where's the
aspects that are outside
of our locus of control every technology
in the world is absolutely useless
unless you have people in process
to feed water it keep it up to date to
effectively use it to its fullest
capability and get beyond using just
five percent of what we paid for
and actually making the best use of it
so let's just go back to awareness while
we're thinking this and thinking of
quadrants and silos
um let's take a trip into the approach
of the adversary
um so the adversary that we're looking
at here let's take it as a simple that
we're going to look at those who use
phishing emails whatever it happens to
be
um quite often we say you need to think
in the
mind think like an adversary um in this
case it works purely to prove a point
um so how preposterous do you think it
would be
if adversaries worked in the way that we
do when it comes to security
um with siloed initiatives that seldom
join up um there'd be a lot less of a
threat
that's for sure um but think about it so
would an adversary look up
slightly less evil gartner for the
latest insight into what they should do
what initiative is in the top right
what's a leader um would they send
phishing emails
and then maybe realize a year or two
later that an exploit included with the
phishing email would take them to the
next level of maturity
alternatively would there be a tad more
joined up than that in pinning stages or
initiative to an overall strategic
outcome and goal
now so you think about adversaries
adversaries are mission oriented
um so so should we be so long as we can
define the actual desired outcome rather
than some near-sighted siloed goals so
awareness isn't the goal that we want to
achieve
um so would an adversary only send a
phishing email without ever considering
what happens
next well no it'd frankly be utterly
ridiculous to
to even come up with that concept yet
think how we of defenders approach our
controls our initiatives
so are we as joined up as the adversary
are we joined up at all
and and and if we're not joined up why
not
so i'm not just thinking about kind of
the analyst angle when it comes to
obviously your gardeners your forest as
you whoever i don't really care
um but also think about the different
touch points that the industry offers to
us whether it's conferences and the
majority of speakers our expert insights
uh
various webinar series and how much is
driven by a singular viewpoint and a
mentality
you know that there's this super
sophisticated emerging threat
vulnerability adversary whatever it
happens to be and i just happen to
offer the very cyber widget that combats
it
i'm not going to sell it directly to you
in any of these things but i'm going to
skirt around it so that you know my
technology's the one to buy
and it is basically a technology and
sales focused or rather siloed focused
approach
um thought leadership or really is it
sales thought
and i don't in any way blame sales
people for trying to sell
but i do blame an industry that places
that at the top
um where money is more important than
the actual security and the
and the achievable or the goals that we
want to actually get to
and there's nothing new or ever likely
to change in that but it's just got to
be recognized as to why we kind of have
this mentality in the way we approach
what we do
which all leads us kind of into this
silo or the funnel to ensure that the
focus is on the product
the solution the silo itself
but we've done that for years we've done
it for years and years and years and
years and years and a focus on
technology and a focus on siloed
initiatives and a focus on things like
doing awareness
because awareness is a thing that we
have to do and it's not really got us
anywhere
i don't know about you but for me it
doesn't feel like the world of security
is particularly in a better place than
it was say
10 years ago or 20 years ago we're still
carrying a massive massive legacy we're
still carrying an incredible debt we've
still got controls that we have no idea
whether they work or not are effective
we're still poor at risk management
we still look to the simple things the
things we're driven to which is
solid initiatives technology specifics
rather than actually looking at how we
address things across the whole
and understand how almost the domino
effect of activities actually work
together to achieve an outcome and if
you remove one of the dominoes then
you're likely to fail halfway
because what we're doing is we're
missing the web and i don't mean the
internet i'm talking about the web of
interconnectivity that runs throughout
everything we do and want to achieve so
one of the biggest changes i think we
can make as an industry or as a
discipline is to really alter how we
approach
the things and recognize linkage and
realize that everything we do is linked
and focus upon effectively one junction
on a spider's web that leads down
different pathways
so nothing itself is isolated there's
always knock-on effects there's always
dependencies there's always people
there's processes there's teams as goals
and of course there's gaps
and the more we recognize how things
bleed into each other
the more we'll actually design actions
with links in mind
and it'll enable us to affect better
change rather than masking a problem
or moving it a long one or ticking a box
it will also build a greater cognizance
of the things around our little world
that impact our effectiveness
things that we don't directly control
but can influence if we understand them
better
so kind of with that little tangential
run on to the side as to why i think we
think in a particular way
i want to come back to that little issue
of awareness where we started kind of
right off the
off the bat
so you raise awareness that's your goal
you've set that
a standard and you do it through
whatever mechanisms you do as we said
maybe once a year mandatory
security awareness training that sits
along your side your health and safety
and all the other bits that i have to do
to tick boxes or you do it properly you
know you use every mechanism possible to
get a touch point with your users to
drive
an awareness campaign that's predicated
on personal cyber security using every
mechanism possible
to build an aware workforce fab
absolutely great um you might even kind
of
use those mechanisms and and perpetually
continue to to drive kind of goals and
champions and
and every possible way that drives that
that awareness and go beyond kind of
bloody pci dss that said you had to run
it at least once a year and everyone
took that as a bare minimum did just
that
but that awareness what does it actually
get you so your business colleagues are
cyber aware
which means what exactly if you set a
goal of awareness and you want your
people to be aware
they are now aware and what
so maybe in one aspect they're more
likely to spot a phishing email
what we do and do what
do what with it what have you trained
them to do in terms of that awareness
you taught them to delete it in which
case you've taught them that
essentially they're masters of their own
risk and risk for the organization and
everything will happen at the user layer
and you from a risk management
perspective will be blissfully unaware
but you can see even just a very simple
step there that awareness kind of leads
into the necessity to undertake an
action
and let's not pretend awareness is going
to hit 100 of the people 100 of the time
and they'll always make the right
decisions along the way but even there
let's just kind of think about that so
let's factor in the fact that the
majority of email-borne threats
because it's a nice easy example to go
through um
are generic they're mass distributed
which generally means that in all
likelihood
you're going to have more than one
recipient in your organization
so let's say for example there are 10
you've got 10 recipients of a particular
email threat email born threat that are
in your organization
that's landed in the inbox super it's
got past the controls because things
always will that's just the way it is
deal with it so now these 10 people
all need to make the same positive
decision to delete the suspicious email
for your awareness to have had a success
for you to have actually achieved a
successful outcome when it really
matters which is when the actual
potential threat
lands in the inbox or it manifests
itself to that end user
and how confident are you that all 10 of
them are going to make the same decision
and actually enact that decision and
therefore achieve that success
so then even if we look at that from
there
we also have to acknowledge that this
happens to happen every single time
so even then as i said the security team
the risk team are blissfully unaware
as our risk management regime that this
is all done at the user level
it's still done at the inbox level it
never actually
flies at all in front of anyone that
needs to assess it from a risk this is a
risk potentially
manifesting up until the point of
potential impact or exploit within the
organization itself or being dealt with
and therefore one of your controls the
human and awareness actually working
and your risk management is blissfully
unaware that that happened and therefore
you don't know
to measure the effectiveness of that
control
so of course what if the user was to
report the suspicious email
would that be better well yeah of course
it would um but then from that awareness
of course we need to understand that
that user then needs to report it
um they need to then understand how to
report it
then maybe we could take an action
before some of the nine remaining
recipients have to make their decision
which sounds great
absolutely sounds great it sounds like
the type of thing that we should do
but as i said firstly we need to think
about how are they going to report it
and to whom
um will your analysts need to talk your
end users through the mechanisms of
forwarding the suspicious email as an
attachment so they can investigate it
and believe me it's something that has
to happen
and believe me it is easier said than
done
even just the simple thing of phoning up
a user and saying you're from security
you can almost feel
the clench the tension in the air before
you even start to have a conversation
about what's needed
and so so that user wants to report it
and we need to get a copy of the
attachments
so how will we find out if there are any
other recipients
do you have access to the mail server
there's a really simple one
or is that run by another team outside
of security maybe even a supplier
and do you have processes in place to
engage and prioritize their work
so without even trying and at the very
basic start of this journey
we've gone from awareness being an
initiative being a goal to already
leading outside of security and to
dependencies and processes with other
teams
other teams will have competing
priorities because funnily enough the
exchange team's primary focus
isn't security it's generally keeping
exchange from falling over
making sure it's kept up to date making
sure it's working well and making sure
any changes are put through in line with
change management
but now think about this for every
single step of the investigation
and the overhead as well that you've
just placed onto your security
operations
by moving the awareness action just from
delete to report
now of course reporting is far better
than deleted
you know but it comes with a cost it
comes with a significant overhead
moreover this is just the investigation
this is just firstly
reporting which understand that every
time you report something you've
generated work for another team within
your organization
but you also need to take meaningful
mitigating action otherwise
what's the point you may as well go back
to the user just deleting and hope that
that works every time
so simple thing can you purge a
suspicious email from all mailboxes
does it require email administration
team is that a supplier again does it
involve
change control believe me in some places
it actually does which sounds bonkers
because it's
a response in a sense to a potential
threat but in some places contracts have
written that you need a change control
in place um do you have authority or
security to actually do it and how
quickly can it be done
and can it be undone if you've made a
mistake
and again without even thinking and
without actually going into any depths
here
whatsoever we've already
got links from awareness into security
operations
into i.t operations and possibly other
processes
things like itel as i say from change
management you'll certainly have service
management in there
you'll need pre-ordained authority
without even
thinking now we're straight away
bleeding from one discipline into
another
when all we wanted to do was raise
awareness but to actually be effective
in what we want to do of having our
people aware making them able to spot
things that are potential threats that
might manifest even as simple as just in
the inbox
just focusing on that alone we need them
for those users to be able to report it
we need them to know who to report it to
we need an easy mechanism for them to do
it
we need them to report it to the
security people who need to be aware
that this overhead and be
ready for this overhead that's going to
come their way they will need to
undertake an investigation that will
potentially involve different data sets
different technologies
and potentially different teams and then
off the back of that make a decision and
enact something
as a result of it and straight away one
simple bit of awareness about a phishing
email has gone
right across an organization into all
sorts of different areas
but if we do that then we're starting to
look at a successful outcome
that maybe if we report things one will
be more aware from a risk perspective
because something has got through our
controls and landed in the inbox
we'll be able maybe to actually get
there before those other users need to
make a decision
and we can show the effectiveness of our
process controls
that actually our response is
potentially quicker than our users
but of course there's always a danger
because there's plenty of dwell time in
there that our users are going to be
quicker than us
and hopefully they'll make the right
decision and report it as well but
generally means that
you've got two tickets for the same
thing and you'll have to investigate
those
but without thinking as i said you've
already started to build a spider's web
just by looking at what happens next
so saying so what what happens when one
of these things occurs and what would we
like it to what would we what do we want
it to look like when it comes to making
successful interventions across the
organization
so that we can actually have a
meaningful impact when it comes to risk
reduction
and response to threats
so that overhead already is quite a cost
and it's the cost you pay for your
security operations team
um for your security operations team now
working more hand in hand with your
awareness team
now if you do security awareness and you
don't involve your security operations
team
then you really should how are you going
to make them aware of the latest threats
that really could manifest if your
security operations team are not working
with you to help you understand what
threats may manifest to those users
or what actions to take how to drive
those actions how to enact them how to
do something
which is bound to involve the operations
team how do i get in touch with them how
do i
log calls with them how simple is it be
how do i start to engage on a human
level between these different teams
how do i get my security teams to work
together which
you know it may seem ridiculous that two
security teams don't work together but
it's really really common it's
ridiculously common to see awareness and
operations
not work hand in hand it sounds bonkers
it sounds like one of the most obvious
things going
but it happens all the time
and sometimes you've just got to break
through those barriers and make it
happen yourself to make sure that
actually if you're in awareness and you
don't work with operations
go and meet them go and investigate go
and join with them just to understand
what type of stuff you can let your
users know about and vice versa
but then when we look at that that
investigative process of what we might
need to go through
um we can then look at it and kind of
see that that in terms of that once that
user hits
you know that that report action and it
comes to security to
operations to do something meaningful we
can then look at all the different steps
they have to go through to understand
well what is it they need to do to
undertake an investigation
and then take a meaningful action and
undertake potential
you know different actions depending on
how this threat potentially manifests
and the actions of the user at the other
end which may swirl down into different
parts of the spiders web
and then start to see how effective are
those pieces
you know you'll get phishing emails
you'll get rogue emails malicious emails
spam whatever it happens to be that's
reported to you
how good are you at actually enacting
that investigation how good are you at
making meaningful decisions how good are
you at getting the facts really quickly
and then how good are you at taking the
action the remedial action to protect
the organization
and of course are there pieces in there
that you can make slicker
is there a process aspect in there that
you can make slicker
is it possible to automate some of it is
it possible to use some kind of rules to
to help you understand some of that can
you use some of the native apis
available to you like
you know 365 there's the native search
api can you make use of this to make
some of the investigation better for you
and and yes you can frankly you know for
something like an email born threat
there are some obvious
tasks that any investigation will
complete
first of which you need a copy of it um
you certainly want the headers
you want any attachments and understand
those you want any links and understand
where they're going if you want to
discover if there's any other recipients
or any variants because let's face it
things like sender subject and that are
going to change
um do you need a human analyst to
undertake some of these acts
do you want things like the sender ip
address and do you want to do
reputation lookups on it do you want to
do who is information from those
registrars that understand the gdpr a
little bit better than others and we'll
actually give you information back
how much of that can you actually use
technology or aspire to use technology
to ensure that your dwell time gets
reduced as you undertake these
investigations
because you've added a greater overhead
to your security operations by making
your users more aware and asking them to
report things
and you see already then we're starting
to look at process optimization maybe
automation we'll hang on and maybe we've
got a strategy about automation
somewhere
um but what maybe we can't do today we
could aspire to use technology to do
tomorrow for repeatable tasks so when it
comes to things like the links or when
it comes to attachments as i say the ip
address lookups any spamless checks any
debark checks simple things that maybe
we can actually just do
in an automated fashion so that when
that user spots something because
they're far more aware they undertake
the reporting action
that as they undertake that report in
action or very soon after we start to
present the analyst with as much
information as possible to help the
investigation and get us closer to
decision making
and remediation as quickly as possible
and look at those and see can we make
those slicker as well and how can we
make it better
there's quite a lot in an investigation
such as this you could potentially use
technology to reduce the analyst
overhead so you can present them with
those results
and the decision-making but it does
require thought and it requires effort
and it requires collaboration and that
maybe you can see though how we can
maybe mitigate some of the overhead that
we've placed
because of awareness by just moving it
from move from delete to report
and how much more of a meaningful
outcome we can create if we start to
follow
all the different actions all the way
through the
now what the user reports it now what
operations have to get hold of it now
what they need to investigate it
now what they need to remediate now what
and all the different pieces
that make up those those puzzles and
those actions
because they'll all have sub-actions
within there
and you'll see that we break from
awareness
awareness being a goal which it isn't
and start to bleed into awareness and
operations
and process and people and relationships
and suppliers and other teams and then
potentially where
we can optimize aspects within that and
all
fit within the same flow which allows us
to look at a more goal-orientated
structure that
the awareness when it comes to say
phishing emails
has this long horizontal trail that
leads to a potentially successful
outcome
and that's where we need to start to
move our minds to
to start to make far more effective
decisions
across what we do as security
so when we think about kind of uh
remediation
um what we're on about there is is is
what we want to develop confidence
levels when we talk about things like
automation we want to have confidence
that this task is repeatable and make it
better
uh and i'm not talking about machine
learning again i said i'm not a vendor
anymore i'm unemployed so i'm not trying
to sell you anything um
but when i talk about things like
automation i mean an ability to
accelerate
something to to get results get to the
next action as quickly as possible
but in a way that actually you have
confidence it's the right thing and
presents you with the right
outcome to then take that forward and
make the next one
um and while we're at it there if you
think about it
is there anything else we can do with
the stiffness of information that our
investigation has covered
so we could obviously send bad urls to
firewalls and web gateways and
scene tools to see if anyone's clicked
on them or prevent anyone from making
any further access so long as actually
you've got the authority to make those
changes and put blocks in space
um we can send the sender ip address to
the email gateways and say no more from
that sender ip address please because
it's obviously delivering bad stuff to
us
whilst at least we investigate in case
there's another wave of the campaign
um and we're starting to get there into
more active controls usage and again we
need to consider things like item we
need to consider
pre-authorization our it operations
friends believe me you only need to
break a live service once for it to
really hamper your ability to make
change a second time
um and where are we requiring that we're
acquiring interactions potentially with
other teams so do you have the ability
to make changes to firewalls web
gateways where proxies are exactly our
good old friends in networks who we
blame for
literally everything that could possibly
go wrong um
and and do we need them now to join the
investigation party do we need
them to join kind of the incident
response party now you might have this
already
trained you might have mechanisms to
engage with them but do you also
understand when they've got competing
priorities so example if there is a
live service incident and there is a
security incident which one's going to
take precedence because
can you actually enact your security
response if there's a live service
incident at the same time what we're
talking about
essentially there is automation and
orchestration in one sense or another
um so whether people are trying to sell
you saw um
or whatever it happens to be or you've
got a strategic initiative about that if
you actually start to think about what
is it i want to automate and why
and why might i want to orchestrate
things and how could that make a
material impact that links all the way
back to something at the start
all of a sudden we've got a far more
coherent case for
proving the ability proving the need to
automate proving the need to orchestrate
and linking it back to an initial um to
an
initiative that then has a successful
outcome that saw
in some form that doesn't have to be a
vendor capability that can be you doing
some form of automation
and you using it to basically produce
requests to make changes
um that you can do that and start to
prove that initiative
and make it more impactful and more
effective in the way that you approach
potential threats and risks that can
manifest in your organization
so we can go from awareness being a goal
to
actually awareness leading into us being
able to look at process
automation and process optimization and
potentially orchestration and build a
business case for how that could be
a beneficial way to reduce overhead and
reduce risk and make us far more
effective
with kind of proven risk metrics
and when we look at that as well is that
a lot of the information there
excuse me a lot of the information there
that we've picked up from the
investigation you could also deem us as
snippets ifc's if you want to
uh of potential threat intelligence that
we could then share with partners
and we can be a producer of threat
intelligence which i'm sure threat
intelligence is on our list of
strategies of something we want to do at
some point
um and already then we complete from
awareness into
process optimization into operations i.t
land i.t operations itil and potentially
into future strategic builds of security
automation
and orchestration and also threat
intelligence as a producer not just a
consumer
and we can start to build out this wider
wider spider's web from all of a sudden
all we wanted to do was protect the
organisation from phishing emails
but actually we're starting to build
coherent
business cases coherent strategies
coherent plans for how our maturity can
build and build and build
and get us further and further forward
in what we want to achieve
and then we can think about well we
could actually start to think about
metrics in this space as well so what's
the relationship between
people reporting versus um our security
team getting there first and actually
finding things
in people's mailboxes when we become
aware of a threat from the amazing
threat intelligence that we pick up
um or we just read the things like
dynamic blog and get something really
useful and actually use that every
morning to try and find something within
people's inboxes
so are people able to report before we
spot them can we spot them before the
users
but also then what time does it take us
to run the investigation what time does
it take us
to remediate well of course if our users
are reporting really quickly then it
takes us an absolute age to do what we
need to do because the overhead on the
security team is too great
you start building a business case for
more people or you start building the
case for
process optimization to reduce the
overhead you start being able to measure
meaningful metrics when it comes to
preparedness our preparedness isn't how
many phishing
simulations did we click on this week
it's whether actually
can we deal with things when it really
matters can we proactively go and find
things in users in boxes
based on threat intelligence can we
react to our users reporting things to
our security teams
and the lead in an effective and timely
investigation
and remediation outcome that reduces
risk to the organization
and if we can measure that in terms of
of how that manifests how often it
manifests and our effectiveness in doing
it
and finding where our dwell and process
gaps are we can start to deliver
meaningful metrics that allow us to look
at areas to improve and measure
the improvement to our security
operations as an example
and also use meaningful risk metrics
when it comes to making risk decisions
which shouldn't be beyond the width of
man but appears to be when it comes to a
lot of organizations
and also kind of the one vital thing
that almost always gets lost in this is
a feedback loop to the user
so of course the result of everything
that we want to do we always want to go
back to the user
and inform them what happened because
the worst thing that we can possibly do
is get users to report things to us and
never ever go back to them and tell them
what happened as a result of it because
why the hell should they do it a second
time if it just disappears into a black
box
a we start to lose the engagement with
users and b we lose a potential touch
point with the user to educate
if they're reporting spam to us we can
start to educate them on the difference
between spam and fishing
if they make the right decision and
report something
that is potentially fishing a
potentially malicious email to us and we
can take an action
let's go and reward them let's go and
touch them let's go and talk to them
let's go and praise them let's go and
show that we're a care and sharing
security team and maybe people will
start engaging with us more and more and
more because we're human beings and
we're just trying to do a good job
and then when you look at all those
different things that i've just
absolutely whistled up through there
how much of that can you directly
control
and how much of that can you influence
and where do you need to beg steal or
borrow
to make a meaningful impact at one of
the stages
in that process flow all the way through
from
raising awareness about phishing emails
through to enacting and purging them
from a mailbox before users
uh interact with them and enhancing our
controls related to the
iocs that you've picked up and also
sharing that as threat intelligence with
other partners
what can we actually do today what do we
need to involve suppliers or other teams
in
are we able to do that in an effective
way and can we do it better
now remember this is all just one
initiative within awareness
so imagine the possibilities if we did
this with everything
and if you think in a goal-oriented way
then you can spider into all sorts of
areas
and then if you look at that you can
spider into them for a reason because
there are clear touch points
clear touch points between them and you
can start to see these knock-on effects
you can start to see these dependencies
and you can start to see the building
blocks and links
and each component or dots if you're
joining the dots
when it spiders off before you know it
you'll have multiple junction points
multiple dots that feed into several
different areas
which will tell you they're really
important things they're key
stages and key dots within your
organization
and those are the things that you really
need to be good at and the things that
they initially touch that they receive
from
and put out too because that's where
their key dependencies and outcomes
are and that's areas where you can
really start to push outwards from each
of those central dots that are really
really important
really heavy usage and actually start to
build the things around them to make
them better and better and slicker and
slicker
but only by kind of thinking in a more
strategic way in a more linear way
and looking at these kind of linkages
and joins
can we really define actual maturity
uplifts
and that's not to say they're all easy
that's not by any way stretch
the imagination but you can start to see
benefits and a rationale of aiming
towards them
and why and you're in a much more
coherent space
if you're able to first see the dots and
see the linkage between these different
aspects of what you do on a daily basis
and then join them and not just at
singular initiative level but actually
at goal level you can start to look at
wider
goals and also how they
feed into other areas of the business
that you interact with on a daily basis
there's something more here about just
identifying and visualizing an
understanding pathways and properly
linking them to develop a coherent
picture
across your organization
now one thing that will really jump out
here is relationships relationships are
so
so important you can basically just go
out and spend on technology and hope for
the best
uh and you can try to follow these
policy pathways effectively
and drive maintainable change but to do
the latter requires a heavy investment
in relationships
then and that might seem a bit weird but
yes relationships um
hopefully i've articulated a little bit
maybe sporadically
that a hell of a lot of security both
what you do today or might do
differently tomorrow
actually sits outside of security or
relies heavily on things outside of
security
now and even more so when you look
beyond this simple example
and factoring things like users and
privileges and assets hard soft virtual
and the absolute myriad others
don't even start on patching and how
much that might even actually be yours
and how much
it might rely on many other people who
organize teams across our organization
and when there's other teams
and other people and potentially
conflicting priorities
regardless that they're not in your
direct control
so what you have to do is foster an
ability to exert some influence
or control and that's done through
relationships
at an individual at a team people and
process relationships
and it doesn't come easy and often these
teams are not focused on security
believe it or not they don't live your
world
every hour of every single day or at all
be cognizant of who they are
listen engage as a human and build a
relationship
um the approach to identifying these
pathways and dependencies
and teams and processes and
relationships will help in bridging gaps
in your effectiveness
um it's about clarity and honesty and
taking the time to understand and think
wider
building a picture and through this
identifying where there are gaps or weak
components and areas for improvement
um maybe some kind of road map who knows
much of which is going to be free it's
not going to be a technological fix it's
not going to be a panacea
the predominant cost will be time and
effort and taking that step forward and
being the human being and giving as much
as receiving
think of bridging like drawing the line
between two dots
um the picture is not completed there's
gaps between some of the dots
the lines may not be bowls from day one
you know there might be pencil there
might be dotted lines but some linkage
is better than
non and it starts with finding the dots
in the first place
so when you're looking to bridge these
gaps between teams or
if you know just alpha techie banging
heads against other teams including
suppliers
it can be really really really easy to
fall into a cycle of distrust and
conflicts
easy without even trying especially if
you're alpha techies it
just happens in seconds um
when you're only looking at your
perspective or your need
it rarely achieves much other than the
occasional fleeting win
when you're proving them wrong getting
one over on them
um basically getting some success at
their outcome which we're at their
expense
which kind of makes your thing move
better a little bit but then also drives
a team that doesn't like you and
therefore will be a blocker to you in
the future especially when you need it
what's the point
what we also need to do here is change
behavior which can be
really difficult sometimes for security
teams it can be very difficult for
technology
teams in general and technologists what
we need to do is encourage teams
individuals and yourself to reach out
and take the first step
in understanding what these other teams
are all about what their drivers are
their overheads their blockages their
culture their ethos
take the first step towards empathy
you'll all have roles to play in the
success of the organization you work for
and supply too um take that step help
yourselves to understand how you can
make
interaction more empathetic more
collaborative and common understanding
with other people's purposes
and where you have conflict or blockers
how often do you work towards
making
that mutual concession or even conceding
ground
to make their work lives easier not
yours
theirs take the first step off of the
hand of collaboration it's honestly far
more beneficial in the long run
and in that way kind of a mutual culture
is born
it means to build relationships
streamline processes
join these dots and take a dotted line
into a full
thick bold line or remove a dot
altogether and go straight between the
two
overcome blockages moreover demonstrate
to other teams how by taking that step
of being the conciliatory
team being the team that reaches out
first you can work towards a more
fruitful engagement and ultimately
success
mutual success times felt building
relationships developing an
understanding of other teams and
encouraging the culture of communication
will be timed far better spent than on
angst or conflict
or just on technology in isolation
as a leader it's absolutely imperative
that you demonstrate the behaviors
both to your team and to theirs and as
team members don't be afraid to take the
step as well sometimes you know
your leadership might not see it you
recognize that you have a dependency
a dwell because of this lack of
interaction or relationship between
teams between two dots
in the overall picture don't be scared
to reach out yourself
and start to make that happen and start
to build that relationship
it doesn't happen overnight and nor does
the ultimate success
but start along the path
um i've been guilty of falling into into
the conflict trap
on many many occasions sometimes just
down to dislike
dislike of an individual person and i
can honestly say all it's done is waste
time and energy
uh i might have felt good once by
beating them in a meeting and getting
one over them and
honestly it achieved nothing my best
successes came from actually making
mutual concessions
with suppliers as well who made money
off my concessions but it actually meant
that i'd achieved a better outcome
and i got a better relationship with
them not even meeting halfway sometimes
but building relationships and building
trust
and relationships that continue to
thrive um
making incremental gains in what i
wanted to achieve and forging alliances
with other people who would then help
fight my corner
came to other bridges and other gaps and
this has been where the good gets
done recognizing these dots and starting
to actually build between them and none
of this is technology driven this is me
building relationships and being a human
being
and being conciliatory crowd and
actually wanting to work with people
sometimes you've got to continue 100 to
someone else's way of working
it's just how it is but if it gets
things moving and improves what you can
do today then do it
don't be afraid to give ground you can
work on it as a build for a relationship
and they'll see you just wanting to work
with them not independently or against
them and it all starts with you making
that first step to conciliation
don't wait for someone else to take it
because you're going to be waiting
forever and it's going to achieve
nothing and put simply will change by
thinking differently by approaching
things differently and it's why i talk
about things like horizontal thinking
joining the darts
linear just to illustrate how things
join in this fashion
against the backdrop of an industry that
drives us towards vertical thinking that
drives us towards silos and magic
quadrants of waves and stuff that
doesn't join up
and of course it aims to make us believe
that our problems are
irreducibly complex and we can't
possibly solve these problems without
faith in a vendor or consultancy an msp
whoever
leader whereas actually they're not
irreducibly complex no matter how much
you're told about sophistication
legacy debt whatever it happens to be
you can break things down into
understandable components for which you
can then start
to build that spider's web of knowledge
of that component
and how all the things are joined to it
in these linear pathways
and if you can do that then you can
improve on some of these things
gradually and you'll get better
and you'll get better in meaningful ways
but always try to build upon an overall
view it's bloody hard
but even at a local level you can
improve whether that's your daily
processes or building relationships with
dependent teams your overall strategy
your adversarial understanding
none of it happens overnight most of all
though
think differently don't just do what
industry pushes you to do
don't be that person who says where are
you on the on the quadrant
be someone that looks and kind of says
if i'm making a technological investment
what are the dominoes either side of it
or all around it that need to actually
be in place and need to work well for
that technology to have a material
impact
and to ensure that technology doesn't
drip from where it is today
implementation as an effective
controller effectively in whatever way
to somewhere in the future where frankly
it does bother all for me to do
all of that you need to approach things
in a different way
and that's what i'm talking about
horizontal thinking that's what i'm
talking about
joining the dots to cyber security
and adversaries are getting more
sophisticated what we do
so is technology in fact it has done
what i've been walking on to you right
now
the tools of their disposal their
awareness their abilities it's all the
same
the same can be said for defenders yeah
adversaries though are not held back by
overarching legacy that we insecurity
or the silos that we create and maintain
beautifully for ourselves
there's no quick fix there's no magic
bullet there's no fifth generation
cyber widget that will solve our ills
there is incremental and well thought
out change
that leads to improvements and the
improvements that mean something in our
spider's web of actually effective
security
it's that changing focus and mindset and
operation that makes a difference
and we can use things existing within
our organization to our advantage to
accelerate change
things like if you've got digital
transformation programs um
but the main thing in there is you have
to be able to articulate things well
you have to be able to identify all
these different parts
whether it's linear parts of one
particular problem and
actually articulate them to other people
whether it's other teams to
process owners to investment boards
business cases to actually build up the
design of how we join these dots in a
much
better much streamlined slicker manner
to operate that overall process in a
better way and achieve an actual goal
um if we joined all of our dots we might
just build a picture
of achievable maturity and have the
ability to articulate it properly and
set out the steps required to go
there and give it a go generally it
can't be any worse than what we do today
and that generally is it thanks
hopefully that made a little bit of
sense you nailed that
ed's testimony there was really um a
point about people
at the end of the day it's all about
people um
it can always only ever be about people
and that's the only way you're gonna get
things done right
there's a reason why people process
technology in that order yeah
yeah people people and process you know
you you look at as i said you know you
just look at kind of i want to make my
people aware of phishing emails so that
they'll
hopefully be able to spot them report
them and we'll do something meaningful
and actually protect the organization
how much of that how much of that is
technology and how much of that is
people in process i'll give you a clue
90 percent of its people process yeah
yeah
you know when you when you rely on
technology to do it as well and you
haven't got the people process
it's when things start to go seriously
wrong anyway and usually people don't
have the processes to manage the
technology if they haven't got that in
place so it all falls apart right
house cars it does it does you know
which is why we use five percent of what
we buy
and why kind of we might implement
things you know in absolute perfect
state from day one and within a year
they've drifted into god knows what
because we've not understood the
processes that run around them
yeah and for years like change
management yeah
and for years you'd hear this notion
horrible notion i hate it that
people are the soft underbelly of the
organization what a terrible
thought actually people are your
frontline defenders of your organization
yeah they're the people at the front
line that are going to actually stand in
the way
of you as a business and a devastating
attack
yeah absolutely and and also you know
it's not just those people there but
then you know your next line is also
people because that's your
that's either your awareness teams who
are trying to drive awareness to those
those
end users or it's your operations team
who can actually
risk management teams and it's all
people it's all people that need to be
effective in what they do but they all
need to be effective
at each step and they can't be effective
in isolation because actually it doesn't
work
if i've got two effective people here
that aren't joined up then actually
are they really being affected yeah yeah
so notionally
we could never argue that people within
the organization or people generally are
the weakest link people are actually the
strongest link
i i would i would probably say that we
we enable people to be weaker links than
they should be
because we don't because we don't create
the links
yeah so in fact we disable people
yeah yeah in a sense yes people should
be your first line of defense basically
really in that sense they they should be
but if you think kind of you
you know if we talk about people being a
link then there needs to be something
for it to link to
if it doesn't link to it then is it even
a link yeah
yeah and then of course that makes the
link to something else you think about a
chain that's
why we talk about change and why we talk
about links and linkages and yet when it
comes to
actually doing stuff inside we never
think about links
yeah and we don't move forward
okay um thanks ed really spirited
testimony
you're a great guy and i hope you get
some work sorted out soon
cheers give me a job well you
deserve it oh yeah oh stu is
there got the the phone
is here actually i need to speak to you
anyway so yeah we'll do that monday yeah
tomorrow
i'll hand off mc duties for a little
while over to stew
and so he was going to introduce tanya
yancer who's going to be giving a
keynote speech
on the blue team track so stu where are
you mate
thank you very much i just wait for
tanya are we are we still alive
[Music]
foreign