Oh weapons-free transitioning hi my name
is Ralph I am 8 years old and welcome to
the many hats club isolation corner I'm
presenting this today because my daddy
doesn't know how don't what's done good
boy why don't hey hey everybody welcome
finally it was my son because I partly
don't know how to present
welcome to the many hats club isolation
con I'm talking to you here from the UK
I am absolutely delighted to be joined
by some awesome guests today and be
joined by 70 people across the world so
thank you everyone and and I yes yeah
this is a amazing event put together in
literally a small number of weeks so
we're really really happy about this
luckily you won't have to hear me talk
too long I want to just be I've got I've
got three other people join with me to
come and kick this conference off
stripped Coulson Stu pursed and Stuart
winter tears I'll be joining me after I
do a brief introduction of the comp oh
so we've got quite a jam-packed day over
three great tracks and you know I'm
really really happy and really grateful
to the team here many hats Club who have
worked tirelessly through the nights and
some cases very late nights to put this
together so we can you know provide you
all these great speakers from the Red
Team side the blue team and purple team
there are a mixture of very experienced
and well-known speakers to people that
may be doing their very first conference
talks so you know there's a really good
track put on today for everyone and
there's something for everyone as well
this really really good talks so please
I'll see check those out over the course
of the day and we've also got some other
great things lined up as well so we got
to introduce our keynote so we have
three keynotes so Dave Kennedy with his
talk the red pill or the blue pill and
that one's kicking off at 4:00 p.m. UTC
on the red team Channel we've also got
Tanya she hacks purple doing her talk on
purple is the new black
and looking for that talk as well that
will be on the blue team tack at seven
o'clock UTC again lots to lots of you
look for two there and then actually
kicking things off after this
introduction we're doing at three p.m.
UTC we've got rated acted with the
complete history of hacking and freaking
so really cannot wait for that as well
and I'll be doing a pretty of an inch
right there and I've seen some of his
stuff as well that he's doing it proves
to be a really in-depth and exciting
talk so there's lots going on uh really
I want to kind of talk a bit about who
we are and how this came about because
for anyone doesn't end many hats Club
we're a disc or community we've been
around for about two-and-a-half years
now which has absolutely flown by we're
you know we're about eight thousand just
surpassed eight thousand members and
we're a discord partner community as
well so we get some some cool stuff
happening there and sort of server perks
and all this kind of great stuff but but
primarily it's about us giving back to
the community about us providing
opportunities to people to collaborate
to share ideas we have a podcast which
we've had like a load of guests on about
a hundred episodes in I think or
something like that
everyone everyone you know in the
industry you may know from tinker sector
Dave Kennedy to some of the podcast
guests actually at some of the talks
we've got today and and you know we have
lots of things that we do and we just
want to give back all the time so we've
done charity events before we we
co-hosted the beer farmers back on one
last year which raised lots of money for
charity before that and Dave Kennedy was
very kind to donate us five derbycon
chickens which we then auctioned off for
charity raise money for innocent or
diner initiative and many other kind of
organizations as well so you know we're
always about trying to raise money where
we can and this seemed like a perfect
opportunity so you know we're really
we're lucky and really thankful for
everyone it's actually can come here
today who's donated or supported our
cause or offer to help else always
participating in the CTF so people like
offensive security who've donated two of
their
two of their computer became anxious to
us big shoutout to TJ null 2.3 for
hosting our CTF they've done a really
awesome job and that's kicking off quite
nicely I think I saw by 80 plus people
scored so far and on that CTF and I know
that's about 150 people signed up plus
when I checked last night so that's
really good an RSS risk as well for
actually being our very first donator
and sponsor donator as well so really
really thankful but we are doing this
for a reason and the main reason we're
doing this is to raise money for
medicine soundfont ears or MSF or aka
Doctors Without Borders and we want to
raise as much as we possibly can we have
a goal of 10,000 but currently I think
about five seven or five seven something
at the moment I need to check that it's
on the screen and you guys can see it
because you've got the livestream of it
but you know we want to raise as much
money as we can today so if you can
donate anything any small amounts no
matter you know how much it is will be
really appreciated because these guys do
great work all year round their front
line in front of you know when there's
things like outbreaks like the kovat 19
outbreak as well and like Ebola has
happened in the past these are the
people that the doctors that go out
there and do a lot of that charging work
they put themselves at risk all the time
and you know this is actually an email I
got back from MSF so this quote here
from Andy Dennis which you can beat it
actually this app is on on on sort of
Friday night after I reached out to them
last week and they said that's a lovely
email actually about how how thankful
they are that we're helping them at the
moment so the more that we can do that
the real impact we can actually make so
obviously on do my standing on a soapbox
if you can donate that'd be great it's
what we put this on for free we're
trying to do as much as we can for free
so we can put everything we can into
raising money for this great cause so I
just want to thank everyone again we've
had so many donations so far I just want
to thank everyone again who's donated
and it is really really genuinely
appreciated by myself and everyone here
who's behind the con oh and again like I
said it isn't just they don't just do to
work all over the world and they do some
some amazing things so a really really
important part of this conference and
the whole reason we decided to do it as
well yeah we did try and do a con last
year a physical con and we just realized
it was you know for a community of our
size that we don't make any money we're
not you know profit organization you
know we're just a bunch of people
working together online to do things and
we've done some quite awesome things
recently and but but realistically you
know we try too big to us we kind of
failed at that so I actually thought
this year we were going to do a virtual
conference because we're an online
community and with everything that come
up and other virtual conferences spun up
no three weeks ago we decided let's do
it
and yeah it's been an amazing journey
and we're really really happy that we've
got here and not just the talks we've
got today there are two awesome after
party activities that are going to be
streamed over three channels so at 21 15
UTC I'd be proud to announce that the
beer farmers pub quiz will be going live
and the link to that pub quiz will be
dropped into the chat the twitch
channels like slightly just before but
things go live so you've got time to
create team or to just sign up to it and
see what happens and we've got some
prizes to give away for that as well be
a farmer's what some merch and I think I
will have a couple of training programs
to give away as well for that so the
security company is actually kindly
donated to training packages which I'll
get into the into the kind of slide
decks for the the closing ceremony as
well before the up for pub quiz kicks
off and then at 10 o'clock UTC whitey
cracker has kindly donated his time to
do a gig for us so we absolutely can't
wait for that so it's going to be pretty
awesome we want to call with me other
day and yeah it's going to be absolutely
great so really really looking forward
to it and again lots going on so this is
an interactive day as well so we've got
moderators on the twitch channel we've
got moderators on the discord channels
for people that are listening on discord
we've got people in our community that
donate their time to really help out so
if you've got questions for anyone
during the talks especially during you
know that the keynotes on this kind of
stuff all the talks there will be a
dedicated
compared during those talks so we've got
on the on the kind of red team channel
after this we've got in Thornton Trump
and Shawn right and also Kim Crawley
will be kind of floating around the
channels as well
we've got Stu Hearst who will be doing
some stuff on the blue team channel with
Mike Thompson for the beer farmers and
then we've also got comparing we've got
and the Zephyr fish and we've also got
Christy Morgan aka salt fish joining to
do the red the purple team track and
I'll be floating between the tracks and
introducing certain speakers as well so
we've got plenty people to host to keep
the day entertaining to kind of keep
things moving and we'll all have
moderators feeding in channels to that
as well
obviously you know we are obviously
moderating the chats as well so try and
keep it clean anyone that does anything
offensive or C will be booted off the
channels and all that kind of great
stuff we do have code of conducts what
kind of brilliant stuff to protect
people we're here to have fun we're here
to raise money but ultimately we're here
you know we're here to ultimately have a
good time as well in this bring people
together and share ideas as part of
everyone being stuck at home or what
kind of great stuff so that was my very
quick overview I started doing 15
minutes I did it in ten so there's more
time for us to talk so we're gonna we're
gonna kick things off with the stews so
I'll be joined by Stu Hurst
CEO Coulson and it's Joe winters here so
hello guys and I'll see Stu hearse is
currently cycling on his bike so yes yes
so yeah that that just that just
happened right um so yeah so guys do you
want to give brief intro to yourself as
we asked Yukon I guess so I want you
hearse to stop why yes I love doing this
because this just outrageous all right
I'm building up quite a sweat e^x I've
been on for 45 minutes so hi everyone
thank you for spending time with us
today thanks to everyone putting this on
it's awesome really especially in the
short time frame during a crazy time
I am the principal cloud security
engineer at just eat you'll see my boss
later on Kevin fielder who's on our
panel I think and my background has been
with Internet companies mainly for those
who don't know I am and morphed into
cloud security over the last couple
years we've stood quite a bit on some
meetups and things and great to be part
of the community so thank you all thank
see Stuart courses yes so I I this year
set off on my own as freelancers that
works out well with ir35 and cope it so
let's kind of put a stop to a lot of
things I'm yeah unfortunate I've known
pet for quite a while I've enough LM
just turn it work out when I first met
you it's been some time I think it'd be
starts Manchester I think yeah possibly
but but yeah so Who am I I'm a guy who
does stuff insiders like most of us face
and ladies of course as well yeah and
strip which tear yeah with areas risk
really my passions for secure design and
automation scaling threat modeling that
sort of thing so that's me
excellent and I think I excuse myself
I'm Stu I founded the many hats Club
many to half years ago and I've been an
InfoSec for for longer than I care to
imagine but yeah and do social
engineering all that kind of crazy stuff
so yeah pretty pretty awesome okay so Mr
Coulson you had some things you wanted
to talk about maybe start with some
subjects give us some stuff to natura
about anyway I thought I'd kind of intro
obviously this forced use so we kind of
nicknamed ourselves to come and it also
kind of this Four Horsemen of the
Apocalypse so I have been trying to work
out which ones which I actually spent
last night trying to work out which ones
death pestilence etc I still not got it
really right so if anyone in the chat
wants to put it which one of us for is
pestilence death except we go for it
that'd be quite fun and we maybe a
Twitter poll or something crazy cuz
someone's gonna do it and know they will
and Schupak will win probably all of
them I'm I'll see you about that in
isolation because the weird wonderful
world were in at the moment and I
suppose their question Xiuquan is how
are you actually coping in this weird
wonderful world and then
to stay Kopacz cash or in a really
remote location to where we are so how's
things yeah yeah I am thanks to I'm in
southern Spain and southern Spain as you
know how these difficulties and then
went on real lockdown we can't even go
out to exercise or anything
now the main difference for me I was
already working remote so I was already
prepared for this and I'm I'm a bit of a
hermit anyway to be honest I just am so
it's kind of in some ways it's produced
the world I rather prefer I know that
sounds sick you know I'm pleased pleased
that I don't mean to belittle the
illnesses and deaths of course I don't
but um you know there's less traffic
everything's clean and clear and that's
lovely in that sense um
the children at home and but I've been
teaching Carroll my wife how to teach
now exactly as we are here and to teach
the Spanish teachers to do the same so
in some ways I quite like it
but I know that sounds a bit horrible to
say so you'll have to forgive me on that
one I'm afraid
well allowed an opinion so good opinion
I think would go to the next most remote
person which is Scotland released you
heard he's quite clearly is loving this
because he's on a set of bike who's that
doing work yeah I suppose
similar to just you in Spain I work from
home anyway most of the time so the
weekdays haven't been too different in
terms of routine and structure what I
would say and we had a bit of
conversation yesterday when we were
testing the audio that um these are by
no means normal circumstances no so just
because some of us happen to work from
home normally and we continue to do that
I think there's an underlying stress and
anxiety
anyway amongst amongst everybody I know
for any of you that about shopping and
just trying to do what you need to do
there's a very strange atmosphere
there's your the merging this it's like
nothing we've seen before and I think
we're trying to get our day jobs done to
the best of our abilities while we move
our way through this madness I think
it's regardless of if you're quite used
to being home a lot the fact that you
can't get out and have some of those
mechanisms normally that you would use
especially at weekends like this which
it's even sewn the in Scotland which
brightens our friends me
so yeah I think we're just all getting
by on with it the fact that everybody's
in the same position for me sort of
makes it a little bit easier it feels
like it's not a sliding scale for
anybody it's everybody's going through
the same same pain really so yeah yeah
trying our best to just get through it
absolutely gee Peck obviously we've had
Ralph on already and can we just say
massive hats off to your your son there
absolutely nail there's an opener yeah
I'd like to see him onstage in to tell
yourself no definitely self just thought
Ralph nailed it
how's life with you with kids at home
trying to do a day job something yeah
you know you're fooling the in in the
middle of business at the moment yeah
I've got I've got three kids swell right
so that's and they're all under eight
well yeah eight five and three so so
yeah my house is just like a zoo pretty
much and then it gets trashed and so
yeah it's good
oh so for me it's been quite interesting
so I do work from home occasionally but
given the role that I do so lot the such
engineering the physical so she ain't
doing stuff and I'm quite
customer-facing so I'll go to lots of
talks and lots of events and I'll do the
consulting with customers so it's been a
real promote for a work perspective it's
been a real interesting kind of change
because I've taken over a bigger team
recently and I've had to consume those
and then try and work out or how do we
do a lot of these services remotely how
do we then there has been quite easy in
some cases like a governance risk and
compliance project where you're kind of
going and consulting and doing risk
assessments well actually you can do a
lot that remotely anyway and also of
course do it face to face but it's
actually worked out quite nice you can
do things on teams or assume if they
really want to use that anyway and yeah
and so like it's worked out quite nicely
I did a like a nap sec talk to like 200
developers and we got a production crew
in to kind of you know snatch it up a
bit and make it look nice and it works
very well so you know we're kind of
changing things in a business level to
kind of accommodate that to kind of just
get through it and try and work out what
we can still do stuff we're still here
from a personal level I also you like
the travelling I like the balance
between that and so
me home and being at home all the time
is been brilliant and although my wife
said still don't see the kids enough
which is fair enough because I've been
quite busy recently but and I'd like to
do more that next week after this
conference is done but it's been a bit
of a culture shock for me and mainly
that the biggest thing I've noticed
which is being you know quite quite
scary as that officer was in London
right up until the literally the days
before everything shut down and you can
see people still not wearing masks still
not wearing any PPE walking around and
then you come down to where I live
and the sticks the other side of the
country and even yesterday when I went
to supermarkets still no one wearing
gloves or masks or any kind of
protective equipment I'm just walking
around you're thinking because it's not
as prevalent down here maybe it is
London maybe there's a slight worry that
oh we're OK because we're really
promoting there's any bit like three
four hundred cases down here or
something like that in the last few
years and so I think I think the the
psychological effect I've seen affects a
lot of people in the community so look
at like my community you can see a lot
more people under stress and strain I'm
worried and I think there's a undertone
that's Dewhurst mentioned that this is
these are unusual circumstances and I
think you know we just have to kind of
work out okay mentally we have to stay
strong and realize this will pass
eventually and we have to work out how
we can get through it you know to come
out the other side with our mental
health in tax as well yeah and we
obviously will come out of this this
will end it's what the world our
industry looks like when that happens
the we can't be the only company that
I'm the one that I work for where you
know an awesome tech company anyway but
but we fundamentally shifted from being
a global business and offices to fully
remote within ten days and we had a lot
of Tector to cater for that even though
there was a lot of internal work that
went on some great teams but we've we've
proved that we can run a business now
during a crisis remotely and I just
wonder what that's going to mean for the
next stages of not just my company but
but every kind of tech organization or
Internet face and kind of kind of
organizational you'll be interesting to
see I think you just said it then about
how this is almost like the new normal
and I'm really interested to ask I'm
probably the stupidest you host you're
probably given the great example to
start with is this the new normal do we
think post kovaydin all this craziness
rumor at the moment did we actually
think this will be new this is what we
will now do from here on will we just
live at home and and actually can get
rid of rate great big color for office
blocks of you know cost a fortune to run
and maybe we see business move to this
it's gonna be difficult to argue against
it because we've proven it I mean that's
a bit of a catch-all phrase now finding
it very difficult lots of reasons but
fundamentally many will keep going this
ignition changes that's for sure but
then we do have to fetch in those folks
that genuinely like to go to the office
they go to work for social reasons as
well that's I find that's not
necessarily a big factor in our industry
and we probably know why but there are
folk that are gonna want to go back and
so I think we will see change perhaps
not everybody but I did I don't think
we're coming out of this in the same
world as we went into it I think they'll
be a remote working revolution I think
yeah I think this would be the site a
lot a lot of companies and actually if
you look at business continue I had I
caught up I was talking on a podcast few
weeks ago about business continuity
planning and stuff like this
and about that you know the fact that a
lot of people like actually realizing
that continuity plan wasn't fit for
purpose it was all theory and they
actually put into practice like properly
its practice governments yeah we go we
got this covered and then like you yeah
we got this no no let's gonna spend lots
of money on stuff that gets wasted but
but like I think that that kind of has
made people realize that you know
actually these plans are actually quite
useful and maybe that's a way that they
want to revisit these things but but you
know like we'll see we'll see a lot of
change after this because some
organizations who have gone through this
we've actually fared frame
well we'll go well actually that wasn't
much of a headache yes we might have to
respect things for continuous kind of
working this way maybe we'll have a
percent central work first force that
can work as much they want from home and
maybe a percentage that spit their time
a bit more with that flexibility that
comes in mind and then maybe some
organizations may just go to kind of
that hot-desking methodology where
they're just going to have like a hot
desk office where people pop in pop out
when they want and I think that's quite
nice and the some organizations happen
anyway right a lot you know I can be
remote as much as I want and you know
driven by projects make me but if I'm if
I haven't got projects I can choose to
go to work in London or wherever or stay
at home and so you know I think it's
important where where it's flexible to
do that that those those opportunities
are there and I think that's that's
really gonna help things moving forward
I think I mean of course so after you
host E yeah sorry no just adamant which
was asking specifically about the
company I work for but just one thing
every optics in in attack vectors and
things and that's an interesting one as
are organized organisations move from
being less remote to semi remote or even
fully for it for a lot it's difficult to
know just now well I'm sure we're going
to see a few different things I do
expect the big cons when they all come
back online later on the year and I'm
not going to name them because you all
know who they are but the big one that
set Excel is going to be extra back
slappy amazingly huggy and really really
handshake II because we've missed the
physical context of going up to people
got hi how you doing we've missed it and
I really do see it can be extra hooking
extra backslapper this year and just
moving south pics I wanted to ask a
question about what have you now
discovered is a new tool or a new
something that you now are doing that
you've picked up as a result of all this
working from home for me for example
zoom as much as we want to tear this
thing apart actually getting in touch my
family has been so much easier because
of zoom trying to get them to go through
the rigmarole of Skype and all the other
tools out there has been painful I think
understanding the fact that there are
some people out there who aren't
technically able like us to get to use
technology that's been a revolution to
literally click on something within a
minute or so you are now home live
conference call with MoMA dad my mom who
had literally just technically dead I'm
sorry for watching this but just the
ability to do that for me zoom they do
get a plus point for me they really do
what about you pet what about you what
few patient you tools new anything that
you picked up uh for me it's been so
many so I think really for me I'll go
specific me into some other stuff I've
been doing so like a two week is it last
week maybe weekend before first we could
make April some thing I participated in
the trace labs
Osen global CTF right with three other
people from here and we run that three
years in a row past strange flex okay
but uh actually tries to know how do how
we won it three is the right but we did
and for me it's like I with all that
extra time working from home and mixing
in evenings prepping for this and trying
to look at no tools so this means really
good like facial recognition software
that we've used and we kind of really
kind of gelled our processes around how
we did the open source intelligence work
the oceans and really just kind of for
me was about kind of having that time
and flexibility where I'm not traveling
that I can I can do that research and
and really invest more time in it and I
kind of I think for me that that's it's
more rather than tools it's all the time
to research has really benefited me that
I can pick out the tools out one test
them go that works me all testing new
processes or new techniques there's more
techniques and tools actually for me
being into testings I've been thinking
about for ages but never we had the time
because I've been running around like a
blue ass fly or spending 90% of my time
on a train or a plane or something like
that so you've got life but it gets the
way of everything yeah I know it's yeah
just travel I've actually I've worked
out I've got something like because my
travel to work from where I live to get
to London if I'm just going London it's
about four and a half hours five hours
as altered or one way so ten hours a
week traveling plus a traveling I do
when is a minimum of ten hours a week
right minimum if I don't travel anywhere
else so I don't go to Europe or anything
so
I've got an extra 10 hours that is
almost dead time in the evenings right
but I can spend I'll sleep with my
family but also doing research like that
so I've used that time that I would have
been spent on a train probably standing
in some cases uh you know actually doing
something so that that's been the
biggest benefit to me really spot-on
stager what about you tools tips tricks
techniques or only similar to you
actually do and the I was already you
got to remember I was already remote so
I was useless but because of the outrage
of what happened to zoom in there
perhaps yeah questionable privacy
they've been forced to improve and that
has that has helped me a lot and you
know because now I can use it and it's
much more stable so I'm pleased from
that regard also I have a 20 year old
son didn't quite make it out of York
University on the final flight so it's a
it's a god set and to be able to talk to
him face to face it makes a difference
oh you could say oh well you know you're
not together it's not the same well if
this is your only option then I would
rather have this option to be honest and
and you know it's worked out very well
so I'm very similar to you and and I
would you know I would also agree with
the time aspect you know I work we all
but we're all different we all excel at
different times of the day for example
I'm not necessarily a morning person let
me just be honest about that I'm happy
to talk to America at 10 o'clock at
night in Lebanon that's fine by me um
you know and and I feel pretty switched
on then so you know as I say it's it's a
world I'm I'm sort of warming to quite a
lot and and it has had benefit with my
son you know as well so yeah big shout
touchy son obviously stuck up in York if
he's watching this and if he's not why
not
and but yeah and I hope is keeping safe
up that firstly what about you you've so
much tech to your fingertips at the
moment more of it flowing towards every
minute with vendors to obviously
knocking on your door will come to those
in a minute but what about you what's
what's new in your world that you've
really warm to its resources so I
suppose just to echo what you guys said
really I'm not I'm not sure there's
anything that's come along that's
particularly new from a tech point of
view yet but
it's more behavioral things and you've
touched it like really it's you know
I've got family in New Zealand that we
connect with for more than we did since
all this happened Saturday night pub
thing with my mates where I think we
socialize in the ER moment and we have
for a decade or plus and then more for
the kids right so I've got a
three-year-old at home and she does like
a ballet classroom the way they've moved
all of that online within a fortnight
which I know the text fairly simple but
for them to have the foresight and the
pace to do that and keep these things
running even if they're just a little
classes for the kids that keep them
interested now that's been the important
thing on a day to day level again I sort
of work similarly during this as I do
normally it's not a straight 95 I'm very
good at taking time out these days for
exercise and I know we can't really go
anywhere but no just trying to fill time
with a few other things if you started
doing a lot more exercise now that
you're at home because of you bike now
and you do more excite um it's hard to
find the time anyway I think I'm forcing
myself now because yeah is about the
tough times stress weighs maybe anxiety
why he's like it's always been my my go
to thing mental health anyway a little
bit yeah so I'm definitely forcing
myself where are the days I'm oh just
when I saw they'll just I'll just do
something else yeah I must admit your
postcode vid or were either gonna come
out this is grossly obese or make a fit
site is I mean loads of crap okay and
votes votes who's gonna crack this
heavier than when they started be every
Friday Saturday for the last three weeks
as well not than for three forty years
absolutely
you mentioned put a mental health first
year I'm first obviously kind of mental
is big in our industry to start with and
I know that this is gonna hit quite a
few people hard because they've now
disengaged from their colleagues they
are now only able to remote they may be
working from home on their own which is
you know again it's all bad stuff cos
that would just add into the pile and I
know from my perspective I've met most
maintain positive mental health through
a lot more writing which I found really
comforting today and simply just having
the family around I mean they're all
running around the house that just that
door there I'm glad it's soundproof as
it is because they have just legged it
down the stairs I thought swim to
actually perform on stage before and but
I've noticed that I'm probably in a
better place because I have got my
family around me and that's helping me
cope with what we don't know how long
this is going to be I'm any tips tricks
from yourselves or how you're coping or
what's your coping mechanism you using
and it obviously can no it's kind of a
personal thing is simply not come
towards stuff think maybe we've read
that you think's relevant I start with
sticker packs in this one keeper routing
thanks for asking keeper routine is
absolutely imperative I know it sounds
silly
get up get ready for the day okay even
if you're not leaving the house these
psychological routines we are creatures
of routine but we don't realize now if
we start to let them slip our minds
start to slip with them we can start
getting down and we don't you know I
don't know why it works I'm not a
psychologist but I'm tried not keeping a
routine and it's very easy to slip into
getting down so keep a routine and stick
to it
it's fine absolutely Stupak big nod yeah
yeah routine is quite important I can't
agree more a mental health perspective
as well it's it's the is the exercise
bit so I did like I had some pretty big
projects coming up recently and I knew
she was that literally had like project
multi projects at one time and I'd spend
from like 7:00 in the morning until like
10 11 o'clock at night at my office I'd
look up and because he sometimes get in
the zone where I'm just doing something
I've forgot I have to eat or drink
sometimes I'll have drink at my office
but I'll forget to drink or eat
something and I look at but it's like oh
my god it's like six and evening and
that the day is gone and I'm the
exercise and I'll just crack on for a
bit and I'll do specs and so the
exercise kind of goes way I think it's
the it's the taking the break mental
break you know stepping away and not
actually working ridiculous hours
because you can write because you could
do that and you could just literally sit
here switch we're busy and the pressure
of like well you know
everyone's you know under pressure from
a work perspective to try and keep thing
of going so I think that that kind of is
quite important but at the same time
it's the connection issue as well so if
you can have sessions like this or you
can connect people whether that is on or
even as a DM someone on Twitter or some
just a Creek zoomkour voice chat and
discourse it's like that you've still
got back human connection especially for
remotes so if you're without family and
you'll stuck out somewhere and you're
stuck by yourself this this is quite
powering time and a lot of the if you're
just embodied by the negative news
stories that you're hearing every day
that is going to get you down that is
going to have a mental effect so reach
out to people on Twitter or reach out or
you're struggling say I'm struggling and
people will help I think that's what's
good about our community because we will
understand InfoSec can be quite
challenging normally ANCA quite
stressful normally so being able to go
and say hey I'm struggling or I'm not
having a good time and knowing people
are there is quite a nice thought so I
think yeah if you see someone struggling
as well and you think they're struggling
and then a bit often don't you know
don't hesitate to reach out to them and
DM them and say how today going also say
I think all four of us at DMS open up we
fir yeah seem to remember we've seen it
and in those two you hosted me belong to
you I know you've really been a big
advocate of this and then oh yeah your
physical exercise has been a really big
help for your mental health yeah keeping
going
yeah so I've talked a lot over the last
maybe 18 months about mental health and
well-being and and we not a few webinars
and various things but I want to caveat
it with I don't actually feel that I've
had too much in the way of struggles
with mental health but what I have been
has been in reasonably stressful
environment as Jake's just diluted to in
the jobs that we've had I've had friends
go through some really bad stuff we sort
of see their learning curves and the
things that they've used and then you
have your good days and bad days like
like any human being but what it is is a
topic that sort of fascinates me about
how individuals get through certain
things and how they're able to use
different mechanisms we did am a mental
health
panel at the digit Expo in Edinburgh at
the end of last year and it was just
phenomenal we had a professor from
Glasgow uni we had a HR rep who was
mental health first aider and then a
couple of people from industry and there
was some great advice and some great
chat about the triggers and you know how
things can escalate and then some of the
ways to make it make it easier and we
had some really interesting content and
it was different for each person so it
wasn't as if there was a
one-size-fits-all thing we had Rory
Alsop who runs beside Scotland and
really active in the community talking
about the fact he loves to keep busy you
know his mechanism is working a lot
actually it's not yet down time it's not
the holidaying whatever he loves his
work and that's what takes him you know
into this happy place and for the rest
of us it's either exercise or being
family or combination of different
things for me I've always trained I've
always done exercise I'm getting old and
slow these days but it's always been my
go-to thing to take my brain somewhere
else and I always feel better afterwards
so difficult to stop doing that when
you've got it's an addiction really of
its own
okay so old and slow just said it in a
race out of us for I would put you at
the front okay just say you're the only
one show on a bicycle right yeah so I'm
gonna switch tone a bit and let's have a
bit of fun with this so we've all been
stuck inside and the big 43 inch plasma
in the corn has been beckoning what have
you been watching the either a you've
regretted starting watching on wire did
I get into the series I want to stop it
now or have you watched and think you
thought TV film whatever it is and you
thought that's actually really fairly
decent I don't got any TV film
recommendations or things to avoid
that's all that I mean for me I'm only
half way through it so don't give away
the ending that tiger thing on Netflix
yeah bonkers yeah yeah that's fun on my
to-do list I'm in the middle of
something at the moment which I couldn't
see in a moment but yeah that Tiger one
does fascinate me what am i you stay go
sorry now yeah I just finished off chapo
which I thoroughly know I have no idea
why I'm started to up started to really
enjoy watching foreign films with
British subtitles no idea why but yeah
I've done a lot of that this season yeah
chapeau so decent that's the earliest
fairly these no points that really laid
Pecha cord yeah so so I been watching
yeah it's been mainly Peppa Pig you know
I thought I thought all the kids into a
lot of the Ghibli studio stuff so I've
been watching spirited away and I've
been watching Howl's Moving Castle and
um princess in okay and and all that all
them that's all in that fix and I
thought oh my god the kids kids love it
I love these comes or maybe fits with no
case a little bit like violent right
beginning when some arrows shoot some
arms the head off but you scrape over
those bits right there okay right and
and like the rest of its okay but you
know even though it says it's a PG in
Atlantis to be fine and you realize okay
maybe that's a PG from ten years ago and
so my kids have been getting a lot of
older films as well so forgetting to
like drastic happens to fight this
classic grassy park which is again
actually as PG and it's actually quite a
quotes in places but yeah but I learned
for me personally I've been watching The
Witcher and stuff like this and also
targeting actually and I won't ruin it
for anyone but but a lot the stutter one
of the people that may have disappeared
as part of that and the investigation
was going into was actually include as
part of our CTF that for trace labs they
got thing that present included although
I don't think anything got found without
giving the hard way so yeah very much
like the case but yeah so yeah so that
the talking's actually open an optimist
imagination iced chai brief I can't I
I find it really like I gotta say I find
it really interesting just the level of
like how it escalates and just the
airplane and I just said I'm such as
laughing just ridiculous it's the whole
thing but yeah so things like that I'm
going the classic reasons like this I
love my anime so we had to show my kids
some but a kind of cool anime stuff
that's going on and then more recently
I've been getting into the alter carbon
stuff again so I rewatched season wanted
to of that because I love those shows
new season just after doesn't just
started yeah we alter carbon - yes been
around for a little bit it's been out
for a few weeks but yes that's kiss the
first one but yes III not been been
watching too much but I always watch the
thing for a go to bed and so
I usually fall asleep to it but yeah
that's kind of I think such a thing
gancho see after you I was just gonna
mention something else that I have a bit
of space geek so I watch a whole load of
stuff to do with the Apollo missions and
things and there's Apollo 11 I think
it's on Netflix or Amazon and it's a
documentary but there's no narration
over the top of it it's all in the
timeline a bit happening with lots of
unseen footage and I'm heard Houston
control stuff and it's just fascinating
to watch I mean everybody knows the
ending like but did they get if you but
if you believe it you don't report in
full hot Sun I would definitely say we
mean the missus decided that we're gonna
start in sheesh I kissed some of the
proper old classic so we start with
Flash Gordon proper Flash Gordon on DVD
it's a genuine version can I just say
the most inappropriate movie I have ever
watched with the child oh yes there were
so many fast forwards it was most our
memories of these older things
definitely don't stack up to PG nowadays
to have these tablets will help you
forget your wedding night
[Laughter]
there's no sputters has to appropriate
scenes and I watched the mask the mask
right Jim carries a mask right yeah oh
my god that's so either it's
inappropriate and like so like like soft
hiss sticks today as well it's like
really bad
it's a SIA I watched it when this film
would never get made today I only spend
every one is so I think we forget that I
think become desensitized when you watch
those from eighties films right yeah
very violent and incredibly
inappropriate right and then nineties
films push that a little bit further
with the inappropriateness but less
violent in some cases yeah then today
it's I it's like people outcry when they
see like depictions of women in certain
appropriate ways and you're thinking
yeah look at the nineties films like
this like to be out crying everywhere
and I think we forget the you know times
have changed so much in a good way and I
think this is a great thing
yeah I agree most of our 80s TV
presenters are in jail there's a lot a
hole in history
pretty much
yeah yeah the other thing that we start
doing is we try to do a better culture
with the case and watch that Andrew
Lloyd Webber they're doing live stage
productions that they you know put him
back on on a Friday night on YouTube and
the first one we watch was Jesus Christ
Superstar think he was no it wasn't it
was the other one yeah Joe Stevens
Technicolor Dreamcoat le character
minute I recognize him from somewhere
and it was a camera his name is that his
perfect white teeth in a straight line
next minute it cuts to a scene it's got
Joan Collins in a fishnet body stocking
you up whoa whoa whoa we stop this right
now
last night we were another Friday we
watched a place if anyone's in the chat
and saw it
I'd recommend go back and watch it if
you've got a small kid don't let them
watch it it was fun to me the Opera and
it was fantastic
apart from my eight-year-old has now
been sleeping in our bed for two nights
because she's having nightmares about
the guy with masks covering her together
and the guy hanging his neck for three
minutes not good for kids but but now
I've got to say our we're now trying to
stop the kids from just sit and watching
telly all day then we actually try not
to move unites in stuff and that's
worked out quite well but this comes
soon good stuff spirited ways actually
on our to-do list of wants to watch yeah
I noticed some people a chap gave a
really big shout out for that one so
yeah so well done good good mr. robots
come up a lot in the chat I noticed as
well I have to see some three went and
get blood of this now yeah season four
season four got like the likely season
got a lot better actually cuz I almost
gave up in it and I thought I'll give
the last season a go at you yeah really
good at the end so I think it's worth
persevering through the first season
always be the best right but yeah you
got better I think this I think that
this is the thing we're quite spoiled
with our TV no I think yeah no I
remember when there was China five came
on and ah that was amazing another
channel oh my god oh you're five
channels now guys I remember what it
started as been quite young but I think
you are this is amazing five channels we
forget like you know we grew up on my TV
was like your choice was nothing right
today it's too much and I think that's
another bring us back to InfoSec right
and it's this kind of brings you back to
like where we are today that if
when most of us started out and there
was nothing right you'd want to go learn
about InfoSec hashtag gay old okay uh
yeah you'd learn something about it and
you'd have to go to four and then people
would get keep the knowledge and you
have to push really hard to find stuff
and a BBS or you know IRC kind of stuff
you'd have to really push hard to find
anything on all this stuff it was what
kind of like it kept a secret kind of
treasure how to unlock right I had to
prove yourself that you actually knew
something and and now if you fast
forward to now it's you know it's all
out there get up you get up early repose
and do you think um I see a lot of the
big conferences are being cancelled too
this summer but and there's been no
online stuff anyway do you feel that the
industry is going to move more towards
catering for a lot of that anyway and
because I know Amazon and big names you
know to tend to do online at the same
time but but this kind of thing with a
few hundred people with some really good
content you know there's a hell of a lot
less anyway but it could be awesome if
we could them you know we've talked
about the meetups a week that we're
under to open them up to the world
rather than just a little country that
we live in just has such a massive
impact I think the DC cons will do
phenomenally out of this because all of
a sudden if I can make a DC con if
you've now got this it's an alternative
form I think we superb I'd love to go to
some of the other DC comes around me you
know DC one for one can just you know
that just you never get to them and if
it is in this format will be able to get
to them and actually be able to go and
see other cons as well which I think we
were fairly cool but yeah I don't think
the big stuff like the info sexing and
stuff I'll and I don't think those all
happen I think that it will stay I think
the big ones are still still stay is
that like that but I think smaller con
same people in my list I'm not saying
b-sides be good like this though I think
be sad to be a bit more tricky to do
like this but I think this this would be
good okay yeah okay well I'm bit biased
because of virtual conference right so
yeah yeah once you go virtual well maybe
that one should go first shall we should
keep doing it um yeah yeah so there's a
dearth con reach
out to me last last week and they want
to promote they want to put our condom
back at their t-shirts like this because
they are like another virtual con that's
not many of them out there now they're
kind of won't be starting it there was
like though it's like pancakes calm and
there was a couple others right there
Grimm Koenig on virtual and so I think I
think that's an appreciation the
conference this war will say well do we
really need a venue do we read do we I'm
a big I'm a big believer that certain
conferences should have been you right
so DEFCON blackhat that kind of stuff
right germ factories right where fluke
on a food can't actually make something
right colorful emedicine think sorry I
and and I think it's important to get a
mass group of people together face space
that's a big special about that I think
we shouldn't move away from it because
they you know you create memories and
your crate experiences and and you make
friendships right from people that you
talk to online and I think that's always
going to be there and I think we
shouldn't take that away but but what
this does what the virtual conferences i
found i mean bear in mind we spent
nothing right we spent okay we spend a
little bit but not much
right putting this together so we've
we've just put our resources or
expertise we've used platforms so that
the cost of doing this is literally very
very little right and and we've managed
to raise money and we've got people
donating stuff because we're doing it
for free and we're doing it for a good
cause right so why can't more people do
that if you've got the right people and
you've got right technical expertise why
can't you put your own calm and i think
i think that reduces the barrier to
entry because when we tried to put on
the first con that we tried to do um we
were looking at like 30 grand plus for
the venue like far show expensive right
and so we looked at it and went actually
that venue then went out of business so
we actually dodged a massive bullet so
we would have been an absolute disaster
so actually in hindsight pretty good
thing but and so you know i think a lot
of venues gonna have to start thinking
about you know well this this could be
impact their business but but for anyone
out there wants to do this just do it i
mean what you know i think you know if
you've got an idea and it's slightly
different i mean there was the one oh a
siscon yester
right in virtual reality whole
conference a virtual reality speaker
staged their slides on and everyone in
sight you know that VR kind of like you
know people I pop my French I love that
I'll say the first person to f-bomb on
here and we're in conference so they go
oh just put myself in the swear jar
right back please Maurice to what we'll
put that will put the professional on
Indus lead amateur here right like I
thought that's such a great idea and I
think that that could be why things go
so you know I think that that actually
worked really well so to answer your
question without taking up too much time
I think we'll see a lot more virtual
cons now and I think there'll be a good
balance between people having virtual
Consulate's professionally done and then
the standard cons will still go on
because I have to write because there
are DNA of this industry yeah i
massively I mean I'm a conference goes
as most people know me from is I'm
always at the cons and I actually think
this will help but I do want to start
from a physical conferences there's
still something about how the tactile
environment of a conference you know
getting flow off you mate is always a
part of every conference season but I'm
fascinated by the VR confident superb
what a great useful fear I've always
looked for a use for VR VR for me has
been something it's just a technology
needs to be implemented somehow and I've
never seen it curtisha that virtual VR
conference what a way for that be Stuart
I mean you course and you probably know
me the best and the truth the matter is
is that I'm in real life I'm very shy
and you know to a certain degree I don't
like to admit it but socially awkward
and this is ideal for me look at me I've
gone from the person that my wife calls
me a Wallflower it sort of blends into
the come somewhere and can't be saying
to the person that's out the front
because I do have something to say and
so you can see the flip side as well and
we just me down to the ground and I I
suspect there's more people like me I
don't gone the only one so I think this
is gonna this is gonna open up for a new
set of people to come and be comfortable
in these environments
I hope so I hope so anything okay is so
fantastic message that really is so
we've got five minutes left so I think
we should point your closing comments
because I've got a slide to show to
people so what's your what's your guess
Stu because you've asked all the
questions I'm going to ask the question
then go back into podcast my Stuart
Coulson
what's been your biggest takeaway from
this whole experience from this cutter
from this citation can yeah you can of
these we need to most you common fees we
need to have a chat more between
ourselves and extend it out to the wider
community as well um I I do miss
chatting Chia mates just even if it's
across the desk and in the office or
even if it's just having a chat with
someone online
I do miss those moments so this has been
brilliant really loved it more of this
please definitely stick up next month
yeah more the same more of a saying the
the more the better unless you're a
person there yeah absolutely
she Hearst yeah I mean look at what's
happening right there this is I know
it's an overused word and in what we're
going through but unprecedented we're
having to fix problems globally we've
never faced before at all sorts of
levels tech you know right through to
mental health well-being family and all
that we're doing here all that we're
putting together for our industry and
the people who work with us it's
phenomenal
when always gonna get it right there's
gonna be some tough days and I think
we'll look back on this generally with
pride about how we've we've conducted
ourselves and the things that we've put
together and the things that we've
contributed as individuals and as groups
so I'm a fairly positive person anyway
right will come through the end of this
and more will look back they'll be
learnings and our industry or kind of
grow from it rather than because of it
yeah so we're down 50 percent you target
5856 Wow thank you everyone I think I
wish I have more of these yeah
iiiiii yeah that's amazing thank you
reform is just donated and I'm sure
identified one knows but but basically I
decided and the guys decided that every
time someone donates
the staff and the moderators are going
to post a meme of me on Twitter with
taking that person donates in so there's
been quite a few memes of me going right
and by the way there's a massive massive
like the back load of them so as Paul
memes that I can count and there's more
being created just in case we run out so
oh that's so good so yeah I mean it's
all for a good cause right so it's not
like I don't mind being beans because it
happens every day so yeah I think I
think to kind of summarize this before I
kind of focus off I think you know this
dis dis to me is kind of made you
realize that the best of people and it
also brings out the worst in people the
cyber criminals and all this kind of
stuff right and like the the Chinese
like I think they say the two words the
kind of crisis and one of them is
opportunity or whether it's danger
there's opportunity basically right and
I think there's always an opportunity
for people to do good but it's also a
massive opportunity for people to do bad
and I think we've got to realize is and
this is a big shout-out to the CV 19
people so the Lisa down dank dank Arden
all that kind of stuff for doing the
work there they've taken an opportunity
to help protect those assets where
people would likely do that and I think
this has brought out loads of great
things the community and I think that's
what makes us great the community that
we will identify things for me yeah I'm
also helping a little bit as well but
but you know putting on a conference and
try and raise money for a charity that
is also doing good is one way of doing
it other ways to actually help protect
the assets from you know the NHS and
things like this and healthcare from
being a talented as well which which is
which which is is happening in some
countries as well so yeah I think we
will have to kind of pull together and
we all have to roll our sleeves up and
do what we can in our work and also
we're in the community we have to pull
it on our sleeves up as well so I think
I am out of time or almost out of time
yes I have got one minute so on that
note and thank you very much guys and
you've got five minutes time there's a
handover between between tracks they've
got the the red team track that like the
main event that for the for the red team
stuff that's coming up you've got the
blue team track
I'll see with the talks come up with up
the keynote on damn ray word I think
you've got
don't hear we got come at first I'm
going to shed in front me and we've also
got another track I got a purple team
track as well so you pick your pick your
track each track actually on Twitch it's
got the schedule on this you can see
which talks coming up and I thought I
can just get back here can turn we
really get rights beginning like that
boom okay yeah I'll Saku on that track
Oscar and also write down Ray word
talking about his bit for half an hour
and then very talented I should have put
that the end point at you though it
might that's what happens but they're
doing production thank you to my three
co-hosts sticker pack student Coulson
stoop Hearst
thank you I'm Stu I'll see the other
school bye-bye and thank you and that's
it stay safe everyone okay Derek a
school
[Music]