[Music]
okay brilliant hello everyone i'm just
going to
i'm not doing the intros this one but i
just want to say hi to everyone and
thank everyone for
all the amazing talks today but also uh
i wanted to give everyone a brief
update for our donation total so far so
we're currently on 7291
we've had something like 80 something
donations or something like that today
it's been absolutely amazing and i just
want to thank everyone who has donated
or participated or asked a question
i'm absolutely hyped for this talk but
it's not my job to introduce that that's
down to andy so i'm going to bow out and
just say
thank you and over to you hey everyone
uh welcome to the last talk of the day
um we've got mr tj now
also known as tony he's going to be
talking about from mantra to mindset
prepping for it's like preparing for the
oscb journey i know tj and i have known
each other for quite a while and he told
me his as much of his
talk synopsis is amazing essentially he
said he does hacks and things
so over to you tj awesome
thanks for the introduction zephyr uh
yes hang on a second let me go ahead and
throw that up here real quick i totally
forgot about that
you only had one job tj it's just just
one it's okay
it's the last talk three have some fun
right it was going so
well really well all right uh
excellent yeah okay can
uh you all see that just to make sure
cool all right so let's go ahead and get
started
um so zephyr gave a little bit of
introduction i'm just gonna go a little
bit more in depth about who i am and
what i do
so my name is tj nall also known as tony
ponero
i am the community manager for offensive
security um so what i try to do is i try
to bring out the communication the
relations you know
for you guys the students future
students or even anybody who
really likes to get in the offensive
side you know try to work with offense
security or communicate with them
um part of my spare time too as well
because i like to do a lot of hacks
right
i also teach at um i'm an adjunct
professor at frederick community college
i teach the ethical hacking course and
this course is there and also
run the cyber team that's there as well
so
a lot of big things i've been doing in
the past i've loved competing in cyber
competitions i've done at least 245 in
the past five years
and i also like hosting cyber
competitions for all ages wherever they
are
just so they can get into cyber security
or have an interest or peak in it
um also like attending uh security
conferences moderate some communities as
well too like netsec focus and many hats
club
but outside of infosec because you have
to have hobbies outside right of doing
all cyber and anything infosec wise is i
like to do a lot of hiking and traveling
play lacrosse and play video games as
well
so getting into this talk right so
what's the agenda we're gonna be talking
about here so
for some of you that know the oscp you
guys are gonna be able to get a little
bit of run down this for others i'm
gonna go ahead and explain what it is
we're gonna talk about the course
prerequisites overview the course what
the new lab environment is like what the
new course material is like
um also some tips for the exam also how
to prepare for it
and tips of when you are taking as well
too and then some resources that i've
prepared along the way as well too to
help you on your journey
and any uh questions or answers we have
after talk we can definitely talk about
that
so for some of you what is the oscp
right so the
offense security certified professional
is one of the most technical and most
challenging certifications
for information security professionals
that is out there in order to be
certified you actually have to take
the penetration testing with cali course
and also
take a 24-hour exam during that 24 hours
if you go ahead and actually score them
the amount of points you also have to
write
a report as well too after that 24 hours
so it's a big certification i think if
you're trying to get into pen testing
uh or into infosec and i think it's also
good that even blue teamers like sock
endless intersponders instant handlers
should also be able to take this course
as well too to get understanding of
what hackers do how to be able to build
that hacker mindset as well too
so why did i pursue oscp
when i was a senior in high school i was
taking a lot of computer classes
actually
we had this school here called the
career technology center and
in that center they actually gave us
gave me my first ever security class
which i ever learned
and one of the things that they dropped
on my desk was a backtrack 5 cookbook
written by william pritchett and also
the backtrack 5r3 cd
and so that was our learning material
basically and i went through the book
and i went through the cd you know just
learning all the different tools the
techniques the methodologies and i
really had a passion for this i'm like
this is something i really wanted to do
um and it took a long way to get to
where i was to do that
and so i tried to find ways of learning
new material seeing where i could be
able to
get more understanding of backtrack how
to actually get certified as well too
into it
and the first thing i saw was on a fedex
web page penetration testing with
backtrack and of course the oscp
so going through the time of it i was 16
at the time i couldn't be able to take
it you had to be 18
to be able to take it the course itself
so i thought all right there's gonna be
some stuff i can
prepare for and get some prerequisites
right so my journey started basically
like this
pwp i'm prepping for it i'm gonna get
ready for it well
things kind of changed uh the course
actually released pwk
and then from there i actually took the
old version of pwk
went through the actual labs went
through the course material of course
had to do the try harder moments right
you know to be able to get to that top
of the mountain just to earn the oacp
so going into the course prerequisites
right
so how do you know you're ready what
should you do to decide to prepare for
the course right so
there's a couple things that we ask that
you prepare for or have at least an
understanding of before you start the
course
uh one of the things of course is tcp
networking fundamentals right know your
ip addresses know your subnetting
how network traffic is sent receive and
also the different types of protocols
right
know your operating systems know how
windows works know how linux systems
work
also have some understanding of
programming languages now this doesn't
mean that you have to be fully
experienced
writing in python writing in powershell
writing it bash but at least have an
understanding of
how to read the code how to review the
code and then see what changes you need
to make to actually
make the code work for what you're
trying to assess in the lab or even in
the course material
and note taking is super important
documentation is an important
key that i always encourage people to do
whenever they're going through this
course now i've also provided some
note-taking tools
joplin is one of my favorite tools now
uh i really like how you could be able
to write everything down in markdown it
has a really nice reading preview
and the other thing too that's really
cool about it it has a synchronization
tool as well too
that you can actually go ahead and sync
your notes into a local
cloud storage a file share or even onto
dropbox or in the cloud as well too
uh before i took the ocp i also used
cherrytree and i was okay with it i
really
wasn't a huge fan of it and microsoft
onenote as well too
and also typora which also is another
markdown reader and writer as well too
that you can use
so the overview of the course what has
changed what's new in the new updates
right
so pretty much all the topics that you
see here have been updated
the new topics that have been added is
active directory attacks and powershell
empire
um the big ones that have been revamped
and updated
have been web application attacks
previous escalation the buffer overflow
section is entirely new
as well too basically explaining and
walking through more information on
how to actually you know find the
vulnerable
defined vulnerabilities in it and also
how to exploit it as well too
so what's the new lab environment like
so for me
this was probably the fun part about the
course is that when you've gone through
the material when you review all the
material
then you get to go ahead and go into the
lab so the lab now has 75 machines
almost all the machines are pretty much
up to date running from windows server
2012 to 2019
windows 10 boxes and on the linux side
you also have from w9 to w10
and also with red hat systems that have
been updated as well too
in the new lab environment when you're
going through the course material you'll
actually be provided with the following
boxes you'll be provided with the
windows 10
box a windows server 2016 box and a
debian test box as well too
and the lab is now broken into four
networks yes
back then in the old pwk you actually
had a student
lab which is a public network the i.t
department and the development network
and administration network now you also
have a new section called the sandbox
network where
you can actually go ahead in the last
section of pwk
you actually can go through a full
assessment and in that full assessment
you have the sandbox network there where
you can actually
walk through what we basically go
through during
assessment in this sandbox network which
is really cool
so here's a basic look of what the old
network looks like and what the new
network looks like
now of what they've been added and which
is really cool on what they've done as
well too
for you to be able to build your
practical skills and knowledge you know
when you're going through the course
itself
so what do i recommend for a lab setup
you know when you're preparing for the
course itself
definitely have vmware workstation
vmware player and also have kali linux
now you could be able to use your own
tools you can be able to use virtualbox
if you wanted for your hypervisor or any
other hypervisor that is out there
but the only reason why i recommend
using vmware workstation or vmware
player and kali linux
is because student admins will be able
to support you better with what's going
on
it's really cool to see also what you're
going to be using and what you're going
to be preparing as well through the
course itself
now the new pwk actually you can use a
standard kali linux 64-bit machine or
32-bit machine that's there
uh for people that are using the old pwk
and going through the old labs
you can use the old pwk image that we
have that's already set up there
and then of course also on your local
systems have a windows 10 box or windows
7 box
and i also recommend having immunity
debugger on both the systems
and the reason why i say it is because
in case you're testing any exploits in
the lab itself that you want to test
locally
you have those boxes there you have
those systems there that you can test
those app those vulnerable applications
to see if your exploit code or if your
configurations are actually true when
you're going to the lab itself
so assessing the pwk lab network a lot
of
people will probably tell you how they
approach the lab how they went through
the environment
and there's many different ways that you
can go through it and also some people
have also said they finished it really
at this time or at this time right
my recommendation is to you is that
everybody goes through this lab
differently
everybody goes to the course differently
and i say it depends on to you if you
want to be able to take the time
and also to go through the material
properly before you jump into the lab or
jump through different chapters of the
material right this isn't going to be a
sprint
this is a marathon for you to go ahead
and go to the material learn it and
understand it
properly when you go through so when i
did it it took me 28 days and 127 hours
to go through
the systems that were in the lab some of
the systems that i went through
were pretty easy one day i would pawn 17
boxes in 14 hours
and another day it would take me two to
three days just to pone one box
each system has its own difficulty set
up by a giant machine
and some of the systems you'll actually
have to pivot through from different lab
environments now
especially in the new environment that's
set up and
of course make sure that you use your
reverts properly
if you're going through a system a lot
of the students that have been on those
systems that have access
might leave some leftover stuff some
artifacts as well too if you want to be
able to learn and understand
the systems properly going through it
make sure you revert the systems
that will give you a fresh clean state
of how to approach the box and how to
assess it going forward instead of
cheating yourself and being fair to
yourself when you're doing that
so other tips i want to say enumerate
enumerate enumerate uh you probably have
heard this from so many people when
they've gone through the lab
enumeration is key there are so many
different things that can be on each
system each system has their own
different scenario of what you're going
to be looking at and understand the
purpose of how these systems are being
used right
why was that system there who set it up
what was the purpose of it being used
for
document everything there could be some
things if you don't document properly
that you could miss
right certain scans that you also do
maybe it's a udp scan maybe there's
something you can't find
but make sure you actually go ahead and
see what that system is doing
and make sure that you document it
properly in the end track your hours
see how long it takes you to go through
each system maybe you're spending too
much time on one
system and maybe you should jump to
another system just to see what it is
and what varies for you
the other thing i also say is don't skip
the lab exercises what's really cool now
about the new pwk is that they've added
a section called extra miles
now depending on the labs that you do
each extra mile actually adds an extra
challenge that you can try and you can
do
now you don't have to put these in the
lab report itself which is nice
but i definitely encourage you to try
out those extra miles see
how you could do and apply your
practical knowledge going through those
itself they are separate
challenges that you can do in the lab so
in order for you to submit your lab
report you need at least still have 10
systems documented of how you assess
them
and also you need to complete all the
exercises when you complete all those
exercises and also have documented all
10 systems that you uh assessed in the
lab itself
you could be able to get five points
added to your exam
and the last thing of course i recommend
when you're going to the lab is use your
reverbs like i said earlier
so let's talk about the exam next what's
going to happen the exam
so you will have a total of 23 hours and
45 minutes for the exam
you will be proctored during your exam
webcam and screen sharing software
is required it is a must when you go
through the exam itself
back in the days when i took it you
could be able to have a laptop that was
separate for your webcam and then have
your system that you were doing
everything with cali
or assessing with the system itself when
you're in the exam be used separately
now that's not the case you cannot do
that anymore you need to at least have
your webcam
and the screen sharing software tied to
your one system that you're doing
everything on for the exam
the exam will consist of five targets
that you get and these targets range
from
different operating systems or it could
be the different level of difficulty
but really it's gonna depend on you
going through that you need at least a
seven
minimum 70 points or higher to pass yes
you do
um and this is where i recommended you
getting that extra five points come in
because
that could be the deciding factor of you
passing or you failing
and if you believe you have enough
points then you have another 24 hours to
write the report
and the one thing i do recommend is that
no matter how many points you get
i'd still say try to write that report
and the reason why is that that'll
improve your writing skills
also prepare you for writing the report
as well too ahead of time
and what's also really good for you as
well too
is that even if you fail you have an
understanding of what you wrote in the
report
what you did you may not get the same
systems in your next exam or the next
one moving forward of whatever attempt
you have
but at least gives you understanding of
how your writing is and how your report
can be
i've seen many people pass you know when
they've got all five systems right off
the bat
and they actually failed the exam
because of their reporting you know it
could be other gravitational errors not
enough details
formatting could be an issue as well too
or not even proper screenshots as well
at least from what i've seen and heard
from the students that have taken the
course
exam restrictions this is another big
one that i've seen
you cannot use any of the following
systems or following tools in the exam
spoofing commercial tools automated
exploitation tools
mass vulnerability scanners any features
that are included in some of the tools
that do some of the following things
like auto pwn or mass vulnerability
scanning
spoofing those are also restricted from
being used in the exam
and the reason why they do that is
because they want you to be able to go
through everything manually at least try
to
you know and maybe even script your own
stuff for what you need
so preparing for the exam these are my
tips on what i want to give to you guys
right
so when you feel comfortable taking the
exam right schedule it three to four
weeks in advance because this will give
you plenty of time of what you need to
prepare for
and once you've gone through the exam
guidelines once you've gone through the
course material once you think you've
gone through enough systems in your lab
or
your pwk time has run out do a couple
things
complete the lab reported class
exercises to get that extra five points
read the guideline requirements as well
too before you take the exam
find a area or at least have an area or
space
that you will not be distracted when
you're taking your exam do not forget to
eat or drink
prepare some snacks prepare some water
coffee tea right whatever you
there's any type of substance you know
you need for this exam
prepare your feed sheets notes tools
exploits make sure you have your systems
up and ready to go
snapshots are very important and i'm
going to give you one of my scenarios
that happened to me
when i took my pwk exam last the day
before i took it i actually snapchatted
my system
had everything my notes and tools ready
to go and on the morning i was about to
take my exam
i'd turn on my cali box everything
crashed i lost everything
files were corrupted luckily i was able
to revert back that snapshot
and able to get all my stuff back in
that clean slate so
snapshots backups are important to have
before you go through that exam
and also start working on your exam
report have that draft ready like i said
earlier
get some rest as well too don't be
overproductive or overthink things the
day before your exam
you need break and you need to have a
break mentally as well too
so spend some time with family friends
loved ones if you can
or at least take a step away from the
computer as if you can as well
this is one of the big quotes that
really helped me
as well too getting ready for the exam
from a buddy of mine from xerox df
you're going to run out of ideas before
you run out of time take breaks
walk away for a bit don't be afraid to
go to sleep for a few hours especially
if you're stuck
because that's what's gonna happen for
you in the exam remember try not to iron
man the exam
try not to sprint through the exam
itself take time to understand the
systems
review your methodology review your
concepts that you built onto it
to help yourself with this exam and
don't feel nervous taking it as well too
everybody goes through this more than
once or even some people who have gone
through it properly
will be able to pass on the first try
but that's okay
failure leads to your success no matter
what you try to do and what you brush up
into
so i prepared for some resources to help
you with your ocp if
some of you have seen this already some
of you are probably still
getting into it starting to prepare for
oc but i wrote a huge guide
uh for last year about the ocp and how
to prepare for it with a variety of
different materials for each chapter
going through it
um i do plan to update this with the new
material soon but i want to give some
time for students that are taking the
course itself
to go through it and give their thoughts
and feedback of how the course is for
them
how they're liking the material and also
what stuff they like going on the lab
itself i've also prepared a huge list
and many of you have probably seen this
list of ocp-like vms
the link that i have right there has a
list of vulnerable machines that you can
go ahead and practice on
uh through different resources that you
can find online and also from offline
like bom hub for
instance other resources that i have
that really helped me prepare for it as
well too personally before i went
through this
um was apache's ocp guide scrunders
passing osep
they were really great guys to help me
out some books as well too like cal
linux revealed attacking network
protocols
those books really helped me out trying
to get started preparing for the ocp
as well and then i have some other
resources that really help me out
so the reason why i'm putting these
resources here is because one of my
biggest issues that i had going through
the lab itself
and also going through the course
material was privileged escalation
uh you probably have noticed that on
linux escalation got milk has these huge
guise on how to prevent linux systems
that was one of the big guides that
really helped me out and also in the
windows side i have a couple links in
there
that also gave me some good inspiration
of how to progress systems on the
windows side and the linux side just to
help beef up my skills that really
helped out
and on the buffer overslow section just
to get a better understanding of the
introductions cornland series really
helped me out
just getting understanding of how buffer
overflows worked how the process is to
go through it
find that exploited space and try to go
ahead and actually get a shell from the
box from there
so one of the big things that i want to
end this presentation on just
before we go ahead and leave is the try
harder mindset right
i know many of you probably have
negative views of tryharder
don't like the idea of it and i get that
and i understand that
some of you have also mentioned the idea
of try smarter personally to myself
i think the try harder motto is an
amazing motto and which really helped me
out going through the oscp and the
reason why i say that is because
the mindset of try harder means the
following things it means to be
persistence
it means to be creative and also to have
a different perspective
and so when you are trying to be
persistent in the lab
you know when something doesn't work the
first or second time and you hit a brick
wall
remember to take a step back remember
mistakes and failures are part of the
process
kind of like i said when you go through
the lab when you go through the course
material and even in your exam you're
going to have those mistakes
you're going to struggle that's okay
take the time to learn and understand
what you made a mistake on to build your
skills and go through this right
so having this mindset is going to give
you a the ability to create new ideas
and also to have new approaches
and also remember to have patience when
you go through this keep pushing
don't give up right thomas edison's
quote our greatest weakness lies in
giving up
the most certain way to succeed is
always just to try one more time
how many times did he try to go ahead
and make the light bulb right he went
through so many attempts he went through
so many processes just to get
one project of his working to make that
invention that we use now today
the next thing be creative right
remember to try new and different things
get out of your comfort zone of trying
some tools that you've used right
near new tools out there there are new
scripts out there there are new exploits
out there
go ahead give them a shot if they don't
work that's okay you know it doesn't
work for this system or for this
vulnerable app
try some other ones that are out there i
bet you there's a bunch of people that
have written different code for it
and also being perceptive situational
awareness is a critical skill that all
of us need to have in this field
and i think it's really important not
even from a red team or from a pen
testing perspective but even from a
bluetooth perspective
we need to be able to understand
situations when we need to find ways to
react to them in those times of need
learn to be efficient and learn to be
effective don't try to iron man the
courses or the exams you take in the
general world
make time to step back and actively
assess the situation to make the good
decisions that you need to do
and keep in mind though that the skill
does not come naturally
but it's important for us to learn it
and understand it so we can build it
moving forward
especially in the field that we work in
today
so with that being said this is all i
have for preparing for the oscp
and going through the new stuff in the
material as well too
if anybody has any questions now is the
time um and if anybody needs to ask me
anything
uh i link my handle stuff on twitter
github and discord and also on netsec
focus as well too if you guys want to
talk to me there
you just finished tj just rattled
through your whole talk in 30 minutes
was it 30 minutes exactly well it was 23
minutes but you've still got that
that's fine i know i'm gonna have a
bunch of questions yeah there's
there's a lot um let me just cleat a few
uh morgan have you got any
on hand yeah i've been dropping some in
the discord so
um we've got one here when
will the joplin oscp
pen test report template drop tj it
looks
awesome very helpful it is it is coming
soon uh
i have a few more things i want to add
to it but i at least give you an idea
there's 40 pages of notes
that i took from pwk and also from
current assessments that i've been on
um i'm currently getting it reviewed by
offset
just to make sure that they are okay
with it and then they could be able to
support it
so right now at this time uh just keep a
watch on my twitter
and any updates that come through it and
hopefully i'll have it out soon for you
guys
the other thing like a lot of people
have been asking is i think you're gonna
be posting your slides afterwards
because obviously you've got a [ __ ] to
the legs
yep yep i will be doing that for sure as
well too um and i'll have that posted
soon as well
uh another question here um do you have
a preferred screenshot tool
in the new 2020 cali image or yes
kazam is my favorite i i really like how
the cali team actually put that tool in
there as well too for the new xfce
desktop environment that they have
um it used gnome had a really okay one
but the thing i like about kazam is that
it also does screen recording as well
too
which is also one thing not to mention
that you also really helped me bring up
with that question
you can't be able to record your screen
as well too during the exam
that is another thing that offset as
well too has now taken out of doing your
exam
that makes sense uh do the currents
do the current coverage situation due to
the current looks like
choose the current government situation
are exams heavily proctored and
monitored more than usual
as well as how often are the labs
updated for the exam
in case one in case you feel your
attempt
so i can't really uh i can't really ask
her about the proctoring
um but i can say at least the proctoring
standards have stayed the same nothing
has changed
uh from what i know at least from my
perspective
but going to the course material and how
that's being
made the pwk lab environment and the
course material is supposed to reflect
on
what current topics and attacks that we
see going on in the real world now
so a lot of the materials still will
apply to what you're going to be doing
in the exam
nothing has really big or changed it's
in the exam itself
it's more of you taking the time to go
ahead and going through those systems
that you will see
so i still encourage you to go ahead and
take the course i still encourage you to
go to the new lab environment
it's just both lab environments will
still help you prepare for the exam at
this time
sweet um another question here
on your core christie um how many hours
should a newbie expect
to spend before becoming ready for oscp
that's a really good question
um time wise that is really up to you
and the reason why i say that is because
you will really only know
how much time you need to go through to
prepare for the course and also what
material and what
topics you need to brush up on or even
start learning more about
um so that's why i recommend tracking
your hours you know having an excel
spreadsheet you know how much time did
you spend on a specific topic whether
it's learning more about python
learning about powershell or learning
about specific client side attacks right
you know how to
craft your hda file or macro attack
right those are things that you're going
to be
you know you need to prepare for
yourself learning wise but also you will
be able to do it through the material as
well too i think
sweet um i've got another question here
uh is there a road map that
one could follow um to ensure they have
all the skills needed to pass their exam
they're on the third attempt
at the moment and they've all managed to
get to the 10-point box
i can't really answer any questions
about the exam unfortunately uh
my only guidance for you or for the
person that asked that question
is figure out what you need to brush up
on and
figure out what you missed you know or
what you need to improve on from the
exam
and that's what the exam is for the exam
is there to
test your skills to test your knowledge
physically and mentally
when you go through it um and also to go
through on what stuff you may have
passed through what you exceeded on or
what you still need to improve you know
one of my big things right
is i didn't use metasploit enough in the
in the lab network
and i didn't really get to use it much
in the exam but coming out now after
i've obtained my ocp
metasploit really is still something
that people still use you know preparing
for their stuff using the exploit multi
handler
using the socks proxy that's on there
and that stuff i kind of had to learn
more outside and i kind of wish i
applied that more into the pwk lab
nice someone asked a question earlier on
i i
skipped past it but they were asking for
um offset have any certifications
um other than osw osce
and between oscp and osce
not not at this time
cool any more questions folks questions
as of offset has updated the pwk course
uh is mentioned on the website that the
exam is not
changed so how can one know assess that
they've learned
from the new updated material versus the
old material
that is a really good question um
i'd say this right the best way to look
at the updates of how
how stuff has been changed is look at is
review the course syllabus that we have
on our offsets page right now
that will give you a better
understanding of what the new course
material is like and what you can see on
there that's been added
sweet uh have we got any more questions
on that i think we've rattled through
all the questions in stream
one in discord um what is considered
manual tools
um
yeah what yeah that's right which
um i guess it's it's down to what's
allowed to be used in the exam
when it so between automated and manual
okay that that makes more sense now
because that's what i was thinking was
the difference between automated and
manual right
the reason why i say you should do
manual tools right is because each tool
has its own different functions and own
different ways that it works
and it's a great way for you to
understand how the tools work how the
command let's work in a tool right
and that pat for instance let's let's
pick a tool right we'll pick map map has
a variety different command switches in
that tool
of how to be able to scan not just you
know one ip address not with one target
multiple targets
and also doing different types of scans
right there's a lot of tools that are
out there like sparta for instance you
know it's an automated tool
that goes ahead and actually does the
scans for you you know in those scans
right you might not be able to get the
results that you're looking for
or you also may be missing results so
that's why i encourage you
or encourage other students as well too
that are going to be pairing or taking
the course
is to use these tools manually start
getting an understanding and build your
knowledge of how the tools work
and also be able to learn more about
what to do with specific parts of the
tool that you're going to be using
i'm not really a huge fan of automated
tools because automated tools really do
skip a lot of things unless you actually
know what the tool is actually scanning
or what the tool is actually doing what
the purpose is for it if that makes
sense
sweet so we've got another question here
from mr angus angus red
do you try harder in your day-to-day
life tj
no i don't try harder every day no i'm
just kidding i
i take that mindset and i take that
motto with me wherever i go and i feel
like it's been a really a big part of
motto not just
even like with me taking the course and
taking the exam but it's been part of my
life for a long time
really going through before the course
starting the course and after the course
and still continuing now
you know trying different ways you know
being creative having a different
perspective on things and also being
persistence on what i try to do
sweet uh going on here uh what is the
best way to my self learning
school and life in general i find myself
spending too much time
in security i'm not enough time in
school and vice versa i should have
tried to schedule
my my exam weeks out in advance i would
say
schedule your exam at least like i said
three to four weeks in advance
you know try to be able to find a
balance of your skills
you know taking time going through a box
and also taking time to do the course
material
but also when you're preparing for the
exam itself using that lab network the
pwk lab network itself
use it as a way to test yourself going
through the lab get getting ready to
prepare for the exam
you know go through boxes on different
ways right you know in the lab network
itself there's probably more than one
way to get into
you know into those targets or those
systems right whether it's through
password reuse whether it's through
security misconfiguration
there's always an alternative to find a
way to get into those targets
sweet uh another questions in here are
there any
specific programming languages that
you'd suggest that one should know
before entering into pwk
i'd say it really it depends
uh i personally recommend python because
a lot of exploits
are used in python right and get an
understanding of how
you know how some people write their
exploits what changes you need to make
to it um i also say powershell is
another big thing to add to it the
new pwk has a whole new section on
powershell scripting which is really
cool
and also using some powershell tools as
well but getting at least a good
understanding of how powershell works
how to write your own command list i
think those are big helps
as well you know helping yourself get a
better understanding of the course
material moving forward
i've got a question from jack and chat
um off topic but yeah sort of relevant
do you have a mentor or someone who
inspired you or motivated you to begin
your
infosec journey my mentor was actually
my high school teacher
without him uh giving me that backtrack
cd in the backtrack cookbook i would
have never got started to where i am now
and he was actually a cisco teacher and
he would just teach me more about cisco
fundamentals
so he really went out of his way to do
that kind of stuff
sweet um jesus there's so many questions
they're all flying in now
um how would you compare oscp to gxpn i
assume they mean
sans gxpn and if you've sat either of
the two i have sat in gxpn and i will
say that
gxpn is a little bit more advanced than
the pwk because the pwk is to focus on
the pen testing fundamentals uh gxpn
definitely focuses on
exploit development uh and moving on to
some more advanced tools there
so sweet so
go on on discord are you allowed to
write and bring your own tools into
the exam you can be able to yes but i
would if you
want to make sure that it doesn't meet
any of the exam restrictions
you can definitely ask a student admin
or an essay from support they'll be able
to give you a better understanding if
that tool is approved or not
[Music]
anymore i think that's
most of the questions we've still got 20
minutes left you rattled through
everything in like
30 23 minutes flat so yeah i figured i'd
get more questions or at least try to
have some discussion if anybody wants to
bring anything up or have any advice
uh at least to get go ahead and get
started with i've got a question i
suppose
after after oscp what what was your kind
of next steps
into like well actually i supposed to
rephrase that question
how far into or before your career did
you take your scp and what were your
next steps after oscp
so i will tell you before i got my oscp
my goal was to get it um but i actually
went down the blue team path i was a
stock analyst
for two years working in my career once
i graduated college
and going through that when i started
preparing more for osp
a lot of the material i learned for osp
also helped me with my daily job trying
to detect things trying to look at
specific attacks or events as well too
to help me figure out
you know how does it you know a hacker
actually do this in this type of mindset
or how to run through these things right
so that really helped me out you know
moving to my career
becoming an actual full pentester now uh
so now i'm starting to move more into
exploit development
and my goal and my plan is to actually
pursue the osce by the end of this year
and also to try to get into the wireless
section as well too so i might actually
even do oswp
as well too and hopefully have a guide
for those as well too in the future
do you know if they're updating oswp
because i sat a couple years ago and it
was still
pretty updated i cannot comment on that
unfortunately
but if any plans or announcements come
soon you will see that on the official
communication channels
sweet uh question here do you need to
do you need the new material to pass the
exam now if you've said it previously if
you've had the course previously
i would say no if you've already taken
the old material and you've already have
sat down for the exam
because the exam like i said is still
the same the only big difference is
between the new upgrade of the pwk
which i highly recommend or encourage
you that you do is there's a lot of new
material and also a lot of different new
techniques and concepts
that you should go through and try to
look into that maybe could even help you
out to your next exam attempt
sweet uh have you got have you got any
tips for the exams specifically anything
for people who are concerned about time
or pace i think that you sort of covered
that thought of it not sprinting
i could go a little bit more in depth on
that so um when i went through my exam
attempt i had a rule
of trying five things i don't know if
anybody could really see my hand don't
show in five
but um i would try five different things
right
five different scans you know depending
on the information i get or from the
systems i would see right
if those five things didn't work in that
time of what i was doing i would move on
to the next system right
and go from that next system to the next
system until i
feel like i had enough information or
i actually pawned the entire system i
got the full access i needed
and i had my proper screenshots i needed
to put into the report
sweet um
i've not spotted any more questions
chris have you spotted any more
questions i just want
um are there any tutoring services out
there
i'm not the best at teaching myself so
uh javanov on twitch is asking if
there's any tutoring services
directly for oscp not at this time
what i'd say is if you need any advice
or guidance you can always talk to the
support admins
they are usually very kind and also
general they're able to help you out or
support you although they won't give you
the exact answer you may be looking for
but they'll at least give you some tips
and ideas of what to look for next you
know this the purpose of the course
itself is to be self-paced you know to
be on to your learning
um but there's always places as well too
to get guidance i'm trying to support
you trying to go through those systems
that you may have trouble with
uh i think that's all the questions
here can we extend the lab after
expiration by paying extra yes you can
so if you ever want to extend your lab
extension as well too
you should have received an email in
your original email when you got your
course
that should give you a purchase link and
in that purchase link you can actually
go ahead and extend your lab extension
from what you there
but that depends on the material that
you've gone through
um
awesome thanks i think that
that wraps it up potentially oh wait
there's no question
[ __ ] they're just gonna keep coming
every single time you say i think we're
about to wrap it up it's like
there's one more i mean we're still
within time we still got 20 odd minutes
how how much is how i need to actually
phrase this it makes sense
how different is the new pwk
and the e-learning penetration testing
professional in terms of updated study
material
i think i'd say between
that material when i took it to the new
pwk material now active directory
attacks is really big
there's a whole section just getting
started of how to access an active
directory environment how to be able to
access a domain controller
what a taxi could be able to do as well
too they're specifically on there
and also to focus more on depth as well
on powershell empire
as well too going ahead and actually
setting up your own post-exploitation
framework as well too with that tool
cool uh right four other questions i've
landed since that question was asked
i'm going to turn on morning chats i can
actually see it
um two seconds um
slow there we go uh right so
question uh what is the toughest machine
and how did you approach it without
revealing anything about the specific
box
hmm toughest machine that i did in the
pwk environment
i have to say was humble humble was the
it's one of the big four boxes and it's
still and it's in the new pwk as well
that was a tough one for me um but
getting to understand the person who
actually
um found the vulnerability for that box
was really cool nice
um that's i was wondering
how how well-versed in networking do you
have to be before you take the course
could a noob take it without any
networking experience
i'd say at least have some understanding
and when i mean understanding
i say understand how you know ip
addresses work how subnetting works how
the flow
of network communication works right you
know how you how
like networking is sent right how
packets are being sent forward with your
sin synack
you know in your act packets right also
understand the different protocols that
are out there right we have a total of
6 65 533 different protocols running on
tcp
and on udp with different ports of what
different purposes they're supposed to
be doing
so if you try to go in with the pwk with
no networking experience at all
it could be a little bit tough for you
in the challenge although the courses
can walk you through some of it
it's good to at least have some type of
understanding you know so get you
ahead of the course more properly and
also gives you a better understanding of
what they're going to be discussing in
the material itself
uh right okay more questions wrong
people keep asking
more questions
are you can you go chrissy i've got one
here from jack
yeah um any thoughts on implementing
gns3
even g and creating your own networks
and
practice phones exploits for oscp
that is up to you entirely as a person
um
you know having that type of setup is
great you know having a home lab is
definitely great to have that all set up
um
i mean i even have my own for what i was
doing um
so i think that will give you a better
understanding experience
you know how to prepare yourself pretty
recklessly you know once you are ready
to get a better understanding of the
networking fundamentals the operating
system's right
doing a little bit of programming will
get you ready and ahead to start the
course but that really all depends on
how much time
and effort you're going to put into that
as well too preparing for it
well thanks just following that um what
ctfs do you recommend
to help prepare for the oscp
so there's a lot of good ctfs that are
out there picoctf was a great starting
one for me
during my high school years especially
um
and there's a lot of good free based
ones that are out there uh if you ever
want to find any good ctfs on there uh
that are around ctf time i believe has a
really good
set of upcoming cts that come out um
that usually people go through
um question here what search would you
recommend doing
after oscp um that really depends on to
that person or that or
what you really want to do what kind of
passion you have you know
some people for instance that i've
talked to over the years you know they
say oh i really like to get into web
exploit you know web development right
or you know finding web
uh web attacks or finding web exploits
right um and they go down you know the
web route or some people like to go into
the exploit development
around that really depends on what you
want to do
or even further advance your skills you
know in kind of you know in network
penetration testing mobile pen testing
that's
really depends on you and what you
really want to do you know for me
personally i think my big thing now is
getting into exploit development
and that's something i want to start
doing next um i did take the awa e
course i was really
i really enjoyed it especially going
through and analyzing the source code
that we're given for each challenge
and also made you really think outside
the box of what you were looking at
but i'm probably going to come back to
that soon because i feel like i have a
much bigger passion than exploit
development now since that's what i've
been doing more in my current role
for fun really nice um
one here does the five machines for the
exam and could the buffer up buffer
overflow or is the buffer flow machine
separate and you have to hack five i
cannot answer that
um like i s the only thing i can't
answer at least is you will have five
targets
that you will have to assess cool uh
follow-up from that is
uh the course materials mentions cali a
lot is there a reason why you need to
use cali
or is it you can use anything you want
like i mentioned earlier you could use
whatever
district you want to use uh cali is the
big one that we use
in the course because that's what we
teach about too there's a whole chapter
based on cali
you know where to find specific tools
review different docs how to build your
own custom
cali those little things are in there
but we refer everything to the actually
the cali's websites
you know that are there um and the other
thing too is that support
admins will be able to support you
better because that's the operating
system that they'll be able to support
you on you know in case you have any vpn
issues
any troubleshooting issues that you have
getting into the lab environment or even
accessing the lab environment
that's the system that they'll be able
to be able to understand and
troubleshoot with you
okay um question here is oscp
a prerequisite for attempting osce
i would think so personally myself um
unfortunately there's no really road map
to you know what to go after next
you know for a specific course that
offset has but i would say definitely if
you want to get into exploit development
go ahead and do osce if you want to be
able to understand more web attacks
understand white box web app pen testing
definitely go ahead and take
oswe or awae right um if you want to get
into wireless do oswp
like i said like i mentioned earlier it
really depends on what you want to
do next that offset security has for
courses and also what cert you want to
go for next that they have
sweet uh if you currently have the old
report and upgrade to the new pwk will
the old report assume they're talking
about the lab report qualify for five
points or will they need to re-complete
a new report
uh to qualify for the five points i was
actually waiting for this question yes
it still counts for which
uh so when you take your next exam that
lab report that you did earlier that
completed all the exercises on there
and also the la also uh assessing the
ten systems that still counts for your
five points possibly
once you submit it with your report
sweet um question here about the exam
can you use a multiple display setup
during the exam or is it restricted to
one screen only
you can be able to use multiple displays
for your exam
the only thing i would totally recommend
that you make sure
is that the proctor is aware that you
are using multiple screens
because their software that they need to
use will be able to review all screens
of what you're doing for your assessment
otherwise they could revoke your exam
attempt
sweet um anything proper specific
wise exam takers should be aware of i
hear the proctoring software is a chrome
plugin
should be okay to fill screen or vm or
what we need to
need the software visible on the host
operating system
i my recommendation is that is that when
you are going to be starting your exam
i would say go ahead and get your
software set up 30 minutes before your
exam
and work with the proctor on that and
see what the proctor says i don't really
have a full answer for that
um but i know that proctoring the
proctoring team will have a better
answer for you
have a better answer for you when you do
that
there's one that's just coming here is
there a minimum recommendation
um yourself have you got a minimum
recommendation of the amount of machines
that you should hack out of 75 before
attempting the exam
very good question um
i say that really like it's another
depending question
you know it depends really on you some
people say the minimum you know systems
that you need to assess is 30 machines
however i say go through them all each
system has its own different scenario
its own different way of getting into
the system and really it's a fun lab to
be in
you know you have systems with multiple
domain controllers in different act you
know different environments that you
could
assess and go into um so i'd say try to
go through all of them as you can
or at least you know go through as many
systems as you can where you think you
are comfortable to take the exam
and if you have leftover lab time and
you fail the exam that still gives you
the opportunity to go through the other
systems that are in the lab to help you
prepare for your next exam attempt
a question here about preparing for
preparing for the oscp
preparation is try hackney a
a good platform to help with oscp and
consequently is it hacked the box
equally as good or as are view any other
further recommendations
this is uh this is a question i don't
know if i really want to answer
um because i feel like there's so many
platforms that are out there that are
trying to help prepare
people for ocp um it's really kind of
tough
but it really also depends on you you
know when i went through it myself
i used you know vom hub and hacked the
box as my preparations of myself you
know to go ahead and
you know prepare for the pwking exam
that's why i have that list
um but that really just depends on you
and also the community's reviews on how
they go through that
okay um
all right there's a there's a joke
question in here so
are there any industry recognized
certifications that have a mantra of try
less maybe tomorrow
oh my god i don't know if i want to
answer that question um
a lot a lot of community has a bunch of
different responses for that and i'll
let the community answer that question
for
that person
sweet uh
i don't know if there's any other
questions i i say i'll say that now
there's gonna be about
nine that will land in the next couple
of seconds if anybody has under
questions anybody can ask me
you know um later i'm gonna be you know
hanging out in the many hats club
general voice chat
so if anybody wants to ask me any
questions on voice or in the general
voice chat they can certainly do that if
needed
how long do you ideally spend on writing
the report after you've sat the exam
so i did the entire exam in report with
a total of 38 hours
um and that's really my fault uh because
i really should have slept
after i got i think i thought that i had
enough points right
you know to go through the exam um but
that really depends on you
and how you balance your time and how to
go through it you know and that's
something you can build off of
okay uh what other
uh mindset slash mantra uh do oscp
provide other other than the legendary
try harder
that is there that is a really big model
that we have um and also our core values
that you can also find on our website as
well too of
you know how we be able to bring the
community together how we can be able to
grow and adapt and also be able to
you know push each other as well to
learn more especially in this field
um
from from the good old thc mods um
what's your favorite dinosaur
tyrannosaurus rex even though it's got
little hands it's still the giant
um another one in here what is a
computer
no not answering that
if there's any other oscp pwk questions
or any prep questions that i can answer
you know this is this is your time to
shout them now
so and you know i i'm looking at the
chat too just
seeing you know a lot of the questions
here you know
don't be scared about going through this
course it's just like almost any other
certification that you go out there for
you know you just have to take the time
to go through it prepare for it
you know understand the material that
they teach you in it you know and when
you're comfortable and ready they're in
the exam
do the best you can at least that's all
that matters
yeah uh well we've got eight minutes to
go uh
do we do it what was that one
we can wrap up if there are any final
questions that we'll ask them or we can
we can do the magical send me the
command i need to run
pj by the way absolutely fantastic
talking thank you for coming on and
taking all these questions as well like
for at least
20 minutes it must be quite hard
i i prepared this talk to at least have
some questions for sure and at least to
answer the community you know that
a lot of people go through this course a
lot and i know a lot of people struggle
through this and
you know my goal at least is to help
prepare the future and you know the
community that want to do this
you know this is something i think you
know everyone should try at least
you know but the course is also not for
everyone as well too
but for you know if you have at least a
good strong passion and a good
understanding of what you need to
prepare for for this course
then you will definitely enjoy the
course and learn from it and yeah you're
going to stress you're going to struggle
but
um but most importantly i want to really
thank the many hats club for having me
on here speaking with you guys talking
about
you know the pwk and how to prepare for
it um i know we're all going through
some tough times right now but i know
certainly that we'll get through it
you know in the future as well too with
this
oh right questions are flown in again as
one would think
you should have escaped when you had the
chance yeah i should have should have
run
uh does the oscp make sense for someone
who is interested in getting into cloud
security
yes definitely i think for sure um you
know
as we now start seeing more systems move
into the cloud right in aws
and google suite and also um in digital
ocean right
we need to have people to be able to
assess those systems that are in the
cloud and those virtual private spaces
as well too
and i think it's really important you
know at least to have that you know the
fundamentals the hacker mindset that you
take in the pwk
it's definitely gonna help you apply
that methodology and your concepts as
well too
going into those cloud environments as
well that's a very good question
uh probably last last question or so and
then we can transition over to
stu uh how did the oscp help
getting into the job field it really
helped me
i i will say that um in order for me to
be a pen tester um
in the private sector where i was um
it definitely opened a lot of doors for
me one once i obtained that cert and
earned it properly
um and also in fairness as well with it
so um
once i immediately got my oscp i was
hired on two weeks later to be a
pentester in the private sector team
that i worked for
and really i enjoyed working with that
team ever since and also working with
the offset guys as well too