[Music]
actually hey everyone
it's uh fat hobbit here with angus
uh red blue so at angus red blue
former british airborne and uh six plus
years
uh doing all sorts of crazy high risk
security consulting
live from cape town in south africa
welcome angus
thank you uh thank you everyone for uh
having me i hope
uh today's informative and uh we'll see
how it goes
right so i guess we'll get started um so
uh today my talk uh is about uh you know
as the term says i recruit hackers so
it's my quickly about my personal
journey
uh getting into infostick and then a
little bit about
how recruiting works and and what
matters to get the job
um so here we go right so today
uh we'll be covering the following um
following bits so just my introduction
we'll touch on my passing to infosec
we'll then talk about your entry into
infosec so
various examples i've seen um for the
last three years doing recruiting
um then we'll touch on the more
important bit which is
what matters so we'll talk a little
about resumes linkedin
certain degrees that's when it goes
prepare for some ambiguity
i might hop around a bit
then we'll go on to your career we'll
just talk about
uh we'll talk about the short term the
medium term and the long term
decisions that you need to make to make
sure your um
your career goes well and that you
represent yourself well and it always
brings value
we'll go through some tips and then
hopefully some some questions at the end
right so disclaimer as it goes uh this
is my personal opinion doesn't represent
the opinion of
my employer nor does it represent the
opinion of my own company
um so uh just bear that in mind also i'm
not a
de facto you know principal authority on
this is just the information and the
knowledge i've collated over the last
few years
right so who am i all right so
uh i basically uh left cape towns africa
um
against afghan military didn't work out
so i decided to go to the uk to get a a
good sort of
combat experience um over there so six
years
two years as a gunner four years as a
signal attachment
ehf and hfcoms for companies um
i then did six years in physical
security contracting predominantly
in east and west africa a lot of time in
mozambique and sierra leone
and then some time in the middle east as
a bodyguard
okay after that um my sort of we'll get
into it shortly in my past crossed
um with someone in infosec and i've been
working for that person ever since
i'm currently i'm a uh besides cape town
co-organizer
um i mentor the shock on resume program
i do a bit of [ __ ] posting on tmhc and
i'm using the main mod
and then i also run a small
group of uh infosec
you know curious people called hacksaws
uh which is
it's kind of like tmhc not as glamorous
but it's all for us
africans in the industry
in summary this is basically me
my likes and desires and and my
background
right so my path into infosec
so yeah basically is so i was an army
um i decided to get out the military um
i went to our careers
uh officers managers it's about a
six-year-old
uh former major colonel and i told him
that i want to get into security um now
when i mention security it usually means
physical security because
exactly sort of industry understood um i
was then told
you know why have you completed becoming
a bricklayer or a carpenter
um and this just didn't fly for me so
um i started building my information and
and running my own track
um i then you know
a lot of guys in my battalion flagged me
as the guy that has the knowledge and
does the research so they kept coming to
me asking me the same questions and i'd
give them the same answers but do
different people
so i set up a facebook group um called
termination sharepoint
um sharepoint i learned was a bad word
because
i got a lot of people adding me asking
about sharepoint administration
um and through that um we basically
started off with guys my battalion grew
to our regiment and then it became a
tri-service thing
and then there was also an offshoot in
the united states um
through termination sharepoint i was
introduced to someone
who everyone knows now as swordfish or
morgan
she helped me with a few bits there she
was a she was an admin for me
um but after that we kind of lost track
of each other
and then about three and a half years
ago she introduced me to
the man in the top right marcelo mansour
he's the ceo
of red blue security she introduced me
to him saying hey he's coming to cape
town
um can i give him a basic overview of
the security posture in south africa
and in cape town you know where to go
where not to go um i was running a small
consulting company at that time um he
came to cape town
um he asked me what i did i said no do
security consulting i asked him what he
did and he said no he would attack us
for a living and i immediately told him
you know that's
that's illegal and i should uh i should
distance myself from this person i've
always been a law-abiding citizen
from there um he told me about the
industry he told me about
you know defcon he told me about b-sides
talking about the community and the you
know
the interesting parts about it and i
found it fascinating and i realized this
is
this is something i've been looking for
for a long time you know i didn't have
i've always had high paying jobs but not
a lot of fulfillment
um so moving on from there um
i joined red blue and now this is my
life a lot of uh tabs on chrome
uh over usage of my uh my disc on my cpu
so moving on okay you're entering to
infosec
how could this look right there's no
proven route into security
um i literally want you to repeat this
after me um there's very different ways
uh the term is used as non-linear um
there is so many different ways to get
in security what i found
in brief is this the there's a few
different tracks so one is university
route so
someone that's studying cs university um
they then you know
find a hacker meet up or they find
something uh
community related in the university i
then get a taste for it
they sometimes change their major get an
internship and start working
professionally
the gamer root which i've seen very
common you know avid gamers that want to
be the best they find cheat codes
they end up not being uh happy with the
chicos and they start learning how to
script
and then next you know they're part of
the hakka community
some other bits activism seemed used to
be a popular one
in 2005 2008 um know this is a this is a
you know a different way to get into it
the uh the key in the activism one is
obviously
not to get caught um a lot of people get
influenced
by you know parents or friends um
they have a curious nature and they
start doing research and they start
figuring out stuff and they find
communities like the mini house club
hacksaws b-sides and go from there
okay re-roll i see this uh quite a lot
it
tends to be the trickier one but it uh
it means
that someone has a good baseline
understanding of
uh of uh i.t um and how
networking works sometimes um so this
tends to be
sometimes a tricky transition especially
if you've been you know a cis ad or a
help desk
individual for a long time sometimes
that transition is tough
um but i see this is a very common one
linear
is the lucky ones that are born into
this age that
are exploited or not exploited that are
introduced to this industry from an
early age
um so that they could be molded into
you know potentially not being a black
cat and being a force for
um all right let's go
your first step so i i drum about this
constantly it's community engagement you
know
being here today this is the first step
um
so congratulations on that i'm getting
involved with community
um there's obviously usually a lot of
noise a lot of drama especially on
twitter
but getting involved in the community
whether it is on a discord server like
tmhc
hack south um you know laptop hacking
or document or whatever is a good start
because it's a good source of
information
and you get a lot of people that can
mentor you um i know there's a there's a
few people on tmhc that really
uh you know do a lot for me and teaching
me basic things
um so you know it's it's it's important
um that also goes for like things like
b-sides like
get involved so if you can't afford to
go
volunteer for a con um point on that um
it's you know as an organizer you
quickly see who the people are
volunteering
um because uh they want to make the con
happen
you know they want to be noticed and
then you get people that volunteer for a
con because they want a free ticket
um try try and do your bits if you have
a good organizing team
you should end up being able to enjoy
the con you know watching the talks that
you want to watch
um but the idea is you give your time
and one of the perks is obviously you
know it doesn't cost you anything
if you can't find your own community and
you know your local university then
start one
um there's enough people out there that
will give you enough advice about that
don't be shy um i remember when i joined
tmhe i was
uh i was really scared about joining vc
um
i did uh with uh with a friend of mine
sticks
and slowly slowly surely people started
joining uh voice
vc and i'm introduced to everyone and
then i guess i've been uh
i've been on there a lot yeah we're all
weirdos
we all have our insecurities i know
fruit was doing a talk about that
earlier
um a lot of people always say you know
when they get involved with the
community they tend to find new people
another thing is upskill take advantage
of free training if there's some free
training out there like i recently
signed up for an autopsy course
um then go for it um
abl i always say always be learning this
is an issue where you constantly
constantly have to learn i know it's
sometimes daunting
but if you can do one course a year one
course every two years
try and do that yeah give if you give an
opportunity
do some training right for summary
there's no one way into infosec
tell the most what i mean by that is i
tell my trainer i've told my mom and dad
i've told
my younger cousins like hey there's this
industry out there and
you might enjoy it don't be evil
basically don't be um i don't know if
it's a peace term don't be an [ __ ]
um there's a lot of people out there
that are a lot more superior to you
in skills and abilities and mindset and
culture
um but there's also a lot of people
below you
um do what you can be helpful um
if you don't want to get involved then
then just sort of
you know stay the gray man and and and
and don't
push yourself too far there okay this is
something i'm i'm looking at these days
is
i now have a few skills in cali um i can
help people that are literally
just just just just getting started um
i can do that because i know a few
little basic things there's a lot of
people above me that know a lot more
more more than me like sticks or cyber
viking or alan
blank if there's anyone else instead of
having to ask them the question
come to me and you know you sort of
climb up the track for the ladder
become part of the conversation part of
the community and there's some
fewer things you know if you can cfp for
uh for a con do so
um there's a lot of value in it always
be learning
and yeah that's that okay so what
matters this is the the
the the big chunk of my talk um okay
so
okay so subjects i'll be covering here
is resumes linkedin
applications interviews tech tests
closing twitter
certain education um i have you know i'm
limited for time
this is this is something that i can
talk about and a lot of us can talk
about for hours and hours
but i try to stick to some of the
pertinent points and there's obviously
some memes for your entertainment
right so what matters on a resume okay
so
resume is the first step in the process
a lot of people fail to realize this
they'll go
you know why is my linkedin not enough
and the
simple fact is that um the resume is the
is like your professional id card you
need that resume
to to to get sent over to a company to
you know
interview for a job so it's important to
have it
okay time on target it is important to
understand
that if there is a big job with a lot of
applications
people aren't going to open your resume
and go and spend five ten minutes on it
the first sift in a resume um
you know shortlisting people look i tend
to look for things that
make you not applicable to this job so
short stint you know if you've done two
months here three months here four
months there
you're at high risk um i look at
it sounds bad but i look at the negative
things right after that
is when people will spend time on your
resume and look at it and assess it
and look for the things that make you a
valuable candidate for the job
yeah as an either beholder when i do
resume reviews i always
push this point it is important to
understand i might think your resume
looks amazing the next recruiter or the
next employer might think it looks
terrible
it literally is not either beholder
okay one page is great two pages fine
three is not
four's four places north korea
so i find i found a lot of people that
have been in this industry for 20 years
industry leaders that i've interviewed
that'll manage to squeeze 20 years into
into a one pager
i've then found people that have been in
this industry for two years and have a
six page resume
um ironically here in south africa the
old tradition was the longer your resume
the better you are i think my old man
used to have a
a 26 page resume and i forced him down
to a one pager
so this is a an important part
yeah okay community engagement
i've you know i've talked about that
quite a bit get involved uh it
what it does is uh your community
engagement so this is you know
volunteering at a con
this is giving a talk at a con or giving
a workshop whatever
it shows commonality it shows that
you're you know quote one of us
um and it's a good conversation starter
right a resume is a working document
it's not something you use
every time you need a job right it is a
working document
remember that work on it at least once a
month
if you've done a new course if you've
done
done you know done something at work you
know you just learned about aws or learn
about this
add it to your resume um the the problem
happens is when
your dream job might come up and you
don't have a resident already and by the
time it takes you a week to get your
resume ready you might have lost
opportunity
okay if and out of your screen what i
mean by this is read your resume and
when you finish resume
send it to someone that's good with
spelling and grammar um
and make sure it is it is perfect
um a lot of times i'll get very
frustrated people that have spelling and
grammar errors
um photo okay so the the contest on the
photo this is my personal consensus
um don't include a photo unless it's an
amazing photo professionally done
uh can a photo help yes but can a photo
be to your detriment
yes it can as well a photo as another
layer
that um a recruiter or an employer
can judge you on whether consciously or
subconsciously a photo
can add a bad layer um so remember that
okay personal
uh per sec or opsec
when it's important include your address
i the city
and the state you live in do not include
your home address
do not include a you know 152
summerfield lane
just say cape town south africa san
francisco california
that is all you need to put in there
don't don't
don't give more information than you
need to basically
okay layout you know this is this is a
tough one i i don't have one specific
layout i look for
but layouts are important make sure you
have something that is new that is
new age i mean a lot of people have
developer resumes
um so there's there's various uh things
you can look at there
color use color i really don't think
color is a problem i like color it
highlights certain
different things what's there to talk
about so this is about
um leaving not including everything in
your resume so leaving something to be
discussed during an interview
yeah we've covered that okay long
service breakdown
um a lot of people if they've been at a
company for 12 years will have one
little bit if you've been uncomfortable
12 years
you know if you've been you start off as
an analyst and you became a secure
engineer and now you're
a staff security engineer i would break
those up it shows
that you promoted well it shows the
timing in which you promote it
it it once again it adds a lot of value
to yourself
ten year legacy so
is it important to include something
that you did ten years ago
it depends on what it is if ten years
ago you used to
the pizzas not really relevant if what
you did
10 years ago military service or you
know working intelligence community
then i would say include it but if it
starts getting to the five ten year
point in the past
what a lot of people do just have the
company they work for the title
and then the year if the company is
interested in it they'll ask about it
okay so at the top of your resume you
have a summary
there's three points you want to cover
there what you did
what you're doing and what you want to
do in the future some resumes don't have
a summary i'm
you either have a summary or not it's
irrelevant to me if you are
transitioning or trying to get into
security
i strongly suggest having a good summary
okay yeah as i mentioned earlier when do
you work in a resume i would say touch
your resume
at least once a month one every once
every three months tinker it
adds stuff okay lead hackers
so the important thing is technical
ability
but do not overstate it you will get
caught out
especially the company as a tech test
especially if the people that are
working that are interviewing you
are far superior to you in a technical
ability state what you can do
but never never overreach never
overstate just
okay so a lot of people ask me how do i
display technical stuff to a
non-technical recruiter so
i found this on a few resumes and i
found it to be the best way to do it
right so quickly on top of your resume
you build a table
with two columns and let's say
uh or two two rows five columns six
columns right
on the left you put the subject matter
so pen testing
and next state you will list everything
that you touched or that you have
experience in
in the right hand column this helps
on a keyword search this helps on a
boolean search
this help if your resume gets passed in
an applicant tracking system
this helps a non-technical critter
understand like oh
this person ticks a lot of these boxes
so they must be good i myself a
technical recruiter so i understand the
nuances
and what what adds value and what does
not
okay and these are just some really bad
resume memes i found on my journeys
okay linkedin use your linkedin summary
as a two to three paragraph resume so
when you whenever when a
profile comes up you can only see a few
lines of your summary or you have to
click more to see the rest
use that as like a imagine you had to do
a tweet and in that tweet well
you had to put your resume like the
pertinent points of view
it's important to have a summary list
yeah who you are what your skill sets
are and your community engagement
you know below that okay job experience
um
as it says here uh you know list of
companies you're working for try
link japanese page
um it it you know it stands out more
okay recommendations ask recommendations
i boss recommendations from my father
from my line managers
from people i have managed and from our
teammates
it all adds a lot of value i quickly
want to touch on skill so that you know
on linkedin there's a thing we can add
skills
various words people endorse you for
there is no value to that
except one thing right and that is
that you can list a lot of words there
that will come up on a keyword
search when uh when we do a search on
linkedin for you which i'll show you
shortly
okay so what are recruiters sees okay so
i pay we pay a lot of money for linkedin
probably about 20 30 000
a year that gives us access to every
profile that exists on linkedin
irrespective of our degrees of
connection
i can search these metrics to find what
i'm looking for
do i use all of these no i do not i
actually use very few of them
as a search starts you start a very
specific search you'll search people
only in a certain city and state you
will search only certain skills only
certain certs
levels of degrees whatever and as the
search goes on
and you filter through people you
broaden the search
all right so that's what happens when i
run the search it brings up this
right it brings up this uh the the
cr the search on san francisco skill
oscp
for security engineers is the key word
for building right
i start on the right uh so these are
company connections so as companies i
follow that
people work there the next is open to
new opportunities which is something
we'll cover
shortly so that's the top real thing on
your profile that shows right
you know i'm open to new opportunities
then more likely to respond does it says
in the 10
it's basically people that um linkedin
algorithm has shown to respond to end
males
and the the the total amount of
candidates is there 71.
point to note linkedin the linkedin
algorithm
is terrible i still say i wish uh
linkedin would hire a former head of
search from google to help them with
algorithms but you know
say la vie okay
open to new opportunities this is a
valuable tool if you're looking for a
gig
right if you have premium there's more
options but this will look like so
on your profile you'll see you can
show yourself as opportunity
opportunities point to note
people that have the system that i have
recruiter professional services can see
that
no one else can if you're worried about
your company seeing it
i think they've set a filter that people
in the same company can't see your
profile
doesn't mean there's they can't work
around it um but it only shows to
recruiters
you can list if you just have the free
version you can list five job titles
five job locations and you can select
full-time contract or part-time
this was just me as if i was looking for
a gig now um
you had a security physical potentially
and then when this is what it looks like
um
let me show you here it will come up i
haven't actually got it
it will come up on your profile to top
your profile
so once again when i run a search and
say now search san francisco
the word san francisco will be highlight
and yellow and will stand out the more
times you have a word that picks up in
the search the higher up in the search
results you are right so i think that is
linkedin
right applications
i will touch on this briefly so it's
important to understand
what to apply for should you apply for
every job out there
i really don't think so i think it is
important to be more meticulous right
you have to be interested in the job but
instead of working the company all right
and it's all important to understand who
wrote the job description there
some amazing job descriptions out there
there are some terrible ones
the company it's important to remember
who writes this thing sometimes it'll be
a hr representative
sometimes it'll be i have clients that
use technical writers just
writing job descriptions um it's
important to also note
one job description does not equal one
job a lot of times there'll be a job
description
for five positions at a company and
they've kind of amalgamated it
right so it's it's important to remember
that because you'll think oh but i've
got to have this skill and that skill
and that skill
if you fit about 50 of that jobs job
description
you're good to go right so this is an
article um that i read recently that
said
that uh women tend to apply for a job
when they fit hundred percent of the
criteria
and men will apply when they hit six
percent of criteria
in my belief if you believe in your
heart of hearts you can do that job
right apply for it if you think you're
reaching to get that job
don't be too disheartened when you get
rejected all right it's just part of it
and the this was some other stuff i
found i've got the link at the
at the end there was an article done by
an executive from linkedin
okay interviews what matters okay so
interviews can go down
in various different ways a
people it could be a zoo meeting it can
be a webex it can be whatever
right it might your first if you might
be face to face so it's important to
prepare yourself for that if you know if
you're gonna do a zoom meeting
don't ask him is it gonna be video just
be prepared for that okay
um sometimes you might have to do a zoom
call and you might have to do a tech
test with like a virtual machine so be
ready for that
treat every interview like it's your
dream
job all right i found it recently that
i have send people jobs
right they have then interviewed with
that interview because they as you know
they they have many interviews with
various different companies
but they don't treat each one especially
if you can't treat one specially maybe
space them out more so you have more
time
to prepare but what you don't want to
happen is is
you to fail the interview because you
weren't prepared or you didn't know
anything about the company
and then afterwards you realized it was
a tremendous opportunity it was a very
high paying job with really
good perks in that in that case
you are literally the only one to be
that failed there so
treat every job like it's it's it could
be a dream job
um right so three knows and i've seen
this before
if if someone like me sends you a job an
offensive security engineering position
at a company all right
don't try prove your worth before you
are asked to do so
right when you're doing if you you can
do oh synth on the on the company and
the
the people interviewing you but keep it
keep it at a very high level don't start
checking what their passwords are and
don't start
looking for them on leaked websites it
it can creep someone out
very quickly um so yeah
as i say they show your abilities when
you are asked to do so
okay video conferences make sure you
wear pants be yourself hundred percent
and remember it's a two-way range okay
so in an
interview it's important to note the
company is seeing if you're a suitable
candidate for them for the position
they're looking at your technical
ability
you're if you're a culture fit and
they're looking at your background
but it's important to remember as i said
there it is a two-way range
you are assessing the company as much as
they are assessing you
all right so keep that in mind if you
have questions on the interview ask
questions
um it's it's it's something that people
fail to realize
you you are in a power seat as well it's
not that the company
no matter how many people on the
interview panel you also
possess and hold power
and these are some things to look at you
know do i have a good manager what are
my team members like what are the perks
for the company there's there's various
things to consider
okay another thing that i find some
people do some people don't communicate
with your recruiter
we are not just you know pimps of the
infosec industry some
are but a lot of us are not right i
myself
i do forget people i have i invest tools
and systems to remember people and to
check into people
but i try record as little information
about people as i can
stay in touch with recruiter if the
client sometimes
the client will speak to the recruiter
to get your availability for an
interview and then it will be like a
like a little love triangle going on
sometimes it is the recruiter will know
that it's better if you just work
directly with a company but remember
that company might be hiring a thousand
people they haven't got time to speak to
us the recruiter
to say hey this interview's been blocked
hey this was a reschedule
something happens if the recruiter has
signal or email or whatsapp or whatever
just drop them a message um and say hey
got an email from the client
they want to reschedule or email from a
client they are moving to the next phase
and that way the recruiter can also pull
information from the from the client
and if you're having trouble with the
process to the recruiter
okay what matters in tech test tech
tests are tricky one
i have seen various different tech tests
some of them will be a hacker rank test
some of them will be a 24 hour ctf with
a
executive report afterwards and another
summary afterwards
prepare yourself for it to be crazy
all right and hope that it's not
yeah i said yeah yeah sometimes on tech
tests you'll be asked to write to report
some companies will send you like a 24
hour cta
the exam works some will give you three
different ctfs
of 12 hours there's such a white
wide mix usually companies use their own
um
virtual machines or their own sort of
ctf challenges um
some companies don't know use hack the
box they'll use stuff for vuln hub
you know if you've if you've done
something on volnhub
um that they sent you you know that
you've hit the jackpot
okay closing the deal
okay points to consider before accepting
an offer
does the job fit your skills and fit
your abilities
if they do not do not accept an offer
if they if if you are doubting if you're
going to be good at this job
speak to the company right a lot of
times they're not going to see that as
you don't have confidence they're going
to see that as you being humble
right and if they are thinking that it
is a reach
they will probably tell you like look
this is a this is going to be a big
challenge for you but
we believe you can do it right don't
doubt yourself
but just have confidence in what you do
but don't don't go for something that
you know you managed to blag your way
through the interview because what's
happening is you're gonna start that job
and you're probably gonna get terminated
within a month
does the company match your ethics and
culture if
i found with like a lot of veterans in
the us when they
in a hardcore hacker company they
they struggle with a culture make sure
the culture is a fit for you
right and then obviously do i get on
with the company
so it's important to note this right
there's three parts
you need to consider the short term
medium and the long term gain
short term gain is the salary the perks
the benefits all that stuff
the medium is what am i going to gain
from this job
technically and the long term is the
most important thing you got to think
about how this company and how this job
is going to look on your resume
how will the title look on your resume
and what value does it bring to your
future
um i feel that that part is the most
important especially if you're going to
make a career out of this
yes you might want to take you might
want to take a high paying job now
but maybe the job is over in nine months
or maybe
something happens with an unstable
company it is important to think about
that long-term thing when i was a
contractor i
look at what do they pay me per day
versus what the circumstances are
and i've worked in some really crazy
places um and then what does the value
of this in my resume
and especially when you have competing
offers that that last part
tends to be the the tipping scale
okay money talking agencies quickly
about this people ask me do you talk to
a recruiter about money
the answer is if you trust the recruiter
and you believe they have your best
interests in heart
yes talking about what you earn talk to
them about what you're looking for
but most importantly in that discussion
try get a bracket from them about
what is on offer usually it's what my
dad always says it's whoever talks
loser whoever to expose whoever talks
first
loses okay discuss money with them
right if you've been in a job for six
years you deserve a decent pay jump
right but it is important to understand
what number they are sending you over at
sometimes i will send people over and
say we didn't talk about money sometimes
i'll say hey this person is looking for
150 000. okay make sure you know what
that number is
okay because some recruiters will bump
it because the higher you get paid the
higher we get paid
um so that's that's important
okay twitter very quickly about twitter
get involved
uh who to follow i say follow the best
follow the noobs
follow a lot of people don't follow the
rest of this i sometimes fail at this
but don't talk about sex politics or
religion
turn air or dead laundry and don't troll
people if you want to troll people set a
patrol account
when it comes to do laundry you'll see
on my twitter every now and then i will
post the words i will not get involved
with
african politics and that's where i want
to say something but it just isn't the
place
okay quickly about certifications
right when do you do a course well if
you have a budget from your company
do a course okay you have to think about
the value you're going to gain from it
and there's very decent options as i've
i've shown here okay always check with
your company to see if they have an
educational reimbursement uh
program a lot of our clients have five
thousand dollars ten thousand dollar
educational reimbursement programs
so you do the course once a year for the
company okay
it's important to understand when you're
doing a course especially something uh
like with offensive security okay
think about the methodology of what you
are doing all right
do not think about getting that piece of
paper to put on your linkedin put in
your twitter
yes there is value in that okay but you
need to understand
the the bigger picture of the course
you're doing
the the challenge you're gonna face in
that course right because if you don't
you will not be able to apply what
you've learned in that course in the
real world
okay and yeah as always guys if you
can't if you can't afford a course do
your course do what this guy does with
the bella clover just
hack the planet and figure it out as you
go along
okay short term long term
uh a medium term this is something i've
already discussed right the decision's
always going to be about the money the
job and the resume
running low on time okay so
if you give me one second i will check
yeah okay
i've done this fairly hard right okay so
tips and summaries
different kind of tips but anyway okay
recruiter 101
it's important to understand how a
recruiter works
okay like i've discussed you today to
understand they they
they the reason why they do this but i
don't do this to buy porsches and buy
ferraris
and live la vida loca i'm doing this as
a job as anyone else would
you know to feed my family maybe go on a
nice holiday in decembers with my
daughter and my missus
and and to take care of ourselves this
is not there's a lot of recruiters out
there making a ton of money
i do this because i have a passion for
it i've often
probably seem like a terrible recruiter
because um
a candidate in mind will have three
offers of which one of them are mine and
i'll tend to advise them
on a taking another offer because it's
going to be better for the career
i believe you know karma that will come
back to me
get involved with the community as i
mentioned before i hit on this a lot
always be learning
if you have the opportunity to do
training do training
help the less experienced and learn from
those more it i
i am i am a testament to this i'm doing
this you know the guys that teach me
taught me
the guys and girls have taught me how to
set up a vm how to set up cali how to
basic commands i know i'm sometimes a
pain in that's about it but
it's important to do that and i know one
day there's going to be someone that
just found out about this community that
i can say hey
this is how kale linux works this is how
you know basic commands work and once
they have mastered that
you know i could pass them on to someone
more advanced than me
treat every job like it's a dream job
you do not want to regret
doing badly at an interview because you
didn't prepare right
and you found out that one of your
friends got that job and it's
literally your dream job okay always
treat it as if it could be
if you trust your recruiter talk money
okay but
don't only think about the short-term
gains think about your career
do not bypass your recruiter usually our
contracts are stipulated in such a way
that if you bypass the recruiter okay
we'll still get paid it creates a very
bad situation
between a recruiter client if recruiter
emails you with a job
hit them up if a lot of people have um
like a little a little sentence they'll
send to recruiter that's automated
um do that get back to them do not try
oscent the job and bypass them it
it it just creates a really bad
experience
do not hack the job is important here's
some sources and links
i don't know why i put the giffy one in
there but anyway
okay we finished that question if
there's any uh any questions i don't
know
how much time we have uh how much time
you have left maybe
rick can assist me with that all right
like we have
literally about two minutes so uh
is there anyone out of question when i
have a question
from empez when seeking for candidates
why does a recruiter put millions of
requirements
that will overroam the candidate and
push them away
it does happen a lot um i try to i try
to advise companies that
if they have a three-page job
description it is just going to scare
people off i always find
when i read a job description it can
usually summarize in about five or six
lines
um so don't be too disheartened remember
what i said
one job description doesn't equal one
job usually
okay sometimes that one job description
can equal five different jobs so
maybe you're strong at a third of that
job description but weak at the rest
tranzol they'll hire you for that
one-third because you're specialist in
that
and they'll hire two other people to
cover the rest not always the case
but it's it's important to remember that
all right angus well thank you so much
for your time
your insight your experience i think it
was truly valuable for everyone out
there
and uh say st stay safe
in south africa i will try my best just
fyi i had a slide with all my thanks and
links and somehow that
that's uh that disappeared and i'll be
uploading this to github shortly
all right post that sucker on twitter
all right so
we now have about a five minute break um
kim i'm gonna turn things over to you
because
you're gonna be introducing our next uh
speaker
uh mike jervis i believe will be joining
us in about five minutes or so
[Music]
you