foreign
[Music]
hi everyone I have four o'clock so I'll
go ahead and get started
um
so hi I'm Nikki Robinson thank you
everyone for coming today I'm going to
be talking about complexity and
specifically complexity when it comes to
security tooling so let's get started
oh maybe
there we go uh so first up all thoughts
feelings beliefs are my own they do not
reflect my employers
now that that's out of the way
so uh by day I'm a security architect at
IBM I worked on the ciso remediation
team so I do everything from incident
response vulnerability management
everything in between
um I'm also a professor of practice at
Capital technology University so I teach
research and design so I'm also an icit
fellow for this year 2022 to 2023
I also recently wrote a book called Mind
the tech gap which was really fun and
some of that uh it's the blend of I.T
cyber security and human factors which
uh shock I'll give you like a little
preview I'm going to be talking about
today
um I also co-host the Brazilian cyber
podcast uh with my good friend Chris
Hughes on LinkedIn live
I have a DSC in cyber security and PhD
in human factors and one of the reasons
why this topic I've really wanted to
talk about for a long time is because of
my research in human factors and in
Psychology so
that research really led me heavily into
lots of different areas in cyber
security very specifically how quickly
things get complex and and how difficult
it can be to manage environments so
so I wouldn't be a good researcher if I
didn't start with my problem statement
so I'll start there
but then I want to talk about how really
how we got here how did we get to this
place of complexity in our security
tooling environments and
not just security tooling but it's sort
of cyber security programs in general
there's a lot of complexity when it
comes to our programs whether you're on
a small cyber security team whether
you're an I.T professional that's also
the cyber security team or or working in
a large organization
uh then I'm going to talk a little bit
about what that means in regards to
human factors and then hopefully
providing some good feedback some good
things to take back either to your own
organizations or your own teams or your
own tools uh to try to see if you have
some complexity in your environment and
maybe see if you can reduce some of that
and improve efficiency of some of the
security tools that you might have in
your own environments and then I'm going
to introduce a cyber security tooling
and maturity model sort of especially
for smaller to medium-sized businesses
where it can be really difficult to try
to determine what do you even need in
your environment what do you need to
sort of go forward and make sure you're
getting the right picture so I'll
introduce that near the end
okay so why are cyber security
environments so complex and why tooling
specifically is so complex it's really
no secret a lot of environments are
moving to cloud or using hybrid Cloud
environments they might be using you
know AWS and Azure or AWS and gcp as
well as managing on-premise systems too
they may still have pii or IP that they
want to keep on premise or or specific
environments Legacy environments maybe
they're not ready to move to the cloud
so that problem statement alone of
having Cloud environments and
integrating that into your organization
starts to add complexity that that's
where that picture sort of starts
because
when you're managing one environment
it's pretty easy to sort of say okay
this is what I've got
I I think I know what I need let me go
from there but once you're managing
multiple environments simultaneously
especially if you're a small team if
you're a developer with complex
development environments it becomes
really difficult to start to get that
picture of what you actually have and
then what do you need and then it starts
to be okay well do we also need this
tool do we also need that am I actually
seeing all the vulnerabilities in my
environment am I not so those questions
start to come up and that's when new
tools come into play or you know hey
let's rip and replace let's rip out a
tool and put a new one in place that
that may or may not solve the problem
uh I.T and cyber Security Professionals
overwhelmed
um I think especially as a security
practitioner I can say this for from my
vantage point too there's a lot we have
to look at and not just a lot we have to
know right there's certifications in
education but when it comes to security
tooling the things that we need to do
our jobs whether you're in a sock or
you're doing incident response or
digital forensics chances are you're
using I would say maybe five tools
minimum
probably a lot more than that and it's
also possible that there are other tools
in the environment that maybe other team
members are leveraging for the same
thing
but they're seeing a different picture
than you so they might be leveraging
other tools seeing a different picture
but you have to come together and figure
out wait did you find this vulnerability
did you find this so security tool
sprawl becomes not just a problem for
managing the environment because you
have to do upkeep on those tools but it
also can potentially increase the attack
surface too all of these tools need
access to other things so not only do
you have this connectivity between
devices in Cloud environments but then
if you're providing administrative
access or opening ports or you know
providing additional access to these
security tools that are containing all
this information uh solarwinds anyone
it becomes this big pile of information
that if compromised could be pretty
detrimental to the environment too
and then I just wanted to hit on a
couple of buzzwords digital
transformation and zero trust you know
there's zero trust tools now there
there's there's tools for lots of
different reasons and it's not to say
that one tool will fix everything
because I think now we need lots of
tools to do our jobs we need lots of
tools to see the entire environment
I'm going to get into that in a second
uh complexity and depth so I wanted to
take that down a level just from
multi-cloud environments to
anyone that's managing Legacy systems
and new systems or had to potentially
even pull Legacy applications or Legacy
OS into Cloud environments and are
probably in transition to using newer or
supported OS and application levels so
now not only are you managing multiple
Cloud environments or potentially a
cloud environment in on-prem but you may
also be
supporting multiple OS levels multiple
application levels that adds to that
complexity it takes you down another
level of oh we're not just supporting or
looking at vulnerabilities for for all
seven anymore we're looking for rel7 and
rail 8. I need to make sure my patch my
patch management tools I need to make
sure my vulnerability management
scanning that I'm seeing vulnerabilities
for both but now instead of having eyes
on one maybe one OS level I have to have
it on two three four five different
levels
a complex development environments if
you have anyone that's running a
development environment you probably
have prod Dev and test you may have
other environments too you might have a
Sandbox you might have other areas that
are specific for you know different
types of applications and so those
amount of environments continue to grow
so when we're talking about security
tooling not only do we need a window
into those systems but we need to then
parse that information and see it at
lots of different application OS and
other levels too so it becomes
really complex really quickly
and then looking at user accounts versus
business accounts you know did someone
open maybe a cloud account on their own
uh for the business maybe they're
running some sort of environment in
there but then there's also business
accounts that they're using for other
things so now you've got lots of cloud
accounts that you're managing across
lots of different areas that you need to
have visibility into and you may or may
not
so this migration uh when we're talking
about digital transformation it's not
really just digital transformation it's
really we're changing the way that we
manage environments you know it's not
like we just need a vulnerability
scanner and maybe antivirus or EDR we
need a lot of different tools now we
need um which I'll get into in a second
but talking about sassed dast
um we're talking about pipelines now
cicd pipelines there's a lot of
additional components and things that we
need to be able to see logging logging
is still a problem because now we have
all this data but how do you parse it do
you need to get another tool to be able
to actually parse this information that
you have so
that's where the the problem started to
happen we saw a need for new types of
tools different types of tools
to help give us a better picture into
our environments because we need that
data we need to see what's going on and
if we can't get into these multiple
environments it makes more difficult
hence another tool or another tool you
know if you have AWS and Azure you may
need to have separate security tools or
separate security tool
solutions for each environment that
might play in their own cloud
environment but that means two sets of
cloud Security toolings Solutions that
you're managing at the same time
uh the needs of business are changing so
quickly I mean we've all seen how
quickly development is taking over a lot
of what we do
there are a lot more devops and
devsecops environments the way that we
managed Legacy I.T infrastructure is
very different from how we do it now and
some of that means that the original
security tooling that we had in place is
a good start but now we have to
integrate other tools probably open
source tools other things to help give
us that picture
and then I highlighted Shadow I.T and
Legacy systems because I think those are
the bane of all cyber security problems
but but especially when it comes to
security tooling it becomes really
difficult when you're trying to
focus on what tools do I need to see in
these new environments these new
application and Dev environments versus
how am I still looking at you know I
hope not but a server 2008 or 2013 or
how or 2012 how am I actually seeing am
I actually seeing vulnerabilities on
these systems and do I need to continue
looking at them while I'm also trying to
figure out how to manage infrastructure
as code so it's very two different two
different sets of problems that we're
trying to solve with lots of different
tools
so I wanted to
take it back up a level because security
tooling can mean lots of different
things
um it could be everything from you know
looking at a vulnerability scanner to
what do I need to look at for IAM how do
I look at my different policies for user
accounts because those are
vulnerabilities too if I don't have any
sort of lease privilege in place or how
do I actually get a picture into what's
going on with my accounts and account
management
so managing current infrastructure while
also trying to tune and manage tools for
current threats current iocs indicators
a compromise trying to look at specific
threats or specific iocs for your own
business or your own domain it can be
really difficult to manage that current
security tooling infrastructure while
also trying to constantly tune looking
at alerts tune alert student alerts so
it just becomes increasingly difficult
to manage
the other is the I wanted to bring up
because when a business is evaluating
security tools The Business Leaders may
be looking at security tools for a
different reason they might be looking
at it for what kind of reporting
capability does it give me what kind of
visibility can I see quickly yeah what
kind of Graphics can I see what kind of
reports can I get versus you know
security tools that we might use as
practitioners to help us get a better
picture of what's actually going on and
we need a different view than a business
leader would so how do we get the right
tools to help make sure that our
Business Leaders Executives and
directors are getting the right
information they need while also giving
us practitioners the right information
to be able to remediate vulnerabilities
to find them and hopefully hone that
information going forward
and then integrating threat intelligence
you know that that's a big
um it's a big step for a lot of small
organizations to integrate threat
intelligence but it's becoming more and
more important to integrate those types
of tools that type of Intel maybe even a
program into an organization so that
you're getting more context into your
own environment instead of saying okay
I've got you know 10 000 vulnerabilities
what do I do with them what's most
important how do I prioritize and that's
really the most important piece of this
is that how do I get the right
information so that I can prioritize
because there are so many
vulnerabilities released every day
whether there have scores or not whether
they have patches available or
configurations available to actually
remediate them but that adds another
additional layer of complexity that I'll
be getting to in a second too but it
adds to that picture of okay I need to
see all these vulnerabilities but now
that I have all this data how do I
prioritize it what am I going to do with
it
which takes me to a vulnerability
scoring so uh I did both my DSC and PhD
around vulnerability training and
vulnerability scoring mostly because I
think it's a really interesting topic
but also because
vulnerability management can be a really
complex topic and for a lot of I.T teams
or development teams you don't have a
ton of time to sit and worry about what
does a nine versus a 10 mean and what do
I fix first you know if I have 5 000
critical vulnerabilities what does that
mean to me you know I can't remediate
them all what do I do first
so that's one of the reasons why I think
this is a good one to sort of dive deep
on because this is just one area of
security tooling and really one area of
one type of security tool to sort of
highlight how complex this can get when
you start to dig into what does this
information actually mean when I'm
getting so much information from so many
different tool sets
so we have now for vulnerability scoring
which is great by the way we have a lot
of information uh it's great you know we
have CVSs is is a place to start it
gives us an initial score but it is it
doesn't provide a lot of context it
gives us a sort of a baseline but like I
said when you're in an environment you
have 10 000 critical vulnerabilities you
know where do you start
now we have the exploit prediction
scoring system or epss which again is
great it's another enhanced uh ability
gives us an enhanced way to look at is
okay a vulnerability is a critical or a
medium or low is it exploitable if it's
exploitable okay should I remediate that
first probably if it's externally facing
should I fix that first yeah probably
but that helps give you that picture
then to sort of Whittle down just from a
CVSs score
but now we also have the Kev another
great tool available to us known
exploited vulnerabilities now we have a
really great open source library of
known exploited vulnerabilities that's
awesome now I can take this information
add even more context into how I
prioritize vulnerability management and
Remediation
but depending on the tooling that you're
using
there are other great product tools that
provide scoring or maybe enhanced
context like the tenable VPR the
vulnerability priority rating
which again is like a heat map and it
helps show you where you probably want
to focus your remediation efforts
but now we've got heat Maps we've got
lots of different scores we've got open
source libraries that we need to look at
to see if this information is applicable
um and then we need to have the context
of our own environments where we're
probably managing multiple patch level
system multiple patch levels we probably
have risks that we've accepted for
certain things certain ports have to be
open okay
but now I've got externally facing
versus internal systems
now I've got pii or Phi if you're in the
healthcare industry
and items that can't be remediated so
all of those layers all of those
individual pieces start to stack up into
building this picture and it's literally
just to ask the question should I
remediate this first
that's it there's nothing to do with
threat intelligence or anything like
that and and so once you start adding
all these other security tooling EDR and
all these other components into that
picture it becomes a lot of information
really quickly
um and I know that once you're managing
10 15 different tools it sort of becomes
okay I've got vulnerabilities in 10
different dashboards
am I getting the right information is
this one is this tool showing me
something that this tool isn't
um so it can it can become really
confusing really quickly
so I wanted to give just sort of a
glimpse of security tooling landscape
this is by no means a complete picture
because it's changing all the time and
we need to see different information all
the time especially as I think
development environments continue to get
more complex and more mature we're using
lots of different types of of tools and
and ways of building code like
um without infrastructure or without as
much infrastructure having to manage
operating systems things like that that
will hopefully help at least some of the
infrastructure management component when
it comes to vulnerability management
but when we're looking at security tools
and starting to look at security tool
sprawl it starts to become this okay I
need EDR because I need active
monitoring but maybe I'm not convinced
that I'm getting a full picture from
this EDR tool I want to also add some
specific type of malware analysis or
detection or I want to look for
something else specifically you know I
used to use Malwarebytes in combination
with other things so it's not unusual to
have one or two different solutions just
for one of these areas logging
any complex environment or any
environment where you have multiple
administrators or multiple developers
hopefully you have logging coming to one
place but it's also possible that you
could have logging going to a couple
different places you might have a couple
different solutions for logging tools
hopefully not because that would be
really complex but it certainly happens
and then when we start to add in the
picture of asset management
configuration management risk management
how are you actually managing if you
have open risks or you know you have
items that you can't remediate are you
storing them somewhere are you saving
them in a database or are you keeping
them in a list somewhere and then when
you're adding in incident response
forensics if you have a small team if
you have a big team and they're doing
their own forensics work you probably
won't have to worry as much about the
you know the sort of forensic tool
landscape but if you have smaller teams
where you have to have all these tools
in one environment it can become really
difficult to manage them all at the same
time and not just the amount of
information that's coming in but
something as simple as oh did I update
that am I using the latest version of in
case or is my attenable Nessa scanner up
to date so it's not just the actual
seeing the data that you're getting and
configuring the information to get the
right picture but it's also the
management and infrastructure of those
tools
okay so I'm gonna hop out a technical
for a second and hop into human factors
and some of the psychological things
that I think are just as important about
talking about the technical complexities
of security tooling
when you're managing
10 15 20 different security tools
I start to think about mental workloads
not just managing the infrastructure
managing the data you're probably
reporting on that data and you're
probably making decisions about that
data so
that might be just one piece of your job
too so if you're like me if you're like
a security architect or if you're a
security engineer and you're managing
lots of different tools you're probably
not just doing that you might be doing
incident response you might be looking
at sock alerts or working with the sock
if something happens as like an
escalation point you might be working
with management providing reporting and
data so you have to be able to ingest
all this information and be able to pull
it out to the right people and giving
them the right context
that is a lot of information to take in
and to make actionable decisions on
um and I would say security people are
really great at doing that but it's also
I think one of the reasons why we see a
lot of burnout in socks and you know in
cyber security in general we have a ton
of information we have to take in all
the time make decisions and get it right
we can't get it wrong in cyber security
because if we get it wrong we might miss
something an incident could happen you
know something could go wrong so it's
really important that when we get that
information that we act on it properly
context switching this is one of those
things that I know we do we do this all
the time outside of cyber security right
you go from one app to another you go
from one tool to another you're looking
at maybe let's say you're looking at EDR
and you're looking at different types of
alerts and things like that and you're
like oh let me see that vulnerability
report was coming in that should be done
uh right now let me go look at that and
then you go look at the vulnerability
report and then you're looking at email
and then you're looking at slack and
um then you look at Facebook I mean you
know how do you have the time
um but context switching essentially
means that you could be missing things
right I could be missing a really
important Facebook post if I'm
constantly looking at EDR all the time
no no but
um but it can be a lot when you're
context switching to potentially miss
something
and if you're missing something that
could be uh could be like an alert in
EDR that could be malware or or maybe
um you know you're not quite sure but I
don't really have time because I also
have this report that's due at 3 pm and
I have to send that in
um it could be missing something that
could then turn into an incident so
um it's really important to for us when
we're context switching to to not miss
something and and uh it's more about I
think awareness of what context
switching can mean and how difficult it
can be when we're doing this all the
time
metacognition this is my favorite
psychology word uh I love this concept
too because
metacognition is how we think about
thinking it's really just meta
um but how do we think about thinking
how do we make decisions if I made a
decision how do I go back and look at
that decision and determine that I made
the right decision how do I determine
that I had the right information at the
right time if I've got 15 different
security tools
I probably have the right information
but did I have time or the right rule
sets or the right configuration in place
to be able to get the right information
to make that right decision and if I
make a wrong decision can I go back and
look at that and say hmm do I need to
tune this security tool to help me get
the right picture next time
um so metacognition again it's one of
those things I think it's important for
us as security practitioners to get time
to be able to go back and say do I have
the right picture
did I make the right decision there
based on the information I had at the
time or could I have made a better
decision if I had tuned this tool in a
different way so so thinking about it
that way
uh perception I'm going to talk about
this again you'll probably hear me say
this like four times but perception my
perception is that this tool doesn't
work we need to get rid of it it's it's
not working and so we're gonna rip and
replace
ripping and replace tooling means
especially for the people that are doing
it not only do you have to completely
decommission any systems that were
managing that or supporting that if you
had vulnerability scanners you've got to
pull all that out now you've got to
bring in an entirely new tool set up a
brand new infrastructure and configure
it all of that configuration time adds
again additional time additional
complexity you could be missing
something because you're also trying to
decom the old systems and bring new
systems online because in the time that
you're ripping and replacing you could
be missing data and you might have to do
both at the same time you might have to
manage both tools at the same time while
you're bringing the new one online again
that adds to complexity and time spent
on One Security tool problem versus
maybe the security tool landscape where
you've got 10 or 15. so perception my
perception is that this tool doesn't
work is that reality is that really true
or is it that we haven't had time to
properly configure this tool because
we've got 50 other tools that we're
managing and I haven't had time to to
configure this tool in the depth that it
could you know I think of things like
Splunk
um that tool can take a ton of time to
for configuring uh rules for configuring
alerting but it works really well and it
can work really well and there's lots of
tools like that that when you can spend
the time to really configure them
properly they can work really really
well
um but a lot of times we don't have the
time to sit down and configure a tool to
even 50 or 60 of what it could possibly
do uh so we're into we end up not with
the full picture we could have and then
you know maybe to management or
executive management it looks like well
but we're not getting the right
information or I'm not getting enough
information this tool isn't working and
maybe that's just perception maybe it's
reality but maybe it's just perception
it versus business versus cyber security
so this is the whole reason I wrote the
book because
um we all need a different picture we
all need to see something a little bit
different to provide context we all have
different goals you know I.T or
development they might have slas they
may have if they're working in agile
maybe they have two week Sprints that
they're really worried about in cyber
security we're worried about the next
ioc or the next exploitable
vulnerability and how that may impact
those teams and so sometimes those are
really competing goals and it can add to
the attention or misconception about how
the security tooling is working or what
we need to see everyone might need a
different picture but again sometimes
that comes down to tuning it could come
down to
how is this tool actually configured to
report the information to the right
person you know am I sending a 300 page
vulnerability report to a developer and
asking them to just fix it all you know
that's probably not a good solution
um so how can we tune and potentially
fix some of these things to make that
picture better for the actual audience
the people that are actually consuming
the information and again that just
takes additional configuration time
sometimes time we don't have
alert fatigue you know this is one of
those things that has been studied
really heavily especially with socks
um because and not the socks that you
wear
um but for socs
um still one of I love that acronym
anyway
um so socks that that is their job sock
analysts they're constantly consuming
information looking at alerts Network
traffic
um EDR alerts or or is this malware did
someone get fished was a file downloaded
to someone exfiltrate data did someone
they're constantly looking at all these
different streams of data
um when you see alerts all the time you
start to think that's is that really an
alert should I really be is that really
anomalous it's probably not that bad
um especially when you see you know 99
of the time the traffic that you're
seeing is probably okay you might miss
that one percent because it's like oh my
God I'm looking at alerts all the time
all the time uh there was a study
there was a study done on alert fatigue
and it was on essentially how long a
sock analyst could
look at a screen and get the actual
context from the alerts that were coming
through and I think the cap was at like
15 or 20 minutes of the amount of time
that you could actually sit and stare at
the screen and get the right information
out of it and that'll be dependent on
the person right like some some people
might be able to take that information
in for longer some people for Less
um but imagine staring at that screen
for eight hours a day every day for
years
um alert fatigue is a real thing you
know if you're constantly looking at
alerts you may miss something and it's
not you know it's not anyone's fault
it's just how we as humans operate
um which is why job rotation I think is
so important for socks you know not
having them constantly look into alerts
all day provide them uh something else
to do you know six month rotations or
something like that to help give them a
different picture before they can come
back to to looking at alerts
um and then decision paralysis so this
is one of those things I just started
looking into recently because uh one of
the things we do in cyber security in
general but especially when we're taking
in all these streams of information from
all these different security tools uh we
have to make a decision based on this
information
when we have so much information it can
be difficult to make that decision to
say is this anomalous Behavior or is
this expected because if you say this is
anomalous behavior and you go ahead and
start with an incident and you're wrong
you might be getting executive
management involved or you might be
getting a customer involved in an
incident that you know may or may not be
happening but then the opposite can be a
problem too if you make a decision too
quickly
without the right context you could also
make the wrong decision in the wrong way
so decision paralysis is this sort of oh
my gosh I've got so much information I'm
not sure what the right answer is
because now I'm taking in so much
information it's hard for me to to sort
of make that decision
um
I think the human factors piece or and
the psychological piece really of human
factors
um and human factors for anyone that
just hasn't studied it in depth I see a
lot of research around human factors as
security awareness training
um and and that's one piece of it how do
people learn but the other piece of it
is uh design how do we build tools that
are effective and and help people be
more efficient
um understanding engineering and
psychological practices together so it's
one of those reasons why I think we need
to sort of bring human factors into what
we do as security practitioners one
because I think it can help make our
jobs a little bit easier but I think
understanding big problems like security
tool sprawl and complexity even just
being aware of some of these things we
can build them into our programs and add
a job rotation into socks maybe to help
reduce alert fatigue or reduce missing
you know potentially major alerts
okay so to come back out of human
factors a little bit
um I I asked this question because
you know when you start to think about
how many tools you have in your own
environment uh
the real question is what do you what do
you need what do you actually need you
know do you have tools in place that you
know maybe you're getting information
from but maybe you don't log into that
tool that much maybe you don't really
need it that much or maybe you're sort
of getting the information from
somewhere else
um but you have to have some sort of
vulnerability scanning in place you have
to have something in place to be able to
understand uh what what vulnerabilities
do I have in my environment that might
be multiple tools it I think especially
in very
um in multi-cloud environments or in
again in on-premise and Cloud
environments you might be able to extend
a tool from on-prem to Cloud uh maybe
not you know it's going to be dependent
on the environment but to really help
with that prioritization piece because
without it it's just a ton of
vulnerability information uh that you're
staring at and trying to figure out how
to how do I fix what do I fix first
endpoint detection and response some way
to contain
a machine some way to contain a an
endpoint that you suspect might be an
issue or have an issue that that's
something that you really need you need
some sort of alerting or capability to
get a good picture of your environment
of sort of what's going on or if
something might be malicious
uh real-time monitoring so that you can
have some type of continuous monitoring
in place so whether that's with a
vulnerability scanning tool you might
have you might have it with EDR some
sort of continuous monitoring and
alerting happening uh you might have to
have another tool for that depending on
what your environment needs are
um and then I should have put asset and
software management at the top because
that really should come before your
vulnerability scanning tool but where
and how are you managing your assets and
your software libraries you know do you
know what you have and and where it is
because without those it it's really
difficult to get a good vulnerability
management picture but it's also really
difficult to determine not only what
vulnerabilities do I have but what do I
need to fix first
okay the other thing I wanted to bring
up
that again adds to this sort of big
complexity picture which is open source
versus paid tooling so chances are
you've probably got a mix of both in
your environments there's a lot of
really great open source tools out there
to help if you have one picture with
your sort of maybe your vulnerability
scanner or something like that you might
have another tool in place that might
help give you better context or better
information
um but multi-cloud environments you
might need to have external Tools in
both sets of environments not always
there are plenty of tools that can play
in multi-cloud environments but it's
certainly about maybe finding those
tools instead of managing maybe lots of
tools across multiple Cloud accounts or
across multiple different types of cloud
environments and on-prem
and then open source again it's another
great
potential area to get a better picture
of your environment but you're also
again potentially increasing that attack
surface depending on what type of
tooling you're using so if you're using
something that isn't being patched or
updated frequently it could be its own
vulnerable uh entity that you're sort of
bringing into the environment too so
it's another one of those you sort of
have to weigh am I getting better
information from this versus increasing
my attack surface but it's another
essentially component of how do I choose
the right tools what do I actually need
in my environment and what's worth it
what's worth it to have in the
environment
so I wanted to introduce this this is
um it's pretty basic but hopefully a
good starting place for anyone that's
got you know maybe massive Tools in your
environment or lots of complexity in
your environments
but to think about you know sort of
where you want to start
um and once you've sort of gotten to the
top I'll go through each of these but
once you've sort of gotten to the top to
come back down to the bottom and start
to evaluate again you know we do
continuous monitoring for
vulnerabilities for Network traffic and
and alerting why don't we do continuous
monitoring for our security tools you
know why don't we continuously monitor
them and see if they're working for us
if they're making sense for us or if
they're configured properly just like
anything else you know configurations
can get changed or may need to be
changed depending on how the environment
is you know I always use something as
simple as if you have
um you know Windows 10 and windows 11
you may need to change if you have a
vulnerability scanner in place you might
have to change your policies to make
sure that you're accounting for any of
the changes in Windows 11 versus Windows
10. Powershell monitoring you know that
may change depending on what version of
Powershell that you have in the
environment so
again it should be this continuation
this iterative approach to security
tooling where you're you're sort of
asking yourself is this still valuable
and if it's not valuable why is it
because I haven't had enough time to
spend on it or is it because it really
doesn't meet our business needs anymore
you know we're moving to multi-cloud
environments we need a tool that works
for both this just isn't going to work
anymore
um so it's really just sort of about you
know asking that question and making
sure that we do this over time so
starting with something like EDR right
that would sort of be the first place
you want to make sure that you've got
something on your systems when you bring
them online and making sure that they're
being actively monitoring actively
monitored some sort of vulnerability
scanning of course and then some sort of
network monitoring maybe that comes with
EDR maybe it doesn't maybe you need a
separate tool for that
um compliance reporting and Frameworks
I've seen a lot more especially for
environments that maybe go through
regular audits maybe they have
assessments or they're beholden to
specific regulations they might have to
have a separate compliance tool or
framework something in place that
they're actively monitoring there are
plenty of vulnerabilities scanning or
vulnerability tools that come with that
but again it's just additional
configuration that will have to go into
place
um and then Sasser dast if you have
complex development environments and
again that's not all inclusive there's
lots of other application testing and
like I said CI CD pipelines and things
like that that you have to consider and
then you know are you getting to a place
of talking about threat modeling and
probably using the tools that you have
in place to use for threat modeling or
potentially getting threat intelligence
Tools in your environment to again
expand the view of the information that
you have but to also give you context
for the information that you're getting
and then hopefully getting to a single
plane of of glass or something like xdr
which is extended detection and response
but hopefully giving you
some some single mechanism some or maybe
one or two areas that you look for
information versus 10 or 15 different
places that you have to look for
information so hopefully that's the end
State you're getting to a place where
you have this sort of Consolidated
tooling and monitoring
um knowing that that's not always
possible but hopefully that's a good end
state but then always going back through
that process and saying okay am I
actually seeing the right
vulnerabilities in the environment am I
not
um and and going back through the steps
okay
so my last bit here
um that I'm going to sort of talk about
recommendations and this is just these
are questions I ask myself all the time
too
um but uh when we're talking about
complexity and this is complexity both
from the technical side and from the you
know people in human perspective too
take a comprehensive inventory of your
tooling that's open source and paid
tooling you know what are you paying for
how much are you paying for it is it
working for you but also you know what
open source tools do you have an
environment in your environment
um and I mean you know really talking to
you know if you're management talking to
your security people and saying hey what
are you using like what are you actually
missing are you missing pieces that
you're trying to fill the Gap with open
source tooling are we not providing you
the right budget or tooling you know to
sort of go back and figure out what you
need
um you know versus trying to come up
with Creative Solutions or building
tools to help give us that picture
um
so what do you have versus what are you
missing this can be a this is actually a
really difficult question to answer
because you don't know what you don't
know
um but I think that's why like
conferences like this are great or
actually like talking to vendors and
seeing what products are out there
because
um sometimes just having a conversation
with someone can give you a better idea
of oh I didn't know that was a thing let
me go check that out and see if I can
use this and maybe it'll give you a
better picture into your own environment
vulnerabilities management is one of
those things that especially in like I
keep mentioning complex development
environments but that's because
vulnerability management is getting more
complex it's increasingly complex
because without the right Tools in place
it might look like an application is
secure
you might run a tool and it's like oh
yeah this is fine
um but it might not be you could run
another tool and get 150 findings and it
might be because you didn't have the um
the right tool for that specific
application or that specific library to
actually see those things so
um so determining okay do I have the
right tools for the actual application
infrastructure that I have
um and then the big question are you
really missing functionality or are they
not fully configured I really recommend
this this is one of those things I do
all the time where I go back and I look
at tools and say
one am I getting the best picture and
two and like if I'm missing information
can I do it with this tool is there
something I'm missing from the
Management console or from the actual
visibility it has to different systems
maybe because my asset inventory isn't
quite right I'm not getting a good
picture of what's actually going on the
to actually determine the risk in my
environment so I highly recommend taking
a look at your tools seeing how well
they're configured and spending some
time with them
um and I say skill sets uh because
something like Splunk I am not an expert
in Splunk by any means that is something
I would need to take time to really
really learn I understand basic rule
sets things like that but I think to
configure a really complex tool like
that I would need training I would need
to go and spend a week and really dive
deep into it to understand how it would
best serve me and my environment so
um taking that back to to the teams you
know do the teams have you know if
you're using like a vulnerability
scanner do they really know how to
configure it or did they sort of inherit
it and they're managing it you know
configuration and operations and
management are sort of two different
things so if you're handed a tool you're
not quite sure how to manage it it could
be worth it to go take that upscaling
and say I'm not quite sure I need to go
figure out how this tool really works
how it's actually configured because
that might give a again another clue as
to
um why it's configured that way
maybe I'm missing something and maybe
how to configure it properly
um and then for practitioners uh I think
having really good conversations with
management about saying you know this is
what we have right now this is what I'm
able to provide to you as you know an
architect and engineer this is what we
have I can't give you this information
or I can't prioritize vulnerabilities
because I don't have this this is
something I need to be able if you want
a better picture or
um you know you want to see
vulnerabilities in any sort of
prioritized way not just criticals and
highs to help open that picture up and
the same for management you know I
encourage management to actually go talk
to their practitioners and say
um okay this is the information you're
giving me is this everything is this
really what we need do I need more
information am I missing something here
um I I think those conversations help to
alleviate some of the perception that I
was talking about before
perception can be one of those things
that especially when it comes to secure
tooling or choosing the right tool or
not
I think it can be really challenging to
make sure that you know management
understands that there might be things
under the covers of the actual tool that
they don't get to see because they just
see a report or they just see a
dashboard they don't get to actually see
all the configuration and time that goes
in to make sure that that tool gives the
right information so
um so I encourage those sort of
iterative approaches to those
conversations because the information
you need is going to change over time
too it'll probably change day to day but
hopefully at least starting those
conversations can help to give at least
a picture of okay this is what we really
have this is what we don't have
and this is what we need versus this is
nice to have
um you know and hopefully that again
will help to bring that understanding
back to from management to practitioners
on you know I know I can't have
everything but if you really want
everything this is really what we need
to give that idea
um so I wanted to
um I really wanted to leave plenty of
time for for questions
um so that's really my presentation on
complexity and security tooling and
happy to answer any questions that
anyone might have
thank you I think Dusty oh
oh hi
[Music]
that's coming down
steps to say here's how
yes totally um thank you for that yes
that is totally one of the reasons why I
wrote the book because uh conversations
between developers and security or it
and security I can say this because I
was I.T operations for about 11 years
before I got into security so I've had
those conversations from both sides of
the fence and I know that they can be
challenging or that there can be tension
and friction between teams mostly
because you have competing goals you
know a developer is worried about their
two Sprint two week Sprint cycle or
they're worried about you know hey I
have to deliver this on this date and
you know maybe my bonus or my pay is
dependent on this or my job maybe I'm
worried about my job if I can't deliver
this this that's I'm worried about job
security
and so as security practitioners I think
that's one of our jobs when we're
working with developers or or it in any
capacity is to lead with empathy that's
always one of the things another piece
of that psychological component but to
listen to what's actually going on with
them and so when we provide a
vulnerability report to not provide them
that 300 Page report I like to start
with the top five that's that's usually
my recommendation is start with the top
five and say Here's the five things we
have to fix
in the next two sprints this is what we
have to do now because if you overload
them with vulnerabilities it's sort of
like what what am I going to do with
this you know I don't have time for this
this is going to slow me down it's going
to break my product
um all these things and so I think if
you can open that conversation with hey
here's the report but here's the top
five things we need to do and I'm going
to help you do that
um yeah so hopefully that answers your
question yeah thank you
yeah
and
like that's I'm sorry I couldn't hear
[Music]
foreign
no that sounds awesome that sounds like
something I need to go to a week for
training for
no but that sounds awesome I love that
if it's tool agnostic or if you're if
you're able to actually build that type
of analysis in
I love that because
um I guess it would depend on the
solution right if you're able to
have the right skill set right for
people to to be able to do that and know
that you're not missing information yeah
I think that's great and you gave me
something to research when I go home so
thank you
[Music]
starting point
awesome yeah thank you any other
questions yeah
yeah
yeah so I yeah thank you for the
question yes I do think that we're going
to get to a place like that I think that
that is one of the problems that I think
our industry is trying to solve there
are a lot of vendors out there that are
trying to solve this problem knowing
that you know hey to do my job I have to
have 15 or 20 Tools in my environment
and that that's not a feasible solution
because we are humans there's only so
much information we can take in and
actually digest and act on that's the
other piece right is I can digest a lot
of information yes
yeah they have a ton yeah if you go to
the website they have a ton of different
degrees and um like I said different
labs and
um so yeah I I mean I really enjoyed my
time there that's why I'm still there
um but yeah they have a lot of cool
degrees Yeah
yes
yeah so
I think the human factors conversation
from both the management perspective and
the practitioner perspective is really
important I guess I focused more on the
practitioner because I am a practitioner
but yeah I think it's it's both ways
right
um really effective management
especially when it comes to a situation
like this isn't to say you know
my security practitioners didn't
configure this properly this is their
fault you know it's really about the
question did I provide them the training
and the Skilling to understand this tool
or did they get hired and I told them
they need to figure it out today so yes
absolutely I think it's it's sort of
um has to be from both sides
um and the
this idea of perception this is
something I just started exploring in
the last year or two when it came to
research because I think perception and
I don't have any proof behind this yet
but my my hypothesis is that perception
affects a lot more in risk management
and in Burnout and things like that that
we're seeing in the industry then we are
aware of at the moment you know if that
perception is my security team is doing
a bad job
um that's going to be negative for
everyone right versus saying what's
actually happening on the team let me
ask around let me ask a few questions
you know did do they know how to manage
this tool no can I send them to a week
for training and fix the problem great I
don't have to fire someone and hire
someone that's bad for everybody
um so yeah so yeah absolutely both ways
yeah
any other questions
no
all right well thank you all so much I
really appreciate it
um thanks
[Applause]