foreign
[Music]
and this is my presentation uh settle
the score CVSs fundamentals will will be
going over just the basics of everything
just about CVSs because a lot of times
people know that the score exists but
how do you get that number well that's
that's a big question
uh
one of these days the clicker will work
oh
first I've been Pro programming for
eight plus years and I've been working
uh somewhere within the cyber community
learning about all of that for about six
years I'm also an avid enjoyer of Magic
the Gathering and a flautas in a video
game flute choir for that extra little
spice and then I my professional
experience I have been with Lockheed
Martin since 2019 through a bunch of
different teams so I was developing on
the M few team working a lot with RF
from 2019 to 2021 then I was transferred
over to their dice team doing a lot of
incident response and working in that
area from 2021 to 2022 and now I'm
currently working with offensive cyber
operations where I do a lot of
development for the actual cyber
community which is pretty cool and then
um and then I also have a bachelor's in
computer science who graduated as of
yesterday and you can see
a bunch of smiling faces
so very busy weekend for me as you can
tell
um and so now uh the start of it all uh
cve and CVSs you know a bunch of
alphabet soup and of course there will
be a lot more acronyms to go over as we
go on and we'll be rushing through those
um so what exactly is a cve well
actually it's uh cve's common
vulnerabilities and exposures and that
is the entire list of all of the uh
exposures and typically if someone
refers to acve they mean an entry inside
of you know the cve but you know
semantics everyone knows what you're
talking about when you say it
um and so what exactly it is is a
publicly documented security flaw found
in some sort of code base like
exploiting a buffer overflow that leads
to code execution you know all of that
little fun stuff that us hackers get to
do it is maintained by miter as you
might know from the miter attack
framework uh just a fun little company
there and it's was established in 1999.
all of these are stored in a lot of fun
places like National vulnerability
database which is maintained by someone
in the government and cves are given out
by cve numbering authorities and a bunch
of different companies are CNAs where
you can have one from let's go with
Lockheed Oracle all of those places that
maintain software and then you
they get assigned a nump a number of cve
IDs that they can assign throughout the
year so if you see a bunch of numbers
close together from a certain company
it's not because someone found a flaw
right next to each other uh in that same
company it's just because they have that
block of numbers to use and then here's
an example of a cve ID number the log j4
attack is the one I'll be using for just
kind of the example one going over the
intro and log j4 as you know was the one
where everyone's Minecraft got hacked
including yours your Minecraft
um and how it goes is it cve then the
year that it was found and then the
number assigned for the cve ID now what
qualifiers for a cve it needs to be
independently fixable so for example if
it is something that you need to fix it
by fixing about three different other
bugs and that's uh then it's not just a
cve you need to be able to just fix that
one patch and then you're fine
it needs to be acknowledged by the fence
the vendor or well documented and so
either like the person that developed
the software needs to say hey this is a
problem or someone needs to come out
with documentation saying that this goes
against the security policy and that it
impacts the actual usability and
security functionality of the code
and then it also needs to be affecting
one code basis if a cve
affects multiple different products then
if CBE affects multiple different
products then you would get a cve number
for each different product that it
affects and then if uh a code base would
have to if there is no way for the bug
to be fixed without
um fixing that one different code base
and that code base is using a bunch of
different products but the only reason
that it is combined like that then it
would have a specific CV one cve for
that multiple different products but
that's a rare case
and so what exactly is CVSs now that
I've kind of defined and gone over the
basics of cve well it stands for common
vulnerability scoring system and what
exactly it is is it's just kind of a
measure of severity of a different
exploit or exposure
um it was owned and managed by first uh
first stands for the Forum of incident
response and security teams and it's
been open since it's been maintained
since 2005 and then over on the left you
can see kind of like the difference in
ratings between CVSs version 2 and CVSs
version three
um CVSs version 3 has a lot more
difference than just how it's rated uh
we'll be going over that a little bit
um but as you can see it the higher the
number the more severe that it is and
then at the bottom of my bullet points
you can see a bunch of letters those
will make sense later on but I just
wanted to show an example of a written
out CVSs score
and uh
so that way then you can actually
qualify it or quantify it now how do
they relate I know that this talk is
about CVSs and you guys are all very
intrigued uh in CVSs
um but it relates to cves because most
cves are assigned to CVSs score and just
having a CVSs score without actually
knowing the thing that it's attached to
is pretty useless like oh hey something
got assigned a 10. cool what was that
something and so the cve kind of gives
you that context for what it is it also
shows the
it shows the severity of a specific
documented cve so people can accurately
identify the threat level of different
exploits
so a brief brief history of version
updates uh CVSs version one was created
in February of 2005. the first release
was found to be pretty buggy so they
updated to CVSs version 2 in 2007 and
then of course again nothing uh with its
first release patch is going to be
perfect so users needed too much
knowledge of vulnerabilities for CVSs
version 2 to be accurate you're never
going to know everything that's going on
inside of an exploit
um and then for CVSs version 3 it needed
a bit more clarification but not an
entirely new formula change so they came
out with tvss version 3.1 in June of
2019 and that's what's pretty widely
used today some places are still using
CVSs version 2 but typically the scores
aren't too far off but there were a lot
of differences in some being a bit
some being a bit scored too highly in
CVSs version 2.
um why is this important why is CVSs
something that is used in a lot of
places well first it's free and open so
free and open that I was able to make an
entire PowerPoint on this
um but also it's not proprietary
information I can use this inside of my
company someone else can use it inside
of their company and it's a way for
everyone to be able to accurately
communicate the different severity of
different flaws like it doesn't matter
if I am scoring something between 17 and
203 because we all know that someone out
there is going to use arbitrary numbers
to score something
you are able to have the same number
compared between different companies so
that way everyone can accurately have a
communication
like have communications between
companies to talk about these kinds of
threats so it's extremely important
important to have
good and open communication between
companies
um and then stripped directly from their
website CVSs was designed to provide
open and universally standards severity
ratings of software vulnerabilities and
it's just great to be able to have an
open conversation between companies
so what makes up a CVSs score this uh
little snippet is directly from their
CVSs score calculator from their website
you can click the little categories and
then when you do that it tells you what
score it's going to be and then here you
have all of the different metrics that
something with CVSs is defined by so you
know with the attack Vector it's either
going to be Network the adjacent Network
local and physical we'll go and be going
more into depth about the specific
categories later
but I just wanted to show a little bit
bigger picture so that string of letters
that I showed you guys earlier that I'd
say be going more into depth this is
where you get all of those values where
you would say attack Vector n and then
the next one you would say attack
complexity let's go with l
and then here is that uh that string at
the bottom with the
uh with the Minecraft Tech that is uh
just that way you can see where I was
getting those letters from and so now
I'll be going into depth what the
different metrics mean so first with the
exploitability metrics you have the
attack vector and this is the level of
access required to exploit the
vulnerability meaning whether you need
to be physically at the computer or just
across the network or locally there and
so it's kind of where you need to be in
the context of the exploit then we have
the attack complexity it factors out of
the attacker's control to exploit the
vulnerability a low attack complexity
means that all of the factors needed to
exploit it would be inside of the
attacker so everything they need to do
is within their hands and a high
complexity means that they kind of need
to wait for specific circumstances or
those kinds of things
um the Privileges required as you can
probably guess is just whether or not
you need admin privileges or what kinds
so none would be you know no privileges
required maybe a guest account low would
be any common user and then high would
probably be admin and then we have the
user interaction uh the necessity of a
willing or unwitting participant to
succeed so either someone clicking on
that link that you told them not to
click on in the phishing email or
someone downloading a file that they
really shouldn't have or it can be
someone physically at the computer
saying oh I hate this company they fired
me I'm gonna help this hacker exploit
some malware and you have that man
inside so none would be no user
interaction and then required would be
any one of those uh situations and now
we have impact metrics and I know for
all of you that have either studied for
or got your SEC plus the CIA Triad is
going to look very familiar to you
um but you have the confidentiality
impact and so it's the amount of data
that the attacker gains access to
um
uh and then you know none low or high
all of those three are the same for
these three categories and then you have
the Integrity impact it's the ability
for the attacker to change the physical
data and then you have the availability
impact which is the ability to change
the accessibility of the data so I guess
changing privileges uh probably
executable but anything of where you're
changing the availability and now we
have the scope metric either changed or
unchanged the scope is if this exploit
can propagate to other components like
leading to more exploits being used for
example if I'm able to get a certain
hack inside of a computer does that open
the door for me to be able to use a
bunch more or is it kind of a one and
done scenario
um so all of those metrics before were
just for the base score and that's what
is next to any sort of cve because it
doesn't change these are two other
scores that you can have uh or I won't
be going over these two too much in
depth but it's a temporal and
environmental and the temporal score
kind of adds to
the base score which are metrics that
change over time like if an exploit is a
lot more severe when you first learn
about it or if it over time it becomes
maybe more documented and wow it's it's
a lot more worse than we thought
um and so this is how uh how the score
would change over time and then the
second one is environmental which is uh
factors that change from person to
person like maybe your level of
antivirus software or your operating
system and that kind of thing so it's
the severity of the attack based on each
person and you can't exactly just slap
this score onto every every cve because
it changes so often so these two aren't
as widely used than the base score
and now here we go into a case study
where I go a little bit of Dipping my
toes into vulnerability exploitation
um and showing my thought process while
using my knowledge of CVSs and what the
scores mean to think yeah I could do
that I could totally do that
um so my first thought was let's look at
the top 10 exploits in 2022 what all
happened there was the obvious ones like
log4 shell spring four shell and like
the Chrome zero a day but everyone has
done a talk about that so I wanted to do
something that maybe wasn't as widely
known uh and on purple sex website was
cve 2017 1182 and I saw that the an
exploit from 2017 was still extremely
widely used in 2022 and that was pretty
interesting to me like how is that still
viable five years later so I was like
yeah sure I'll check this out I have
nothing better to do so what exactly is
it uh it's a bug in multiple versions of
the Microsoft Office Service Pack that
allows an attacker to run arbitrary code
in the context of the current user by
failing to properly handle objects in
memory what what does that mean to some
people who don't know what that means
well the Microsoft Office Service Pack
is handling data in a way that it
shouldn't be and that leads to you being
able to redirect of what code it should
be executing next and injecting your own
code inside of that so instead of
running the next line you're now running
whatever hack I put into it and in my
case it was running I think the command
line and over on the left you can see
the picture just the physical picture
because I know that that blob of letters
below probably doesn't synergize with
everyone so I saw that you needed to be
local and well I'm local I have my
computer I can execute that the attack
complexity was low and the Privileges
required were none and both of those
appealed to me because that is something
that if x would it could be pretty
dangerous because you don't need any
privileges or extraneous circumstances
to do it and it does need user
interaction but it's mostly just the
user needs to click on the thing that
you want them to unwitting or wittingly
um the scope is unchanged and that
didn't matter to me as much because I
was just kind of seeing if I could run
this on my computer and then the cool
part is that uh it impacted all of the
confidentiality integrity and
availability on a very high level which
appealed to me because if this is a
simple attack that I could do and it has
this amount of data change and access
then that that's pretty that's pretty
rad it had through all of these things
it had a base score of 7.8 which is
pretty high and the reason that it
wasn't you know Perfect 10 was because
of the scope being unchanged the attack
Vector needing to be local and the user
interaction needing to be required
um so trying to test the exploit after
about 30 seconds of searching on the
internet with the Google search
parameters being just the cve ID I found
a GitHub link and as everyone knows
github's pretty cool
um so
um guys
I love GitHub
um the contents of this repository was
not only a readme with extremely well
documentation uh there were comments
everywhere that I needed it to be um
there was an entire exploitation script
in Python where you just kind of needed
to run it with the commands with the
different command line arguments with
the extremely well documentation that it
gave me it was great
um it also had debugging instructions
with specific break points where if it
didn't work hey here's where you go to
look extremely well documented it was
great the hacker Community wants you to
hack others it's so
um so here are the steps taken uh very
riveting I downloaded the script I ran
the script with the instructions given
so just the very few command line
arguments it created an executable and
then I clicked on that executable very
riveting very obviously difficult I'm
kidding this was very easy
um does it work long story short uh yes
but I have Windows Defender and Windows
Defender really wants to help me except
for when uh I'm trying to create a
presentation about exploiting my
computer
yeah
um short story long ish
oh
I swear that there's more to my
presentation
uh short story long after realizing that
my python version was wrong remember
kids python 2 can save lives
um I uh quite literally all I needed to
run was the exploitation script hey
um
not hey
uh all I needed to run was the
exploitation script the way that it was
telling me to
um with this with saying cmd.exe that's
the executable that I wanted it to run
with the output file of the name and
then I run the output file and then of
course you know Windows Defender deletes
the script and then gives me the little
fun pop-up it's doing its best but that
does mean that I was trying to do
something that I shouldn't have been
which I count that as a personal Victory
um so connecting it back uh that was a
very simple exploit for me to do I
showed you the steps I showed you why I
thought that I'd be able to do that
um and it worked enough it worked enough
um but if my system wasn't patched for
it I would have been able to impact the
security on my device to a very
substantial amount as I've said before
it had a very high scores for
confidentiality availability and
integrity of data which was pretty
interesting to me
um so here are the takeaways um Windows
Defender it's pretty good uh I don't
think I have other antivirus software on
my system because I already knew Windows
Defender does not suck
um hackers make it very easy for people
to get their hands on potentially
dangerous software again 30 seconds of
Googling gave me the exploit script that
I needed to run that exploit and knowing
why something has a high CVSs score can
save a lot of Heartache it
had very easy steps for me to take
through and I thought that I could do it
because I read the information that was
easily given to me and I used it to the
best of my ability and
I was able to succeed and give this talk
to you all so uh thank you my name is
Beth mosang and you can follow me on the
Twitter account that I don't use and
just made so I would be able to put it
on this presentation
um
uh thank you any questions
[Applause]
yes
the top critiques
um is that it probably it's still just
as a score there isn't as much
documentation of more of the specifics
like yes it says user interaction
required but does it mean that someone
just needs to arbitrarily click it or
someone needs to knowingly Do It
um essentially it just doesn't have as
much details as it probably should have
um other critiques probably is that it
does change over time like through the
different version updates uh between CVS
version 2 and CVSs version three like
you have to be specific when talking
about it of what you're doing
um and there's still probably other bugs
with the current system that they're
still trying to fix just because it
isn't a perfect system
um
nothing's going to be perfect and I'd
say that uh the
best part is probably just
being able to have a baseline Community
communication with other people
am I good to take more questions or
cool
um uh Chris
um
I haven't taken uh as much time on some
of the smaller exploits but as I've kind
of mentioned before
uh
that
for the smaller for I'd say it's
probably the lower that you get in this
in score for example of the lower
numbers maybe anywhere from one to four
it gets
less important of what the actual score
is just because it's either a lot harder
for someone to implement or because
there's less data that's being changed
in that kind of aspect but even scores
with low scores still have an impact or
else they wouldn't have a score in
general just because they are an exploit
so I'd say while understanding
uh what the score is for some of the
smaller exploits it still is good to
treat most as a Potential Threat just
because of the idea that just that it
still is an exploit and it still has the
potential to do harm to your system so
even if it
doesn't seem something as impactful it
still has the potential to do greater
things
[Applause]
thank you