foreign
[Music]
so I I told Dr Green after his keynote
this morning this actually is gonna his
talk was not gonna be the only crypto
means cryptology talk so
Buckle in because we're doing we're
going way back to when when Taylor Swift
wasn't born for 75 years so I'm going a
little further back than than Dr Green
went
and and the reality is uh that this
story the story is really a love story
and
it's a love story that kind of begins
and ends with a pretty powerful concept
a concept that what really makes a
person powerful isn't anything in the
traditional senses of power but not in
you know strength or Force but that
knowledge uh knowledge itself is power
and that's actually a quote from uh
Francis Bacon who was an English
philosopher uh and Statesman who lived
in the 17th century uh the time of
Shakespeare the time of the colonization
of North America and when the
foundations of a lot of really modern
science uh was being laid
and yes Francis Bacon is the uh bacon in
the title of this presentation so I'm
sorry to disappoint any bacon lovers
that were expecting something a little
different but
uh hopefully it's okay and while Bacon's
quote is kind of the beginning of our
story it also ends with that same quote
on a tombstone of a man named William
Freeman and then again our story isn't
really about William but about his
better half in many ways Elizabeth Smith
Friedman
and Elizabeth is the one who decided to
place knowledge's power on the tombstone
that was her husband's Tombstone and
would be hers too the end of her life
later
and she also put in that quote a secret
code uh code that reminded her of how
they met how they ended up spending
their lives together lives that saw the
foundation of a different modern science
cryptology spoiler alert and the one
that you and I rely on every day right
that one that's Central to everything we
do and how we secure ourselves like Dr
Green talked about this morning
how do we secure ourselves our knowledge
really from those who would seek to gain
its power
so before I introduce myself I'd like to
introduce Elizabeth Smith it is
Elizabeth spelled with two e's and no a
uh she was the youngest of nine Smith
children and the theory goes that her
mother kind of wanted to give her
something when your last name Smith
you don't really have anything so she
got an illusion unusual spelling of
Elizabeth to help set her apart she was
born in a small town in Indiana uh
raised on a Farm by her Quaker Dairy
farming father and mother
and his her father could actually Trace
his lineage all the way back to an
English Quaker who sailed to America in
1682 on the same boat as William Penn of
state north of us Fame
and from a young age she knew she wanted
to do something different than the
ordinary she didn't want the
pre-prescribed life for herself she
wanted to break with tradition break the
mold kind of plot her own course
a letter early to defy her father's
wishes and attend college and even after
that the prescribed path for her at that
point would have been well teaching at
the high school level and you know
living at home that didn't work out of
her out for her so she left and headed
to Chicago hoping to find their job
there doing something interesting
something unusual and boy did she ever
and so I'm really excited to talk to you
today about that story my name is
Brendan and yeah it's also spelled in an
interesting way and this is actually the
first b-sides that I've ever attended so
back in December I was given the
opportunity to join a company called
project Discovery where the makers of
open source security tools like nuclei
and SubFinder and httpx and many others
and I was really excited to join this
community
I spent most of my career up until now
in developer tooling most recently I was
at a company called gitlab for five
years and that led me to see the power
that open source can bring to bear on
problems that real practitioners face
not just the ones that look good in a
demo or sell really well from one person
in a suit to another person in a suit so
I hope that you'll indulge me a little
bit here with Elizabeth's story I
promise if you stick around I'll apply
it back to our day-to-day lives and
working to secure ourselves and our
organizations
I just also think there's something
special to be learned from the history
of what Elizabeth did what part she
actually didn't get credit to credit for
until very recently and even how she
came to do in the first place
so how she came to do it in the first
place is Elizabeth was always interested
in history and language and she learned
that in Chicago at an obscure Library a
private Library called the Newberry
Library there was a rare and unique
piece of History called the first folium
so you see in Shakespeare's time the
spoken word was valued much higher than
the written word and so while he was
alive actually none of his plays were
recorded and printed in any meaningful
way
and it wasn't until seven years after
his death that a group of admirers
gathered 36 of his Works into a
published book and the act of publishing
that first folio was in and of itself a
radical act right to suggest that some
mere mortal man like Shakespeare
deserved the same treatment and
preservation that was at that time
really only preserved for the Bible
so not many copies of this first folio
existed and in the early 1900s uh the
Newberry Library had one of the few
copies available in America and
Elizabeth's curiosity and desire for
something new drove her to go see it and
that would start this chain of events
that led to the foundation of a science
when Elizabeth got to the library she
started talking to a librarian about you
know the folio and what Elizabeth wanted
to do next in her life and the librarian
remembered this eccentric millionaire
who was looking for someone just like
Elizabeth
and within the next hour George Fabian
showed up in the limousine absconded
with Elizabeth took her to a train
station led her all the way to his
estate in Geneva Illinois which was
called Riverbank
and at Riverbank Fabian uh here had
assembled uh scientists and inquisitive
Minds from all over the country and he
was footing the bill as they
experimented with a wide-ranging set of
activities from uh botany to genetics to
Acoustics and most critically to
Elizabeth one of fabian's most prized
projects was involved the first folio
and a theory about the true author of
Shakespeare's masterpieces
you see a riverbank there was this other
woman Mrs Elizabeth Wells Gallup with
the traditional Za Elizabeth rather than
Elizabeth R Elizabeth Ze she ran a
school called the riverbank Cipher
School
and a cipher of course is a secret or
disguised way of writing you know some
sort of code and Mrs Gallup had been
working for years on a secret code that
she believed was embedded in the first
folio a secret code that if proven
correct would have changed our
understanding of not only English
literature but of the history of the
United Kingdom itself as well
so here we're going to take a little
detour there's lots of detours on this
road today sorry to talk about the
cipher method that Mrs Gallup was
pressure was was pursuing and looking
for in the first folio so in his time
Francis Bacon had actually revealed that
he invented a new type of Cipher a
method to Signal what he called Omnia
per Omnia anything by anything
so the Insight led him to the discovery
that you know you could have this
ability to represent all the letters of
the alphabet using only two letters if
you combine them in permutations of five
letter blocks
and at the time his time uh I and J and
and unw were interchangeable so
um the bacon alphabet looked something
like this
and I was going to make two slides but
that was hard but yes this also then is
the part of the theory that led Claude
Shannon much later to come to refine our
modern view of information theory that
binary code zeros and ones could be used
to represent
all of the world's data and in fact
interestingly enough
1916 was the year that Shannon was born
that's also the year that Elizabeth
showed up at Riverbank so history kind
of has a lot of those fun little little
uh notes but that's another digression
so Mrs Gallup believed that uh and had
written actually an entire book that in
the first folio the printers had
intentionally used an A and B form of
letters through you know differences in
how they printed the letters to embed
this bacon Cipher into the document
itself
and she had produced many pages
translating this by literal ciphertext
into real text and what she found really
Disturbed her and actually made
headlines in the day
um
see she found uh that Francis Bacon
himself was actually the author of all
of The Works attributed to Shakespeare
and other authors and that he was
actually the illegitimate son of Queen
Elizabeth and thus the rightful heir to
the throne of England
and Mrs Gallup had been doing this work
for 20 years by this point and there
were a lot of people that believed this
Theory throughout history so Mark Twain
Nathaniel Hawthorne they believe that
this was possible but proof had always
been Elusive and Mrs Gallup thought she
had that proof a scientific method of
determining this a versus B form of the
letters and it was a and that she had
done it in a reproducible way but what
she needed was someone to reproduce it
which is where Elizabeth came in
so Mrs Gallup would set her to work
trying to reproduce those results with
kind of this vague and honestly hard to
understand description of what the
biformed alphabet was like there's this
slight difference in the stem of an H or
the tilt of the oval of a g is more or
less in this form
and so Elizabeth at the time in her
diary likened it to trying to sort
blueberries by color or beach pebbles by
smoothness
uh and she needed Mrs gallup's help to
even get the first 24 word translation
done but from there she was sent out to
go on her own and try to reproduce all
these results and for weeks she
continued in this work right she tried
her best to interpret Miss gallup's uh
notes and what she had created and while
this was tedious work she was enjoying
the cool Illinois summer and got to meet
all these nice cool people doing the
stuff at Ware Riverbank and met a man
named William Friedman who was an
aspiring geneticist who was Raising
fruit flies to try and understand the
role of genes in various traits and
again this is 40 years before the
discovery of the double helix of DNA so
you know relatively new and
groundbreaking science
so Elizabeth and William had this kind
of instant friendship one that they
cultivated on weekends and in between
their work they understood one another
they trusted another in one another's
intellect in a way that was different
than other folks that they were friends
with at Riverbank
and most of the folks at Riverbank were
content to kind of you know be paid to
do interesting work and not ask too many
questions
uh William was aware of this first folio
Cipher project as well because he was
the resident photographer and so he was
the one that had to make the
enlargements of the folio that Mrs
Gallup was making
uh and he was also fascinated with
ciphers he put hidden messages in
sketches that he made
um that would then look like any other
Botanical illustration but would have
like hidden words like bacon and
Shakespeare in them
and as summer turned to autumn and
winter Elizabeth knew that William and
her were growing a lot closer but she
was unsure of what to call it but this
growing closeness led her to build up
the courage to share something that she
had been thinking about for months
something that had been kind of eating
away to her and something that was very
sacrilegious to even think at Riverbank
much less share out loud
and that's the reality that there are no
hidden messages in Shakespeare
Elizabeth was revealed to find that
William shared the same doubt you know
they were they talked together but what
if everyone involved in the bacon idea
was was you know delusional except for
them what would that mean for their work
and their lives together
but before they had time to figure that
out
a much more pressing matter came to
change the course of their lives
so at 11 A.M on February 27 1917 the
Secretary of State at the time Robert
Lanson carried a copy of an intercepted
telegram that had made its way up the
chain to in Washington after arriving
from London to show it to president
would President Woodrow Wilson
uh Wilson's only response was good Lord
so this telegram had been sent from
Germany to Mexico a month before and was
encoded in numeric blocks kind of like
this you can see it here
and when it was translated it took about
a month for the British code breaking
team to translate it they found a
conspiracy against the United States of
America
whoops went too far
so sent by the German ambassadors or
sorry the German Empire's foreign
secretary Arthur Zimmerman to the German
ambassador in Mexico
the telegram would later be known
colloquially as the Zimmerman Telegram
and it proposed that if the United
States entered the War uh World War One
on the side of the Allies that Mexico
should join the Central Powers and be
Germany's Ally in return Germany would
help Mexico with financial support in
order to regain the territories that it
had lost to the United States so that
included Texas New Mexico and Arizona
previously the United States had been
neutral in the conflict but the proposal
of this alliance between Germany and
Mexico which introduced the possibility
of an attack directly on the United
States outraged the American public and
led to a big shift in public opinion
towards entering the war on the side of
the allies
and President Wilson used this telegram
the Zimmerman Telegram as justification
for asking Congress to declare war on
Germany in April 1917.
and the revelation of the Zimmerman
Telegram had a lasting impact on
international relations it demonstrated
the importance of cryptology and code
breaking and warfare
and George Fabian at the time in
Riverbank Labs had the only code
breaking school and team William and the
soon to be Mrs Friedman Elizabeth Smith
and this is the moment that Elizabeth
hadn't known but had been waiting for
the moment that defines the rest of her
life the fact that she was able to trust
herself at 23 years old to trust her
instincts about this code doesn't launch
a thousand ships but does eventually
save thousands of lives on ships it
leads to the birth not only of the
Freeman's eventual children but the
birth of a new science science that we
take for granted today
you know cryptology touches every aspect
of our lives and most humans interact
with it unknowingly but at the start of
the first World War
uh for the United States Elizabeth and
William were maybe were two of maybe a
handful literally a handful of people
who understood enough about cryptology
to even start looking at encrypted
messages
and Fabian is quick to volunteer river
river bank in Elizabeth and William to
the war effort in previous conflicts
code Breakers hadn't mattered that much
right because before the days of radio
transmission and Telegraph Etc if you
wanted to intercept a military message
you had to you know capture the
messenger on Horseback right or maybe
exploit the postal system in a you know
simple way
but this Great War was different than
previous ones because radio allowed
Wireless Communications over great
distances and then it also enabled
anyone with a radio and a receiver to
pick up those messages that you were
sending
so this meant that powers on both sides
of the war were also fighting to find
the best ciphers and methods to encrypt
what they were sending
and that's where Elizabeth and William
came in they were placed in charge of
the riverbank division of ciphers and
they would together not only become the
main source of decrypting enemy messages
for the United States but also create
some of the seminal works that serve as
the foundation for this type of work
which they actually coined the term
cryptanalyst to describe it in decoding
coded messages
the riverbank Publications most of which
they worked on together even though only
a few mentioned Elizabeth as a co-author
codified a lot of the knowledge that
they gained through their hard study
about the frequencies of letters and
letter groupings in languages the index
of coincidence and various methods to
get around ciphers of the time that were
you know all documented in these
Publications
and these methods are the very
foundations of cryptology right take for
example one of the simplest ciphers a
mono alphabetic substitution Cipher or
mask right so this is one where you
change one letter for another so in this
example for the English alphabet you
change a to X B to y c to Z Etc
it's one of the most basic ciphers you
can think of it's mono alphabetic
because the alphabet stays the same for
the entire message
and these type of software ciphers can
be found you know even dating back to
the time of Caesar there's even a
specific type of monoalphabetic Cipher a
name for Caesar
but even the simplest method of ciphers
there are 403 septillion possible
alphabets that you can create with this
type of Cipher that's on the order of 10
to the 24th power or roughly on par with
the number of stars in the known
universe roughly rough enough so a
number this large means that a thousand
computers testing a million alphabets a
second would take more than a billion
years to try and solve for every
possible alphabet yet this is also the
kind of Cipher that you'd find on like
the back of a Cracker Jack box or a
puzzle in the newspaper so so given the
right conditions even an inexperienced
person can solve this kind of Cipher so
how is that even possible
what's possible because we can start to
identify the patterns right this is the
incidence of code breaking and it's
something that humans have evolved to be
very very good at doing right taking
what appears to be chaotic input and
finding patterns in the chaos
this is the most important skill of a
code breaker at least definitely the
most important skill at the time of
Elizabeth and William it's not pure math
skills it's you know Elizabeth was a
poet William was a was a botanist by
training but their ability to pay
attention to look for and see patterns
in what appears to be a chaotic
patternless environment
and I'm going to return to that idea of
patterns but I'm going to keep talking
through Elizabeth and William's wartime
efforts for for a few minutes more
so their efforts in World War One were
actually very well documented especially
with the publication of that
foundational research we were talking
about
in fact for the first eight months of
the war Riverbank did 100 all of the
code breaking for every part of the
United States government the state
department the war department the Navy
the Department of Justice
and not only that they would go on to
then be the main training ground when
those various departments decided they
wanted to kind of expand their own
in-house code breaking capabilities
you know code breaking and code making
were invading every part of their lives
together
so even here this is a picture of them
at one of those training classes they
actually embedded a secret code in this
picture in the style of you guessed it
Francis Bacon and a b Cypher where the
folks with their heads turned at an
angle right it looks kind of weird got
some folks with their heads turned away
are the B form and then this isn't the
whole photograph the photographs wider
but the entire photograph spells out
knowledge is power famous break and
phrase
so then after the war as the government
continued to see you know what code
breaking meant in a modern world
Elizabeth and William would actually
leave Riverbank and find new careers in
this field
she would go work for the Coast Guard
which at the time was part of the
Department of the treasury and in 1927
when the government came knocking and
asked her help with a new challenge and
that challenge was that during
prohibition illegal alcohol smuggling
and distribution became a very lucrative
business for organized crime groups uh
so to invade law enforcement these
groups would use sophisticated codes and
ciphers in their Communications with
their boats as they were doing rum
running up from the South America
typically
and the Coast Guard was uniquely
positioned to help with this because
they had listening stations on the coast
and then Elizabeth's talents uh were
critical in deciphering analyzing uh the
messages that were there and exposing
actually a number of critic uh criminal
networks and disrupting operations
she also was involved in apprehending
major crime figures and provided crucial
evidence in numerous legal cases
her work led to successful prosecution
of lots of bootlegging operations
including one later run by John F
Kennedy's father
and she decrypted radio Transmissions
between the ships and their criminal
Associates to prove uh the guilt of many
of these folks
and throughout her tenure at the Coast
Guard Friedman played a critical role in
shaping that agency's intelligence
capabilities and establishing its
reputation for counterintelligence
laying the work for modern day code
breaking and her reputation was growing
as her reputation grew right newspapers
started to feature prominently right
because she was testifying these public
cases they taught referred to her as
America's first female cryptanalyst or
highlighted her critical role in
Breaking seemingly impenetrable codes
and they were also full of a lot of
focus on her as middle-aged which she
really resented and almost always
involved the word pretty like pretty
code breaking ladies somewhere in there
um so Elizabeth's Fame in the Press
during this period helped kind of Raise
This importance of cryptanalysts you
know in law enforcement and natural
security
and it also overshadowed what William
was doing at the time working for the
Army and William was always tormented by
this fact that his hands were kind of
tied when it came to sharing his work
and at the same time Elizabeth was
tormented by this press that she was
getting that wasn't always the most
flattering or focusing on the right
things and she was trying to raise a
young family
but soon their roles would actually flip
and Elizabeth would happily Fade Into
the background
but that change also meant that her
amazing accomplishments in the next
World War would be overshadowed for many
years by her husband's efforts in
founding a National Security Agency but
in some ways Elizabeth's work in World
War II is even more unbelievable than
Williams
so during World War II her expertise was
pivotal in identifying and apprehending
Nazi spies and the description of their
messages
and this work was instrumental not only
once the US entered the war but before
they entered the war
so in the Years leading up to the U.S
entering and entering the war
Elizabeth worked closely with British
intelligence sharing her knowledge and
assisting them uh because there was a
huge Nazi spy ring in South America at
the time
and so she contributed significantly to
the exposure and capture of lots of
enemy agents all throughout the Western
Hemisphere
and during this period it was called the
silent War period before the United
States was actually in as a combatant in
World War II Elizabeth's work proved
invaluable to fight against this kind of
enemy Espionage that was happening in
silent
however her accomplishments were Again
overshadowed by the Federal Bureau of
Investigation which took credit for most
if not all of her discoveries
so her work was focused on deciphering
encrypted messages of course sent by
Nazi spies from South America to Germany
and back and so they were operating both
in Argentina and other countries in
South America and then also some
operating within the U.S
she was responsible for breaking these
codes and uncovering vital intelligence
then led to the apprehension of these
enemy agents and the Coast Guard
Crypt analytic unit that she had founded
was actually who was both receiving and
decrypting these messages
the FBI though at the time was led by a
guy named J Edgar Hoover and he was very
eager to build his reputation and
strength as the nation's Premier law
enforcement agency
and so in doing so the FBI often would
take credit for the successes that
Freeman and her team were making the
decrypted messages were used by the FBI
to apprehend spies and dismantle the
networks but her role in these remained
undisclosed to the public
and for many years historians even
credited the FBI and their field work in
breaking up these spy rings and
decrypting these messages and helping to
win the silent war in South America this
was both because of Hoover's desire of
course to promote himself in the bureau
and because of the highly classified
nature of Elizabeth's work
but the FBI wasn't the one that
intercepted these messages they didn't
break the codes they didn't have a code
breaking Department the Coast Guard was
doing that and Elizabeth's team was
doing that
and once the documents behind those
accomplishments were they classified it
was really obvious who the vital source
of the information was because every one
of these documents even in the FBI Files
said CG decrypt at the bottom for Coast
Guard decrypt right that's something
they placed on the bottom of every
document when they sent it to another
agency the FBI or to the British or to
the dod and so these descript
decryptions uh you know they save lives
they stopped cues of fascist coups in
South America they
um drove wedges between Germany and its
would-be South American Allies
um but Freeman's most notable work
during World War II involved uh cracking
the Enigma machine
so this is an encryption device that was
used by the German military to encode
and decode messages it has complex
settings right which everyone thought
made it virtually impenetrable billions
of permutations and combinations
but alongside British count and parts
including Alan Turing and his team at
blatchery Park Freeman helped develop
and devise techniques to break the
Enigma code which ultimately played
obviously a critical role in the Allied
victory
uh and her efforts you know
allowed the US to and its allies to
intercept and understand enemy
Communications uh was invaluable in
making crucial decisions during the war
and like I said saving countless lives
so an example of that is that there are
over 8 000 soldiers being transported
upon uh in the on the Queen Mary
uh and Hitler himself had put a personal
bounty on the Queen Mary promising the
Iron Cross and a bounty of one million
reichmarks to any U-Boat captain that
was able to sink her
but then again following the war all of
that was classified so her contributions
to this were kept secret to protect her
identity and the sensitive nature of the
fact that we had broken the Enigma and
so it would only be many years after the
war that her accomplishments were
publicly recognized
right and this groundbreaking work
that Elizabeth did and William Freeman
did in the field of cryptanalyst uh was
foundational right it was the foundation
of the modern National Security Agency
um the pioneered efforts in code
breaking and its importance in peace
time and in war
and William is often regarded as the
father of modern American cryptology he
founded What's called the Army's signal
intelligence service which would uh
evolve into the NSA and was responsible
for intercepting and deciphering uh
foreign military Communications he
focused heavily on a number of
encryption machines from Japan during
the war
um
and so those combined efforts right of
the Freeman significantly influenced the
US government's understanding of the
Strategic value of cryptology
and as the war moved into the you know
after the war we moved into the Cold War
area that need for an agency to handle
this increasingly uh complex challenges
of cryptology and signals intelligence
became evident and President Harry
Truman established the NSA in 1952.
and the nsa's primary mission was of
course and is still in theory to protect
and defend the U.S national security
systems and produce foreign signals
intelligence
um and originally the NSA had named an
auditorium at Fort Meade uh after
William
however uh and this is this is actually
Elizabeth
um at that dedication with a bust of her
husband when they dedicated that
Auditorium but later on after
Elizabeth's death it became you know
public information that she contributed
so much to this effort as well and that
her work probably deserved equal
recognition
and so in response to that the NSA
actually took the decision to rename the
auditorium it now honors both William
and Elizabeth
and this change underscores the agencies
in our uh understanding and
acknowledgment of the significant
contributions made by both of the
Freemans in the field of Crypt analysts
and so that that renaming you know
serves as a testament I think to both
Elizabeth and Williams uh Collective
Legacy in cryptology and also highlights
I think the importance of recognizing
often over overlooked work of female
code Breakers and cryptanalysts uh whose
efforts were instrumental in shaping the
course of history and the development of
modern intelligence practices
and furthermore the Freeman's work went
beyond their professional careers they
both dedicated themselves to the
education and mentorship of future Crypt
analysts and their commitments to
nurturing that talent and sharing
knowledge created this kind of robust
and skilled Workforce in cryptology
that's of course continued to evolve in
the ever-changing landscape of Global
Security threats
so that's the story of Elizabeth but
what can we kind of take away from all
this how does this kind of Tangled
history of you know the works of
Shakespeare leading to an incorrect
theory about who authored them uh to the
founding of one of the greatest code
breaking security organs Focus
organizations we heard about this
morning from Dr Greene how does that all
tie into what we're doing today and and
help us think about how do we secure our
future together
so I think I think the lessons are these
I think they're crucial for
understanding uh both the current and
future cyber security landscape and will
help us better protect ourselves and
organizations against threats and they
go back to the principles that I think
Elizabeth used uh in helping to find
found this uh this science
so first let's look at the concept of
interdisciplinary thinking and problem
solving so
you know in today's world we've just
heard from cat and I'm hurt we've heard
in lots of talks today about how
evolving cyber threats are and then they
can be increasing complexity leading to
you know the idea that we have to think
a lot differently right gone are the
days where there's you know one root
user or you could rely on a single
technology or a single method to secure
an organization
the most effective cyber security
strategies today incorporate a diverse
set of tools techniques drawing on the
experience of multiple Fields right
incorporating other disciplines like
psychology and sociology and economics
and into a cyber security strategy can
provide valuable insights into you know
what are the motivations behind
attackers and how does this impact their
behavior this allows you to anticipate
and mitigate threats you know more
effectively
so by fostering this culture of
interdisciplinary collaboration within
an organization I think you can find you
know a holistic approach to problem
solving that helps tackle you know
today's threats
the second key I think and this is
something that Elizabeth did her whole
career is you know thinking like your
adversary think like an attacker you
know in order to really defend against
threats effectively you have to
understand that mindset and the tactics
that your adversaries are using right
there we if we go back to uh her code
breaking uh in World War II uh or in the
silent War World War II uh there was
actually a famous novel that all of the
Nazi spies were using
um in order to be the like seed for
their encryption and so she started to
learn like what parts of that novel
people liked more and and what parts
they would be more likely to start from
so adopting that attacker's perspective
when evaluating your own security
posture is definitely one of the most
effective things that you can do to
evaluate the effectiveness of that
posture you have to ask questions like
how would I try to exploit this system
what would be the most valuable Target
if I was attacking it and that can
uncover potential vulnerabilities that
might not have been immediate
immediately apparent if you're just you
know starting from that posture
and then again I think you know we heard
about it before but conducting regular
threat assessments and penetration tests
that help you simulate simulate what a
real world attack looks like
um identifies areas where your defense
is lacking and that creates a proactive
approach to security and not an
assumption
of security
and the third takeaway is to not over
assume right to know that nothing is
impenetrable right the the Titanic was
Unsinkable the Enigma was impenetrable
but no matter how robust your security
measures will be well we heard this
morning from Dr Green that you know
128-bit encryption or a thousand twenty
bit encryption was unbreakable and then
we found out it was broken
so no matter how robust your security
measures may be you know there's going
to always be an attention a potential
for an attacker to find a way in
and so it's crucial to constantly
evaluate where you're at and adopt that
mindset of continuous learning and
Improvement right we heard of training
and continuous learning from cat just
recently
and so by regularly challenging your own
security measures you're going to be
able to identify and address you know
where there are issues you know where
there have been internal or external
attempts to breach your security and
then things like bug Bounty programs
that can incentivize or security
researchers to do the same are going to
really help you take a look at your
system from the outside in
and so by embracing this idea that no
security uh plan is perfect you create
this culture of vigilance and resilience
and I think the most important thing
that we can take away
um from Elizabeth's life is to speak up
when something doesn't feel right right
speak up when you're seeing you know
compliance uh as security or you know
complacence with compliance right this
final takeaway is the need to address
this idea of being complacent with
compliance you know far too often
organizations are relying on their you
know compliance standards as the primary
security measure and of course you know
we're in an area where compliance with
regulations and standards is critical
for organizations but it shouldn't be
mistaken for a comprehensive security
strategy
you know that complacence with
compliance can lead to a false sense of
security leaving your organization
actually more vulnerable to cyber
threats that aren't addressed through
existing regulations and so it's
important to go beyond the minimum
requirements and proactively Implement
security measures and it's most
important that when you notice that the
focus is more on ticking the boxes of
compliance rather than addressing real
security concerns that you're not afraid
to speak up right you're not afraid to
say what might be sacrilegious you're
not afraid to educate your colleagues on
the importance of robust security
measures and the potential consequences
of not adopting them instead bearing
your hands in the heads in the sand of
compliance
and that will help ensure your
organization you know remains resilient
against evolving security threats
right that's the idea that started
Elizabeth's career this this pattern
recognition we can think about how
important that human element still is to
this day it's it's interesting to me how
Full Circle we've come actually
um you know originally Elizabeth was
using pencil and paper to solve these
complex puzzles and codes using her own
unique ability to identify patterns
and then of course you know today the
opposite is somewhat true right
cryptology is based in some of the most
advanced math that we've just yet
developed as a species
yet what are we coming back to right
we're circling back to this idea of
artificial intelligence which in its
current form you know machine learning
large language models boils down to
trying to reproduce that thing that
humans are better at and best at right
pattern recognition and so I think
that'll change the way we work but I
don't think humans and our ability to
speak up and see problems with patterns
is going to go away anytime soon
so in these four ways by you know
fostering interdisciplinary thinking and
problem solving speaking up when it's
complacents with compliance uh thinking
like an attacker remembering that
nothing's impenetrable you'll be able to
significantly improve your
organization's cyber security posture
and when you do you take a minute to
thank Elizabeth Smith Freeman her
remarkable accomplishments in the field
of cryptanalysts Crypt analysis have
left an indelible mark on you know the
history of cryptology and code breaking
in general uh but her work was also
invaluable in trailblazing you know in
in starting a science and and was
matched maybe only by her husband
although he would say otherwise
and her experience or her expertise and
dedication paved the way for future
generations of cryptanalysts but also
demonstrated the importance of
cryptology in protecting the most
powerful thing knowledge
and that is unsurprisingly what she had
inscribed on William's Tombstone when he
passed away in 1969. again we see the
phrase at the bottom here that came to
find both of their lives knowledge is
power
but this is Elizabeth Smith Freeman
we're talking about the woman who would
write her kids letters at camp in
ciphertext who threw a dinner party once
where the menu was encoded and one of
the dishes was called a dish mixed
together in an Inseparable way it was a
hash and you know play on the word yeah
uh so she couldn't let a simple thing
like a tombstone not have a secret code
embedded right
so the letters that spell out knowledge
is power she actually
um specified which would have serifs and
not to make a bi-formed alphabet right
making it a famous a b bakonian Cipher
uh and at Betty Williams initials uh
again in the tombstone at the bottom
so while cryptologists like all mere
mortals will die one day their impact on
society and indeed their hidden messages
can go on much longer
so as we wrap up I encourage each of you
to reflect on these key takeaways you
know think about cyber security as an
ongoing journey and see how you can
adopt those principles right they're
they're critical for understanding both
current and future State uh and how you
can protect your organization
so thank you so much for your time today
and for those who came expecting bacon
that's all I got for you
um but hopefully even if you didn't get
the bacon you were looking for you were
able to start thinking about what it
means to be a modern security engineer
and in the end that should be able to
bring home some bacon for you okay sorry
no I had to do that one
thank you
thanks and if you want to uh find out
more about this presentation or even
better read the book that inspired this
talk call the women that smashed codes
you can find a link to that at nux.gg
bacon uh and then you can also join the
project Discovery Discord if you want to
chat more I'm on there all the time and
find me on the internet at O'Leary crew
most places thanks again
[Applause]