foreign
[Music]
all right so I got kept up till four
o'clock in the morning last night I feel
like I have more energy than all of you
so can we try again what's up besides
charm
that's much better
how are you all doing today my name is
Sean uh it is bring your boss to work
day so I brought my friend Taylor here
hey how you all doing Taylor would you
like to introduce yourself sure I'll go
ahead and introduce myself so uh I have
the wonderful wonderful amazing job of
being Sean's boss it's exactly he's
lying I don't even know how I have
energy this morning to be honest taking
care of him but uh no and in all honesty
Sean is amazing to work with uh we work
together uh at uh at Yahoo we're with
the paranoids uh before that I did about
10 years with the FBI doing some
counterintelligence type work it was
super secret and super fun
um but uh yeah I had a good time but
here uh to talk to you all today and uh
go over the Action Group method Sean
yeah he also left out so he is the
director of threat detection and
response at Yahoo uh I am the director
of forensics and incident response
engineering lovingly called fire
internally
um before that IR consultant sock work a
whole bunch of stuff so we have spent
the last couple years working on what we
call the Action Group model the incident
response we think it's kind of a cool
thing so we figured hey we're going to
come talk to a bunch of people about it
because it'll be fun yeah it seems to
work okay for us so hopefully you know
this might be interesting for you all
maybe maybe not we'll see take what you
can home with you yep all right you
wanna you wanna Dive Right In yeah let's
do it John
cool all right so we're going to start
you off so this is our general workflow
for the action group model so
essentially this is not terribly
different from most other models of
instant response you have sort of an
intake section hey how are we actually
bringing things into uh our our area
um are we finding detections do we have
things that are being sent in by our
partners we have to do something with
that after we have it though this goes
into our triage section where we're
really asking the basic facts of what's
going on now our folks that are in our
fire area essentially doing these first
two areas they're receiving things in
they're then asking the basic facts and
trying to determine do we have a problem
here fundamentally that's really what
we're wondering and really what we're
looking for is is there some sort of
malicious activity
um that could be going on and do we have
something that's a big problem that's
what we mean by imminent material
compromise that we have up there on the
board right now but if we do have those
two things we go into activating our
Action Group if we don't have those
things this is our normal BAU stuff hey
you looking hey we've got maybe a fish
email or something like that we need to
deal with doesn't look like there's
anything going on whatever we can handle
that normally but when we do have
something that looks like it could be a
big problem we move into the action
group and this is really the gist of
what we want to talk to you all today
this is where we bring in a number of
different folks a number of different
partners from all across cyber security
Human Resources legal ethics and
compliance physical security to work on
these big major incidents when we do run
into them and this is really important
we'll get into the details of these in a
few slides but as we go through this we
kind of continue on through the general
method we do our response this is where
we're asking what are the key questions
that we need to deal with here uh and
then we then go through set forward
those work streams that we have
afterwards we go into our closeout this
is our normal Lessons Learned
post-incident response activities and
things like that but as we go forward
and as as Sean starts to walk you
through all these I want you to be
really careful and be thinking about
sort of this Action Group model bringing
a number of folks together having these
pre-established connections to be able
to come in and provide oversight and
assign things to a dedicated Incident
Commander that can be really any of the
individuals that you're working with so
anybody that's working in a sock in our
area anybody that's working on our fire
team can step up and be an Incident
Commander with that guidance of that
action group that we have across the
organization
you get over you Sean yeah go ahead jump
to the next one so we'll go through each
one a little bit and something to bear
in mind your mileage will vary we
actually tried to extrapolate our plan
out into a much more simplistic concept
that can be applicable to your
organization so some of our language is
removed and we kind of open this up a
little bit so like intake intake is just
how you find stuff how does stuff come
in do people tell you about bad stuff do
you have detections do you have threat
hunts do you have a threat intelligence
team it's ultimately about all of the
different processes and feeds that feed
into you finding bad stuff or I should
say at this point investigatable things
it's really important to know your
intakes because those are going to tell
you what work you have to do those are
going to tell you what gaps you might
have as you look at your intake so on
and so forth we're not going to spend a
whole lot of time here we'll go right to
the next one
so triage we simplified this one a
little bit too basically this is your
general sock which I kind of hate the
term sock these days IR whatever case
you want to make your investigative
teams are going to do this and they're
going to start here
so first thing they have to do is kind
of ask themselves a very simple question
right is this bad
that's really the first question if it's
not well you're done hey move on to the
next thing or you know tune it out
there's a whole bunch of other things
you can do if it's not bad but for the
sake of the IR process if it's not
you're good if it is then the next
question you have to ask yourself and
this is really important is does this
meet the definition of an incident at my
company
your mileage may vary on what an
incident is some places every
vulnerability that's critical is an
incident some places it's not so your
mileage could completely vary but you
have to ask what is the definition of an
incident and this yeah it was just going
to add in there Sean too this is
something you need to be asking yourself
before you actually get into something
that might be an instant uh we talk
about this a lot all the time is this is
something that you don't want to be
discussing right when you see something
bad yes so it's going to be really
important to jump in there talk with
your folks talk with your leadership
talk with your partners that you have
and make sure that you understand
exactly what that means for your
organization there are lots of
definitions of incident out there but as
Sean was saying this will highly depend
on what your business is doing what is
valuable what your crown jewels are what
your critical assets are it's really
important to make sure you define that
early so quick note on IR burnout a lot
of ir teams burn out because they don't
have a clearly defined definition of an
incident so everything gets lumped on
their shoulders and becomes an incident
that's not where you want to be you need
to Define that very early so you can say
hey this is when we have an incident
process because incident processes are
time consuming and involve lawyers which
is exhausting looking at you
our lawyer is here so I got to make some
jokes
um so if it's not then what we do is we
move it into a process where an analyst
can handle it so to use Taylor's early
example of a phishing email if it's one
email low impact nothing bad happened
right an analyst can handle that without
a whole bunch of people we don't need to
spin up and call in the the strike force
or whatever words people use these days
all we need to do is just go mitigate
that one little issue it's what we call
an event rather than an incident now if
it's an incident that's where we come
into the Action Group concept and that's
really important so as you'll see as we
work through the workflow you initiate
the action group meeting you set up a
comms Channel and you assign an incident
commander and we're going to take some
time and dig through those components
so go ahead Mr Johnson cool so let's
talk a little bit about the action group
so we talk about this action we've set
it up Bunch but like what what actually
is this and and really what we're what
we're looking at here and what we're
talking about when we mean Action Group
is getting stakeholders in the right
place to be able to make operational
decisions uh and to be able to provide
the right guidance to the folks that are
actually working the incident
um so this is really really important to
establish this up front and determine
who actually needs to be in the room and
this shouldn't be folks that are up in
the c-suite these should not be
Executives who are going to say okay
cyber security stuff bad guy doing
something all right uh call the police
like not not that right we need folks
who are actually at the decision-making
level they can make tangible decisions
on what's going on but also are close
enough to the operational level to
understand the ins and outs and the
different work streams that you're going
to have when you're working one of these
incidents and so typically this action
group is going to be making decisions on
where you're going but really
establishing work streams
um making sure that these work streams
are are answering the core investigative
goals that you actually have and so you
know when we talk about who's actually a
member of this action group like clearly
you need the folks that are doing
incident response so
um for ourselves you know Sean myself on
this
um but also you want to have other
elements of cyber security that are
important to have in there as well such
as your intelligence teams that you have
uh potentially even a red team point of
contact maybe some of your policy folks
this can vary slightly depending on what
you need to deal with in your
organization but having the right folks
in that room that you can really get
answers to most any questions or at
least know the right direction to go to
it's really important so one thing
that's actually really important about
how you structure an action group if
you're going to do it it's split up into
what we call responsible parties and
support parties and that that is kind of
the key because a lot of people when
they think about an incident they think
about just the responsible parties right
the IR team is a responsible party up to
your CSO is arguably a responsible party
but they don't think about support
parties your detection engineering team
great support party your threat
intelligent function great support legal
sometimes great
[Laughter]
so it you really want to look at like
who can help with this in some way shape
or form because as anybody who's worked
an incident knows they're all complex
they're all different especially like
big ones so bringing together a
multitude of experience thought
processes and skill sets is going to get
you through that better and I'll dive
into that on like the importance of like
variable work streams later but good
yeah absolutely and I think if you think
about this we take a practical example
say you've got a corporate account
that's been taken over by an adversary
or something like that as you dive into
that yes you're going to need to deal
with sort of the Tactical of okay how do
we evict this actor how do we actually
figure out where this actor is but
oftentimes you're also going to be
wondering okay what data has been
compromised could things be out the door
do we have any regulatory obligations
and having those right folks in the room
that really understand how the process
works to be able to give you that
counsel really in the moment is
incredibly important because one of the
things you really don't want to be doing
is when you're dealing with an incident
who do we talk to who do we actually go
to to get an answer to this question are
we under some regulatory obligation how
do we actually get this data all of
these questions may come up during an
incident and I think it's really
important to be able to have these
relationships pre-established and make
sure that they're all in that room now
one of the things that you all may be
asking and are probably wondering here
is hey we've got a bunch of cooks in the
kitchen now so we may have those
responsible parties or maybe these
support parties that we have in our
Action Group too
but how do we actually make decisions
how do we make sure that operational
control is maintained and and for that
I'll kick you over to Sean in The
Incident Commander concept cool
so this this probably isn't a super New
Concept everybody but this is something
that's super important to talk about
across your organization to make sure
that it exists right
the first thing that the action group
does before we do anything else is we
establish this role of The Incident
Commander one of the great things about
the Action Group model for us is it
makes The Incident Commander a very
accessible role so it's not just who's
the most experienced guy or who is this
because they have a team of people that
are there to support so we can make it a
junior and we often will on different
cases and can it makes it a very
accessible model because they have
support it's kind of like being thrown
in the ocean but having somebody next to
you with a life vest
that's really kind of my whole model of
leadership so
it seems to work all right I don't know
what is the front row say over here yes
good no okay we got one no it's okay I
can do that
um so the other thing that you really
gain from The Incident Commander model
though is you have somebody who has
operational control that's really
important and that has to be agreed upon
at a business level so when that person
regardless of their rank or title hits
up a VP somewhere and says I need you to
do this they understand that they need
to do that
that is like the most critical thing
during an incident it's also the person
who frankly keeps track of things and
helps us sign out the work streams that
we'll talk about in a minute and all
those other things because somebody's
got to keep track keep everybody on task
and make sure that we have the power to
handle the thing that we need to handle
in that moment
yeah and I I you know it sounds scary in
the moment particularly for junior
employees who are going to be an
Incident Commander oh my gosh we've got
an adversary that's doing something we
got to deal with them and I'm the
commander looking at you mark over there
uh but uh but I think fundamentally
that's why the action group is really
important because you do have the
leaders in the room who are tasking out
those work streams and understanding
what we need to do and really empowering
that Incident Commander to get done what
we have to get done for the incident
itself
um also really important to bring in say
legal counsel with that Action Group to
say like hey this is what we can do this
is what we can't do those sorts of
things as well just wanted to shout out
bunny Smith Who's down there supporting
us and gave us these these lovely shirts
today give us these lovely shirts
all right so this all kind of bleeds
into the what happens when we actually
do response though right so the way we
do response and the way that we think
about response is this very secular
thing it's also meant to be particularly
adaptable this isn't some Playbook that
says always go do this always go do that
always go do this other thing I
mentioned earlier incidents are
different different things happen
different things are affected there's
different ways that you need to approach
it so we put a whole bunch of smart
people in a room as the tldr and we know
Ann Taylor and John yeah plus Taylor and
John true and then we go what do we need
to do
okay like we need to know this we need
to know this we need to know this we
need to know this we should investigate
here mitigate here do this this and this
we build that out and then we assign
people to it and we assign across the
entire scope of the action group so
we'll go to if our threat intelligence
of threat intelligence members on the
Action Group who from your team is
assigned to this thing who are you
giving us we need somebody you have a
work stream you're going to do that
we'll build out this list and then we
assign it and we get very secular so the
investigation portion happens
it's a little bit kind of out in the
wind but the investigation is going to
be different could be different logs
could be different servers could be we
need forensics versus we just need
Network Telemetry it doesn't matter
we do that and then we come back
together as an action group and say hey
what have we learned what do we know now
well with what we know now
we can move back and establish some more
work streams because new information
means new actions that we can take
yeah absolutely and I think you know as
we think about hey different types of
attacks that you may see okay you've got
ransomware you've got you know an
account takeover or something like that
um
you may have Sops for those things and
that's fantastic but you're always going
to be finding new information during
your investigations that you're going to
need to be able to Pivot through so okay
you might have something that means
you've got a completely different type
of attack and you won't necessarily have
an sop to be able to account for every
single type of attack that you're going
to see so that's why it's important to
sort of remain flexible keep bringing
that new information back into the
working group we have the action group
and then making those decisions that
come out of the new information that you
have also for anybody here who who all
here Works in IR
is someone blowing up a helicopter with
an arrow not the perfect explanation of
what we do
High tip to Taylor here for finding the
gift last night but it is the perfect
explanation of this job
um all right let's let's keep going so
this is the whole model all laid out we
can leave it here for a second if
anybody wants to take a snapshot or do
any of that kind of stuff like you are
more than welcome to
you might be thinking that we haven't
yet covered post-incident activities and
we're going to do that with a completely
different model in a minute and we
actually have time to do that give
everybody a minute to take a picture
first and then we'll uh we'll jump into
the second model that we have that is
going to be a very brief overview
because we have a little bit of time
that that might be what we come talk to
everybody about next time yeah sounds
good go ahead
cool let's go into it okay so this whole
everything we've talked about today is
really part of what we call the threat
detection and response cycle so this
cycle is really intended to explain
everything that we need to do on our
side to be able to to detect and respond
to different threats that are out there
so this is something that Sean and I
have been have been working through and
really trying to understand okay so if
we take something if we take a critical
asset in the organization something like
that we need to be able to do all of
these different things we need to go
through each stage essentially and be
able to cover all of these things and do
it well so for example the first stage
that we have investigative tool
management this basically means we need
some sort of tools to be able to use in
our investigation this could be a Sim
this could be Splunk whatever something
like that this could be a number of
different things that we absolutely need
to have to be able to run our
investigation we then need to develop
use cases and this is a little bit
different from detections but what we're
essentially looking at here is hey can
we establish high-level use cases of
what we actually care about for
something that's going on for example do
we actually care about data being lost
something being sabotaged do we care
about something going to a competitor
these types of things we need to
understand and how that could actually
happen is something that we need to
establish and talk about
uh sort of that next stage data
architecture hey we need to have the
logs and we need to have the data to be
able to discover whatever use case that
is so if we care about data going out
the door how do we actually see that do
we need some coverage on our endpoints
do we need application logs what is it
that we actually need to be able to see
that next stage pretty self-explanatory
I think everybody gets this building
detections to actually describe those
use cases and making sure we have those
sort of next stage goes into alerting we
kind of separate these a little bit out
so yes we need to build those detections
but we also need to present that in a
way that really makes sense for our
analysts does it actually Elevate to
somebody's eyes that you're looking at a
painted glass now that being said this
industry changes all the time attacks
change all the time you cannot account
for a detection for every single bad
thing that happens hence we also include
threat hunting in here as a component
this is a relatively important part of a
program to be able to respond more
quickly than the detection Engineering
Process might take to look for stuff now
all of this feeds into all of it right
threat hunting feeds into detection as
we get in as we can continue moving
forward we talk about the incident
response and event investigation that
all feeds into detection that feeds into
data architecture that feeds into
everything but that's basically what we
were just walked through that so this
The Upfront of this whole talk was
basically the workflow for stage four
now what's really important and this is
where we get to the post-incident
activity component
mitigation Automation and control
recommendations is one of the most
important things that gets overlooked by
IR people and like investigative people
a lot we see things that happen we see
risks that other people might not see we
then need to take those risks
communicate them in a meaningful way to
the business to bring proactive change
or close those gaps we don't do that we
continue to see the same risks over and
over and over again you want to add on
to that yeah absolutely and this is
something that you know Sean was saying
hey we can't just live in a silo an
incident response we really have to be
able to work with the rest of our
partners that are out there be they in
different cyber security areas um be it
in Human Resources uh maybe we have
issues with something that isn't even
technically related like background
investigations or something like that if
we're dealing with Insider threat type
things so anyway just wanted to call
that out that this is another place
where you can really leverage that
action group that you use for
operational things now for those sort of
mitigation uh mitigation actions and and
automation that we want to do you can
then they understand the incidents that
you're seeing and can really help you
throughout the rest of the organization
make those changes those Upstream
changes that you need to ensure that
you're not seeing uh too much stuff
coming down the pipe on the IR area
so that's basically the talk and I have
to say you must be lucky or something
because this is the first time in my
life I've given a talk that's like bang
on time like just dead on the amount of
time it was all the planning we did for
this right right yeah the one hour last
night
um so that being said it's also worth
saying we don't have like an end slide
we totally have time for questions I
think right yeah questions okay cool
um none of this would have been possible
without the conversations that we've had
hell some I've had with many of you all
who are probably in this audience the
people that we work with every day
except Mark
um
but none of this would have been
possible without them so we have a lot
of people to thank and we're not going
to name them all but like it's just very
important to say that like this is not
just us like this is a lot of experience
and ideas that kind of built into this
yeah absolutely huge thank you to all
those folks and this has been you know
over the course of of several years
we've been thinking through this and and
putting some of these things into
practice and and we've found them really
helpful so if there's any elements of
this you know that you all want to take
back to your organizations please do at
the very least hope it starts some good
conversations about how we can build
some Partnerships internally and as well
get more folks becoming incident
commanders and actually working through
these things
good finish so for questions if possible
or if you can I would love if people
would come up and like I will like come
down here
that way they can say something and
they're like if not you can raise your
hand if you're not comfortable doing
that you just have to repeat the
question got it
hi question for everyone for you is that
um for I get this for a 24 7 sock but
for an action team what happens if this
happens on Saturday or Sunday
we call the action team yeah we call the
action team uh so I think that's that's
something that's really important and
I'm really glad you brought that up
actually because you know this Action
Group particularly that core the
responsible parties in the Action Group
do need to be available so we will call
people in the middle of the night uh we
will call legal in the middle of the
night if we need to and we'll wake Folks
up we actually prefer it yeah yeah we'll
actually save incidents for early
Saturday morning maybe 3 A.M or so and
then
but no that that's actually a really
important part of it right you need to
be able especially if you don't have a
24 7 soccer or IR team um to be able to
have that Action Group really at the
beck and call
um of the folks that are working this
that is incredibly important um and you
have to have that buy-in ahead of time
as well so it's not always easy
convincing folks to be part of this
action group but usually you have some
cool examples you can use uh and we you
can sucker people like Bunny and doings
well let's be honest it extends past the
Action Group to be completely honest
right like how many IR teams have full
mitigation control across every possible
bad thing that could happen on their
Network or do you maybe sometimes need
to call somebody that doesn't like to
pick up on the weekends like that's just
part of the job calling people who don't
like to pick up on the weekends like
they'll deal that's why it's so
important to have this kind of stuff
agreed upon across like the higher up
leadership of your company because then
they can be mad about it but they know
it might come
what else anywhere please
how do you handle The Incident Commander
role going around the globe or around
the same lines I can take that one if
you want so we genuinely try to like
Incident Commander is somebody who is
there and available and like can do it
we can also hand off that role it's one
of the great things about doing this
kind of work it's not hard to hand off
that role and say hey you're in charge
now
or you have a team like mine I'm looking
at all of them with disappointment who
just don't leave when things happen and
just refuse
and that's on them not on us
yeah so this actually uh speaks to the
importance of making sure that everyone
uh in your soccer IR area is really
trained to do this and gets the
experience so if folks haven't done this
before hey get them to tag along in
Shadow something like that you got to
make sure that everybody really can step
up into that instant Commander role
because hey uh you know you may need to
be able to transfer something uh over
across you know the weekend something
like that
um you know or you may have folks pulled
off onto multiple incidents or something
which which does happen in the IR world
the other thing that's worth mentioning
is it's really the first couple hours
that are critical anyway because that's
when you take your first pass on work
streams you figure out what you want to
do and then people go off and start
working right so until there's new and
damning information if there is new and
damning information that's when the
Action Group gets back together and
that's when you can figure out the best
course of what to do next so it's very
much like meet plan work meet plan work
round and round in a circle all right
what else
go answer whoever
all right oh Elite come over
so it sounds like you guys have put this
in effect in the last what year or so
something like that a couple years
so what's the trade-off between you know
the red tape that comes with bureaucracy
when you add in all these different
teams and their way they're uh let's
just say ability to rapidly respond to
something is different than what IR or
security teams usually do so what's been
your trade-off or how you work through
that uh challenge
yeah so there's a really important
component to the Action Group
hey deal with it there's a really
important component to the action group
that we talked about earlier right
that's the responsible parties and
support parties
now I'll let you talk yeah absolutely so
um I guess I guess I'll talk a little
bit over Sean here um but yeah I think
fundamentally this is why you need to
pre-establish the action group and make
sure that you have uh not just a
commitment of the responsible parties to
actually show up um but to actually get
the job done and ass and and really make
sure they are pushing off uh the current
work that they have so we have a lot of
times where we have legal counsel or
someone else who is dealing with other
things that are going on but when we do
activate that that Action Group there's
an understanding on all those parties
that that is the priority to do right
now so getting that buy-in ahead of time
is incredibly important to do and that's
really how we've sort of fought that red
tape now it's not always perfect but
generally for those responsible parties
that you have
um making sure that they understand that
well Bunny wants to jump in this is
going to be good
so uh one of the pieces I want to add to
this is appropriate air cover one of the
red tape Killers is having somebody
that's got the facility to talk to the
rest of them and make them stand down
and that's where you make friends with
your HR your legal counsel somebody that
can give you that air cover and that's
the other piece of the puzzle because
without that without having the
effective Partners you are going to get
bogged down in the red tape
quick question where can we find more
documentation about the methodology so
we had this brilliant plan that we were
going to work all this up and we were
going to launch a blog post alongside
the talk and we're going to do all that
and then we wrote the talk last night
and have none of that
um that being said we are planning on
doing all of that when this recording
goes live
so like we should have companion stuff
and like the actual workflows and all
that kind of stuff around that time
presuming that legal approves or I
decide not to listen
all right uh we probably got time for
one more
anybody
please
how do we train people and how often do
we exercise for the clear roles and
responsibilities you want to take it
yeah all the time um hopefully we're not
putting this into practice all the time
uh that's a that's a really good way to
to train Folks up uh but I think one of
the core things that I think this is
something I really want to call Sean out
for doing a really amazing job with is
sort of as we started this Sean is a
veteran Incident Commander here uh he
really took that role of The Incident
Commander to sort of LED as the leader
in the organization said This is how we
do this and so we built a lot of that
stuff and modeled a lot of this stuff
off of how Shauna's do it has done this
and as he's put some of this stuff into
practice we've brought a lot of the more
Junior employees along to sort of
observe that I think there's really
nothing better to do than to really
understand how this stuff gets put into
practice and activated so that's really
one of the ways is making sure that our
our Junior employees are here actually
see Sean or really any uh senior person
in your organization put this stuff into
practice uh the other piece is that yes
we have the specific processes all
documented in outlined mind internally
as well so that folks understand this
and are able to essentially follow along
with what this what the requirements of
that role specifically are in terms of
regularly Drilling and training this is
something that we that we do probably
not as often as we want to
um I think regular drill of this sort of
stuff is is actually incredibly
important it's just sometimes finding
time in an IR shop to do that which we
we find a surprising amount of time
though think about tabletop programs and
all that kind of stuff like there's
there's quite a bit Yeah so one of the
things speaking of tabletop programs
that we actually think is is pretty
important to do as well is to make sure
that you have tabletops with your
Executives using this model or whatever
that you have so when you come up to
some of those big time decisions that
need to be made during an incident you
do need Executive cover for that as
bunny was talking about earlier making
sure that your objectives your
executives are roped in they're telling
you to shut up yeah I'm getting pulled
off the stage I thought that you're
gonna play the Oscar music to get me off
stage was that no you'll have to come up
and drag them trust me all right all
right thanks everybody so much I
appreciate it we'll be around to talk
thank you