come come whoever you are just come
these are the words of the beloved 13th
century poet Rumi they were shared with
us by the chief of cabinet to the
president of Turkey and uncle just a few
weeks ago and they echoed the philosophy
that has brought us together once again
ICANN's door is open it is open to
everyone no matter your nationality your
language your position your level of
expertise or opinion it is open because
the unique voice matters to the future
of the Internet welcome to I can 41 and
a wonderful Singapore it's a living
example of the transformative power of
technology in 2011 for the second year
in a row singapore was rated as the
second most connected country in the
world thanks to your leadership and
others in the government and private
sector ICANN's first public meeting was
held here back in 1999 as Peter
mentioned we welcome our special destiny
guest today who honor us with their
presidents their presence miss grace foo
senior minister for information
communications in the arts who spoke
earlier and of course miss Eileen chea
deputy director of the info
communications Development Authority
they have spearheaded a national effort
to ensure Singapore smooth transition to
ipv6 the Singapore internet exchange is
now a major internet hub in the region
serving our interconnected world I would
also like to recognize some of Asia's
internet leaders including professor
1010 we a Singapore for his pioneering
work on internationalized domain names
dr. Wu Jinping of China winner of the
2010 jon postel award professor Killman
Chon of Korea James sing for his
contributions in advancing the
development of idns and professor June
Mirai of Japan's wide network
who have done so much to advance the
internet they are a reflection I know
James I know James is here I'm not sure
who else is there a reflection of Asia's
legacy of achievement in the high tech
field a legacy based on solid
engineering excellence ingenuity
creativity and a lot of hard work we
were also deeply grateful to Leon can't
I the infocomm Development Authority of
Singapore and their Singapore Network
Information Center for their generosity
and unparalleled hospitality in hosting
this meeting and for the attention they
have paid to every detail to ensure the
success of this key event in ICANN's
history and I ask you have you ever had
such great hotel food before it's
amazing as we gather here we face a
number of important issues a decision is
expected shortly on new generic
top-level domains recommendations of the
accountability transparency review team
including implementation plans are due
for action by the board of directors and
a new GI know there's some interest in
that and a new chair and vice-chair of
the board will also be elected this week
this is a truly significant moment in
ICANN's history according to a recent
study by mckinsey global institute the
internet contributed about 1.7 trillion
dollars to the global gross domestic
product in 2009 the internet overall is
contributing about three-point-four
percent to global gdp according to the
study in more mature economies
twenty-one percent of all economic
growth twenty-one percent over the last
five years can be attributed to the
internet at a time when the world needs
more jobs our efforts to open up in
advance the internet and the DNS can be
a contributing factor for every job
through technological advances 2.6 are
created according to the study that's a
good ratio this increase in employment
and resulting productivity boost have
led to higher living standards and
greater wealth worldwide they've also
become key factors in international
efforts to alleviate poverty and spread
education in developing countries and
this is a potent argument for keeping
the internet open and unified as we do
the internet advances economies through
innovation it provides a global launch
pad for ideas that will generate
tomorrow's great economic opportunities
it empowers creative thought and
risk-taking and never never in the
history of mankind has there been a more
fertile field for innovation to grow in
here in Asia you have much to be proud
of South Korea in Japan enjoy the
fastest broad broadband access speeds in
the world reportedly far surpassing the
United States and many European
countries in Japan the average access
speed for broadband is 84 megabits per
second in the United States 17 Asia has
forty two percent of the world's
Internet users more than 800 million
people 400 million in China alone it has
grown the user populations grown by more
than six hundred percent since the year
2000 and according to Cisco global
internet traffic will quadruple by 2015
forty-two percent of that growth will be
here in Asia and China alone is expected
to have 670 million users by 2015 the
Internet's mega economic impact and is
potential for greater growth and
influence make I can and our role
collectively more important our economic
future depends on maintaining a stable
domain name system in order to provide
the
foundation for continued communication
and innovation I can must be part of the
dialogue to ensure that this role is
understood and to advance our common
goal of a secure stable and unified
global Internet a key element of that
dialogue is the Internet Governance
forum through the dedicated work of many
stakeholders the IGF mandate has been
extended for five years thanks to the
efforts of many of you at the same time
the UN called for changes that could
profoundly alter the IGS form and
function I can is contributing to their
development through the Commission on
science and technology development for
development and we look forward to
participating in future IGS including in
lovely Nairobi Kenya this sep tember
engagement with governments is also
fundamental to icons role and to the
very future of the Internet in
representing government that I can the
governmental advisory committee or gac
continues its growth indicating the
governments are increasing their
participation in our work the gac
significant role in I can of course
complements many other groups this
constructive international engagement
was well demonstrated in the board gac
consultations in Brussels and in sorting
through 80 complex and challenging
issues related to new gTLDs it
demonstrates that once again the
multi-stakeholder model is alive and
working and now for today's big news
every I can public meeting is important
but this meeting is particularly
important for an obvious reason this
morning the board of directors will
consider whether to approve a program to
introduce new generic top-level domains
into the DNS it has been do I need to
tell you a long long long hard road but
we are here
almost six years after the formal policy
development process began we're facing a
decision today on whether to move ahead
with one of the most significant changes
in the history of the internet and the
DNS and a lot of people thought we'd
never get here if the board votes to
approve the new gTLD program the
namespace of the internet could expand
dramatically with the promise of
significant economic impact many
organizations with an online presence
will be affected in some way this
represents great opportunity as well as
some risk that we must and will manage
new businesses are already poised to
move forward consulting businesses to
advise applicants have sprung up over a
hundred and twenty organizations have
publicly said they intend to apply in
declared applications and more than 90
have active web sites marketing their
proposed new concepts and ideas this is
innovation at its best they are
proposing all all types of new gTLDs
city names community ideas branding
opportunities for companies and products
I gos and others this demonstrates the
rich platform for innovation that new
gTLDs represent others are preparing to
take advantage of the upcoming change
even if they do not intend to apply for
tlds themselves development of the new
gtld program continues to be conducted
in a highly transparent inclusive and
comprehensive fashion and this has
continued here over the last several
days the community has contributed to
tremendous lengths to address the
concerns of all interested parties and
to seek balance among them some claim
that i can stands to profit from this
new program this is not true the program
will be running a cost recovery basis as
designed by you the community and as
approved by the ICANN board if approved
by the ICANN board
as CEO I have neither advocated nor
opposed this program now that the space
has been completed I will be my raising
my hand to vote this was a strategic
decision I made when I came to I can to
remain neutral I saw my role as
fostering the environment the processes
the skills and the practices to develop
the programs framework successfully when
the i kin community develops and
implements policy everyone gets a say
and the close cooperation among the
community staff and board was
particularly beneficial in the
development of the applicant guidebook
this careful an extensive consultative
process especially on detailed matters
of such consequence takes time but the
result reflects a well-considered
community consensus we have reached the
end of the policy and implementation
planning phases of new gTLDs now the
real hard work begins program launch and
execution application processing will
proceed according to our policies the
applicant guidebook and I Cannes bylaws
the ultimate decision following staff
processes and independent panel findings
comes when the board chooses whether or
not to gelug 8 a string into the route
we have an obligation to represent the
global public interest in every aspect
of this policy development
implementation and execution but each of
these phases is distinctly different and
I can and this community must
acknowledge that once a decision is made
to move forward with this implementation
if it occurs today one chapter has
closed and another begins the open door
process of private industry and other
parties promoting specific outcomes
which contributed so richly to the
policy development process must now come
to a close application processing must
be neutral and objective
and be seen as such with new and clean
lines of separation among community
applicants board and staff on all issues
related to applications as applications
are evaluated we must maintain the
integrity and transparency of the
process so that all stakeholders can
have confidence in this program i can
has a clear confidentially i can has
clear confidentiality policies and under
my leadership we will continue to
enforce them I think we can all feel
proud of this community's achievements
in developing this incredible innovation
and in bringing this innovation and this
issue to a conclusion huge technical and
political challenges have been overcome
through inclusion cooperation diplomacy
compromise and a lot of hard work by
many many individuals a lot of them in
this room we thank you no one ever
thought it would take this long but the
commitment and some might even say
extreme endurance needed to bring so
many conflicting interests into balance
to produce a credible and well grounded
program has never wavered it reflects
the very best of the multi-stakeholder
model and this community at work
internationalized domain names make it
possible to access the internet and
scripts other than latin-based
characters and their successful adoption
has been one of i kin community's
greatest successes the new gTLD program
will enable additional IDNs one pending
issue is the potential delegation of
variant top-level domains some scripts
Chinese for example exist in multiple
forms with several ways to represent the
same concept ID invariance would allow
their use at the top level on Saturday
the community started work on case
studies of variants in Arabic Chinese
cyrillic Devin Hari Greek and Latin
these keep the commute these community
led teams plan to finish their report to
the board by the end of this year you
may recall that at the Silicon Valley
meeting I called for the widest possible
range of voices to respond to the US
Department of Commerce's notice of
inquiry on the iono functions no matter
what your view in keeping with the
multi-stakeholder model it's important
that everybody be heard it was wonderful
to see so many people organizations and
countries coming forward more than 80
organizations and individuals offered
their views on these important issues
the comments indicate strong percent
over eighty percent for ICANN's
performance of the ayana functions and
for keeping those functions together the
call for greater transparency and
greater multi stakeholder involvement in
and oversight of the ANA functions was
also strongly supported further evidence
of support comes from the IETF the
internet architecture board the number
resource organization at their request
we have begun discussions about I can
managing and operating the single global
trust anchor for internet number
resource certification we applaud their
important efforts as many of you are no
doubt aware the Department of Commerce
has asked for additional comment on
enhancing the iono functions this
further notice of inquiry seeks input on
more detailed proposed changes to the
ANA contract again I urge all of you and
everyone in the community each one of
you to please submit your views no
matter what they are on how you think
the IANA functions should evolve and
this component of the internet again I
urge you to to join us and in engaging
in the dialogue it's imperative that the
performance the ANA functions receives
the support of the global Internet can
and we thank the ntia for providing the
community with multiple opportunities to
provide open and transparent input I can
continues to implement the
recommendations on the accountability
and transparency review team we have we
created a team of executives to focus on
this area to ensure that adequate
resources were dedicated and that the
work got done we have proposed at all 27
recommendations all 27 be adopted the
board must take action by the end of
june and allocate the necessary
resources we have been conducting the
analysis listening to the community
input and developing implementation
plans for board consideration many
operational improvements have already
been implemented as you have seen i can
has a strong foundation of
accountability and transparency related
achievements and we will continue to
build upon this the internet has
tremendous capacity to improve lives
through greater economic growth as we
discussed but its capacity for good also
has a shadow the capacity for bad and
harm the new gTLD program includes many
new protections for right rights holders
and measures to mitigate malicious
conduct but the work does not stop there
the gns o is reviewing concrete
recommendations to address domain name
registration abuse in gTLDs including
cybersquatting malicious use of domain
names fake renewal notices uniformity of
contracts and who is access problems
among other issues the community is
developing a discussion paper on
non-binding best practices to help
registrar's and registries address those
matters and a workshop is being held
here in Singapore who is data includes
registered domain names registrar
contracts and other critical information
the gns o council is working with
ICANN's policy staff to conduct who is
studies to provide a more factual data
driven foundation for
future policy making one is reviewing
previous Gina so who is policy issues in
current and potential technical
requirements a strong whois database is
a priority as I can increases its
collaboration and engagement with law
enforcement law enforcement has a key
role to play in our multi-stakeholder
community and Interpol is an important
international leader in this field I was
privileged to visit Interpol
headquarters in Lyon France last month
where I met with Secretary General Ron
noble to explore avenues for further
collaboration on internet security this
was the first high-level meeting between
I can and Interpol we were pleased to
learn of their interest in joining the
GAC as an observer the i kin community
is also part of a wide-ranging
discussion on the registrar
accreditation agreement to better
address the concerns of security and law
enforcement communities enhance
protections for registrant's and provide
better compliance tools I hope that more
progress on these matters can be made
this week this meeting will also bring
together a broad spectrum of community
experts on DNS security and stability a
full day working session on the AOC SSR
review team work Shep's workshops on DNS
SEC implementation and technical
sessions with a ccTLD community as
always I can continues to face a massive
global agenda we must have the
leadership professional skills and
experience to meet these increasing
demands and while we have made solid
progress the challenges continue to grow
and we must redouble our efforts these
past two years have been a period of
significant transition for I can staff
many changes have been made to ensure
that we continue to serve this community
and the public interest to the highest
professional standards I was explicitly
given this challenge when I was hired
our need for different leadership and
process
does not diminish the enormous
contributions of previous staff members
who have given so much to this
organization in community many of whom
have moved on to other organizations
where they continue to thrive and
contribute to the ICANN community from a
different perspective together we have a
true success story to tell we are
building a world-class organization we
have upgraded policy development support
created a communications department
enhanced Diana processing and enhanced
its resiliency and we strengthen the
security team and also contractual
compliance the changes a date have also
produced a mature and cohesive senior
management team that functions at a very
high level of quality productivity and
teamwork and continues to grow in its
scope and abilities simply put we have a
great executive management team we
continue to bring in many individuals
with diverse international backgrounds
this helps to globalize our organization
and extend our language skills to
address more communities we're also
building new tools so our staff can do
their jobs more effectively a new
financial system the TLD processing
application processing system and a new
and more effective internet that
replaces previous outdated systems all
of this has been achieved while keeping
turnover in the organization well below
industry norms a normal rate of turnover
in the high-tech and nonprofit sectors
as most of you know because you function
in it is twenty to twenty-five percent a
year despite material upgrades in
numerous key positions ICANN's turnover
in 2010 was only eleven point six two
percent 11.6 two and in 2011 overall I
can't turn over is tracking at an
annualized rate under thirteen percent
still below average but it's important
to note that turnover is likely if not
certain to increase if new gTLDs are
approved today we will be substantially
augmenting and improving the new gtld
program office and we
see a rise in departures as our highly
qualified staff are recruited by other
organizations including some in this
room for their unique experience in this
emerging area this would be a solid
endorsement of our staff not expectedly
the first such resignation has already
occurred I'm pleased to hear the
community begin discussions on whether I
can FX policies need to be strengthened
the past two years have been a
tremendously rewarding period in my
professional life but we have all
achieved together and only two years is
truly remarkable if new gTLDs are
approved it will be our fourth major
achievement of global significance since
my arrival just two years ago together
we completed the affirmation of
commitments we then completed ID ends in
the fast track program not long after
that and then DNS SEC was success
successfully launched last year and has
now been rolled out around the world
everyone in this community can be proud
of these accomplishments on time in a
high quality manner and of course we've
seen a significant strength of the
multi-stakeholder model through enhanced
relationships around the world we did
all this while ensuring 100% accuracy
and I ana delegations Andrey delegations
and maintaining the stability of the
Internet's route which is job number one
but our work is not done I will not
stand here and pretend that any of this
has been easy it has not been easy or
that there have not been naysayers there
are I am proud to have led this
organization through such a productive
period under such enormous pressures and
change Peter den gates Russia and I are
very different people we have different
talents different work styles different
backgrounds and interests but together
we forge an extremely productive
relationship that has always been
focused on performance delivering
quality and lifting this organization
Peter sharpen the focus on the board and
i did it with the staff we've worked
closely together on countless occasions
to ensure that the public interest is
always well served the pie
our and the stability of this
relationship will be gone on friday as
peter completes his term as chair of the
board quite successfully it has been a
great platform for board staff and
community success and Peter I'm thankful
to you for everything you have
contributed I look forward to building
that kind of relationship with a new
chair and Vice Chair today we face a
fateful decision for I can our
reputation and the future of the
multi-stakeholder ecosystem depend on
how well we respond and I'm confident
that the new board will rise to this
challenge the new gTLD program will be a
crucial test of our ability to execute
and stay focused on what matters not on
the noise that can distract us all we
are dedicated to delivering this program
and all of our responsibilities to the
highest possible standard and we will I
would like to thank icann's incredibly
dedicated staff who have worked so hard
and with such professionalism to bring
this moment the new gTLD program maybe I
cans most important achievement yet for
the community the board and the staff
for everyone who has worked so hard to
make this happen this is an historic
moment the moment that we together can
and will make history thank you very
much