are you guys were just about to get
started so if you're out there
in the a Event Center come on in
%uh there was one thing I forgot to
announce if you just look for the
the team that's in the safety yellow
green construction worker shirt so much
that's what they tell me
I made them where on that stops the
conference stuff you can grab anybody
give any questions concerns talk to them
nominal to make sure gets taken care of
so
I'm just really excited odd
%uh this morning as you could tell from
earlier but the very sad about this next
speaker
%uh the fact that he took the time out
of his busy schedule to come down here
in sport conference in sport as is
is just a row honor and I just like the
give them a brief introduction before we
get up here
so Davis served as chief executive
officer
a fire I since November 2012 and
chairman
Chairman of the Board since May 2012 I'm
as many of you probably know in this
field
he led by right when the most successful
cyber security IP o's
and is involved in defining a entirely
new approach to security
and information scary protection umpire
to fire I
Dave served as president and executive
officer and director Mack p
on this is from April 20 2007 through
August 2011
and up at which time he led
I mackey to be acquired by Intel i think
is the largest cash
acquisition in tech history so very very
impressive
I he held various executive positions
throughout his career
and served I am on
so sorry hun acid use our positions at
EMC Corporation from December 2003
to March 2007 after the company was
acquired
arm at a a document I think was acquired
sorry
where he served as president and chief
executive officer from July 2001 to
December 2003
I currently sits on the board directors
for Delta Air Lines
the University of San Francisco other
national security Technology Advisory
Council
for President Obama and 59 he previously
served on the board of directors a
Polycom
from November 2005 to May 2013
and as its chairman of the board for May
2010 to May
2013 as well board of directors have
Jive Software
from February 2011 to April 2013 there
was a BS in computer science from the
University of Delaware
and I'd like you to help me give them a
very warm welcome
mister Dave Dewalt chairman and CEO of
iraq pyrite
megadeath
of them morning overrated
well Chaka Khan six
I just want to say thank you honestly to
secure DNA and sort of all the folks
Jason and Ernie and the whole team here
six years the putting that song together
what great professionals they are great
people we give them a big round of
applause could date someone to
Bank today from often alright
I was really looking forward to coming
to Honolulu and
doing a presentation I get a chance to
speak all over the world sometimes
up rarely do I get to do it right
outside Waikiki the beach
and wondered why we're not out there
during the presentation at the moment
but
I kinda fun to be in here as well and i
just want to welcome hopefully everybody
can see me okay
I I think the BIOS gonna be longer than
my presentation so apologies for
for that I'm I was gonna go on when I
was age a to root my first program
and we missed out the bile anyways hey
I'm
I'm gonna try to talk on a serious note
today about kinda what's happening in
the world
I know a lot of newer are very seasoned
security professionals
i've a technical background and Pinot
really I
interested in technology since I was a
little kid
and it's amazing kinda what we're
dealing with the world today
just absolutely amazing and up a little
on a spinal
but I have appear to the dawning of
cyber worse up what time I really seen
an incredible amount
evidence to suggest that we we really
are on the precipice
from pretty dangerous times in the world
on
if you link back about what's happened
over over mankind's history
whenever a new domain it's discovered
typically mankind has a conflict over
now whether it was the lambs our oceans
or airspace or
or now cyberspace we end up finding
ourselves
really with conflict and kinda where
we're at right now
when I when I first got involved with
some other
the global superpower conflict that are
happening I was the CEO
McAfee man dont 2008
we had a a pretty famous operation
called Aurora
anybody remember or pretty interesting
attack
we were involved with that McAfee in
alternately discovered
that Google had been hacked and we gone
and seen some of the evidence of how the
J pics were loaded down the spear
phishing occurred
who they were targeting how they were
going after the system's
and over the course of about thirty day
period
we ended up finding a 153 companies with
a very similar attack
all in Silicon Valley all focused on
source code
about databases kinda quality assurance
systems
and we realized for the first time how
long the attacks have been in place what
the research was going after
and just you know how powerful the
system openly was
I found myself opting invited to the
white house
about 30 minutes later and up
President Obama had just gotten office
beginning in 2009
and my job was to brief the president on
what happened with operation Aurora
so here I am presenting know what
malware is an appt czar
to the president that states I eiffel
early was like in a pinch me it was
pretty amazing
time but you know fast for six years
later
and were given briefings premieres in
presidents all over the world
on what's happening in fiber and I we've
just
elevated from 12 Kong level to another
and
with now arrived at indictments up major
military officers in China
what you've probably seen it it's a
pretty serious situation
we're all and somewhat kinda pink this
for you
and give you a little insight what I see
around the world
I have a pretty interesting view to
what's happening
now travels are not only with choir I
but also at the National Security
Council
also my views from safety and security
of Delta Air Lines
and to sort of how physical and cyber
terrorism and security are coming
together
and tell you a little bit about what the
offense is doing
how are powerful that often serve model
it's become
are in many ways how weak the defense
%uh models become help this located at
spahn
and then ultimately a little kinda where
it all going so I like to start off with
an analogy
many view out probably know this analogy
pretty well I love history
hopefully someone you do too and I think
history is repeating itself
literally right now in cyberspace and
the analogy that I like to use comes
from mom
post-world War one I it's called the
match in Oman
and many vino what occurred on
if you don't 1929 the up
French had proposed Andre imagino
who was the world Minister France are
proposed for the French parliament
nine billion French franc about the
fence asleep
at the time nine billion french francs
was
nearly the economy for that year and
this was a serious undertaking I
probably knows the greatest defense
system
that's on the world has ever seen I was
about to be built
this was a series of forts that were
sensually put in place
every three quarters of a mile and out
there for 25 it was an incredible
architecture that was created
this thing was never been seen before
every learning a world where one
was essentially put in place with this
the front system
how to overcome gas attacks how to have
ground forces be put in place for years
at Marshall attacks if you look at sort
of the architectures that are put in
place or if you can see at the back
but it was incredible now literally air
pressure gas chambers
all kinds have long sustaining you know
up to a decade-long
sustaining operations are complete
hangers built into the
the bay's tank commands will tunnels
coming in telecommunication systems
gymnasiums medical systems
now this thing what's up a work of art
and probably what's most amazing about
it
was never use most if you probably know
this
I the up ultimate the fence when all the
way from the English Channel
all the way down to the Mediterranean
Sea literally every three quarters of a
mile
pretty impressive %uh system others
actually to open that was built the
National and the Alpine line
one across Italy in another crossed the
the French border
and most you're probably know this when
the Second World War was
up was done how the germans with
superior technology bypass the National
line didn't literally
days an occupied Paris and six weeks
from the outbreak of the war so nine
billion french francs
greatest the front system ever built and
built from the previous kinda war and
ultimately defeated
index cell what I kinda see happening
today
is almost the same national line analogy
most companies are putting in place very
complicated complex the fence and DEF
model and at every layer of the
architecture of the network in the end
point cloud
we're building incredible architectures
advanced next-generation firewalls
you know proxies for the web gateways
email gateways
intrusion detection prevention systems
data loss prevention systems
all kinda sick one Jackson systems and
the list goes on and on
the average company fortune 500 company
spawning spending
over 100 million dollars a year in
defense and DEP
pretty amazing numbers what's the
reality
we're seeing almost the same thing
superpowers are bypassing these defense
architectures
in minutes literally in minutes
most you're probably fall the I a pack
event that was here
I'm not too long ago on the attacks can
occur literally an hour
be successful from a Wichita man didn't
fire I responded to to some the
delegation that was speaking at a pic
event here in honolulu
were breached to find what speaker notes
what were they speaking about so the
abilities to be able to breach
this complex systems so we see today
its its kinda scary the offense the
defense or completely
just look it and it goes back to almost
what happened in world war 1 going in
the world war two
the architecture is that we have in
place are creating
a massive hole they all have an Achilles
heel
and the understanding of hey I've got
anti-virus I put in these defense in
depth players somebody's gonna find it
I've got thirty forty fifty different
security vendors
I put in all this technology and of
course some secure
and morality is most companies are not
secure
and we're seeing that more than 95
percent of the organizations are
compromised are completely owned
other data exfiltration its massive and
their family
to protect their core IP so we're now at
the dawning
I've just got major ship in terms of
power
are complexity ingenuity to go after an
attack this type of model
and the offense is getting much more
aggressive then the defense
models that are there and of course we
try to
respond to these threats but at the
heart a bit
is a system mo said you know what I was
part of it for
for almost five years McAfee we built
the system's
there any virus model blacklisting
signature pattern matching kind some
models
and what we try to do figure out how to
match a virus
we read a signature for with right
thousands on every day
we really for dad engines mobile plan
today
and I would send them out every
computing device McAfee had nearly $300
million computing devices
that we were deployed to and we would
send these out
and ultimately became sixty-plus million
signatures or updating every day
and of course the effectiveness of the
system is
not very high today tackle show in a
minute
single-digit effectiveness and what we
do we put that
different anti-virus model from McAfee
or semantic Trend Micro Kaspersky
so foes name vendor for an IPS solutions
something up a firewall we put this
model in place after work
25-year-old model has single-digit
effectiveness
and we look at what's happened you're
seeing that the average breach
from the time of infection the time of
discovery
is 243 days this was over almost a
thousand incidences that we responded to
over the last two years the average
infection 243 decks
from the time it was placed the time we
discovered it
and then ultimately another about 32
days it took
from the climate discovery the time
remediation
for 270 plus days to go from
climb a breach figure it out what's most
interesting is 63 percent of those
companies
learned about it from someone else
they couldn't discover with their own
technologies that came from an agency
came from a private vendor an almost all
along
one hundred percent among had up-to-date
anti-virus
and most of them had it at every layer
of the architecture
and I'll show you some stats here just a
minute it's kind of an interesting state
of things
spending a hundred million dollars a
year on average fortune 500 company
and ultimately ninety-eight percent or
so or breach
most summer finding out from a third
party and most of them have the attacks
in the network
for almost a year kind in the state of
reality of what we're seeing
on the market for fire I we did a little
study
just the kind of prove what we were what
we were seeing and a combination Manian
fire I we looked at
are 1,217 companies
over the course of about a hundred day
period and this was just done recently
I'm from about December tormented and we
did it across to 1,614 appliances at
fire ice sixty seven different countries
so this was the first time that we
looked at a network
you through an instant response for
through a fire I appliance
and the reality of it was quite
interesting we ended up doing across the
lot of different verticals
financials high-tech government banking
across-the-board again 67 countries
twenty verticals
and what did we end up seeing 225,000
unique pieces I'm our
75 percent seventy-five percent of them
were seen one time forty attackers doing
today
the right them our very uniquely
targeted at the company
so 1,217 companies all them our
three-quarters of them were seen once
so interesting and about 18 percent
detection rate across
all about at most so that detection rate
was across a thirty day period
the anti-virus vendors found 80 percent
of the time
in the first two or three days and then
openly about thirty day period
they discovered about 18 percent of it
so kind of an interesting stay the
things we sorta look at
kinda some real not you end up seeing
the numbers like this
1/4 about 25 percent Sol an appt
a persistent our advanced attack
about 75 percent of them saw active
command and control server activity
which was using data exfiltration almost
100 percent at them
use foreign crypto graffiti so no its a
cell-type connection
although all types of poppers be used
and of course the average attack was
very regular Matt
I'll several times a week so these are
kinda the state of things that we it's
all
and then we're kinda look at all of them
almost a hundred percent along
had firewalls web network endpoint
and other anti-malware type solutions on
the host
so elaborate technologies nearly 100
percent for breach
most of them having data exfiltration 67
countries twenty verticals
1000 Posco's my point about this
this kind of the National I Networks Inc
the state a fiber security of france
it's far ahead of the defense a model
right now
and we sort of start to look at what's
the motive upper and I have some other
superpowers
took an understanding of why this is
gonna just increase
as we move our there's no doubt that
these numbers will continue to increase
we're seeing it regularly and the
ultimate state of things is this
you're starting to see the headlines and
almost ultimately
you're seeing what i think is the
greatest transfer wealth in history
happening most that's happening from
American the Western world
the emerging markets but the
intellectual property
the dollar fast is now measured in
hundreds of billions of dollars a year
hundreds of billions here pretty
interesting
so minutes or so my is this all you go
what why is it happening
what's causing this and what I find
really interesting as we have almost the
perfect platform
evil like I created in a great way all
this wonderful innovation that we have
is amazing every couple months I have a
new cell phone
I'm always connecting on social networks
we all are
we all have all this wonderful
information at our disposal
but it's created literally the perfect
platform for the aperture is to leverage
and I'm sure over the course of the next
couple days you'll see that
but what are we finding cyberspace
itself this new domain that we have
ISC tremendously flawed from a defense a
point of view
why because we have no governance model
where one click away from any website
know world
any search can connect to just about any
domain
ninety-five percent of all the domains
are in the dark nap
today ipv6 and driving towards a new
types of topologies we have on the
network
are adding trillions of addressable
devices
and ultimately we have complete
anonymity on the Internet
the attackers can hide behind whatever
IP address they happen to buy
now with capitalism we can buy domains
for three to five dollars
and we can by tens of thousands of them
without any identification
for kind of an interesting world we're
living in where we've got this perfect
platform set up
and of course most worthy adversaries
are the government's themselves
up superpowers are the ones that are
driving these activities
and it's not directly the superpowers
someone acting on behalf of the
superpower
so this isn't gonna change anytime soon
for common interesting situation that
we're leveraged and as we move forward
think about this from couple factors in
this is what I find most interesting
what's gonna happen what's the dark side
of this innovation
kinda thing about this and four areas
probably number one
the cyber espionage kinda components
expand
the number countries that were tracking
now how often serve activities
probably is in the 51 or 52 country
range right now
this is up from about eight or ten three
years ago we believe there's about 51
countries right now
how put in place wanna build research
labs
put an offense if teens funded those
teams
and those teams are very active when it
comes to often so that's been arch
and that spread pretty virally across
the world
are part of the report that I mention
the match in online we now track
command-and-control servers and 204
countries
I actually didn't know there is 204
countries combat a huge number
hosted domains that are using to text
tration models and leverage with their
telecommunication systems for
om exultation up information so we're
gonna continue to see this
on the amount a recruitment coming out
the military and most other countries
around the world extreme
when we see the Syrian and the Iranian
activities how much we're improving
every couple months you can see the
knowledge transference occurring
into these parts the marketplace not
talk about that just a minute as well
probably the biggest change we're seeing
recently some the cyber sabotage pipes
apart now work it's
on no intent whatsoever to steal the
entire intention
is so destroyed we've seen several cases
in the United States just in the last
hour
60 to 90 days summer which were very
high profiled
one involving one the largest casinos in
Las Vegas
due to a comment the CEO made about a
particular country
alternately on came about with a massive
attack in four days
so in this particular attack high and
David destruction types of
worms were deployed ultimately with a
spear phishing front and
but was able to be put together in a
four day period
that brought down the company for five
straight days
so common interesting time where the
motivations
are not only just offer crime or for
intellectual property
but now for hatred religious purposes
other types at your political purposes
as well
other types things the crime element has
really hit
equity markets so most have you probably
see this
are a lot of changes occurred from what
I think up this high volume
low credit card low dollar amount types
a crime still made famous by targeting a
few others
but we're seeing a tremendous amount
insider trading types of activities
today
and a lot of hedging of that insider
trading information
a lot of the breach responses were doing
we only find three or four or five
are breached a host and what are those
hoes
arm people doing Financial Controller
investment relations personnel anybody
who was high
access information for the whole idea
get access to the information hedge the
stock
hedge the commodities get information
ahead of the market
make money that way very very difficult
to track that
with very little regulation in place to
do it
and most the attackers are using bank
account somewhere in the world
with the number of degrees of anonymity
so a tremendous amount of change
in the way in which the crime elements
occurring as well
and a lot happening in the Eastern
European marketplace today
last one which is probably more
frightening one which I had experience
with directly
is a bit accidental problem
with all this activity that's occurring
from so many different groups
we now track about 300 offenses actors
in the world
studio flies over 300 motivated group
most amor playing now with very very
arm interesting areas of the operating
environment so the stocks that we all
you'll find comfort in the BIOS a woman
so far
of our infrastructure our critical
infrastructure
weather for transportation in the sky
transportation on the ground
are critical energies and a lot of the
activity
is directly related to trying to monitor
it
steel firm at and of course the
slightest state can cause an accident
and we've seen a number of scenarios are
this close
to creating an accident and some the
accidents can actually occur from the
security vendors themselves
were from the vendor trying to patch it
in an emergency patch conaway
I don't know if you follow a fire I too
much but we just really stop
a major zero-day in Internet Explorer
couple weeks ago called
and that's fine Fox contest but Fox was
your day we discovered in one of our
in San responding areas hit not only XP
but all the way through
all the Microsoft platforms Microsoft
was absolutely amazing in the process
and help patch all the systems women to
patching several hundred million devices
in a 22-hour period
I to help remove the vulnerability and
within a weekend we had gone from
non discovery for patch management 22
hours
very difficult to Q way that process to
be successful
there was a mistake along the way you
can reach massive infrastructure and
equip your time
when that McAfee released a faulty that
something might now
was called 59-58 was centered out out
it up porn king the food execute a ball
on Windows I'll Service Pack 2
and we took down three million computers
and 16 minutes
over I think sixteen hundred companies
so the accident problem
couple was from a crime sabotage an
espionage
sorta creating a very interesting dark
side to the scenarios were facing
so again for to be to ominous here but
we gotta think about how do we close the
defense and the offense
this is probably the number one top that
i think is a community
up security professionals we have to
figure out
what can we do to get it back to very
incremental offense and defense activity
right now that gap
is enormous the power the money the
complexity
persons what the defense can do is too
great
and it's gonna create when I showed you
as a problem
so as you think about this evolution you
know we have the birth of anti-virus
as you started to see those first pipes
a virus attacks occurred
million no code Red Melissa love you
viruses things like that
I remember tracking someone owes of
course my favorite person John McAfee
guys remember this guy
I am his he helped invent that
and of course I i think is now involved
with security began but
little scary up but nonetheless
we've seen a huge evolution other types
of of France
and pipes from our creation that's being
used
and of course the defense keeps trying
to follow along
in years past particularly in the last
10 years
which a pretty close correlation right
about the time we started to see
advanced persistent threats nation-state
activity at a much higher level
with all that just location change
dramatically and not really
obsoleted a lot of the technology but I
talked about before everything from
blacklisting
using anti virus the blacklisting using
data loss prevention
Trojan detection systems a blacklisting
web URL but everything there began to
break apart
as we watch the model move forward so
where we are today
we now have to figure out a way to do a
different type of analysis
a different way to think about things
and it's exacerbated by
the fact that almost all the offense is
using dark net domains
to start an import rate their attacks
and I'll show you in just a second
almost a hundred percent of the attacks
will start with the visible web
had a whaler you to click on a Web site
how do I start
exploit to occur but then all the
command-and-control server activity
is all happening in the dark nap stuff
that's protected by password
stuff that's highly cryptid none of
which is using
standard for Parker fee most the which
is using anonymity
hide behind and ultimately we have a lot
of
combinations here between the visible
net and the Internet
to access so what are the attackers
trying to focus on
here's what we see almost the number one
area the attackers will do first
the offense a model typically starts
going after high-tech
almost all the cases that we see the
large campaigns that are launched
most of them came from an attack on
high-tech sector first
what do I mean by that typically it
happened where
a startup company a cloud based company
whether
an Adobe or no work or microsoftr Apple
or Google or something like that or
smaller company
appt for put in place to go after
critical source code
about some sort of digital trust
certificate something to gain access
for the core of the application as as
on known as possible once we have access
to that we can start to put technology
in place that has much longer
persistency
than any other types of malware that
could be used
so huge number the attack vectors we're
seeing measured in hundreds and hundreds
the company's
come from this type of attack gain
access to the bug database
source code learn how to load DLL try to
do something that enables it to be
are invisible to the the current systems
levers that vulnerability
use an exclusive or some sort
polymorphic technique
and then stage in overtime
maybe in the first instance its use to
download the exploit weeks up a couple
weeks later
it takes another command and then all
tingly creating
a multi-stage the pack over a period of
time sometimes lasting
years as we move forward so what are
they ultimately do you
the leverage it across multiple
fractures in the architecture
I can come in through five different
domains weekend the sea
a lot of it is now moved into the
bring-your-own-device Syria your
smartphone
where some cider take on device this
area is probably most prevalent today
particularly with the Google platform I
think we're now up over ninety percent
the attacks were emanated from the
from the Android platform into a spear
fish
not just with the email but now into the
mobile of course it's attacking and
multiple areas and what's happened is
that national
architecture that we have is exploited
because these products don't work well
together
they don't communicate from one to
another and it creates
holes in the architecture as we move
forward pretty interesting
scenario if you look at the types of
attacks that occur
these are the stages we typically see
stage 1
drop in explain in understand how to get
it to a unique individual in the room
load that exploit down to your device
put it memory
start to communicate back to a
command-and-control server
low-down cryptography work back and
forth with a command-and-control server
that alternately crepe cryptid data
exfiltration commands
that's creates probably most powerful
own ultimately they're going to reach
that my work they can
and then create valor potential login we
get the combination
getting the exploit in erasing them our
and then walking in
validly for a long period of time
recreates the architecture we have today
on average 243 days unknown
a pretty interesting model keeps
evolving with these attackers
this is a global cyber threat map kinda
illustrate the picture
you can see in the back this map here
shows how many command-and-control
servers for monitoring every day
we're now up to about 60 million
command-and-control servers globally
all using the Dark Knight components
that I described earlier
most the which are using APT's to talk
back and forth to the servers
I on an average day we're seeing someone
a neighborhood a few hundred thousand
new exploits occur someone a
neighborhood a few million
command-and-control server
communications and it targets summer
neighborhood
of I think it's ninety percent
in high tech sector initially and then
openly emanating out
from multiple verticals so she kinda
watch this map occur
you'll start to see that this ATT model
that we're using is coming across over
200 countries as well
a pretty powerful combinations where
multi-stage the tax
coming in lasting for 100 today's
coming across the globe hundreds of
thousands have unique communications
and of course most of the earth is very
difficult to track who the actual
address serious
you can see some the numbers that are up
there
one particular point to make sixty-seven
percent of what we tracked
were from known good command-and-control
servers as well
this is the their own website in some
cases the first hop
is often a waterhole website from the
company that's being infected
we've made a couple those are famous was
from the blog but
in the case for like a target or some
others the actual sleep the website
itself was actually the launch point
for the command-and-control server
activity initially that ultimately
became a dark nat type a command and
control server
up give you a kind of idea of summer the
APT campaigns that we're seeing
across-the-board high-tech that the
fence
for telecom and so forth these APT's
common across many verticals won their
first deployed
from you probably know go Strathearn
couple others a
be bustle talk about the second but
they're very migratory for once we see
even one
sector will seem kinda crossed many many
industries in a pretty quick period of
time
here's the example I just mentioned
operation the bus
now some you know this the bus this was
on the defense industrial base
about a year ago or so it was targeted
the UAV use this is the unmanned aerial
vehicles
they are attack initially came in from
China
initially linked with the PT 1 but the
idea there was the Spearfish
getting APTN steal from the AutoCAD the
repository
can access the UAV information and then
ultimately we've now seen that activity
permeate in
replicated you a vis in the marketplace
in China with some %uh their defense
industrial base
and of course the idea there is to keep
up with the latest defense technology
up five stages attack mobile hops a
command-and-control servers
several hundred days undetected and
ultimately arriving in
a very successful attack Matt mechanism
we look at the big four superpowers just
the kinda wrap it up in summary here
you'll see
we have a lot happening in the China
were Jim
we have twenty two groups were tracking
across the Army Navy
I People's Liberation Army for bureau
and my sass
these organizations are highly focused
in on are
areas of espionage in activity rarely do
we see
for crime activities related to dollars
and financials
most the activity is to feed the
emerging markets
in the middle east we're seeing similar
to these Russia similar activities
not most of which are gaining momentum
every couple weeks every couple months
and resulting in pretty successful
attacks officer look at the Chinese
playbook a little closer
you'll see not only is the activities
focused
entirely on innovation and high-tech
but now it's pretty viral around the
world as well not just on the US markets
were seen incredible man are actively in
Japan problem
activity in Germany are some other
higher innovation countries
lots of focus in that region
and you start to look at the strategy
low-profile
the night bility trying to orchestrate
this across
schemes and of course a lot of pretty
known attacks have occurred
and a pretty quick period of time
something which I I mentioned her
these are some other famous hackers that
were indicted in the %uh Pittsburgh
federal court
summer which are very active to this day
none of which will actually see a court
I'm sure
parts are pretty interesting for the
first time in history were seen the
indictment
Chinese military officers my opinion
will see an equal and opposite reaction
occur from time in the next couple
months
we've already gone see it pipe this
event here will create
a pretty interesting whiplash back
the US markets in my opinion we look at
russia
somewhere activity tremendous activity
focused on crime
what's the focus coming out of the
Ukrainian markets crimean markets
russian businessmen network markets in
saint petersburg
lot of focus and on high arm
high-volume low dollar types of
activities
prickly with the equity markets credit
card market step occurred markets
a lot of %uh interesting personnel
involved here
I want my favorite to our summer the pot
notes that were brought down
and a particular letter that was used
public can see it back there but
om this was a letter back the fire I
after we brought down their botnet
and of course what's the saying I what
are you doing
why are you bringing down the spot nap
you have no ability to affect
the about the outcome assessors no
criminal prosecution were protected by
the government
and I'll this is a waste of time
basically so interesting to watch
the protectionism that's occurring from
the government's in most of these
criminal activities
and another example of that we just
watched with target and a few other
major retailers Middle East some more
much more focused on kind of
geopolitical activities
we've seen a tremendous amount
affectively coming from the FTA
recently on as well as Ajax security
group in Iran
against sabotage focused lot of activity
targeted towards hi sensationalism
critical infrastructure
I cannot focus on our destruction as
much as possible
we've seen a number these from these are
pretty famous you probably know I'm
routes gas around
around coast from the more radical
bodies that occurred as well
and most recently the casino
so do you think about all this activity
that's occurring you know what we
flaming
highly persistent actors highly
polymorphic activities
leveraging all these new domains that
are occurring multi-stage the tax
very interesting you know zero-day type
celebrity from source code and high-tech
actors
environments and ultimately crated a
very different threat landscape
over the next few years and we've been
seeing in the past
so part when I try to communicate when I
come to these events
is how do we think about changing the
way in which we do security
how do we begin tonight the communities
that we have together
products won't solve this we won't be
able to close the gap immediately with a
product
but if we can improve the learnings and
the people on the expertise
couple that with the products put
together a better process
we probably can close the gap a little
closer and we have today
so with that I just wanna say I think
we're seeing a change occur
a pretty big shift I think we have to
reimagine summer this
this is what we're trying to do if I
rise focus and on a whole new generation
of technology
using virtual machines the idea there is
to create a much stronger learning
environment for attacks
not only know what's going on from known
attacks but also unknown is your day
typeof attacks and be able to put these
working machines
in nearly every area of the architecture
from the web
email profile to mobile and ultimately
through 10 points
if we can put a different type of model
than any virus in place and have it
learn from each other
we can probably create a better
architecture to be
proactive with the intelligence be much
faster at the attack learning
and then labor sat across the globe
quickly
so we believe that creates a a nice
change from where we were before
with antivirus corrected
get still there all right thank you very
much I really appreciate it
and thanks for your time alright here
ok cool
I get official t-shirt shirt thank you
knife
I read baghdad from
fire Edgar carriers have to get nowhere
I well i were now
what up through the questions were up
and then we can answer up
love up