hello everybody I am Vladimir and one of
the authors of this talk and the topic
we supposed to talk about it's travel so
how many of you live in Amsterdam okay
so everybody else supposed to travel to
this conference will travel quite a lot
and this talk is about a romantic
profession of hackers and how we spend
your free time so we split it took in
several sections something like a hacker
point of view something like a victim
point of view some suggestions how to
fight with this kind of fraud so like if
you travel quite often you can be a
victim of a travel fraud and sometimes
you never know about this so because we
are eager to buy like very cheap tickets
and save some money and hacker know this
we created sometimes underground travel
agencies sometimes it's really looks
like a real agencies but on the
background we use stolen credit cards or
something so it's quite quite easy to be
a victim of a travel throat wherever you
take in taxi buying airline tickets or
reserved reserving a hotel so let's talk
about the reasons why where is a market
demand for travel fraud so you know the
process of reservation tickets on the
underground agencies is like for example
if you need a flight you can send like I
want to go from Amsterdam to Bangkok
with business class next week for a week
so this cost like if this airline about
like three thousand dollars what can you
offer and the hackers came back and give
you usually like between forty and
seventy percent discount and actually
this is a feedback from the customer so
we flew
with business-class a river price which
is equal to the equator of the price of
the normal economy fare so underground
travel agents are quite flexible and you
shouldn't clean up your money so like we
often accept bitcoins we didn't ask like
where you get money and so on
so let's you what on the ground offer to
us so like what what travelers need so
when you travel what do you need
actually what about you
what do you need when passport money and
what so what about hotel all flights
airport transfers some food some
entertainment so actually everything is
available on the underground market so
like this is one of the bundles of
travel agencies this is like a head
traveler and this is an advertisement of
underground travel agencies on
russian-speaking on the ground forum so
basic services what is basic like when
you go into the travel agency you're
supposed to buy tickets or flight
you're supposed to reserve hotel
sometimes transfer so what about
agencies on the underground it's
actually the same so it's like 35
percent from the normal price for the
hotels about 40 50 percent of the normal
price for the flights and haida scones
are starting from $1000 and here for
example you can see countries like
Thailand Greece keeper dominicana
Emirates and like a special offer to
tours to Israel so and this is not about
russian-speaking market the problem
exists globally and where are some
flavors of particular markets but
everywhere you can buy you can buy like
flights hotel
and taxes and here you can see like on
Arabic English and Arabic speaking forum
like offers for booking hotels and
flights among many our interesting
authors so what about hotels so like for
the hotels hackers prefer some fancy
rooms so like we'd wait don't try to
save like small amount of money so we
can spend like thousand dollars but
sometimes we spend this money like to
order all villas which really cost like
five thousand per day or so on Chinese
market we can see like offers for famous
brands or Russians market Russian
markets mostly about all-in-one and like
customer comfortable offers so for
example here you can see like a telegram
channel dedicated to the travel and like
the price for the hotels is 30% of the
real price flights 50% and very
interesting exception we didn't sell
flights over Russia so the thing you can
see on many underground forums and among
many criminal groups with malware so
like which mobile malware doesn't work
in Russia and Russian speaking country
and so on on some agencies you can see
the similar trends for the travel
services and here you can see a happy
customer
we've quite interesting a rented car and
I'm not sure if like person an 18 or 20
years I can offer this kind of car for
rent with normal price so when you land
in the airport so yesterday I took a
taxi and I paid 60 euros for airport
transfer so what how much should I pay
if I do it with underground sir
so for example you can see like uber
trips for free use there for 40 minutes
or over black like more fancy cars for
10 years after 2 hours flight in our
agency a which called like looks taxi
world offer taxes over the world and the
prices is like for Mercedes s-class it's
about 12 dollars or like $15 per hour
Airport transfer is like 100 or more and
for cheaper car it's very very very
interesting prices so you can watch the
prices in the real world and on the
underground services so what's the basic
services but what Elsa we need so as you
said we need travel documents so travel
documents sometimes is I use it for a
Cardian fraud so it's very popular thing
like a scans of documents which
sometimes required to register account
on each shop or on social networks
skins of documents with your pictures so
what percentage holding a passport and
what's the way how you can recover
password for example for a key social
network in Russia but with so many our
things like stolen passports on the sale
and very interesting Phoenix like
European passports where you can provide
your personal data it will be passport
on the real blank but it not supposed to
be on the citizens that database so as
long as police or border control doesn't
check you on like electronic base it's a
legit document and here you can see a
driver licenses for a higher this is
Russian driving less isn't licenses and
here is very fancy Fein you know what is
a green card in the US so how many
people want to get a green card I think
like many people playing in lottery but
this is an
offer to vin green card without chance
to lose so you pay around $900 for the
service and you pay when you want so
what's one of the interesting offer in
our offer is here
it's a blocking access to Russia for the
travelers so you have a neighbor you
have a like a competitor which you don't
like so you can spend like $800 on the
Russian on the ground and next time when
first of all travel to kind of sport
competition over ever it will be
arrested on the border we'll spend some
times on the border control and when
extradited like to - to the initial
country so what's the fancy services you
can find does anybody familiar what is
like commercial important person what is
difference between VIP and CIP anybody
from China from Asia nobody okay so like
VIP it could be like president of the
country so he's supposed to be in the
lunch but he not always supposed to pay
for this and commercial important person
it's not it's money pocket so it's a
person who are ready to spend money for
the luxury vacations of something or for
the launch in the airport so you can see
like offer like launch access and like
special services at the airport for
commercial important persons in China
guided tours so like as long as you land
somewhere you want to have very
interesting trip somewhere to see
surroundings and the normal price on the
underground it's about 25 percent of the
normal price sometimes you request
available offers sometimes you can just
point I need this tour which cost
like hundred bucks and pay just 250 and
of course where we are interesting notes
like we doesn't work in Russia and Nixie
uses our and my minimal price is five
thousand roubles it's about eighty
eighty or ninety dollars we have a good
reputation like we working more than
four years Oh
every client is very valuable for them
so like this this is a business and this
is like a not hop on and hop off
business its long-term business with so
many travel agencies which were click
from thousand fifteen four thousand to
two thousand fifteen two thousand
fourteen and we still have good
reputation and we're still providing
services for the clients so here you can
see a feedback from I think with two V
two or three weeks ago and of March VIP
tours Jamaica so what's one of the happy
customers of underground services so
food so food is cheap in some countries
but doesn't cheap in our countries so
for example I think in California it's
sometimes cheaper to buy jeans instead
of pay for pizza so for this kind of
cases you can buy gift cards from the
restaurants or legality points we've
we've did coins or sometimes if just
cards or electronic payment systems so
you can see you like Pizza Hut Domino's
Pizza restaurants and many hours because
we have a plenty of offers for this kind
of services entertainment so everybody
likes cinema or so here you can buy like
access for VIP rooms in in cinema you
can do it with telegram so chill
is really hardly abuse it with
underground actors and I would say but
like it's kind of trend like IRC when
underground forums and everybody now
moving to telegram
so telegram allows like secret chats so
people can communicate instantly and
very fast and secure way we can promote
your services and if you look into
telegram groups you can see like a tenth
of counted people on the groups related
to the underground topics so here here
like it cars forged taxi and tickets for
the cinema which cost less than two
dollars so this is example of one of the
shops offer related to the travel
industry so it's I price is not in u.s.
dollar sexually it's in roubles you have
to divide on something about like sixty
five or seventy so it's like cinema
Burger King occur hotels want to trip
and several offers for taxis and a lot
of precautions for the customers and we
will touch this topic again a bit later
so this agency sales like very cheap
spins and you can see all in ones like
air tickets hotels autos concerts a lot
of bonuses and of course precaution so
currency is Google translated that's why
English may be improper and sometimes
and sometimes it's really fun to read
English version so and this service
accept bitcoins and it's work to
guarantee guarantor service so tickets
to this lenient available on
english-speaking market a lot of abuses
of Ticketmaster way you can buy
wherever you want in the terms of
entertainment and of course very
interesting point about legality
programs of airlines hotels over ever so
along the flights or hotel stays you can
use loyalty points for gift cards or to
buy almost everything you need for the
travel so if you don't found something
what you need on the underground you can
do you can just buy point like a loyalty
points and transfer it to wherever you
want
very interesting service so sometimes
you can do everything electronically
sometimes you have to have for example
paper tickets or anything
so where is underground Postal Service
which will deliver you like stolen
credit card tickets or wherever you want
it's a Pruitt on the several underground
forums you can pay only after delivery
so you don't spend money if service
doesn't work and we accept like a lot of
payment systems like like like your
cards from Yandex TV which is like very
popular electronic payment systems in
Russia so what what we can see like how
happy are travelers with services so
after after making the trip sometimes
seller offer a special offers like extra
discounts for the travelers for the
video reviews and people pushing video
reviews like in the airport in the
hotels over ever and promoting nickname
or any contacts of the seller and get an
extra discount so you can see how people
drink beer and cocktails and same happy
and same saying thank you for for this
travel agent from this underground
Tector
so you can see Hilton hotel room you can
see KP traveller to Miami and his he
climbs like where is no questions from
the stuff you just get in the keys and
you are in the room everything is happy
so since since I'm living in Munich so I
found a Munich hotel and a lot of beer
from happy traveler to Minich and bura
a lot of our things like like like you
you can you can see like the best travel
agents you can see like made two hotels
in Italy and this is like suits in Rome
Italy and you can see like nickname of
the actor who sells and like who travel
so technically like somebody can track
the actors for travel and this is a
special gift so this this message climbs
like one of my customers who buy it a
lot ask it to send roses to cure to his
girlfriend in France so and this is the
result of the underground travel agency
to make a special gift for the girl in
our country and I think like a lot of
like a woman's like this kind of size of
the gift I would say so so but sometimes
we can see people afraid about quality
of service and we offer to put some
deposit from the underground Tector and
this is like a book and ticket or
reserved ticket but it is just a Google
Translate as we see like like and person
says like everything can happen so
sometimes you will be unable to jump
into the plane or sometimes you come to
the hotel and what will ask you to
provide a credit
card which you can use it for booking
and so on so not only not not every
travel and if happy end so here you can
see example like when traveler was
asking about credit card and he was
unable to jump into the airport and this
is actually abused so it's called
arbitrage on the underground service on
the other ground forum when not happy
customers
I can feel abuse form and when forum
forum moderators at this site were ever
sellers should return money or shouldn't
so this is one of the keys of unhappy
travelers this is another unhappy
customer so he tried to buy tickets four
times and every time like a ticket was
both but when canceled it
by the airline so what actually on the
background says with it's not matter
underground actor with just which just
use a stolen credit card and try to buy
tickets directly on the travel agency so
what's the Fein which doesn't work
actually because many agencies have
anti-fraud system and attacker is
supposed to use more complicated schemes
to buy a ticket
so writers so as long as one agents you
have a pretty good reputation on the
underground forum and we announce your
contacts for example for the telegram
you can see how a viewer like twins
appears on the telegram or somewhere and
steal the money from a customer and ruin
the reputation so this is the climb on
the underground forum where person tried
to both something and seller says I have
a telegram without logo or avatar here
and whatever you contact it wasn't me
and when a during the discussion you can
see a proof how many like a duplicate on
the telegram so in our opinion on the
travel agency it's a part of the service
advertisement and this is a very big
note at the bottom so this is so please
note my telegram and is this and you can
see L at the end it's a real account and
be afraid because where is a twin
account which will steal your money so
like I think like this usually happened
after several abuses from the unhappy
customers so for example here like it's
like hi I'm Sasha and what's with my
money where is my money
are you ignore me you write me what why
you ignore me and when it's like where
is my mommy money on the cycle so this
is like a voice of the victim maybe we
can make short break
if videos catch it I can show you like a
feedback from happy travelers so so so
so this guy claims like I'm flying over
Russia so it's very rare service and
thank you ok thank you for tickets ok so
this is the same seller and a video
review of the hotel room so it's like
watching thank you for the hotel and you
can see the room size the room location
and like what was on the room so and the
room doesn't look very very cheap so
sometimes you can see Vilas sometimes
you can see cars which costs like
several
hundred thousand dollars sometimes
people flying like on the business class
or first class over ever so I think it's
small school and Moscow State University
on the big stage so it's like hackers
from suburbs coming to the capital or
wherever here here is another review
from kilogram channel or people just
confirming the quality of services but
whatever like what happened on the
background so what hackers doing to
provide these kind of services so if you
look into english-speaking market in
Chinese market it's more about like
building blocks for all-in-one services
so you can buy for example account with
miles for particular airline like horses
like from SkyTeam or like Star Alliance
or ever you can buy something like
sometimes like a gold status for Hilton
Hotel and for Russia it's totally
different so it's like a real travel
agencies with 24/7 support on telegram
or on the phone so we reach you cancel
it tickets sometimes we saw like seller
come to the airport to bring you tickets
for the victim of anti-fraud system
because a victim was unable to jump into
the plane and ticket has been canceled
data after ticket in so on on the ground
you can say you can find the things
called manuals or step-by-step guides so
here you can see manual for uber for
short trips for long trips
this is like hotels and flights and
features and concerts and car rental so
it's a step by step guides on the sales
after people buying this as long as
usually itself - just several buyers so
for example Goodman old never sells like
for hundreds of people it's usually
sells like two three or five cans and as
long is it not went to the very very big
scale people doing were like 10 or 20
thousand dollars per month and we are
happy so and we can see confirmation of
an hour fein when hackers hacks into
travel agencies portals portals and book
tickets on behalf of a legit legend a
travel agency so and this news climb but
it happened so hackers stole a trip for
forty seven thousand trouble roubles is
just some hundred dollars but the same
happened before and the same happened
all the time and now we're very
interesting abuse it's kind of business
process compromise when people hack it
into the travel agencies and we both a
train tickets and when went to to the
cash desk of train service and return
tickets for real money
so we earn money like well spending
nothing and the amount was about like
fifty thousand US dollars at the time in
our approach like how people think about
committing the fraud so it's not not
something criminal it's the way how we
abuse like a special sales from Airlines
so for example this is a sale from
Russian this counter discuss it and you
can buy tickets for eight USD per trip
tickets not returnable not refundable
but you can pay
like 80 bucks to change the name on the
ticket so what why do we found the
customer closer to the newer event we
sell a ticket like 30 times 30 times
higher price we spend like around like
less 100 bucks to fix the ticket and we
earn like extra like 150 bucks per
ticket and technically there is nothing
criminal in this scheme because
everything is legit
everything is a little bit bye-bye
airline so but not not not metric not
metal reactors usually a stolen credit
card and it's like uber doesn't work so
I think you can do me an hour trip and
it's okay
because you don't spend your money and
guys say no I'm just using stolen credit
cards from an hour supplier so I'm
spending money on stolen credit cards I
can I can't arrange you another right
what's your problem
so and like where a lot of confirmations
about attacks on the booking systems
like Sabra and like in our in our
reservation systems which exist and
actually the volume of the fraud it's
like several billions US per year so but
the problem is like I think as long as
the volume of the fraud lower when fraud
resistant rate so what's the term people
use it in the industry which is usually
about like six or five percent often
nobody cares about this because we just
put these risks with risks on the price
so this is a funny thing you know like
if you use uber or like in another taxi
application you you you have one
application and taxi driver have another
one so what hacker did we patch it
alleged a patient for Yandex taxi and we
sell it on the underground market so for
example if you're a taxi driver you're
unable to call
the customer and lives you are 50 meters
away from keys location so we fix it if
we fix it fake GPS detection so
customers can be charged more when we
write we we we fix it the function which
required a regular car review so if you
provide like a bmw x5 car as a taxi you
have to send a regular photos of this
car like to renew your application in
your validity like a taxi driver for
Yandex we fix it this thing and we fix
it a lot of things like whatever you
don't know what what your victim of the
fraud you can be victim of this kind of
applications use it by not fair driver
drivers I would say so of course like it
could be like GPS spoofing and it's easy
you can see several science but it's
already happened on the scale and in in
several parts of the world so what about
airline loyalty programs so like people
consider miles it's not the money but
for hackers it's a real money and you
can see were like is sales on us
speaking market like particular accounts
with miles or dedicated shops for a
airline it counts on the Russian
underground market so you can where
people can buy like a building blocks to
commit travel fraud the same situation
is with photos so wherever you take any
famous brand you can see underground
offers for abusing loyalty programs of
these hotels so you can see like Hilton
you can see like hotels come ihd
accounts the same is for car rental
companies so sometimes it's offers to
sell loyalty points sometimes it's
offers to sell something like a gold
status where you can
get a free upgrade of the car or extra
days or something and it's valid like
not only for six six ten years but for
many hours other agencies so regard
according to the problems with telegram
in Russia so russian government try try
to force telegram to provide encryption
keys for the chats and as long as this
news came some of the travel operators
from the underground of the Tikaram give
a manual how to use VPN with telegram
both which made AV p.m. to maintain
availability of the service while you
travel if telegram will be blocked so
another interesting thing with sometimes
mentioned it's a corporate rate for the
hotels so if you google for images like
corporate codes this is a Google images
you can found a corporate codes for
different corporations and you can get
extra discount sometimes it's like 30
percent sometimes it's 50 percent or so
so this thing is abusive but what was I
afraid about this and we aware about
this so we can ask you for ID from the
company you work for and what's the
problem yes oh no you can buy fake IDs
on Chinese speaking market for like way
very cheap prices like 1 RMB and you can
find IDs like for this case a General
Electric here you can see a disclaimer
from Siemens about abuse of corporate
rate erase for the hotel so what's
really a big problem but it's almost
untold so what like victims can can do
with this kind of problems so if it's
corporates we can use a travel fraud
systems which is obviously and it's
obviously works
but not for every case and another
suggestion like look for the bookings
from VPN from tour notes from strange
locations and in our teens we did like
to detect incidents before when I work
at incident response team we do data
analysis of everything we have so like
if you have like several cases about
fraud try to find some similarities and
do manual rules for your anti-fraud
system and of course know your customer
like but it's about what happened with
Cambridge analytic are we know the
customers so it's like a quite a
dangerous feel dangerous thing so if
you're just a normal traveler just
double check the reputation of the
agency and not try to buy like really
Bergen deals until you confirm it's
legit and protect your accounts so never
use like once you free Croisette
password for your airline accounts or
like for like reality points from the
hotel
so generally I'm done if you have any
questions
okay we're waiting for a microphone can
can you can you tell the company name
you walk for before you ask a question
yeah Bokan okay I'm reading between the
lines because it's it's a very
interesting topic I have a question
about the loyalty points do you see any
other way to get loyalty points
besides account takeovers I think
vulnerabilities on like sites of travel
agencies it's an hour point as long as
you happen to like that database you can
make a count and just change the amount
of coins and or use them to increase
them you mean yes yes in our way like
you can check over account by
brute-forcing or you can check your
account by intercepting open Wi-Fi in
the hotels or in the airports or you can
do it use it like a phishing campaign so
where are a lot of options to do this
any other question so nobody from Airbnb
where is one question on this row and if
Airbnb IVA was an interesting story
where was a campaign from Russian bank
with like a secret promotion code for I
think like a MasterCard black card
holders and somebody leaked at this code
and Airbnb were forced to come sell a
lot of existing Buchan because it was
abused by underground criminals because
it's supposed to be very private code
like for several customers or like
several hundred customers but it went
into the scale but Airbnb was unable to
fourth yes your question yes just wanted
to say jurors you can get much better
prices if you just make a run for it
like you use the service and then
instead of paying they just run away
so it's up to you actually I'm not used
my company please no just for this level
but I travel reviews from the real
customers of this kind of services you
can split it into several categories so
one is the script kiddies and flights
are often often cancel it or like people
ask it like to provide credit cards or
any other evidence of payment but in our
travel agency has like hundred of
several hundred of positive reviews and
just a couple of cases which has been
fixed to the arbitrage so we use in our
means of booking which LOM to keep a
book in active if you look into the
process usually many agencies suggest to
book your flight just three or four days
before the travel and for many agencies
wait doesn't book you a return flight
unless you land and spend a couple of
days in the hotel but it was a tricky
situation and was discussion on the
arbitral section when one of the person
flew into something like seashells
spender like 12 days and decided to get
back in to next days he tried to contact
on the ground forum seller but seller
was on vacation and person hangs up for
several X a day trying to get if almost
free tickets and when both tickets like
for a couple thousands of dollars
because there was no options and wrote
and abuse on the underground forum and
you have a question
hello I do you see any kind of
prosecution against the clients like for
example if I'm going to an airport to
get it a plane by this way is there any
chance that there because it was with a
fake credit card or fake logic no at the
points is some airline or credit card
companies are actually prosecuting the
client so if you're looking to the news
where was several arrests of the actors
who sell and if you look into the
negative comments for the travel
underground travel agencies the worst
thing you usually see like I was forted
forced to pay for this night in the
hotel because was I was unable to
[Music]
provide evidence of means of payment so
usually it's not ends up we've arrest or
something so as long as person pay for
the first night here what abused to
underground travel agency and this
agency just booked in our hotel in the
same location from the next day for
example so and the same is for flights
so usually we have like 24/7 support and
we get back with new flights in several
hours software abuse questions anybody
from Airlines here okay how did you
travel here
I spent 190 euros for the trip it was
economy flight which was one a half hour
so it was the normal price
but if you supposed to travel somewhere
quite far away if you try to buy
something on the Underground you can do
it cheap of an economy on the business
class but double check the reputation
and I'm not suggest to do this because
it's not like I love it by local laws
usually but where are some processes
which which are quite leggett or it's
kind of gray gray area does anybody need
like URLs or dorks
because here I think like nothing is
hided you can see sometimes you can see
URLs for forums or you can use a
keywords or a almost or hide almost
everything so you can look by nicknames
by travel operators of happy travelers
just to Google this because it's not on
the hydrant sections of the forum's so
everybody can found like the services
they want if we want okay one more
question one more from organizers yeah
organizers actually cover flights and we
can ask organizers go away buy tickets
yes sorry you keep saying we during your
presentation what what is your active
part in that so actually it's a style
how Russian speaks so it's more like a
lack of English knowledge maybe and I'm
saying if you are usually definitely if
and if it's usually beginning of the
phrase if somewhere I miss it sorry I'm
not intent intent to do this
thank you for this question yeah
[Applause]