hello everybody welcome welcome to my
talk about
scepter so first off who am i I'm useful
diet and I work as a research analyst
for large c-cert and so this is a hobby
project of mine which I would like to
share with you so in my spare time I'm a
demo senior make music with electronic
devices and I have a hobby and
electronics officially embedded systems
engineer but day-to-day work I add more
more of the IT security essentially so
[Music]
today we're gonna talk we're gonna start
with with existing existing USB you
human input device tax I'm gonna tell
you what's wrong with them because they
are not optimal and there's there are
some available protections we will cover
those and we will have a look at how to
bypass these and yeah by showing my
proof of concept and the whole reason
for for this presentation the whole
reason why I wanted to look at this at
this topic is well we have to raise some
awareness on USB devices I mean we've
seen the rubber ducky and such well I
think I guess you all know why we should
have a look at this so let's let's start
a brief history so the earliest
mentioning mention of USB key loggers
that I could find was from 2005 if
anybody knows an older product please
let me know then there's a gap we jump
to 2010 and we see the first the first
key stroke injectors essentially so in
the same year iron geek also known as
Adrian Crenshaw created his funny
name
essentially teensie the dusky keystroke
injection and hak5 brings brings robbery
buggy to the market and the year after
Adrienne combines his earlier keylogger
research with with the rubber ducky kind
of attack the keystroke injector then in
2014 we get the the the interesting
research done by Carson Knoll and & Co
the bet USB so reprogramming the
controllers on on USB devices mainly
mass storage devices to introduce
different kind of functionality like
network interfaces and such and Samy
Kamkar shows his USB drive by which
essentially is a keystroke injector with
the mouse emulation as well and then we
have some research by David k-zone ski
I'm really bad with that name sorry
probably pronounce it right not right
USB - essentially - two devices with a
intermediate PC in between that controls
the the protocol stuff also also
primarily focusing on human input device
and last year we've seen the Bosch bunny
essentially emulating all kinds of
devices and well having the opportunity
to program it freely makes it makes it a
versatile hacker tool and the cactus
wireless keystroke injector what they
all have in common is that they are
pretty in your face I mean if you sit
behind a machine plug it in and you see
weird stuff happening you will probably
shut your computer throw away throw out
the device and call a call the help desk
or something
so you either need to need to have a an
unlock machine on a tablet computer or
be very good in social engineering to
make it a make it a success and next to
that many payloads require internet
access for example to set up refer shell
and let's have a look at the things that
could block this kind of attacks this is
what what I found out we've got some
hardware protectors the use good from
Robert Fisk it's an interesting thing
USB device a USB dongle that sits in
between your mass storage device or
keyboard and your host it is interesting
because it protects protects against
some of the of the attacks so it was
meant to block the the bad USB kind of
attacks so if I plug in a USB stick that
later on reconfigures itself as a
different device it will detect it so
essentially this device Syria numeration
so that's the process where so normally
if you plug in a USB device in a house
it does we do use the enumeration to see
which devices are there and if it
presents itself while connected as a
different device that gets gets blocked
so in order to bypass this we have to
have the functionality within the device
without reconfiguring
then there's USB proxy from Dominic's
bill it's a bit faster than the USD that
USD is very slow it's really like less
than USB one speeds so I think it's even
noticeable if you connect the keyboard
you it's even noticeable when you type
so that's it's - really too slow
then on the software side of things we
have a USB guard from Danielle Koh
paycheck from Red Hat yeah he created an
extension to you deaf - on Linux of
course - to have a user interface where
you can allow or block connected USB
device so as soon as I plug in a
keyboard or a nice storage device I will
get a pop up on my screen that says hey
is this a good device or not and like
like a personal firewall you can you can
choose whether it's okay or not good dog
is a non mass-storage kind of class USB
cloth protector on windows and then
there's beam gun which which also block
stroke USB network adapters and hits
that doesn't work in all cases so
finally we have the USB key word guard
that warns you when when a new hit is
connected so it will block all
keystrokes until you click the button
it's allowed we have duck-hunt it's it's
another kind of thing it's not filter
used to be filtering cross filtering
device a piece of software but a
superhuman typing detector so if you
really type fast there's probably
something something going on there are
exceptions though if you use a Yubikey
or something like that
it's meant to type things fast and we
have dr sec your security patches for
the linux kernel which allows
to block devices that are being plugged
into your computer after it has been
booted so my my idea about the implant
is that we would have a human input
device attack that works with lock
machines and that can bypass the
described protection mechanisms and in
order to be yeah well for it to be
feasible to really being used in real
world scenarios I thought it would be
good to have a cheap small and coverton
coverton operations so the design
requirements I had was the implant
should be in line with the with the
machine so it should really be an
implant on an inside of a keyboard and
it should have some notes of time and
you will see later on why that is
I had to spice it up a bit it would be
nice to have some other channel
communication channel to off the air for
example to to communicate with it
and have some control over it you might
recognize this this thingy from the from
the NSA catalog it's not going to be
that small essentially not because it's
a proof-of-concept so what I came up
with this essentially a host adapter
that lets you connect a USB device to to
that a computer so it's actually a
microcontroller with a USB device
support so that it can read relay stuff
a real time clock that has battery
backed not a notion of time a
communications module in my case a 4 33
megahertz UART and an EEPROM to store
store config stuff so non file volatile
run
this is what I came up with it's a bit
big it's a bit bulky but well it's proof
concept right and I could ditch the the
EEPROM because the the the teensy
controller has has an option for it but
you get to get the idea
the the house to use we housed the
microcontroller the brains the
communications module with a antenna the
clock battery-backed clock and the
configuration built into printed case so
first off how to bypass the the flaw the
use usb policy kind of protections so
let's take use B card from Daniel cope I
check as a as a as a reference you could
simply clone use B descriptors that's
it's not very hard so this proof concept
doesn't clone it lively that would be
really convenient but if you know for
example if you want to infiltrate in a
company they probably have some brand
being used primarily and you could
easily clone that kind of device it's
just a matter of going to the shop clone
that scripture and you can present
yourself as that device it's a bit of a
yeah I had a bit of tweaking time on it
so first off its it shows itself as a
full USB ESP device but had to downgrade
it to a low-speed device and once you're
really done so the way USB card works it
just dumps your complete use be a
descriptive table and make a hash of it
so once you miss one bite of one bit you
already you already get got caught by
the program so I literally make a copy
of it
and then bypass the the the superhuman
typing detection kind of demons we just
introduced on random delays so I use the
the arduino environment because it's
really easy and simple to quickly
prototype stuff to create a new kind of
so you saw that it was well typed in one
second that's the superhuman type typing
that I meant I created new a kind of USB
profile essentially called Evo keyboard
that just clones the description table
to head that the clone scripted tables
and do the slow typing so here we see
that yeah it looks like human typing so
it will not be triggering at superhuman
typing detections so ducking for example
so when I started I thought let's
measure power because we cannot go
beyond the limitations so normally for a
for keyboard it would be 100 milliamps
max if you look at the specifications so
I stay with under under the radar it's
100 milliamps max but this device was
it's crap it's it's not very accurate so
I did some reassuring this has better
this was better insight in how it's
actually the power consumption is doing
so the plane keyboard is very low then
we go to around 30 milliamps for a
keyboard with the bright LEDs on key and
receptor is even using more if we have
three LEDs on the on the keyboard we're
still under the power consumption of the
key intercepts but if we have the key
interceptor and the keyboard we clearly
go up high so essentially we could
detect an implant
so if we look at the cost of the of this
proof concept of Keynes chapter it's
really affordable so we can check you
can check that so use cases well we can
control the keyboard over here because
we have a communications channel we can
do auto log-in with captured credentials
because it's in line with the with the
keyboard and the computer we can do
keystroke injections after activity with
the chosen time so let's say we know
that the office is open until 6 o'clock
and evening and after that it may be
activated we can block user input with
an hour of radiofrequency kill switch
for example for takedown I'll enter your
scenario here I chose to make it a bit
more complicated and spice it up with a
companion so what I did is I took a dell
power adapter and i inserted the nano
pie with a again with a 4 33 megahertz
communications whether the you arts
essentially a UMTS or for the dongle to
have a connection uplink and a power
block this allows me to do the following
here we have the the target let's say an
office building one place is the Quinta
chapter in between the kyboot and the
computer or have a keyboard prepared
that that's inside the the keyboard
itself we have the the power adapter
that can communicate with this device
the power adapter can also communicate
with a VPN server the VPN servers the
the hops outside where I can connect
with a laptop or with a mobile phone to
the to essentially reach reach out to
the machine to the
companion and well let's just show that
with a little video to give you an
impression
[Music]
them about some hard to please so let's
retry this
[Music]
sorry sorry for death guys sorry so who
in the audience here has a form of
protection on USB any hands
[Music]
yeah yeah explain up the place taffy
sorry there it goes
so we're at the evil Corp placing the
opinion
so first powering it needed up without
plugging it into the network then we
place the kids after in between the
keepers in the house
[Music]
and you'll notice that as soon as I
connected to the the end point will
start blink linking the let the LED will
indicate that it's requiring a
configuration and we'll send the
configuration through the opinion - yeah
interceptor I connect to the VPN
connection for my phone have 4G I opened
the application the interface of the
Interceptor and we see that the ETH era
was not defined yet or I mean I mean we
didn't get a DHCP lease and that's
because we didn't have an up a link yet
so we connected to a network wait a
while we get an IP address and we get to
choose either a time to tech frame or we
choose demo to make it activate more
quickly so that be down there to wait so
now it's configured the leg is not
linking anymore
this means that this sector is
configured it now has the IP address of
the companion so it it will reach out at
some point as you will see later on to
the companion
and and now we're good to leave so at
another location we we hook up the the
computer of 4G with a again with a VPN
connection once we're done we have the
ability to login to the companion and
start a listener we will start listener
on the left side and we'll start the
keystrokes never on the right side
because the keystrokes are sent over for
33 megahertz to the companion so the
listener is a called Lafayette II and
now we'll just wait for a connection and
decides we wait for the for the user to
to bind its desk as you can see we see
the use of typing near real-time
complete with timestamps so the track of
what the user is doing user locks his
machine goes to the toilet or something
returns to its desk type in his password
the kids chapter detects the key
combination to unlock the machine so it
knows at some point what they've got a
prize for this so now that we have
captured the credentials it goes into a
state that it waits for the user to be
gone it automatically locks in and will
start a payload the typing is slow and
it's a purpose because we're pretty sure
that the user is gone gone to the home
or something
and here we reuse the IP address that we
got from the kids separate because that
this is just the first stage and second
stage is here I mean I mean the actual
monitor control is done from the ok
window style hidden so it's gone logoff
and the computer well if the user
returns will not be very clear that the
mission is compromised this one says
it's done it got a signal that the
machine is part we see the top the price
with the sub top secrets and we got a
failure and we can do whatever we want
to teaching on the network and that
essentially is the
now the demo of the truth concept
so well you all know the post
exploitation stuff I guess that's not
very interesting
at this point
okay so new medications how to block
this kind of attack well essentially I
think the cleanest and the easiest way
to do this is to have a multi-factor
authentication each time you unlock your
machine or log into your machine it's a
bit of pain
of course a user will get backed by by
these extra questions but I think it
might be it might be worth doing it
depends on the situation if you are in a
high-security facility I think it's a
good idea the other one is profiling
monetary power consumption per device
but then again hardware support is a bit
problematic most laptops don't have a
way to see how many currents are drawn
from a from a USB port so just to see
whether that could work I created a
little proof concepts for that as well
so here we have a nother microcontroller
in a little box that just allows me to
plug in a device that just got groceries
relay to to the Machine and it just
monitors the current that goes through
the through the through the reports here
we have a monitoring a link and what we
can do we can define our maximum
milliamp per edge paired a kind of
device we have so here we have the
Packard Bell fuel Packard's elite
keyboards that I also used for the hit
cloning and use use big art shows that
there's a new new device which is USB
policy-wise allowed and and the use
cheap Powerman that I created that
communicates with the little box shows
that that everything is okay and if I
introduce the Interceptor
in between the keyboard and that port it
will be Beth because we use more than 13
milliamps more than we would expect so
then the Machine get blocked and it's
showed off with a different weather the
amber colored LED that works but it's
not very feasible for lots of course but
you could build in something like that
into a PC a full-blown PC or something
is it feasible I think so it yeah cost
some development time some lines of
curled some years to develop it but I
think it's very feasible there are some
future work we can see if it's I can
fill it in in real Hardware I'm pretty
pretty confident about that automatic
descriptor cloning will be doable as
well even maybe with a FPGA and the
encryption of the code of your
communications is also quite easy so I
think it's it's very feasible and we
should be thinking of ways to mitigate
and I think the operating systems having
some form of not factor that would be a
good starting point again are there any
questions yes so I brought my hardware
so I can give a full demo you can see
the hardware I can screw it open if you
want or whatever I will be in the corner
next to the heck in the box booth so if
you have prices you can come up to me as
well so thank you for your ok attention
and sorry for the delay
you