thank you very much for having me here
and thanks for a nice introduction
I was never linked to that movie before
probably also not so soon again but so I
have to enjoy it now so who have you
have worked and then some on something
that has to do with steganography in the
past 100 some of you that's quite
surprising usually I talk to people who
hear the word for the first time but I
introduced it very briefly so I have two
examples here pictures from Wikipedia on
the left side we have the classical
image hiding scenario so that care of
the pictures hidden in the image of the
tree and the 20 euro notes has a
watermark that's two forms of
information hiding but in general we try
to hide something in something else and
this is something that we can that we
hide can be basically everything it can
be code can be images texts can be
multimedia data can also be any form of
raw data so it's it's up to us what we
hide and the thing is in what can we
hide it well that list also gets longer
and longer
we can hide data and text and code in
multimedia files in executables in
network flows and block chains recently
someone did that meter data of basically
everything like file systems and
cyber-physical systems
I will pick two of these fields Network
flow data and cyber-physical systems so
first I will speak about introduction
the fundamentals for a few minutes of
steganography and information hiding
Dana will explain how it's done in these
two domains so in general what we have
to do and steganography is try to look
like something else
so we hide a message in some object and
check should look like something else
that's done in nature as well and called
mimicry and the the idea is that some
predator cannot decide between some some
prey and a not prey object so can I eat
it or can't I and animals try to look
like something else so that their
predators cannot detect that they are in
their reach for an attack during history
I don't go into all these details but in
ancient Greece development and
application of steganography already
started so people were hiding messages
on human skin using tattoos later they
hid data in musical compositions and
during the world wars these technologies
emerged quite well and a lot of
development time was dedicated to fool
the enemies so but in the 1980s that
started to become digital people started
to hide data in image files and audio
files and so on and then in the late 80s
the first approaches were published
where data was actually hidden in
network transmissions so in nowadays we
have a few more domains I already listed
them and more and more domains that is
covered in comparison to the historic
application of steganography where
someone had to carry each steganographic
object each cover object to the receiver
separately we can now have a constant
transfer of steganographic data over the
network and that allows us to hide much
more data and on a in a constant manner
that also means that it's less pricey
when we look at the basic taxonomy I
will speak about steganography and cava
channels there are also other domains
anonymity research and watermarking but
I won't focus on them I will focus on
covert channels in steganography or but
what's the difference between these two
well a covert channel actually the term
is already also from the from the early
70s means that we have some kind of a
communication channel that is not
intended to be there and used for
communication purposes the early Cobra
channels were found on operating systems
and we're not used in the network
scenario and the standard scenario for
coercion application is that we have two
people in jail it's called the
prisoner's problem so Alice and Bob are
in jail and they want to exchange
information about an escape plan but the
only way to communicate is wire a Warren
Walter so they have to give Walter their
messages water can look at them analyze
them and if they write okay let's ask
Helen and then then he will most likely
not develop deliver the message so what
I try to do is they hide their message
in some object and hope that the water
does not see it and we call that object
in which we hide the data a color object
and the steganography secret message
that we transfer so we have a little bit
of more terminology I don't want to bore
you with the details but you can also
apply keys similarly to cryptography and
the we say that we embed a secret
message in a cover object and then we
extract it so now back to the warden the
warden can have different capabilities
so if you apply steganography the warden
can either try to just detect that
there's the canõt graphic communication
at all that's called the passive warden
or it tries to detect that somebody
else's and walls did it that's the
passive but he can also be active that
means that he can modify your messages
and then tries to remove your messages
from the cover objects if he is
malicious then he can also spoof the
messages to
the covert communication that's the most
sophisticated version of the warden so
question is is it applied in practice
yes there's certain malware that applies
steganography and steganography and
wolves as the Cova channel creation
process so we have that and in in the
wild and it's it's increasingly used so
if you would like to see a summary i put
two links there to summaries however
what they do is basically i think the
traffic appear like it is something else
like messenger traffic or ssh traffic or
something and they hide the data in this
kind of traffic we found funded europe
or supported initiative called queuing
criminal use of information hiding to
track what is actually happening in that
domain and also to share knowledge about
steganography so if you're interested
let me know and maybe you want to join
however besides of that malware scenario
there are also other application domains
for instance in apt you can use
steganographic communication to have a
stealthy data exfiltration i think today
is also one talk on the agenda that has
the focus on the data exfiltration then
we have criminals who share secret
information like child pornography what
happened several cases in several times
in the past
malware already mentioned and secret
services of course but there are also
positive sides of the steganography
application like citizens that can use
it to exchange their views in a way that
is not surveyed detected by the
government or journalists who want to
express their opinion in a free way so
that the government does not restrict
them with censorship
so in network information hiding we have
basically two domains if we focus on
what we can what we actually hide then
we can hide the identity of
communicating parties that would be
anonymity techniques we can also try to
hide the content of a communication
that's done with cryptography but in
information hiding we either try to hide
the the fact that the communication is
going on at all or we hide the
characteristics
that's called traffic obfuscation so if
we try to hide data communication that
the secret communication is taking place
at all then that's Network steganography
and this is what the talk is also
focusing on so how can we describe the
techniques that are used to transfer
data over the network in a secret way
well the problem is there are hundreds
of techniques that we knew already since
ages and more and more techniques are
developed it's impossible to to mention
them all in such a talk and it's also
not useful to focus on every single
technique so what we did is we looked at
everything that was published since the
late 80s we surveyed it we categorized
it and we concluded that there are many
many similarities some techniques they
have just different names but do
basically the same thing and we came up
with a list of quite few patterns that
describe the basic idea that these
hygiene techniques apply so if you
understand these patterns you already
understood
hundreds of academic publications core
ideas at least of the last decades and I
will show you these patterns now this is
the basic pattern taxonomy don't worry
it's actually quite easy and I will go
step-by-step through it there are some
new
versions of this but I've focused on the
2015 published version because it
contains the most fundamental patterns
and in the meantime we just have like
Sreenu so you don't need to worry about
that we split them so that the Cova
channel techniques we split the Cova
channel thickness in those that are
influencing the timing of data transfers
and those that influence the storage or
the the data that is actually
transferred because these two
separations were already proposed in the
early 80s by the DoD and are the general
distinction of cover channel techniques
so that we keep them we also distinguish
whether we modify some metadata some non
payload of the network traffic or the
payload itself I exclude this part
that's digital media steganography so
you can select every media type and
modify it that's no news but I want to
speak more about the network side so we
exclude that and if we exclude metadata
then we can keep the structure of the
metadata or we modify it that's
basically it so we came up with these
eleven patterns plus a few as you can
see subpatterns special types of the
patterns and I will now go through them
starting with the with the one in the
lower left corner to show you how easy
it actually is to hide data so the size
modulation pattern basically uses the
size of network data that we transfer
network packets and changes the size
like for instance by adding additional
data to the payload and then a larger
packet can encode a zero and the smaller
packet of one so it's basically easy if
you add some error correcting and
detection then it's also reliable large
packet means one symbol small packet
another one you can also have multiple
packet sizes so you can encode more data
per packet
then we have to sequence pattern here we
modify the order of elements the
sequence of elements in the metadata as
well for instance here we have one
example that is a standard HTTP 1.1
request in one case we first sent the
user agent and then the accept language
line and the other case we flip it this
way we can signal different covert
signals works well was I think already
proposed in 2006 or so so all that I
show you here is in terms of these
patterns is work done by by several
people you find it in a references then
we have to add redundancy pattern at
redundancy means we just add something
that is not absolutely necessary for
instance we can add the user agent or
other header parts but we don't have to
and we can also use that to encode the
hidden message and of course you can
instead of using one line you can add
multiple of these header lines and you
can also do this just for selected
packets et cetera there are plenty of
ways to do that also one idea that I
really like was to create a new IP
version 6 destination option that's also
a form of this add redundancy pattern
then there's PDU corruption PDU the
protocol data unit so if you transfer
network data you have usually something
like a checksum and you can somehow
detect whether the data that arrives
that a recipient is corrupted or not but
if you corrupt by intention then you can
also use the corruption a packet
corruption to signal hints from hidden
information of course you will say now
yeah we also have regularly occurring
data corruptions because of the noise on
the network but here again you need some
form of error
directing or detecting coats then random
value pattern that is quite easy to
understand because several protocols
have some random field like the IP
identifier at least pseudo-random you
put some arab pseudo-random number in it
and that's it
and several protocols like the IP
version 4 identifier the tcp is an or or
the ID field of dhcp have such fields
that you can utilize for that however
you may want to make sure that the
distribution of your well use matches
the general distribution of that these
values for the protocol then there's
value modulation in that case this is a
little bit special because we we have to
select a one out of n allowed values so
it's not a random field we cannot write
in the field whatever we want it's some
kind of metadata that has that follows a
structured design and we have to adjust
to that so we cannot use everywhere you
that we want but for instance in a
simple scenario k you can switch between
upper and lower case for non case
sensitive network protocols like this
HTTP request so where the uppercase
letter indicates a covert 0 bit and a
lowercase letter indicates a covert one
bit you can also use the TTL of IP
version 4 or the bacnet message type or
similar way so it does not it's not
necessary that you use some plaintext
protocol for that order the destination
IP address on a network where n hosts
are located and you just don't want to
send it to some house that just does not
exist in a network because it's an
animal e itself however also this would
be a slight animal in if you have this
kind of user agent with a mix of lower
and uppercase characters
several protocols have unused or
reserved field if you look into the
RFC's you find plenty of them and you
cannot also write some data in these
fields traffic normalization may destroy
your data but at least you can try and
however this is it's an easy to use
pattern but it's also one that is
recognizable by many countermeasures so
most IDS's just detect that if you if
you set the IP ID reserved
flag and you snort and it's very likely
that you have a rule that detects that
however there are more sophisticated
ways okay that's it for thus for the
storage patterns I now show you how you
can modify timing behavior of network
data to also encoded messages the
standard approach or the the most the
[Music]
the one that is used the most is the
inter arrival time modification so if
you over time send your nectar Petach
packets with a different time gap in
between you can use the time gaps to
encode also different hidden bits and
that works also very well however you
have to make sure that the values are
not so small that the noise on the
network influences you too much you can
do something similar with the Lister
throughput of your data so you send a
burst traffic for a short period of time
indicates one bit if you sent your data
at the low rate you indicate another bit
also you can do the stepwise so you can
signal more information per time this is
like the little brother of the
inter-arrival time modification that we
had before then second last pattern PD
you order corruption a PD you order
pattern so many protocols have a
sequence number like the
authentication header or TCP and if the
well you see should indicate the
sequence numbers so we can mix packets
because and this is reflects a normal
behavior in networks because as you know
IP packets can take different routes so
packet or and maybe mix this up this is
why we have TCP to sort the packets at a
receiver set but we can also
artificially jumble the packet orders
and then the the the the the sequence in
which they arrive at the receiver
indicate the hidden message by the way
all the figures are from our our book on
the infinite book information hiding
topic so last last pattern is the
retransmission pattern the
retransmission pattern forces a
retransmission either at the receiver
side or something or by the sender side
so in that case figure we see that the
packet with number two was sent twice we
just caused an artificial retransmission
packets are retransmitted all the time
because they got lost so we can do this
also for steganographic purposes also
the receiver can cause a retransmission
at the sender side but just not
acknowledging a packet and then the
sender has to send the packet again but
the non acknowledgment reflects the
hidden information so it's a I sent data
to someone and someone tells me ok this
is a 0 and this is 1 by not
acknowledging my data looking at what
was published so far we can see that
some patterns dominate while others were
almost not used the reserved unused
pattern value modulation and at
redundancy pattern were used the most
while for instance the retransmission
pattern we had two or three examples
that we found ok so I have a challenge
for you actually I have three but this
is the first because you are hackers
and you like challenges so the first
challenges do not find a new technique
fighting data but find a new pattern if
you find a new pattern you find you have
developed a completely new idea more
creative input is necessary for that but
if you find a completely new way how to
write data that is not reflected by the
existing patterns well then you did
something very interesting and most
likely and you can present it on a
conference like this if you found one we
developed a unified description method
and that is tailored so that you
describe all the relevant aspects of it
it's easy to use and why should you use
it because it allows you to communicate
your ideas in a way that everybody
understands them that also will make
your work maybe more appreciated because
a lot of the papers on information I
think are very very technical but if you
describe the hiding techniques in a
structured way it's easier for everybody
you can also use it to describe and
you're hiding technique if you don't
found a pattern but it works for both
okay so besides of these basic hiding
techniques there are also very
sophisticated methods on top of these
hiding patterns one is micro protocols
the idea is we've put a protocol into
the cover channel and that enriches the
functionality of the cover channel a lot
we did lots of stuff in recent years
like building up cover channel overlay
networks doing dynamic routing on
overlay networks to bypass firewalls and
stuff like that you can transfer
firmware upgrades for for systems that
run your cover channel software for
instance as a cover channel proxy or
cover channel Rooter of course you can
have the error correction and detection
in it there's there's a lot of stuff you
can do
then there's pattern combination so
instead of using one pattern you can
combine them let's say you modify packet
size plus inter arrival time then you
have a pattern combination and you can
basically combine all patterns you can
also do this in a multi-layer fashion so
maybe one pattern influences the TCP
header and then I want the IP header it
depends on you and pattern hopping
pattern hopping means we randomly select
one pattern per packet that we sent what
per flow or however we want to do it and
then we switch this has several
advantages for instance if one technique
gets blocked the others still work if
one gets detected the others may still
remain undetected okay challenge to find
new countermeasures because it's it's a
challenging thing to find a good
countermeasure there are some good ones
you can either detect you can limit or
you can prevent such a covert Channel
but the big problem is there are so many
so what I think it's necessary a pattern
based countermeasures and not
countermeasures that focus only on
single techniques some people started to
working on that but there's lots of
works that that still can be done okay
so that's for a network information
hiding part I also want to show you some
very recent work that that we published
last year on an SMP workshop at least
the core idea of it because you can also
hide data in the IOT or and
cyber-physical systems and the question
is why would you do that well it's not
the case that many people will look for
secret message in a building automation
system or something so why not use it
for storing secret data also cps systems
are not always so secure as you know and
while they are carried around with the
people they are maybe not as well
protected by data leakage protection
etc so you can bypass traditional filter
systems using the IOT network components
how can we do this well them several
ways one is that we use utilize unused
registers of CPS components that worked
quite well and fast another one is shown
in the picture we modify actuators so
let's say you have a heater and you can
select different heating values for your
heater and you learn how the building
functions and which values are usually
configured for which device then you
know okay this heater is usually set to
level four point one out of five for
something what you can do is changing
the value slightly to four point zero or
four point two and then this can
represent your hidden data bit if you
combine multiple devices you can store
more bits and however it's problematic
because CPS status device components
usually changed status a lot so you have
to be adaptive with your hiding
technique that means you constantly have
to monitor it you have to apply
redundancy so that your data is stored
not just once but multiple times and but
that works fine however so far we could
only store about 350 bits to 1.5
kilobits and a smart building of a
medium size or in other words we need
about 30 actors just to store a s key of
128 bits size and here's my cert and
last challenge for you store more data
in a CPS and try other CPS types we just
focused on smart buildings actually the
temperatures ensured that we also
utilized could be deployed in other CPS
environments as well but maybe it works
with wearables or healthcare equipment
or whatever so be creative store the
data show that more data than just a few
kilobytes can be stored and then the
application domain may
become much more interesting okay here
are the references
most of my publications that are in the
link below and you can just download
them from there that's it I have one
minute left thank you and maybe you have
questions hi regarding challenge one is
there already a pattern that the text
messages which has different types of
resource allocation for instance if you
can trigger messages to a system which
up to CPU cycles on an average to 90
percent or not yes that's that's the how
did we call it whether there's one
technique developed by a by Stephen
Murdoch that utilizes clock screw of a
system and you influence the temperature
of the system using many requests that
you sent to it and then the recipient
can reduce the the the sending the
sender's information in that sense so
yes there's a pattern then I'll keep
working on challenge one well there
there's there's lots of stuff you can do
and there are just I think two
techniques that represent that pattern
so there's room for more okay last
question so so there's a slight overlap
between certain attacks on crypto and
steganography like the crime attack from
a compression ratio information leak may
be made easy would that classify in your
in your classifications of steganography
attacks or not so that the thing is that
there are overlapping Zinna terminology
that's that's true
in cryptography you usually have side
channel attacks and side channels are
covert channels that are sending without
intention in that sense so it's a
subtype of Cobo channel in the classical
taxonomy Thanks
okay thanks very much please give a hand
for Stefan
[Applause]