hi hi okay hi guys first of all mana
good afternoon thank you for coming to
our talk and and then next few minutes
we will talk about how establish cover
channel and are using or using 80
comments in the SME networks okay
well sort and brief presentation about
us I am Alphonse who knows mine clip on
Twitter I am the head of cyber security
lab in a in a important cybersecurity
company in Spain and what my my skills
are focused mainly on offensive and
defensive security and what here you
have more information about me and here
with me my friend Jorge Colorado cocaine
7:00 to 7:00 on on Twitter and well he's
a very good cyber security researcher
and he is focused on cloud security and
pen testing okay well here you have more
information about us and if you want to
contact us okay here here is a well this
talk is a little bit strange so we need
to hear some some previous concept okay
all our tests were realized for academic
research and up to our knowledge no real
system has been done it okay have to our
knowledge may be yes but we don't know
okay and well but this is enough for now
okay we'll continue what after before
explaining our results we would like to
introduce a couple of previous concept
okay because we focus on ways to train
information using covert channel okay
and in the rest case without pain well
that that point is important for that
we want to study the freakin history for
us is interesting because maybe I'll go
to a starting point okay sorry for that
but I need to some definition okay I
read but quickly friggin is as Lantern
going to describe the activity of a
culture of people who study experiment
with or Splore telecommunication system
such as equipment and system connected
to public telephone network okay maybe
you know the term freak is a sensational
spelling of the word freak with a pH
from phone and maybe also referred to as
to the use of a audio frequency to
manipulate a phone system freak figures
on from weak our names use for and by
individuals who participate in freaky
okay well the freakin history is is
amazing and as a tribute we've printed
some whistles we have here for example
with our 3d printer we have small words
did you want okay and we have a big one
okay
it's is true that well obviously it
doesn't work but is it funny
this one is a stone but what in the
slide you have more information about
this this topic if you want to what to
advance and what there are a good
reference and a good links ok what is
the beginning of our research well with
all previous information we our before
is to to understand better how the
mobile phone work at a low level okay
from our computer security point of view
in fact there are some proposal and new
attacks that is interesting to to know
maybe as you know there are some attacks
that are difficult to avoid from our
mobile phone there are some some good
examples for example well ss7
attacks and attacks to the manats radio
communication okay
some quick reminders about ss7 attacks
ss7
is a set of protocols allowing phone
networks to change the information
needed for passing calls intent message
between each other and blah blah blah
okay what is the problem
once they they have access to the ss7
Syst system a hacker can easily have
access to the same amount of information
and a snooping capabilities a security
service okay
this is a very famous and very big
probably money okay another kind of
attacks is about the solar that managed
radio communication and as you know
every mobile phone runs to operating
system the one you interact with like
Android or iOS and the one that controls
the radio hardware that you know the
second OS is so insecure okay so at this
point we think that it's a good idea to
build our own mobile phone okay to have
more control about what is transmitted
and how is transmitted and maybe we can
after create maybe cover channels and
maybe to send information and maybe
without pain okay so now cookie talk
more about that because it's the basic
for our results okay for the later I'm
sorry okay well obviously the good idea
is to study what other researchers
obviously have previously done in this
direction okay okay talk more about that
but this is a good example of this idea
is turns Krita phone that maybe you know
okay well we are we going to talk about
mobile construction now as Alfonso said
this was the original for research
we were talking about privacy sakra
funny well dis coolest stuff and we
ended talking about
what's the control we have in the data
in or the smart devices nor smart phone
in north telephone what's happening
inside was what are the services that or
devices running at the end of the talk
we were not so sure you know it's like
what's happening is like so obscure it's
not easy to know what's happening there
so we decided to build our own phone we
decided to discover what's are the main
parts how they interact with the gsm
network you know if you want to research
something you have to start from the
base in this case we decide also to
define some objectives okay we decide to
make an easy is it to written to
recreate device we decided to made it
and also with the objectives that other
people could build the same device and
with another objective we decide that
this device were also usable in the real
world we don't want something some
device that it's only academic with we
want something that could call that it's
easy to use you know and also we define
another objective we decided to make it
recycling recycling for us was like a
way to meet the building process more
simple and also to decrease the budget
of the project in our case if you look
at this at the left image you can see we
recycle some headset we have in your
home a wish like recycle also a power
bank and well it was also not only
easier to mate also it fix some problems
that other open hardware project has
with the battery in concrete well also
you can see or
first or first bet up project and this
marvelous
even and it's little than a normal
smartphone but well that's not true
because this device doesn't have any
battery and you have to plug in to the
Elektra electrical network so well but
we discover only with this device that
it's possible you can make your own
phone so it was a start of all after
that we decided to improve or phone this
is the second version you can see in the
videos host interface
sorry is in Spanish and you can see a
simple menu you can see the input of the
pin number you can see there that is a
Debian cell the things you are looking
and also you can compare the the size of
the device with my smartphone you can
see that it's more or less similar size
well happy news
we are release all the knowledge we have
gathered about this project all is free
in the in it having this link you can
you can see the wiki of the project
which is where all the knowledge we have
is record well its health translated to
English
it's how alpha I will translate it in
when I have time but shortly it will be
all translate and well you can see there
also a picture of the of the team of
construction it's so simple as I said we
wanted to make it as simple as possible
and also you can see the a case we built
for our all 3d printer it's an a simple
one but well it was easier than we
expected to mate so if you want to to
try it I recommend you there is some
simple programs to make this kind of
projects and it's so great well we will
continue with the now with the
investigation okay with this preview
information and knowledge we talk about
our research okay we want to create
cover channels is the idea and we want
to use 80 comments okay 80 comments and
in some way to send information in a GSM
network if it's possible without pain
better if not what bad idea is is that
okay so a quick a quick definition we
try to use cover channel okay as you
know a cover channel is a type of
computer security attack that creates a
capability to transfer information
object between processes that are not
supposed to be alone to communicate by
the computer security policy okay we
don't have time to tour deeper in in
these principles or ideas about a
stenographer or cover channel but all
our project or our research is about how
to create different ways of cover time
okay well here is the more important
slide okay what is our research okay we
focus on the client side sorry sorry
and here for example is the emitter and
here is the receiver
okay Google made change to the Train
antennas or mobile phone for sample here
or here using 80 comments is the idea is
the idea we use the antenna that we
already use in our Sun handmade mobile
phone okay so all the knowledge is
useful here okay with this information
the idea is to see if it's possible with
this kind of 80 comments that you apply
here in these antennas it is possible to
to same in some way some chains throw
the GSM network that allows to send
information to a destination and dinner
okay so do change here using 80 comments
and
some way the networks and information to
the destination Tina okay is the idea
and in in the back in some way the the
network telecommunication great a cover
channel okay all our experiment don't
exploit any failure about the
telecommunication companies we use
standard protocols and we think that
this kind of attacks are genetic for any
boy okay
in fact we only focus here on the
interface node network interface okay
more details about the specific
component in our research okay cellphone
so said we are only focusing on the
interface of the GSM network so what's
an interface for us an interface has two
components too many too many components
okay we have the GSM module and we have
the sim card of the module so I'm going
to start with the GSM module and
literally will explain about the sim
card and this is erm or module this is a
Sinkin a sim 900 and it's a so usual one
not so difficult to to get and why why
you have to we have we choose this
module for our project well this module
can works in this bands of frequency to
consider 850/900/1800/1900 so this
module should work in more or less all
the world ok and what we have to do to
interact with this module this module
works using 80 commands that are so
regular comments is using in many of the
devices and it's not something so
strange in this case this module is
using the 7.07 and the 7.05 and
proprietary standard of simcom well what
can we do with this commands
we can send SMS we can send MMS we can
use the GPRS and of course we can send
voice and audio and I know and also we
can interact with the with Internet so
as you can see this module is so
flexible we can make so many kind of
different projects but also it's also
some forgotten characteristic in this
kind of devices it's also that
temperature range that they can work in
these cases minus 40 degrees to last 85
degrees so also if this module was
flexible now you can use it not only
inside you can use it in every part of
the world independent of the temperature
and you can I don't know you sit in the
mountain if you want and well also so
important part is the price this module
is 21 euros and you can get it in any
online store you will get it maybe four
in one week so I think that's also
important and here the the other part of
the our interface is the SIM card ok
if you want to cal using the GSM network
you need a SIM card we are making calls
so we are using SIM cards and there is a
there's a fact if you are going to make
a covert channel you're interesting in
made it anonymously do you want to be
anonymous so if you want to call
anonymously you need also an anonymous
SIM card now in Europe is not legal but
it's a pity but it's also possible to
get this kind of cards nowadays for
example in the picture you can see some
anonymous sim parts of London well why
are we focusing in the in the interface
of the GSM network well
traditionally companies and systems
trust their security in the fact that
the user can interact with the hardware
many years ago and maybe get a BTS
hardware or a GSM client was so
expensive so difficult it was not easy
to manage to get one but we are seeing
in the in this years that is cheaper and
cheaper and easier and easier to get
this kind of modules so this kind of
security by obscurity now not as
trustable as it was so that's the reason
because we have a start this
investigation about the GSM interface
but it should work not only in the DSM
interface we think many systems trust in
this kind of assertion that users can't
interact with the hardware of the of the
system so how have we managed to into a
starter research how have we made it
well there is in the corner to eat ice
cream soft of up to it that we think
it's summarized well wholly managed to
do it we have get the manual and we have
we have go command by command looking if
it does they think it's it must do and
also if it doesn't the things it
shouldn't here you have the first page
of the documentation of or module well
the the main part I can say is like it's
so great if you'd come to sleep it was
like so many great naps after reading
this so here you can see the boring part
of an investigation but is needed is
like you can see notes notes above notes
not beloved notes if you don't if you
don't like only one color because it's
ugly you can use various colors it's ok
but
at the end you get this it's only one
it's light but this is the the result of
all our investigation and in the the
comments
the first comment you can see is the
ones we are using in or demo and they
the below comments
it's ones that we haven't used but are
also useful for another project
okay so I will start with the ones we
have used first we have the ATV and ati
eighty eight's command which is the call
command and hang out hang up comment we
have the 80 plus VL IP which will show
the metadata of a call we have also the
80 plus VL I R which will show or
metadata when we are calling or will
hide it it's a normal hidden call and
also we have the 80 plus M or ring which
will say us when Oracle has arrived to
the destination so as you can see only
with these four commands we can create a
simple data flow we can start the data
flow we can stop it we can use the 80
plus VL IR to send the data we want and
also we can be sure that the data has
arrived to the destination only with
these 400 comments and well after I will
explain later a bit more about these
comments how we have used it but I will
unless I will mention also this another
comment that we haven't used because
they are so interesting and the first
one is to enable the error report in
your case or errors were sent so so
useful but in another company
proprietary standards there are another
errors that can be so useful also in the
second one form is the most fun comment
with the 80 plus BTS you can create
songs using code you can in this case we
haven't used it because you have to
establish
in your case we are not establishing a
call we are only dialing but if you want
to establish a call you can use it and
you can send attitude a huge amount of
data also there is the third one which
will also deal with proprietary a
standard metadata and also the fourth
one is so interesting because well we we
haven't use it but we should and with
this comment you can receive well you
can see the metadata of more than one
call at the same time so this is great
also and well there is another two ones
they are also really interesting you can
see the slides after that all but if you
have any any question about that later I
can explain a bit more about that okay
well here is also another pages for
manual this is for example you can see
the ATD command which is the command we
use for a call first article and you can
see also the metadata
well the errors that this command is
sending to us we have in the first
version so for software we use this
metadata you can see it's four values
and you can in every call you can send
two bits but the problem with this
command is like when we were like
routing calls in an especial ways to
generate these commands but the problem
is in some of them you have to
disconnect from the network and it has
slows down all the process so yeah you
can send a real message with this but it
will be so slow so we decided to don't
use it also we have also the 80-plus
still IP with this command you can send
a metadata now you can see the metadata
file also we can manage to make the
goals in a special way to change that
metadata which kind of metadata we can
send
this with this comment you consent okay
your mobile ID your mobile number the
station you are connected to and also if
you earn an internal phone network you
can send also the internal ID so this is
the main common we are using to transmit
information because it's clear that it's
useful and also we have the 80 plus feel
IR which is like okay I will show you
your metadata if I activate that or I
will not show you it's 1 or 0 it's so we
seen it's so clear way to transmit also
information and well here is the the
first demo ok here is the an example of
first demo ok here we can see one of the
possible cover channels that we we can
create ok on the right you can see our
environment more or less through this ok
you have two antennas to Arduino and
obviously 2 SIM cards ok so at the end
we have an emitter and receiver ok and
here is an example of a covert side for
example using 880 commands here for
example this number is fake ok it's not
real using this this kind of command we
can send for example be it one at the
end we use a Miss call with hidden
mobile phone number ok and we can send
bits zeroes with this specific command
using miss Kohl with visible mobile
phone number okay so with 80 comments we
can manage a protocol and at the end we
can send information and if you you
think in this example with an
information without pain because with
establish any formal communication
what video always is better so so okay
here well we can see the first demo well
in this demo with an 88 bits
okay of information now it's important
to listen
as you can see in the left part we are
sending information and well in the
right part we are receiving it
so every seven second more or less songs
are a missed call okay
and what is true that this
this mechanism is very stable and
obviously you can send information
without establishing a formal
communication so without pain okay
always the same idea and well obviously
this mechanism is a slow okay but what
is free
it's fine as you can see the receiver is
receiving Geo T so we are transmitting
gameofthrones
yes or not
well obviously this video is 70 minutes
I don't remember what okay obviously
what is the
the mouse yeah okay Oh to the end
so 70 minutes 488 bits
okay it is so fast okay what works but
at the end here you can see I made a
message okay
the message is hi hackers hi and
what we we send 88 bits and in this
specific example we use 88 miss cold
okay every miss Kohl one bit
perfect yes well more information about
this specific example okay we discover
different ways to create covered
channels okay
all our tests have been restricted to a
Spain that but we think that they work
in other countries okay because it's
Israeli
but in general we we can send more
orleans 12 bits per minute okay so the
filling capacity of our cover channel is
12 bit per minute a good question is if
this quantity this amount of information
is enough or not too much or too little
okay well it's true that you can send
informational of interest with this
amount of of time okay for example in 3
minutes you can say my IP address you
can send one address at aura gains one
GPS coordinate so what is it's great for
example one hour more or less 700 bits
okay so 700 miss Cole ok it's a lot of
miss Cole okay here for example you can
say it a bit traffic buzz borewell a lot
of information and obviously if you use
this mechanism one day for example do
you say this amount of information that
maybe I don't know a picture image
with good resolution okay
well another good question is how stable
this kind of cover channels okay
there are some important topics or
results about that for example no seams
in our research has been banned in the
last five months okay every day more or
less we send one hour of information
okay more or less
700 missed call per days a lot of
milken's and 700 bits and this while
always in our experiment we use register
pay paid register prepaid sim and
anonymous purposes a prepaid sim the
longest pace was two days without
interruption or or blocking and we
decide to stop it
the feeling is that network
telecommunication companies don't apply
any control about that so if you can
send information say maybe it says low
but you can say okay anyway today well
our our interest now is to study a
amplification techniques so what
examples to send more information using
less for sample less miss miss Cole okay
let the idea is one go go faster so we
studied several amplification techniques
in the NASA site we talk more about two
samples of amplification techniques one
is virtual phone numbers mechanisms
configuration by the internet but
working in A to Z a scenario without
internet and
the possibility to create cover channel
using caller ID spoofing technique that
in this case we combine different
mechanism working in a 2g plus internet
scenario okay so more detail about these
amplification techniques
well last autumn so said one of the
characteristics of a copper channel is
the capacity so when we started to
research that it was like the most the
most simple method you can imagine is
like okay we have one SIM card with one
GSM so why not - why not foreign why not
eight if you can send one bit with one
why not eight with eight SIM cards so
this method was like so expensive of
course and also not so easy to configure
because at the end you are dealing with
so many hardware devices you have to
synchronize them so but well if you like
that idea you can see in the picture the
modem pool that it's so cool actually to
use more than one SIM card at the same
time but the other alternative we we
managed to found was the beautiful
numbers well when I started with with
this research and I didn't knew what was
that a brutal number what's that mmm a
beautiful number is some kind of numbers
you can you come paid for but it's but
you earn you don't have it you can call
them and you can configure the mobile
number the virtual number to make some
comments for example if someone called
this number you redirect the call
forward the call to me for example or
you can do the opposite if I call this
number please forward the call to
another device in the next demo we are
going to implement this for we have get
six pin virtual numbers and we Hank we
have configured it too
forward all the calls to the receiver of
the optical so mmm it's so clear to see
that if for example I call the first
beautiful number the call will be
forwarded to the receiver and the
receiver will see the mobile the
beautiful phone number not mine so when
the receiver get the call
it's C okay this is the first one so
it's zero zero zero 1 because we have
sixteen numbers but that's not all if we
can get another two bits for example we
can use it for a control flow if we call
down directly to the receiver we can
call it normally or we can call it
hiding or ID so the receiver will be
this 2 bits also another interesting
interesting fact about this is like ok
we have a ladder between the emitter and
the receiver so the emitter doesn't know
what's the receiver and at the same time
the receiver doesn't know what's the
emitter if you don't use this control
channel and the important part what's
now the capacity of data in this example
you can send with 28 bits per minute you
seen seven calls in a minute so we have
more than duplicated the capacity for
copper channel with the another demo and
here the tennis demo ok well in this
demo there is music so enjoy is three
minutes ok because it's important to say
is this a okay it's an information part
with a few polls his idea say the same
environment but in the cloud okay there
are a lot of beautiful numbers
do the impossible see the invisible brow
brow fight the power
fashionable untouchable break the
unbreakable brow brow fight the powers
very simple is one year old when you
know in two years not more expensive
it's possible to get free and we send
this this message in this case
is 1440 bits
I remember one
[Music]
you can see us play we are using 16
beautiful numbers we are selling 4 bits
in its Chrome
[Music]
it's not what a reality toys engaged you
need to
bowling
Oh
here's the father within 40 beats and we
used only 10 so every missed call for
bike in this specific example
so with this mechanism we want to be
less noise amplification techniques and
in this example we send this especially
the URL HD b 1a and this is onion on a
tour address that if you want to rent a
hacker occasion this is the URL what our
last demo is about how to use some
specific internet service to do this
kind of amplification techniques okay
here we can use for example caller ID
spoofing mechanism to create covert
channels this is the idea the idea is to
use the combination of fake mobile phone
number to create a cover channel okay
because it is possible is very easy to
create fake mobile phone numbers and
with this idea for example we can send
up to more or less 29 bits per
permissible okay so one missed call 29
bits so it's a good amplification
technique what our our specific demo
demo well we we try to in a chain a lot
of information only with one miss code
okay only one and for that we use miss
Cole obviously we use the fake modified
caller ID spoofing mechanism and the
idea is the receiver will receive a call
from a fake mobile phone number and this
fake mobile phone number in some way in
gangway hi the information okay the
hidden information is in the fake mobile
phone number so the receiver only need
to decode in some way this fake mobile
phone number and to get the hidden
information okay so we can see here this
demo for example for doing a quick demo
with use short URL for example we choose
a valid URL but we put a fake parameter
okay
and this but in this parameter we
configure a lot of information we we
create for example a short URL okay here
here we have the URL and we create two
two scripts the first one you put the
hidden information in this case the
short URL and convert to a fake mobile
phone number okay these are a stupid our
origins here but you have a effect now
for number and in this script you can
recover the information okay you put a
fake mobile phone number here is the
sorry here here is the hidden
information okay that you same but
obviously is a URL you can con it and
after that you can recover all
information in this case what if you
traffic passport or address Bitcoin
address a lot of information and and
more so the the last point is how the
receiver will receive the the code okay
so we can use a lot of service for
sample this is in in Spanish the malleus
/ divas calm
you put the fake mobile phone number
okay this for example put the number off
for sample my my mobile phone this okay
well this is a butyl number - because I
don't want to show my real number okay
but is this
and and play and that's all the service
phone call to my mobile phone here is
the number okay
and the receiver only need to get this
number put in this crib and recover the
hidden information okay so with only one
missed call again without paying we can
create a cover channel and in this case
transmitting here 20 20 bite bits and
here a lot of information okay what some
conclusions and future work well to
summarize all we have talked about how
we are how we have managed to create a
cover channel with the most simple ways
and then we have trying try to ask to
improve the capacity we have my we have
we can send and finally we have mix it
with internet so the conclusions we have
here is like this is not we are not
exploiting some vulnerability we are not
dealing with an error it's more like
about the design we are using normal
features of the network
it's and we think it's not easy to solve
this we think the ISPs should monitor
strange behaviors in the in the use of
the network but it can be useful for the
first two methods but in the last one it
was only so only one call so we are not
so sure about how to how to fix that
well to finish we have talked about a
mobile phone this is a free project and
we also want if you want to collaborate
with the project if you want to help us
to improve that and to help with this
project
please contact
or maida or or or mate Apple requesting
it have and because we think it was the
the the region of for investigation but
we think it could be also the origin of
another ones and it could also help to
aside occasional project for other
people and concern about privacy so well
guys thanks for all and things for come
here to do to Herrick about this okay
thank you very much
Thank You Alfonso and George some
question are there any questions we have
two key results so this is the best one
so all right thanks for the talk
great stuff so you're like the problem
and there is no solution right so there
is no easy solution so do you plan to
bring you know the problem you I lied to
general audience
for example police Mobile World Congress
which is like a huge conference on a
pile it might be that you know these
people might listen to you and might
come up with some solutions even if it's
not so easy so you're planning to work
with standard organizations or with
vendors or telcos to try to address the
problem somehow well by now we have we
haven't plan about that but well we are
open to to try to continue researching
about that but we really don't know
because it's something about the
protocol and how it the design of the
network so we will see if it is a normal
behavior so in this this is the simple
examples and it's only cold so well but
if you lose ability now that you have
presented such a problem to try to at
least talk with the people you think my
you know work to find solution okay what
I can listen what okay
thank you I know that well you are part
of group baby the baby we're well being
like a large company in Spain and you
have relationship and I guess with Bora
phone or telefónica have you reached
with them just to see if they're
actually care of monitoring this or they
have the capability or anything
quick we make a suite on yeah and you
know the answer is no way this guy a
specific guy okay and the problem is not
that the problem is in some way you need
to block the SIM card and the problem is
when you decide that 10 miss call 700
maybe is about the favor but 10 miss
Cole per day one per day no obviously
not
I imagine so that that is the pole two
months of transmission thank you hey
thanks for the talk and are you planning
to add the other metal other methods to
your research because you were just
using one method and you presented
different methods taken from the
specification so alright
am I wrong well here we have so only the
method sweeta the methods we have
implemented for the demo but we have
more methods that it was like okay we
can talk about them but we think it's
more interesting to show you the result
of something implemented
do you know what is the capacity of
using this other method to transmit data
in conventional well there is another
two more that is more or less the same
capacity because they improve in some
things but they but the performance
decrease in another things
it's more or less the same capacity in
old but for example in the Nasus in the
last sample in this i don't remember but
i thing is 1000 bytes i think but it's
not real because here is only 29 bits
but you use our URL and in the URLs you
can encode more information so depends
with only 2 G calls up to third 30 bits
per minute is our best result okay but
if you use means a scenario a a lot of
information a lot thank you very much
any more questions come on then give it
up one more time for Georgian dolphins
thank you very much
[Applause]