you
hey guys my name is Philip and I'm gonna
talk a bit about lateral movement WMI
but first an obligatory about the slide
yeah so I'm a security researcher at a
company called cyber easing and I'm not
really good at choosing creative twitter
handles and also this is my first actual
conference talk so you could just
mentally uncross that third line yeah
yeah cool so let's begin
we're gonna give a short introduction to
WMI and just speak a bit about the scope
of what's lateral movement in this
lecture I'll show a couple of new
methods and improved methods of lateral
movement using the WMI feature in
Windows and will have small we'll have a
couple of slides about how to detect
those things so in recent times there
has been some work in taking lots of
cyber security methods and putting them
into a neat geometric shape like the
cyber kill chain the threat attack
lifecycle they attack matrix and my own
invention which is the hexagon of
discomfort where the red colors is
symbolizing danger and the frowny face
is your general dissatisfaction with
getting hacked and all of those things
pretty much have a part called lateral
movement now in recent months the scope
of lateral movement was a bit expanded
with stuff like the eternal blue exploit
and its friends but the scope in this
talk is going to be this so let's say
you as an attacker have gained some kind
of initial foothold on a machine either
by fishing or by exploiting some kind of
application but you're greedy one
machine is not enough what you have on
this machine is not
interesting enough and you were lucky
enough to find some interesting
credentials so you want to use your new
found credentials and run your evil
disgusting code on your on another
machine so in the scope of this talk
lateral movement is using authenticated
remote execution and running your code
using stolen credentials cool so the
thing about lateral movements as opposed
about lateral movement as opposed to to
gaining the initial foothold is that you
don't really subvert any kind of
application you're not using a
vulnerability to make to make software
act not as it's supposed to act you're
not exploiting some kind of persons a
user using phishing making them do what
they don't don't really want to do
you're actually using a feature that is
intended to let you run code remotely
this means those things probably won't
get patched because running code
remotely is a feature that actual non
evil people need so the most common
lateral movement methods at least on
Windows environments are remote service
creation mostly with be exact and its
derivatives
remote task scheduling and what people
mostly call the W my method of lateral
movement which is which actually uses a
class called win32 process and a method
called create now as you can see we
already have a couple of methods that
let's run code remotely and these are
not getting patched because they are
features people actually use them for
banana readings so why do we even need
anymore stuff like that
so one of my favorite things is catching
a thread actor using some kind of really
sophisticated innovative payload with
lots of stealthy techniques
and the and those attackers use PSA deck
in an environment that doesn't really
create any services remotely so this is
extremely conspicuous and even though we
have this really cool payload you still
get caught and probably lose some of
your new evasion tips so expanding your
toolkit of lateral movement methods
allows you to shape how you look to the
defenders so you can better get masked
by the noise of what actually happens in
a network or be noisy and channels that
are not monitored so because this is a
talk about WMI I'll give a short
explanation about what WI is so WMI is a
windows feature that basically allows
you to gain information or influence a
lot of unrelated elements on a machine
without resorting to using lots of
different unrelated api's so if you want
to gain information about stuff like
processes but also monitors and sound
cards etc instead of writing lots of
unrelated code you basically ask WMI for
the relevant class and this whole thing
is available remotely it basically works
remotely just as well as it works
locally and this is done via the decon
protocol which is based on DC RPC or
window ram which is based on HTTP so it
looks basically like this I want to know
something about the processes running on
my machine I asked WMI hey can you
numerate some processes for me and
that's what happens you can do this by a
sql-like syntax you can you have some
really nice powerful api's and you can
and you can also use this to call
methods on w my classes so you have lots
of w my classes representing really
unrelated stuff on a machine like you
could
you have a class enumerate in processes
but you also have win32 protocol binding
which enumerates network adapters so
without w my you need to write a lot of
unrelated code and these things pile up
so some of the things I'm going to show
need an understanding of W might that is
a bit deeper so W my is made out of
three main components the wind
management service of WI providers and
the W my repository the wind management
service is actually a mediator between
clients of the W my feature as a whole
and all of the and all the other
components of the model so when you are
using W my as a client the only
component you're speaking to is the Wynn
Management Service it doesn't matter
what you what you ask off WMI you speak
to a service it knows what to do if
you're asking for an enumeration of the
class it knows how to which other
component can give this to you if you
ask for a method the same happens and
all other components of W my interact
solely with with a W my service another
important component is the WMI providers
so while if you use WMI as a client you
basically magically enumerate lots of
weird things on a computer or you have
or you can call methods but somebody
needs to have implemented all of those
API calls something actually runs the
code that you didn't write so the
component that does this is w my
providers those are actually implemented
as calm dll's and they communicate with
the W my service and basically process
all of your requests so the W my service
knows which provider needs to process
which
request forwarded to the provider and
then that's what the provider does the
last element is the WI repository this
actually stores the whole w my model of
classes their relationships and
definitions and also stores a couple of
persistent instances of specific classes
so let's get back to W my lateral
movement as it is known now this is done
by the win32 process class which
represents a single process on a machine
the class has a method called create and
calling the create process simply calls
create process on the machine so what
happens behind the scenes is that we as
a W my client speak with either a local
or remote instance of the wound
management service it checks which
provider is responsible for win32
process it finds out its provider called
sim 132 and passes the request to that
provider the provider knows how to
create processes it creates it returns
returns all of the returns codes back to
the WMI service which then gives it to
the client well obviously this is not
all as I have 50 more minutes of talk
and the WI feature is pretty vast there
are lots of lots of classes so we must
have another way to run code the first
method the first technique is actually
an evasion technique the WMI model is an
object-oriented model which means there
are classes that are child classes of
other classes and if you as a defender
are looking for the win32 process class
we could just have a class that behaves
the same
and it's called something else so how is
it done WMI has a functionality called
class derivation you can basically you
can also do it remotely so you could
first create a new derived class on a
remote machine so we create a subclass
of win32 process called winter you do
not evil at all we do it remotely by WMI
so without running any new code the new
code inherits all of the new or all of
the methods of the parent including
create so we can just call create and
that's it we have a new process on the
machine without directly using when when
30 do process which is pretty much what
we want so a short demo I'm going to
show class derivation while I'm
monitoring the machine using the W my
activity egw provider and let's see how
it looks so that's the provider we need
to enable it first so if you can see
this is some code that creates a new
class and then immediately calls create
on the new subclass so we have created a
class called create launch an instance
of evil evil notepad and as you can see
when 32 not evil at all create so yeah
so if you are looking for wintery due
process it seems you can't find it here
so does this mean we have evaded all
detections if an ID 11 shows all event
of client all the events of client calls
to the win32 to the WMI management
service this means that we have asked we
have asked WMI to run when three do not
even allow create
we still somehow can see when three due
process create why is that so while we
have manipulated the WMI model and
created a new class we haven't really
introduced any new code into the machine
so W might isn't magic this method needs
to be implemented somewhere so if we
look at event twelve of the same
provider this event shows you
communication between the WMI service
and providers so the WI service
understands that when we're calling not
evil at all this functionality of the
create method of the create method is
implemented in the sim when free to
provider in it and it is implemented as
the win32 process create so this evasion
isn't perfect some takeaways
while this evasion doesn't really work
that well for calling methods if you
know if you if you're trying to do some
evil by creating new instances of WI
classes without calling methods you
actually only see the name of the new
class you've derived so the servation
method is this evasion technique is
better if you don't really have to use
methods for your for what you want to do
another way to detect such things is by
WI introspection WMI itself can tell you
a lot about what happens in the W my
model so you can know when an instance
of a class is created or when a method
is called etc etc so if you look at
something like select everything from
instance creation event where target
instance is some class this looks at all
subclasses this means that if I look for
all instances of win32 process I also
get all instances of children of
subclasses of win32 process
another takeaway is that I had an idea
to do something a bit stealthier and use
the cloning feature of the of the WMI
model it's a it's a function which
allows you to take W my class and create
an in an identical class which is not a
child class of the first one
this didn't work as while we have copied
the definitions of the methods the W
Mike service doesn't really know where
they are implemented so you try to call
the method and it tells you there's no
providers for that so this didn't really
work right so another technique you can
do is taking Alta cold lateral movement
apiece that don't use WMI and sort of
forcefully use them through WMI so just
throwing an acronym at a technique
doesn't make it better and you need to
achieve you need to evade something by
using this viable by WMI now the best
tools that I know for detecting lateral
movement are actually network traffic
monitors so if you use W MIT to
implement known techniques traffic is
going to look a lot different which
means you can invade you can evade lots
of network monitors idss etc so let's
move to the first technique of this sort
the win32 service class represents a
single service on a machine and the
class itself basically provides all of
the capability of SC to eggsy so we can
start a service we can pause it stop it
create it and delete it which is
everything we need to move laterally and
create a new service on target machine
and what's even better is
that not only when 32 service provides
this capability but it also has three
other but we also have three other
classes which allow you to create delete
and run services so we have one through
system driver terminal service and went
through based service which is actually
a parent class of win32 service so if
you were trying to detect the first one
and didn't really write your detection
correctly somebody can still create a
service using WMI and evade your
detection so let's look at the bit of
pic of pcaps the sir s cedar eggsy uses
DC RPC as a protocol you basically
connect to a specific interface and
[Music]
depending on the operation number you
supply you call function on the remote
service so the DC RPC interface for the
service manager has an operation called
create service W or start service etc
and even while you can encrypt this
traffic the even while DC RPC supports
traffic encryption it's only KREEP
encrypts function arguments this means
that even when it's encrypted you can
still know somebody has created a new
service or somebody has run a service
but if we use the W my classes this
looks different
all of WMI basically uses the same DC
RPC interface and all W my method calls
use the same operation number so if you
use the maximum level of encryption on
this your PC the best thing you can
discover while looking at this traffic
is that somebody called something using
WMI which is really a lot less
informative
so another technique like that is using
the winter you do schedule job which
represents tasks created by a Teeter
eggsy now this isn't a solution API as
service creation you can only create and
delete tasks and if you want to
enumerate tests you basically just
enumerate instances of the class but
just like 82 X Z you can easily overcome
not being able to run news tasks by
scheduling tasks to run in one minute
sadly this method won't work on you on
when 8:00 and after because this
functionality has been deprecated just
as you cannot use without significant
configuration changes you can't use a
detour eggsy unwin 8 and up the whole
underlying functionality has been
deprecated so trying to use this by WMI
simply won't work and the last technique
of this kind is new style scheduled
tasks so 82 X II got replaced by SCH
tasks not XE which uses a different in a
different DC RPC interface and there's a
W in my class for a new style schedule
test called PS scheduled tasks but this
is only available for win 8 and up this
means that while you have the new task
scheduler on Windows 7 you can't believe
replace it with W my another fun thing
is that the powershell commandlets for
scheduled task creation actually use
this API so if you've ever moved
laterally using those commandlets
you were probably evading ideas and not
knowing it so as you can see here you
can create tasks run them delete them
change them and add new custom actions
right so another demo I'm gonna use WMI
to create a service on a remote machine
and just run a meterpreter from an eggsy
that I dropped that I dropped early so
let's see here's Wireshark which first
has substituted for IDs here it's
filtered to see only service creation
related packets so we're gonna create a
new service using WMI and see what
traffic was generated so if your PS eggs
egg or remote service detection was
based on network traffic analysis this
is what you're gonna see which is
basically nothing alright another
technique you can use to move laterally
using WMI is win32 product this class
actually represents applications
installed using messy exec if you open
the add or remove programs dialog in
Windows you basically see everything
this class represents same as with
artifacts you can find in the registry
so winterly do product actually has a
method called install it takes an
arbitrary MSI of your choice you can
even point it to an network host at MSI
file and uses it to install a new
package and not only have you installed
but you can achieve similar
functionality with the admin method and
I think also with upgrade now even
metals for is able to take an arbitrary
payload and
it into an MSI so if you have nexi or a
dll based payload it should be pretty
easy to turn it into an msi and use it
with win32 product and also there have
been instances of pretty sophisticated
actors using the msi as a for payload
delivery but they haven't really used it
with msi specific lateral movement
methods but which is a shame so let's
see a quick demo of this here I'm just
gonna use an MSI package interpreter and
use the win32 product class to run it on
a target machine
so we now have a system shell and we
have created zero services zero tasks
and then use wintry due process process
at all
so if your detection was based on was
based on a specific execution vector
this is pretty much an unknown execution
vector I did try to do some other stuff
with this class and they generally work
first of all MSI executes itself has a
really nice parameter caller which is
MSI exec /y
this turns MSI x'q and to sort of
replacement for replacement for reggae's
VR and can run an arbitrary DLL from
what I try to do there isn't really a
way to replicate this using the product
class which is a bit of a shame another
idea I had is because I I prefer not to
use files that I draw in a machine I
tried hijacking uninstaller z-- for
every installed application there's a
registry there is an registry entry that
specifies an uninstaller and it is a
command line which means that if you
hijack an uninstaller and somehow run it
run it
you can basically supply your own
command line and try to uninstall some
arbitrary non interesting application
and run your command line instead so
this also does not work with 1:32
product because it for some reason just
ignores the uninstaller entry and runs
msi exact with a specific good which is
a shape all right so another way to run
your codes remotely is by using evil WMI
providers these providers as i've said
our class instances and methods are
actually
and this means that if you have your own
provider and which is mostly a comm DLL
or comm eggsy and you can run it you're
basically running code on the machine
a guy called Alexander Leary showed
during the last there'll be Callen way
to register W my provider using only W
my functions which means you don't need
to run any kind of code on the machine
first and just communicate with it
through V W my interface this means that
we can install a new provider cool but
this method has a couple of drawbacks
first of all we need to drop a file on
the machine because we need to write and
UW my provider and we don't like files
[Music]
even harder for me you need to run to
write a WMI provider from scratch and
this is a calm DLL and it needs to be in
a very specific shape and I'm a lazy
person and I really don't want to write
comm really don't so what if I could run
something as a W my provider but it's
just it's just an hour it's just a
command-line like it has no relation to
W might whatsoever but it will be run as
a W my provider to do so what we need is
to create our own call object with a
command line of our choosing
we need to register a new provider and
then we somehow need to get the remote
machine to load this provider so we
actually have our code running so let's
begin with creating a cob jecht contexts
are identified via a class ID which is a
good like an identifier and if we want
to use just some kind of command line we
can put it in a sub key of the class ID
called local server 30 32 which is the
give four out of process comm objects
which means they run as exes and you can
supply an arbitrary command-line
argument so we have created our comm
object now we need to register and eww
my provider now providers are
represented by an internal W my class
called double underscore win32 provider
it's a pretty big class and it has a lot
of properties but as we are not as I am
NOT a developer who actually wants to do
useful things with W my but I'm more I'm
more like a monkey hitting it until it
submits we have free interesting fields
which are the name field as we need to
reference our WMI providers somehow the
class ID field which references to comm
object we would like to run as the
double my provider and the hosting model
field which tells WMI how should I run
this comm object-- so do I want it to
run as a standalone XE do I want to run
it as a DLL I load into a lower
privileged provider into a lower
privileged host process or do I want to
run it in as a DLL in this in a process
that is run as system so we could just
create an instance of win32 provider and
that is enough to register an actual new
W my provider so we could simply name it
whatever we want supply the class ID but
whatever comm object-- we've created and
set the hosting model to something like
so post which means an out of process
calm object which is run as the system
user and that's it that's what you need
to register a provider but you need to
also load it
and W my providers are generally loaded
on demand that means you have some kind
of class and it is implemented in a
specific provider and when somebody asks
for this class if the provider isn't
loaded it is but as you remember my WI
provider is PowerShell running calc
it doesn't really implement anything WMI
so we need to find some kind of
alternative way to load a WI provider
thankfully there's a class called MSFT
providers and this class has a method
called load MSFT providers actually
represents wi providers which are loaded
at this moment in the system so this
load method load method allows you to
load W my provider basically by name
you could also suspend resume and unload
providers but that does not help me with
the real moment so this technique didn't
work at first but it turns out that was
a typo but my first instinct was to open
Ida so I can tell you a bit about
internal about the internals of this
thing like we didn't need to reverse it
at all but I didn't think I did I made a
typo right so the load method checks if
when turidu provider is registered
correctly it basically checks this
against the WI repository and if we
register it via PowerShell and provide a
real hosting model this is enough to
have a provider considered to be
registered correctly and what happens
next is a function called create
instance is called now as you see from
this one block it pretty much
unconditionally called cocoa gate class
object with your with your supplied
class ID
this means the first time somebody
actually checks if your provider is a
real WMI provider and not just a bunch
of gibberish it's after a code your code
is run so the WMI service looks at your
local server three dookey under the
relevant clsid runs your supplied
command line as the system user and then
tries to communicate it with it and
query some relevant interfaces relevant
comm interfaces and it obviously fails
because this is not a real WMI provider
but this wasn't really what you were
trying to achieve your code is already
running and you really don't care about
whether it functions together with WMI
itself a problem I had with this
approach is the self host model I'm
hosting model which actually it's
building is one of the only ways to run
W my provider as an egg's e it runs a
system and it leaves a really nasty
event in the event log it basically
tells you hey you've registered a w my
provider that needs to run a system this
could be a security issue and if we're
going for stealth with our new lateral
movement methods an event saying this
could be a security issue really doesn't
help so it turns out that for backwards
compatibility we have an additional net
hosting model called Network service
host or self host this hosting model
makes the WMI service first check if
there is a DLL version of the provider
and it tries to load it with a lower
privileged hosting process and if and
when it fails then it just loads it as
system whatever so this doesn't write
anything to the event log and because we
control the comm object-- and how it's
registered
in the registry we can just not supply
any kind of DLL version of the provider
so it always runs as system and never
writes anything to the event log at
least on registry what does happen is
this comm error event because you're not
really running any kind any real decom
object and this is also known artifact
of lots of comm hijacking techniques but
I've seen a lot of these happen with
just arbitrary benign comm objects and
this is also really non informative so
if you work really hard you can bypass
this by nobody will be looking please
now so let's see how it looks
I'm gonna remotely write a new comm
object into the registry using W my
register a new provider using the same
comm object-- and then load it with the
MSFT provider load method
so again we have a system shell and
again we have not used any variation of
previously known that all movement
methods this will all of the actual
lateral movement techniques I've
discovered but I did want to show like
the stupidest thing I found you could
deal with WMI which is messing with boot
configuration boot configuration on
Windows is stored in what's called the
BCD store boot configuration the forgot
for the D stands for ya and it contains
data on the boot manager and bootloader
which files are actually registered at
the boot manager and boot loader and J
and manipulating the BCD is mostly done
using the BCD edit tool or if you have
any kind of replacement already running
on the machine but it turns out WMI has
a class that represents the BCD store
and like every single W in my class you
can use it remotely so this allows us to
switch when load XE to a follower of or
choosing to be used as the boot loader
for Windows and this way we can
manipulate the windows loading process
so we basically just need to open an
instance of the BCD store class on the
target machine find the corresponding
BCD object for win low drag Z and we can
simply set it to calc
instead of win load because some of us
cannot write boot kits and or don't have
the time for that and then make the
Machine restart and see it load from
calc so if you want to see how it looks
it's basically like this
tim is red and attacker is blue because
I got distracted so here's the code for
replacing window with calc and we can
also use now first of all here we run
bcdedit and we see the Windows boot
loader is windows system32 Cal Tech Z so
we can use WMI to restart the machine
and see what happens
so if you've ever wondered how windows
looks like when it tries to load from
calc it's this not very usable but I
suppose if you really want you can use
this for some kind of ransomware scheme
or something like that and you could
also use the whole BCD object for more
useful evil things but that's like the
stupidest thing I could think about and
all right let's go on to detection as
I've already shown the WMI activity etw
provider basically tells you everything
you want to know about queries about
method calls class and manipulations of
the model itself and creation and the
creation of new instances of classes and
this is basically everything you need to
know to to detect pretty much all of the
methods shown here also using WMI
introspection you could basically gain
the same information the main problem
with the ATW provider is that it doesn't
really show you the arguments to methods
but it's still enough to detect pretty
much all known techniques if you know
how to read it so you have basically
these two things and they can detect
pretty much every known WMI attack and
pretty and possibly most unknown ones if
you just supply it with a correct class
name but as people are mostly not
looking at those things using WMI to
move laterally or at least using the
methods described here will probably
evade lots of lateral movement detection
this talk was about only about WI
classes provided by Microsoft
but they are not the only ones who write
w my code so there are some classes and
providers that other software and
hardware develop developers right which
means some of them could have unintended
functionalities like I've seen a way to
use my laptop's bios WI provider to set
a new bios password and then enable the
bios password and then we start the
machine making it unusable for quite a
while but you can probably use use it
for I know some more practical stuff and
really knowing what WI providers you
have which classes you could use on your
machine and knowing what happens in the
model could really it will only do you
good because this is not the only evil
you can do with WMI it's a huge huge
system and well that's about it
any questions
[Applause]
Thank You Philip whatever any questions
no then I'd like to ask you all to give
a big applause once again for uh Phillip
thank you very much
[Applause]