real planes what see
what show you what's it be to view my
bookmarks
and a course my purse bookmark use my
own home page
I'll the Cheshire Cat was amazing shows
ever since 1975
ever seen and pound 153 well what's
email
alt be for bookmarks home page
bring it up and notice that that 153 put
up the trademark symbol
we go to
digital yet killed the
RZ slash test HTML
as is my roommate back in Titusville
Florida are taking all the
characters you can by and
put up a little file so I can see what
numbers go to which characters
we get down to 153 we have a laser
pointer
okay when we get to 153 others will TM
up there
174 as these are the largest trademark
copyright symbol there's a sense side
and though see down around
very much better
all and push a button
okay high-tech done around number to
sixteen we've got this
with a slash in it girly I wonder what
we could do with that
well let's go on down and see what I'm
doing this weekend going to be on
hope I've been to all these places and
following the con
I intend to go to the computer museum in
boston and loft
with a slash in it Heavy Industries
and all I've done actually I didn't use
the
the number all the for
you s for sources I mean netscape
PC under Internet Explorer what we find
in the source code for this
use
L ampersand 0 slash
semicolon which gives us a no slash
and put up the characters that one
and then I put in a comment are you
looking to see how I got a slash
0 and then give my email address that
gesture 2600 dot com because
if you go alt airport to get rid of that
window
control L WWW dot
L 0 PhD got Cobb
we find it lost Heavy Industries
they have the graphic
even they're all tags uses 0 character
they had the slashing their graphic but
down below
the use 0 character which under HTML
does not show a slash
no core lost know where they've got the
zeros
because it is cool spell kewl modern era
up you buy that they don't have to slash
show up
so is mine more usually free
wrong but the question then becomes
using the all are back your love hero
is mine really for having to slash 0 as
part of the character
over here
got tell that up showing by Cheshire
catalyst page and you'll notice
that we've got the beyond hope logo
animated by me
in square brackets the square bracket is
a clue to people with nine graphic web
browsers like
links which I'm using by using telnet
here and
this is a clue that this is the alt tag
image at the backslash key
and we can see farther down here we've
got
image source: equals in my images
directory
things
Kim accidentally wrong
here here
okay hope references to hope dotnet
the image the sources images last BHM a
doctor which was the name of the file
a line is all the stuff from there at
the Altair quote beyond ok logo
close quote border 0 and this
allows you to have something that can be
/c by a user who does not
have graphics let's go back over here a
minute
little further down the
hope area the original beyond hope web
page
actually is a page that I created
on the places 100 email list about the
whole conference
for about a month the ever had to say
you know we really ought to have a web
page in you know somebody ought to have
to stop
up on the web finally somebody wrote an
email to you know
when we do the web page you don't have
this this that and the other such
so I used his format I just started
putting things in
now you'll notice that
we have in line here
okay let's come back over to
not skate let's go to the original
beyond hope
web page use light
here see what it looks like
over here now over here I've got these
little blue dots
okay like it's a real graphics
like web page so when we do love you
source what we see we've done
is we use a datalist
up every got the image towards the blue
dot dot Jeff but the alt tag
equals quote asterisk close quote
and we do this all the way down until
we get down here where we seem to have
accidentally
him forgot to put a the all equals
quote asterisk and that gives us the
dreaded
in line message and this is what up
people with links
see when they don't have a graphic
or they have a graphic that does not
have an alt tag
all equal to get them a textual idea
what graphic is supposed to be there so
you wind up with pages it's a
inline inline link link link link in
line is mapped and there's nothing I
have to give the Lynx user
any clues one thing I hate
our programmers that bitch about
clueless users
and then never put anything on the
screen that give them clues
it's a pet peeve I'm sorry wide
thats you page all EPCOR will close that
window
down here we by that at the bottom his
original letter
and I spent the time about the new york
city website the convention visit your
website
and I'm leaning on buttons and excuse me
the email questions was to be put it
later
contributors page include and
when we put airline here we see
that it was too the gestures home page
when you went to an annual goals team
that went to 2600 dot
up so knows how to protect it was fun
and geysers a letter he said this we met
with the webpage
can be done quite quickly and updated
maybe later day
so I by thing as the suggested
web page it will get updated on it but
get pretty this web page that work
measures art not record what school
Cheshire as I type that I realised yes
at this lecture this page would be
by graphic web school back over in the
nine graphic side
when you use the you well the a numbered
list
you get the asterisks you get the plus
signs it will bring it up somewhat for
you
thing is you need to tell that in to
your host and then use the lanes
controlled the will get me out
I can do it LFC my directory CDs
basic HTML you know so I'm out I'm in
the real
shell world L Y and X
enter love and you're up on the world
wide web
using this software sleep
Kansas see information
%eh up from that
help its the links help files
for used to be you can't
voters on where'd you go to this about
links by from the
X for help will give you all the
information eventually
and I should've email severe
to be years ease a guy who's really
about links
that probably to bring up reference
things
both just go to top
links dot work see what we get
art thank you
so that's not the right one so it's
go to
go to points roser
or bring up
01 able to connect way
roser work able to connect
okay so will
know that word
that home page
likes know that
all
yes appear you'll notice that the title
at this page is currently
404 file not found posted robots keep
out
now when Emmanuel look at this page from
because I
sent to the email was look at my page is
ready its until the Cheshire
slashed beyond hope slash and
just index HTML page which is the
international standard
whole website file name: people did and
he put it up otherwise
dot com site may be very proud but then
he left the title it
had noticed this title which was
specifically put there so that when the
robot
by resurgent they would see that
not put it into their search engines as
this is the place for the page
should reside in the 2600 not come with
what
by did got changed to the got home page
as the title
but I had to point out two in two days
later that was fun are we're going to go
back to my home page
see yes
know you'll notice that I have this
thing here here's a link to pick up a
new york city all attending the beyond
hope conference
the pops up which is directly across the
street the artwork to keep hearing
I go to the subway what's years years
ago and
Lawton OK I'm cool up talk work with i
think is wonderful
Lucknow yep cyber cafe down the block
was stopped in for lunch yesterday
Rosa bill is a friend at the arcade I
mangled body by
way back she's here she just emailed me
her page
so what we're gonna do is show you how
we just at the stop
online as we go sometimes now
when you tell the area control the
ordinary users depending on
your Internet Service Provider might get
on menu Florida online
my personal internet service provider
has this menu
where you've got one the World Wide Web
to email user all these different things
I've was heavy shelling out I just do it
from mandalite a
you can't get to a shell probs
peco
HTML index HTML
accept that
I was already in the
a single directory so ego index HTML
control W to search
notice on the bottom two lines I've got
clues
search for xxx and there is
the comment like so I know where the
bottom my list is
lol I and a
a trip equals http://
W dot 2600 he's
6 100 magazine
offices
by was ruble
to the allowed
to take a shower
there thank you
I'll a hacker known English major okay
and
see and control
age believe will I guess one of the
things
relates to bring up help menus is always
find out how this works
another black
their control 02 right out schiphol
have control
are to repaint the screen netscape and
now we find
we have added still waiting for a reply
filling in the stuff above where I was
at on the page
now with that
2600 magazine officers so
now if we work on that off we go
so with just a Telnet connection
I can log in I can check my mail
i cant edit by web page are
but when I get to other people's pages
the
for example you think really class
outfit like the reader's digest
okay they have a very pretty page they
have people
who are doing a wonderful job making it
look
real good well golly I did my public
library
and I would like to go visit
the reader's digest so
here G for go to WWW dot readers
digest doc I get a page
was templates to at the bottom
if you look at the things on the bottom
here it's badly for the dress template
you know it if we look up here
on the other page we see
that when I put it because I just got up
it aliased to astor's template equals
all the strangest up and links going ha
what this is a bad web address I can't
buy
this so they had sent many emails they
come looking at fifty pay
and I get this crap I can come look at
their pay
I got very irate I tracked down the
webmaster and we're having lunch
tomorrow to discuss
making their pages available to not
graphic
doing wonderfully
hi it's just this little thing these all
tags
that will make such a large difference
brains see
going to show up BBW got
MLS net way
you cancel that
you me actually go to
digital net Cheshire
politics
digital you know all these FBI guys
Secret Service guys going on with the
politics are a bus hackers
and
group yeah
okay my homepage so I finally put down
my political agenda there's logos and
army
Michael Douglas and I me which is the
supporters group for the US national
soccer team it was the game the rest of
the world love
americans are finally starting to pick
up and
are getting into finally we're going to
dress the world with something and not
shoving it down their throats
this is what I like about this is why I
think it's politics
these are people who is this news with
go out the sporting games with
up peace through killing each other
of the soccer field but over here
and the tell that side go to
you
see if town politics
is good enough no okay so we'll just
space on down but
where I have a graphic on the one-page
over here
nothing shows up no link
no in like no asterisk and the reason
for that
is that all equals quote quote
ATL string so I have
a strictly superfluous graphic for no
good reason other than to just show up
the bunny head on the soccer ball which
looks cool the graphic people
the nine graphic people don't have a
clue if they're and don't
need one so this is you know one of the
little tricks for making a webpage
more user-friendly two guys that can't
see or graphics
and who are the people who can't your
graphics besides the guy
the public libraries using the card
catalog for like
I do Wright County Library System in
Titusville Florida
the blind kids these boys
box you get a feel for it because
computers came around they got this
piece
size is going and just got working with
of
Along Came Windows they're just trying
to get their windows
sup a software squared away and outcome
flames give them a break
people you can't just have low bat with
you gotta have almost no band with that
allow these people to read your pages
all I forget which page that
go over analyze that show what I want
you
MLS net and I'll try in NASCAR
alright think analyst Major League
Soccer page and
if you have frame please put your
contents frames
on right not the left the reason for
this is that
links and not Rep browsers will start at
the top
and of course you go from left to right
in English all and the first thing you
come across as your content
so you have to go through all those
content before it gets the content
up that particular page if you put your
content
frame on the right you get first
contents when you click on one of those
things and then
your references are at the bottom the
ways you always have to cite their
graphic
click on for this that the other and
email me
you also have in text at the bottom so
that the not got the people can't find
it
okay
we seem to have well i think is under
the table not as frames that wasn't
quite what I'm looking
are but you get the idea you
you've seen rain you know what it's
about the people who have never seen
range do they just cant see get really
confuse
I personally don't like brains
I want people to be able to bookmark my
pages
if I have a page a couple global that
that's what they wanna go to
that's why they should get to really
they should no what that URL is
inside the freemen doesn't tell you you
really gotta get
really good with the up all view and
then sores
try to go these things are Major League
Soccer's
course our Premier League I'll see
other good pages
this is %ah his pride and joy he sits
there in Titusville Florida
trying to keep track of all spacewalk
going on across the river
Space Center and keep this more
up-to-date than its home page
and is really proud to because
the Scott who's playing here for the
show the next to like September not on
this up now these guys have their own
webpage
they want nasa so what would it take to
rust our own website all we have to get
the approvals that it would have to go
through no
that's alright we will go out to our own
service provider
as up
that these guys are Phoenix dotnet
Houston they have their own webpage
to keep track of their play for us
there's 8635 it's up there now
and as you done I think week 13
he gets a mention for pointing out they
should have square brackets in the all
tax
that the guys know description up a
photo
or logo a patch or something so he was
very proud to be included in that
will go back to
launch page okay reading file
notice they have a no frames home page
which is the one that I was elected to
doesn't waste your time going through
the stuff to where you want to go to try
to get you there
are carry Space Center Visitor Center
has
a home page and it's just this graphic
you click to get to the
first information well as you look you
straight that person make
was with time the next
unmanned rocket launches this is Q
that
because this is thank you for the Dow
same page
you can see by the think jump down here
got a bunch
question is that the one by first
and point
systems look im sorry we want to back it
analysts so all right here will take me
forward
it's as if I had a forward but up by the
way I have great my childhood and come
up with a hero
anyone remember mister jinx the
hanna-barbera cat
used to chase pics index to yelling I
hate nieces to pieces
my hero unmanned launches
and we find that the air force has a
classified payload going up
ghali isn't that interesting I wonder
who
we should link to for further
information about the classified watch
so will just click on that
find out where we're going and we wind
up
visiting this week port on the guitar
world wide web home page
I'll the National Reconnaissance Office
people used to be even more super secret
the National Security Agency and now
there on the web but isn't everybody as
we
slide on down the page best place to
park
for a space shuttle launch which is in
Titusville word unmanned Lodge
to serve walk from the Kennedy Space
Center that
up the coast where the old workers and
demonizes a lot from
but the unmanned still go keep Naval Air
Station
for the depth of those addresses tight
to go from you wanna be at Port
Canaveral down by Coco Beach
the better what you watching go can use
your shuttle landing
how to get a car pass radio and TV
stations
now notice a graphic say wrecked the
shuttle amateur radio experiment but the
only graphic on the page
because I have changed out the mission
patch every mission
it's just too much about but
this lies almost every mission where
there's ham operators on board
and ham radio is one of those few happy
you can take up
with you space as recreation
as equipment that is potentially useful
as emergency rescue equipment oh and in
fact
I want the shuttle flies it was STS
seventy five there was a communication
outage and as their passing over
Australia
I get the ground please call Houston let
them know you know we know about
just called up to them through the
Australian
hands gave informational headed back to
come over gold though
and you know mister a short outage
but the messages did go via ham radio
you don't need more scoring
up tell yah are
I went to a half bath he said have you
heard about packet radio
scratch scratch what's that poets data
communications over ham radio updated
upload
I i cant wears those Morse code learn
Morse code got my ticket short way for
twenty years
BBC World Service recanted national
never needed to talk
was like you need to talk I got my hand
take and
six months after I got my have like the
way with words
where and with just the check
take it technician take it you can play
with space satellites
and Steph the emitter radio said like
organization
is are they build satellites they're
built by Hampshire washed
piggybacks with other payloads going up
it's wonderful stuff you could
play with their lives in the comfort of
your own home one thing I wanted
show was the editing process
when you've got Windows things are a
little easier I have to admit
okay we're back up here at
the menu we're going to accept that up
hi some
my email a body of the set me a message
are you having fun in New York please
remember to buy me some picante sauce
while you're up there
anything but pace the reason being he
watched the picante sauce made in New
York City
New York exactly you see in the air
well I live in New York for 12 years
down there to see this said
I want parties are made in New York City
up
so now what we're gonna do is were to
take
URL he's got detectives message we're
gonna highlighted
then go
alt edit copy
now the Highlands gone away so
never gonna go cue to put the mail links
to bring up our nine graphic web browser
G for go to an all
at pace why I didn't type it wrong
isn't that amazing
if I wanna pasted into my pile got the
page
I could that take something
let's see beeper or bookmarks
and let's try
all 26 the MIT
IIHT FB hack gallery
and thank you nice stalker for giving me
this one stalker
CDC now we hit the equal sign
%uh this gives us the information about
the current document
we do group
we do the highlight back
alt eCopy come over here to netscape
control L for location
and now because we're in a Windows
environment control be to pace
are do I need to take up space right
probably not so adjusted enter of it
goes
and up comes page because some pages
you really should graphics they got
there because they might be cool
there one day I walked over the Office
Depot in Orlando
and it was pouring rain downpour
wannabes
have been at things we get every once in
a while usually daily
I went next door to the eggplant
software just to kill time
has a 10 minute Thermaltake the Passover
there was a young freakin their freak
acker showing off his home page
social they're serving I took down the
URL went back to the library brought up
link to the URL
it was all click link are in line in
line is map link link link
your browser's Sox the only all tag on
the entire page was
your browser sucks you just knew that it
was part up the
illustration the kids white put his page
didn't know was there
so that is the absolute worst case I'll
a graphic web page I've ever run across
so here we got the energy hack gallery
it's got a small graphic but mostly
it is but nine to graphics
and will be over here if we go back
you for up we buy it hasn't inline image
that we don't really need it it's not
too bad has
the by year by location by topic
so that means that here with got
the images to use all the calls quote
quote
so these guys have been sensitized to
the issue
now notice also that they got the great
background
by pages I generally tend to have a
white background
this is the only time I really cared for
the graphic route
I think the grey socks I called
executive great
to make it you know sound like 22
insulting sometimes
but the term executive gray should be
insulting up
and this is the but the only counter
that God
pages 89 one so far
up see oh the web accessible
here and if we click on that
where we go also notice you are reading
it should be gone
you know I got the URL of the page here
okay
why would anybody peoples have to do
that they're looking at the page I will
be there
if somebody prints out the page
handed the somebody else that person
will be able to find your page
little things that really make a webpage
work
this is the National Center for
accessible media where they discuss the
budget is accessibility
things and up because I make pages or
accessible
I grab their logo and ran with it
the XOR various companies that are
involved now
for this listing waterlogged where
people are getting sensitized
you know what check back in a month guy
does it again its Readers Digest
Johnson bucks good
up
see up alt left 0
to go backwards and that backwards again
backwards again backwards again
being foolish to go all schieffer go
but I want for for the Cheshire Cat was
homepage
what you do is copy down by URL
which at the bottom there http://
notice no www that won't get your page
digital that net slashed chill d Chae
SH I R you so
if you get there at the top of the page
crucified my email address click on that
ship email it's just Cheshire at 2600
doc
it may be a week or two before get back
because I expect a budget email when I
get home
but I I will respond to email
and a course up links compatible
which is linked to enhance and proud
other
which mean probably get disappears page
here
summer somewhere
oh yah at UTC 9704 22
that's going nowhere fast go of your a
minute
talking about getting people clues okay
70 4.2 is very strange
format so the clue is click the
hyperlink
it takes you out to university in
germany to explain to you
that what I am using is waiting for it
to come around on the guitar
it is the international standard date
time
notation love year month day hour minute
second
income future store double order
and thats the real trick their
again you know links available for my
hope a city Cup these damn
I do have a link from your job as the
Space Launch FAQ page
the higher media today you remember the
covered call
okay it really is good
you haven't been there also the Capitol
steps to do political humor
Washington DC that a song about the
wonderful stuff
and do we have a sound hooked up
you know their their speakers in here
now
okay is not coming out okay
okay the trick is
that they play the soundtrack to bash oh
here comes
worst
okay its it's it's not worth it don't
worry don't worry but it's just plain is
a MIDI file
pleased with the music to mash K
ever members the TV
okay who remembers the movie
there were words back that what were the
words
suicide is painless it brings on many
changes
and that was the joke there well you can
see their road
their web pages article part you know
the graphic links
this job you say no the different
graphics
so it's hard to break down it's been a
few months now but
this this week this this parity site
with up within 24 hours the news
breaking
and so I immediately linked to it
and it was really great stuff
funny if you go down these links its
it's hilarious
sick I admit but hilarious
yep
that's why where I got this I got this
whole warning about it
you know but internet parlors rolling on
the floor laughing my ass off
sick but funny so if if you read it at
your own risk oh yeah but political
agenda is deaf to the shootout but
that's all
thing for the world game in the world
rules this counter is we go up
to the Ozzies baseline viewing page on
this page just look at the counter
without committing it so I can see how
many
have gone were other users for
are and the trick is folks yes I am
ozzie I've been
real hearted
is a part subtype the trickiest everyone
knows no like it says at the top of the
page
okay the Cheshire Cat this is really
Richard Cheshire former drift ap
photo/the Cheshire Cheshire
you don't know everything tackle Richard
but only salesman ever tried to call a
dick
the thing is that they want to know with
just got was this
a course Richard Cheshire the other
Peter Parker spider-man
they know superman is park at a third
level the object
for privacy purposes doesn't occur to
most people my real name is Robert of
business
the privacy issue when I get that phone
call it a night a Cheshire
I know what direction you coming from
okay
that the whole thing it is the worst
kept secret on
forgot and i'm happy to tell you when
we're together
like this but I asked the journalists
just
keep it you know quite fact in the 1982
technology also read your article
which up by ACO 3 acting years ago
up the author there
hello really great thing let me control
f 25 page
kept up well that's taking too long
okay the quote was the Cheshire Cat
a-listers
his real name back it is even israel
pseudonym either
very very angry at that and I loved it I
thought the white just yes
that say because I'm not really trying
to hide it
it strictly the privacy issue so you
find me you've got this route
to get down to BRT pages if you want
space
now let's let's go to space that the
minute
and show you some other stuff link to
okay there's that
that nice big space to click on
because free space kids out there
art
oh that was love what was the article in
wire that was amazing is the question
and there with your
few months back about flag the fiber
optic
link around the global it was like a
fifty-page article it goes on for ever
do not read it
on the web bring it up click File
say save it off on your hard drive
not with your online time reading think
that goes on forever
and you are the kinda freaks hackers I
think you are for being here
you will re you will be amazed you will
not be bored
it was great I loved it but what's
really
okay we'll I am I love CL
got all bunched things here yep
the question was about the cognitive
overload haven't
away are I everything email
I'll in which I have built honored
because they tell me
they don't bookmark all the way they
bookmark me
I have like they wanna go to at
one lady told me that she thought look
at my page
don't like it night get there till 3
a.m.
using psychologist for design pages now
the too much information as
down they can only rent
that's true but the thing is got I don't
have much information
not if you look I've only got a few
things a few paragraphs
but length if you want more information
you can go there and I take you directly
there
mars global surveyor for example I don't
need to have much
I don't need rapid I will take has the
graph
nation what have you and
you know you what if you want it I don't
expect
everybody what all I've got I don't have
to waste
I disk space that information I wing
them for the guy who has the it up today
you know there it is
up reason this is up here as a ham
operator
there is a communication system from
art to orbit in the ham radio
or forty and Gautam down that low
the tested on the way out her yes help
and so I got up that way
have just kept up but
I don't need it have this information I
know there's information overload going
on
and yes are
I'm the other but the thing is I will
link you to other information you going
out about the iPod
and this is part of the share the
knowledge
Sep that I help published tap for
wide any publicist 600 to get
information
out and the World Wide Web greatest
resource their
up and when I find think I know my
printer
did email the URL and
usually that got like that you are a
highlight that
because let's let but just WWII that
would highlight it people highlight also
little trick
bring a pie in a minute
this week for come around on the guitar
okay back up to message mazy do thanks
very much same way
are but you'll find that
hero said the HTTP
URL's I want to be able to click on your
Netscape mail
it says mail to Colin and for us quiet
and said
work which is call sign at the Everett
is a letter
nation is just a a dot forward file out
there
but because mail to is an actual URL
netscape highlights that email we see
so they can just click on that rather
than reach up to the reply but
actually I've got friends who are so
clueless they have begun to reply but
yet but something comes up blew a
hyperlink
that we can figure out that the
government got out so
that way I make sure that side this is
my permanent
email address because it's a router the
forward file ever change are two
different ISP
does not apply and set they change the
port file an email
follows me only the one change because
go out same with Cheshire 2600
power I just so the email too many he
just be right for
while I don't have an account dot com
I've just got that work well
now there but its it's so easy
much easier for people to email me that
way one also
be so I just because I saw us as you got
this
before you become do best rise with
court scheduled rising video displays
let me remind you that information is
not knowledge knowledge that wisdom
and wisdom is not foresight each rose
out at the other end
all Arthur C Clarke Colombo Sri Lanka
okay all
about 10 minutes ago any other questions
yes
mail to text you not have to slash if we
go
cue quit links
the purview bookmarks
enter for my homepage then backsplash to
view the source
we find that
a trip equals mail to colon Cheshire a
2010 a dot com so that is able
URL that question mark said that it was
home page
will drop home page in the subject line
I clicked on
somebody's l2n had something come up
such a quiet and I totally
free I ranked view source to find out
how the heck he did that
and this is how we did that it's it's
very useful because people will you know
you it's a
hey there with you more information on
it what with it
so this way each place right footed
email me
I put some tag subject to tell me what
yet
was about clues
they're gonna be clueless
gonna make you clueless to gotta leave
clues
the question yes that team
okay ok good
let's do that about only to send email
and
we will control the other that pine
dash I to go directly to the index and
oh I'm in the hours you count no I'm not
way
you send mail to the other hell that's
what it was
yup this is the problem with having good
friends you know you well
and when you've got to email accounts so
we'll
tell that to the
shy folder blah blah blah
way yes
okay up
okay so now we're going to highway
alt at copy
over here control L for location
control V to paste
enter and find
net tamer which is a low back with
dos web browser
so works with 286 is at 386
central and
happened here
okay that came home page a dust PPP
dialup access program
are no tears are back a driver a web
browser get
send your email who okay this is neat
stuff
so now I I've already got it captured
I can with the mail PWD present working
directory
I'm in the account exit that fishermen
Cheshire down and in the html directory
so
peco index yup
that finger syndrome index HTML
wait for come around on the guitar
control W researcher where is
search xxx up
a liar to lol I rate was
point a a trap equals quote
alt at paste close quote
and net
tamer home page
okay there's
supposed to go there okay
they felt that way that hours ago
home page with thanks
to ago
okay
a web roser
with PPP action
in dos Bank Bank bank
okay so now control odor right
all to head back to netscape
all be for bookmarks Cheshire catalyst
home page
your glass cup
back
and what will find is that it's not
there
because it got from the cage control
are to refresh from the net
and now than it ever home pages there
and
click alright that's a hell 9000 I
I with that is I know I have
I've got the full length going on my
desktop at home
there are various reasons you can
download graphic goes executive great so
you know this is optimized for links to
people with such
rates up
other questions lower res
source images well with the negative
prozor even lower res
won't show up so even a little icon will
come up with the big
in line state
yep it's good double blow them out it
might be good
if you've got like a red ball chip that
you're using to all
equals quote asterisk close quote you
know put something in there
so the nine graphic user does see that
there is something there
it looked a little bit like with the
graphic user sees they will really
understand there's a difference either
but if you don't have it there they get
the inline
L thanks very much
okay fellows a today around for
MetroCard with the
red dollars lover coming at coming into
one
so thats anytime now
three minutes out cigarette