we'll be starting up in just a minute or
two
here comes a Ryan
your for your yeah
yeah
up
to
I
are we on all good welcome to be on hold
the
hello okay trying it again
yes
thank you
now ok
okay okay welcome to be on hope
the
arm we only starting about 10 minutes
late this year
three years ago we started about two
hours away so we're getting better and
as you may have noticed registration
went smoothly this time didn't have to
wait around
morning thanks to the registration
volunteers out there we have a lot of
things going on
right now we're looking at live pictures
from our twin
conference Holland packing in progress
where their
know what they're doing actually but you
know we have this picture tells unit
we can control the camera from here can
we do I go
ball back or something or more power
see we're doing that were controlling
their camera right now
over there over an hour on now it looks
a little bit
jerky and the reason for that is because
it requires three ISDN lines right now
we're only using
1 we will be using three later on today
says we are not a few kinks
by the idea is to have them communicate
with us real time we communicate with
them real time so it's
it's breaking edge technology
cutting-edge technology what this is
also
the first hacker convention in this
country I've been to do that
actually as really good connection to
the outside internet
and for that we should thank Marco and
all the other
network people that have work going
through the night to get that happening
Ryan is here he's got some updates on
network stuff that's happening
things to do things not to do problems
we've had so far
we're hoping to accomplish Ryan I'm not
even a star with the
I
we have a 10 megabits connection to the
inner small
home odds are call that's about 71 look
at all the pictures
the logistics if you've got a computer
you want the network through
I hope you saw that work became hitters
there's got Hobbs
we love you plug them in some ways and
share
if you need all-star
with the serious geek stuff if you know
it DHCP
is and you can use it do now your honor
if you need a static IP I will be in the
network room after this
will be giving out static IP's
for you what it involves will give you a
piece of paper with a number on it if
you already have a static IP if I talk
to already given your number
you need to come to me and pick up the
piece of paper with your number on it
so if there's a conflict you with if you
don't have a computer
ignore everything I've said because you
don't need numbers
I DNS servers asks
stuff like that if you do you're all
that information is on a poster
up near the doorway between the network
room commerce by
stock if you don't have a computer by
the way you can still participate if you
can
I look over people's shoulders ask a lot
of questions and make use of the public
terminals that we have as well
we have banks public external makes a
public
dumb terminals their guest for those
the BR machine ready for human
consumption we will have
a at least a couple a handful
hope that volunteers
there will be giving out your usernames
and passwords
as orderly a fashion as we can manage
look for me in network room I will be
with the
people
there's favor circulating I hope awesome
that as a forage
say this is what I like by username to
be so
have that hand you
reached the front at the very very order
to
ok network operations marchers
okay are we ready to begin to pick up
love notes we've
we've had all kinds of media people here
their TV crews around if you don't want
to be filmed just tell them so
they will leave you alone they don't you
leave you alone when a bus
will take care of them expect a lot of
people to be around though
looking at what you're doing expected
your being washed all times if you have
a machine on the network expect to be
act because that's what we're all here
for we have a couple other interesting
marketing typing first evolved with
nothing to do with all the stickers
popping up on people and drop pounds
we don't condone that kind of activity
it is kinda interesting out just like my
neck stickers speaking
speaking of stickers I have it on good
authority and this is the true
this is the God's honest truth in the
oval office
in the White House president clinton's
office underneath the rock
you will find one of these don't ask me
how
for the beyond hope original stickers
that was sent out on subscribers I don't
know
you subscribe to restock it there but I
happen to know for a fact that this will
drive the secret service crazy
has enough to rip up the carpet but when
they do the
the coin a phrase we r everywhere are a
couple things that we have this time
we've never had before
we have CD-rom's over the merchandising
off the hook which is the radio show
that we do
on the radio station WBAI here in new
york has to do with acting
2600 all kinds and the things that
happen throughout the years
we've been doing this since 1988
actually in this the first time all the
shows have been available
I and we're making this cheap as we
possibly can make it so if you wanna
was just shows a CD-rom is about two
years worth shows on each CD-rom
I like about a hundred hours and is the
real audio format are so
check out the merchandiser and I ask
people about those good things but
we have we have a limited supply of
those so I were also a limited supply of
these
major hacking cookies on the freeway
seen these by there's
there's a is gonna be here later
actually is a guy who is in the army
he's a major and his last name is
hacking and
he makes cookies and the really good to
sell doing some souvenirs to bring back
we thought this would be kinda cool
thing to have some major hacking copies
available in three flavors:
we also have the new issue 2600 was just
came out the last week was on the cover
I don't know
and we have the free issue which shows
available to anybody who wants it are
we have a bunch of things to tell you
but we'll tell you know throughout the
day we don't want to
keep rock makes waiting any longer Brock
is
someone has been within the hacker
community for quite some time
back in nineteen ninety-two we had an
incident
in washington's Pentagon City Mall at
2600 meeting
where security guards broke up the
meeting brock meeks is the reporter
discovered Monday morning by calling up
the security office
that the secret service was behind the
whole operation in a
had ordered the security guards
illegally detained in search people
funny thing is he call them at nine
o'clock at about 9:15
the security guards got a call from the
secret service saying don't tell anybody
about this
so it's a an example of how good
journalists can get the story before
I anybody can stop them since then iraq
has been
a key player in the fight against
clipper the fight against Israel
telephony all kinds of privacy issues
that affect every last one of us with or
without computers
and now you can see rock beats as a
regular correspondent on
MSNBC and rock is here today
is our keno speaker pleased to introduce
brock meeks
thank you very much
to pleasure to be here now feel take
your Bibles and turned it around on me
start speech
let me say
hacker community
has always been wanna my favorites
I am NOT hacker by any stretch of the
imagination I'm just
journalist scribe I chronicle what
happens
back in early
I guess the mid eighties when I first
got on the net before it was even called
the net
you some the old-timers here will
remember that you had
type in all the machines the 12 route
your message to email was kinda like
digital
Pony Express I was on at that time
using the net are using an electronic
means
to report and the report on a lot of the
things that were happening
even back then in the early eighties
we saw the start the incredible
misinformation
that the mainstream media was spinning
about the hacker community
and I always took a separate in contact
the folks that were involved
activity and not judging them but say
look
I wanna tell your story from your point
of view I didn't go on a pretend to be
somebody else like
newsweek reporter Richards stands or
whatever and
and trying to see anybody I was always a
prime and I think I got respect for that
and I think I also got respect for being
able
to get to the bottom things and tell
their side of the story tell your side
the story as fairly as I could
let me start now
with my own hack start
with the media hack how many journalists
do we have here in the room today
good will turn off the cameras
this is all off the record did you hear
me
the cameras this speech is all off the
record
no objections
well ladies and gentlemen this is what's
the problem
with mainstream media today no balls
I should have heard cries of outrage or
people
getting up any journalist that would
accept
a public speeches off-the-record you
know I should hear some UN cry
walk out the room do something now of
course I'm kidding
the speech is on the record but here's
the point that I wanna make
you're gonna have to learn how to hack
the media because frankly
you haven't a good job you set the terms
when somebody when a reporter calls you
you
said the ground rules tell them this is
off-the-record this is on background
this is not for attribution whatever
don't know what those terms are you
learn
what they are and you discuss the
journalist before you say
anything you control
the interview because once the words
come out your mouth believe me having
been on the other end
the word processor I know how words can
be spun
entirely outta control so you set the
ground rules
you learn how hack media
okay now we're on the record
when I spent my torturous year with
wired magazine
last year working for that great
dysfunctional family
ice to show up and speak at different
events
and because I'm was the washington
correspondent you know I'll
I wore the Washington uniform with a
suit and tie and
and people would often be amused or a
little bit
put back when they will see a represent
Wired Magazine
wearing a tie and so i would tell people
look I'm the only one in the company
that
wears a tie and doesn't yet have a part
of his body
here's so I succumbed to peer pressure
and had my nipple pierced well
as it turns out of course then I went to
work for
MSNBC where
everybody wears a tie I but nobody has
a part of their body pierced as a course
you believe that ugly double piercing
rumor about tom brokaw
that's not a true story
let me tell you about one of my favorite
hacking stories kinda set the tone here
it's not a classic act in this sense
getting into a machine or something like
that but it's a good illustration
couple years ago maybe several years ago
now I forget was when the
Democrats still control congress
at Marquee the chairman of the
telecommunications subcommittee was
holding a hearing
had Emmanuel Goldstein up there
testifying
it was a setup marquee wanted to rake
Emanuel and 2600 over the coals
he called him a criminal call even
outlaw said 2600 magazine was nothing
but
you know I think even use the word
terrorist publication or something like
that I mean it was
it was a slam job and i cant believe
marquee was
was doing it cuz precluding guy but this
was markey's
and 10 market just didn't get
what the whole hacking culture and what
the whole
process is about certainly didn't
understand 2600 magazine
now there's a million ed markey's out
there
you gonna have to watch out for
now I can't condone hacking activity
the majority hack why
because it's legal
those are the laws in other words were
parted jail
don't you understand that said
I accept hacking and hacking culture I
believe in it
and I believe that it serves critical
vital function
in today's community as part in the
delicate
checks and balances what's happening in
cyberspace
hacking at its core pushes the envelope
or it should push the envelope
exposes witnesses it forces people
corporation and yes
even governments to and to make
themselves
stronger this is what ed markey most the
people in washington don't understand
month after month I guess it's quarter
after quarter 2600
publishes new hacks new holes in the
telephone system and what does the
telephone
telephone companies in AT&T do by and
large they ignore it
now anyplace else
in the financial community if
security all popped up for a problem pop
Wall Street insured would be all over
some fucking corporation if they didn't
fix these holes in the telephone
companies get away with it
read these things I guess they think you
guys are inactive
and they fail the patch these holes and
then they cry about it
when somebody exploit got them all
doesn't make any sense to me
Wall Street ignores it the financial
community
ignores it the holes that they do patch
of course
only makes the system stronger
this is what I'm talking about with
checks and balances with Mark
didn't understand we thought it was just
some kind of outlaw publication
now personally I'd some 16 year old with
no social life sitting around trying to
expose a security hole
pentagon computer then some rogue nation
back into the Pentagon
and if you don't think the rogue nations
are out there doing this type
you're wrong you can tell by the sweat
breaks out on the upper lips the NSA
guys and
CIA guys when they testified now they
get a lot of things wrong
have to spend for the public but they're
fucking scared folks
because it's happening I'd rather have
one
you exposed all then have some kinda
rogue nation that
for some kind economic espionage or
worse
that's where the national security
threat is not from some 16 year old
sittin around as hell
that reminds me I was just on capitol
hill the other day
listening to some Subcommittee on
national security
figure said that twenty percent of our
government's computer systems
have been subjected Thames I wrote that
I said what the fuck is this twenty
percent you that's a pretty god damn low
percentage
get off your ass and go up
you know
in baseball 200 batting average
every factory and
the government's line fudge factor we're
talking about less than two
a less than 200 batting average
and that's the ticket to the minor
leagues 20 percent
unfortunately I think that
figure which is probably much lower than
20 percent
represents hack
yesterday in the minor leagues now
where are the elegant hacks up today
elegant hacks I'm talking about dan
farmer
and its creation say that's an elegant
hack
we're talking about
iraq's was chronicled in a sec were
dispatched
look wrote about informed
hacking infamous spammers
wallace's machine pointing out that
information to the net
that's an elegant hack the most
hacks course was when Matt blaze some
the clipper chip when he found easy way
disprove a key part the verification
process
now Matt crack
clipper chip sure the hell at and for
all intents and purposes
he signed Clippers DEP warrant and of
course there is
the penultimate law and that's using
your experience to eventually gain
big bucks consulting contract
and you know who you are now
these days all too often
we hear a stories so-called
hacking stories for example this
extortionist overseas who finds a
security hole in netscape and decides
that the standing-room Ward money isn't
enough he wants more
so it tries to blackmail did netscape
to give any more money for exposing this
whole that's not a hack
that's extortion and then we hear
def on a few weeks ago where people are
trying
pass of counterfeit twenty dollar bills
that's not at a crime
that's a crime and then we
scores scores a quote unquote
lol hackers
let me tell you
when the media thinks about
won the first thing that pops into their
mind
are these digital juvenile delinquents
masturbating on on AOL
only al-haq
Nicholas Ryan figure it out wrote the
AOL for free program everybody else
since then is basically just been a
copycat we talk about copycats for a
while if you're following some
buddy else's hack if you grab 2600
magazine
your type what's happening there
all you're doing
is basically following
nothing more than martha mitchell
cookbook and
no bake in a bunt cake 2600 magazine
the
2600 magazine wasn't meant as an
instruction manual
2600 magazine is like
guy where people have gone 40 use that
and to build on it you have to invent
and develop
and build things and god damn it
you have to break not just fall in
somebody else's
footsteps now going into the next
millennium this gets even more and more
crucial
if you continue to push the envelope
and you do this with the business world
and with the government I guarantee they
will probably continue to despise you
but they won't be able to ignore you
if you to if they try I'm sure
that she'll hurt them don't be gentle
do not go quietly into the night and for
christ sake
be smart if you gonna follow
you gonna do something don't leave your
digital litter
strewn all over cyberspace it's a quick
ticket to jail and again
what part jail don't you understand you
find people here that have been there
it's not a pleasant place now
the feds are getting smarter don't you
get stupider keep them racing to catch
up
it'll make you stronger it will make
net stronger and when the net is
stronger
in the end we all win thank you
now willa open the floor to
questions if you have any and I'll see
if I can some answers
next thing any questions
Campoli I
okay got the yeah I will
also we're gonna have people come up
here and they can party from this micro
she s basically what I thought about
how the net is becoming more
commercialized with big money
interest suck more more than that making
information less available
to other people make it more difficult
for people to get information as
becomes more and more commercializing I
think about that
generally i I'm not opposed to the
commercialization
the internet because he is making it
generally
more available to a wider number of
people more and more
corporations are coming online and what
does that do
well for one thing gives hackers more
than opportunity to
explore their application but I think
the other thing that
is a problem is that as
the big moneyed interests get involved
they want to protect
their interests and so they start to try
and gain control
one other things that we see is a great
example that this is the whole flap
that's going on
now about domain names and who's going
to become the registrars and so on and
so forth
we have this proposal on the table right
now that essentially turn
the domain name registries into a UN
type system controlled Geneva
by the International Telcom
Telecommunication Union
operates under charter Swiss law for
christ sake
if anybody has ever had dealing with the
UN
you know how that places and now they
want to put
net domain name registries under control
you in style tribunal it's bad news
I A yeah
question what made you decide to take
her side
storms that the the slant ration because
I could
I did
for one thing I knew that the people
that were doing the heck
in those days it was a majority was with
kids I knew that these kids were not you
know all
miscreants and juvenile delinquents as
as the media was was portraying to be a
think they were inquisitive
they were kids maybe felt ostracized
by their peers and so forth they got
into computers and
just sense they got into computers
because they're interested in
they were being as criminals and I knew
there was a different story to tell
besides that I had talked to a few
started hearing things like
you know I see my parents
making cassette tape recordings of
and passing them around
isn't copyright violation and I see my
parents cheating on their taxes and so
on and so forth
what with they were doing wasn't hurting
anybody
they were still on anything for christ
sake and yet they were being portrayed
as criminals
nobody's telling their story whenever
as a journalist when I see a big hole
nobody else is covering well
opportunistic it's that I am
I moved right into I was telling a story
that nobody else was telling X question
have you
ever had any story slam by MSNBC that
they just did not
on done no one other thing I was very
leery of going to work for MSNBC and I
got assurances from
everybody I worked with their I was
gonna be working with Microsoft wasn't
habits fingerprints on any of the news I
believe
the people that I was talking to because
they were all news professionals
but I went to it being very skeptical
pleasantly surprised that
Microsoft is really nowhere to be found
on the news side
except for the fact that we all pitch in
because the brain gets software we have
to use that Microsoft supplies
got knows
several years ago i didst all of my
you know when tell step so my PC's of
and got everything and got maxine
declared
declared by declared my home Microsoft
freeze
and of course Microsoft
because I work with their software but
the thing that I
is working for MSNBC is that Microsoft
huge and there are so many different
05 them projects nope and everybody's
concerned about keeping their project
alive in keeping their budget alive
nobody really has
time to put their fingers on the news
one things that's in my contract is that
the first time I get a whip
MSNBC has stopped Microsoft story
anywhere I walk my contract
hit your critical the media
but what I herbal lot of packing stories
about what happens to what about what
the government does is in reverse crack
it's a tempest what can what does the
media due to its
stuff like that government taxing that's
what they've come up with
share with us well I think we have a
media panel later on today and that's
one of the questions you should ask
it's a fair question right now
just last night somebody turned me on to
a story that I think you
surprising involves the NSA
and this one is reversed kinda crack
stories wanna tell anybody about it
journalists here
break in that story pretty soon years
ago
I was the first one to break stories
about the the pentagon
had signed on hackers and they were
creating
viruses to putting computers that were
shipped out to Bulgaria
to and they were doing this all on the
slide
or so you know i've covered those types
with the media in general
and that's a good question to ask I
can't speak for all
media so asked the media panel
hi as a journalist yourself do you see
push technology
as going backwards instead of forwards
and development better information
transmission
and customization I'm not a big fan of
push technology
I think that push technology as a matter
fact stars to make
become more and more like a broadcast
medium in that you no longer have to go
in search for things
they start to come you and when
net starts to become more and more
like a broadcast medium what happens
congress is gonna come in and they're
gonna say
back in 1997
it was in a broadcast medium knew that
so we struck down the communications
decency act
now it does look like a broadcast
smells like a broadcast in functions
like a broadcast medium
now we can regulate I think we have to
be very careful about how the net
involves
we're gonna see this issue revisited as
the net looks more and more like
broadcast I don't see a whole lotta ways
we can defend seen is different and
broadcast so i think thats
push technology start just down there
it's not going to be the critical factor
streaming video stuff becomes more
I think still maybe five years out we
have to be very careful on how the net
develops
or its gonna look a lot like TV and
radio happens
its regular like TV and radio for
someone to say I was a good speech
I do the tape the market hearing with
the I know boxing testifying if you do
could you produce it
I don't have the tape I'm sure somebody
you get a transcript but that was
several years ago
open it was a time when there weren't C
span cameras around anything like that
ask emmanuel I think he has a transcript
pay
following you consider all country I
mean in other words in
your personal opinion what's the
difference between hacker in the US
into a government agency computer or
want in any other country was a bit
different
any personal opinion how can you call
such countries as
row some countries stroke countries
thanks
some bro countries well if for
for one thing the rogue activity
I know is when hacker
is a government agent is his
operative a rogue nation that is
attacking
US installation US government computer
for the sole purpose espionage
ort or for some other kind national
security violation that
there in the employ of another
government hacking into somebody else's
government now
if our government attack to iraq
to France or whatever America becomes
the rogue nations the same type
deal if it's government-sponsored
attacks against somebody else
the same dealers in america differences
a 16-year-old home
and somebody overseas that is employed
pay
by some foreign country
what do you think recent my curse of and
Macintosh
alliance that's in my
holy war speech for another time okay
that's fair I mean for every for
everybody Apple stock it was great
Apple about six bucks a share my
my parents who I told to buy thousand
more shares
Apple when it dipped to thirteen dollars
a share
my dad is extremely happy now followed
my advice
there's a lot of employees at Apple
morale was way down
they saw their stock options damn near
double they're very happy
I think Microsoft make sure
has healthy revenue stream secured
for a pittance for 150
million dollars they saw their own share
and Apple
raised by about fifty million dollars so
for 150 million dollars which is peanuts
to Microsoft I think it's a good deal
all the way around we have to see the
key thing here
course focuses Microsoft the devil's in
the details of the licensing and patent
agreement
want to see how that shakes out because
Microsoft frankly doesn't have a real
good track record going in
looking at other people's books and
technology implant fair and square just
ask
to it about I was
sorry I was wondering here you had a
tape the when he called the Pentagon
City
mall the security officers yes
duality I refer to it as Johnson tape
because security directors name
last name was Johnson and
at it was very funny because
part I was gonna ask possible
on the web somewhere somebody wants
touch
later talk about transferring and so
forth was very funny about that
that instance because I did call very
early in the morning
this guy on the tape and I said doing
harassing these kids
they weren't doing anything Johnson goes
well you know it was there was an us was
a my guys it was
the secret service and FBI there all
year this of course was after I ask
I can talk to you and I said I'm just
trying to get some information
i cant talk I said well if I come down
there we talk to me
talk and so I I'm just going on and on
you think I slowly crack city secret
service the FBI
here so I published my story
then he was denying that he ever said
this to me
of course I forgot to tell him that I
was taking the conversation sue me
course in the district of columbia only
one person has to know that the tape
recording is being played and
done so I knew
so Johnson was the nine this and people
were
journalists were then writing stories
countering my story Johnson denies
so on and so forth for the next all day
I was just telling i got really pissed I
said listen just give me a phone call
play
tape for you so tape reporters common as
planes take over and over again
and so then of course the next day
stories were we contacted
rock he played the tape yes indeed the
secret service and so on and so forth
there course they were but they use the
Pentagon City
a cop guys as therefore oils and the
whole thing was just a big
as our mess still have the tape I don't
think Johnson
I know Johnson around it Pentagon City I
was wondering
where do you think hacking is going next
hacked
cracked going to be any predictions you
know
I don't have any predictions I think
downward slide like I said I think it's
in the minor leagues
I don't see too many elegant heck's
going on these days
I see I see a lot of copycats
we see quote-unquote ale
step I see far too many elegant
tax I think you guys have to pump
ratcheted up a notch
busy like I said push the envelope start
to break things to stop other people's
footsteps or the next big hacks gonna be
that's your job
my job to report no predictions
questions
all right thank you very much