of ever here
welcome to be on top after dark
where the new york times
this happened last time to accept this
time or in the magazine section which
means they they actually wrote this
article x ever weeks ago
for two get into the color section
or they say about us hackers for hiring
or they got that from
this weekend thousands of computer
hackers are gathered in the plot
building in manhattan for beyond hope
billed as the largest hacker convention
ever well we didn't bill it that way
they did um... but they probably is
there's all kinds of uh... we're going
to earlier uh... panels in everything
from credit card security which i don't
think we've talked about
uh... to hacking new york's metropolitan
to be happening tomorrow afternoon
uh... the event is also drawing
four-part wraps and various government
outfits like darpa
who are on hand not to arrest but to
hire
so um... go out there and get hired i
guess
why we all know that the cyber cafe
being hacked job
kind of funny isn't it but if you do
hack something
the uh...
the nice about it
and leave plenty of backups of the
people can put it back to the way it was
we don't condone that kind of thing by
the way
all right our next panelist are winkler
will be speaking about hackers and
criminals
should be quite interesting and don't go
anywhere after this we have our g_s_
empanel going on
the worry about the rave it's gonna be
happening all night long so if you want
to go there to play time to get there as
well
how it's working
okay uh... basically i came up with a
title it's originally
uh... irish they gave this presentation
of death time an adept con they were
trying to figure out a good title for a
and the name changed about three or four
times and what happened was jeff moss
thoughtful
bt sorry
dat thought to be a good thing named
after michael corporate espionage
a hold on
she plot
by the book everybody says it's great
not just me
but i'm biased
so was corporate espionage
then it turned out where hackers and
criminals collide because
i kinda don't want to teach people how
to go out and commit espionage
specially nothing like setting like this
where
people are likely to use it
this kind of like a little bit
you know i a opening thing for in my
opinion because again
like one of the palace i believe lewis
called said
online happy to be here because it's
among the best in the brightest
well i personally don't believe that
being hairston wearing a black t-shirt
makes you the best or the brightest
so i'm here to see you know again
i'm here to try to like hoping your eyes
and just to give me an idea what i'm
seeing around here
i'm seeing some people like learn some
really elite things
yes
he had stashed a u_s_
then followed by killed minus nine
number
you know if that's the type of stuff you
think is a lead and all that makes you
leading edge
you know
you need help
and then a lot of people also when i was
up there during the tiger team testing
came over to me and said
you know the body
now that password sniffing stuff
what how does that work i can see that
you know and they don't know how
passwords nothing's done
i think people know how password
sniffing stunt
now this is scary because half of you
don't
this is a major problem
you know again
password sniffing is a basic concept in
any sort of hacking
but the thing is i get worried here
when i hear people say
i'll be a hacker then you'll get a high
paying job
and that's not going to happen
you know again just because you're an
actor it doesn't mean you know what
you're doing
it means you call yourself a hacker
and additionally
the problem is the people who are least
technically skilled present the biggest
problems
causes these people
'cause ida well
let me start by next lights are
okay anyway
this is what i do
farley i was with the national security
agency
i perform work for other intelligence
agencies after i got out of there
and while i was in their and again did a
bunch of stuff
right now i'm performing penetration
testing
so uh... some people call me the best
social engineer in the world and again
if you read my book or read my articles
which are out there on the internet
you'll see why
and also uh... you know bunch in
newspapers call me the modern-day james
bond in all that sort of garbage
i'll talk about this in a second
again i've taken over banks using only
telephones i've stolen billions in a day
i've given it back but again that's i
did this all legally
and again
else investigate computer related crimes
so not only i guess you know i learn a
few tracks investigated crimes were more
often than not
they become big problems
because
i don't learn anything new with all you
people breaking into systems
you're not on the leading edge for the
most part you know like it
what the guy who barton meets or
something like that he was out there
saying there aren't very many good hacks
going on
and that's true
next slide please
uh... now even when i am catching them
they're not good
okay first of all my attitude on this
unfortunately again you know being
called the modern-day james bond
when you read it and when i write about
it
you're gonna see if i don't really think
what i do is unique
i lie to people
i hacked into computers
and to me that's not special and i've
been quoted as saying i could train a
monkey to hack a computer within two
hours
and that's true
i can teach anyone you little tools
kitties out there a software poppies to
go ahead and have to computer with the
best within two hours
all you need to know is the right
information
again breaking into a computer systems
pretty mindless these days
and again most of all it takes is nerve
in the willingness to commit criminal
actions
that's all really takes to be a hacker
these days again people call let me say
people calling themselves a hacker
cuz i think there are a lot of people
calling themselves i have heard who
really aren't hackers and i think the
better ones know what i mean
and again
you know as far as people getting jobs
it's much easier for me to train an
honest person tak like a criminal
than it is for me to train a hacker
and make them act like an honest person
there's again the people i look forward
to do penetration test with me
are primarily good system administrators
who i have to do is teacher few little
skills teach them how to do things in
reverse
that's life
oak and as far as this presentation goes
i'm not here to teacher criminal methods
i think too many people are going to use
them abut again you know i guess they
don
some sort of prostitute is something do
you want to learn how you can buy my
book or go on the internet
it's available for free or my book is
really good you can all take your pick
okay let's talk about criminals and the
hackers let's talk about how hackers and
criminals collide that will go into some
details on actual criminal hacks
d cover that up please
or just unplug it
yeah this is really sophisticated
first of all let me talk about the inner
circle the circles are what i consider
to be the hacker community
outlines a little bit on will for
something before i go into this
five perceive people
growing into the hackers
what i see is a i mean in my opinion
even though i don't think a lot of many
hackers i think they do go into hacking
for well-meaning purposes
for the most part i've seen what
elementary schools teach students
in other words
they teach students a little bit about
computers they teach them how to buddha
mob
and go through reader rabbit for six
years
and then if you go through rita rabbit
decline in interest it'll open in
computers
and one of our and more
and they have to go to your teachers
that i want to learn more and they like
sorry
than you don't go to ask your mother get
your tutor and the odds are that are
almost nil
so what happens you get out there on the
internet
and you run into people on the internet
you run into things you run into wanting
to do fun things
now what are fun things well
computer hacking
that's the simplest in the easiest thing
that come to mind
you know again there's out there's
people out there tell u all your freedom
fighter if you're a hacker
you know you're protecting the world if
you're a hacker you're really a lead if
europe after the meeting is out there
helping this would stupid movies like
the movie hackers for example
and you know it's really cool
you know so what do you do
you go ahead and with an honest effort
to be cut learn more about the puter as
you get sucked in
but the people out there a telling all
breaking into computers
that makes you leave
you know breaking into computers makes
you a boy or while talk about that the
into my briefing
but anyway
that's my impression help people become
happens usually have to have to get a
real job
you know most of you outgrow this stuff
because most people again aren't that
good aren't good enough to get jobs to
penetration testing all talk about that
okay now back to this thing
first of all there's this in a circle
here
these are the people that
for lack of a better term i what i
consider the true geniuses
you've got people in your like minds
route other people like this and what
these people do
is they find problems with software
programs
hacking is nothing more well exploiting
a computer is nothing more than finding
a problem with an operating system or
some sort of computer application
and what happens is
these people are the smart ones
these people are the real genius is that
the media would like to portray as the
evil people
but these are the people that are out
there just trying to
learn about computers like every hacker
claims they are trying to do
so again you got these people finding
problems with computers
they put out the information to anyone
that wants it
they also pointed out to the second
inner circle
these are the people that are
necessarily sprite you know as as smart
as much or bobbitt
but these are people that go out and can
really use these tools very well
they can actually develop tools off the
information developed by this in a
circle
then you have what i consider the rest
the hacker game by the way i you know i
from what i've been able to see
despite out two hundred people in the
inner circle maybe about a thousand and
two thousand people
on the uh... on the second inner circle
they got the outer circle
and these are what hobby and much at all
those other people consider to be
clueless teenagers
and again these are people that take the
information that the genius is due
and they go ahead and use the tools to
break into computers
and again you break sickly they're using
tools to break into computers they try
to prove their elite and all that sort
of stuff
and what they end up doing is feeding
information
back into the work that the other half
or so for example
when i'm investigating computer crimes
alcee some clueless teenagers out there
who break into a bank
you know again they'll get delphi
building some password guessing they'll
find an account without pay user i_d_
dumb tax n mail for a hundred fifty
times
and i'll be able to buy the user idea in
a bank
then the first thing they like to do is
go out and to the world hey guys i
believe i'm not a loser
so what are they do
on of bulletin boards they go ahead and
say hey i'm really cool gimme wearers
nine people of harassing that posting
these are the people that are includes
actually read it and get a laugh out of
it
because all other clueless people say oh
he's a leave let me give them whatever i
have
but anyway
these people are out there they go ahead
in order to prove that they know
something
they'll say here's the account i found
here's the credit card number i found or
whatever
so attacks into computers end up getting
put out on the internet
or bulletin boards or wherever but
primarily the worldwide web is where
allow disinformation sets
then again these are those of the inner
circles they've got these little things
that kind of look like an airplane
airplane propeller actually that's the
way half opic called it
but anyway what happens is
you have these ellipses out here which i
consider criminals over here this side
and foreign intelligence agencies over
here at the side
now what happens is the far end
well let's talk about organized crime
this ellipse i say goes a little bit
into the inner circle cause there are
people in what i consider the inner
circle that are working for criminal
elements
it's incredibly profitable to work for
them
and some of them have used their skills
again primarily for criminal purposes
now what happens is they go ahead
and organized crime tends to use their
own people which is the section out here
the you some of the clueless people
cause
you know they're good to take a fall
let's put them out on the women
ifn by takes the fall it'll be them
which is most of you i think
anyway then you got a few people on the
inner circle and so on
organized crime also has a few of their
own geniuses those all those little
circles there
now what happens is these little
geniuses
are the people for example if you talk
about the russian mafia russian mafia is
very good
at recruiting former k_g_b_ train people
the g_r_u_ the russian military
intelligence agency
basic indirect rate have some of the
best computer hackers in the world
and it's much more profitable to work
for their organized crime
as oppose the russian military new by
the way is a pain anybody at the moment
so you got over a bunch of really good
people working for organized crime
and what they do is
primarily they look at the information
that's already out there they were they
get the tools
they get the information like here's an
account on this bank or here's an
account in this company
and they go ahead
and hacking using the information that
these little clueless people provide
they end up going in there
and using that information to steal
money
or steal information or whatever the
case is
sometimes these really smart people will
end up putting out some more tools
because if they develop an attack
that's it fairly easy to guess but it's
kind of
you know if it's if it's fairly easy to
guess what's going on but it looks a
very advanced in new
what they'll do is they'll put out the
tool
too though into the internet through
some like you know anonymous postings
and things like that
and then all the whereas kiddies in
everybody start picking up on these
tools
and then those whereas kiddies end up
going out
and using these tools much more than the
criminals do
so finally when the criminals this when
the criminals decide to use the tools
what's happening is
they're using this tool which is using
this attack
which is being hit in by all you other
clueless people out there running those
attacks
so you're hiding or real crimes and
again when i've investigated bank
robberies and stuff like this
for for and stuff like that for every
one real crime i'm supposed to be
investigating are usually end up running
off investigating a dozen little petty
crimes like stupid password guessing
trying things like
field service on route no password rude
rude rude juror or whatever
for all you people are guessing it
every time i see one of those i kind of
have to stop what i'm doing
and figuring out if it's some clueless
person which you usually is
or it's somebody just doing some forward
reconnaissance to see how easy would be
to break into the spanker organization
to go back and steal information later
'cause again the criminals are out there
using the same tools
and they're lazy they want to do it
quickly
so that they get the highest paid back
and they're going to try to default
things just like you do
so if you think own oh well the
intention is good let me tell you
the difference in in tension between
hackers and criminals is about five
keystrokes
you have to see what's going on up until
the point where those five keystroke
sergei
for example if it's a competitor warning
to take down the company all you have to
do is take foreign star
you know r m star returned five
keystrokes they've wiped out a whole
corporate network possibly
survey on the stand that one at least
our agm
everybody know what our anis
r m remove
no problem
uh... so anyway that's what happens
they got the foreign intelligence
agencies essentially doing the same
things
and if a car or foreign intelligence
agency needs something they go ahead
and if the fight for example they want
to break into a specific organization
they'll go out in two point attackers
are really trying to prove that they
really
and they'll go out and say all if you
were cool
or if you are if you weren't the loser
that you are you'll go ahead and get a
login at this company
and then the actor will eventually go
out and get along with the company what
they do is
they use the clueless hackers to do
their late work like i said and again
foreign intelligence agencies organized
crime
all tend to use the same methods
in-game information
any questions on that
go elya
sorrows
flap proof of the links
yet lol i personally witness most of
them
well actually for example on
one of them is fairly well i've seen far
intelligence agencies by the way i'll
talk about this in a second q s t
bulletin board anybody you know that
if you're happy back in them early
nineteen nineties
to usd an a_ c_ k_ which is a german
bulletin board system
were the places to go in exchange
information
q s t is run by the french foreign
intelligence agency that the g_s_a_
she eight c_k_ is supposedly run by
project for a half which is uh... the
boom well whatever be andy breaks out
too
which is the german foreign intelligence
agency
so there were out there planting
soliciting information
and all this information was following
through these bulletin boards maintained
by the foreign intelligence agencies
now talk about a few more
well talking a few more
take the book open
k'nex line
okay let's talk about examples of crimes
as mentioning before about on how people
are tong did
uh... in one case we saw this person
which we do traced back to the russian
mafia
and he was out there on all the bulletin
boards could be kept noticing this
pattern
where he would be on this bulletin board
saying all if you are any good to have
something at this bank if you're any
good to have something at this bank
during good yeah something at this bank
and eventually he found some eyes like
all yeah well i have since i have super
user there
as i can really prove it
and the kid gave him
the super user privileges for a system
which was an s or the financial trading
systems
but it did provide the criminal foot in
the dorcas we watched him come back into
the organization
try to break in
and try to get super user privileges
based on that
next on there's the israeli government
which is doing an awful lot of this
a lot of times in the rolling in the
u_s_ the jewett israeli government
is really good for recruiting people
based based upon being jewish
and they go ahead and they have a lot of
people out there for example comming
industrial espionage for example
jonathan pollard
you have the navy cases which are going
on besides apology dot some other people
and again most of this you know they're
going out income convincing people do
espionage
there also convincing a bunch of jewish
hackers
to travel over to israel
and they're putting them up for aguirre
to and their out there hacking and i
know people who know the person who's
out there have been out was really good
and again there been other people
well this was actually a good one
uh... my nose person works for a very
large company
and what happened was
they had some might hacking into a
computer system
align which was
essentially
dot under a defense
sent into a building
and then hooked onto the network
and it turns out when they followed that
back to link
he turned out to go right to the israeli
embassy
so again you know just little things
like that
but of course they'll never get the
media 'cause nobody likes
noi like sat down
israelis are hacking u_s_ computers
everybody's hacking u_s_ computers
you know it's a given
u_s_'s like height you know u_s_ is
still the technology leader in the world
were invented even though everybody says
oh the japanese
the japanese are good at taking
technologies in using them in innovative
ways
they're not good at developing the
technologies up front
i for example the walkman
the walkman is nothing more than u_s_
develop technologies put together in a
unique way
and same thing with software programs
and things like that
then there was project black book
and again this is where the japanese
were recruiting a lot of u_s_ hackers
and again people i know i've been
personally approaching and these are
some of the real elite ones
and they were approached by the japanese
government
hey we can make light very easy for you
if you come over here
and do what you love doing
the u_s_ government doesn't appreciate
the hackers like we do
why don't you come here
and we will love you for it
and again
there were three three people that we
know that they go over a month the
arrest them turned them down
anyway on there's also hackers being
solicited on a regular basis
i don't know that uh... they're better
hack well
let me tell you about the criminal
underworld now this will be of gold for
half of you are bad
but what happens is they're a bunch of
hackers are known to be very good
you know there are people out there
who liked post really good stuff to
bulletin boards
there's also those anonymous posting
stalled out twenty six hundred anybody
ever see one
where you know happier you know come
here and
if you're good and you've done cracking
you'll respond back to the synonymous
address i've seen three of them over
like a past three years
but what happens is
people replied to those most summer jobs
but every so often there's one or two
which say hehe
if you can get this file and what they
do is they test them
became a file that they know it's hard
to get they say if you can do this will
give you money
and again that's just to get them
something say go ahead and they get
about thousand dollars fraph
for getting this file then what happens
is their periodically test
and the way it works again testing is
done primarily for anonymous email
and what happens is you send back
you send back your
the program the file whatever
to the people anonymously
and then you get a check from a
seven-eleven money order
in the mail sometime in the near future
and apparently i know to people that
have told me they did it any game we
check this out little bit
doesn't look like they're lying
and when i asked them how many other
people they know they're doing it
they say there's about a hundred hackers
out there who make a living doing this
for example they'll say that on average
they get paid one to two thousand
dollars per person doing this
some of them work in teams
but for example it might be five people
working together
well charts like two thousand dollars a
pop but these five people can keep
on an ongoing basis taking a lot of
these jobs
they say on average if you're really
good
and they know you and somehow you're
into this little very tight network
you can make on average a hundred
thousand a year
and that's kinda like the profession
line a little in very organized
but that's a little underground there
that does that there's also another set
of people where some people just no you
owe you claim to be a hacker
i know one guy who was solicited
by this couple that said hey you know
you're kind of like famous arches like
well yeah now what happened was they
said
they approached him like a month later
and said look this is what we want you
to do
we want you to come into our company
on this day we will let we will get you
into the company after-hours and we want
to go ahead transfer five million
dollars for us and you could take
whatever you can get the czar company
does financial transactions
you put one into the computer system
it'll run the next day and they need to
go ahead keep whatever
that he's like well
you know won't you be caught
as like no we know that they only audit
the computer system once a month
so in other words will have a month to
get out of the country
again the guy tells me turned it down to
be nice to think so but anyway that's a
separate story
but this or stuff goes on again another
hacker i know
was approached by
uh... this is actually kinda funny a
porno a guy who runs a portal website
and what happened was
he said i want to find out
with this other competing portal website
offers them for what prices
by also wanna find out their customers
are so i could go ahead and solicit
their customers so i can offer them
cheaper porno
and again you know
i would imagine a lot of that goes on
'cause i don't know how many people
i think there was one study i think a
few people can correct me
but wasn't it like
porno on the internet civilian dollar
industry
does that kind of people read the same
thing but again its work a lot of money
might not be a billion dollars but it's
worth a lot of money
that is the biggest commercial use of
the internet as far as i know
okay i also met those are a few examples
of hackers being solicited for crimes
i'd also mention that u_s_d_a_ they seek
a bulletin boards that are ryan
it was kinda cool let me tell you the
way some i've found that u_s_ t
was a run by
deje counts are part of the deje asi
is kinda funny a hacker
hacked the bulletin board and found that
it was taxed to the deje asi network
and again that's just really stupid
basie here the foreign intelligence
agencies make stupid mistakes
i'm excited ease
okay now let me talk about this
now getting back to this like the inner
circle the outer circle that's kind of
like the examples of basic rights of
talk about the morris
the presentation goes on
but the real hackers the people that are
out there trying to lauren about
computers
are offended by all the people that are
out there breaking cuz they say
you give us a bad name
there was at this on black
we were at the black cap briefings which
was right before death time
where the heck it's got together and
support professionals
how to protect their computers based
upon how people penetrate computers
and what happened was
you know they were there meet the
hackers and i don't consider this a
typical hacker panel
you know you had hobbits you had route
you had mileage
and a few other people
you know those are your typical hackers
a nearby say well what about all those
people
they're just out there using the tools
you developed to break in
and their core was there not hackers
they're clueless teenagers
now if i asked how many of you are
clueless teenagers that just using tools
to break into systems
or just grabs people give your tell you
all the type in p_s_ minus a u_s_
sinning till
you know i'd bet if any of u_s_ it
honestly about half the room would raise
your hands
so again
you know this is they start getting
offended by this next please
k they say gives hackers a bad name
talked about that
and they use the term again they use the
term feliz teenagers not hackers
and again
this is kind of you know hit on me
because
i'm saying here try to figure out
who goes in which circles anyway
containing
and again their quote was hacking is
about learning
not about breaking into computers
breaking into computers again is totally
clueless
hacking is about warning about the
internals about computers networking
headed to new in unique things with it
finding problems with it
it's not about running sendmail a
hundred fifty times next
okay and let's talk about r_u_ clueless
let's figure out if you fit into these
categories
some of you already kinda get the
feeling you know where you are that's
good
okay it's a ten point asp
and see what circle you fit into
and again this came at a black at
discussions it
i kinda check the questions i would much
in hobby to see if they're fair
and again the purpose of this is just
the sea
if you're really out there break into
computers
where you're really out there to learn
anyway next
okay first question
have you ever written app third
generation language program are more
than five hundred lines
well let me ask this cut i think people
know what a third-generation languages
all this is the fed
third-generation languages like c
basic is even a third generate marol
etcetera
okay next
one points for yes
and the reason for this as a question
is that if you can't program a slightly
complex program
you're it then you really don't
understand operating system source code
puzzles operating systems you break into
are nothing more than a series of source
code their programs
you know l sendmail isn't just this
thing that's camille lead there for
hackers to break into them
sent mails actually a software program
that's supposed to do it useful thing
sangli keep that in mind
and subtract a half-point if you've
never programs
can you understand attack scripts
line-by-line
one point three s
and if you don't bother looking at them
before you've run and then you're really
stupid
you know if you're going to go to a
website and download a hacker program
you know let's face it their first
packet be let's see which morons gonna
download this program
and does run it without checking it out
you'd be surprised now made people are
there i know some by that went to you
know the job i hacked page
they went ahead and set click on this
for the job a hack
and he said well wait a second let me
he had a clue and the first thing he did
was turn off java
then it clicked on the wait a minute
chug away for a second that's like
how the hell a my gun out go ahead and
destroy your hard drive if you have java
turned off
so anyway i just think that in mind
kenya port scripts to other platforms
one point for yes
and then this basically shows that you
understand attack scripts and know the
difference between different operating
systems environments
for example
the load module a tax credit
is going to run one way on a celeste box
that's gonna run another way on in h_p_
box and so on in you have to know where
where to look for files
and maybe
well that's the next question go ahead
you can modify the tools for
optimization
or bob fixes
you know a lot of the tools well go on
one point for yes
and again tools had varying quality and
it shows that you can understand them in
other words
they would be cool when i'm writing an
exploitation script i delet off the
internet and yes i'd aloe them off the
internet when doing penetration testing
this hey i'm getting paid and i wanna do
it quickly
but i'm going to take those scripts look
at 'em line-by-line
and then make like a super attack script
on it
that automatically goes out searches
likely directories
and says hey wait a second this is this
type of box
then this files in this location in
needs these paramus
so you go ahead and write a nice little
tax group which optimizes what's going
on
this is a big question in my mind
have you at least tried
and applied to the word is tried
to write your own attack script based
often advisory for example you have
certain advisory sciatica eyes res
yep postings to bog track
yep postings to cipher ponds and things
like that
and you find out they say here is a
problem with the computer
you should go out and if you really want
to learn about them peters
you should try to say hey
i'm gonna see if i have half a brain i'm
gonna see it well unless if i can apply
what i learned and develop my own
attacks propnex
one point for yes
subtract three points for now and again
this shows your understanding and more
importantly
your willingness
to apply what you've learned i don't
condone here i am attack scripts in
doing it
by realize you're going to try to use
them but the question is are do you have
half a brain
and the energy and effort
willing to try to go ahead and apply it
what you claim to be learned about them
theaters next
have you ever installed lenox or another
units operating system on your own
computer system
i'll even give u_n_c_ server what the
hell
one point for yes
and again this is really gain your hands
on the internals cuz
i don't think you should be hacking
somebody else's computer system
before it right back in your own
and again it's free
you can get limits for free you can get
you know go out there and buy from
the law ought to combine openbsd you
can't download versions of b_s_t_
if you wanna learn about computers what
better computer learn about
the one that you don't have to worry
that they're finding out that you're
there
so again all this is widely and freely
available for you to learn about
computers it that's our goal next
find an install needed patches in other
words after you've gone ahead and
install limits r_n_c_ or whatever
go ahead and fix it so it's a secure
system one point for yes
and for the most part for those of you
that don't realize this it's much harder
to protect the system than it is to
attack it
and i ever find that out
very good
so anyway
you have to go ahead and finding install
the need to patches in this shows you
really
at least are trying to learn
how to protect the computer and besides
that i'll get that
returned to you
besides that it's a marketable skill
that you claim to be trying to learn
okay next network multiple systems
one point for gas
and again apply what you should be
learned let me go back i should explain
that slightly more
why me by networking multiple systems is
that you actually go ahead you have your
box
you might buy another box of five
hundred dollars
or borrowed your friends box tell your
friends who bring it over
or maybe you can connect over the
internet via modems
and try to get them working sharing
files and all that sort of stuff
well that you hit the returned i think
this is there
and again it's learning tool it's also
protect the network next
and it's also uh... it's also a very
profitable skill to have
next
can you get shared printers working on
the network
one point three s
if you've ever had been a stereo system
if you've ever administered a system
you'll know why this is important
let me tell you
i've had praised talking to apple's
talking to little windy windows three
one one boxes
and damn it if you ever get though those
printers working together properly
you know printers will be your biggest
downfall next
have you ever maintained a multi
platform network
one point for yes
and if you know what multi platform
means i'll give you a half-point
how many people know what that means
it's a start
multi platform means
that you're running multiple operating
systems on a single network
have you ever stolen a telephone handset
because you think that makes you a freak
or
you'd be surprised
subtract five points trieste
you know a lot of people think this is
funny but i mean honestly it should've
been likes attract fifteen or something
you know i mean israeli looks funny but
you know for some reason everybody was
out of death con likey not this year but
last year
and all the telephone handsets at the
monte carlo were missing
that really makes you hackers look very
good
and for some reason i really wonder why
you think petty theft makes you a hacker
or as part of hacker culture
now just a thought to think about
have you ever intentionally change the
computer system you have to work damage
the system
actually that he had damaged
don't even bother telling your story
you know again
remember
you're out there to learn they're not
out there it was mine
let's total this up
seven to ten you're probably not
clueless
five or six you're off to a good start
there are four you're definitely
clewiston yes for those people have
stolen telephone handsets
keep a low profile
okay let me stop and talk a word about
software testing 'cause now it's time
now marketable skills there
you know everybody thing software
testing is kind of like a very low tech
thing to do
is the job you get when you really suck
at everything else
well let me tell you
what do you think that loft is doing
they're out there finding problems as
software they're out there were looking
at the internals
and to me i don't know why they doing
this
but essentially they're doing beta
testing from microsoft in my opinion for
free
you know i think they've gotta figure
out way to get paid for but that's their
business not mine
but anyway this is really though how you
learn about a computer system if you are
interested in hacking
hacking chichi you if you're doing to
legally should be nothing more then
software testing
you want to beat the system to death
and find out what the problem is how the
system to work in all that
and decide that you know some people do
pay a lot for people doing that to them
okay this is a big thing
computers were not developed for your
enjoyment
nobody develop sendmail
so that you have something to do on a
dark evening
sendmail is there for a purpose
the only reasons computers exist is
because they serve a business purposes
is what people don't realize
when i was up on a on the pact on the
penetration testing panel
you know we were talking about
if you just back into a computer system
proves nothing
but when you hand the c_e_o_ their it
basically you hand the c_e_o_ their
company's ads
that gets their attention
wide because computers are a tool that
doesn't matter
if you break into a computer matters
what you do with an after you break in
and again
if you have a computer
it does america to that you have a
computer singer matters what do you deal
with it at home
and again
college helps you understand this next
wek
and i want to make any comments on the
last thing if you want to be stupid
that's your thing if you don't want to
degrade
and you want to get paid him get stuffed
into a system administrator career path
for your whole life
that's your privilege not mine
and the big thing why i think the
college to get education is a little bit
more important
and actually this is more for anything
else
if you can write or you can communicate
your really doesn't make it dan
if the people of the loft went out and
just found a bunch of software bugs and
intel and by about it
could and explain that
and in endless like fashion that people
would you know that people can
understand it would be totally useless
and any practice you get writing or
talking or whatever
helps you be more effective
at doing things
again it helps you out there it helps
you communicate better
it helps you get paid more
is i don't know yet
you know i'm not there are a lot of
people much more qualified than i am
that do the job i do
the thing is i can express my opinions
better
and i can also expressed to management
what the implications are communications
make sure that much more elite if you
want to call it that
okay so if you're not trying to learn
about them pewter system star head
don't call yourself a hacker
you know if you're not out there trying
to learn about the internals if you're
not out there trying to go ahead
and find out the problems find out how
to improve your own computer systems
don't call yourself a hacker
call yourself what you are which is
avoid are
iconic don't like that thing
and it kind of you know it's a little
bit more cd they need is our but
on next
pull yourself again pta
you know i'm not here high grew up in
brooklyn new york
for everybody is out there in the
apartment building in all these all
ladies
who don't have a life for their own
try to make a life of their own by
talking about what other people are
doing
why ask hackers what they're doing is
like
are we just want to learn the
information that's being kept from us
it's like well first of all before you
want to learn the information about me
for example
tell me everything about yourself tell
me everything about your family
tell me was the last time you went to
the bathroom tell me every all your
money
tell me where you can keep it tell me
everything about your life
they don't want to do that for some
reason
but the yet they want to know the same
thing about all of you as long as it's
not them
you know there's some little dollar you
know irony about this
and i gotto admit uh... you know a
little bit is a bit of this is
hypocritical
night meyer manual goldstein in some
ways but for example
he was on a t_v_ show
or actually was on his radio show once
where he was saying how he doesn't want
anybody to know for example that he
brought this case of beer because he was
upset
that he went into a store
and he took down some information about
when he bought the bear
and what happened was you know nobody
wants that nobody wants a might have a
record of that
not just with now because you're bashing
for beer because it's not of a buy stock
in business
if it's on a computer system all of you
wanna learn about it as long as dot
about you
and for some reason
everybody can understand that
nice but i think that's stupid
sedi way
if you don't like the word ghanta 'cause
it does it you know it's not high-tech
enough for you go ahead
call yourself a digital yen tha
that's really what you are
if you don't have a life of your own e
just try to break into computers to
learn about all this hit in information
your digital yanked out
just remember this is game back more
into the criminal stuff
good doing talk a little bit more about
that
you're helping the criminals no matter
what your intentions
again most people think it's a good
thing to exchange information
again the loft is out there they realize
their tools are being used by criminals
and again
that's part of what they're doing
uh... and they've realized that again
you know thought is if companies were
protecting themselves well enough
it wouldn't matter
and again to a certain extent i have to
agree to that the promise of criminals
are still out there exploiting it
um... the big thing though is again this
happens on a regular basis cuz i mean
tell you
the criminals of foreign intelligence
agencies
every attack we've seen have been
straightforward attacks and then there
was a comments on mine eight all that's
just the ones are attaching
when we go ahead and put his line
stiffer where we see every dot gambit
that goes across
we can't tell which have which pacs are
being used
lots of government agencies do all the
better government agencies do this
the better companies do this
and again we're watching some new
attacks being developed and there are
very very very few of them
there's like one new attack that we see
every other month that's not reported
and again these are problems if you
think all it's out there on the leading
edge it's like no it's not
most of it is just send mail a hundred
fifty times you'd be surprised how many
people actually think that still good
now calling it now let's talk about this
for a while let's say you still think
that its right to have
which you probably do i'm not here to
change invites mine
i'm here to open up to rise a little bit
the laws are only going to get worse
you know bard meets uh... idea i'm sorry
for him
best arising his name
but basically he was up there saying
you're all doing allows a p_r_ job
and that's really true that you are
doing a lousy p_r_ job
but personally i don't think it's going
to get any better the world is out there
computers are becoming more more
connected
everybody has more more information on a
computer and i don't think people are
just in a welcome
hackers randomly choosing
which computers i got a break into
i don't think i want that idon't think
do you want somebody randomly choosing
to break into your computer breaking
into your credit record or whatever
you know so laws are only going to get
worse
and as other hackers will tell you and
this is the more important thing
everybody's out there is like but i'm
hacking and that's the right thing to do
it's like
well no again to quote the room
began to quote the initial speaker
what part of jail don't you understand
they really want to put people in jail
you know again prob that's what cops do
i mean people like to sail cops really
out there for the hackers note they
really
go with the gusto for anybody
they're trying to prosecute
and again
if you know it's a crime andy and let's
face it let's say you think they're
really out to screw you
if you think they're really out to screw
you
and you do something that's criminal and
might attract their attention
you gotta expect that when they catch if
they catch you doing something criminal
they're gonna really screw you
accept that as a fact
you know if he ever watch for red and
most you probably haven't but
don't do the crime if you can't do the
time
because again
your out there helping people
and again i want to keep reiterating
that when i'm there investigating a
crime
i'm going to head investigate a real
i'm not out there to put like you know
your clueless teenagers in jail because
it's not worth anybody's effort
although i should say there was a
teenager huamn took down a website with
that on microsoft's website hack if you
remember that
the one that took down the microsoft
site
but what happened was somebody use that
against the commercial website and they
had really good administrators how many
people know what they did
i can't believe that yet well let me
tell you they bailed
the part of the kids mother who did at
four thousand dollars for investigating
and fixing the problem
and again i'd like to see more that
there's a kind of puts on the effect
whose again hacking
itself if it's investigated properly
cost people money just to investigate
and again more importantly for my
purposes
i really don't want to waste my time
with you and i said earlier that you're
really all just pains in the ass we're
breaking into systems
that's really all you are i don't want
to bother with you i want to bother with
the criminals cuz
they're doing better things are more
interesting things
it's more fun to investigate somebody
that's doing a million dollars
and that's the really good stuff i don't
like to have to go up and do other
things 'cause again
you are giving them the tools and the
knowledge to attack the systems
and that's where hackers and criminals
collide again i have everything you know
again you're not just out there in a
bubble
you're out there in the real world
and let me tell you something
if a by by chance happens to
accidentally take down how financial
system
you think the government's going to come
after you well let's talk about this if
you want to get really scare about
breaking into banks
i don't know how many people realize
this but drug lawn ball money-laundering
involves a stable financial system
they like the banks up and running
caused billions of dollars are laundered
it legally
a day
and that's kind of a large sum of money
now if you are the russian mafia where
you are a drug cartel wondering a few
million dollars a day individually
and some hacker
accidentally took down the system
you're going to tested on
aim i get away with the wants well that
hacker might get away with it once if it
happens a second time
they're not gonna wait for a third time
they will will come after you
to make sure that their money laundering
will go on
and again just think that what they do
to like you know a little drug dealers
that steal money from them
little drug dealers and steal money from
them they come after they say this first
time we will forgive you for being
stupid
give us back the money
what happens away people turn themselves
that is they've already spent the money
bagel run into the police
but usually they sify in some way to get
the money back
if they steal money from the drug
cartels the second time they're really
in trouble
same thing if u scrub some sort of drug
deal
for some crime or some organized crime
thing
they will come after you when you do it
the second time please
they don't like things happening to
third time
and again you can uh...
you can actually read the newspapers on
this this is my source for one of them
where some
people were let's just say stacked
did some nasty things for
a criminal organization
and they did
some nasty things against the criminal
organization and they did come after
them
uh... that's about it i'm kinda rare
renting right now but
unless it quick question
how many people
score between seven and ten
yeah you
max
five to six
okay how many people are totally
clueless
yanked for people that i actually
admitted
but maybe this gives you a little bit of
guidance
on what you should be doing if you
really claim to be a hacker
versus being a digital yen tha
same way
uh... if there's nothing else
i will take questions if you have any
all sorry
corporate espionage twenty six dollars
almighty it was a recommended book at
amazon dot com in june and they were
cited for forty percent off
you might get it for like thirty percent
off now an amazon dot com
yet give your credit card over the
internet right on that network there
they'll be smart but anyway on
let's available barnes and noble and
better bookstores everywhere
all good
you know it's years you're seeing here
that dinner shouldn't have anything like
that and just you know myself before the
devils their system that you assume the
fix themselves
this is like uh... law office and they
know they have for microsoft all about
problems they have they don't believe
them
really the only way to get anyone to
burn
view that they have holes in their
systems the only way to anyone will be
safe as if you go ahead and take it in
your own hands and do the job now
so it's pet owner cn you know you're
kind of
almost contradicting yourself
basically what you're saying is
basically if i'm correct what you're
saying is that
it's
you know you are proving a point to
accompanied
europe using a company
to find a home with their system
i'm not saying that it's right that
microsoft close off lost problem you
know close off the proms law
what bob
what i'm saying is
and i really don't care
what goes on but basically what i'm
saying is
is that if you choose
if you take it upon yourself to prove to
an individual company
they're using the microsoft product
which has problems with it
and you get into the company
and you commit a crime to prove it
i don't really give a damn what your
attitude is
it's not my position to do it basically
if the company decides to prosecute you
criminally
they can
that's their position that's all i'm
saying
i'm not saying it's right or wrong i'm
saying if you decide to choose to do
that you're committing a crime
an expat
to go repre questions and don't say for
me i couldn't expect this it's like now
you know they're gonna come after you in
space
can see that
you're referring to people like us as
you know a pain he has to you
years assuming that every corporation
as a network or has any type of
need for security is going to hire
people like you and spend the money for
it
and build is assume that they have told
c_n_n_ are not not not assuming that i
know most of them don't
are going to companies like five
millions of falls
i walk out there tom how to fix it
i can guarantee they're still millions
of polls a year later
i know that's not the case
what i basically saying is that if you
go ahead
hackett computer system
to prove that there is a problem
to the company you're committing a crime
the repertoire since from that i'm not
saying it's right or wrong
i'm not saying companies are smart but
the promise when hackers break-in and
i'd always
this is the point l always comes back to
you
when hackers
break into a computer system
if you want to do good
but the system administrator no the
promise hackers that are out there
breaking into the computers
they don't want to do the right thing
and let the sysadmin so maybe about two
or three people i've actually heard of
actually have actually done that most of
the side of the place the policy
information
is on some bulletin board or some
a website
to prove they relieved they're more
interested in proving their elite
than doing what you are saying is the
noble thing which could be the noble
thing to prove their is prompted helped
the company fix it
yeah i i i wanted to do
to make the
of
your industry's roland
leslie the halls that are smiling all
people because a lot of obama understand
how quickly
they're beautiful
yes sir
i say this there are a lot of companies
that have a bunch of really good system
in ministry here's again if you go to
lisa conference
there's thousands of people going there
these are people that are actually
learning how to do things right
and that's just internally
farther as far as business goes and
since that response businesses
you have companies like i_b_m_ essay i
see
and a bunch of other consulting
companies are doing in service ponds
you got the real group which is out
there bringing uh... 'em detection
systems there
and again people are getting better like
i gave the example before
the candidates mother
even better than the kid was sent a bill
for four thousand dollars
there are a lot more packers in jail
than you do know about
every time i could for example
inc magazine excerpted my book
i got three letters from people in
prison
saying
all i'd love to work for you
you know again that's just the thing
all on one of the better hackers will
ever find
it's hard to find a social engineer
better than me you know being the hacker
michael you should read my book
but anyway
that's you know there a lot of people in
jail it's not going to be a shrinking
phenomenon
f_b_i_ computers crimes flight
is supposed to grow to seventy-five
agents just at the central location
when right now they're used to be
i think it was fifteen
so it's growing by over five times and
there are getting better train bynoe
they want me to help train but that's a
separate issue
sorry pat
getting back to your circles
uh...
what do you think the people in the
inner circle started circle lines
you think that they started in the outer
local doubled up
without a cell like this is hope for the
enters a
now there is hope for the united states
they do decide they don't want to be
getting his
the problem is they're not interested in
going out there and learning
books out there damn good books when the
people started they had to go into
almost elite status because of the
nineteen eighties
there were no computers computers were
expensive
these days you can buy a used to be a
cycle but i don't want to buy a four
eighty six
but yes you can buy a four eight-six for
two hundred dollars
and run limits on it and again the
people originally like the law
they started out wanting to learn about
computers and they might have had to
break into learn
but that's a separate issue right now if
you think to some of the people in the
inner circle actually started on the
other hand then moved in i mean it seems
like
yes i mean everybody has to start the
outer
i mean i put dennis based on your
intentions with liam will benefit
it's based on intentions if you want to
learn about them uterus you will get
into the inner circle
just as you want to persevere
and again you have to one of her sit
there and learning about computers
now learning about other people's
business yeah
you said earlier that
the problem you have
when people break into a system is when
they start committing crimes in the
system
uh... but now isn't technically just
breaking into the future of crime
yes on let me say so then how are we
supposed to
inform anyone
it just by breaking into the system
we're already were already criminal
and then by letting the people know
cm all foreign aid and assistance to
turn over the break into a system
because that's what she feels
but it was nothing gets all let me put
it this way i have
never heard of a by going to jail
by letting asus admin know that they
have a problem
and you just email route that system
or sysadmin or like mid postmaster
whatever
the only person that knows that they
have a whole at that point is the admin
if they're stupid enough to let a little
yet by the way left our computer system
wide open
nobody has got me that uh...
prosecute you because you're just
telling them they have a problem they
have to actually
prove that you were there in order to
prosecute you or do anything
but is it just feel that you sent them
to did you with their
now i just need to make their know you
could be totally wrong for the test i
don't mean that group dot the
administrator
okay because i've seen this a lot
i can't tell it isn't ministers you know
that they go to jail to get in trouble
you know institute the belief that the
cold on that subject it every night at
nine a
finance dot pano
kanata hetnet dot efy
that's a good way of doing it
wrote thanks alot
i thought they open back up
there's three dozen other and not a
lowest in the database was turned over
to the justice
object dot
so gulf using i mean there's dozens of
an honest three mailers
yet have itself
more of a state are hardly legislative
it's in the uh... the angle that you've
taken this kinda like a kind of person a
lot of people in the place but to me it
just seems that you need to take a
little bit more about you point between
our your your godliness and you know how
to work to stop and the average against
that doesn't know how the program is
p_c_r_ david that is another begin
therefore hacker to exist in between
those two points
i've i've probably sport like very alone
your testified
uh... it seems that attacker can exist
a new just a between those two point
noah hacker passes these days
because you can go ahead take college
courses
if you go ahead get a bunches
you can go ahead read books load your
own computer with an x
you can go ahead by
debt with friends
network the computers together
practice for the prompt likert like that
better people are doing right out there
today
they're going out there today
and practicing hacking into each other's
computer systems on their laptops
as you know you'd like i said out there
it's like you know the people doing the
passport sniffing
you know they're going to head on the
network where it's okay
and you can set up your own network
saying okay i know hackers
boots that i've been around you know
i've been arrested i don't want to deal
with this
and they go out and set up their
networks in the eighth
about what had been doesn't have to be
on unix and media
it's just
it just uh... i mean your probably
really really good at doing that and
really really good
on those was also a hesitancy while
they're about computers
you can take up graphics program you can
develop your own gains why bother paying
fifty dollars somebody else's game
and i think it's easy
that's the problem
it's really easy to just want to be a
digital yetta
the hard part is going on in michigan
there
to one of the earned about computers
and take the effort to read books to go
through installation manuals to get
openbsd
alone on the system sorry
pass that test
as some of those
built eleven as well
and written books
both of the consulting practice
you are right fucking
to people agree
i want to encourage everyone
jeppesen computers gets an ethernet
cards
stick it in your laundry room
loaded up
and look at it
the time that i started learning
operating systems with united
they got a question that night
and then go downstairs
airs in the middle of the night and try
it out
and then go back to bed
this is the way he won't work
and that's what he's talking about so by
some cheap computers
it doesn't have to be one x it doesn't
have to be your next week
you get a lot of the
consulting on into a problem
is anywhere from last year
actually haha just walked in
i know but certainly better than that
good question
when when you're when you're looking at
uh...
inefficiencies
in microsoft products
do you do it on
uh... corporate networks for two
you do it on your own network
what
alright anyway
anywhere
military prosecuted for it
break it into your own network that's
what i'm trying to say
and he's with swine six hundred magazine
in some ways to perform day
nevermind
of just just the volunteer
hiatus jayanti very well only if they
are all in a shortly
i'm just curious because i know that
parking where we have a
computer science department and we also
had a delicate and it's a constant
war going on because the main issue just
relaxed oh what goes on i'm just curious
how you would
but what's your opinion in the opposite
direction
jewlery administrators not just the
people who are trying to go against serb
anterior do what not
what is your opinion on the ambassador
to make it easier for these people
day using tools are packages okay okay
let me talk about this i think most
people will appreciate this position
actually
i think most administrators
barbieri are either
are poor are under trained in overworked
also underpaid as a matter of fact
a lot of companies these days
reap the benefits of of
automating their entire company
but it's not like well i can understand
by a computer system but
i have to hire a new person
or i'd have to send that person to a
class
bikes at well that person administered
windows three one for workgroups
followed our windows n_t_ a big deal
that must be the same thing as a net you
know just the next generation what
happens is
at mold most administrators are
well-meaning
the problem is
well actually all relate this story i
was talking to stocks ronnie
whom some you prolly hate
he's a person in charge of the
department of justice
computer crime unit he's responsible for
investing
for prosecuting federal crimes dealing
with computer laws and he told me it
scared him when he first learned about
them peters they took a class in
baltimore
and he was saying around having the
teacher introduce everybody
well yeah he's like this one woman
struck struck dumb
she's like oh yeah hi my name sue uh...
i'm the admin i'm the new administrator
for my company and i was made the
administrator
because on well
we ended up
hi i was a person with the most computer
aptitude son now the administration here
learn about units or whatever
and that's who they put in
they tend to put in some might without
good degree then in putting somebody
should be well paid
and the companies are suffering for that
i'm not saying the company's
are free a blaine but i'm saying it's
still a crime that's all
but again companies are
tefl enough real blaine if they don't
want to put the truck the effort into
training their people but again it is
getting better there are better people
thanks
as you say that
arugula minister came in with a degree
in four st and uh...
you had to use that ought to be
mentioned dots so i guess it kinda shows
well again i don't say one degrees
better than another most of those who
say that mister i'm happy breeze
and i'm also a psychology major so i a m
uh... sucked back
yet thanks for your talk ayam
i definitely agree with
the gist of what you're saying much
seems to be uh...
for hacking to take place today you
don't need to break into anybody's
computers you can do it by yourself
do dinner on that in the privacy of your
own home just like all sorts of other
things that you could do it
that's nobody else's business
the excuse me
and i'm and i also agree
that uh...
for the most part the real difference
between the people that are here today
and the people that are committing the
true crimes that you
enjoy prosecuting that the crimes
i don't know there may be people here
who are here to find out about how to do
corporate espionage
or how to find out about have a small
secrets out of this country words with
other countries or whatever
it seems to me that
you know the most of the
people here and i started using
computers as a teenager
and it seems to be the most of the
people here you know younger people
people who are older
all have an interesting
informational technology not in criminal
technology and i really liked your talk
differentiating the two was very
informative but your attitude
towards calling people like digital
wannabes traditionally enters who are
here
you know that's definitely sort of more
should be more sort of directed towards
the people who wanted to crimes
but don't have any idea of how to do it
so highlights the whole thing
let me give you my attitude on that
apprised
and i'm saying they're trying to explain
to people know this is wrong you know
and really
it's sort of you know i hear people
getting up here in saint although you
know all your the best in the brightest
here that you're the information wars of
the future your this year that
when really i mean i got a limit
you know i've tried it both ways i've
sat down to talk to people
i tried talking to them nicely and i
don't know we're just wanna learn about
information we just want to do this and
my differentiation is if you are a
person who just wants to learn you know
read other people's email
i really have no respect for you
if you are a person
that wants to learn about computers
and in all honesty many of you do
who do fit into the clueless category
pour into my test
my test was meant it to be in a funny
way maybe it's a little harsher for some
people and they want to take
polite s was meant in a funny way to
give you a direction to go in other
words of learning when it's going ahead
in taking the next step after the next
to protect the system
they're going to head of protecting the
network
yeah again it's in your face type of
stuff at
i guess that's what the site called it
but on
honestly it's
that's just my style i have to apologize
if you are offended
and fit into the
you know fit into the wanna
learned category but there are a digital
yet i make no apologies
anyway i listen to dole's speech and i
got mixed reviews both ways whichever
way you want to take it
me personally being run around in acting
since the late nineteen eighties
i can understand where we first started
we had to do little things that you
think stupid or what happens to do
you call crime
i mean this day and age
what happens on the can do that
and me personally yes i did my time
got in trouble with the fed spent time
in rules for a prison camp and so forth
and so on
this day and age
maybe do you want
you'll have is one of the actors or
whatever you would like to uh... call
them mentors or whatever
they don't have to go through that but
back in the time when i started
computed c
there was something that was needed to
get information how would you be subtle
trash on another subject
but i've relied again
did position is that again i've got to
talk to other people the size of
you know i've talked let me put it this
way
i have a lot of good friends that fit it
that people would know of
and you know i'm so i'm not on the inner
hacker circle that a well-respected
and again these are people that i admit
if they wanted to learn about computers
in those days there was no such thing as
documentation
you know a later up and so i mean in all
honesty up until the nineteen
ninety
sue free time frame
you know computers were widely available
there was no such thing about the
internet
now not condoning this in any way but if
you do you wanna connect with computers
world wide and learning you know and
learn about other computer systems
you did have to do some level of packing
their phone freaking to get that access
and that's the thing is again like i
said up front
the intentions of these people were
purely honorable
the problem i'm having those lately
the intentions of the newer people
getting in there
the clueless teenagers as quote again
i believe it could be comment came from
route
you know the clue people f into the
clues teenager category
are not out there to learn about them
puter is
what i'm trying to do win this thing
again my purpose my presentation was to
help differentiate
who's a close teenager
and try to get them if they really do
you want to be a real hacker appoint to
the real hackers
or who they consider the real hackers
then i'll try to point them in a
direction i mean again the like you're
saying i sampled by clarify that up
front
by babbling outside but also at the same
time i've seen quite a few black base i
mean i see them at the
or one of the action you act is on the
way
peggy said all one one two or three them
with uh...
how the system and what's going on how
to handle
westley dodd
more than a dozen active set
i've met that shortly damn little
little groups that they go through
different system today
notify the system at
and at the same time activated at
notify the system admin office two
months later of course it would exploit
up on the website of p_b_s_
the digital
semester time but i think is
fair enough to let everybody know what
the exploitive
but i appreciate that and again the my
reaction to that is
if you're really posting that
information on a bulletin board
ill-equipped to supposing the
information on the bulletin board is to
let other people know you did it
i mean i know there's some mighty hacker
ethic which says
ono share your information given the
opportunity
i wish more hackers who do that
you know give them the opportunity to
fix this system before they posted
i know the loft is intelligence about
how they
release vulnerabilities you know so
there's a chance to fix it first
you know again my personal opinion is if
you're good
you're not out there to prove anything
to people if you broke n
your duties should be content enough
with yourself does otherwise in all
honesty if you let people know you just
advertising the facts
he did commit a crime
balance architect we don't have any
questions that i don't respect
european but
there are other people and i don't be
rude to the people following me
what would you say the portraits people
that don't have a
phone system in their bedroom to go and
play around with i mean that's back in
the nineteen eighties for just generic
here akers
my and i'm really
like you know my these adjust my
opinions and
as far as phone freaking goes on
that's to me as a really dangerous thing
'cause the people that sensitive phone
freaking
the people out of ten to do tended to do
it
it's just two easy for them to start
getting into
listening to friends family and people
they don't like
and tapping their phones
and again there's you know in my opinion
if you want to hack something to learn
about it that's one thing but when you
want a hack
when you and a hack and start listening
and invade people's privacy that's
another
sicily
digital wireless really difficult
on august again
if you thought about really want to get
in trouble and really want to do crimes
in time and all that sort of stuff
going after the phone system as a way to
get like elevated to like the ten most
wanted list thang
i'm not democrats
i'd just like to make a comment
you eighty-year
and i got the negative three on your
test by the way
i'd like to say
hangout
that hide
that i know that i know nothing and i
knew that before i came here
haven't told me
where to learn anything
you say if you say there are books out
there
where are they
of nine i haven't seen them
if you have to tell me this stuff if you
could tell me where i can go to learn i
would get back and let me let me start
right now and answer your question
okay first of all practical units and
internet security
good book i know a lot of people hated
all hate staffer or whatever
good book
prom belle of intense chess wiccan valid
and catching stalking the wiley hacker
firewalls type up
excellent book
corporate espionage of course excellent
book uma
so i accelerate read pages again the
basic sits out there
you know if you really want to learn
about doing stuff n c security though
and see security website a mailing list
go to ohio s_s_ dot net
hi acess dot net is an excellent site
with a lot of hotlinks summer links are
to mailing list should be should should
be subscribing to
they should also be to bulletin board
you should be reading by net web sites
and things like that i s s dot net
yes for information about write it down
troubles me
anyway what else some
sorry thank you very much i've been cut
out
thank you very much
oddly all stick around we have uh...
chasm with uh... fiberoptic is to be on
a couple minutes
uh... stick around