kick
and wire
hey what's up
this is a rip at all
only for 27 here my to the law
seems to think that I should you wanna
see weeds
but is gonna happen since mostly
here dispels well
well well people at the law the people
at CDC rock various operating systems
we give that a try with with our
OS you probably never heard about it
that's for very good reason speakers
it didn't get very far instead
what we a router doing is on the socks
or
unusual step because it's cases the
North boys overstepping
the South boys firearms issue
me Creek moving up here in 0
okay no real name with you
well yeah I'm I'm Rs and we've come to
the conclusion over the course of this
show unfortunately
don't happen because New York City laws
show you but become
to the conclusion over the course this
law that we're going to go ahead and
doors
sector 29 as the official handgun
and that was
thats really although I I have to say
this is entropy and he's asleep
as low-key basically when anyone
to styles route is about three to four
years old
originally stars Joe what do you mean
originally started hits
still should be a joke granted now a
twenty-seven members france
posture country collectively we are
technically
really we own every %uh
we need to discuss because we found
federal agencies taking it seriously
when I told her soccer
I saw coca-cola squirting out those
really
right at some federal agencies
users we just tell those rumors because
we don't do anything malicious need this
opportunity tell everyone do anything
here we'll period me
we don't do anything
by means cross-country I'm sure that I
understand why some
we r evil or so to speak
we try to do as much good as possible
our membership includes
the editors of rack magazine is pretty
widespread
this is Moses elders we
don't wanna be arrested by the feds
two-step not a good thing
it's not just that we don't do anything
with that
me we we have a lot of pipes in in the
works which is like a lot of space will
have a new york space
anyone's been not which is hopes by six
hundred
so long city but the route space will
eventually have enough servers
anybody time show just come and say hey
a two-run products server web server
run incoming pursuit of our servers yeah
a full toward I was
our website is up always has been up
just that we had some difficulties with
the internet that simply
but you'll find that be archives
actually
much even in some way or cash on that so
Pfizer it's just going to be all
I love you to give you a penny in for a
real soon now going out biggest art
on that all sorts essentially just
anything you can pick up granite were
mostly UNIX
must play it we do really dnt once in a
while that's what's
his loss K
we just need really the opportunity to
sponsor
spares you have no idea what it's like
to be kinda freaked out and
have potential to be treated by that one
day
I actually we will be happy
first its credibility has for
heard a rumor it's a bit like a slight
to people
were two people serve instantly but to
be 27 people spread across the country
working for some the biggest network
service providers programming houses and
engineering companies
if you are and what you said hey that's
a little like organized
the rumor I heard worries
where we actually do anything at all
right I mean
their people going out around their
sites and sticky
means them and signed in saying that we
did was
networks yeah database Bayside
and on the bottom accrediting room we
had nothing to do with I mean their site
awesome napping me sign with our logo
sister
that we just have nothing to do it and
work that we're taking which too old to
be doing shit like I
quite honestly we make too much money we
just Angello
virtually exactly just just two I mean
we'd love to tell you see here and tell
you
takedown networks is
that's what's up now it's possible even
know
we'll 4.5-inch know it. and
granny when I went to school secret
credit supply
love lot brilliant me well much our big
guys but their local organizing I was
just on think that was a witness
we're not we're not we're just a bunch
of guys that let's just hang out
just the law the tickets for me pressed
we
we aren't we r one-tenth organize have
to be
do all the stuff that's attributed to us
you its
I mean I see a lot of like kids coming
up these days a week
group I get male every weekday hey you
guys at the
hello dear modu the nineties I see
Goggins on the weekends like
got crack wired one-piece suits you and
absolutely right we don't want to be
like
its it's just environment where
these also smash skip
that just
so we really don't anticipate there'd be
any questions
we'd like to for questions just with
just one more thing
I mean anybody wants to come up here and
give
answers for us for the world well IMEI
Anderson come back to what some think
its time group's days as one should I
speak
its its it's one thing started before
five kids
local area I mean once you start gather
attention
it doesn't become that funny a lot of
responsibility penniless fan mail
I mean I'm see 26 week mass on a lot
considering
route was also member also crack
magazine
get some average 5200 friend he's
a media whore he is army I mean
a lot crack contribution much Mb
ties that we have to almost every other
group like killed I'll of course EC
group it's just a bunch of guys having
fun
that's all it is what should I start
taking a little bitty seriously
you gonna find yourself in a whole world
champ use I would say that given the
amount of stuff outside
sitting around grousing about interdict
get any Tiger I mean
it's just its really where you should be
aware
so we have a question front row year
I'm actually going to be really
residents both
own
okay you clarified
your statement that you said before we
own you
what's your own and specifically in hell
do you own okay
three years ago we r the mantra is
that we only look stupid because we
choose acts PS
and there is sorta said
that justices they're sort sent churches
geniuses only as a way of life owning
historically owning the pride of
ownership
exact much being able to break into
machine and Tony
group or de niro
certain core routers at
owning has changed from marks it's now
week
me you'd be surprised how many kids just
go out towards the cons
just said would be so afraid years
they want the pic like destroyed what we
not like that we're switching
guys that get too drunk and seven
creates
that exactly mean it is really
grant collectively we kid if we want to
yeah
we could public to its
to pick up her ass actually wanted to do
something with the cause mass
twice them spread across country were
large some large companies
because it's a Trestman at the same time
Rossi like in all in her mid-twenties we
have these in South joslin not about the
risk
or federal present so
in in summary video news but sasser's
a facetious on slogan really doesn't
have much
with it's been like
space like everything else do it first
first-line
that microphone up there out there okay
sorry it's alright I'll basically I i
cum
to this with very all
right replies short first
what are these things ledge dog
that's a first what is me I've got no
idea
this massive reputation undeserved
reputation
that you talk II don't as acecomm very
all second
woody possible for person to make
these things happen human being making
things happen
the Sun rose morning nobody at 10:15
make that happen
and their I
that so you can't those
to questions I at appreciate no
what these sorry spec that
late done and quoted
quickly could min agents be involved
in site speak up just a little bit
are you serious alright our for
getting a newfound respect for the
people get set up without a studio
monitor
got but i wanna know is I'll
what do these things that relates to
work done
whether or not Don I'll we don't do
anything literally well used to be kept
so all
that much these and second
it almost sounds like these are
with you talking about and I have no
idea really what these things are
that's good possible to to be done it's
almost
like are that something happened
nobody did it let's find somebody to
blame I don't know
this sort of thing that you talk
we we are categorically deny it anything
morally
jaywalking phones across street over
here are
the simple fact matters the most of
don't have time ball
it was legal yeah
if we want to be actually but do we
conscious decision
not week we find ourselves in a curious
situation
wearing we're were actually more stop
actually really happens ends up being
attributed to its
I have newfound respect for the
jewish bankers in the Masons and not
image
build burgers trilateral us
that that's exactly what it sounds like
talk about
thats on say the week
in that's not to say that we deny
categorically
we own the world in some stores
spiritual sense
and we where actually controlling some
fight scenes but we're not doing
anything illegal
haha thats explain yes next
I meets this what is it reserve
reputation love I'll
deed one that that your you
it said done out of the word accuse even
applies if nothing illegal it's been
going on
says just fun and games I don't know
what's being talked about
okay any outside right now what you
trying to do
is just get the heat of you
that don't have any use for said the use
just that we can afford
to have easily elected is achieved
a granite we did something most
to it because we have no possible
legal but we just it's on to a friend
machinists as a practical joke
yeah just a prank chip but yeppers
should should tribute to some within do
we've got to the point where our
membership
in the SoCal
are pretty much the elites said
Sony doesn't like to admit to it but
truth of the matter is
all twenty-some have have always been
pretty much right way I see it you guys
are
are three-year are actually for on-site
guys sleep
%uh to a whole bunch up people months
the computer
Technical Community you guys happen to
be well respected because you have a
very
tensely high degree of technical skill
nice
that very fundamental to the
core operations have internet
telecommunications et cetera so
for that you have a well deserved
respect in this family a lot of people
in this room in a lot of people
one soon be you or at your skill and
therefore
with all the disinformation and that
kinda sheik
a glorification of bad boys like Wired
Magazine
pumps out to the coca-cola job holla
consuming public or whatever
eg and movies like hackers away
glorifies is that is probably lotta
wannabes who found that
a the bug in the NT Ethernet card or
whatever and got in the back door and
put your logo on the site
because we're rootin
the may be wired magazine or printed
test well I see is basically is that
that there's a lot of perhaps wannabes
posing giving you guys
credit because they think its cool and
you go
and a it's unfortunate that people are
misbehaving that way and you have to
take the is is that a fair assumption
100 can speak no no I'm just nervous you
know i i
I personally like how I agree with I
Mounties does track you're likely to end
up drafted as three spokes
say what you have my way I'm a very good
medium for me
your lead but you've done a better job
cat
explain this than we ever thank you
thank you later
but know by anyway I just wanna say that
having never seen you guys in knowing
can do behind-the-scenes
I just want to give you my greatest
aberration because what you do makes
what I impossible not having your level
of skill
and if you ever find yourselves perhaps
in a position where
where I can employ you I'm very happy to
do so let's have a round of applause
these guys and stop these abortion
portion
lynching and you know it anything that
they have to share I came here to see
here
what I can learn from these guys not not
this in your hand and
look at them %uh at the Nuremberg
process have you been drinking tonight
not at all I like this start you very
much very much
said exactly what I wanted them me so I
went on asking you guys now is
if this does anything in lightning
technically that which
know like new things or whatever share
your knowledge on that level and stop
defending yourself
don't apologize for what you're great at
doing and
I really wanna from Bradley also we we
at the smaller Hans %uh we with ties
have all 27 us
as many bus there are on usually ap
members I get up on a panel let
audience pick their brains
as I think it's really well done rather
hear some guys apologizing man
you know let's have a look you know a
bug festival
man like you know flow into a fuck fest
like for a weekend or something and
bring all you guys down and you can just
tell what people need to do to fix that
that's that's kinda like to see the
perks
he's the do that and
yes so that the moment we start talking
about bugs I want to mention
any particular by unity if the moment we
do that is a moment resort our time
defeat the purpose
say that we are not responsible great
yeah
obviously knows we went through
collectively is mostly like
attack reforms of course I think that
that this is the essence of it
and then again I mean if I by after like
72 hours it is conference
people here haven't gotten the the
message that criminal hacking
is exactly that in fact it's not even
hacking its criminal its if it's done
such forget it now we know this already
now let's go on it looks like I'll got
to take it one step beyond that it's
clear to me
case funny anymore it's not on breaking
into a website
and changing the contents of it was
funny
sort of the year and a half ago when it
first happened maybe two years ago
and it's turned into the same joke being
told over and over and over again
and I wouldn't waste my time doing know
it's all die I would rather hear like
the kinda constructive step
guys are good at doing you want
everything to me she by yourselves
last run caps bring yourself there's no
reason
touch say you want it up here and
actually give you information about bugs
and exploits
out actually counterproductive for us
because our last
to say that I i'm I'm saying you know
I'm not asking you to do
holds like out understand
the even speaking about that kind
against
point we're trying to make which is
group basically
about you guys to get together hang out
and don't do anything so coming up here
talking but experts up
be we've done in the past
just just not hope is not for
because
I don't think the time a grand I'm sure
on 101 now but
reform no I'm talking more routine stuff
you know guys like you know how to keep
a network really running
help people here have a knowledge to do
that it's not about breaking things
anyways about running
the right was not even now would you
agree I would say that in my opinion
years after the show will I explain our
rate schedule
okay thanks a lot other other way
hi %uh you guys claim that you don't do
anything
you yet you get a lot of credit for
doing something
won a few appears to be asleep have any
you considered a career in law
enforcement
the fact crosses my mind
time to time these are actually played
by
BR the Internet is actually a lot more
lucrative place to make one's
living these days if they start paying
150 dollar an hour
consulting fees I'm there I mean
we're not kids eventually I see a lot of
young pacer
grow up lot of money a member
youngest members eighty
his kids are making six figures brown
I'm
all is like our own before it is
most must rely on each other part berkes
we can forget someone else
so it's a collective you think that
that kinda easy someone like this car
we're not 3 legal there so when you get
to a position
when you're playing for a lot of stuff
then search answers
I take your type person never been
rescued
another I am I thank God this
but the moment people start talking
about virtual out
second to time in your life
you go to const you're worried about him
I can be fussy for something I'd even
hey do yeah my were
I we're about associating with people
because I don't know what they do in
their free time
such and
that's pretty much how and I need this
for renews
12 much just the whole losers because
as much as hell live music as people
think yeah it's called
school addition for but
these people are eventually gonna go out
to the job market find
I kept ok to my job
and there are issues that technical
skill to do their job very well
and when there at that point where all
this are
not one anything tell you just because
you have a sec
Association to you group of people who
are generally
accepted as hackers who are just
completely me
skill just for that Association you want
to be
thought some people happy because people
his constant
you want its some
2012 way
that's actually why top yeah some
country where that's really you guys
went up there said
whatever whatever you wanna match wits
with be fine go ahead
mesh that's perfectly fine but the point
is
I've got a life I've got my check skills
and I have over to france we share
technical and just
you know personal ish and mission fall
like people have to
now but
that's pretty much it
i'ma leave give me where's are
where c1 where's us where's I
the other in the wares house
the check is in the mail
that is much some ish
and I i think we might say in summary
we only look stupid because
we choose Daxter yes
%uh ok I
don't know nothing Oman knowing nothing
is great but
okay I've heard doing nothing gets
plausible deniability
first said into port dotnet so maybe
cats here continued conversation
email my next 3 p.s
the or something like that anyway and
other slacker nice
some working I'm running Windows 95 in
mice
everyone said about my sound card that
is and then
the that isn't playing music and i wanna
do
retail and stuff all would and Linux and
what flavor should I try n
learner run I've no actually
I think a short say if you want a free
UNIX on your PC almost up here would
recommend OpenBSD
appear to rate who also is that's very
was the author
is has close ties what
speak BR the opinion on Linux is
its software written by rank amateurs
for Ag amateurs
spend about walking around sign facts as
hack
limits really just as hell have any
respect my if you want to learn a good
UNIX we recommend OpenBSD
I because I feel uses a solid I
however for a beginner really doesn't
have a lot of these experience
I would personally recommend previous
because there's
so much support for I also extremely
easy to install
up and running I is it downloaded 3
on some from I'm sorry is it 3
www FreeBSD FreeBSD
good reference for technical mission
just like
against them tips is fire C
%uh okay if you go on IRC yep I
channel previously as a lot I previously
box and all season the authors see miss
there
okay thank you very much from on much
at two questions sheler one I you there
1x the one sleeping of argued %uh
humphrey of no fact my name badge says
I am NOT comfrey I and
and we're supposed to believe that okay
and that the other thing
is that arm if you could size of us even
have to
to deferred people morally the nice on
occasion and
my particular case I must for to Don at
Mikes
next question I
Mike of this is a question so much as a
request
up could you week entry up I actually I
need any
to him to go away with me now in
handling large amounts of money
I see s1
he's learned to you might wanna thank
manual for there is a sub much
I we actually thought that the art
though
Lee on the last night BR up the show
after most people gone home was actually
sort fitting
place for furry to give its presentation
its last word
with your to a single still want to be
actually one
yours and discuss still a mess
the third patient people that we really
want to be here with the only ones that
woulda stayed around
those are people that we really want
yours
so I think Amanda supped
he does it every time thanks
payrolls she got all this equipment so
chief now pat is gonna put up some
really kick ass live what happened
thanks patty
somehow she found time to put this
together okay we'll keep
introducing all of us and you can give
us all the shallots you want they say
one more thing
it's backwards is me my rounds
means the girl that's been working
registration
shout out for me
better up here the
okay what's coming up you're all gonna
wanna know a lot about what happened
here
we're gonna tell you about it I will
answer a lot of questions about it in a
few weeks
and later I summers me she's hiding
this is me in %ah
ok all
I've never seen this guy before but I
think I live with him
it's read about paula
he's behind a blue screen
alright on I just wanna see okay
mean just ran registration that's what I
might've was supposed to do and I did
she rolls to everybody up here is the
most fantastic bunch of people on the
planet right now
almost having convulsions
a shirt not to be happy anybody think
that's funny
okay
the oh yeah thank our thank God
okay kicking it to everybody who worked
here as a volunteer
got a redshirt got on right hand p
I have one last thing a clear up in case
you didn't know this
everybody sitting at this table is
included in that group that clear their
readiness
we have no network know like corporate
sponsorship for anything
not been we don't ever want to hear that
question will make it really clear a lot
okay call
on yes thanks to Kmart for
for their cooperation earlier here's
what I want I wanna shout out from this
side of the table
everybody's name shout out your name and
tell me what you did cuz I can't see you
got
Ryan added a
everything merchandising registration
and cap
am call thank you
yes I kept giving me a backrub steer
I'm or chop I didn't realize you know I
did stuff in the NOC
and I think that that fights
like lights yes like a mine
and David did some network stuff I did
some suffer the picture tell
away
the Garth Brooks picture yeah I was
that was designed by Corey just hang out
with us
on is waiting right now in an airplane
is a great kid
i'm sarah
I did the website and all the other
design stuff but you see around all the
banners and placards and posters and
t-shirts and hats
all that fun stuff
Sarah had this posters all over the
fuckin City
mackerel the
did you say about the
up those are the stickers not the
posters okay that's alright
the posters um well we don't know who
stuck that their
it really doesn't matter the sun is %ah
but it like you look better the
for writer
shout out to patty she's the only person
you thought to do this
make the sly feel like I'm okay
I'll
bernie is I a we try to anyway I got all
the free stuff for all you folks for
door prizes
gotta love it love it we're not going to
give away grazie video projector that we
got out solace in the big screen
and patio wanna read the
and acquired various network and power
conditioning equipment for
smooth running at work which I had to
really credit people for using probably
say thank you okay up
my name is Jeffrey Jim and I can't tell
you some other things I did
other than that I generally made a
nuisance of myself everywhere and ran
around like a chicken without a head on
I try to keep am saying and I almost
succeeded
and the that's about it
okay we need to know if n is in the room
areas all in the back
is hiding spend a lot of stuff
right actually if you bought something
from 2600 you probably bought it from
Ben any problem if you buy something
else
cut take you there
good
thank you thank you hey Ben thanks
your ben is the reason that we are
allowed to be up here right now
just
also hear it I'm this is here try
for the last like two or three or
perhaps the whole day hours
he's kept me sane my sister did it
yesterday she's not here today
0 hear it I made those
really great posters up like I van
crashing into the
it on boats with Walter the dog on them
you people want them they're not going
to be for sale when you leave though
all that shut down you can order the
magazine he also does
the that the 2600 website off the hook
web sayin
the fiber side is done by Sarah
I actually did a shitload of stuff for
the off the hook
a CD and no website
and the cover and the covers well
class you guys know who he is
right disc if you ironies away I can say
what I did you kept me sane
the six months
and this congress would not have
happened it certainly would not have
been a success
am and okay on
the guy next to him is David can you
even say your name anymore
I this is David David dot com
whenever there is a problem we put on
his shoulders and he handled it
when the ship when the shit hit the fan
my job was to be there
and I should used a helluva lot of
unnamed companies
I to go to slaughter the services and
technology that we need
interesting thing is that they don't
want to be mentioned
call wat i do you think we should
mention that one
yeah well what the
your local are providers above ISDN
service
on me this all possible but I can
mention their name
what you see in their arm telephone
booths car
decorated with our original mom logo's
and bumper stickers
okay and I need to get some shout out to
people who aren't here
but one thing I have to say is like like
I shit I forgot the okay I'll give my
shadow that's probably our member
ok david is the best measure on the
planet yes
okay we need to thank duh an array
there are radio guys the radios you see
here
other reviews you don't show they
Aaron those radios those words those
ones
David are you done
I'm done I'm I'm pride okay
the guy sitting behind a rigid stand up
and introduce himself
I'm now weasel and I don't sleep
the okay
now implies a really cool website and
I keep calling him do you mind if the
user name they've been calling him all
over the place Jersey Ryan
you for that name that's who that is he
just kicks ass he's done more fun shit
for us like
while we've been running around in
connecting us up his boss got us like
his centrist pick people up at airports
for us and stuff
I'd like to thank
com the cop in front of Grand Central
Station for not noticing
the sticker that I I mean that someone
put up on the phone book
two feet in front of him no need to know
this he actually had like
for at least 45 days when those great
beyond hope stickers
on the yellow divider when you enter the
Lincoln Tunnel
from when he was stuck in traffic there
for hanging out with us too long
everybody left New York saw that the
barrel
I did too we also have to thank the nice
people a job boxer
for announcing our event everyone to the
Times Square area
fight I have like a month things to say
I wanted to shout outs we need to %uh
say that we don't want to thank the
people at the cybercafe we tried to make
it up
organized event have been with them for
over eight months course I have anything
bad happened
we'll work it out okay everybody do this
this is fun this is stupid dietrich's
gonna see how fast are we can turn
around look at the guy in the green
shirt at the sound panel
p
commando on of somebody give a mic but
like
mass has been just a solid rock master
the microsite
I no rx you guys that don't work you've
been working for months
is what do you do for us Manos
I'm mostly web sites yeah look we're
gonna say what else to do for us in a
minute
at our our space earned unlike help us
once again
thank you thank you about the credit
goes over there
okay
when you met me more i do. she also
designed the great animated gif
just say it it's about low notes on the
payphone it's really call come to the
website and get it
you mind which now I ami'm take it
get it do it you went there you did use
it
this I can see over there is next
Mark A you guys know Marco is
the the like
hiker has no mic
its okay area
just like to thank everybody who helped
out so
entirely volunteer network across the
network guy
0 bar-coded our network key sinking his
own volunteers but Marco did our network
all you got it hey Marco want to say
what kind of a connection we had
speed yeah we had a to make that will be
home
up that mean a thing the upheaval okay
I
it's really call we're not gonna tell
you provided that but you'll find out of
here
whose
Marco a dusty wanna say speak into the
mic
like the guy next to him is your Ryan
hi your crime New York right this I'm
not New Jersey Ryan
I'm Rhianna right about that I I
had to be like David everybody I wanted
to get mark with a comma some
tablecloth company took it that sucks
I and what to do and in a lot of stuff I
heard a lot of cats
earlier I I did the WBAI
stuff I help market with as much network
as I can
I can you roll the slide back a couple
to our British friends
K you guys have to understand I hosted a
my I'll on my desk to a a lot of our
new friends from Britain a that's me
that cyber junkies I am still here
a sophomore dont wait your 10
home yeah don't shake your head the
anyway I
oh well the
greatest need to stand up stay standing
the come on up here
the hire a personal thank you this
morning anybody
okay we're gonna give you a shit after
this maybe
yeah anyway I Thursday night these guys
got together and
at of I guess most the beer is actually
cleared off the desk for this
the shot here but we
got a little bored so we their little
creative
web design in the Netherlands
Africa I the okay that brings us to a
question
that a lotta you probably wanna know how
the hell did this happen this is
like really an easy question we're gonna
do it anyway
but I
okay but what I was talking about was
the organizational stuff
and I'd like to let you know where it
happened it happen in our
development labs if you've heard that
name raise your hand
not work on its Wow their the PR
Newswire
alright on if this conference probably
had
like a logo on the bottom like hips did
that said powered by Sun
I think this Wednesday powered by not
work
I think that's just about all I need to
say about it except
I'd like to not work members in this
room to stand the
point on the clock
just want to know who the hell we were I
we were wondering
it's been a really big secret
okay know what I want to say about it is
first of all the really great British
guys have been hanging out with us there
all the time
and totally call clear background
the panties guys has anybody been there
today
now well I have I don't wanna know what
it looks like
the health department any made it back
where did the couch cushions girl
what where are the couch cushions feel
like that
later you don't worry the Twizzlers are
still there
four years old
alright yeah they are foreigners
although K that was our own little
internal thing
up I think they want to give away shit
we're gonna give away shit
on now we're done shouting each other
out
matter I had out
I don't know I i was outside most this
that are without Pam here Pam
is like was eyes and ears nose throat
and bring up this entire convention she
did
a little bit of everything I wanted to
meet anybody else now
Pam a lot of the stuff they saw what
happened I just want to give everybody
so everybody get a round of applause the
by best
mare clear can we get a big round of
applause for the big guy himself
mister emmanuel goldstein the
this is
love a hug from bed you can hold my head
thank you venues like the best hugs on
the planet he is the harder
he did it the first tho he still there
and it only grew up a little
its call over 10,000 people so far
pay I need to say something K alright
Eric 0
of okay Emmanuel
thanks for letting me do this my
pleasure
the iraq fun
let's do it again sometime we will do
this again sometime I'm sure
let's give away shit we actually
don't accept call
the wait a minute the only last thing
you need to know about that is the
British guys were all there when we had
to
unload the major hiking curfews and we
did
and I helped a lot of other people in
this room where chill our elevator
broken our
of boy at 4:30 in the morning and there
was like
60 twenty people away we made a fire
brigade up the stairs
6 play that's all you need to know
okay I Ascot he's on his way back to
England to
oh yeah he left this afternoon he's won
a British guys
okay bike path way below what time it is
go on to
top said that he was gonna
outlast us all that he was gonna stay up
the Thursday before through the entire
weekend
and not get one went to sleep have
pictures taken here in the staff room on
Friday
the he's already been doing it though
for like a week
no it's alright is if anybody here at
this table is had less sleep than Tom
major hair past
know it time alright
its i three minutes to midnight okay arm
we really need to shut this down give a
shit
what we're gonna give away she ran away
free shit
and okay then we all have to go yeah
on yeah okay
is everybody at this table feel unhappy
about shallots given
Company two areas okay ok to
right yeah I
the 58 people are in the room
stand-up forget them there are some
while Paula they left at about as much
without
know I know exactly who they are they
slept on my floor after the last one
when their van was towed
the DH hey guys rock they covered our
asses
on this one and the last one and the
last one and the next 12 right paid by
we got a question for the HP I got one
did you guys get treated okay here
alright
I'm really sorry I'm really really sorry
that I didn't thank you a tear for major
hacking
the the
okay
scandal for arrest that guy
mister mister talking with its really
elderly people that were here yesterday
if you didn't see them on the radio show
they were walking around
major hacking that's his real name
then tell the story we tell the story
all his last name is hacking and he was
a major
at a yes I need to know but we're gonna
tell the whole story on the website
look from our major hacking info it to
be evaluated at 2600 dot com
its core okay alright
well make sure you get the info and
major hacking major hacking is totally
call
if you were 84 would you come to a
hacker conference
the the if you got lost
and I went to the wrong Convention
Center on the way would you still come
the the make the Fla
lot
ok all I gotta say AOL
here please major hacking
got home safely by the way if anybody
else care
the thank our Dutch friends even though
we didn't see much of them
I we were supposed to have all kinds a
conductivity but didn't quite work out
with that we saw them a few times they
saw us but we don't know what happened
to them
there read my heart
reply was cool the red light was call
the my
KSK
stand up again the back I came all the
way from Holland to make a light
caremark wait a minute do you guys know
what he did
okay he came all the way from over there
to make a switch here turn a light on
their
on a switch their turn a light on here
it is art project I'm sure you'll be
able to find out information about it
alright through the net you left the
white on
yet why did most people would have shut
it off we're gonna have to do everything
for
I proper roles
props call did to these people know what
happened during your opening up here
are well okay I actually
ciphers not here right now but some some
people who were here
kinda hacked their way 10 their web
pages anyway and
we announce that to them 05 over the
picture tell
lawler was giving the hip opening had
all
it was totally call had a shot can we
say who did it
are well I see a few people did okay or
something yeah a whole buncha people
have had it not work well we were like
really craze did it was great call
I okay I think it's just about time to
go away shit
okay yeah okay what I
we we wanna stay up here anybody at this
table right now that wants to leave it
the table can porch up cuz first up
we have mister okay you on Tuesday
file image this is the first time
everybody up here had fun
at this conference that true %uh
what's first time I've had any fun
Hassan call we're gonna give away stuff
at a really lot of fun
but I have never heard anything that
happened in this room until now
okay I apologize that was totally made a
this has been the best thing I've ever
done
the best time ever had Park check
coming past that stuff down here
up
but
here's what I need to do
somebody sitting right there with a
watch
I know I have one on but I don't use
watches
needs to tell me when it's 1230 that's
your job
that kid that just answered
dismay and didn't wear known by Pam
share when you tell me the time and a
half an hour from here
here just leave you watch the somebody
else do it for me gas to go
thank you alright we have any idea how
we're doing this
on yeah actually there's a really cool
thing that happens
when I made these attendance badges
there's all sorts of ways we planned and
had fun with so that you couldn't go
photocopy them in
think you had a real one we really
didn't check
to see if you did it but
I
does anybody think they did it there to
what
call no problem
we did some cool stuff to make sure
wouldn't be hacked lol
alright on
to does anybody in this room think they
know what the numbering sequence is on
the badges
okay all day that's all I wanted to do
was make that a contest
alright okay
the first thing we can do is give away a
prize if anybody get that right
I'm gonna take it her
anybody who knows can answer now
security people
you work security Steve that was really
lame
nice try okay
is anybody who doesn't already know
think they know what's on their numbers
okay
I don't know yet
that's my answer okay we had a lot of
fun and not work
asking a lot of people including British
people on people that were visiting us
people from other States they all spent
hours trying to figure it out
they didn't do it or have a contest for
that afterwards then
we need to make this go quickly on porch
up hold up something
I this was donated by Bernie s
its is a or maybe you can explain it
your
three years ago it hope 94 I
demonstrated to to clipper chip in
Christian
systems I he found out they weren't the
greatest thing since sliced bread
because the NSA had a back door to the
year getting corruption scheme
but added algorithm but highly doubt
over two thousand dollars for those two
things to test them out and
I sometime after that the secret service
rate at my house and
took a whole bunch of shit from me and
it took
one up the two clipper chip in
corruption unit I don't know why didn't
take about but
I they left me with one and
while the box is a little mill do it
because they put it in storage where was
a
not best for electronic equipment on
I did get it back and inside its
Christina still wrapped in plastic
it's an eleven hundred dollar speech
encryption unit that you can use to
speak to anybody else
it's always a call unit and that works
on all phones and it's really cool and
we're gonna give this away okay the this
is gonna be a surprise
for anybody who um has this badge
numbers everybody should look at their
badges
know your number cuz that's the way
there were gonna do this and we just
decided now
okay the middle four digits there two
digits
but started then therefore in the middle
then there are two digits that ended
this is a clue a pretty big blue
it's a really big clear I'm not taking
volunteers for my contest you can answer
it
CNN I'm gonna read out a number
okay if the middle four digits of your
bad
art 2600 you can have that as long as
you live within the United States
I this is not exportable it is a
munition
okay we tried to give it to the guy who
hacked crude
there's Canada he was from Canada and
needed to take it on a bus
lol he wanted other stuff anyway what
you didn't want anything
he hacked route to okay does anybody in
the room have a badge with that number
on it
no alright
26 what 26
now can't do that on okay
what just hold it well we're actually
sending him some NSA stuff and some
other really cool things and
hooking him up but we can give them this
so when I need you guys everybody at the
table
wat everybody here at the table
everybody at my hope for table
needs to read yell out a number starting
from here cuz I can't even think in
numbers
anatole pick a number yallop a number
you just said
music music they have that number
does everybody know their number right
now as we need to do this fast we're all
really crashed and burned
okay
16 33
okay this just isn't gonna work I guess
my numbering system tells
to good the AHSAA one in 10,000 that
they would have the console
no you can't do that I'm sorry plenty of
people have 26 on their badges
does anybody have about 300 okay
for the people at the table your number
is a four digit number
for digit
okay unless someone at this table yells
at a four digit number right now that
someone has
steve is gonna get this thing Steve the
guy that just yelled at for digiti just
hack me
you got it
Steve come up here and get
use it use it in good health up
must be taught a graphic if if anybody
at this table as a better suggestion for
how to do this
do it now we don't know those
okay
was wicked is he still appear at the
table %uh
what there was another machine here that
had great act on it
makin wasn't there get a mic
are those people here you up ala
okay on you guys
I can't think about how we're gonna do
this somebody else pick a number our way
to give away the stuff now
yelled
we go up getting now shut up
down rose here saw
see often loss
we could just throw stuff at you
you know what you like that that's no
fly I can throw some other stuff
I'm about to the point where I'd like to
but I love it's like clinic CDs and earn
boxes and I'll kill you that's not a
good suggestion
I don't know summers
rose no
if anyone can break dance right here
that would be pretty cool Terry but
has to be in the middle
four-digit what I need
yes while first
play also what happened I like any
fear you met t-shirt and beyond hope see
if it is something like that you just
like enterprise right away
no no a t-shirt and one of those beyond
hope stickers everybody wants stickers
open them up week
away use he designed a shirt he's
wearing
think okay old
Noel
work security sorry serious
now depend how about now
no no no nah nah nah we're not worrying
about if you know how r badge numbers
works now
we got it covered okay everybody look at
their badge number
when you gonna do this again ignore the
first two numbers
if you're next digit is old one
there should be a lot of view okay
if you're next digit is to well we're
gonna do is buy elimination when there's
my nephew will stop over next is a
3 it has to be
okay what your numbers 123
that's it
you have all those three numbers in
sequence stand up we have a winner
come up here okay may help poor people
we just figured out a way to do this
it's really easy we will be checking
cop car people look at your badges now
if you're on the table okay where
your badge number is one
a two digit away from hiring ok
give them something you decide lennox
that's what I needed to know trying to
limit your next
you get some where with three winners
okay minutes
people giving away stuff she go over
there your waist up
I'm take the prizes to wait a minute
if I'm this is a I read oh wow
you know we said we make this up as I
went along if you really want stuff stay
if you guys need to leave got home on
okay
everybody had 123 and the portage their
badge number
their badge numbers are really close to
mine
they just want something hair should win
something to write
what are you must have 123 in your bed
I don't want anything I want this to be
over
what's your number ara what I was asking
for was for everybody at this table
to look at their pads I don't have a
batch
I shit I make you pay for on how I don't
have a patch shit
David do you have one no I don't have a
veggie the okay everyone on the can
anyone
rap okay cool I got my ex ready one
one everyone who's got that number in
that
four digit sequence 1.1 stand up
for the next number is a6 stay standing
how many people are standing to
you come up here now get some free stuff
degree
way antique every port
you top okay
I on okay
if you're bad starts with the number
very good okay is that all the stuff we
need to explain when we give it away
okay if you're middle for did it starts
with six
7 a
how many people are standing home now
the see
what's your next digit ravel well
that's right well I p rebels bad numbers
one away from me answer and registration
you get something free somebody give
them something don't give a microphone
travel here's your bad
travel Ravello you don't wanna lose this
side of their
now they've the table Captain Crunch
mapping project Captain Crunch yeah
the play what's your number
from what I've heard to Captain Crunch
is quite the raver
doctor doctor lyrics
what's your badge number
call okay
no as anybody in the room still has a
678 bad
okay does your badge number start
two numbers on that I'm sorry
it's the middle four digits okay we're
gonna go stupid
eat checks are we taping mess okay
that's a mistake why no I wanted taped
okay everybody look at their bad in the
room stick your
Bama over the left two digits
okay take your other com if you want to
win something
do this and stick it over the right two
digits
thats your number ok cool it
okay if your number is starts with the
two
start Ben next come seven
next comes three I
are you the only person now coming here
your badge number is what
when you get here this a good system
with Alice not work development labs
and me right what your badge number
I designed the numbering system
2732 alright to did so where you get
free stuff
call their up and got ants what's your
best
means Ryan
okay if your badge number but me a 10
minute break
we have him an excellent if if your
badge number starts with 3
0 0 anybody
come up here next bad from the table
if your badge number starts with five
one Howard said s
anyway still standing come up here
alright
by the way that's the a record up to a
67 magazine that's really call
give him something really call it's not
right no
wat you can went to 55 did you when
something here
know it's 516 5 one
6 the four digits spell 5
one 6 you should be looking up four
digits you go five
Juan 6 thank you they may not know that
we're stopping this in 10 minutes
somebody else had me a bad choice
somebody at my table now
hand me a bad every the badges reggie
what's your badge number what
okay who's bad starts to 66
you get the door prizes
ed do you have a better job IQ
what's your that we give away anything
on your shirt
who has a number that goes three
or one anybody
anybody now we've got a bad
here bernie ass i Laura
Euler you
yell out your badge number bad luck I'm
site you know i right here yell out your
badge number
that that four-digit some looking for
middle
okay if your badge number goes one to
to he's gonna win
he's not gonna win this actually
you can have free stuff for yelling out
the badge number the you can tip
the one tale
tear anybody else in the room at about
like that then you come up here
pretty you too what I need is a badge
number from my staff at this table do
you guys have any more
451 thank you that was at
I've been saying that several times one
more lap what we'll all get
one more what okay thank you guys wow
that really works doesn't
the next number is three to
anybody standing is this year
the next digit is three then it's yours
come here
this guy kicks ass
this guy balance might
door for the last several hours that's
myself ok
this guy just gets whatever he wants
what's left your keys to
thank you him everything that flap
that here we're done thank you
actor would like to thank you all the
free stuff is gone
take your badges back hurts our staff to
arises
okay if someone answers
I want this