thanks for having me my first time and
Brazil
%uh nice to be here I'll try to go slow
the other countries on
so a that's the thing I understand he
had things to say
about the incident so I have like 10
slides all about the fact that
just getting I know um
so other what white
lead I got me to think about this talk
was
there's this conference and United
States called up and
that is like a hacker conference and
it's very common your people go to staff
person talk about I
you know they they're not it turned the
phone off or
you know they bring a buyer found just
for the conference and then they go to
wear something ridiculous
right so a oasis in the Lakers
me and so the stock is sorta about
that and on and
you know what you need to really worry
about with mobile security
and unit what you should you are a doll
how much you should worry
its or just try it you know from my
opinion to get the facts out
a about like the real problems that were
once a person like most people
I X O
so there's some stuff about me I can
talk more about that
so here
like if he does Google Mobile Security
you'll find
tons of articles about that right
moles okay so here's a son that I just
wrapped up the Anna
things like the smartphone
cyberattacks to grow this year this is
mean year 2013
and I size ASO these I'll grab
basically and from December he doesn't
well so they're talking about this year
and you can
you guys like to see that nothing really
happens here so you guys either that
they were sort of bullshit
so where's there's one actually at all
really
mobile devices the new prime and right
or growing
there so this one specific other hand
right answer them our magnet
so how you can protect yourself mobile
rights
happened the last so there's the
it basically you never see an article
that those are there is no more that
they always talk about how to use the
mobile
on this one was very important to me
because you know if you can't let point
on your phone was the point of having
thus far
up so so there's there's a lot of
headlines out there
and on and you reporters they like you
to read
read what they have to say and I just
wanna see what you know
I want to talk about what is is you know
reality at least
amount so this is so that and I don't
really hate
a all classy news
news stories like you know I think these
are you okay to apply to say here's some
more
so the sun's about like iPhone being
exploited
the sun's about Android asunder by
that's a nice tax this is that happen
kinda
on and about like
does anyone know the what these all have
in common yes these are all about me
so a our tax I've done and
like I like at you know reporters as
much as anybody maybe more
on but but that doesn't necessarily mean
just because I
you know hacked the iPhone that you need
to worry about euro I so that's the
difference that's why i wanna talk about
is a just because you see that there's a
is that the radical
attack doesn't necessarily something
Paso
I wanna talk about supper someone talk
about a
units its very basic level sorta what
what kinda attacks are on and I'ma talk
about why those attacks
are different when you're are talking
about your mobile platform
hearses like your your here and to do
that out I give a little background on
an Android OS and how they're designed
on now talk about a actual problems that
I think
exists for from all on I'll talk about
so
how attackers the and finally I'll
all you know so today I say mobile isn't
the biggest
right but maybe unification out that
won't be the case and so
so it's like a wide things might change
oversight at them was a very basic level
you guys are probably understand this
like let's let's talk about how
attack happened at all so
lazy two ways that that bad guy can get
code on your your device your computer
or your
your he or whatever the one is that you
download and run it
malware right and the other is that
there's some explain about services
your disorder using the the device like
it's supposed to be
use but there's some more ability that
allows
attacker to get coburn that I like it as
a little more
so in the case the malware
a you say you're downloading code in
running it
and and maybe you think it does
something that doesn't
or you're somehow kinda you know tricked
into running it but but the bottom line
is from the
devices perspective user wants to run
the comps so it's
its you know computers I'm designed to
to help you there
computer designed to run code that you
want to run so
so traditionally the way that we deal
with this promise something like
antivirus
with his job the suppose to be able to
tell the good and the bad code
knowing that you want to go and you know
whether it works are not as a different
story but that's what it's there that
on the other hand a exploits again
are something where a you're not trying
to run code necessarily
news trying to your web page or read
your email or whatever
but because there's some problem with
the software
you have you are exposed to lead in the
bag I
on you change what your programs doing
it
to do whatever they want to do and on
a lot of what happens at the end to that
is the code will download
you know something sorted software to
run that the attacker want
so
up let's talk about like how you can
you know what you can do to to stop
for the same so it's a basically I'm
there's a few things that you was that
an hour
showing up on your on a computer or are
refrigerator or whatever there's there's
like a few basic things you could try
he you tactics so you can make it hard
to get on in the first place
you can limit what he can do you want it
there
a you can
and you can limit how long making me you
can be there
so like if you had malware on your
computer but
after I meant to stop working like that
I would be bad but not too bad
Amanda finally you can you can watch it
and try to
attacked when it does something that you
think is bad on
on the exploitation side you can try to
make your software using
and I have on abilities are happy or a
you can make it hard win there is a
vulnerability
to a to actually explain it
missus they say what the industry spent
a lot of time going
me like 830 given up I'm banging on the
bugs
and and and a paper with more on making
it hard
actually yet like on and
you limit what the you know the
compromise of work and do
into this is me ideas like sandbox and
and so far
I you can and you make a hard to persist
so this is the idea like we'll talk
about this later but like on the iPhone
I much you have came together I'm
hopeful things typically like when you
you restore your iPhone the the pain
would go away
so you know that we'll talk more about
the persistence
even in the case anyway a so you can
make it to where it hard to stick around
forever
and finally you can try to you thank you
if your phone sex calling out the China
you can you can
alike users so
so then if you want to you can I read
that but it's the same thing that is
with the
that I talk about the things that you as
a user can actually do
verses like we're Apple or Google or
something new so
I on those that like basically you can't
do anything you and you can really
try to do is detect problems so you're
not going to be able to make
Mobile Safari fewer bugs you like and we
all make it harder exactly
and these are all things that you know
the device manufactured can do
but you user I'm so you know it's a
to discuss the show that I'm there's not
much you can
you can really do except %um its
pressure your vendors into
going better sounds
so so let's talk such as I talking about
that
everything I just said with
supercomputers are mobile device
lover let's talk about why mobile
devices actually different beers when it
comes to you
now our application like that so
a it the David there is genuine or a
slow start because as the Brazilian
thing that you guys
have seen like two people so it is a
movie from the 80's
as their support it's pretty good
he travels around the world as a
archaeologists clicking things
knowingly it's really about but and like
critical
I so anyway i some back and and you know
when computers were
resorted coming into existence and and
people were saying to get them
there really was no security like
thought about it was like these are
devices that you wanted program in run
code and
yeah it when you could download
something when it was like
when you got something you use Rand
and that was it and there is no there
wasn't even really antivirus and there
was a
there that I wasn't like you know memory
RAM is a saying that it was just very
simple and
and I was a on if you move forward to
a you know more recent times in
psychology they see that
a are result I wanna things that changed
a lot right so
so we we at least an idea of what we
wanted from security we weren't
like super good at it but we we we at
least new
a where we want to go so we had things
like
miss security built into the software
development life cycle
we had antivirus course by then and I
was working
you know the sales people tell you it
works very well
in the world of them it's okay on
and then exploitation have really moved
on to a point where
you didn't see a lot of places and
things like a
you know the you'd
so so you may be three years before this
like all the acts with you it you when
you hear my time I would be like
and on you know the web browsers out say
but
those had a gotten significantly harder
recently in this time period to to do
that and saliva explodes
you were seeing at this point we're in
like that by playing like Java class or
something like that
and 1298 that everything had
I is lined up and things like that
wheelies knew what they were and we're
putting them in a lot of products
I'm so we had actually negations even if
the worker
that so those going into any idea who he
meant the other day it was released
so well security improved movies
burglars with so is the one that sees it
as a
today as a as they say when you know
what we call smartphones a
you know I was like all smartphone came
out so they had a
on that I guess you got your smile but
for me it was
it was when i punti came out and the
Android a phone book came up in 2008 so
if you think about
yeah so how come I'm not by my iphone 1
so I'm an old guy
for you guys might not have have been
around when I for one was out
ivan was like a totally different
creature that happen to you iPhone 1
there was no App Store there was no STK
is was designed to be a basic like a web
browser
and which is cool back then but um
you know when when people would bug
Steve Jobs say I
yeah we really want to download absinthe
up use like now now
what you want to do is you wanna write
web pages that look exactly like taps
and then you can set that what well
after
the year I guess you decided that was
kinda Stephen because it is
and so they changed
when I think you came out that's when a
may include the App Store
and I i should say an eyeful when there
was based on a security
so your web browser and Andrew there was
no
explanation that was very very he
actually
on my iphone to he
the cavalry designed it to make it to
where
you know you could download lapse in
order to do that and protect themselves
at a budget stuff that
on was really to protect their
their app ecosystem but as I back to
make the device a lot more secure
so anyway i so that this is in 2008 went
on schema
and you know I claim that one of the
reasons that
its smartphones as a inherently more
secure than
like your your computer is because the
fact that
when they were developed like we had
learned a lot more about security we
thought about security
you know maybe not as a primary
name but at least we knew about it and
so there were some design that went into
it that made it better
so I ask that wheelies knew that
someone sunday was gonna try to write on
malware and make better
bill that into beginning on both these
devices had some
some actually mediations got them from
the beginning and there are you thinking
down the road
at and I'm I think bothers by that is
that
at up me you know
I think they both had on
may be able to get up and I S large to
make that many wait now they
portable that on you can
and for both those devices they were
really ever intended as downloads
opinion and run them
so they're always developed in mind you
know it might be possible
as it was developed in mind where you're
supposed to go to a particular place a
Gap store
down and that this you know these app
serves special in some way
you can download them around them but
you're not with this guy goes around
website
on and every application
is you know has the runs are some sort
of them much though
so they're already thinking about the
many things as well so the totally
different experience than
and your typical PC the expectation is
higher in a lot of ways to him
and you know again from these are maybe
accidental or at
companies are arguing over tyre or
something that made it this way but
the end result is that it's the tires so
a
that tax services mall are you don't
have Java running on your
your mobile browser you don't have class
and stuff like that and so
others there is less so that we know how
to
went to look for bugs right experts and
ice at heart
we have an ass alarmed up built into
a you know the phones now and
since the ass on a sandbox you're going
to need more
you most like splits the to get out of
there anyone to get the initial code
execution right million other one to a
whiskey so the wild not
I mean obviously since I've done before
it's not possible it's higher
so
up I specifically talk about somehow I
OS and Android are
a bill and I will help us figure out why
why it's hard to do these things
and in particular will compare so I was
and Ryan
lie one maybe are using up
me with the this quote I have here is
sort of about
the difference but also did well that it
was a blast
the so a Apple as so very
very much once they control everything
on your device on
and serve as a side effect they get
security from that
where who'll want to have a very open
device
and the use the communities are police
themselves
and the you know one maybe isn't better
or worse than the other
but it is different and there design yes
on so the main difference people
is a good sign so
and and of higher than that but anyway
and I left at least
everything so all all binaries all
libraries
had to be signed by some person party
which %uh the box
the only person parties up and you can
add other cuz
ours enterprise you want but
a box everything I said basically the
same
on and the sex and even further than
just the things that you
you load and I'm binaries in Lima raise
I K
actually gets the point where every page
a memory has to be signed with a few
caveats but a for the most part every
page ST sign
what this means is that and you have
the actually download they have to come
from the App Store or someplace that
place
a and not only that but when you
download that they can do things that
that they weren't doing not for everyone
says night
where i download something it's going to
be a one way and when you done lately
have a different way
and they can't change what they do and
apply he the static
analyzed them you'll see everything that
they can do making at
making Alki pages right go to it and run
because the whole court thing
on so that means that if you
you could say exploit I
Mobile Safari air are some other program
as I tackle you might wanna download
your tools or whatever to the device and
and run them
well because they're not sign the Napa
that they will be on the run
so you can download year novels to your
phone
actor I owe us expect it so to
to work on and likewise you're not going
to be able to without doing some more
work survive remove
because you won't feel the love any coat
around if you have any good around and
then you try to actually
run it when it backup it would run
business
it has a lot of consequences for
on and so up
so you know at some point you can
imagine
came together some sorta exploits wanna
get code running
and you have maybe a second when the
brakes are the same box
maybe if they're going to get through
you need all that work
we saw nothing will survive a review
because no you kurt is going to be
signed
I'm so you have to actually do more work
than even that
to the
T is about that yet basically all turn
off because I
he was a battery with an outboard
so you can see like that's that's a lot
of work
so on what about the app so can you
maybe
says as since exploitation soundly hard
maybe we should focus
as an attacker on I'm our a game
that people run badass
so the weather protection you after well
if the run is your mobile
they run a sandbox a
or or something like contact the photos
they have to ask the user
permission that we signed the course
making games
so oslo restrictions on what here
happens again we'll do
even if you can get something the App
Store it's gonna be limited and
thing you on
and and so gaming's into the App Store
as have a painting
so you have to have an account and the
App Store and that's gonna cost like 100
bucks
and also they have this thing where you
have to verify who you are
the a credit card and then you also need
in some cases you can see this when the
sometimes that you need something else
and they're not really clear on what
that is
I maybe you have to I call them or
something I don't know but
it the the fact that they don't tell you
exactly what you need to their house
officer scary
your attacker and then um once you have
an account you have to upload your app
the binary only you apple and a a chance
to run it
and play with it and see if they think
it's malicious II if it passes that goes
into the App Store
and so even at uses a pose as a matter
of their
you get to meet the App Store that's the
an hour
eventually someone going to figure that
out and when they do
Apple of course remove it from the App
Store
an afterthought love you nominee Mitt
which is sorta
you know that's pretty different than
what happens in the winners world so
are other PC world if you have I write
some hour and I put out on some random
website
and people start downloading it a how
it's gonna be there
and I thought I have it some website
and so no one knows for sure but most
people
think that Apple can actually Molly Moo
perhaps from your device
only anyone i knows about that but it is
another thing that you have was
basically works as an antivirus for your
phone so it looks all absent for you can
run it
and then it can again asleep
so what really I was an hour as a
well there really is is almost nine
there's been a handful things that
a wall maybe grab your contacts or
something like that
the elderly then any we're on our
on so if you wanted to up
you wonder I'm aware that would grab
your address book and set up the same
server
and you're okay with you have to click
OK you can't do that
you only something more time again that
you have to build an expert in here at
I but the problem with the is that
you know if you have a exploit for new I
last device
and you build into an apt you have to
give it to Apple to review before
its yes and you know miss you have just
five or six
explicitly around you probably don't
want to do that as you don't want
Apple the they probably won't catch it
but if they do a
there you know that I don't like an
expected and urs
so back so um
so this is %uh the story about me
encanta estar
I so this is what I had to do to
up to do it and it and it is so that's
that's a real pain
as an attacker so if you've done an
attacker what I'm not
a at the end a ITRI Mina App Store cow
I did that as a hundred bucks I then I
IIIA so that I can make
I wanna make an app that was a I could
do something like this
and so I had to find a a vulnerability
that love me do that so I found upon
ability
that allowed my program to download you
going right that was inside
which you should be on the sat on a Mon
ability
that I wrote a nap that have that
exploit that one really built into it
a blow to the you up a review to Apple
this is that was scary right because I'm
giving Apple
a information about or a vulnerability
in their system that I don't really want
them to know that
exists or that I know that exists so a
I did that it past review
so so that that of 1000 maybe the review
process isn't that good
so then I Roco that it would download
and run and unsigned code
and and that work and then like if I was
a bad guy I guess that
some point I could try to make money was
like I don't
and I'm not a bad guy but then
eventually they figure it out
a and they removed it from the App Store
an A removed me from
from the they they take away Mac Mac how
so I lost ninety nine dollars from that
with and I'm Dana right so
as an attacker I'm I'm terrible I love
I'm a terrible attacker
as I just lose money so
so it just shows that like yet but i
wanna do the same thing against
you know some desktop computer would've
been a lot easier I would have lost nine
dollars and
a satire so if
you know it's again if I'm just
contrasting it to
by WED have you downloaded I'm hour and
run it and you're running
say windows or something that they got
Windows because
other Systems Inc but I have to get you
to download my executors ball
I you might have a BMI to bypass that a
big deal
on and one side done that I'm there
forever like I'm never going to go away
I could you ever online anti
on where I last had a that have a cow
unless I'm I'm all I want is like a
contact or something
I'm gonna have to build an exponent
any to bypass the absolutely be
processed
on and then depending on if you're
talking about
exploitation and I have to actually
break because I mean in order to
to persist either way it's the time is a
much harder to
to do that really is our I'm it's like
so what about Android iOS Android a you
know hard to you
this is a quote about up open societies
are good
on so so
inter has like pretty similar security
the biggest difference is again they
don't have their coats and requirements
they have some cuts are required but
it's not really a
it's not meant it is meant for like
record if that meant
um so
they have some similar restrictions on
the haps
you they run a sandbox the difference is
that and I was
all that happened in the same sandbox up
to a
if you include the whole like you have
to group sex things
where and Android all the requirements
that
absent me to ask about prime and you
have to agree on a
so up I also the another huge difference
P
because the I have code signing is that
an Android app skin on the new cut and
run them
runtime: and that's okay so you can
imagine ap
that is a you know totally innocent
doesn't do anything bad others a
download code and run it and that could
download sometimes good and sometimes as
bad
Leslie different you can't do that
like as you can imagine Co that may be
downloaded exploit
that exploits you know that the brakes
on the same bat or something
and Android and then you get you got to
change that
to you as new versions and it matters
I'm what a fucking absence in the Google
Play Store
so again there's this is there's a
chance for
for you know for Google like that and
your malicious ass
here on but it's actually a
much easier ABZ through this I main
difference is cheaper
twenty-five dollars you can also
register someone anonymously
so here is in this picture a John Doe
an override that talks about I V you get
these like
temporary credit cards and talked about
and Mike
their way phones that using your phone
number two register
it's very easy to get more or less
anonymous accounts on
ago place or and then the way that they
do that
the check in at the absolute fully
automated so
use a system called bouncing the to do
that where an apple they don't
it is a mystery so they actually do you
do
I they do
I'll automated announces the Apple as
well
and and people talked about that but
there's also some
some mysterious you know potential and
a but that
monkeys yes yeah they have they have
humans involved and so there's a there's
always a chance that humans can actually
be smart
number but probably not so
at Dino and I talk I wrote a paper about
how to bypass bouncer
it's pretty easy because its automated
system and you can you value it was
doing and
it differently you know you're inside a
bouncer
you think ira on but a
so if they do you ever catchy though
they can remove your app from
from their store and they can definitely
remotely remove at st. they've done it
before
I am so so you have a city choices
if you enter and win our you can and
just hope the user's
David and as you know a lot let you do
things that you want to do
on which is probably a pretty good good
bet that they'll be that
so here like a after asked for Kansas up
and the permission that it probably
doesn't need
user says yes and you're gone as an
attack are you
you 1 and the other way to do it if you
actually turkey is you don't ask for any
missions we have built and sorry gonna
believe they get your router something
on
on the phone that then lets you do
things that didn't have permission
that I was a lot higher on
so if you want to do the same trick up
getting
I now where onto a Android devices it's
a
it easier than I was and you get ideas
by fast bouncer
which is again pretty easy on generate
some girl recounts
a maybe you don't may be right next play
or maybe just that the user
you know hope user clicks yes on
and so I have a abused him and so i i
recall mess up the high standards
when it comes to a you numbers and and
houses and so this is the chart I came
up with
very sophisticated and houses here
so up how hard is it to write malware
like this is
this is my my takeaway is it pretty easy
he just going if that's not
and great attire I it's much harder
so so and it and it took crews the case
when you look at how much power again
these numbers are disorder made up but I
give me some actual numbers as I
on you don't really see I mean attackers
are totally stupid
they're gonna do with what where they
want to do
the in there for whatever reason they
want to do it
but usually they're not good you
something that's hard on purpose
only guys like me that
because we don't really wanna you
doing things saw so a so so you so that
you know there's been much more in
cynicism our windows has been
more and more than i OS it has been
almost no there's some actual numbers
a the
came out Maccabi so this is how much
mobile now where there was through
the year so is you can see there's been
there's almost none
and so it doesn't while with the last
year then you saw
something like your 40,000
uses them our or something and the
and the other 13 you around the same
amount this is from a antivirus vendor
and so they always
say way more than there really is so
this is like they would probably tell
you there is this many
and you know and windows and making our
side
so I read it as it's not that much if
you compare
like winners and if you look at what I a
now where they're seeing again this is a
McAfee a
almost all videos and read so I was
doesn't even get a mention
and and the tighter it's a small doesn't
get a price
the most an hour this is Andrea maybe
that's because that's all they're
looking for something
probably this is I realistic
on so that malware what about
explication
so I you don't see a lotta mobile acts
like
either and and there's there's reasons
why so this is the chart
that shows I how much
people are using their computer's web
browser ever since he's in there
mobile web browser the moves are the
blue line there is
the as the on the computer's web browser
you can see I could still you know it
started back in
the type size in 2009 and
back then I was like I never said is
your computer
and by the and and you know now its at
and the like you know eighty-five
percent or something still
eighty-five percent in traffic is gonna
nappy from mobile only like 15 percent
is going to be for mobile browser and so
if you go to trial writing a mobile
exploit
the ads are like the people visiting
your website are not going to be on
mobile devices you not to be like split
so make sense if you're a bad guy who
see this I why am I gonna
write a mobile exploit I'm a writer no
actually our web browser
PC on
another thing is that most and in real
life
most things that are displayed are are
plugins
if there's a a graph /a a USMC these I
came out and
what percent to browsers have that
plugin
and you can see that the most things
that are being exploited things like
class in Java and that and stuff like
that well known these things are even on
a mobile platform
so it eliminates times %uh the farm boys
that we see in real life
another thing is that up
it's hard if I want to exploit your web
browser it's hard for me to
get you to come to my website and why
would you come to my website
and so wanna tracks that a bad guys do
the paper advertisement on
and website you would really go to you
and then they build explained to the
advertisement
but it turns out that it's hard to get
advertisers
show up on mobile devices that's why
like every time you visit the webpage
on your computer is like at all over the
place Ryanair
on your mobile browser your nose is
usually not peninsula and like that
sometimes and this is reflected in this
chart
shows a how much cheaper it is to get
advertisements
on a mobile devices because
which switzer shows that it's hard to
get these mobile devices to actually
show your at
so it's it's cheaper to the to the
advertisers
because no one no one sees
advertisements and
level so that's that's another thing you
can do is an attacker
so up so but but explain to do exist
right so so with wanted them the only
well-liked like the
ever really been made public is Joe
break me to come to
3 him and he doesn't let them buy comics
so basically let me tell you how that
worked and then you can see you like why
it was hard
the fact I had said identity it a about
a year before that we would never see
actually
on but I was wrong so they got my mind
everything I say today so a anyway the
way it worked was there was a bug
and the parser and that with you then
the
and the web browser and it was them for
name I was that was not only allowed you
to override a buffer
allowed you to read about her as well so
it was a memory leak and I memory
corruption on one buck
know you're probably going to bobs that
and then
the ones he was able to figure out where
he was and crop memory
then immediately return I am programming
inside the program because the DUP
a so that he had he had code running and
the web browser
that's not enough so then he
he knew another vulnerability I in the
kernel
that he exploited from within the return
or and programming
payload to turn out good time
2010 up road sign you downloaded Ubuntu
stop and ran it
and so this was not an exploit and the
stanza
you know it was bad like people visit
the site on purpose I visit that site
it was the jailbreak your phone but
obviously if you can jailbreak your
phone
they can do anything so this could have
been bad
but it was a will show you how hard it
was to do so required
a in this case to vulnerabilities
usually right revitalized
a required Ryan exploit inside over
another act very difficult
so up so this is a wrap that up
say you everyone actually a dust-up
system there's tons a
under them out there got lot supply and
on you're gonna have to bypass I
actually mitigation
may be the heaviest tamoxifen on the web
browser like you've been cromer
something is amiss and maps
but then you're done you get to be there
forever on the mobile device
it's harder because they're probably not
going to be
me the average person going to website
is gonna be a dust-up system
power like smart access
same thing you're gonna buy passes
you're going on your end up at this game
is hamas
you have to base it turned out good sign
in or something I was at least
to persist and really not sure about
that they way said I was in my car
you expectation among the less than this
but you might say a Charlie a what about
all the things that
you know that their there's more tax
service on mobile devices because
you have things like you know text
messages that you don't have one
investor
you have in a basement attacks and you
have Near Field Communication
lotsa things that most and that that PC
dull
so maybe that makes up for niceee
now that matter so I I had a
there's been like to SMS a attacks I can
they go
on never always by researchers never in
real life
there's been a few baseband tax nothing
as many rely for that either
and back is only a couple researchers
who really know how to do that
I'm not gonna and see again there's been
maybe
theory explains in real life a
I to their explains all written by
researchers not by
actual people who were recounted so
so either is more taxers again we
haven't seen attacks
against
I'm so it's not do some more digging
into this to see whether I'm this fall
said or not so but you can't really read
that but this is the worst a
all the exploit that that we've seen
inside
everything as this talk etc all black
hole which is something like
Black Cats use frequently to yet like
browsers
a man so you know if these are all TVs
and things like
a you know PF renders our Java
or are
no other complications but the point is
not have these explains that are in this
this no one and took it work against
mobile devices they're all for
for PCs one must play
well mostly with the exception of a
couple things that working at like
iPhone 1
there are no exploits or mobile device
um you know is very well known operation
or other happened a few years ago
that work that was a exploit thing as
web browsers but it was a
against mobile devices were brothers
on what what other mobile us like that
their bed well
I mean I've done a few others wanna have
XLR sale
you like the year two ago I was the
phone owners live exploits
government not coming I talked about let
I you don't seem
there's really been no cases a malicious
a more mobile I
exploits amor so it's I mean to be
worried about this is
to be very paranoid I think
what about in real life like real
attacks it happened you got mine on
that nobody's as much and they're all in
the US that I know about
but Mike earlier this year I think New
York Times got hacked
on so Facebook got hacked and I much as
I pass on
Apple an act buyers of that Act all on
the same attack
I and Twitter good to you but we're not
talking about that
so up so these are back right so so im
how did the attacker you did today
attacked the you know their mobile
devices
now it was a mobile it was just your
standard it was exploits against web
browsers and that stops
so a in real life as far as I know
there's never been an attack that's the
traced back to a mobile
I'm export
so so or you know why are we so we're
right is as there's a max I'm I'm trying
to tie is nothing really to worry about
now but are there some things we should
be worried about
and Isaiah Bay City problems I wanted
I users are are not so smart and the
other is
in our prime location which is like a
pretty bad this
so the biggest problem with users is not
that they're going to visit
a bad site that they're gonna download
malware which is the problem
and dust-up world the problem with it on
phones that there is no these are
so up as I you can stop them from doing
that or protecting them would like
and we appreciate also uses are gonna do
things like your break their phones
because they want to have you know like
Hello Kitty
that stuff or something on
and I'm listening to hear the
translation
um I'm a and I think that you know how
but a the so what happens when you
jailbreak your phone
what time they basically turned up all
the security think this is turning up
some
little bit but it time's up every
terms of a much limitations and I was
like to download
go from anywhere that's what it's the
Pacific it also the code to download no
longer runs in Samarra
and it might run it through that and the
the code you download now can
dynamically change itself
witty sobil you add more attacks
sommersby anymore code
and they can actually break what little
security software
is that are you there
so anyway when when you did you ever get
on their good turn up on their security
so again this is this is my last the
user promises and apples
all that people do this
um so yes I you jailbreak your phone you
basically go back to
that's up security or worse
so the the biggest issue really and
mobile in my opinion is this
this problem up fragmentation
the problem is with Android up you don't
as by
phone and and you're done right so up
you by phone within the US
it's made by some companies like Samsung
so they physically make the device
and then you get your your carrier I
AT&T or whoever you guys have done here
they add software to it because they can
and then Upper School has the has
provided you with times a
occurred in the operation you got the
three parties
involved anytime that there is a problem
and they want to update it all the
parties have to be involved in that
process
and and the biggest problem with that is
that to the party's
the manufacture and repair they don't
actually want you to upgrade
they want you to buy me a call so
they're really not motivated
to to provide you an update who was the
only one that actually has a
interest in you opinion advice and so
yet three people that we get along
they don't like each other and they
don't actually want to upgrade
and so that's why we don't see upgrades
iPhone is a different story Apple
controls everything
very easy to break your phone make it
happen over-the-air
and the people people one up
so I could hear some numbers are just so
the case
for prime locations this is a a graphic
get from Google
so the adoption above the new a person's
as they come out
a you can see the these lines they don't
go out very fast
so Ice Cream Sandwich which came out a
long time ago as though on this chart
less than 30 percent
use so here's some more numbers on
on Android and house how slow it is to
upgrade
so on the left the the date that the
various versions came out
in on the right is the adoption those
versions you can see
that a so for
came out almost a year ago
but is only eight percent adoption I
likewise a like 4.0 came out
two years ago and you know that and they
were is that why
you know 50 percent so 30 percent phones
are
rain and rain are running a virgin more
than two years old
I O S it's like a totally different
story so I ask you but very very quickly
the the graph I took a
months ago and value guy I seven members
on the next slide
but here so virgin sixty-mile
about a year ago and ninety percent
abuses are on
virgin sex when this came out
that's a big difference I and II
southern
the obviously that just came out a you
know two weeks they are something
you can see that already
over sixty percent users II 7
so in two weeks you got thinkers and
people are you upgraded to the new
version
I'll so that a very different Andrew
and you know for the few pieces the
malware that have
have involves a exploits the gingerbread
was one that
that allowed you get root as that
affected up to 234
Android but it still packed somewhere
between 22 and 33 percent devices
even on the socks place two years old
yes we're talking about earlier
jailbreak mean I have three
effects I was that the 433 on
its you know it came out around the same
time and it only takes 3 percent lace
so up so it's only you probably believe
my now
but that's a problem you probably
believe hopefully that
that mobile devices you don't have to
worry too much about
exploitation an hour at this point what
what did things you can do
that you know help protect your device a
year you you really want to do that
it's your job to I'm William I guess are
you can't change
you know how secure the average system
is that's not that's not under control
you can't change how hard it is to get
them review
on you can change the sam i've seen you
can't change
up you know that a flying the DUP
you can change whether your devices have
hardware encryption more than anything
like that
and you can't really even install
antivirus on phones
because %uh the whole fam oxen model
hope this doesn't work
you just have to trust the operating
system is gonna do things like that
the beatings you can do are things I can
force Pasco's
to help users when they they lose their
homes began forcing the encryption and
you can use remote white
amal I'll okay
and things like and are you can limit
where the app's can be downloaded from
on but again these things are things you
can do but users can still
a change you they can they can get
around it if they really wanted
lows or so so who are we worried about
what were the attackers we care about
so you got your your teenagers and and
you know
you that are just trying to show off
their friends and they're just
doing it for fun so neck is what are
they gonna choose to do
well it if your teenager and and you
just wanna impressive runs by
I'm in a little but that or something
nothing about them all is it harder
and we're gonna pension and PCs reveres
fire come I'll and that case a you're
gonna want to try to make money
and you want to do that easily and as
quickly as possible
so again you're gonna you're going to go
up the pieces because it's so much
easier and you probably are you got a
buncha codes and around a bit
so really if you're smart criminal
you're not going to worry about
a mole because it's harder what if your
are like the Chinese government or
something
you're going after the president Brazil
a
then and it's certainly a possible
right they have a lot of money and they
have very to go target their own after
so nekesa they might like them all but
most people in this room probably I the
target
other or so on if that's the people you
worry about than you probably have
a real fear to story but I'm not worried
about that
on so severe someone who has to decide
how to focus your energy or focus your
money
um what you gonna do about mobile so I
went completely ignore it
but it's probably not worth it to spend
a lot of money because
I guess that your really you're not
gonna see attacks against it
and there's not really any evidence that
there's ever been an attack against that
cause
a problem
so what might change in the future use
so like maybe
maybe something a change and use on
their mobile will be a problem so what
would have changed for that to happen
like the mobile OS's are gonna get any
any worse
right you like I see I I can remove it
are not remove a symptom
but what what's gonna what one might
change though is that
might not get easier for mobile attack
to make it harder
the PC attacks so a
like this OSX there have been App Store
other anymore there's more so much and
brothers already they might be lesser I
can't
and so while it's always going to be
very hard to the mobile tax
like and that's something I figure I
commence lead at that time attacks get
up to here
then may be fair game for everybody
also I the the Tigers are trying to make
money they need to file the data
so if all the data then she ends up on
your phone that eventually the
the bad guys I think about your but for
now that's not
surroundings up up you know I think I'm
you know we've also known as researchers
at North Texas and the possible
on but but %um in real life we don't see
them
and if there's going to be a mobile
attack against a platform
it probably be it and make it easier
you might see if I like a super
sophisticated
um a attack but
not just your normal kinda you know
attack
on attackers ice-t_ will do what's
what's the easiest
for them to accomplish their goals and
right now that's not normal
and here's my side resources that
tobacco price a
and at that you have any questions
well be around if you have questions
come up to me and we can we can chat
thanks %ah