okay series and that was about half full
well winning want to meet up read it
wasn't doing something
and wardens woohoo
this low versus what is clear is that
lives with me
what I was always nice for Muslims other
hikers the main wouldn't
western region of them who believe my
eyes will also work incorporates a
bronze
you all my calls me my own business
porky well
I a plethora based real momentum energy
E
King lost with the idea me however he
wants another software
it wasn't much but I think we will see
move long hard look
emmett was has been a consultant
violence what led
how DL we're going to be in good
iight is said
and then you need a shot good
as a man could bring me an apple power
supply to the handy
I'll I as it today I'll be telling you
about the southern appalachians Space
Agency Inc
which happened when I was drunk I need a
and purchase a satellite dish that was
their place in the United States Navy
I ahead is delivered to my farming in
Tennessee in
which is where Jack Daniels is made mom
which coincidentally enough was what I
was drinking
when I but the satellite dish and then
my friend in I
repurposed this satellite dish to be
able to track
satellites that are lower orbit
most satellite hacking is done against
satellites in geostationary orbit
because they're study target
so if I A take a ham radio and I a man
in tennis I'll
from Tennessee I will hear Portuguese
over the radio because Brazilian truck
drivers by reusing
the american satellites the nineteen
seventies in order to
bounce traffic and across the truck
driving routes
but I wanted to track the satellites
they're moving very
close to the ground the satellites that
are moving very fast in the sky
and that moved to this guy so quickly
that you can't
leave an antenna pointed at them because
the movie the entire sky in 15 minutes
and examples would be the International
Space Station
were some the
telephone satellites Azumi radioman
Globalstar
these moved to this guy very quickly and
you need custom hardware and software to
track them
the software that is available for
tracking them isn't very good
so I had to rewrite my own from scratch
I'm
and my friend Collin Mulliner demands
did with a bet going as you can but were
dinosaurs on stage
so I score one point
and I I did this work thanks to the help
the that the end and skating two friends
9 from Berlin
and and it's already built up on work
from Adam Lori engines you have any
who did the earlier work in
geostationary satellites the ones that
are so high
that they stay in one space and relative
to the air
and and also to the good neighbors
apartment
I'm who were I'm around for a lovely
conversations involving this
now you can't have a space agency in my
case the southern appalachians space
agency
without a mission patch and this is my
mission patch
it's based upon my peoples native
culture and
we have lots um and
like cinder blocks in cars and cinder
blocks and its traditional that you'll
have many
on used cars in your yard in Tennessee
so do I have here is in a box beneath my
satellite dish
and and this is back to all this really
is sitting on cinder blocks
and on the right you have an alien
I there is little green men about this
tall we call them burgers
head in the background it's kinda hard
to see
there that many shine still
because it's traditional to make with
you at home where I come from
and good in this guy
you can see some space garbage and the
International Space Station and there's
a glove
and a banana yah
and because you know they they have to
ship their garbage downward
weight stays in the same way with their
end and it's not a big get cluttered his
pieces break off
I and then on the left there's a man
with a neck beard and a shotgun
and has the shotgun to defend himself
from the book or on the right
would
so at at Berlin sides last year again a
lecture in reverse engineering
the spot protocol mmm
and anything that mean where the guy was
hiking
and the rock fell on his arm and he had
to cut his arm off to get away
I'm he really would like to have some
cell phone reception
with spot does is it allows you to send
a message
from your cell phone up to a satellite
and the satellite redirects the signal
to the Internet
so even if you don't have a cell phone
signal you can still transmit a message
from the middle of the desert
or from the middle of the ocean and
so I reverse engineered this protocol
and first a reverse engineered the
Bluetooth
that's used to allow the phone to talk
to the spot
and then I reverse engineer the
satellite link which runs at one point
six figure hurts
it is completely clear text it is
uninterrupted
and if the entire recording and the
signal is very easy to parse it
into interpreted I contains the serial
number GPS coordinates
and would ever text messages and up as
if you say they came I'm alright
I'll get that if he say oh dear god the
rock is pressing my arm please and help
I'll get that and this is the
photograph the device it's about that
bed
and these are really easy to program
their Bluetooth protocol is very simple
and and their easy to reverse engineer
up
to reverse engineer the home
coffee is complicated at your residence
near the Android application that
initially
control this and and raid at least the
site engine
my drums contains a tool called ABC i
dont
which will dump a log of all the
Bluetooth traffic
that that particular devices had this is
important because his
and which is terribly difficult to sniff
external im
but he's defeated from one in the device
is that supposed to be in the
conversation
you can get a very good recording and on
the right is a screenshot
although what the output looks like
sitting at Google Map
results everywhere in this case I was in
philadelphia walking west across the
Schuylkill River
when you have the recording what happens
internally
is that the spot sends a long series
in a siddur and code
for either is 0 or 1 but when it
switches between these
is little pop on the radio sinew when
you look at the recording
a which goes down we didn't miss
recording your number zeros first
and then whenever there's a switch from
the 02 01
you have a pop was a little circles and
the circles
happen between that the circle is not a
bit itself
and the status was that I know the
protocol and I can sniff yep thanks
I'm what I want Downing's
I'm I don't want to see people in Mason
City talking to the satellite
I want to see people on nice n Clinton
and talking to the satellite
and the way to do that is to sniff the
downlink
but that requires a satellite dish and
and it requires a moving satellite dish
because
the satellite moved to this guy very
very quickly
to a take a look Adam raises tools for
playing with your station satellites
which he published in 2008
and in 2010 he is
a KU band receiver with HDTVs
television part this is the same sort of
setup that you used for receiving
satellite TV
in the next and and then
he made me the television is moved by
AntiSec motor
and I think motor can only move left and
right it's not be able to move up and
down
and his tool is available at spots at
now it's at this URL
this is the photograph and his the
scanner and with this tool is doing
is its I'm it's trying every frequency
on the current satellite you know teach
you look
for videoing and the this
may be playing on the left is coming
down from that to be silent
and you can also make maps this way I
made this map by moving
one of my dishes left and right and then
recording which frequencies are being
used to the x-axis
is the acid in and the y-axis is the
frequency
and wherever you see a dot there's a
transmitter
you can see that satellite which are
next to each other try not to use the
same vacancies
and he moved from left to right their
gas
and you'll also see the something can
seize
are just like a little pinprick that's
the way from the others
I'm there is a I think are physically
separate satellites that are just
near each other and and it is stepped in
as admin
and sing about three degrees in this guy
in with you
and if I go much further east or west
this diagram
my dishes misaligned and because the
geostationary satellites
four missing bring in this guy I'm this
is called the clock bell
after a sick like and because it's
curved shape and I can only move left
and right with this dash
I can't like see things that are in the
wrong position this guy
to the bench is a bit are that there is
cheap hardware available you can just
buy
kid to run Adams tools and
you'll pay about 200 250 US dollars
the and the particles were talking to
these motors are standardized
zoo your machine doesn't really care
what brand of motor you have
you you don't have to do much more than
and simple rewiring
and you get TV signals video feeds so
it's really easy to point
at an incoming signal and say hey I got
that and you'll also find you
weirding signals Lake I'm
on the news when the interview people
very often the interviews are bounced
over this network and see you can
actually watch the interviews
live and you can sometimes the
embarrassing footage where people say
things when they think they're up camera
and and they're also it is the IP
packets going across this network
and said he's dead by this or you can
actually catch internet downlink traffic
and which is certainly sniffing have a
wifi connection
you see what the access point says the
user
what you do not see what the user says
back to the access point
but their disadvantages the only works
with
geostationary satellites so in essence
24,000 miles in this guy
exactly and staying in the same place
orbiting
one Spurrier said the real day exactly
you're not going to be able to receive
it and it's very
slow very inaccurate tracking and this
is my guy 24 was measured in pics
and not degrees on the acceptance that's
because my mother isn't
accurate enough to properly tell me how
many degrees and
I would like to be able to move a
fraction of a degree
perfectly accurately in repeatedly and
you can't do that
with the dissect motors
you also limited to standardize signals
you'll find his VIP
you will find the video and that said
and a lot of that is encrypt data and
becoming more infected
and the general rule a catastrophe is
dead
and satellite TV providers the only one
to do it right
this there is a helluva lot of money
whenever anyone can make
think receiver cards as they've invested
a fortune
in preventing you from receiving using
captain signals
so I but a satellite dish and this is my
a dish being removed from the
Navy warship it is a billion deathbed
the and the ship have to have also
written communication methods
see you might also be able to find when
the same dishes come say hi and got
were and cruise ship
and my dishes FL come 81 its when needed
ish
intended for use with Inmarsat
and it has stepper motors for azimuth
elevation and
till and because the Disney this dish
would be plated
at the top of the ship's mast and his
ship rocks
this dish incorrect for the rocking
I paid 200 I'll between fifty dollars to
the sunny day
um is cost me two hundred dollars for
delivery bed
likely the guy I bought it from one and
an excuse to
drive near I was and if not
I would have had to pay a king's ransom
in airfare to have it delivered
and so I'd recommend that if you want to
repeat this work you find a port city
and
someone who repairs yachts and try to
buy addition and cheaply
and and it has spinning gyroscopes
visibility
see the way that this thing can tell how
the ship is rocking many that
these this was designed before the
iPhone
this is designed to be poor man's was
available said he couldn't just have an
electronic accelerometer
you had to have gyroscopes and the sky
was gives had to have
spinning wheels in now after these
wheels been up
the distance to know exactly how far
they've turned
but a gyroscope doesn't tell you that it
just tells you that you're too far to
the left it too far to the right
so actually has motors that move just
the gyroscopes
so that they can measure the difference
between the gyroscope and the dish
in order to be able to turn in specific
unknown number degrees
and unfortunately the software that it
ran was closed doors
and anti this runs on an 80 286 chip
internally
it can't even run and windows
ninety-five
up and so I A
built my own software to run on it which
I call the pasa framework
were southern Appalachian space agency
it's designed for tracking low-earth
orbit satellites
and and it produces the as a validation
and
I'm until values that
the dish needs but there is no reason
why
its limited to tracking the things that
are moving so
may suffer also track stars I contracted
space probes
strikes which one in Voyager 2 I'm
and I threw in a software-defined radio
to
I can record as strange signal and then
the modulated later
not really caring what is the time that
I recorded
this is very important because it allows
me to separate the problem
a finding the signal from the problem
the decoding the signal
and I can give a copy to my cousin is
better at doing some predefined radio
than I am
and he doesn't need to have his own dish
in order to
get the recording or in order to build
is and receiving software
and this is particularly useful when
identifying
unknown and I meant
and and I run the entire thing through
Linux machines that are spread around
the house that holds the satellite dish
so I have the BeagleBone the inside a
over the raid on
this is physically strapped to the dish
and these moves with the dish
this has the something fine radio this
has the motor controllers
but its night powerful enough to do this
often defined radio person
soon it sends all that data in the role
of
over Ethernet to a server inside the
house
and it's the server that actually does
the some predefined really cutting
and recorded because the server can have
as much towards I care to plug into it
but anything inside the Reno man has to
move with the debt
I is too much weight and is the way gets
above a threshold
the dish will become an actor and and I
run the entire thing through
post-crescent
so if you were able to do a single
injection exploit against
sassa you could physically move this
dead
and by doing the right relations at the
statement you can cause it to
rapid similar quarter round and said
hang it up
um and the the simple framework makes it
really easy to give the thing orders
and see if you want to know where your
my dishes pointed
you can select as El azimuth and
elevation
from position table and that tells you
where you are
and if you want to 18 min at say which
one
UN updates the and update targets at
nichols' Voyager 1
and then the targeting the men will
begin tracking that object
and at the moment I'm using a real tech
STR for the something if I radio
but I hope to move that over to hack
arrests in
use and I but word for motor control and
I have an inertial measurement unit
from back turn up and because today
the them to be back as
I'm today you can afford to have
an inertial measurement unit whereas
when this dish was designed
and I and you is the sort of thing that
you would only have in say a cruise
missile
now we all have them in ourselves and
this is the dish itself being worked on
I'm this is their rearview you can see
that there's this
central stop here and that their motor
is based around
as if in this position I could have the
entire dish turn left the entire dish
turn right
or had the dish raise up were fall down
or could have it till and
on the central stock I have followed the
devices wired up
and they're connected to each other by
USB and then connected to you
the household network by a 100 megabit
internet
the read more downside is not a
controller the green bernie is the
standard commercial USB hub the
whiteboard
is BeagleBone which is an alarm
system-on-chip computer that's it
you know about that'd
the stepper motors are undocumented but
there are only so many different types a
stepper motors
there are 6 pins the promoters and
therefore pins that matters
these are six but if you ignore the
inner 2 pins
then it's easy to connect them to the
I'm
the separate controller December
controller is and I but bored
and I is German for Ag and
the two all the
the Paris and connectors in the top the
apims in total
those are for motor one in motor to
and this is what the board was
originally designed for this is
a way that he needs Easter eggs using a
pen and moving
the eg around I'm but this same motor
controller
is powerful enough to move that large
satellited
because the reduction the the dish
itself
has small motors that are connected to
you polly's
the police's reduce the movement but
increase the port
so that the small motors and satellite
dish are enough
to you in the dash
as a backup in case I forget where my
dishes
I have a webcam on the back and
and this white thing here is the radium
at my brother's lovely car in the lapd
that's my father's lovely trapping
writing I'm
so that is made it home had his like a
white insight
and the Sun night comes through it just
a little bit because this is fiberglass
to we painted the rate home so that the
webcam to look out at the rate on
and then if there's a software bug you
or if you know what if you were to be a
jerk in to run a single injection
exploit to make my district where it is
I can repair its positioning remotely
and this is important because
I built this in Tennessee and tennessee
is a long way away from
anyplace good airport
see you you know it takes me a long time
to get to Tennessee and it takes me a
long time to leave
by a painting the way to make this I can
remotely repair it when simple
things break these software
also runs through this post test
framework and so this is
photograph the sassa commander which is
the
lying commanding control utility
all these read entries always satellites
andy green when is the satellite that's
being targeted
the crosshairs show at which point
misguided the
dishes Inc and as the satellite moved to
this guy which everyone is being
targeted will be followed
by a the she goes three
sorta hovers in the same region this guy
I'm but it moves up and down a lot
and I can just leave this alone for
hours to follow
that target and
a comedian the lights in the front just
a bit
is a screenshot so hard to see these
whiting pieces in the background and
those are stars
and I can actually project missing star
Matt onto the Sasa view
as you would see in the night sky said
he is in is at night you can look up in
the sky and actually
visibly see by constellations which
party this guy you're targeting
it's a bit better thank you and
now is to bosnia polar view and seeing
this case you seeing like
a top-down view on the main satellite
dish
with here you see a first-person view
IQ's if you're looking out from the dead
and by comparing the two you can start
appalling things that are harder to
track
for example dolores is the Northstar
its Justin Center directly up
from the centre circle and that's either
the extreme left in extreme right below
the standard you
the policy allows me to see that and
there's nothing going on cell phones
so this is my Nokia N 900 controlling
the says addition
and and in this game China and connected
over wifi
but in cases where there is the 3G
service
I can actually develop the dishes
software
on public transportation and so
significant portion this development I
did
from the subway in Berlin
they have good and networking activity
there so
I would just you knowing SSH over to the
server
open up in accession and began hacking
away
and I can do that motherhood by peddling
the post-test process
than mice implanted could run Isles is
running on my Nokia 900
which is terrible for development
because the as I'm a Nokia n9
this is terrible for development because
it doesn't have a keyboard
but it's really cool to be able to just
pull out a cell phone and
ordered the dish to do something
and this is a a program called
viewpoints from nasa
this is particularly handy if you're
trying to find
a satellite but you don't exactly know
who
where it is so you do is you program the
dish
to use think this guy I'm and to look
around the frequency that you know the
transmission will be made on
I and then whenever you see a pop-up you
can record those
hines and this software allows you to
deal with large datasets
so you can
in a call in this spot recordings the
you know
this pregnancy was in use with the
strength at this time I'm
week for months and you can take all the
data for this month
and sorting work with it until you've
identified how to select the satellite
you're looking for
and then run it backward to log from the
protection anyways
to figure out which satellite was not
who's this guy at that time
and now I I told you there and
everything
through a Postgres database but they
didn't really tell you how the post test
database
hood do all these things make is
normally
when you do an update statement that
doesn't keep changing teacher
things inside the database so I built
this
all around multiple UNIX demons which
Ryan
throughout May home network I'm 20 min
that does nothing but orbit predictions
and two it will predict where the
satellites are
and then it will make an UPDATE
statement you the database table
for every thing that it's tracking
and I have another team in the grads
norad Tulane
entry and elements I the motor control
demand
this is the thing that actually gives
commands to the white
circuit board to tell it how far and in
which direction to move the motors
I have an inertial measurement unit in
play which takes an accelerometer input
to tell you know how high a my dishes
tilted
and also and integrated accelerometer to
tell how far it move left and right
and its sanity checks the motor control
demand
the motor control even remembers how far
it is moved
sometimes this is inaccurate the
inertial measurement unit can compensate
for that
and I also have the radium I'm a couple
different radio demons because I want to
the different things with the radio
and for example I might want to do a
spectrum analysis just to tell which
frequencies are in use
or I might want to record an individual
downing
and this allows me to do that and
also because certain other signals is a
strong
I'm sometimes I get home said for my
peoples native culture
so I can actually download the local FM
radio stations
and listen to them through this I like
this
for all the predictions I initially used
program called predicted
on this is a ily applications you have
to the started inside him
the new screen were something else will
keep the
graphical window open and it allows you
to query the positions
other ads satellites over you TP but
it's limited to 20
birds and you can predict the some
planets
like to the moon or the Sun but it can't
predict others
so it won't tell me where jupiter is or
where Mars's
so they switched to a library called
high FM pie from a lousy team
predicted the positions have hundreds of
different satellites
and it doesn't require any weird EP
tracking
it's just a Python library that you can
directly
use in a demand that also talks
post-crescent
I'm and i cant read more than 500
satellites that difficulty this way
I'm it also has planets and stars
and this is I N a test in which I
haven't predicting every single object
that is in geostationary orbit
and also everyone in the GPS satellites
these more than 500
satellites in total and it's able to
protect them without
any performance trouble what are the
checks that uses I prioritizes
the satellites based upon their velocity
and whether they are being tracked
to if and
if I were to you click on one in the
satellites in order to follow it
after the computers time will be spent
tracking just that satellites that I had
it as accurate as I possibly could
but I you also need to know who what the
orbits are
because these orbits change we're really
old satellites things that are you sort
of drifting up there
the orbits are consistent Voyager 1 has
no fuel left
so I don't have to worry about going to
one changing environment
a paper published before you won once
every decade
and by I need to be able to track
moving satellites and I need to be able
to track ones that change
orbit rather often the International
Space Station has a lot of fuel
and it very frequently moved to avoid
stay strong
and to its orbit is very unpredictable
if you were to attempt to do with pen
and paper you would never
be able to keep up suit norad runs this
project consultants track
and so this track is list everything in
orbit
and they also provide smaller lists
based upon and
particular types is that elects if you
want to list every television satellite
were every GPS satellite or every
amateurs Adelaide
you can download is this and then
looking directly into your predictions
are
so I have a demand that automatically
grabs these files the sales rack server
and then feeds them in my purse
guesstimates were
protectionism tracking things
the motor control the men was
surprisingly easy to write
the I but word shows up as a thick
serial port
this ice dance class TTY ACN 0
and you can just give it commands in
asking so if I wanted to move
and 500 steps up and four hundred steps
left
and I wanted to do this in 3,000
milliseconds
I would just runs first manned SN 3,000
500 -0400 and then using a carriage
return
and then removed it sends an okay back
to you at the end
and so by waiting on the issue
consortium I'm
big things what you need to know both
where your target is and where your
target will be
and in order to track accurately
to moving in 3 second bursts becomes a
little bit unpredictable because you
wind up
moving too wary the satellite was three
seconds ago
which were very fast-moving satellite
can be off by more than half a degree
you can also enable and disable the
motors and they have different stepping
motors
to these are stepper motors which have
many different magnets and then and you
can move a fraction is dat
but if you want to freely move the death
to push it around
you need to disable the motors so when
everything is this Steven will do is it
will turn off the motors
if I order it till so that I can
physically reposition the dish
when and and debugging things
and this is the close up on rewiring the
motors
the he said big grey box on the right
that is a 250 watt microwave
transmission
I'm up
this is when the stepper motor is is
always something the the gear assemblies
so this is the motor on the bottom right
and you can see that is running a few
different gears and pulleys
in order to increase the motor string
and decrease its
the decreasing in speed also increases
its accuracy which is useful for me when
I'm trying to
track objects now I'll is also an
inertial measurement unit demand
which is giving me all sorts of trouble
if I were to build another one in these
I might leave the I am new album this is
the most expensive part in the dish
cost about five hundred dollars and I
used an actor now being 100% which has
men's accelerometer it has a gyroscope
and it has a compass now it
its easy with modern men's technology to
tell
how the hell did you are because you
just a teenager
the direction of gravity and gravity is
very strong
it's a lot harder to measure and your
as and your asthma like how far left and
right you've moved
because the magnetic field of the earth
is very inconsistent
not only does it move but it's several
degrees of frontier North
and it's very difficult to work this
into your math
and also it it drifts based upon
magnetic interference
from the motors and I made a mistake
amounting is too close to one of the
motors
soon the I'm the compass is the last
season's
at the turn of the heritage and then we
and our
for that it has been recently I
I needed another reason is like in love
so he and his giving you an actor
instead it was all about turning
the I'm the amazing and you can use it
went straight up
just like you know generating 80
training is free to your
lol believe this guy and I'm saying I
agree
and then you turn bills been very very
thing
and that's because we knew move your
mouse let anything
review telling your character to
rosy to his left and he went straight up
it in his saw
no position the company is ACE elevation
to the inertial measurement unit even
and he hasn't from another team
and the miller also help millions on
television and this allows me to send a
check to make sure that my mother is a
nice to earn any bells
and because when the retail stuff coming
in the linden trees
and messing around wish is
you always hours not especially if
you're trying to not let me know that i
won
and at night using aluminum to you know
English
in the left and right I A don't have an
immediate need for that
design easy and on solid ground into a
shed
I have made a difference which run
myself in Miami
radio there's a spectrum analyzer the
desert where is every single takes the
best
reagents for and then a tragic figure
out
how strong the signal isn't releasing
and also
how that strength the race movie ever in
position
and in with your router it is just a
little bit
off to the left to the right and even
too high and low
and so that I can read these things out
for also telling
we're anticipating the raw almonds are
defined radio
and raise it directly into yes
right grab it later be the state's
several megabytes per second
so it's not usually mean I have to
download it to you live recording
which is difficult to do bill
on the a slow him in an action in a
small town
and i actually considering a 20 and a
buncha
I guess into trap so they can drive a
truck for the nearest big city
issues and yeah you know
and these crazy people in the Nativity
where
cyl is a spectrum didn't think the
decision on the
the %eh I salesman the frequency and the
name on this island I was targeting
and this is another figure out whether
a blessing only is various think even if
just
came on a little bit where exactly
consistent right to ask
%uh that's sad
this is when I you with a few months
I'm and the point presents all is
there's a Giants got it I'll using only
go and then Israel color the flames
by Ian different axes and then selecting
the lies that you find interesting
and see how the background ways find
jessica lynn you're interested in
me to my issue
a strong signal weak signal this is a
things
and then you can view different Las see
you might wanna see
I'm PVC you really see how the
diversions changes
is let you determine when it is I'll a
tracking was
listens to the air and you might also
lose
word ABC single-stranded regions in
order to television channels and yes
when the masses bank in order to find
local NHS
so not only can I listen to the radio
this but I and also has been left to
right and tell exactly in which
direction the organization s
and the plant billy is my
City easily do you single very
sure there is almost no I mean another
any the satellite logic in sight
the gigli does not understand this is an
elitist
doesn't understand it is moving to the
owners all eight
is doing is showing the results a
lesley Anne and apply it is I'll as an
artist
you can just as easily is million dollar
JavaScript to run
retired tools on these days and this
summer is all they had the lead
which is why it's not a problem for me
to run as on my cell phone on another on
because all I was doing is showing the
available data
like it
I'm I as i said im bored as either an
all-new
over and I'm Upolu
to the lead and accurate tracking and
Silas
I have is operating 24 hours a day for
months at a time
a we are now the decisions that a as in
all this time
things and trying to unify successfully
I have
something finally when he's working
I'm but I don't wanna the next to the
were scanned the entire sky
a every group has over Tennessee
I'm certain restricted idiot he said
last night and you basically my position
he has an interesting movies and less I
can get a life
such as eligible for themselves law when
they're in the wrong position this time
for example russian television
satellites are adamant on an all nighter
they find very high in the northern
hemisphere very low in the southern
hemisphere
and the only transmit know the answer so
I didn't see you cannot see them and
reserve
I'm an excess
it is the intent wasn't to be seen by
Russia
I just can't see the satellites this day
still on the far side of the year
so many things that is a are over Asia I
will never see his the number and a nice
guy
but I'm getting us and I can take some
time to find me weddings and everything
else
by first identifying to see that he is
and then taking reporting on that
and the result is a visa to terrorize
incised
by you really wanna know that is a
play I don't like to build other
presentations
so this offer should be portable to your
hardware
and install model to having won the
lines were
and I have a rather large yard and I and
I'm wearing these things 7 I'll with it
and as a different frequencies
and Alyssa array8 satellite dishes like
sky I'm
is a another I the sadly I don't even
play where
this is an amateur radio
I'm satellite receiver this is for lower
taxes
the EU agencies
but it also requires less accurate
weighing
be his using in a direction and a
stylish
and I like to look at these you compare
it to my age
and president fears
and isolation and never let me have a
picture
I'm say this is Brad it turns out I was
pregnant when we took this photo
so if anyone would like it is let me
know
think tank
does is the way we're at it sells
whether or not I have time for questions
okay you have time either team as light
%uh
yeah when you shop
come on Yahoo yeah
thank God and its