it was pointed out to me I didn't
introduce myself when I came up the
first time and and that's because I
think I know most of you and most of you
know me I am either Jean spafford or a
modestly well working AI simulation
thereof and I'm sort of the corporate
memory of this organization now in some
regards and and that's where I'll reach
for introducing our first keynote when
we were sort of planning these events on
a yearly basis to both expose our
students and faculty to research going
on outside and also to have people
outside for you find out more about what
we were doing here at the University we
structured the symposia around the idea
of some selected keynotes where we'd
reach out to distinguish individuals
representing a government representing
industry and representing the practice
and so each year for the past in years
for n a small number we have sent out
these invitations and we have been very
fortunate to you have people come to
represent those various sectors for the
industry side we've managed to attract
CEOs and CTOs of international
organizations individuals who've gone
from startups to multi-million dollar
companies and they've been very happy to
share their expertise with us on the
government side we have been able to
attract presidential advisers cabinet
secretaries and deputy secretaries the
Executive Assistant Director of the FBI
and on one occasion the recently retired
director of national intelligence so
we've had some wonderful speakers in
here and we're continuing that tradition
today our first keynote representing the
government sector is a brigadier general
retired a Greg to Hill Greg started off
as an engineering major
at Penn State and he has an interesting
story i'm not going to relate all of it
here but as a result of a missile launch
gone awry he decided it might be safer
to move to a different field and ended
up graduating with a degree in political
science along the way in his military
career he picked up two masters degrees
in systems management and in strategy in
the Air Force he served as director of
command control communications in cyber
for Transportation Command was the
deputy assistant director for for cyber
at DHS and most recently was the first
federal see so the chief information
security officer we're especially
pleased to have him here because at our
first symposium we had the first ever
see so Steve Katz who is the CSO for
citibank i had was the first person to
occupy that title greg is the first
person to have that role in the federal
government we're thrilled to have him
here please join me in welcoming general
greg to hill thanks Beth thank you
can you hear me with this mike is it
turned on alright thumbs up in the back
I'm going to put the hands held down yet
to complete the story I would say like a
third lieutenant intern at the rocket
propulsion lab at Edwards Air Force Base
between my junior and senior year I saw
an o-ring burned through on the solid
rocket fuel booster and frankly I didn't
like the people I was going to be
working with and I was going to go there
as a second lieutenant and the only way
I could escape that assignment was to
not take a Bachelors of Science and with
the support of my father and the colonel
I flip flop my major in my minor and the
Air Force didn't know what to do with me
so they put me in this new field called
computers and electronics and the rest
is history I never went back I mean
credit short of chemical engineering and
I'm not going back and funny too because
my father's got PhD in engineering he
really really wanted me to go there but
no I made the right choice i think it
was a divine inspiration today i would
like we've got a choice and i'd like to
do a quick poll as a former government
official i have been trained to stand
behind the podium and read to you a
speech how many want that kind of
presentation today as opposed to let's
have a conversation with lots of
pictures okay let's go for the first one
stodgy speech anybody okay we've got one
brave person who has he's juiced up on
caffeine he's ready
how many folks want to have a
conversation about cyber okay great
alright so today what I'd like to do is
this I'd like to share some of my life
lessons on cyber security and the first
thing is cyber is not a technology issue
technology ism most important part of
that I might my view as a technologist
but it's not the only part at its heart
cyber security is a risk management
issue it's all about risk and you know
why should you care about cybersecurity
well I've been asked that question
throughout my professional career and a
lot of different fora and you know I
talk about it as a risk management issue
and it starts getting the attention of
directors of companies there you know
cabinet officials it gets the attention
of the c-suite as well and I think it's
really important that all of us be
prepared to make the business case for
what we're doing in cybersecurity
because the decision makers who allocate
resources are critically important and
making sure that you're able to follow
through because if it ain't funded it
ain't so anybody know who this this
picture represents this is Sunzu okay
sunzu and adds a war college graduate
I'm obliged in every speech to refer to
Sunzu and quote a dead German so sunzu
said if you know your enemy and you know
yourself in a thousand battles you shall
not be vanquished today what I'd like to
do is walk through some of the lessons
learned as to knowing yourself as well
as knowing your enemy and give you some
tips that maybe you will be helpful for
you as you're putting together a
cybersecurity program to better manage
your risk and as you go into that why
should you really be paying attention
two sons ooh well the first thing is
this information is an asset people want
to get your assets so you got to cover
your
asset you need to protect your
information because information is at
the center of every one of your missions
your operations it's your intellectual
property it's your brand and reputation
it's the privacy of yourself and your
clients your integrity your trust levels
safety competitive advantage all of
those all of the above are now wrapped
into your cyber security posture you
can't operate a business you can't
operate a government you can't operate a
household without having a solid
cybersecurity program in place think
about that Home Office and everywhere in
between and now with such legislation as
sarbanes-oxley and some of the new
legislation that's come out for
corporate responsibility do care and due
diligence is also part of the
cybersecurity lexicon if you are not
practicing best practices in managing
your information you expose yourself as
a business to calls that you are not
practicing do care and due diligence
which now under the legal construct
carries with it a heavy burden for the
officers and the directors of companies
as you go in and you talk to the head
shed make sure that you do a little bit
of homework on what constitutes do care
and due diligence and put your language
in their language okay don't get hung up
on the technical terms because it'll
just cause the eyes to roll in the back
of their heads they won't really care
when you get into your inner geek what
they do care is when their bacon is on
the line make the business case now
here's a interesting a little slide
frankly I've gone through in my military
career and my government career and
working with the private sector I see a
lot of folks put out for both tones
spelling out strategies strategy for
this or strategy for that
I'll tell you that anybody who puts out
a lengthy strategy book is fooling
themselves because very few people have
the time or patience to read them what
was our strategy in World War two hold
in the Pacific when in Europe go back
and defeat the Japanese in the Pacific
that was our grand strategy hold win win
every soldier sailor Airman and marine
knew that strategy everybody at home
knew that strategy everybody was coming
together what's our cybersecurity
strategy for your different
organizations that you work with anybody
bueller bueller anybody well you know
when I came in as the federal see so our
strategy was codified in a lengthy tome
that very few folks outside of academia
and policy walks actually read and it
was increasingly difficult to articulate
in different circles within the federal
government so I came out and I put
together a strategy five sentences
because if the troops can't articulate
the strategy it doesn't get done first
part of that strategy harden the
workforce everybody's on the cyber front
lines right Home Office everybody needs
to be cyber aware you don't need to be a
cyber expert and you know all the secret
cyber ninja stuff you don't have to be a
cissp or cism to be cyber aware you know
for crying out loud mom don't click that
link to you have to treat information as
an asset right information is an asset
three you've got to do the right things
the right way and arguably at the right
time for continuously innovate and
invest wisely you know we've got to
introduce into the federal government
that's really groundbreaking concept
called depreciation and recapitalization
of IT assets and then the fifth one is
we got to make informed cyber risk
decisions at the right level too often
folks were seeing the leaders were
kicking
decisions to the kids in the server room
and you know what it wasn't working so
from a strategy standpoint five
sentences make sense you know we fleshed
it out too because the strategy that
doesn't get executed is just shelf where
so we actually put goals that were
feasible acceptable suitable and
affordable along with them unfortunately
often we have when the new teams come in
they throw out the old strategies and
they got to go create their new ones
let's see how the new strategy compares
to that strategy as it's coming forward
but in the past the government went out
and bought everything you know and
frankly one of the things that as I came
out of the military and then to DHS is
the deputy assistant secretary we didn't
know all the stuff we had you're not so
one of the things we did is under the
continuous diagnostics and mitigation
program which is a six billion dollar
program one of the first things we did
is we put together a strategic construct
to it know what you have you know what's
on your network who's on your network
and what's going on in your network
three strategic lines of effort known
what's on your network turns out to be
and we knew that it was a mess dog's
breakfast you never knew what you're
going to find and we found that just in
the first pass and putting discovery
tools on government networks we found 77
million dollars worth of additional
equipment that the departments and
agencies didn't even know they had and I
think that number is going to go way way
up strategy matters but it's got to be
clear and concise as you're putting
together the strategies for your
organization put it language that
everyone understands bounce it off of
your mom if your mom understands your
strategy you're making a good start all
right let's see if I can't get this to
move all right anybody know this group
here these are the flying will lend us
do you think that every single one of
them
those where their risks are I would
submit the answer is yes we all need to
make sure that we understand our risk
and against in with the hardening the
workforce standpoint this is not just an
IT issue when we talk about
cybersecurity it is a business issue
everybody has a stake in it so you need
to culturally address cybersecurity from
the top of the organization all the way
down and in the federal government one
of the things that really irked my well
let's just say didn't make me happy was
we did just one and done training and
you know the annual watch a stupid video
and I pick you know sometimes you took
that sometimes you did one and done
training doesn't work folks and one of
the things that we tried putting into
the budget that just came out with some
additional training and exercises
because if you don't exercise you don't
succeed how many folks know who Knute
Rockne was famous Indiana coach right he
said practice makes perfect right how
about Vince Lombardi what did he say he
said Rockne was wrong Vince Lombardi
said perfect practice makes perfect and
whose names on the trophy now as you're
going through and building your program
make sure that you focus on the culture
and make sure that everyone knows what
the risks are because all it takes is
one stupid person I'm sorry I went
through government counseling uh one ill
informed and unmotivated person to you
know to trip on the wire and take
everybody down now Sunzu say it's
critically important to know your enemy
who's your enemy ok you know training
camps going to be happening and you know
I think Andrew Luck is probably looking
at this guy and saying hmm
this is somebody who's on my watch list
okay everybody knows who Tom Brady is
right yeah I'm from Pittsburgh we know
who he is what do you need to know about
your enemy well first of all you need to
identify who they are and you need to
understand what their motivations are
and why they may act against you and
what kind of information would they be
secant that you possess you need to know
what their objectives are and their
capabilities you know there's some
people who are still wanna be's do you
give them as much attention as those who
have more capabilities this audience
participation is where you give the
resounding no okay you got to know your
enemies you also need to understand
their patterns of behavior their attack
vectors their typical plans and the
light and through information sharing
and I'll talk a little bit more about
that you certainly can get that
information even when some folks say oh
well that's classified I can't tell you
yeah there's ways to get that
information and that's one of the things
that I think the government does a
crummy job on is the intelligence
community's will classify everything top
secret sensitive compartmented
information as a default one of the
things I tried doing is turning the
tables and say everything's unclassified
because pulling it off the internet you
got to prove why it has to be secret you
know top secret etc but know who your
enemies are investing business
intelligence invest in information
sharing because if you don't know who
your enemies are at sunzu would say you
will be vanquished now there's a lot of
threats in your neighborhood okay so
here are some of the typical types of
enemies that I see out there and when I
retired from the Air Force a friend of
mine gave me a laser pointer that looks
like a bullet it's great going through
TSA with this
ok so I would submit that the first
enemy that you've got a plan for our
vandals okay vandals are folks that are
going to come by and there it gotten
agenda they're going to come for example
to your website and friend of mine Geary
harbison is the C so at Monsanto every
time Monsanto comes out with a new
formulation of roundup guess what
happens they know that they're going to
have some folks often it's going to be
anonymous they're going to come in and
they're going to try to deface their
website impugning their brand and
reputation Monsanto plans for that and
can do a wipe and reload in about 20
seconds or less and they have
competitions to see who can detect and
do the wipe and reload and you know if
they reward those who are active on
their team but they note that threat is
out there who are the Vandals in your
neighborhood what about burglars
burglars they're financially motivated
they're crooks and you don't have to
have the name that ends and off or ski
to be a burglar you know my friends in
the FBI and the Secret Service they're
tracking burglars you know criminals
that are financially motivated around
the world here in the United States as
well as overseas you know frankly the
ones overseas generally get a little bit
more safe haven in some places that then
they get here in the United States and
computer crime in the United States is
actually pretty sophisticated but it's
not as pernicious and prevalent as what
we're seeing from overseas sources and
for those folks who think that the bad
guys overseas get away look up on on
your favorite browser sometime later
tonight Victor drinkman Victor drinkman
ripped off a couple of you know dozens
of the millions of dollars from some
financial institutions from his safe
haven in Eastern Europe but Victor and
his young bride decided that they wanted
to take a newlywed trip to Amsterdam
home of some of the greatest artworks in
the world and some pretty liberal laws
regarding
cot x and other things and they were
going to take a great vacation so Victor
and his new wife they get to Amsterdam
they pull out the cell phone and they
take a selfie and post it on their
facebook and what did the victor fail to
do we forgot to put off geo-tagging he
forgot that the Secret Service which
does financial crime is like monitoring
you know Facebook and looking for him
all it took was that post an alert
Secret Service agent a phone call to the
authorities there in Amsterdam and
Victor won an all-expense-paid trip to
New Jersey you know the United States
government is serious about this and
we'll track down these folks even if it
takes three years like it did Victor
drinkin or more but burglars are out
there and you got a plan for them and
they financially motivated and there's
big money in this game now how about you
know the the spies that are out there do
you think that these spies are the most
prevalent I think there's two types of
spice there's the nation-state spies but
then there's also and those that are
seeking intellectual property theft and
they're pretty prevalent and you know
just ask some folks from the CIA or the
NSA over the last couple of weeks about
spies what about your business what kind
of intellectual property do you have and
who has access to it what data loss
prevention systems do you have in place
I would submit that if you take a look
at the Edward Snowden and the Bradley
Manning cases both of them could have
been thwarted by more effective
frontline supervision not necessarily a
technical technical but frontline
supervision what are you doing to train
your frontline supervisors to thwart
insider threats and spying something to
think about something to implement about
muggers do you think that there's
internet
muggers out there I certainly submit
that there are and it goes beyond just
the high school bullying that's out
there do you think that the folks at
Sony motion pictures felt that they got
mugged by North Korea yeah I'll
definitely tell you that they thought
they got mugged in some regards though I
gotta tell you and this is not a an
official stance of the United States
government or endorsed by the
Commissioner Major League Baseball but
frankly I think the North Koreans did
Sony a favor because I don't think many
people were going to go watch that movie
you know but once they hacked in boy we
were doing in the end kick the national
cybersecurity and communications
integration Center where I served as the
director you know we had us-cert the
industrial control system cert and a
host of alphabet soup pretty important
entities in the end kick we did the
double feature of team america followed
by the interview gfb cuts were Americans
right but there's muggers out there you
got a plan for that those are part of
your enemies that you've got to
understand they're out there I think
saboteurs and you guys recognize to me
Timothy Olyphant from the arguably the
one of the worst die hard movies ever
who are the saboteurs you know saboteurs
are pretty pernicious but they're very
difficult to detect you never want to
have a single point of failure when
you're designing or architecting your
networks or your information stores but
you have to understand you've got to
build in according to the cybersecurity
framework the resiliency to take a punch
and keep on going you have to be able to
survive a saboteur and there will be a
saboteur at some point out there and
that saboteur could be deliberate or the
greatest threat that's out there the
careless negligent or indifferent
now that's a of course Jim Carrey and
his sidekick Jeff Daniels from dumb and
dumber I would submit that over
eighty-five percent of the incidents
that my teams in the US cert and the
industrial control system cert responded
to were the result of careless negligent
or indifferent people I'll repeat that
eighty-five percent the result of
careless negligent or indifferent people
now I used to append stupid but those
years of government training and
counseling came into play and I was told
not to mention stupid again but wait a
minute I'm no longer in the government
ya plan for stupid alright that's going
to be your number one risk factor to be
perfectly honest to typically speaking
careless negligence and indifferent
people offer a great threat risk
exposure you need to plan for it and how
do you mitigate some of that through
education and training and exercising
practice makes perfect but perfect
practice makes perfect ok let's see if I
can get this to advance I got a step
back there we go here's some other
threats that are out there I'm not going
to delve into these but physical threats
remain an issue that we all have to plan
against geography matters you know for
example I consulted with a company that
is in the greater Phoenix area and one
of the reasons they picked that place
for their data storage location is
seismically it's not very active there
if you go to Phoenix good luck getting
any seismic activity only seismic
activity you're going to get there sonic
booms from Luke Air Force Base and they
have water uh you know this right here I
used to be commander of Keesler Air
Force Base that's the comp Center at
Keesler Air Force Base I was sent in as
a commander after Hurricane Katrina and
they were ten miles east of Ground Zero
and my job was to not only continue to
train and educate airman
to rebuild the base it's amazing what a
billion dollars will do folks you know
if you're living on the Gulf Coast you
got a plan for hurricanes if you're
living here in the Midwest tornadoes
those California you know what gets what
California is thinking about earthquakes
there's a Fukushima if you're living
near nuclear reactor don't necessarily
feel comfortable if it's on a seismic
location on the coast where there could
be a tsunami who would know right don't
forget to about your paper records
cybersecurity isn't just the ones and
zeros it's all about the information
down in the lower corner corner and I
don't think everybody can see this is a
the residual detris from the devastating
fire at the National Archive in Seattle
upon me in st. Louis a lot of World War
two veterans all of their records were
in st. Louis and hard copy format there
was no backup for that information and a
fire went through and destroyed all the
paper records my uncle dick is going to
be interred in arlington on may fit he
died he was World War two fighter pilot
it took us quite a while to get his
records together so that we in fact
prove that he was a World War two
veteran you got to figure of your paper
records as well as part of your your
backup strategy and then of course you
know for those of us who have spent some
time in the Great Pacific Northwest you
know there's mount st. Helens are you
ready for when the next big volcanic
eruption occurs plan for all of your
threats as if they were an enemy I think
it's important to that you participate
in what I call the cyber neighborhood
watch I I coined this phrase when I was
at DHS because I think it's really
important that we all think of ourselves
like a neighborhood watch when it comes
to cyber if you don't know what's going
on in your neighborhood you can you're
going to be victimized one of the things
that I did while I was at Homeland
Security
when it came to information sharing is I
tried building that culture with my
folks so that we could in fact share
information in a manner that people
would understand but also protect the
identities of the victims so if a guy
like Greg comes into Gary's neighborhood
and I come in at two o'clock every
afternoon it's a gated community too by
the way let's say it's all of our
neighborhood and there's the gate Greg
comes into the neighborhoodies about six
feet tall he's driving a 1998 green
toyota sienna van with a dent in a right
rear quarter panel aaron golf ball
wasn't mine I break into Gary's house
I'm there between you know 132 o'clock
every day when most folks are out at
work or spouses are off getting kids
from school and the like I break into
your house Gary and you had some really
cool electronics thanks so much your
silver collection I know it's been in
the family for years my family will
enjoy it for years as well and that cute
dog you had thank you so much my
daughter will really like that dog does
everybody in the neighborhood need to
know it was Gary's house that got broken
into this audience participation no do
you need to know as much as you can
about Greg the assailant his tactics
techniques and procedures what he looks
like what he's driving how he's going in
that he defeated the lock on Gary's
front door and oh by the way you want to
check and see if you get the same lock
maybe that lock was manufactured in
redmond washington you want to see if
you've got the same kind of lock i think
it's important that you join information
sharing mechanisms and subscribe to
different products that are out there
one is through the end kick you can go
to ww us gov and subscribe for
information sharing from there you can
go to soar got at Carnegie Mellon Center
for Internet Security up in Albany New
York the ice axe that are out there the
information sharing and analysis centers
you can go to join infragard the FBI
partnership
program you can come and participate
with different information sharing and
analysis organizations and you can
continue to support serious because
serious is a fabulous well renowned
across country information sharing
mechanism that's out there does it
matter how many you join as long as you
share and you benefit from the
information sharing it's important to to
know yourself can you guys see what's
behind these divers for those who can't
we've got two divers there with a great
white right behind them and the the
fraser says situational awareness yeah
it's important when you want to know if
there is a great white behind you I
think so I think it's critically
important that you'd know yourself and
don't take a look just at the technology
understand the business and the culture
of the organization that you're in
understand your information the
architecture upon which it's stored the
hardware and the software tools that are
used to store maintain retrieve archive
etc you have to understand the workforce
and their talents and their weaknesses
and here's some foot stomping stuff this
is where you take notes better
understand your suppliers and your
third-party chains and your you also
need to understand the strengths and
weaknesses of your third-party vendors
and a lot of folks leave that by the
wayside with really bad results OPM the
Office of Personnel Management anybody
hear them OPM got breached because a
third party vendor that was doing
background investigations private
company they they had a investigator who
in short the evidence points towards the
investigator took his laptop plugged
into a dirty network was compromised and
then the adversary set used the user
name and password credentials of that
background investigator to come in
through the back door to OPM and the
investor you know the investigation
indicates that the adversary understood
the business process that was being
followed and came looking feeling and
acting like a legitimate user now
frankly in my view is they probably
could have and should have detected the
bulk transfers a lot better but
nonetheless you know frankly username
and password with state of the art and
80s why are we still using it now and
that's something you could talk about
later today all right knowing yourself
really starts with your information
Napoleon said where is ninety percent
information I'm checking another box in
my ear War College requirement I'm
quoting a dead general but how much is
your information valued where is your
information who has access to it do you
know yourself most folks do not and most
folks are hoarders they're going to be
on the Discovery Channel where folks are
going to buy stuff we'll open up the
information faults and find all sorts of
stuff but they didn't know they have we
see it all the time both in the public
and private sector take a look at your
own gmail account how many folks don't
delete things from their their Gmail or
the yahoo hotmail outlook 365 you know
because they don't have to storage is
cheap right so why delete how many of
you are guilty how many of you are not
honest okay all right another thing to
as you're taking a look at knowing
yourself beware the good idea fairies
there are so many folks who have
declared themselves cybersecurity
experts who wouldn't be able to pour
something out of a boot if the
instructions were written on the heel I
was at a forum in fairfax county
virginia at the beginning of the month
and folks were looking it was an
entrepreneurship summit where they were
trying to bring folks in to teach him
how to create their own business and
this woman came in and she said she was
starting up a cyber security business
and she arrived fashionably late which
was really appreciated by most of the
folks in the room but when they asked
her why you know what credentials she
brought to the table she said well I see
it as a growing field I'm an attorney
and I see some opportunity there you
know that's kind of cool if you are a
lawyer and you specialize in certain
stuff but you know what when it comes to
what we do for a living make sure that
you are you dig deeper when you've got
these folks that are claiming themselves
to be experts I frankly was raised by
parents who told me anybody who declares
himself an expert isn't but there are a
lot of good idea fairies who are going
to come around they're going to try to
sell you the latest tool or the the
latest hardware solution aight demanding
customer and if anybody says they got a
silver bullet to solve this problem i
contend that they're wrong there's a lot
of different you're going to have to
spend a lot of bullets in order to
better manage your risk now I did
mention as part of the strategy that
continuously innovating and investing
wisely is critically important that was
part of our strategy and age does matter
in our business now I introduced the
concept that I called to Hills law in
talking with the the folks in the senior
levels of government week I would go in
every month and I would brief the
president's Management Council which is
one layer down below the cabinet it's
basically the deputy secretaries and we
are trying to get a three billion dollar
IT working capital fund to replace a lot
of old computers I had to put it in
terms that they could understand so I
created well even when I was in military
created this call to Hills law so
me explain what two hills law is because
you may want to use it someday how many
folks have heard one human year equals
seven dog years come on it's Indiana I
always thought to be a whole lot more on
that one yeah I'm from Pittsburgh that's
a midwest city it's west of the
Alleghenies all right so one human year
equals seven dog years how about anybody
here of Microsoft never right well
Microsoft and great American companies
like it typically come out every three
years with a generational leap forward
right and then health and human services
department says the average lifespan in
the United States 78.7 years I'm going
around that 275 because it makes the
math easier 75 / 3 equals what 25 so
therefore under two Hills law one human
year equals 25 computer years I'll let
that sink in for a moment one human year
equals 25 computer years so I would
contend that if you do the math you've
got a four year old computer it's about
a hundred years old ladies and gentlemen
in the federal government we had several
computers that were well over thousands
of years old I found one computer in a
certain space agency that was
commissioned in 1964 and of course
somebody decided hey this needs to be
internet-facing so we're going to bold
something on so I would go into board
meetings the president's Management
Council and I'd say look here's a Wright
Flyer circa 1903 we're putting ripe
flutters up against MiG's and a new
Chinese jade j-20 which looks
surprisingly a lot like a some of our
aircraft how about your infrastructure
if you're making a business case for
security you need to be current and it's
not just current with your equipment its
current with your software its current
with your people and training your
technicians never stops you have to
factor that into your business case
you have to know yourself now a lot of
folks are flying into the clouds right
now and i'll tell you i I've actually
lost some friends who flew into clouds
only define it as a mountain on the
other side literally by the way that's
me and when I go and I talked with folks
about cloud computing I'm a big fan I
really am a big fan but you have to go
in with your eyes wide open and you need
to know what's on the other side we had
a lot of government agencies and I saw
this in the private sector as well who
ran into contracts cloud computing
contracts because everybody said hey it
so that the latest and greatest newest
coolest thing but they didn't put
portability into their contract so when
the contract came up when they go for a
rebid they could get a better deal
somewhere else but what about taking
that information putting it over oh so
here's a couple of lessons learned as
you're going to do a cloud computing
contract security needs to be part of
the requirement set portability needs to
be part of your requirement you need to
retain the ability to do independent
third-party auditing to make sure they
in fact are meeting your requirements
particularly when it comes to security
do not route do not relinquish your
ability to conduct pen testing during
the life of that contract as well
there's a lot of companies that are
going to bristle at that but you know
what if we all make it a requirement
then they're going to wake up and smell
the coffee and then further make sure
that your security teams have access to
the logs you need to know who's trying
to access your information I consulted
with a company a financial services
company that had some pretty serious
intellectual property they went to a
major cloud provider they did the
boilerplate contract and I asked them
how many folks have tried getting into
your ear system to get your secret sauce
they said no I don't know you know that
our provider takes care of that for us
hello mcfly if you don't take care of
your own stuff the company that you're
dealing with does not maintain the
responsibility you can you can delegate
a lot of things but you can't delegate
the responsibility for your information
fly into the clouds with your Y eyes
wide open I already talked about doing
the right things the right way you know
this is than just cyber hygiene it's in
fact following best practices and I
would contend that compliance is not
good enough because a lot of regulations
and rules it takes a long time to go
through them compliance is important but
I'd rather focus on best practices
because best practices will bring you
compliance but compliance doesn't always
get you the best practices pay attention
to doing the right things the right way
and at the right time if you take a look
at the ver the leaf verizon report
eighty-five percent of the breaches were
caused by not patching 1010 SI VES most
of them dated back to like 2001 is that
doing do care and due diligence I don't
think so you also need to be aware of
your attack surface you know in the
federal government the current
architecture is like a domino ready to
knock over it's one of the things I
tried getting fixed but that's going to
be a long term project you really do
need to take a good look at your
architecture the 1980s organization
chart architecture does not work anymore
you need to be very very attuned to your
architecture and your attack surface and
you need to think like a hacker when
you're building out your new
capabilities every capability you and
your business put out if you're a see so
you need to think like a hacker how
could this be defeated by an adversary
and who are those adversaries and it's
part of that business case you need to
make sure that you're baking it in or
you've got a formal acceptance of risk
as part of your business case and you
also need to be a demanding customer I
don't I'm getting a little fatigued I
don't know about you guys I've have
to accept products that are coming and
being delivered that I'm going to have
to patch every single month you know
would it be better if we build quality
in from the beginning let's all be
demanding customers but recognize the
facts of the marketplace and then you
need to anticipate and innovate for some
folks I don't know if you can see this
this is a it's making its way around the
internet here's they drown with a
fishing hook on the end of it so this is
the next generation of what we're going
to see with the drums you know we're
going to see them do fishing expeditions
against us I guess is what some folks
are saying what's the next thing how are
you going to protect your information
are you agile are you able to identify
protect detect respond and recover so a
couple of parting thoughts first of all
don't panic it's on The Hitchhiker's
Guide it's on the cover of The
Hitchhiker's Guide don't panic a lot of
companies are out there going oh my gosh
you know the sky is falling no we're
still being able to maintain the
greatest economy in the world right now
but our competitive edge and here in the
United States is eroding we can do
better and we have to do better cyber
risk management needs to be part of an
enterprise risk management construct and
nothing is risk-free at some point
you're going to have to accept and most
folks don't recognize who the real risk
owners are make sure that you understand
how risk is managing your company and
ultimately your directors and your
officers of the company are the ones who
are the ones that manage and own that
risk but every of every one of us owns a
stake in it also recognize there's no
perfect model for risk management I'm
one of those guys who does not believe
that the government should dictate your
risk posture I think that's that's wrong
that's against the spirit of innovation
here in the United States but don't
necessarily try to reinvent the wheel
go out there and be part of that
information sharing you get bonus points
for for copy and best practices so do
some and make sure that you are
continuously benchmarking against others
you know I belong to a group of CISOs
who continually are calling each other
saying hey you know I'm running into
this issue how are you guys dealing with
this you know participate in those
conversations and keep your leadership
informed if you're one part of the tech
team and if you see something say
something it's critically important to
keep leadership and formed up the chain
but go cross and go down as well and
don't be afraid to ask for help Tim the
tool man Taylor I blame him for a lot of
problems in society today because Tim
the tool man Taylor didn't read the
instruction book we all need to be
reading the instruction book and we also
need to be able to be strong enough to
ask for help when we need it Tim didn't
ask for help al Borland had to go in and
help them out every time and then
finally the enemy is dynamic you
shouldn't be static you should be
dynamic as well adapt improvise and
overcome and with that we've got some
time for a few questions does anybody
have any questions for me yes ma'am and
there's a microphone right behind you if
you want to yell into that
hi boy I'm definitely a younger one in
the room so I work at eli lilly and
company and i'm kind of i'm on the risk
assessment scheme and you were talking
about third-party vendors and how that's
becoming very important to kind of know
your vendor and know what risks are
facing so as we're going through and
assessing these fenders what are kind of
the top three areas you would say to
look for to make sure they're really
found in their security thanks for that
and the question was isn't taking a look
at third party vendors what would be the
top three things that I would look for
first of all do they in fact have a a
solid cybersecurity strategy that aligns
with my own and the best practices out
there and I think taking a look at the
cybersecurity framework is part of that
look so I would assess their strategy
and their governance of that strategy
through the lens of the cybersecurity
framework that's number 12 is I would
ask to pen test against them I'm finding
that there are some folks that say oh I
don't want to be pen tested and I've had
conversations with folks as to why and
the ones that are pretty confident in
their abilities will say yeah go ahead
and sometimes even if they say no
because it could reveal information from
other clients that they have it opens a
conversation with them and you get a
better sense as to their their abilities
and then three is I would ask who
they're third-party vendors are and how
did they assess third part their own
third party because they may be a third
party to you but who are their third
parties multiple back doors and trees
and all all of that becomes critically
important so those are the three that i
would go with thank you thank you
hi Chris Clifton from here at Sirius and
you've made several statements involving
training and additional users everybody
needs to know the risks one of the
problems though is all of these people
who need to know these things have other
jobs to do as well and they don't ask
you to know their job how do we deal
with this fact that many of the people
that need to know things have too many
other things they already need to know
well you know frankly and thank you for
that question I never asked anybody to
do my job but I as an executive risk is
part of every executives job doesn't
matter if they're a lawyer if they're an
operations manager what you know risk is
part of running any business and it
doesn't matter if it's a public sector
business or a private sector business
putting terms putting risk in terms that
people understand is critically
important I'm not asking folks to
understand the technical wizardry that
me and my team were doing but rather the
impact and as well as the risk exposure
so i would i would discuss risk in terms
that they would understand and put it in
basically the operational cases when i
was in the military i I made the case
for blocking some some activities you
know some Facebook and some social media
things from some of our operational
elements and a lot of folks came in I
had a forced our commander came in and
said my last command we had access to
facebook and you know linkedin and all
of that so what i did was i first of all
i got with my director of intelligence
who was picking up information from bits
and pieces our air crews were going
around the world delivering stuff to our
troops we were able to make the business
case from a risk perspective that would
show that our adversaries were
harvesting in from
from social media and we're able to
predict when that next great tale with
the US flag on it was going to land at
such-and-such a location where that ship
was going to show up we were able to
demonstrate how that was adding risk
exposure so we invested to train our
crews not to put information out on
Facebook and the lichen and further our
chief of staff said you know what you
don't need facebook to do your job at
work we're going to cut that down
because frankly it was adding drag to
our organization and our j8 our budget
guy he said oh yeah because we were able
to show the data that shows how much
folks were spending on ESPN and you know
some of the other stuff it was we put it
in business terms we didn't put it in
technical terms and we shaped the
behavior we shaped investments and we
helped the commander make informed
decisions based on his priorities thank
thottal Boyle proud boilermaker that we
have in the cup not anymore so you were
talking about enterprise risk management
yeah how does your philosophy change as
you start to talk to smaller and smaller
companies yeah I'm a I'm a small
manufacturing firm 100 people 100
employees total may have an IT manager
who's a repurposed network engineer how
does the conversation change well I
think the strategic aspects remain
pretty much the same time and I think it
scales well you know you need to harden
your work force against the threats that
are out there you want everybody to
pretty well know some of the rules you
know that they should follow are you
you're keeping them aware of you know
how important it is to protect
information I'd say yeah you know it
doesn't matter if you're a single person
proprietorship or a large multinational
conglomeration to you need to be
sensitive to the value of your
information you need your secret sauce
protected you know your intellectual
property you know do you need to
maintain your competitive advantage in
the workplace and the market yeah I
think so how about doing the right
things the right way you know if when it
comes to the technology but you know
just the handling of information you
know how many folks leave stuff out on
their desks and then you know the
janitorial crew comes in and can come
and Hoover stuff up you know it doesn't
matter the size i think it's an
understanding though how to do the right
things the right way that becomes a
training issue which is very personal to
and that's really a frontline
supervision responsibility and I think
that scales up and all the way down
continuously innovating and investing
wisely I think that goes with everybody
to you know my wife just graduated from
a flip phone to a an iphone that I got
her and oh my gosh you know the vistas
that that has opened up
she gets it now because she sees what
the rewards are for continuously
innovating and investing wisely but you
know what I've also got as my wife calls
it the Starfleet bridge down in our
basement where I've got my collection of
computers and I am downsizing now I'm
starting to retire on you know
begrudgingly too but I recognize it if
things became increasingly difficult to
defend I just unplugged some of them and
you know there's some games that I like
to play that they won't run on my new
systems but you know what as is my needs
grew and capabilities came out you know
I went out I got some new stuff too and
I think continuously innovating and
investing wisely that scales up as well
from the smallest to the biggest and a
great example on that too is web
presence small business now you can open
a storefront who you know just web
presence and you know you can go through
etsy and do things your you know at home
and then laughing is just making
informed cyber risk decisions at the
right level I think that scale is
extremely well as to you know you've got
to make sure that everybody understands
to risk but the risk is being the
decisions are being made at the right
level and OPM was a great example where
the folks in the server room knew that
it was a disaster waiting to happen and
I'm not convinced that it was fully
communicated as well up the chain of
command and you know one of the first
things I did as deputy assistant
secretary is we brought in Kathy
Archuleta and Donna Seymour the director
of OPM and her brand new cio and we said
your own we had the US Surgeon there
with the NSA and we did an evaluation we
found the bad guys so we said your own
big time Kathy understood the things
were not good she didn't understand how
bad they were I don't want to see
another Kathy arch
that take one for the team I think it's
a critically important that we
communicate risk we have risked
conversations on a regular basis and
those conversations go up across and
down Thanks thanks doc it's at the hook
Joel all right great thanks
you