welcome to the next stock in the series
of CBS seminar for sprint 2017 so today
we have our own squad car Scott recently
defended his PhD successfully in capital
science department where he worked with
professor Matthew spire and then I guess
he is going to join NGC soon after
finishing his PhD over here Scott's
works on typical say program analysis
did dynamic analysis static analysis in
that field and today he is going to
share what are some of his recent work
that he is going to present next week at
HS e seus and today is going to talk
more about what he is going to talk
about their but obviously a bit more
detail so Scott you Thanks yeah so
professor prescott i mentioned i'm scott
caramel a PhD student here at Purdue and
I recently defended he mentioned that i
work with matthias pay our groups called
the hex hive group so if you want to
google that to find out any more
information about the group you should
be able to find that online so I'm going
to be presenting this paper is this talk
is on the main research paper for my
thesis that I've been working on for
three years now so the first thing I'm
going to do is talk to you about the
problem that I want to solve in my
research and what motivates the problem
why is it important and then i'll give
you the introduction to the my talk in
background that will make the rest of
the talk more understandable if we have
this back from information already
covered then i'll talk about the design
and implementation of data
confidentiality and integrity which is
the name of the project and then i'll
give some highlights of the evaluation
there's a lot more in the paper
basically for each of these bold points
there's more on the paper if you can
look into if you're interested and then
i'll wrap it up in the conclusion so
first our motivation so we're interested
I'm interested in we taught language
based security which is using looking at
why the C and C++ programming languages
are insecure and why do they lead to
security problems and in particular I'm
just going to call out one
we found vulnerability if you follow the
security blogs right you see that new
vulnerabilities were being fault found
all the time but we'll just talk about
this one a little bit so it's called
heartbleed and the root cause is a
missing bounced check and it's in the
library called openssl which is a crypto
library implemented in C and it allowed
a clever attacker to send a message to
the server and then it would the server
would send back its private encryption
key which could allow the attacker to
impersonate the server and this affects
um any server that uses openssl which
apache engine X the commonly used linux
web servers all use open SSL and it
could have effect potentially up to
sixty six percent of websites on the
internet according to some metrics so
it's a really big vulnerability that has
a high impact in terms of how widely it
could be exploited in the wild so a lot
of security researchers are interested
in saying why didn't we already detect
heart play there's a lot of security
work in static analysis and bug finding
these different approaches but currently
none of those fountain tire played in
particular we're going to I'm going to
talk about cfi which is control flow
integrity and it basically says that I
determine what the control flow of this
program should be statically and then at
runtime IC did my program deviate from
this static control flow graph but the
heartbleed blood bug does not change the
control flow of the program it just
simply leaked a sensitive data so that
motivates our work which is looking at a
text that leak sensitive data or corrupt
data on a remote server for example
similar to the heart please logon the
exploit I described and so we need new
tools to protect sensitive data like
encryption keys or password lists or
authentication tokens and that's what
data shield and data confidentiality and
integrity is targeted at so um the key
inside of my worker the key idea is that
some data are more sensitive than others
and they're worth paying overhead to
protect because the my mechanisms in
language based security usually work by
inserting additional security checks
into the probe
graham to check for for example missing
bounced checks for for ray out of bounds
and each of these new additional checks
costs overhead so we are proposing that
you want to protect key data with these
additional checks examples of approaches
along these lines that that identify a
specific subset of data to protect our
stack Canaries which are special values
that are on the stack that indicate that
if the secondary value changes that
indicates the attacker overwrote the
stack and try to corrupt the return
address or a similar another approaches
depth which says that any code that's in
memory can cannot be writable it could
only be executable so attackers would
target the code to overrate the code in
memory with their own code and hijack
the program and the final example I'll
give you a CPI which is a basically a
specialized cfi CPI stands for code
pointer integrity and it keeps its own
protected copy of all the function
pointers and virtual function pointers
in the program and stops the attacker
from tampering with them so all these
mechanisms identify a subset of
sensitive data and protect it in our key
difference is that we're enabling the
programmer to choose which data is
protected so the policies as I mentioned
before all have the data that is going
to be protected chosen by the designer
of the mechanism and the programmer
khaya cannot change it and the reason
that we do partial protection rather
than protecting the entire program for
example of bonds checking every single
pointer in the program is that Bond's
checking every pointer is very expensive
in at a very very high level the way our
mechanism works as I briefly mentioned
is that we take the program source code
we compile it with our compiler and then
the resulting Viner has additional
security checks that are missing from
the original program so this is going to
further frame the problem and how our
solutions to that problem are going to
be based on these assumptions so we
assume that only low overhead is
acceptable so when we say low overhead
ideally we're getting down to five or
ten percent because so this paper
theorizes that if it's down the over it
is only between five and ten percent the
end user might not even perceive it
we assume that we have the program
source code because as I mentioned were
compiler based mechanism weary compile
the program and we assume that the
original program contains bugs so the
original program should properly process
expected input but the attacker can
potentially create malicious input that
causes the program to leak sensitive
data or to corrupt sensitive data so the
key concept that we're going to talk
about is memory safety so memory safety
means that whenever you read and write
through a pointer and a C or C++ program
you read or write the object to which
the pointer was most recently assigned
and I'm going to go into detail about
the different ways that this could be
violated on the next few slides and I'm
going to note that confidentiality means
memory safety for reading and integrity
means confidential or memory safety for
writing so one way that you can break
memory safety is a spatial memory safety
violation so say we have the code
snippet over on that side of the slide
and then a buffer in memory somewhere so
we loop over the initialize I 20 and we
loop over the cut the elements of the
buffer setting them all to some value
and this is fine as long as the buffer
of I is still within the bounds of the
array but when we go past the end of the
array we write whatever memory happens
to be there and this is an out-of-bounds
right and it's a violation of spatial
memory safety so we would like to
ideally prevent these out of bound
rights from happening another way that
you can violate memory safety is
temporally so in this example we
allocate a rayon the heap using malloc
right to one of its Ella elements and
then free it free the buffer so now it's
gone but we can still use the pointer to
write to the element an element of buff
that is pointing to now d allocated
memory and now this in this way we're
writing to an unintended memory location
that doesn't contain the most recently
assigned object so this is another way
of violating memory safety so as I
briefly talked about in the beginning
why don't we insert checks before
a pointer dereference to see if the
pointed to object is the most recently
assigned object and the reason is that's
over costly in terms of overhead so
state-of-the-art complete memory safety
mechanisms have about a hundred percent
overhead or more depending on the
program itself and how often it I uses
pointers and the over overhead is a
function of how many of these new checks
we insert into the program so the way
we're going to tackle this problem is
we're going to define a new policy that
allows for protecting only a subset of
sensitive data with lower overhead and
we're going to give several ways of
implementing this new policy and finally
we'll evaluate the security of our
implementation by seeing if it can
detect publicly found are publicly
available exploits so now we'll describe
the design of data confidentiality and
integrity the the design is that
sensitive pointers can access only the
intended sensitive objects so we have
memory safety for sensitive pointers
non-sensitive pointers are isolated from
sensitive data but they can point
anywhere except sensitive data and then
explicit data flow between sensitive and
non-sensitive variables is forbidden so
the compiler is going to apply this
policy to the compiled program that it's
given and at a high level the way this
works is that we divide memory into two
regions one contains sensitive data and
one contains not sensitive data and in
the sensitive region it contains all all
the sensitive data as well as metadata
about those objects which has allows us
to insert our bonds checks and track the
size of the objects in the non sensitive
region we simply have all the non
sensitive data separated from all the
sensitive data and the way the the
programmer identifies the sensitive data
is by using annotations and
organizations are tight based
so if you add an annotation is shown at
the bottom this makes the entire object
sender sorry fee if you annotate a
struck that makes all the struct and all
its members sensitive sure so you're
making this perfect segregation between
census you in on sensitive but there can
be situation where indeed at least the
sensitive part want to read something
from the non sensitive case yeah so
currently there's no support for
information any information for between
sensitive and non-sensitive so our
subject is that the code that's doing
the sensitive stuff is going to do with
sold thing deal with it sensitive data
and the non sensitive stuff will be
totally separate in future work we plan
to investigate ways of making this safe
so maybe you could have a sanitizer that
allows you to write from sensitive stuff
down just to nonsense of stuff but that
would be something that we're going to
investigate in the future so along the
same lines if you if you annotate a
struct all of its members are the are
now sensitive so this annotation is
recursive one of the key metrics are the
key benefits of our approach is that you
don't have to make many annotations
because we don't want the programmer to
have to do a lot of work and change a
lot of their code so when you annotate a
struct all the members of the structure
sensitive and then recursively if the
struct itself contains pointers to other
strikes those types become sensitive as
well and pointers to a type and the type
itself have the same sensitivity the
only case where we don't have this
recursive rule is for primitives so
integers char's floats they're not ever
explicitly sensitive types and now I'm
going to talk about the implementation
of our mechanism which is as I mentioned
implemented a compiler that we use the
LLVM compiler infrastructure so the
annotations look exactly like this so
say we have a struct foo and we put the
annotation before some instance of foo
now all foods in the program are going
to be sensitive so let's say we allocate
a struct foo on the heap using malloc
the first thing we do is replace the
normal malik call with
call to our region based alligator which
I showed the diagram before with the
sensitive stuff on top so that our
alligator ensures that this allocation
will be in the correct region the second
thing we do is that we want to be able
to bounce checks all these objects right
so we have to record this first address
of the object and the last address and
we put that in a metadata table which
again talk to the beginning it's above
the sensitive mountains of region
boundary and the memory overview diagram
so we record the base address as the
pointer returned by Malik and the last
address is the pointer times the size of
the struct then let's say now we
dereference the pointer to foo now is
the time that we want to do the balance
checking so in this example we have
pointer arrow X before we can
dereference the pointer to determine if
it's safe we look up the bounds of this
this pointer using the address of the
pointer and then we check that the
pointers between of course the first and
last address of the object now for an
non-sensitive objects so anything that
hasn't been of the annotated type we
again replace the Mallik but this time
we put in the nonsense of Mallik which
ensures that the abbot already allocated
below the boundary and then when we
dereference the pointer that's not
sensitive we have to have to ensure that
doesn't point up into the sensitive
region and one way of implanting that is
using a mask is shown here where we
clear the upper bits so the maximum
value of the pointer is below the
boundary after it's been masks and then
we allow the pointer dereference to
happen so I mentioned that it's
implemented in a compiler the compiler
past has two different parts it is a
module analysis where it finds all the
sensitive types all the annotations that
I mentioned before and then I mentioned
the other pieces of the dataflow piece
so the data it does an inner procedural
conducts context-sensitive analysis to
find all the variables that have data
flow with the variables of the annotated
types and it makes them all sensitive at
runtime there is a library for actually
creating separating the sensitive
announces of variables it has
different allocators for the heat
variables it Maps it separates the stack
variables it creates a stack dedicated
to this non-sensitive region and then
Global's are mapped into their regions
by a linker script that I will map the
nonsense of Global's to the nonsense of
region appropriately and the same thing
for the sensitive Global's so now I'll
talk about the evaluation of our
mechanism so this is going to be the
highlights of the evaluation from the
actual paper so if you're interested
there's a few more case studies in there
that you can check out so a key question
that we want to answer is does our idea
of protecting a subset of the data do we
actually observe lower overhead when we
have this condition so this graph shows
two experiments for two micro benchmarks
that I wrote that we're designed to
allow me to control what percent is not
sensitive and what percent is sensitive
so the first one is insertion sort so it
creates to erase one is an answered
array and one is a sensitive ray and it
puts random data in them and sorts them
using insertion sort and I can the input
to the program is the size of the two
arrays how much sensitive data to I want
the number of elements is the mansa's of
red number of elements of a sensitive
right and going on the bottom axis from
left to right that's having a higher
percentage of sensitive data so as we
would expect or as our hypothesis was
that as we increase the amount of
sensitive data we're putting in more and
more checks or executing more and more
checks and our overhead is increasing so
for point of comparison we have soft
bound and softbound CTS those are two
mechanisms that give complete memory
safety so soft bound is complete
okay that's interesting how we have the
ton of time left yes we have still have
and we have 20 minutes 25 minutes okay
go okay so did you say something okay so
as we can see I was as I was describing
southbound south on sets their total
memory safety so as we move there their
overhead is totally independent of about
a sensitive data because it treats
everything the same in fact softbound
and self on sets don't even read the
annotation so they don't have any idea
how much data is sensitive according to
our annotations so question sure my
question is what do you buy sweet say
insertion sort right sister they seen
such I'm sorting an airy yeah run house
of the elements are insensitive and a
half our non-sensitive but it but then
how can we compare because they there is
a clear separation so it's not always
half it's ten percent or sensitive ten
percent and answered sort of up to
ninety percent but then how are you
going to compare them because you are
not going to take anything from the
sensitive area and make it applicable so
let's say you want to compare one
element insensitive render the Reno
density sorry they're totally separate
so it sorts the sensitive array and then
it sorts the lancet said of array so it
does it starts two totally separate
arrays it's basically like imagine you
have a program that deals with sensitive
data does a bunch of stuff does deal
with Dan sets of data does bunch of
stuff and they're totally separate but
it's still sorting the amount of
elements that it's sorting is the same
it's just how much is sensitive and how
much is dance isn't but they're two
totally different arrays they can't be
you can't have an array that makes us
sensitivity does that X yeah okay
because I was just doing trying to
understand the experiment oh because
specially in your second example maybe
as I increase let's say you have 10,000
elements no in your area maybe the Green
Line is catching up and making it almost
equal to the blue line of singers so
because your data set here it's
I think it's hundreds of thousands
armies alike yes so I need to run it for
a long time in order to make you know
account for measurement noise and get
good results in terms of being run long
enough to measure the time accurately so
it's a really big array it runs for like
i don't know i made it or something so
the other benchmark is find max which is
just a linear scan of the two arrays
yeah and is he pointed out the the
overhead of softbound decreases in this
I i attribute that to measurement noise
or perhaps some optimization that
softbound implemented in there compiler
that's kicking in on this benchmark I
don't know the details of the
implementation of soft bombs so I i can
really always speak to what's what I've
done good so thank you yeah how come the
word hadees below zero so it's there's
there's a couple different sources of
speed up in the program one is that when
we do the sensitive regions were
changing the locality in cash effects so
we actually observed in doing our
benchmarks that we would tend to speed
up programs by do using our partitioning
and changing the way the allocator works
for the other benchmarks we actually use
the region based allocator when we
evaluate the baseline because we it so
we have a run that has no
instrumentation then we have a run with
our expectation and we compare them to
figure out what our overhead is we found
that the regions were giving us a little
bit of unfair advantage because we were
increasing a locality and having a lot
fewer page faults so we ran everything
in the next the remaining slides that
I'll show you with the region based
allocator which separated the two
regions it's a interesting question
though any other questions at this point
yes I think I've talked about that what
ah so then the other question that we'd
be interested in knowing is let's say
that our hypothesis that we have a
really small amount of sensitive data
holds and we're mostly working on that
sort of not sensitive data but we still
have to stop the sensitive pointers from
ever pointing into the sensitive read
so we evaluated the spec benchmarks in
this configuration the spec CPU 2006
benchmarks are pretty much the standard
and my fields for benchmarking
performance however they're not really
security critical programs they're like
one is a chess simulator one is a go
board game simulator one is a you know a
pathfinding algorithm so there isn't
necessarily sensitive data but these are
simply measuring used to figure out what
the overhead is for a variety of
programs so they're the along the bottom
of this axis are the individual package
marks and then the different colored
bars are three different ways of
enforcing the isolation of non sensitive
stuff from sensitive stuff so in my
example in the beginning I showed we
used a mask to clear the upper bits so
that the pointer can't point up into the
sensitive region but there's two other
ways of enforcing that one of the first
of the two is MPX which is a harbor
feature by Intel it actually introduces
for new bounds registers and explicit
bounds check instructions that you can
use to do bounds checking so the way we
use this is we put the bounds of the non
sensitive region in the first bounds
register and then every time before we
dereference a non sensitive pointer we
execute the bar insert the bounced check
instruction so effectively it's a
bounced check implemented at hardware
that we can use for the nonce instead of
region the last one the the yellow one
bar is a feature of the x86 64
instruction set called address override
prefix and what it does is it tells the
processor to interpret the memory
operands of this instruction as 32-bit
values so you put this magic number for
the instruction and then it will assume
that all your pointers are 32 bits so
instructions with this prefix can never
reference the sensitive region that's
the third way we can enforce the
isolation so if you compare the heights
of the heights of the bars maybe for now
focus on the last one which is the mean
because there's a lot of benchmarks we
can see that masking is
the highest overhead because we're
loading this value into where to
register doing the hand and then using
the mouse pointer whereas MPX we have we
can use the bounds registers for free
essentially we might actually have lower
register pressure because we're not
using a register to store the mask
itself and then finally the yellow bar
which is essentially invisible is the
address override prefix and it's all in
hardware so it's very very fast that it
has essentially no overhead any negative
over at is essentially measurement noise
so the question that arises from this
observation is why would we use the
different options so one reason would be
almost every processor has and
instruction but not every processor
sports MPX and edges override prefix and
the other good thing potentially about
MPX is we could have multiple sensitive
regions because the we could change the
values in the bounds registers and have
there are four of them so we could
eventually have four different regions
as well that's not currently implemented
but that's sort of an idea that could be
interesting to pursue in the future any
questions about this now the question we
want to ask answer is how much of we
improved security have we done something
that's actually going to detect
vulnerabilities and attacks in the wild
so we found a crypto library called
embed TLS which is now owned by arm it's
used in embedded devices to do crypto
and there is luckily for us there's a CV
found in mpls which is common
vulnerabilities and exposures so the guy
that found it wrote a nice blog posts
showing how the vulnerability worked and
he also had a proof of concept exploit
so we checked out this version of a med
TLS compiled it with our protection our
compiler and then checked if the exploit
would still work but no we in fact we
found that we detected the out of bounds
read and we were able to abort the
program rather than leaking
the server's contents so we were able to
detect that the attack was taking place
in a in a software that's actually used
by people out in production and there in
the real world any questions about that
so now I'm going to wrap up the talking
and summarize the points the key points
we in DC I we have stronger production /
sensitive data and relax production for
non sensitive data and the reason we
have this relax production is it allows
us to have lower overhead overall and
that's a key metric for getting people
to actually use our mechanism is that
people want fairly low performance are
really high performance in practice and
we have lower overhead than complete
memory safety and we suggest that one of
the reasons that memory safety complete
memory safety is not being adapted is
that is the prohibitive overhead and our
security evaluation with M bed TLS shows
that if our technique is used and we
compile embed TLS with our compiler
we're able to detect a real
vulnerability that was found in the
software and lastly the compiler is now
open source you can go to this URL and
check out the software user yourself
compile your own programs and I would be
glad to answer any questions about it
our questions about the talk to so my
question is that did you already talking
with some people about some companies
who are interested in using this or what
kind of what kind of or if not then what
kind of industry can you focus on for
this kind of yes so the interesting
thing about my research area is that
there is a little bit of a lag between
what is the cutting edge research and
what is being done in industry so I
mentioned the beginning cfi that see if
I doesn't protect hardly but it can
protect against it different rotax
attacks that target control fall and it
is actually being adapted an industry
the combined Chris the new microsoft
latest microsoft compiler has a form of
control flow integrity GCC as a form of
control flow integrity and so does llvm
clang so the interesting approach for me
that i think would be more adaptable to
industry is trying to potentially not
rely on annotations is one drink
important direction for future work
because it we assume that the primer
knows what's important but in practice
an industry you would like to have a
tool that works automatically and
doesn't require you to go back and say
what are the really important things
here you would just like to have it all
work out of the box interesting so any
other patient okay so then maybe just
one final thing are you immediately
jumpered both confidentiality integrity
but let's see if I want integrity only
yes is dead already something easily
solid a value yes so the interesting
thing about confidentiality and
integrity is the rights are more rare in
programs than brees so usually you read
a bunch of things you complete some
results when you write it back to memory
so there's actually a mode in the
compiler that only protects rights
that's confidentiality our integrity
only and it has much lower overhead
because the rights are rare we have few
we have to check fewer things than we
only check rights if you want integrity
of data then no pretty much my approach
is the is the only way if you want
partial into prediction softbound does
have a mode that's right only that they
call out and they pay for two but i
think that integrity is actually a more
maybe widely applicable approach to
industry and end users because it will
be low overhead as i mentioned it a lot
of mechanisms focus on stopping the
attacker from corrupting the data rather
than stopping the attacker from reading
the data partly because it's lower
overhead to protect integrity but
confidentiality on its own obviously
doesn't make sense because he can just
overwrite the tiger can just overwrite
your protection mechanism we like turn
it off so you need integrity so
mechanisms do focus on integrity
you