so first as our as our welcome addressed
presenter comes up this morning I want
to let you know that again thank you
very much for being with us today this
is the start of our year of celebration
as as Jerry Hahn has has deemed it so
right now we are celebrating the 25th
anniversary of coast so Coast was the
first security dedicated laboratory at
Purdue started by Professor Spafford and
professor Wagstaff quickly grew and six
years later after that Sirius was born
from coast
so right now 25th anniversary started
this spring 25 years ago this spring in
a year from now we'll be celebrating the
20th anniversary so welcome to our year
celebration we started last night with
the first event and so I believe she is
here in the room waffle and Millie who
is the CSO at Eli Lilly was part of our
women in InfoSec networking event last
night so thanks to those who
participated in that event last night
and thank you to our students who showed
up and and walked away pretty impressed
with the roomful of men and women who
were there to support them later tonight
is our celebration party for Coast that
will be also the serious poster session
so as an opportunity to see I believe 53
different research projects that are
being managed here at Purdue all within
the area of the information assurance
security privacy resiliency and
cybercrime so come celebrate with us and
come learn more about the research
that's going on here at Purdue with
serious and with that I'd like to bring
up our first our first presenter this
morning in stuff in is the chief
innovation officer for the state of
Indiana and we've had the pleasure of
this last year getting to work closely
with in and his staff at the Indiana
Economic Development Corporation their
tagline which you have probably seen or
will see very soon here is a state that
works
and while serious has a very very broad
global view it is wonderful to have a
supportive state that helps both what
we're trying to do here in the state but
also off-campus
so Ian thank you very much for your
support of Sirius and Purdue University
and welcome to Purdue thank you very
much good morning on behalf of the
governor and our Secretary of Commerce
welcome to this symposium I was invited
to speak this morning back in January
when Joe and I were going around the the
State of Israel for the cyber tech
summit there so we were over there for a
week and you really get to know someone
when you're in the back of the van
traveling hours around small roads in
Israel going back and forth but what we
did learn there was that we have great
partners in the State of Israel while we
were well we were over there some of
whom are are here today on behalf of the
state again welcome looking forward to
this symposium today I'd like to call
out our state's cyber security adviser
Doug Rapp Doug Rapp if you could raise
your hand he'll be here throughout the
two days of the symposium so feel free
to track him down as well you know I've
been in this capacity for the last three
years serving under governor pence and
now governor Holcomb and I can tell you
that as I travel around the state you
know I see billion-dollar industries
solving billion-dollar challenges every
day in a diversified set of sectors
whether it's agriculture pharma advanced
manufacturing aerospace and defense we
have those industries here that are
solving the next challenges that are
opposed to us and certainly the
cybersecurity industry is one that's
taking off strong here in the state of
Indiana as well we have many growing
cyber security firms including ponderin
Sand rook security and Kenny group and
many others that continue to grow I
would also say that it's an exciting
time to be in the state of Indiana as we
look forward to our third century of
innovation here in the state I would say
that you know we just celebrated our 200
your anniversary and this is a state
that continuously performs works and
it's a state that makes things grow
strings connects things and moves things
and you can't do any of those things
without securing those those
transmissions as well as the secure
transformation of our information
technology sector I would say that cyber
security is the fastest growing area in
the tech sector that we see here in the
state of Indiana and one of the fastest
growing industries in the world you
don't need me to tell you that you live
and work in that field I would also say
that the cyber security market has not
escaped our attention in terms of its
great growth so in the last 13 years
growing from three and a half billion
dollars in 2004 to one hundred and
twenty billion in 2017 I started off in
the semiconductor industry our worldwide
market share was three hundred and
thirty three billion dollars annually
and I have not seen the type of growth
in any industry since my experience in
that industry than I have seen in the
cyber security industry so
congratulations for those students in
the room you've chosen the right field
the market is predicted to grow eight to
fifteen percent each year for the next
five years worldwide cyber security
products will eclipse one trillion
dollars in the same five years think
about that one trillion dollars in the
same five years the market will grow
comparable to the growth of the rate of
the Internet of Things an industry that
I grew up in you know you guys were
talking about IOT before it was cool and
certainly IOT would not exist without
cyber security IOT let me be clear is
one of the strategic sectors for the
state of Indiana it is one of seven
strategic sectors and we were proud to
announce the first IOT lab through the
the leadership of mayor fatness and
Fisher's earlier this year
Purdue IU and many other University
these are a part of that IOT lab IOT
labs that will grow throughout the state
this is the first state that has done
anything like it
worldwide spending in terms of cyber
security protection seventy five point
four billion dollars in 2015 and it
certainly shows no signs of slowing the
increasing threat and the increasing
opportunity in my view will continue to
shape the market not only here in the
state of Indiana but worldwide threats
to the Indiana economy so we look at
opportunities at the Indiana Economic
Development Corporation and we look at
opportunities general threats include
nation states cyber criminals hackers
hacktivists lone wolf insider threats
and 2016 cyber crime cost the global
economy over four hundred fifty billion
dollars four hundred and fifty billion
dollars over two billion personal
records were stolen in the u.s. myself
included given my federal government
experience I was the recipient of
multiple letters and I'll tell you
certainly a great deal of disappointment
there as well but certainly opportunity
many leading industry experts predict
the three top threats for 2017 will be
ransomware extortion attacks on
industrial control systems and again
insider threats eighty percent of
ransomware attacks are in the healthcare
industry so many of you are here in the
healthcare industry you certainly know
that very well personal health
information is 50 times more valuable in
the black market than financial
information stolen patient health
records can fetch as much as $60 per
record and certainly the market is
demonstrating a need for scaled
solutions for businesses and many of
those small businesses that we see
around the state those small businesses
that are just trying to come to grasp
the situation in which they find
themselves in so the Indiana initiatives
here are the opportunities what are we
doing here and Doug and can certainly
tell you a little bit more about this as
well throughout the course of the two
days simply put our goal is to establish
Indiana is a worldwide leader in
cybersecurity to be the nucleus of
cybersecurity in the region and without
serious that doesn't happen so I will
make that very clear without Purdue
University without many of the
universities throughout our great state
that will not happen so that's number
one we are also developing a strategy
that supports the governor's five
strategic pillars IDC is currently
producing its final draft of our
cybersecurity economic development plan
that will be public and shared and
fortunately many of you in this room
will have an opportunity to weigh in on
that plan with Doug this is very good
timing as he will be incorporating the
feedback from this conference into that
final report so track down Doug rap on
the economic development plan certainly
private industry and the university
input will be very important as that
plan comes to fruition in April 2016 I
had the good fortune of working with the
governor and the Secretary of Commerce
on the announcement of the formation of
the Indiana State Executive Council on
cyber security so again a trailblazing
state we're the first state to have the
cybersecurity Council of which Purdue
participates and it very much is charged
as a public-private partnership that
will be tasked with enhancing Indiana's
ability to prevent respond to and
recover from also cyber security issues
and more importantly draw on the
experience of the private sector without
the private sector in this room the
council would be you know quite
meaningless in my view and certainly the
private sector has embraced this council
that will pave new paths for us here in
Indiana some of you may have heard about
the 1 billion dollar innovation agenda
the 1 billion dollar innovation and
entrepreneurship agenda was started by
governor pence in July of 2016
governor Holcomb has fully embraced that
agenda it's one that I lead on behalf
the Indiana Economic Development
Corporation 1 billion dollars over 10
years what does that look like well a
great deal of that 1 billion dollars
will be devoted to venture capital
investments in fields that are strategic
to the state like cybersecurity like IOT
we have seen that our venture capital
deployment continues to rise
but our it is also a risk if we don't
keep up with our neighbors we will not
have the type of small business growth
and start-up growth that we would like
to see so about a half a billion dollars
will be devoted to venture capital I'm
also calling this a hundred million
dollar fund as part of that 1 billion
dollar initiative it's called the
industry driven innovation partnership
fund this will spur industry investments
in strategic sectors in areas like like
cybersecurity I would say that what this
will look like is a group of industry
coming together alongside a university
and suggesting here are some challenges
that we want to solve over a multi-year
period they will bring cost share to the
table and Sirius is a great platform to
help organize such an industry-led
effort so that's a hundred million
dollars over ten years I felt very
strongly that we needed to enhance our
public-private partnerships in our
strategic sectors across the board when
I first came to this position we started
off a few other partnerships and the
composites Institute's some of you might
be familiar with the Indiana
manufacturing Institute here at Purdue
that was enabled by seed funding from a
similar fund
we're just taking that and putting it on
steroids and I would say that we're very
excited about that so that in a nutshell
is the one billion dollar initiative
there are a few other components
including a transferability of our
venture capital Tax Credit which will
enable additional startups throughout
this exciting space Indiana's great
assets as we look around we're standing
in one of them and it's not just because
my wife graduated from this fine
institution of which she's always fond
of reminding me that you know the first
and last man to walk on the moon
graduated from this school I would say
certainly our great research
universities you know put our state on
the map in this field and others I came
to know Indiana from my experience in
the semiconductor industry where I was
supporting partnerships called the focus
center research program here at Purdue
later known as the dastar net program
where industry Intel TI micron and
others were supporting a six point one
research at Purdue at Notre Dame and
others across the state so I firmly
believe that that is the direction that
we need to go we need a spur industry to
do more and you know certainly that is a
great asset our great work force our
extraordinary work force in this field
and others continue to differentiate our
state not only on a national scene but
on an international scene we saw that in
Israel we saw it in India we saw it
throughout many of the destinations at
the secretary and I travel to and our
workforce put us on the map what we need
to do is ensure that students graduating
from this fine University have
opportunities after they graduate simply
put that is the challenge and that is
what I hope comes out of this conference
as well talking about you know what does
that workforce need to look like and
what are some of those potential
economic opportunities that we see in
this field IEDC
conducted a series of seven
cybersecurity town halls across the
state that Doug Rapp Ladin from
Evansville Columbus Fort Wayne West
Lafayette Westgate and Bloomington we
made a very sincere and genuine effort
to get out there in the field and listen
firsthand to small businesses to large
ones to local community leaders that
really wanted to roll up their sleeves
and figure out how could they be a part
of the cybersecurity economic
development plan whether it was securing
information
or coming into compliance with new
federal regulations certainly there was
a sincere interest in being a part of
this growing group and I would say that
it's an extraordinary effort that has
brought communities from across the
state together to formulate what will be
Indiana's cybersecurity economic
development plan during the town halls
the IEDC
created a survey to conduct a
cybersecurity asset inventory and
solicit feedback from the industry all
of this will be published very soon so
I'm very proud of that effort and Doug
thank you for leading it the IDC is also
engaged in both national and
international cybersecurity efforts
through participation in events like the
cyber tech which was in Israel blackhat
RSA the ICS conference in an
international resiliency conference I
will say that as the chief innovation
officer there are many conferences that
come across my desk that you know over
the 770 staff that you know report in
through that in innovation
entrepreneurship department want to go
to want to represent the state I will
say that I think in the cybersecurity
field we're about 90% there and full
coverage of these events why because in
order to lead you have to be at the
table you have to be there and you have
to demonstrate that not only is Indiana
place to grow your business and expand
it but it's a state that wants to be
kept in the loop and helped define and
shape the future of this industry so I
would say that again that that is very
important so from the town halls to you
know the universities to the work force
that we have here I would also say that
over 30 academic institutions in Indiana
have a cybersecurity information
security specific course focus area
certificate and over 70 with degrees
related to cybersecurity analysts you
know that's important that is very
important that our university community
our community college have realized the
growing opportunities in this field and
have adjusted the curricula accordingly
I would say that survey respondents to
the
dc's work said that innovation and
entrepreneurship is only second to
academia as Indiana's greatest assets so
there is a culture of innovation a
culture of that pioneering spirit here
in Indiana one that you know encourages
folks to want to stay here I would say
the investment climate you know when
we're on the road people are well aware
of the low tax rate here but also you
know the triple-a bond rating you know
we're a state that is consistently you
know saving for the future and that's
what enables us quite frankly to invest
a billion dollars over ten years you
don't see some of our neighbors you know
doing that because there's just simply
not in a position to do that I would say
that research was identified as one of
the top Indiana assets Indiana is home
to the six major research institutions
and some of whom I've already mentioned
and numerous NSA and DHS academic and
research centers of excellence so that
certainly puts us on the map
Indiana is home to the some of the
world's first complex cybersecurity
training some of you are familiar with
the Muscatatuck and the urban training
center down south I would say last year
the state teamed up with companies and
universities to conduct a full-scale
exercise named critics that included
over six major water providers the
military the state the national
emergency management organizations so we
not only have access to people but we
have access to shared infrastructure and
if any of you have not been to
Muscatatuck it's certainly something
that you need to check out and something
certainly industry is very much
interested in leveraging NSWC crane is
also very important to us in southern
indiana the center of electronic warfare
for the country and the third largest
Navy base in the world is in Indiana in
southern Indiana and crane the battery
Innovation Center right on the outskirts
of the crane Navy base you know
certainly something that is of
great deal and importance to the cyber
ramifications to the electric grid we
have that that shared infrastructure
available to us and lastly Indiana does
very well in cybersecurity and digital
forensics the partnership with the
Indiana State Police and Purdue you know
certainly is on our radar screen and
securing industrial control system
securing the internet of things that I
you Purdue and crane have partnered on
and managing security services through a
number of cyber security providers both
in-state and out-of-state so I would
just conclude by encouraging you to
think big throughout these two days I'm
pleased that Joel is continuing to
encourage folks to think big and to
bring the right people together from DHS
to to the State Police to IADC I mean
you're really approaching it from all
angles here but also think about what do
those public-private partnerships need
to look like to and continue to ensure
that Indiana is not only different but
Indiana will maintain our leadership
role in this strategic sector throughout
our diversified manufacturing and life
sciences base we need to take advantage
of those assets and I'm sure the people
in this room will chart new
public/private partnerships that will
encourage folks to not only stay here
but to come here because of them so with
that I encourage you to have a great
time here and look forward to working
with many of you here in the next couple
of days thank you
[Applause]
[Music]
thank you in we have long valued the
support of the state as a land-grant
institution we certainly have focus on
public service public issues here and we
look forward to continued cooperation
with IEDC and state agencies many of
whom are represented here so as in was
going through the list of various
organizations crane Muscatatuck the
Center for complex operations and others
we have people here registered for the
conference from all those organizations
so if you see them in the audience see
that on their nametag you might strike
up a conversation as well along with
many of our corporate partners we value
for their ongoing support of our
programs and a number of other
interesting organizations many
represented by our alumni so feel free
to reach out to people as you go along
you