okay so yeah I'm Matt Johansen I run the
32 tenure at a white hat security and
you just saw my talk next door the
lovely speaker Wranglers a blast
counting think we could put me twice in
a row I also did not make a spy outside
so the beard destiny is not my audition
but apparently it's fitting I don't know
do you have a clue who denied beard of
Destiny status does anybody can anybody
compete with that no okay so yeah that's
true mr. so gone the cheerleader that
we're gonna mention gauntlet miss talk
and he runs gauntlet I like the I would
like to say on the contributor but I
don't write Ruby so I'm a cheerleader uh
and yeah I've done the speaking thing a
few times yeah yeah cool yep and yeah
James and I work on gauntlet and he
liked my like my photo yeah no I have no
beard to compete so I was like what else
can I do here things look at you guys
you guys watch watch it and i work at
signal sciences and we are a start-up
working on making appt sec effective and
practical apps tech approaches implement
you know implementing them i said that
completely wrong but you got it yeah
should just read the slide we're making
apps sec effective and practical so
sounds good right and very mysterious
and if you want to find out more we have
our website and you can just click in
there and give us your email address and
you will be mysteriously contacted about
that so what we want to find out real
quick like where are people in the
audience coming from like what do you do
do use our young are in the cloud are
using kind of bare metal metal metal
cloud hybrid okay who's like all cloud
yes yes all right now i'm scared
actually um okay and who's like who's
all metal okay so pretty much everybody
else is like a good mix right it's like
it's like we had some stuff and they're
like oh its cloud thing sounds great now
do people mention the word devops in
your organization
yep okay about half the people mention
agile do people talk I'm not saying you
actually have to be agile or DevOps
that's a whole bag of worms rise if we
don't want it open yeah I don't know yet
we were up too late last night or Boeing
and yeah ok and ok what about how do you
guys get or how do you get code to
production is that like a you know one
week process daily monthly monthly or
more ok weekly or so ok daily lots of
times a day ok great all cloud all baby
that's right come just keeping it real
back there all right great and then ok
how do you do security testing do you do
security testing kind of like after its
efforts been deployed or do you do it
kind of somewhere in the in the pipeline
or in the mix so if you're early on I
raise your hand like if you're kind of
considered early in the pipeline ok if
you do it sort of like it's it's been
out there it's like you know getting
crafty or whatever betrayed your
starting big okay no hey there's no
shame about that you know feel free to
and then what if I yeah what if would be
kind of mixed right maybe you do some
some parts of your apps you do really
well in some parts like we don't touch
that one because we know you know and
and then okay and then and then maybe
just like we just only do it a little
bit for like pci or compliance or
whatever so I see ya ok so I mean it's
like it's kind of what we expect kind of
a mix here and so some of the things
we're going to be talking about our the
way we see the world shifting and and
sort of some principles that we're going
to look at for you know how you do a
modern security team or modern security
approach and we'll also be talking about
how are you some what are some good
practices you know matt has a ton of
experience in his in his life and his
job about how can how could we help fix
some of these things and is give you
some real practical things that I think
will be helpful even as security folks
or if you've been exposed to app sex
stuff that still should resonate with
you and you can come
should kind of click and then we're
gonna at the end of the talk will do
sort of like what does it look like to
have a build pipeline to some of that
stuff integrated but I thought it would
be good to start out with like okay what
what is the world look like today and
and I like this awesome definition
that's how it's pronounced awesome and
and actually I want to add a p2 it
because i want to put because this is
like a definition for this is actually a
definition about the cloud and I so then
you could call it possum and the P still
deciding what it would be maybe public I
don't know but you know something like
that but but anyways we'll stick with
awesome but when you when you when you
look at these this list it really should
stick with you and you should think oh
yeah this is um this is really kind of
where the world is heading I see part of
it in my organization i see start part
of it out there but you know people want
to get stuff that's on demand you want
stuff that's scalable self-service and
measured right this is sort of a
definition that's been proposed as like
this is what cloud really is we don't
have to like call the little vmware
cluster you have like hidden in a data
center cloud like I know that your boss
maybe want to call it wants to call that
cloud but like like when we thinking
about cloud and real practical sense
from all the way from SAS to
infrastructure as a service you know
this is this is what we're what we're
talking about what we're thinking of and
and it makes sense because in the
consumer world it's like oh I get my my
gmail application and it's like wow like
I I get email sorry I can email a lot
easier than I do at work right you know
it's like it takes a week to provision
and all that sort of stuff and the old
old enterprise approach you know and
people are starting to see like
commercial and consumer tech is better
than enterprise tech and so and I saw
this I really this stuck with me about
four years ago I went to national
instruments to do cloud cloud start up
there inside we're basically taking some
some tech and you know cloud enabling it
and in previous gigs whenever I would
like buy or acquire make decisions I
would like you know I'm added like a
whole grid I was like how does it
perform what are the features said you
know how much was it how does gardener
think about it right that really
mattered to me
you know what is a trial period look
like and how are we going to pay for
this thing and you know what's the
support costs and all that whatever we
whenever we switch to cloud it was like
really simple like do you have an API
can I integrate you with my other stuff
do I have to pay you yearly big
contracts or can I just give you a
credit card and then it's like oh yeah
and do you work you know somewhat okay
you know like that like that was like
that was what we started doing and and
it really could have assessed to me like
we need to be about the business of
playing nice with others and like so
inside of the inside of security like if
we can do that inside of the
organization and fit into those the new
way that people are doing things in the
awesome world that is really important
this is a long-standing business thing
that people have heard of and it's the
you know people are more important and
so what's a skip through that and say
yeah influence the people in your
organization okay let's talk about
DevOps like what you know how does
security play inside of a DevOps
organization I really like the cams the
cams piece sometimes called clams and
that's also debated see how people love
this stuff but this is a John John
Willis and Damon Edwards they run the
DevOps podcast and and it's a culture
lean automation measurement and sharing
and high emphasis on culture like that's
one of the big pushes in the DevOps move
in for a lot for many years they were
just like DevOps culture like don't
don't don't talk about anything else
like don't talk about you know your
chefs and your puppets and ansibles or
whatever like you know we want to talk
about culture and like it's it's
complete correction and a change of
course correction here so a short story
on this at my house we have a moon
culture my daughter is two and a half
years old and she knows the difference
between a crescent moon a full moon and
a half moon we go on walks and like it's
like you know it's kind of dusk and you
know there's a min she's like the moon
and I'm like yeah it's like she's really
excited about we start telling stories
about the moon so I have a little story
I tell her and it's like yeah we're
gonna build a rocket ship and then
you're gonna fly up to the moon and it
was really cute one day she like she was
like she saw the moon she says I want to
go to there you know it I was like like
that warm my heart as a dad is like well
math and science very important you know
but but we started orienting around the
moon and like and then I started
realizing how effective this this was
because one night I was taking out the
trash and I like look up I'm like I
wonder where the moon is like what do I
care where the moon is right it's like
but it's like I think I can tell Lydia
where it is and we could have a have a
moment I downloaded an app to tell me
like the phases of the Moon and so I
could be like yes honey it's a waxing
gibbous moon two nite you know and like
ed and stuff like that right and and so
what the point of that is besides just
being kind of silly but it's like the
things that we value like that like in
our in our culture dictates kind of the
stuff that we value and so like you're
you're tooling and your other things
that you put around your culture you
know that is what is what really sticks
in an organization so you know there you
go and continuous delivery I think this
is the last point here there was a book
released several years back and you can
sort of trace back a lot of this to the
flicker days whenever they said you know
we produce we deployed to production ten
times a day and everybody's like what
you know but then it started really
thinking about what does that mean to
deploy what does that mean to deliver
how do we actually you know influence
how do we deliver to our customers and
so these are some sort of guiding
principles and then I think you could
arrive arrive at this conclusion that
there are really two paths in the
security industry or like how we can
influence an effect kind of the way
things are going in the industry and one
I think is really important so we're
going to spend our time talking about is
the development and build pipeline and
so like in a world where like code
commits and tests and failing tests and
all that stuff our currency
like security people can actually play
in that really well and then I also
believe operational runtimes runtime
state and monitoring is also the other
place like what's actually happening
while it's happening we're not going to
talk about that one for this this we're
just going to really focus in on the dev
and build pipeline so Matt is is going
to talk to us and kind of tell us like
the stuff he sees and how it's going in
the industry apparently yeah okay so yes
you did detecting diffic and fixing
about development is kind of the point
here right is oh no Mike this isn't
working okay so when we kind of asked
earlier where you do security testing
this is kind of where this falls in
right okay so do you do your security
testing as you're writing code you're
doing static code analysis are you doing
security testing when you put your code
in some sort of QA environment and
you're doing dynamic analysis on that
living QA environment or you just kind
of let's do the skin at the end when
it's all in production already and let's
scan it right this is really important
especially when we go back to the other
question that we asked is how often do
you deploy to production right so now if
you deploy to production a month or
greater or even weekly you know or
bi-weekly and you don't do any security
testing until production now all of a
sudden you know about a bug in
production that you cannot fix for days
weeks you know potentially months if you
can get developer time so this kind of
stuff gets it's pretty scary right so
some of the stuff we've been preaching
for years is ok move that security
testing back right move it back earlier
and earlier in the process which is
still really smart but people like
Flickr and and and an Etsy kind of
turned this on its head and they said
hey we push 20 and 20 30 times a day to
production and security people go what
the heck are you talking about right
like how do you view that code before it
goes out how do you do change control
prod you know what's changing and so
that you know where to focus your
security testing let's kind of stuff and
I gave a talk at black hat this year and
we were just kind of around two
discussion at one point about this kind
of this this whole realm of what we're
talking about and one of the guys from
etsy was in the room and he said well
you know vulnerable code existed before
we started pushing 30 times a day you
know vulnerable code is a thing that
existed when we only pushed once a month
right we can now fix it in a couple
hours I stand that kind of was like oh
okay yeah the room could it was like uh
huh and they started nodding right so
this is kind of a theme that we're going
to go on for the next couple slides so
we usually give this kind of
presentation to more developer focus
people how many people in the room are
more developer than security cool okay
that's awesome okay but you are an
application security conference so I
think a lot of this is going to be
review I tried to pull out some of the
super boring stuff for people that would
actually be coming to an application
security conference but anyway so try to
try to make this interesting so if those
you not familiar with white hat we put
out a stats report every year we publish
that we have 35,000 websites under
contract it's a really cool data pool of
vulnerabilities and this year we always
do a little spin on it every year like
we did a customer survey to ask people
they're like they're develop the same
kind of questions we just asked you we
try to correlate that the
vulnerabilities and this past year we
actually correlated the vulnerabilities
by language right just to put a new spin
on the data and see what kind of came
out maybe start some sort of religious
war amongst developers because you know
we're just presenting data these are
just hard numbers that we have we are
not making any claims of one language
being more secure than another but this
is just what we see right so this is
what you're looking at here is
vulnerability percentage by
vulnerability class by language so the
percentage of sites that we have in each
language that have at least one of these
vulnerabilities so that makes sense now
so you can kind of see the heat map
coloring is cross-site scripting is
everywhere right we've known about this
for ever and how long have you known by
press
2001 we've known about cross-site
scripting and insight I mean I don't
know how many pearl sites what we have
but sixty-seven percent of them have at
least pool across site scripting bug but
if you tried to draw a line somewhere
near all of those numbers it's it's
pretty easily say half half of the sites
that we test period have at least one
cross-site scripting but most of them
it's going to be a lot more than that
branch all the way down the gamut
information leakage content spoofing so
vulnerable code is everywhere right this
is just something I'm not gonna spend
too much time on this right what is this
I didn't put this slide thrown
curveballs at me from ten minutes ago
okay so uh I ripped out a lot of the
what is cross site scripting I hope that
you guys you know you're out of an
application security conference i hope
you this something you know what it is
at least in general terms and why it's
bad right but still i find that how to
fix process mechanic still kind of
resonates with a lot of developer so all
your hands go up that's really good
right so something we've been preaching
for quite a while as input sanitization
right that's great that's phenomenal
okay it's not a bad not a terrible way
to do it right there are better ways to
do it because input sanitization is
usually means blacklists right usually
means if you see this special character
don't allow it or something like that
right if you see this string that kind
of looks like cross-site scripting
blocking right this is the worst cat
mouse game ever we see it all the time
where certain clients of ours just
insist on doing blacklist and all it is
is we just you know break it again and
break it again and very ok we're going
to encode this way we're going to code
that way when you implement a blacklist
you have to be smarter than the attacker
all the time as the defender right you
have to you have to be on top of every
new technique that comes out every new
browser version you need to see how it
handles input to update your blacklist
that's a gigantic task right I don't
want it white lists are way better right
hey here's this input it only ever
should have letters or numbers ok just
don't allow anything else period done
right you know if you're allowed to if
you want to allow special characters
still should disallow
significant amount of them right the
whitelist is just way better you know of
a global strategy on XSS than
blacklisted but even better is outputted
Cody right so how many you knew familiar
with up and coming cool I'm going to
skip right past it right this becomes
this and we're all golden sequel
injection we kind of left some of the
basic stuff in here because it's just
kind of cool to remind ourselves of how
prevalent it still is Robert how long
will be known about sequel injections
eight Christmas Day 1998 still
everywhere still really bad you all are
kind of familiar with this I stole Jim
Monaco's password if any of your
familiar with Jim medicos presentation
he always gives out his password on the
y right silly but just really basic you
know what sequel injection looks like
this is kind of like our first interview
question if you're coming to try to work
at white hat it's like here select star
from users where username is Matt
passwords fluffy bunny you know and you
can just kind of edit the sequel query
from there write the sequel period
becomes or one equals one and you're in
and of course we have to do the
obligatory XKCD comic when we talk about
sequel injection of little Bobby tables
this resonates really well with people
that haven't seen it before but I'm
assuming most of you have okay so how do
I fix it parameters queries this is king
here is really no argument about it it's
not a black lifting web this thing I
mean you could input sanitize like there
are people that try to fix sequel
injection by not allowing sequel type
queries in the input which is ok but
again you're fighting the battle of what
a sequel injection and maintaining that
when this is way easier parameter screws
those of you who write PHP this is what
a parameters query looks like in PHP so
let's look familiar to some people cool
so instead of just taking the user input
and throwing it directly into a sequel
query your parameters you first so that
no matter what that input is it's not
going to affect the sequel query okay
that's the gist of it this is the syntax
for PHP and all right you know a
difference here is you know Java uses
these ? placeholders and PHP does the
little colon trick cool look familiar
makes sense that room cramped
queries not not too new ok cool so
cross-site request forgery also
absolutely everywhere we see it
constantly we've known about it for a
very long time you know how to fix it
it's actually really easy to fix this
happens i think this happens twice a
year I feel like this has same exact
headline shows up every six months
usually fazil for some reason and I
think this was Brazil I can't remember
but routers are just awful at protecting
a stuff it's like oh well it's not
available in the internet so whatever we
don't need to worry about process
scripting and csrf and every year we
find a way to see Sir FL we changed your
router password we flash the firmware
and we're just perma in your entire
network right and this happens all the
time those you don't know what that
attack looks like for the router attack
you visit some malicious website the
JavaScript on that website can force
your browser to make a request to your
router right since people in the
internet can't make a request to your
robber but you can force your browser to
make a request of that router and do all
sorts of nasty stuff right change the
nameservers you can flash the firmware I
think every year black that some new
things someone did to a router via CSRF
there's a talk right how do you fix it
anyone what's the easiest way to fix
this crap not okay I knew you're all
going to say tokens well okay you're
right it's tokens but there is an easier
fix to the CSRF the most people probably
didn't realize is affixed to CSRF in one
particular situation of csr out and it's
this right so your change password page
right if it just ask you for your
password if I force your browser just
make that request I just changed your
password right you don't need to
tokenize this you just ask for the old
password this is actually a CSRF
protection right little negative of
truth right okay tokens yeah you all
said tokens really super easy everyone
knows what this is if you watched my my
last talk i showed you a few different
ways that people are stealing CSRF
tokens and this is why they're stealing
them those are you not familiar CSRF
token is you add some random giant
unguessable string that is not known to
the attacker so that they cannot force a
legitimate request from your browser to
actually do some CSRF makes sense again
this stuff so these things that I just
showed you is just unbelievably
everywhere and this is kind of we're
going to get back in the developer land
here it get fixed really slowly right so
this is what this chart is is average
days open / vulnerability / language huh
Ruby's hard we don't we don't have a
giant sample size for Ruby and so that's
why that that kind of goes away Ruby's a
cool hip startup language and they
usually can't afford high-end web
scanning and metrics right so Ruby's
kind of our outlier that yeah we put it
on there because we do have some with
some cross that scripting and stuff but
the rest of them we just didn't find
enough bones to to show that okay so
HTTP response splitting and asp is
actually one of those outliers it's like
vol my default incredibly hard to fix in
ASB classic it's it's kind of silly
right but on average here you see you
know triple digits all across the board
that these golems are open for just
another cool data visualization of how
long these bones are opened / language
I'm going over my time as usual if ever
so this is just open like so that was
time to fix if they ever got fixed this
is just remediation percentage right so
this is the percentage of times it's
ever even of a mediated period so blue
is bad I think oh no no no blues good so
one hundred percent of times some of
these right in certain languages and
then ribs bed so you're still seeing we
just from the time that a site came
under contract with us to the toll
present day you know they only fixed
seventy-nine percent of the process
scripting that we told them about type
of thing right if I starts to make sense
for language cool so these phones are
everywhere they're always almost stepped
n slide I'm going to blow past at a loss
of confidence
cool all right soon now you know we
talked about it what does it look like
that would build a pipeline and how do
we put all that together hey does any
does anybody have laptops and they want
to actually set up a build pipeline you
don't have to come to the front thing
but I was like wondering we have some
yeah we should use a workshop we could
do it kind of workshop do a little bit
of both we're like I don't bring my
laptop to hear you don't trust trust my
my fellow attendees all right well
that's all right but we'll do we'll do a
little bit of a of a demo but the whole
idea is it that what you could do if you
wanted to and maybe I'll make it
available but or I'll all kind of like
help you if you're following along but
you can take we have a repo in github
you can fork the repo you can set up the
Travis build for it and like within just
a few minutes you'll have your own build
pipeline with running a runny website we
used mac conda's triage application it's
a ruby on rails the application that we
stood up for it and then we run run some
gauntlet attacks against it or any
different type of stuff and we'll
actually go through that I'll click
through and you can you know if you're
like what I do it later you can but i
think it's a it's a reason why we're
going through this and we want to talk
through it is because a lot of times in
organizations well have a bits like who
who uses Jenkins yeah travis anybody's
travis familiar with Travis okay so this
is Coco Travis is cool it's a it's all
the stuff that you don't like about
Jenkins isn't there well they're
actually working on adding those pieces
back Travis unfortunately but it's a
real simple version of Jenkins yeah
don't tell the Travis guys I said that
will delete that from the video anyways
but before we get into that let's talk
about what is going to be the test
runner and a test runner is going to be
gauntlet gauntlet if ya familiar with
gauntlet okay all right so uh yeah we'll
do a little bit of how it works and then
we'll we'll get through it you can
actually see the code and how it all
pieces together i think that's that's
probably the most most helpful part ok
so it's built built on top of cucumber
really just as extension on
topic cucumber important parts about
gauntlet is it comes with pre-canned
step so one big knock against cucumber
is that you know you can like write one
step like 20 different ways and you can
have a lot of overlap right now gauntlet
doesn't let you bring your owns bring
your own steps you actually have to use
the pre-canned steps that they have or
that we have in it and some people like
that some people don't but it helps you
avoid that kind of nightmare cucumber
scenario or you have like you know if
you've had to deal with that you've seen
seen that before and gauntlet doesn't
install any tools it's not a package
manager doesn't do anything like that so
you have to already have that stuff
built up around it it's a tries to be a
good citizen of the continuous
integration and continuous deployment
pipeline so with clean exit statuses and
make sure that it handles all that
properly and it's an open source license
so what what does a gauntlet attack look
like this is this is how it's structured
so it's this the idea is given when then
if you can say those in that order you
are now an expert in gherkin which is
the the language that cucumber uses for
this with it's the same thing for a for
a gallop but there is the idea of a
feature or like kind of a big big main
story that you're testing and then
individual scenarios now that stuff
that's run up at the top where it says
that background that gets run each time
before each scenario so each scenario
kind of operates in its own independent
environment and every time it's going to
make sure that like a in map is still
installed and everything's all set up
for it and you can do other stuff and
there's some other tests that you'll see
like this is a real basic one but you
would do things like oh like here's my
login page set some environment
variables anything that you're wanting
to and up and make fresh every time it
would do that and so and it's also
important to note like the tests there
in the middle won't affect the test at
the bottom so whatever says the output
should not contain those lines where it
says that then those don't those don't
mix and match right so every time it
runs it gets a clean clean set of output
and that's what you're you're parsing
there so this one is running just a port
assertion so it's like on example com I
want to make sure that when
run in map that port 80 is open later I
want to make sure that port 25 is not
there and not listed right so yep 4439 I
mean you can test for you can test for
anything right so do I have a typo in
there okay yeah so but the yeah you but
you look at you look at this and you're
like alright so let's make sure that all
this all this is set up properly and
we'll see some other like gauntlet
attacks that that the pull through there
there's some quick links will have the
deck up so you can can click these and
jihad James has done this so he you know
he knows that it's cool right so not too
many of you heard of call it before but
the reason we kind of go around talking
about it is like that whole moving
security testing early an earlier thing
now now you're not even doing not even
putting security in the security
person's hands and saying okay developer
like when you write code I'm going to
run my static analysis tool on it right
which is currently kind of the earliest
phase that we have this is actually your
speaking developer now right hey you
already right QA tests right you already
have to write QA test your unit test
your end-to-end tests if you're doing
any sort of continuous deployment or
this pipeline you're having these tests
right so just getting going back to what
James started way in the beginning
getting into the culture of okay besides
when I click this button it turns blue
right when I click this button it also
doesn't you know let so it doesn't I
can't force this button to BCS a raft or
something like that if you start to
think about these things in security
terms in unit tests and that's what
gauntlet really is doing all right it's
writing security unit tests with some
help of some outside tools you know this
is even earlier and now you're also
speaking developers language you're not
all of a sudden being the security guy
trying to butt heads with developer to
get you know hey hold on we can't push
this co2 production I didn't look at it
yet no okay hey we have some bar here
our unit tests went out it is at least
this secure
because the unit tests pass the build
past the code went out right I'm not
saying stop testing a production because
of this right because that would assume
you're writing perfect unit test but I
just wanted to take a step back well
yeah and that's a good point too i think
another aspect you see is like sometimes
you fix maybe you fix a loaner ability
or you put something out there and then
later like you make a typo or a change
or something like that and you have a
regression right now that that thing is
back so you can help systemize some of
the vulnerabilities and things that you
found through this process and it's
using our stats report the screenshots
are showing before is reopen rate and
like we see these villains pop up okay
we had a bone right it's the way that we
work is every phone gets a unique ID for
the lifetime of that volunteered so we
can tell if it's that same exact moment
comes back again and we have a reopen
rate we have some theories of why this
kind of happens but it still happens way
more than you would expect it to happen
right one theory and kind of like this
the pipeline is like okay you have this
whole QA process where you put this code
into QA and then it does this and change
control and yada yada and goes out to
production right and then we that we
find the reopen rate is higher for the
most severe bowls like the sequel
injection has the highest reopen right I
mean like really really bad stuff and we
think that's because it's like a hot
patch all of sudden that goes out of the
regular pipeline and out of the QA cycle
and we got to go everyone's hair is on
fire we got to get this fixed into
production yesterday but no one
implements if your QA and then the next
time the QA goes out the moles back
right and so yeah like you said this
kind of standardized is it to make sure
okay we fix that bone make sure to write
a unit test with gauntlet so that you
know that balm doesn't come back ever
again period right yeah cool well if
you're interested in gauntlet there if
you through the life of the conference
of you send an email to book a gauntlet
or you can have a free gauntlet book
alright let's let's take a look this is
what we're going to go through there is
a a repo called the secure there's a
organization on github called secure
pipeline and then there's a rails Travis
exam
so if you have a web browser and you
want to want to go over to github.com /
secure a dash pipeline you should see
the rails travis example now Travis will
get in to actually pull it up and we'll
look at the cow runs and how all that
sort of stuff works but Travis operates
on this file Travis camel and you can
see there's some real simple like okay
it's Ruby up top and it says like a 20
and before the install I'm going to do a
bunch of stuff so it does like install
in map SSO lies sequel map is up there
Iraq knees inside we have it packed as a
sub module so it's inside of there so
there's all this like before stuff right
and like so your build is sort of just
setting up everything getting everything
ready and then there is a there is the
script we're saying we're actually
running before because I wanted to
really focus on the actual test you
wouldn't probably do it exactly this way
for an app that you're building but you
you know maybe would but the before
script is we set up some tokens we set
up the rails we do a database setup and
then we start the rails server and so
everything is fired up and so at that
point this is the real execution of the
the tests and there are five statements
down here and they're broken up in
different rake tasks and rake is just a
just a ruby kind of like harness that
we're just using so it's does nothing
more it's like it's super easy to read
but helps you kind of bundle everything
up into different statements and you can
see there's different ones down here
once called that network attack ssl
attack cross-site scripting information
link wit leakage and sequel injection so
we'll take a look at a couple of those
and this so this this clarifies a little
bit on some of this but you see the
setup pieces and there's the we'll look
at these two right here the information
leakage one I don't think we'll look at
sequel injection but just just probably
that one so for this one if you notice
there is there's three different attacks
and you can see there's gauntlet on the
left hand side and then it did kind of a
path but it says email leakage attack
backdoors attack and Derby attack so the
email one is you know sometimes people
will
will crawl your website and grab all the
emails of users or that they know of and
they'll make a fuzz list off of that and
so you can say well anything that
contains my domain name I don't don't
let that be out there right and I want
to want to block that and back doors is
like has somebody puts on something in
like some sort of PHP or some sort of
executable back door in your system
that's well known you know it's not
completely like you likely but if it
goes off you really want to know that
right it's like that's it's like one of
those ones is like it will probably
never go off until it does and then
you're like oh crap so here's what the
email one looks like and we're we're
doing some of this set up a profile and
so inside of Travis that that whole
thing is starting up on rails on port
3000 so we're looking at localhost for
3,000 so this is all contained travis
has its own build box that it sets up
does all the pre configuration and then
now it says I want to launch an Arachne
attack and I want to look at the modules
emails and then the output should not
match you know whatever your domain is
right and you could parse this in any
sort of way there's lots of like regex
availability for you there that that
makes it real simple for you to look at
all right and oh yeah there's there's
that piece see I got ahead of myself
there here's the back doors attack and
and then this is a sequel injection
attack so this is showing you know I
think I think something that's really
interesting about how how we use
gauntlet and how we work with garlic is
like this right here this is not
speaking their language of developers
right why because this is really
confusing and this is like a sequel this
is a sequel map mad science that like
the security person knows but you know
what like you know it is speaking
language of developers like this whole
file right because it's like I don't
know what this is but I've been told
like this is bad this fails like now I
know I got a problem and it can be taken
that way so we're sort of like taking
that that knowledge that's been kind of
hidden away in the information security
application security silo and we're
systemizing and making available
everybody else in the organization okay
let's let's do a demo and let's try
let's try some things here alright so
this is our is their application
you're this place
all right you see this okay all right so
yeah so this is our free application is
running Tucson my local local machine
you can see there resemble this as
cross-site scripting and other problems
with it but we're just going to stand it
up as an example like here's a rails
rails app we want to take a look at if
you go to this this this repo and get up
you can come down here and you can just
say about the repo notice he had 177
people working with three minutes so
pretty though that so let's make it
let's try to give 200 but look what you
can do is you can see right now here
this little button this is bill passed
let's let's click over there
right this is what the Travis out those
like so it gives you a bill number 57 in
ran for about six minutes yesterday it
has has different pieces to the bill
that we talked about so it has the whole
setup piece it does it first checks out
the repo does the sub-module updates all
those statements you should look
familiar actually labels if you see the
before install and then there is the
four script which are those portions
right there and then it actually starts
this correct references okay here we go
and we started going to do their over
she ever be through a couple of them and
it will open up a couple of attacks so
here's the here's that map attacker is
running so here's that in map attack in
the end it's running there and you can
see it's looking for port 3000 and you
can see what at the bottom it says I I
found that so I'm going to call it good
you probably want to say like and like
these certain things not available here
we're checking for heartbleed and we're
checking for heartbleed against Google
not against ourselves since I don't have
a search set up but that's another cool
thing about Travis it can actually make
outbound requests and has ability to do
that if you have some sort of
requirement for that and so we're like
you know here we're saying okay not not
vulnerable to Hartley that's what it
needs to say and here's like the
statement right there at line this line
this line right here right and it
validates that okay let's see some other
ones that look interesting here's some
here's a cross-site scripting attack so
we're using Arachne as the engine
underneath there to test that and so
we're like well let's look at the new
password page and 11 really important
thing about some of these tests is like
the security scanners you could like
turn or acne on and like walk away for a
day right and like depending on your
site like you can come back and it could
be crashed or it could be you know still
running or you know you're just not
really sure
so we we have some filters in here like
saying okay only go to one page you know
don't don't go throughout the entire
site because these things need to be
fast like you can't just put up a bunch
of tests in there that like take forever
to run see okay we have to have two
minutes maybe we could just let's do
this
so that the Rick file inside of the repo
so as you kind of look at through you're
like well here's the here's the attacks
and let's let's pop open another one of
the attacks to just take a look at it
real quick and so that was inside of
tests and instead of attacks and let's
look at that it's like the email one so
again we're using that real simple
gherkin a statement we're saying you
know given i have my testing tool
installed when i launched this attack
you know then the output should match
over here and that makes it so it's real
discernible like what is what's actually
going on and we could actually change
this so oops and we'll say my domains
all right and then what i do this is
going to fire is going to fire commits
into github and this is going to kick
off a new build all right and then this
is the update to the email leakage which
we just push it shows our commitment and
then click into it and we'll let this
run the build status so populate as we
go we are using the Arachne scanner so
it's not that we're just you know we
haven't like hard-coded what cross-site
scripting means like we're using the
rack neat scanner and then we're saying
hey I want to like pull out and you
could do it with other type scanners
like that's totally possible and and
then I want to look at just the
cross-site scripting types of attacks
that they offer and I only want to look
on certain pages on the pages that I
know that I exist right because a lot of
these scanners they end up trying to
build a crazy map you know of your
entire site and that takes a lot of time
messes up your build completely so we're
saying is like go after the password
page go after this page run all your
cross site scripting payloads like we're
telling Arachne to run that we're just
saying don't don't go nuts with trying
to find a bunch of other pages to
identify yet this is this is this is
kind of a minimum bar right it's like it
it is it is possible to have cross-site
scripting that Arachne's not
and a pickup you know on all those pages
but you know you might also else you
might also have it right so this is just
a this is like in the build pipeline
this is where you can be effective
inside of security right there's this is
does not replace penetration testing
that's do not replace you know good good
coding practices all that stuff so it's
just that kind of helping set that
minimal book minimum bar across your
organization you know it's funny like
the one that people really like a lot is
the in map one is like sometimes people
spin up new services on their on their
pieces that you're like we didn't even
know right like Netflix uses a gauntlet
and pedro duty uses its you know but a
lot of them they use like we're just
trying to make sure people don't start
up new random things that we don't know
about you know there's a dharma plugin
and garma is one of the mozilla projects
like okay how does mozilla do
development and we want to make sure
that it fits to our model and like we
want to make sure that code doesn't go
out that like you know goes against our
security policies I know people that
have taken gauntlet put garma with it
and they look the gauntlet has a little
test it says like is this a login page
right and anytime it finds a log in page
the security person says like that's an
error right because it's like they just
want to know when like new functionality
for logging in to the application or an
application in the organization pops up
at that point then they're like okay
we're going to engage that do a real pin
test on it and then we'll go back to
like putting in you know actual test for
it so it's it's kind of a watcher it can
be a lot of different different things
for so I know we're over time sorry
about that will be cool thanks