they're coming out yeah like she said
I'll be talking about DNS based
authentication by named entities how it
interacts with the ca system and see if
we can't fix some things just out of
curiosity uh who hears heard of DNS SEC
so nice pretty good size what about
dating yeah a lot less alright great
well this is gonna be a good good
starting point so who am i I'm Tony
cargile uh I'm a security engineer at
aiesec partners I get to carry a lot of
application infrastructure and pin Tess
anything ranging from white box to black
box mobile infrastructure web app you
name it before that I was work alike UT
in Austin of the degree in here science
and before that I was programming and
web application and configuration
management environments so when we going
to be talking today well I'd love to
just start jump right in today but
unfortunately can't really do that with
a good primer in DNS SEC and you can't
talk about Dina sec without the problems
of DNS so and then after that we're
going to talk about you know what was
what's the purpose of day was fixed why
is there for those people playing
security bingo talk about heartbleed and
then we'll end up talking about some
potential issues with pain so what is
Dina's domain name system well hopefully
this is a refresher for most of you
otherwise let's talk might go so well
but uh DNS is basically just a way for
us to resolve www be calm into an IP
address a client sends a request out
with an a record type and gets response
back with an IP so what's with some of
the problems with Dina as well it's old
bind was created in 1984 saddling up
that was before I was born the RSC's
finally got ratified in 1987 so back
back in that time security was a blip on
the radar no one was really worried
about DNS goofy cache poisoning or
hanging really
get the issues that we're having to deal
with nowadays so let's talk about the
first issue with DNS and that is as
provides no integrity no confidentiality
no availability so it's pretty trivial
to spoof dns so say a hacker it gets in
the middle of a client making a request
to the dns to a website making the DNS
request if you can intercept that we can
just simply reply back with the IP of
our malicious fake site and the client
simply goes there there's no guarantee
that that information that that clients
receiving is legitimate information so
the second issue is dns cache poisoning
and this is a little bit more
sophisticated attack what this is doing
is instead of just replying back to the
client saying that are the legitimate
sites at IP is actually are malicious IP
we're actually sending a response back
to a caching server and then I caching
server is then going to send that
response back to anybody that asks that
server so what this is going to do is
our attacker is going to send a request
to the DNS caching server then it's
going to spoof a response back saying
that oh woh kaam is actually 1337 and
then now anybody who sends her a DNS
request that goes through that caching
server well now it's going to respond
back with that 1337 for as long as that
TTL of that packet so originally it was
pretty trivial to do this um all you
really had to do was a match the query
ID of the DNS request to spoof a DNS
response so in that query idea is only a
2-byte identifier that you can just
trivial brute force so the original
solution was just make the TTL extremely
low
but that really wasn't a solution when
de Kaminski came along and showed in
2008 that he could just use a bunch of
different subdomains just brute force
subdomains randomized subdomains and you
just got around that TTL and that was an
issue for a while finally the the real
issue was pork randomization basically
when a request goes out it actually goes
out on a random port not on port 53 so
you can't just send our forged response
to that poor get to also get support and
the query ID map which gains a ton of
entropy it's a lot harder to brute force
but it's really not a perfect solution
if you can sing get lucky then you can
still do cat Dinah's cache poisoning so
then there's some other issues with DNS
um there's really no validity checking
so I sick partners com you can actually
you know register a domain of one sec
partners com you don't have that same of
lady checking that you would if you say
went to get ssl certificate for one sec
partners com hopefully you get denied
but we'll see later on that that's not
usually the case and then also of course
we're relying on DNS so DNS servers are
another issue there's been some
compromises and DNS protocols so that's
always something we need to take care of
so now that we talked about kind of the
issues with DNS jump into DNS SEC and
this was really created just to answer
the problem of you know Dina's not
having any security by default so when's
DNS say DNS SEC provides origin
authentication of Danis Donna it
provides authenticated denial of
existence and it provides data integrity
notably it does not provide two things
availability
reality so we're gonna go ahead and talk
about how it does is it's kind of a bold
statement to just say you know complete
data integrity complete origin
authentication but we're going to show
how it does this so first of all it adds
a few record types so it adds this are
our sig record type which is going to
hold the signature for every record in
the DNS zone it's also going to hold a
DNS key which is going to be the public
key for the signature it's going to have
insect which I'm going to go into a
little bit later about for use for
knowledge existence and then you use
your delegation server so I'm going to
go over these all the more in depth in a
few minutes because this is really
important for Dane but what if what this
essentially does if you have a zone
which you have each record type in that
zone you're going to make a you're going
to sign that zone with your key signing
key part of me your zone signing key and
that entail will be provided to that
signature will be provided a way that
makes a request out to say an a record
you're going to get an associate are our
sig record with that and then the public
key for that will be installed in the
DNS key and then to provide a chain of
trust we also use a delegation signer a
das record type to specify our parent
domain so this can be a little confusing
this might cleared up a little bit so
what we're doing right now say we're at
um we're looking to sign wao my bank
calm well my bank Dom will sign that
certificate using its upkeep ought to
keep hair and then when it does that it
will publish that is public key also to
the dot-com domain and this domain will
hold that DNS key and it will in turn
sign that key with his private key
and then publish its public key and also
push it to the root domain and that's
where this entire chain of trust lies is
in the root domain so we would pin on
the public key for the root domain um so
let's just go ahead and jump into what
this actually looks like tangibly so
this might be a little bit small for the
people in the back but um this is just
going to be a wireshark capture of a
request sent out so it's pretty simple
we just have a type a record request to
day good game jerry-san labs com looks
like a normal a request or just one flag
that's been changed that says dns sec
approved or cape capable so then when we
send this request out we get a response
back that looks so much this so one we
get a response back with our type a
address just like we would normally see
if we send a request out but then we
also get this RR slicked back which I
said was a signature for that type a
response so in here it specifies a few
things it specifies the algorithm that
we used it also specifies the signature
of course and the signers name so that
now when a DNS SEC client wants to
verify this they can then go look at a
good day verisign lab calm dns key and
then they can perform a chain of trust
command to make sure that the request
that they just received that typed a
record is actually coming from the
server it hasn't been modified and it's
actually there so hopefully that was
just kind of a refresher but so there's
some issues with DNS SEC right but they
also provide some really good things
like I said it provides authorization in
and integrity so no more spoofing no
more cache poisoning which is a huge
benefit like I said it's still an issue
that we're having to deal
right now notably though it doesn't
provide confidentiality so anyway the
sniffing on that network can well know
where you're going um there's some some
other solutions that take care of
confidentiality if you want to if you're
interested in that people look at Dean
s-curve that's a that's a pretty cool
solution for for the confidentiality of
DNS records but something that's a
little bit out skilled for this talk so
how does this house the in a sec take
care of you know Dina's goofing or
Dina's caching well anytime an attacker
is going to try and man in the middle
that DNS connection and modify it he's
not gonna be able to sign that are are
sick with his own private key because it
wouldn't match up with a DNS key that's
on the UM the fake site or sorry on the
the legitimate sites dns server so if an
attacker was too man in the middle and
give its own it's that DNS SEC
validation would not happen and they
tack simply fails so one thing that kind
of glossed over but Dina sacrifice a
denial of existence so if you send a
request out to does not exist on
google.com it will actually come back
and say that domain doesn't exist in our
zone and here's proof of that and it
does that by sending back in in sec
record type so let us look like so we
send a request out to a ripe ripe net
with a a a domain that doesn't exist i
think i put a dot right dotnet right
here what this actually does is it since
back requesting that doesn't exist and I
can prove it to you because there is in
this one it shows there's 256 C&S type
net and e-learning dot riped on it but
there's no e dot riped on that so I
don't know thinking kind of already put
the pieces together but this allows you
to just do simple zone enumeration so if
you were able to just go in and speed be
like alright is there a
they're going to tell you anything
between before and after a and then you
can just go down the line and you can
figure out all of the domains the
subdomains in that zone so the answer to
that with a modification of the DNS SEC
RFC which introduced insect 3 and what
this does is it just provides hashing
before it does a two checks in the zone
so here we send in this is actually
going to my domain now e to me cargill
com now what it does is it hashes that
sub domain and then checks against a
hashed a list of my sub tomates so now
it's saying okay uh you know DMC bought
our URL doesn't exist but in you know
the hash before and hash after it does
exist so what this does is this allows
us like we would not have to crack all
the hashes in for this zone to be able
to enumerate it so that does provide
some security but this is just a sha-1
hash and so a big negative is people are
saying that you know with big enough
computer you can just go ahead and crack
all these all these hashes and get still
dude Ximena enumeration on DNS SEC
approved sentence so and it's like well
phone enumeration was I really matter
but I've seen some pretty creative uses
of DNS records like txt records that
hold passwords in it or you know
information about internal networks
inside its own records so Adina's some
enumeration is a pretty pretty powerful
thing so another thing on when we look
at a DNS SEC record response its
containing a pretty sizable hash of that
record type and so when you know a
simple request of an a-type with a
spoofed source IP would result in a
response to that IP of a very large data
charm and so we could actually use
is to do dns amplification attacks for
ddos we've already seen this in the wild
a few times of using dns do
amplification and DNS SEC would just
make those email more powerful because
it's quite a bit of information coming
back from a small response and then
finally like I talked about there's a
chain of trust right so we're using the
zone signing keys and the key signing
keys to validate the record and then
we're validating each um each step of
that chain until it gets that root zone
and we have to pin on something so right
now we're pinning on the root zone and
that's owned by the government so that's
owned by iono and so take that as we
will some people say the less really
good things other people say they don't
trust it so that's just more of your
interpretation of that and then finally
the the biggest component DNS SEC is the
implementation so you know DNS I
carcasses been out for a while the
Runestone finally got signed on 2010 and
the.com zone got signed in March of 2011
so it's been around for a little bit but
as you can see with this graph what
we're looking at here is a chart of DNS
SEC implementation over the entire zone
so this top one edu that was not as
complete let's pod one this is a net in
the.com boom dotnet being the balloon
and hop one and if you look over there
right now we're peaking on the.net at
point five percent of all dotnet domains
are actually implementing DNS SEC and
even lower than that calm right now is
that about point three percent of all
calm domains are DNS SEC approved or
sign and a pretty funny little site you
guys could go check out is DNS SEC name
in shame calm and it will actually see
that but you can show you the
the top 25 and not a single one of those
signs their records with DNS SEC you can
you can just put in named after named
after name to this site you know none of
them none of them validate dns f so
going to a little bit this later why
this is but needless to say that's a
huge negative when we have the security
out there but no one's adopting it so
now that we've got a good primer on date
um okay go ahead question asked this
does it just doesn't do the same
functionality for the eight Hatter
conical side of the truth um you know
what I'm haven't actually I checked that
so um yeah yeah um my thinking if I
could guess right now so it should but
Ivan actually verified that if you like
it get with me after this i can give you
my card i can go check that real quick
and let you know alright so after we got
a good brief Rodina second you finally
start talking about day so what is dane
um dein is a way of being able to do
certificate pinning using dns records
instead of using ssl certs oh sorry pkix
certs so it's built completely on top of
DNS SEC we use all of the integrity the
veteran authorization of DNS SEC to
verify our date records and its goals
pretty simple it's just take away the
reliance on the certificate authority
and put down the dns server so it does
with one simple record type so we get a
TLS a DNS record type and what that's
going to do is that's going to hold the
signature of the ssl cert that you're
about to receive from an ssl server so
um you can actually check this by just
udit dig for a TLS a record type and
then it goes in a format of your
for the port this could be running on
dot underscore the protocol that's gonna
be running on dot the domain so if you
wanted to see the certificate that
you're going to receive from good dank
verisign labs com you would just make a
TLS a request to that URL is that's up
there so what does the TLS a wreck your
type actually look like it's actually
pretty simple it's just got three
different fields plus the actual
signature I'm going to go over these
fields but their certificate usage the
selector and the matching type and then
a signature so first of all what's that
selector so we can actually say that
we're about to specify a full
certificate or we're gonna actually
specify the subject subject public key
info so we can get a pin on the full
cert or on that just a simple field we
can use uh we can do a one for one match
so the full binary certificate will be
in that record type or we can use the
sha-256 sha-512 in Danes RFC extra
supports expanding algorithms but the
most interesting field by far is a
certificate usage field so what this is
going to split this field specifies is
what kind of searching ticket are we
going to be receiving and how are we
going to handle the search idiot once we
do receive it so say we get a signature
back for a certificate and then we use
the certificate usage of zero well this
will give me a CA constraints so
basically this is saying that we
specified the certificate of a pkix
approved so be in your trusted store
certificate route so we can say we don't
want to use anybody other than verisign
labs com for this certificate that
you're about to receive similarly if you
specified one not only does this search
if you have to be verified by pkix we're
saying that that exact certificate has
to be the one that we received from from
the ssl cert so even if it does verify
it goes
the PK x checking and it's a legitimate
certificate it's gotta be the one that
we specified in that a TLS a record type
and then conversely two and three are
similar but the exact opposite so we're
saying that the the we're going to if we
specify two it would be a certificate
that there gets verified as a trust
anchor but it doesn't have to be
verified by a public key infrastructure
so we could create as ssl cert that we
then sign other search for and we could
actually use that as our trusted CA
basically without at using a actual
trusted CA and then finally three which
we call it kind of like cert penny is
this is a certificate that you're about
to receive and it doesn't be validated
by picada XO there's no reliance on
public key infrastructure when you use
such as usage 3 so what does this kind
of look like again a wireshark capture
of the query and like I said you just
whenever so say we're going to make an
HTTPS request to good daniel-san labs
com along with like a record request for
the IP then we would soon a TLS a
request to underscore former 30 short
tcp dot the domain um and then what do
you get in the response well like I said
you get a few things so you get the
certificate usage the matching type in
the selector as well as a signature so
this right here that 03 thing that's
highlighted that's the actual sha256 of
a record that you're about to receive
from that https server and then you'll
notice also along with that you got the
verisign labs com are our sig so this is
this TLS a record was just validated
using DNS SEC so how does this stop you
know at an ssl man in the middle
you know that what this does is now even
if a ssl shirt was compromised we can
now say through DNS SEC we can verify
that the certificate that was specified
in that DNS request has to be the one
that you're going to receive you can't
use any other of such as we as long as
that client is validating on Dane so why
am I kind of talking about Dane Oh like
what's the need for a game and there's
there's a few problems with the ca
system but first one should start off
with a couple of examples i think really
highlights the problem the first example
is a digi notre in july twenty eleven an
attacker was able to compromise the
generator and was able to create
wildcard certificates for it for anybody
so they created for google and then they
use that to man the middle gmail for
about three hundred thousand Iranian
users and then during that time they
were also created wild cards for Yahoo
Mozilla wordpress and in numerous other
sites so no notice these states in July
of 2011 this happened in August
twenty-ninth of that year Microsoft
finally revoked that certificate using
crl another example did you certainly
age and not to be confused with dessert
the u.s. provider two separate entities
they were intermediary CA for interest
and on November third they started
releasing really poor quality
certificates editor like 512 bit RSA
keys they didn't have a lot of the
things that are required by ssl certs
and they were given to the Malaysian
government and and the day it was
realized in November third Mozilla
finally used revo keishon on November 17
so about two weeks before they were able
to actually even push out of the
relocation so one of these two
kind of signify well one I compromising
the chain completely compromises the
entire chain of trust you know if if did
you search compromised then not only is
this the ssl certs that digi cert has
already signed compromised but the
entire system is compromised because
there are CA we've completely trusted
them for the security of say our HTTPS
traffic and then also once a certificate
once a compromise has happened it's
incredibly difficult to revoke eight
that because of the way that our
relocation system currently is and thing
is perfect for fixing both of these
issues one depending on the DNS
completely eliminates the need for a CA
system you know like I said we can
actually pin on an ssl cert and now that
we control you know our organization
owns that DNS server we now own the
security force a our HTTPS traffic and
then also it handles reeve occasion
really elegantly and it's kind of a side
effect that no one's really talking
about right now but it's I think
something that's really good to be noted
speaking of your location how are we
doing relocation right now and really
there's two two answers there's crls in
OC SPS CR l's are basically Alyssa gets
pushed out set you know specifying you
know which ssl certs have been
compromised or rolled out or no longer
valid and it's it's too large you know
there's no there's no way it's scalable
that's a huge list and so because it's
too large they got cut out like a bunch
of them and it's not comprehensive and
also if we don't get this list we can't
just shut down our CA checking system
because like if you d-don't a crl server
then just take down the entire
or at least all secure internet and then
similarly ocsp this is more of a /
receiving a CA signed cert it checks to
see if it's a valid certificate and
again they've got issues with like
you're constantly going to ocsp servers
to check for searching validation and
again it's a fail open system so like I
said we're going to talk about some
heartbleed here so you know an
interesting consequence of Heartlake was
that everybody thought there see a
surplice was compromised and then
everybody wanted to revoke their
certificate and publish a new one but
there's there's just really no way of
handling this currently um Adam Langley
from google basically specified that you
know chrome uses a mixture of crl no CSP
and either one who can handle a
relocation properly earth are
significantly enough to revote mass
amounts and certificates and Dane he
knows this really well so say your your
certificate guest gets compromised well
now all you do is you know create a new
certificate pushed up to https server or
whatever server and then simply update
your DNS record with the signature of
your new certificate and now you have
your opinion on a clean separate
certificate and if anybody uses that
compromised cert to try and meet an
earlier connection it won't be valid
because the TLS a record type takes care
of that so you know yeah we have these
problems with the ca sir but there's
there's also problems with a DNS server
so you know with their CEA system it's
not really any longer a chain of trust
more web of trust just because you know
there's so many intermarry intermediary
cas out there and you know anyone
can you pop whereas adina's a ding dns
connection is more of a tree of trust
DNS SEC you know you're either yours or
your com or your route has gotta get
compromised to compromise your DNS SEC
traffic and so and then there's there's
some other issues with like you know
with your CSS and we have multiple root
trusted cas whereas this one only used
one and that's a government so that's
really kind of a pro and con depending
on how you look at that um you know the
people that run those cas are
multinational conglomerates a new sim
and tech Komodo Go Daddy globalsign
those are the big ones versus this one's
going to be owned by iono and then
people that own those tlds and then
that's going to kind of change when we
have all these generic Quixote's coming
out because now we're gonna have a lot
of different separate companies like me
there may be able to publish DNS SEC
validated records so it's going to be
something to watch out for and then
protections in the SSL handshake you
know at least with the ca system it's
all in one protocol right it's all in
the SSL protocol whereas now we're kind
of breaking it out into a second
protocol to handle this so there's some
introduction of some more attack surface
by using two protocols and said just one
to validate our ssl traffic and then you
know something to look at is your how
many cas have been compromised there's
how many DNS servers have been
compromised and you know what if we
decide to move towards a more DNS based
approach to security I'm definitely
think that we're going to start seeing a
lot more DNS compromises but there's
already been some significant ones just
take a look at ms 1105 eight huge
compromise and is Microsoft's DNS so
luckily not to choose though because
like I said with the certificate usage
we could actually pin not only using TLS
a but also using your see
using certificate usage one which
basically says this certificate has to
be validated by PKA is but it also has
to be the certificate that we valid that
we specified and this TLS a record type
so I'm starting to run out of time here
something she's going to jump over that
um so well again we have this issue with
with implementation and this this is
going to be it's because it's a
bootstrap protocol right so no one wants
to implement Dane no one wants to
implement DNS SEC because it's protocol
that no one uses and no one uses it
because no one implements it so there's
kind of chicken or egg situation and you
know like i said point three of calm
uses DNS SEC like handful of sites used
and right now there's a really good
toilet their cult in a sec validator
that'll actually you know check for TLS
a records as and as well as DNS SEC so
check that out if you're interested in
actually using that for your client
there's a couple of good sites i can
actually test that out on a date any
cargo com that will be validate that is
validated by TLS a liquor types as well
as good Dame de veras I'm labs com and
also if you want to check out your
validators worky there's bad day at
verisign labs com as well so um well the
reasons I took a look at this was
because NCC domain services mcc sub
parent company for I sake partners and
actually releasing this new TLD called
trust and what it basically does is it
requires that anybody in that TLD to get
in regular penetration testing and they
have to comply to a rigor set standards
to be in the dot trust TLD and one of
those standards is that they have to be
using Dane and they have to be using DNS
SEC so I think this is really great sign
that we're you know we're going to start
seeing this a lot more there's a reason
why people are talking about this a lot
more you might not be implemented yet
but good to start talking about this and
start you know looking at the security
of this before it gets implemented any
kind of going with that
what can you do I think there's three
different ways of looking at what can
you do if you actually believe in dane
or DNS egg and as builders breakers or
hand shakers you know if your builder
obviously this kind of plies to you you
know if you're a web server maintainer
why not sign your zone with the NSA or
if you're an application developer why
not build into your HTTPS stack
validation for four day um also breakers
so the stuff definitely is going to need
testing right so we're building new code
it's using crypto so plugging you see or
some native language code to write the
validation for this date and DNS SEC and
we're going to start putting this in a
lot of different clients if it picks off
if it picks up so um and already we're
kind of starting to see that a recent on
2013 there was actually a arbitrary code
execution and GNU TLS in their day
validators so I think you know for
people like me that get paid to just
break things I think we're going to see
a lot of issues with breaking things in
Dane and DNS SEC for developers that
aren't paying attention to this new code
and finally hand shakers um you know
like I said no one is adopting this
right now and it's going to take some
pushing from IT pushing from
organizational standpoint just to
finally get you know Dana DNS SEC into
Google and to you know any of your Alexa
top 25 or top 100 you know we need to
start communicating with upper
management that you know this is why we
need um DNS SEC and this is what it will
provide for our organization so I kind
of rushes that last bit because we're
kind of running out of time once you
guys get be able to get to launch here
but do you guys have any questions about
why just went over
yes not yes I've to question why he
mentioned a handful people were you can
gain do you know like close to the
numbers whatever you had like the
percentages for DSS like we're talking
maybe 10 I mean this is this is very low
I don't I don't know the exact number
but like it's enough to tally no well
and then you know I'm a huge advocate of
XL finish up like that waters for the
hurdles to keep all of the signatures
that you're keeping any game 7s melted
and gets up to date right so that when
you actually do that I wants to keep
inning on a bit of direction correct
yeah so that doesn't big like a a lot of
people like to complain about Wally you
know there's some some standards for
like how long do you keep yours Arizona
sign for how often do you resize that
kind of thing and in the RC they kind of
specify using an HSM to be able to hold
your your keys off the server and then
you can use some sort of automated
pooling of that aspect but that's going
to be more of an organizational decision
um but kind of going with that is that
bond is now released to set tools that
really makes it really easy like Reese
on your zone introduced a key rotation
so those solutions are becoming more
more available no the larger that DNS
second dank it there's going to be more
cleverly that tools but right now it is
kind of limited and that's a big
negative that allow people don't want to
hassle of having to rotate another set
of keys any other questions yes one
point chrome has
so yeah I kind of I mentioned Adam
Langley and his talking he's got a
pretty good post on that about you know
why it was a Google and why they took it
out but really why boiled down to was no
one was using it you can actually get a
fork of chromium that's still supported
basically just took the cone that code
put it in chromium forks and none you
can use that but that's that's the
reason why yeah at least that's what
Adam Langley says is the reason why they
took it out of crown any other questions
I things everybody for coming out i
really appreciate it