hello everybody hey there we are this is
the fireside chat as you can see we've
got the Yule Log going it's the closest
thing I think we could get without
getting some fire marshals involved
anyway my name is robert arsenic Hanson
I'm the vice president labs of white hat
security and a lot of people ask me what
that is basically I build all the stuff
that doesn't really have a home anywhere
else or no one can figure out how to
build or whatever so I go off and build
it some examples are like aviator and
some internal stuff that you'll probably
never see you've never ate the light of
day and so on but on the black cat
advisory board every strong hackers or I
guess I still technically do wrote some
books and I break the web all the time
so um let's just get into it how about
that so I want to talk a little bit
about how bad guys find websites and I
think it's it's possibly evolving very
very rapidly so let's talk about how
they used to find websites so once upon
a time let's say I want to scan the
entire internet looking for vulnerable
websites of a particular vulnerability
that I knew about or something it could
take you know anywhere from months to
even a year or more when I first started
off on the internet because processing
time was not particularly good bandwidth
was bad you know the ecosystem was kind
of really spread out we didn't really
understand the whole RFC thing and you
know scanning things like 10 dot was not
particularly effective and all kinds of
stuff but anyway it took you know
sometimes what we would call like an
endless amount of scanning where
effectively by the time we were done
scanning you kind of had to start the
whole process over again and rescan the
internet because the Internet has
changed significantly and let's say in
the last year or whatever so now due to
a change in the linux kernel last year
you can now scan the entire internet on
a single port with about four machines
100 megabits each you can do it in about
four minutes four minutes so that has
changed the what landscape landscape
looks like from a threat perspective
very significantly or at a minimum it's
about two and
the reason is just because the attackers
haven't really figured it out so TCP and
UDP on on ipv4 is effectively probed
there you hiding something on a high
port or something that does not work
anymore I mean it never really worked
but now it definitely doesn't work ipv6
is a whole different ballgame you still
are technically safe in there as long as
I can't figure out approximately where
you are but that whole operation based
on you hiding on the internet with ports
does not work so let me talk a little
bit about the technology so once upon a
time or a tool called fears which does
DNS enumeration also finds
non-contiguous IP space so let's say you
had a target you'd scan for that targets
using fierce then you turn nmap loose on
the results of that and you would get a
listing of all the open ports of your
target now you have stuff because that
change in Linux kernel I was talking
about you like zmapp and mass can and
these don't require all that nonsense I
can just scan the whole internet I don't
need to do anything funky like figure
out what your IP space is I'll just
figure out all of the IP space on the
entire internet it's actually just more
efficient to do it that way this
particular screenshot is actually taken
from a botnet that was scanning the
entire internet probably maybe as much
as once a minute it was scanning the
entire internet and it was able to
detect changes you know basically
servers going up and down on the
internet based on Hurricane sandy coming
through and kind of wiping out the city
so as damage assessments you know if
you're in a wartime situation and
there's bombs blowing up you can
actually detect that that particular
target has been taken down by virtue of
you not being able to ping that
particular IP address or set of IP
addresses or whatever so they were able
to watch it turning on and off basically
as it was happening which is pretty
amazing so I'll talk more about that in
a bit so I know that sounds bad but it's
actually much much worse than that so I
know no one's ever said I'm a bearer of
good news so why is pre computing better
than
fast Gant so fast Gansey oh I can scan
the entire internet like I said in four
minutes for a single IP address or
single court rather skinny entire
internet get all that data back but
that's actually kind of slow if I
actually scan the internet let's say
last week because I doing it all the
time is pretty obnoxious if I did it
like last week I can shove it a new
database and if I have in a database I
can do lookups effectively in real time
I can say find me all of the open ports
that are you know vulnerable to whatever
whatever i'm talking about some
application or something that I'm
exploitable or whatever show me every
all the results now and so I can get the
results back in seconds not minutes
seconds and the internet does change and
in a week it will change a little bit
but not significantly enough that you
won't get a huge target list if as long
as it's a fairly you know dense
vulnerability or whatever we're talking
about and the nice part is it's
effectively no false positives because
the internet doesn't wrap it doesn't
change that quickly so we're going to
start seeing a lot more of that we're
going to start seeing people started and
use this stuff and I have a lot of
evidence of it so there's some people
working on this already university of
michigan in conjunction with rapid seven
there's any rupted seven employees here
no that's too bad shoutouts to those
guys they're doing really really cool
stuff if you run into tray for tell them
like their stuff they're doing is very
very important to all of us by the way
so right now they're doing several
different types of scans this is
actually not a complete list they doing
HTTP s ecosystem scans of things like
HAARP lead and stuff figuring out what
servers are vulnerable reverse and also
for DNS that's actually a new thing
service fingerprints port 80 just
basically crawling the entire internet
so that's actually really cool stuff
barely what I need it's there's some
other smoothly cool stuff that they
could be doing that there hopefully
going to be doing the not too distant
future but it's it's definitely going
also muaks uh guys familiar with muaks
you guys know him awesome good he's a
cool guy he's running a reverse dns scan
of the entire internet right now it was
temporarily offline i'm not sure if you
brought it back online
and I think the reason it was offline is
because he ran out of hard drive space
so the other one that's pretty cool
right now is unicorn net it's basically
an HTTPS heartbleed scanner where he's
basically charging around like a half a
Bitcoin or something for any result that
you want of a target list so basically
you say here's the IP address or a set
of IP addresses that I'm interested in
he'll tell you if he's got information
about it no give you little snip it and
then you pay some amount of money and
you can get the entire heartbleed dump
without actually doing the attack
yourself why is that bad well for the
obvious reason that now I know for
neural lists and I can go attack
individual targets I'm interested in but
also from a forensics perspective this
is a total nightmare so imagine I have a
heart bleed you know vulnerability and
then I close it right so a month later
or something somebody attacks me and the
very first attack the very first attempt
they make they compromised something
that's really esoteric on my site like
how the hell did they do that must have
been an insider they must have somehow
like no like compromised my vendor who
wrote the code like there's got to be
something else going on there but not
snot what happened what happened is
they've got this old heart bleep data
went through called it found like old
cookie data they found a directory that
was supposed to be hidden to isn't some
source code that might have an SQL
injection or command ejection in it it's
unique so that minor information leak
can be used way in the future even even
though you think you patched the
vulnerability if there are any
vulnerabilities that were disclosed
during that heartbleed which is a great
way to you know uncover all kinds of
stuff in that file system they can
effectively use that against you and so
just been a few minutes of testing i
think i was able to compromise about 40
different machines just using harper lee
data from unicorn without even paying
for it which is pretty crazy um so the
other one is the insert internet census
project this is actually no one knows
who did this apparently it is by
anonymous anonymous hacked into 1.2
million routers and he was using that to
scan the entire internet which is pretty
cool and this I like this botnet because
he used one of three passwords default
passwords like admin
squirt in one two three four five six or
something and he was able to hack into
1.2 million routers which said another
way is 1.2 million networks so you and
with 1.2 million networks at your
disposal usually on broadband it turns
out you can scan the internet very very
rapidly so you can make pretty graphs
like this which you totally can't see
because it's too dark but basically that
it's a really beautiful looking graph
that you're going to miss out on but it
basically just shows the landscape of
the entire world and it's actually a
full-motion he has got gifts and stuff
they showed turning on and off as it
kind of traverses the entire day span
like machines turn on and off in
different countries so he's able to scan
the entire internet literally in seconds
and you can do it basically all day long
so you can find everything coming up
turning off so again you thinking you
have something on a high port that that
doesn't work but it gets worse so show
Dan it's a really fun little tool if you
haven't played with you definitely
should especially if you're a nap sec
there's all kinds of cool research stuff
you can do so let's say you have a
vulnerable service like HP five point
three point three that I want to go
attack let's say let's say get a
vulnerability in that remote command
injection as an example in this
particular example if I'm 1.5 million
targets that are potentially vulnerable
that I could go take over and
effectively I just need to pay and all
of a sudden I get this huge dump of all
these vulnerable servers and I can go to
tack and create my own botnet which I
can use for this at other attack stuff
that I was talking about you can use it
to probe so the reason why this is bad
is bad for two given reasons one it kind
of articulates the whole store and then
attack type mentality that we're moving
towards but also it shows that that
minor information leak of that exported
for re-export for what i was saying
expired by rather is although it is a
minor information leak it actually can
make a big difference it suddenly puts
you on the target list where you
wouldn't have been in another case not
that it's just I mean ultimately they
could just attack the entire internet
and some people have done that in fact
that's what they're kind of currently
doing but I think that will change very
rapidly once people figure out how much
more efficient they can be then it's all
about saving money so in my opinion you
should have banned in the hole
time-based obfuscation so once upon a
time being on the internet having a
vulnerable service it was like okay well
we're vulnerable to this exploit or
something we have time like people oh
there's a great quote it's like the
problem is you think you have time you
don't have time or a very little time at
that and what's really happening here is
that whole time based obfuscation like
we have time to fix this vulnerability
because no one's going to find us on the
internet that is not really a thing
anymore or at least it's going away very
quickly and maybe that's okay for the
small-time attackers who don't really
understand what's going on but any of
the more sophisticated adversaries are
definitely moving in this direction so
let me give you an example so we had
this Ruby on Rails vulnerability he was
last year and basically you know someone
came out with it I've got putting as
Floyd and it started being attacked so
here's a brief example of a timeline of
one of our customers who have this issue
over on this side is basically on the
your left hand side is basically when
this vulnerability came out and then you
can sort of see they found out about it
it got put in mezz flight they patched
it if they put an ids rule in place to
look for it and then suddenly they were
attacked and that's the red boxes there
you see so they were able to defend
themselves but just barely I mean really
just by a day or so so that is that
bracket there underneath it is really
what i'm talking about that is shrinking
very very rapidly the time it took for
it to get into metasploit and actually
being attacked in that case was one day
I think that's really slow really really
slow I think I mean that sounds like
really fast to you i'm sure you're like
oh god i only have a data patch no no I
think you have possibly seconds possibly
seconds so I think it's important for us
to think like our adversaries instead of
spent a lot of my time talking with
adversaries but we also think I have to
think you know who could be our
adversary maybe it's not just some
random hacker trying to steal data from
it maybe it's our competitors because
some of the bad guys I'm talking to they
work for companies or they are companies
there are attempting to take over other
companies or do bad things to them
because from their perspective from a
monetary
monitors respect what this all comes
down to money right I mean all at the
end of the day everything's about money
what they really want is to remove you
from the index and Google if they can if
they can do that then you're less likely
to get clicked on people aren't going to
know about you they're not gonna write
articles about you therefore you're
eventually going to go away or they can
hurt enough of your market share and and
they get that market share that they can
make money so this is a very brief brief
brief list I know it's going to seem
long but it's a brief list of some of
the examples of the things that I'm
starting to hear them talk about and
this this is the non technical stuff so
this should scare the out you
because basically anyone can do this so
ways that you can totally screw over
your competitors some examples you build
a robot tell it through tor and name it
your competitors bot and basically you
crawl the entire internet and basically
what happens is you get a whole bunch of
phone calls saying please stop scanning
the internet you're really annoying the
crap out of us and waste a ton of their
time and they don't have time to
actually do real business send tons of
spam spoofed messages of from your
competitors email accounts and that
Chris's gigantic back stressed like
please stop email me it's
terrible I hate that stuff and it wastes
a bunch of their time you sign them up
for every type of spam email you can in
fact the actually have a funny story
about that I used to use a asdfasdf calm
as like a test email account turned out
that poor guy who owned that email
account was getting completely slammed
by me so you had to change his email
account which sorry so you sign the
competitors teams phone numbers up to
every contact form you ever very similar
attack decide the competitive team for
every type of physical mail you can this
actually sucks a lot because physical
mail if you if you get enough of it you
no longer can find the invoices buried
in the mail so you stop paying your
bills because you just can't find them
anymore you know when you get over a
hundred thousand pieces of physical mail
a day you literally can't do anything
other than deal with that mail I mean
you're just you're done or just don't
deal with it at all and just leave your
house like a hoarder full
male right so you submit the resume of
your competitors top people to various
job boards this actually has occurred
this is actually a real attack this is
not a theoretical one and so what
happened is the HR team started emailing
like it's like like are we cool like are
you going to leave us and like no why
and so what ends up happening is a you
waste a bunch of their time but a lot of
internal conversations and hallway stuff
it's all waste of time and it also means
that that person is much more likely to
actually leave because people going to
call and say hey got this great job so
you're going to lose your best people so
you mail bomb the competitive team with
a landslide of overly large emails crash
the mail server bonus points if you send
it from their email account so people
say please take me off your list or
whatever unsubscribe and people start
responding it's awesome so you can write
to be forgotten all of their pages this
is definitely something they're already
doing by the way and rightfully be
forgotten is really a UK thing it
doesn't really work in the United States
but if it's an overseas international
organization that would be a good
example dmca some of their pages and
domains there's actually another version
of this which I just heard one of them
one of the black hats I talked to just
email me two days ago about this and it
was you can basically sign people up and
say they are not paying their Adobe
licenses there there's they're basically
using a bunch of hacked accounts for
like Photoshop or something and this
organization will come down on it like a
ton of bricks on them and like do this
huge internal investigation totally wipe
them out for months which is pretty
nasty autocomplete for the brand name
you know spam and brand name fraud brand
name whatever and so when people are
typing it in on Google they're like oh
this is a fraud oh maybe I shouldn't do
business with them and just waste a ton
of time because they try to deal with
that send them up to rbl lists so all
their emails get blocks so more waste of
time like oh did you get my email it's
like Chris Nickerson said it the best
I've ever heard email is UDP I mean it's
a one-way thing you never know if it
gets there really obnoxious you can add
the word unix box to all of their pages
it will block all the Chinese users
china does not like unix boxes you get
negative reviews about the company's
senior management that basically means
that now they have dual is brand
reputation repairing stuff and that's
extremely expensive and also a huge
waste of time right foot articles I know
this seems like a lot of stuff and it I
know it is but this is believe it or not
the shortlist fraud articles and
basically more waste of time it's all
and none of it's true but it
doesn't matter spoof email from the
competitive exec team to the IT team
asking all kinds of garbage stuff
because I mean they're like oh you know
am I hacked and like oh you can't
imagine that downstream shitstorm that
would cause sent a lot of friend
requests to the exact team from ha
single ladies get them to dump all their
information when they finally do try to
sleep with you send that to email at all
at which total shitstorm it would
totally light up a company send a flood
of text messages to the IT DevOps
marketing teams during product launches
like oh it's broken whoa they're just
running around so they never know which
ones are real and they're just wasting
tons of time and they've missed the good
stuff so I hope that's sort of
demonstrative sort of demonstrative of
some of the things I mean there should
be a big old etc at the bottom of this
this is definitely by no means no
stretch all the things you can do and
this is the non technical stuff there's
all kinds of really gnarly super
technical stuff that's an entire extra
deck I haven't I don't have time to go
through it all but this is it turns out
much easier to do this kind of stuff
than it is to do the hearts technical
stuff so even though you're thinking oh
I don't really care about this stuff it
doesn't matter the adversaries are
already starting to use this so if
you're working with companies who
actually have real-world adversaries out
there this is the kind of attack that
the bad guys actually can do they know
how to do this even these very
unsophisticated let's call them
corporate bad guys know how to do this
stuff or they can get imagine enough to
figure enough of it out to do it
themselves so sometimes i'm wrong and i
don't like being wrong but i think it's
useful to examine when you are wrong in
this particular case i spent a lot of
time
figure out why do bad guys like sequel
injection I just don't get it I mean I
understand that it's a bad vulnerability
that I understand I'm not that dumb but
I don't get why they like it better than
command injection it never really made
sense to me so I sat down I talked to
one of them and I'm like okay tell me
give me the lowdown what why why or do
you like sequel injection more like let
me give you an example if i gave you
sequel injection and i gave you command
jection on the same box and all you'd
get out of the sequel injection nothing
special all you get is the data out of
the database and that is it imagine
there's no way to pivot there's nothing
actually can do let's say that's all
lockdown or ending up on a different
machine and that thing's totally locked
down which would you prefer he still
said sequel injection I'm like why I
don't I don't get it command jection you
get all kinds of stuff you can pivot you
can attack the source code you can
change it if you want you can add
malware and you can remove yourself from
the logs and on and on is all this great
stuff you can do sequin jection you just
get the data you might be able to pivot
you might be able to get effectively
command injection but with command
direction you definitely get command
injection you know I just never made
sense to me and also from sin tax
perspective it just seems like a bigger
pain in the ass you know but it turns
out it's actually not it's much much
easier to do sequel injection because
really the only thing they do care about
in this particular case is getting the
data maybe they want to modify the data
in some cases that is true like I've run
into healthcare organizations where the
adversaries want to modify data to
change certain records so that certain
things that are happening study wise
turn out it to their advantage but for
the most part they just want to steal
the data so when you want get command
injection you land on a box effectively
what that does is it says all right
you're you got a shell here now what
okay all right what kind of operating
system iowa okay you named ina say i'm
on some bun to version blah blah blah
it's like okay where is apache stored is
this version 11 points um thing or two
points something it's like this is two
points okay is it / etc Patrick like
you've got to find the directory start
moving around like okay okay the
database is at a local database or is
that remote
like the stroll to the source code make
its java I'm on java his strings or
something and like it just turns out
it's a bigger pain in the ass once you
get command injection I mean you can do
it and any sophisticated AB adversaries
going to go of course you can do that
it's really simple actually but it takes
so much more work to get the data even
though you have command injection then
just to get the data with sequin
Junction so this is all like a trade-off
right how much how much work are you
willing to do as an adversary to pull
that data out and it turns out sequin
Junction is just far superior so let's
talk about things that are easy so I'm a
big formula 1 fan yeah we have Kota here
in awesome so I'm not huge for our I fan
but I respect them quite a bit but I was
listening I was watching TV the other
day and Steve match it who's like one of
the nicer guys is talking about from one
cars by the ways is not a sports analogy
this is an actual attack so just bear
with me for a second so Steve matchick
was talking about you know basically
they don't do any of the strategy at the
pit they basically sent everything over
the wire to marinello in Italy and in it
in Italy they do all this analysis on
the data all the telemetry data and then
they send it back all the way to austin
let's say and tell the car drive like
this right and as soon as I heard that
I'm like what are you doing what you're
sending it over the internet like what
are you talking about you can't be
sending like two car telemetry over the
Internet you insane have you seen the
internet oh so I started thinking
about like what would I do if I were a
competitive team an example Williams
team the difference between a third
place and fourth place which is where
they are standing right now is worth
millions of dollars millions of dollars
to them so what would I do if I were
Williams what I say I should invest
let's say two million dollars to lock in
that third place position or let's say
do something else what what else could I
do well two million dollars and i only
make 2 million dollars that's a wash but
if I don't spend the two million dollars
I lose two million dollars so that's bad
right that seems bad so even though it's
a wash it's just a wash you know it's
like the better of two evils kind of
thing or you could just launch it an
aisle service right so Matt you're
handsome
and during my Grossman who work for me
or work for the same company rather they
don't work for me let's be very clear
don't don't repeat that I could just see
that storm anyway so they they came
up with an attack basically where you
can seed a little piece of JavaScript on
AB networks and take over take out
basically anything you want so they test
this against Akamai Akamai's homepage
actually and with a chrome eyes homepage
they were able to prove that with about
three hundred dollars they could take
down Akamai a coma right the company
that a tons and tons of companies use
for anti denial service stuff just
because you can flood the network with
that much traffic using ads so so what
should you do if you're an adversary
let's say our Williams or a crazy
William fan Williams fan where I don't
have two million dollars to spend on R&D
and even if I did I'm not giving it the
Williams would I would I what I prefer
to do all that work or maybe just spend
300 bucks on some ads right it doesn't
even have to be my credit card I can use
somebody else's I'm good at that so not
only do I save the two million dollars
in rd but I also make two million
dollars in winning on the the team right
so from an adversarial perspective it's
much easier to do these low hanging
fruit the type of tax I know they seem
less good than the right way to do it
from a purely academic perspective but
it just turns out adversaries don't care
they just don't care at least not the
ones I talk to you they just don't care
so if you you've got to find evidence
that these attacks are actually
happening one of the biggest problems I
have with like the last threat
classification although very good is
that it doesn't really articulate how
likely these vulnerabilities are to
happen or even if they are possible or
even if they ever have happened sure
academically yes I'm sure someone found
it in a lab or created it or whatever
I'm sure if you do have access to source
code in some very particular situations
yes you can initiate those things but in
reality I just don't see it so when I
talk two adversaries I asking questions
like have you ever seen this type of
xpath injection ever used in the wild
ever even anecdotally even Keyser Soze
you know so you know like oh I heard a
spooky story once about X
like know the answer is no not even one
time ever have these guys ever seen or
heard about it used in the wild even
amongst their own community not that
it's not possible maybe it has happened
once maybe it's even happened five times
100 times or whatever but not internet
scale not the stuff that we should be
caring about not saying you shouldn't do
the research I'm just saying it's not a
real risk today so and likewise other
things like sequel injection are
actually higher or actually worse than I
thought and you know me being a more or
less an academic I guess in this context
I'm always shocked to find out I'm
completely wrong about stuff so it does
happen but one thing I really don't like
it's a little bit of a pet peeve of mine
is when people say like high medium and
low severity it's I've always disliked
it we've been stuck with it and we're
still kind of stuck with it but I just
don't like it because it doesn't really
give context if I say there's a high
medium a hype of ulnar ability on one
site and medium vulnerability another
site which one you go fix right it
depends on the site if one's internal
enter need someone's desk with no
sensitive information on it and the
other ones your corporate front end
which one you go fix right the one that
it's actually going to get attacked
right the one with actual sensitive
information on it so you're missing that
context and it's it's always bugged me
because if you run a US Nessus scan or
whatever it's going to say this is high
you're like I mean in without any
context Navy but you know it doesn't
have any sensitive information on it
it's under someone's desk it's you know
and behind the corporate firewall it's
totally shunted off it's in a lab right
that's not a high that's not even alone
that's not nothing so I think it's
important if we start we got to add
context to what we're talking about keep
the bad guy in mind if you're not
thinking about what the bad guys are
actually going to do you're going to
miss a lot of stuff so this is kind of
what I'm talking about so bear with me I
know graphs are a little funky but so on
the vertical axis is what you call the
expected value of Los post compromise so
let's say
you had a vulnerability and you expect
that you would lose about a million
dollars if it were exploited and let's
say there's a ten percent chance it's
going to happen within the next 12
months let's call that a
hundred-thousand-dollar expected value
of loss right and there's a bunch of
other factors involved right like the
risk how likely is that anonymous knows
who you are and whatever right and then
on the on the horizontal scale there you
have the investment pre compromised how
much does it cost to fix a vulnerability
before the bad guys find out about it
before anything happens if I want to fix
this today how much would it cost me my
corporation to fix this vulnerability
right pretty straightforward and then
you plot your vaults so this just
visually you're already starting to get
a little bit more contacts than you had
before right this is a little bit more
useful but it's still missing something
pretty important which is what do I give
a about just because they're easy
vulnerability doesn't mean that I want
to fix it I know there's a lot of
security purists out there they say I
want to fix every vulnerability but that
doesn't really make sense economically
there's all kinds of reasons that's true
and we do it all the time I risk myself
right now right now I'm standing in
front of you anyone you could shoot me
right you could kill me right now I'm
sitting on the pit stage that is a real
risk it's not a very high risk I've sort
of risk rated it right it's not i'm not
gonna take any defensive measures I
don't have any like plexiglas-in-front-
of us or whatever so I've taken that
risk and we do that throughout life
there's all kinds of contexts where we
do that so what we need is something
something like a risk curve so a curve
might indicate it totally depends on the
person the situation the company there's
all kinds of different ways you might
want to calculate this but a curve that
kind of tilts away like this would be
what we call a risk adverse curve
somebody who really does not want to get
exploited for whatever reason they're
very sensitive about it or maybe their
business models sort of a tipping point
if it happens too often people won't
trust them or whatever right and the
other one is a risk tolerant curve this
is a company I like to pick on oil and
gas a lot like oil and gas where they
take a lot of risks because the reward
is so high they're making billions and
billions of dollars so you just sort of
decide what type of risk profile you
want so let me give you an example how
you might calculate
so let's say there's a vulnerability and
it'll cost you expected value of loss of
one thousand dollars let's say it cost
one hundred dollars to fix would you fix
the bowl what yes you would okay well if
you're the oil and gas you'd say no you
know why do you have any idea how much
money they make picking up the phone
will will not give them anywhere near
what they would if they hung up the
phone and start drilling you know what I
mean there's no way they're going to
recoup that cost that they do not care
but a little mom and pop a little
grocery store is something they might
say a thousand dollars is all I'm going
to make all day that's 100 and 356 of
the or whatever of our annual budget so
it's definitely worth fixing right that
it's a good it's a solid investment so
the curve looks different so you
basically asked that question over and
over at different sliding scales and you
can sort of plot what your kerpit look
like just just kind of mental model here
it's obviously a lot more complicated in
that but you get the idea and then you
fix the vulnerabilities in the order up
from the upper left-hand corner down to
the efficient frontier of the curve and
then you don't fix anything below that
curve and that makes people very
uncomfortable people don't like talking
about not fixing bones and i'll tell you
why you have to do it but an innocent
anyway you fix these vulnerabilities and
this is really cool because you can go
talk to your see so or your CFO even
which is even much more interesting and
you can say instead of you there's three
sequel injections to command jection
there's a clickjacking and what blonde
this is when we're gonna click and
they're like okay sorry can you stop
looking Klingon and you know give me
some real information I have no idea
what you just said what so instead I can
say we have this amount of expected loss
here's how much money I need so you
don't have that loss like okay money in
equals money out I get this CFO's can
talk that language that dollar signs are
what they talk they don't know anything
about our vulnerabilities they don't
really care about our vulnerabilities
but they do care about loss and if they
can look at a curve like this and they
can argue with you and say what is the
math behind this you can show them the
math and they can argue and say I don't
like this piece of math you can fix it
and then you have a meaningful
conversation as opposed to this one way
thing rhyme technical and your
and it never goes anywhere so that works
great until you don't know about the
Volm if you don't know about your
vulnerabilities how the hell can you
plot so you can do sort of basic mental
modeling like we have ten percent of our
vulnerabilities that we don't know about
let's say right whatever whatever the
numbers and they're approximately let's
say this bad you know you can sort of
you know diagram them out what you think
they might be in general right but
they're still there like what do you do
about them you can't fix them because
you don't know where they are right so
what you can do is you can do insurance
modeling you can put insurance in place
to limit your liability to the point
where it is below your risk tolerance
curve now it's an expected value of loss
of a known quantity you know how much
you're spending on insurance you know
it's worth you know you're going to get
out of it so this is where things are
going you got to get on the train if
you're not already on the train is
everyone a train get on the train yeah
all right good you better go on the
train because this is the way business
is going and I i'm also a technologist I
promise so let's talk a little bit about
individual vault so this is why people
don't like the idea about not fixing
bones I will talk you through it because
I agree it's scary as crap so first
let's say you plot along and let's say
it's something that you're like okay
this is something we definitely want to
fix this is bad command jection and home
page it will basically take us all out
this is this is the end of the world
this is the this is the type of one we
all talk about right or sequel injection
sorry my bad so then you're like ok
we'll we'll outsource this to some third
country or whatever is somewhere well
give it to some company that'll do for
us or whatever they're way cheaper
whatever but whoops we didn't sign any
isolate the SLA is there is that
vulnerability but we forgot to say you
had to fix the vulnerability so now it's
sort of like they don't they're not
incentive to fix it like what do they
care right
hello all right about the same sounds
louder all right so so anyway in that
example where you don't have an SLA in
place the cost of remediation goes way
up because now you got to like pay them
to do something or like like break your
contract or whatever does all this funky
stuff you have to do just to get that
stupid vulnerability fixed right so
let's say as an example that would push
that way over as an again then let's say
you're like screw it screw ringing this
company I hate this company they're
really pain in the ass I'm going to stop
clearing credit cards in that website
I'll do everything off the third party
so now the data is off of that thing
right so we went from it being something
that I would fix but maybe not right
away to something because I can't
because it's too expensive to something
I'm not even gonna bother fixing at this
point there's no sensitive data on there
anyway I don't care right whatever it's
you know from a liability perspective it
went down far enough the expected value
of loss is much much lower now yeah we
maybe have some brand reputation issues
if it ever were compromised but it's not
going to steal the money out of the
database right because there is no money
in that database then let's say you
install a wash in front of it and then
it's like well you know the expected
value of law stay the same but now it's
so much cheaper to fix this bone all I
have to do is roll out a laugh roll I
mean I do have to QA and stuff and you
know maybe not perfectly fixed but it's
close enough so it's barely worth fixing
it's not really a big deal anyway so
volt have moved around over time right
this is why continuous assessment is
really important because you have to
continue to look at what your risk
profile is because it changes over time
and then anonymous figures out who you
are right and they decide well this this
is a target we're interested in and
brand reputation is like a guaranteed
hit and suddenly it's something you care
about again is everyone with me all
right so everyone in saw the train
that's right yeah okay good I think it's
important for us all to be on the train
because this is the language of business
it's not it's not like it if and what
this might happen or something this is
already happening the instrumentation we
need to create this stuff and doing
insurance modeling is still infantile I
think it's got a long way to go before
we're actually
err we can actually do this stuff but
this is where things are going so but
the important part of the sort of the
theme of this whole thing if you weren't
following it did you just wake up from a
coma if you weren't following it the
whole point of this is we have to be
more aware of what the bad guys are
actually doing just because we have
found a vulnerability that we really
like and it's something that we're
interested in just because I love
command injection oh I love it so much
it doesn't mean the bad guys like it
that it doesn't mean they care and
doesn't mean they're going to exploit it
as regularly as something else that may
be less like amazing or whatever to you
personally or make show up as a medium
instead of a high in your and your
vulnerability scanner you should not pay
attention to that in a vacuum you got to
think about the bigger picture like how
is this work in ecosystem and I'm sure
we'll end up happening over time is
you'll have different data sources like
like Akamai is a great example of a data
source like they have all this graph
stuff coming in threat information but
you also have underground channels like
people like somebody's start talking
about our company you know you have
different companies doing threat Intel
that might feed into something like this
or you might your employees might say
hey we're starting to hear when we go to
conferences people are talking about us
in a negative way maybe that feeds into
it right there's all kinds of sentiment
analysis stuff on Twitter and Facebook
like all that stuff might feed into this
system that might design what your think
your threat profile is from an external
perspective also how many people know
you can exist how much traffic you get
all those things over time might
actually change it it really depends it
depends on the company depends on how
much instrumentation you got in place
depends on what you can build with
whatever budget you got I'm not saying
this is a completed science by any
stretch I think there's a lot of look a
long way to go but I think this is
definitely an area that we all need to
start spending a lot more time like we
like even just sort of swaging it you're
going to say do you have a firewall is
not the right question to ask it's just
not the right question to ask the
questions are asking are really terrible
if you want to look at probably the best
document I've ever seen not from an
application security perspective at all
but from basically every other question
you should ask it's the bits sig that
used to stand for like the banking
information security something
rather but now it doesn't stand for
anything for some reason anyway a bit
self assessment document it's really
really amazingly good it's like maybe
like a hundred pages of questions long
but it's terrible from an application
security perspective but only says a
wast top ten and unfortunately bad guys
don't care about us top 10 as the sole
way that they can take down a website so
Taylor credence love you all bye bye