welcome to intro to GPG and web of trust
we can get well you said my name's Doug
I'm not gonna mention my last name
either I think called butchering too so
I'm a software developer at Rackspace
and I work on cloud security products
and so what that means is I get to work
with some really talented security folks
and I get to learn some cool stuff they
also make me really paranoid and so
that's sort of where I got interested in
GPG and and sort of what what all they
can do for us so given that this is a
crypto track talk I figured would
introduce usual players and so this is
all a lesson Bob and so Allison wants to
be able to talk to Bob over an insecure
Channel right and some of the things
that that they're gonna be worried about
is I don't want each dropper so I like
it if I'm Alice I don't want anybody to
listen sort of the things that I want to
talk to Bob about so I want to make sure
that that when I send a message to Bob
only Bob can read it I also want to make
sure that that you know if I was Bob
receiving this message I want to make
sure that that yeah the message is
really coming from Alice and it's not
you know some other person pretending to
be Alice and also want to be pretty sure
that the message hasn't been changed in
translator I like maybe Alice try to set
something so many intercepted middle-way
changed out the message and then gave it
to me right so this is sort of the the
things that I'm concerned about when
when trying to talk to somebody else and
so what Bob and Alice can do is I use
GPG because UBD provides a lot of really
cool features that can sort of help us
secure these insecure communication
channels and so one of the one of the
things that gbg can provide us
confidentiality right so these fix
speaks to that concern about preventing
third parties from reading your
communications and so what GPU can
guarantee is that anybody who only the
people who have access to the right keys
are able to read the messages right and
still pretty much like anything in
encryption in the crease up the security
is gonna come down to how secure you can
keep your keys and so if you keep your
keys pretty secure it'll provide kinda
confidentiality for you
it also provides integrity and so with
GPG we can sort of have that assurance
that a message has not been tampered
with in transit and they don't also
provide non-repudiation which i couldn't
find a good picture for that
unfortunately um but it basically means
that once somebody's written a message
they can't deny having written it and so
you can sort of relate this to like
signing a contract in the real world if
you sign a contract with somebody later
on you can't go back and say well no I
that wouldn't really mean this has got
your signature on as soon so GPG sort of
provides us that concept of of having a
signature as well that you can't
repudiate also interesting is you know
saying saying okay well if it sort of
the contrary is true too that you can
you can't produce a message and claim
that I've signed it or that I've sent it
without my signature so there's that and
so once we think about all those three
things together then we can sort of have
this assurance that a message is
authentic right I know that nobody else
has read it except for the people that
are intended to read it I can make sure
that it hasn't been tampered with and
the I can be sure that the person
claiming to said there really really is
who they who they claim to be right oh
and I could do that with GPG because hit
all use this encryption a little hood
right and so I'm gonna just do a quick
little crypto 101 so we're all on the on
the same playing field here and so first
thing I want to talk about as far as
crypto primitives it's gonna be hashing
and so hashing I'm a developer right I
like to think of this it's just some
function I don't care about the
implementation but I basically give it
some input it gives me some output in
you play we're gonna call the plaintext
or the message and the output is gonna
be the digest and so what's interesting
about hashing is that given the same
input it'll always produce that same
digest right and then the digests always
going to be the same size so if weather
you know you give me a huge email huge
file or just a little bit of text the
size of the digest is so it's gonna be
the same
and one of the interesting features of
cryptographically secure hatches is that
even just a little bit of a change in
the message will cost a completely
different digest right and so for
example here we're using a shop 256 as
the encryption or sorry as the hashing
algorithm here and if I search - this
message attack on Pearl Harbor December
7 you can see the hash of this would
produce but changes one character on
that you can see that the hash is
completely different right so this is
one of the tools we're gonna use in GPG
you're sort of guarantee that a message
has to been tampered with right we'll be
able to compute the hash of a message
and then if the hash is different well
then what we expect will know that that
it's been tampered with if is the same
we'll know it's good another for
encryption using GPG is symmetric
encryption and the idea here is that
basically there's there's two functions
right the encryption at the decryption
function they both work with the same
key and that's what makes it a symmetric
encryption thing is that it's the very
same key used for encryption use for
decryption you know give the plaintext
on the key you see the encrypted cipher
text the key and the encrypted cipher
trucks then with the Christian gives you
back the original message so this is
useful when you know you have to encrypt
something for a lot of people or you
sort of give all the people that same
key and then everybody can decrypt this
thing sort of another encryption scheme
that GPG use this is a symmetric
encryption and so the interesting part
here about asymmetric encryption is that
you have a key pair so we start two
different keys that are sort of related
to each other right they have a special
relationship and because of that they're
able to do some pretty neat stuff like
whatever you encrypt it with one key you
can only decrypt with the other doesn't
matter which key you use you know if you
encrypt it with one only the other one
can decrypt it and sort of the inverse
of that is true right like if I'm able
to decrypt something with one key then I
know for sure the other P was used to
encrypt it
that's basically the idea behind public
key encryption right except that here
we're taking those two pieces of this
key and assigning a role to each one so
one of them's going to be our public key
and we're gonna publish this just give
it out to people attach it to your email
put it on business cards whatever public
key can go to everybody and then I want
to keep that other half of the key that
corresponding key pair I'm going to keep
that private and so then what I can do
is that anybody who's got a public key
can encrypt things that only I can
decrypt because I'm the only one who's
got the private key now I mentioned
earlier and an element should I get a
couple times throughout the presentation
like it's really important that you keep
those keys secure right especially you
know anybody who gets a hold of my
private key can effectively pretend to
be me so important that would keep you
safe also interesting is that anything
that I encrypt with my private key
anybody else can decrypt who's got
access to my public key right and so
they might not seem you know interesting
at first just like well why would I want
to crypt something that anybody can
decrypt but the implication here is that
the only person that could have
encrypted it is me because I'm the only
one who's got the private key everybody
with me so far if you got questions by
the way just raise your hand or yell at
me and so once we start combining these
things we can make some really
interesting stuff right and so if we
think about hashing and then asymmetric
encryption and we use those together we
can arrive at this concept of digital
signatures so basically the way the
digital signature works this is how we
would make one how it would sign a
document so I take the document and I
calculate that hash now where that hash
is just going to be that that small
unique number that's going to be
different for every message and then I
take my private key which only I have
and when I take that that digest that
hash I calculated I want to encrypt it
with my private key and then that
effectively becomes my digital signature
and then I can attach that to my message
I want to send out and so that to
everyone and on the other side whenever
somebody receives that what they can do
is they can take that this is an
right they can take the message and
calculate a hash themselves of the
message they receive now remember we
talked about hashing if you have to say
messaged you only know about the same
hash or at the same digest sober site
not take that message I received
calculated my own hash of what I
received then I take that digital
signature and I use the public key of
the person that sent it to me to decrypt
it
there are because I'm using the public
key the only thing that could have been
used to encrypt that it's the private
key the corresponding private key and
then what that'll give me is to digest
that the person who wrote the message
arrived at and what I can do then is
take that message that I decrypt it and
the message or the digest I calculated
myself and I compare the two and if the
two are the same then the implication of
that is that the message is not being
changed right it only has not been
changed but the person who wrote it it's
also in possession of the private key
that matches that public key everybody
with me so far possible and so the
important part here obviously is the key
sort of the operation is we don't need
to get into the details so that like the
GPG tool will be able to manage that for
us but the key management is it's a
pretty important part of G GPG one of
the sort of complaints about it is that
it makes me maybe makes you manage too
many keys right so if we go back to
think about Alice and Bob well if I'm
Alice I'm gonna have you know I was
thinking my private key that I'm keeping
secret and I've got my public key too
and then I want to send a message to Bob
and I want to set this in as an
encrypted message right and so for this
to work I'm gonna mean Bob's public key
right I'm gonna need their public key so
that I can encrypt something so that
only they can decrypt it because only a
have the matching private key but if I
also want to talk to Carlos in addition
to Bob I'm gonna need Carlos's public
key too as a matter of fact I'm gonna
need the public key for every single
person that I want to communicate with
via GPG and so you can sort of think of
GPG as the key management axe bit of it
it's like a like a big contact list or
rolodex or so
like that we're constantly keeping these
public keys from people that you're
communicating with and now there's a
couple of ways that you can get those
you know they can send them to you
directly there's a couple of file
servers public file servers where people
upload their public keys and so if we
talk about gbg keys and though it's sort
of the way that we're gonna think about
them so they're gonna be stored locally
and some database and the GPG yeah I'm
mostly going to talk about the
command-line tool with some a developer
and I like the command line but there is
some nice user interfaces for this if
you're not comfortable with the what
like a mainline so one of the options I
have here is to list all the keys and
this is going to show me basically every
one of my contacts for which I've
acquired the public key
I'm also it's also going to keep track
of my private key or many private keys
some people choose to have more than one
maybe you have a project or something
like that that you want to dedicate a
key to so those are all going to be
listed there also the key your private
keys are going to be protected by
passphrase now it's important that you
make this really hard to guess cuz in
the event that somebody gets ahold of
your private key the file and I remember
the private key is still gonna be a file
on disk somebody gets ahold of that the
only thing that's gonna prevent them
from using it it's gonna be this pass
race right every time you use your key
you have to punch in this race gate pass
race
keys also have a unique fingerprint it's
a really long number and this is how you
can sort of coordinate with people to
make sure that you're talking about the
same key this fingerprint is gonna be
unique for everybody who's using GPG
right and there's also a lot of people
call a key ID which is the last eight
digits of the fingerprint now this is
sort of a shorthand kind of way of doing
stuff locally it can be dangerous no
because if there's some attack that you
can actually fake this key ID and so
when you're talking about you know it's
changing or verifying keys you want to
make sure they use that full fingerprint
the GPG key itself is actually going to
consist of a whole lot of cryptography
keys we don't really need to dive down
into what the keys actually are stuff
like that unless you want to but
basically when I talk about you know
your G B G key is actually a collection
of a bunch of different keys there's the
key pair of this used for signing
there's a separate key pair that's used
for encryption and you can actually I
out of the box you'll get two keys not
signing an encryption but you can also
add other sub keys if maybe you want a
different key for encryption depending
on the email address that you want to
use or whatever and one last thing that
that your GPG is gonna have attached to
it it's a user ID or UID this is
basically going to be a legal name that
you want to use this will be you know
usually your given name so my my key
you'll have my legal name on there
comment which is just whatever it you
can think of to help people identify
your key or identify US you and there's
some email address and this is how it's
gonna sort of tie in to your email
system and stuff like that is you'll be
able to identify these skis by the email
address that's attached done I mean
actually uhm if you list out the
fingerprint here you see I'm referring
to a key idea for my own key and this is
the fingerprint right here and so if I
was to to want to communicate with one
of you guys I would give you my entire
key fingerprint and then it would be
your responsibility that when you
download the key verify that those
fingerprints match you know so see here
this is show me my public key if you
were if we were looking at a private key
here it would say SEC these are all
options of what the different actual
like cryptography keys underneath are
you can see here I've got my master key
up here to sub keys down here now
getting to sort of what this means here
in a little bit and actually you have
like four user IDs on my key I've got
four different email addresses that I
use and so I use the same key for every
single one a lot of people like to use
separate keys for different
versus it's really up to you on your
comfort level with reusing the key so
the first thing you're going to want to
do well at first you're going to want to
install GPG and so most Linux
distributions have that out of the box
for Mac there's a project called GPG
tools that you can download and install
and I'll come with the command-line
client as well as the email plugin for
Linux for email you can use Thunderbird
with a plugin called at nick mail these
are all plug-in to to the command line
system and the database and all that
that's all shared and so usually like
when people get excited about gbg you
want to go try this will happen to me
like when I go make my key and then it
starts asking you questions and then you
don't really know what's going on and so
the first thing that it asks you is like
what kind of key do you want now this
relates to that the actual crypto keys
underneath there's a whole of different
options I'm not going to get into the
details I'm just going to recommend that
everybody do RSA and RSA in newer
versions of GP G this is the default
you've got a little bit older build you
got to make sure that that you're
choosing the option to have RSA in RSA
this is going to be for the master key
and the sub key but do you say you don't
really want to and it's the key space is
too small nowadays to be really really
recommend it so if you want to key this
gonna last you good five ten years my
recommendation is pick RSA RSA next
thing it's going to ask you this for it
for a key length basically uh the idea
here is the more bits you have the
harder it would be for somebody to guess
the key now also there's the trade-off
of efficiency there so if you pick like
the absolute highest bit key possible
and that's gonna make it difficult for
people who have to verify like they'll
have to do more work they have an older
computer I might take awhile it's a
trade-off my recommendation would be to
do uh 4096 as you can see that default
is 2048 which is currently considered
secure but I want my key to last you
know get 5 10 years so bump it up 4096
that would be my recommendation it'll
ask you then about X
it would be a good idea to set your key
to expire you don't really know whether
you wanted to experience it this is zero
or set it to not expire you can always
change this later so don't you know
don't think about it too much like do I
really want to expire it's gonna be you
know it's gonna last a while it don't
matter you can change it later and you
can always make a new key later on after
that it's gonna ask you for generating
this user ID it's gonna ask you for your
real name
now I recommended you actually use your
real name because it won't it'll help
people that want to communicate with you
they can't get ahold of you right away
that's for you email address and then a
comment just a helpful comment to help
people find you and then it'll you know
summarize the user ID in that format
that I talked about earlier once you say
okay then it's gonna ask you for your
password
live is gonna be real important that you
know you think of a good passphrase also
the safest place for this is in your
head like don't write it down on a piece
of paper next to a thumb drive that has
your key that that'd be bad and like I
mentioned earlier if somebody was able
to compromise that key database and
includes your private key the only thing
that's going to prevent them from using
it it's gonna be this passphrase and so
at the end of that well you know we can
print out the fingerprint and this is
what we would we would have it's
considerably smaller than mine is this a
brand new one as you can see here we're
looking at a public key 4096 here is
gonna be the bit length of the key so
here we can we can sort of verify that
it did make the correct size the are
there is going to be for RSA so whatever
you check on your key just make sure
that are is there for RSA a fingerprint
this fingerprint is going to correspond
to your master key and it's actually
going to be the same no matter like
whether you add sub keys or remove them
or expire them over time to fingerprints
that we're going to change so this is
the thing that you can get you know
tattooed on your arm to get the people
and stuff like that lynnie as we can see
here I've also got a sub key like I
mentioned earlier the master key is used
for signing
subkeys for encryption Sookie it's also
4096 also RSA and this is the
fingerprint of the sub key we don't
really use this much for anything that
I'm aware of anyway and then one more
thing what's sort of more security
feature you can do is create a
revocation certificate and put this in a
nice place a revocation certificate
basically tells people like this key is
no longer valid and the reason you might
want to generate this upfront and then
just keep it in a safe place is that in
the event that your laptop that that was
the only laptop that had your key or
something like that blows up the
revocation certificate if you have us if
you have one already created and stored
will serve tell people like hey this key
is no good anymore
I've actually got a buddy who had two
really nice keys that he gotten signed
by a bunch of people and stuff like that
and then his wiped his hard drive
because he thought he had backed them up
and he had not so his keys are gone
forever and they still looked like valid
keys because he never made a revocation
certificate for those so this is
important to have not necessary just a
little extra security measure in the
event that you lose your key yes so -
would you be able to recreate the key
with your passphrase no no the
passphrase is really there just to
unlock the key yeah so then also so now
that we have a key we're gonna want to
share it one way to share it is to
export the key and here export is it's
only gonna export the public key right
this is not not gonna share my secret
queue of anybody there is an export
secret keys command if you want to back
it up back back up a secret one that is
armored here is just telling it I want
to use s key armor so it's just going to
look like plaintext on the file and then
I give it my key ID that I want to back
up and I'm just piping all that out to a
file now this is a file that I can start
giving people right doc this is my
public key here you go
whenever you're trying to email me like
use this public key to do encryption and
signing and all that good stuff
another way to share your keys upload it
to a key server another so few of these
and they all I think sync with each
other and stuff like that the one that
I've seen people or the one that the
people that got me in a GPG were you
seeing was this MIT server a bun - Scott
one - that they use I'm know if I
mentioned a lot of distributions use
this to verify their packages when you
download your packages and so stuff like
a fedora and no bun - will have their
own key servers for for hosting and
stuff now the key servers are
interesting because they're right only
and so once you upload your key to the
server it's there forever and so my
buddy that lost the keys his keys are on
a key server and they're gonna stay
there forever unfortunately for him yes
no because he didn't make a revocation
certificate so when you have a
revocation certificate you want to keep
that in a safe place right so like on a
thumb drive on a safe or something like
that
and when you're ready to revoke the key
then you would you would push that
revocation certificate up to a server
and then the server would correlate the
two and then show that kiyose that's
being revoked yes and so once we've had
our key once we've shared it we can
actually start doing some pretty neat
stuff we can start signing our email
this is something that I started doing
once I started to GPG because I don't
really need anybody else to talk to to
sign my own email and the idea behind
this is that people that are then
receiving my email so I talking a lot of
developer mailing lists and stuff like
that the if they want to they can take
the time to calculate this hash on my
message and then calculate the signature
and verify that it's fine if you've got
a nice GUI like gbg tools for mac which
is this tiny picture up here and you
probably can't see um it'll have like
little status bars right so if you
receive something with the signature
will have a nice green check mark there
that tells you that the signature was
good it's got a signature that you don't
have the key for you'll have a little
yellow question
you know hey this might be good but
maybe not
and then if for some reason you get a
message with a signature that doesn't
match it'll highlight that in red until
you hate don't trust this email the
signature on this is invalid GPG tools
the way it does that is it attaches a
file when you send your email so people
are receiving your email they'll just
see this little attachment maybe try to
double click in will make sense to them
in thunder or what am I trying to say
thunder thunder very thunder the email
client with an egg mail it actually does
all the signing in plain text sort of
like this and so um I think an email
does actually give you a little star as
sparse as well but you can then also
take this plain text and sort of
manually calculate these things yourself
you can also um start sending your files
and this is something that we do with
OpenStack releases right like I'm making
a tarball of this software package and I
want to I want to assure you that the
tarball that you're downloading is in
fact the one that the developers made
the way we do that is by signing the
actual file right and so there's there's
a few different options for signing the
one that I like to use is this detached
signature and then you give it the name
of the file as so what that will do is
it'll read that entire file as input and
then give it the signature for the file
as a separate file right and then you
can put both of those up in your website
to download people would download both
the file and the signature and then on
their side run this verify and then
given that they have your public key
then it will tell them that you know the
signature was good and then you can go
ahead with the installation of the
software because you know the software
hasn't been tampered with you could do
this too so if you wanted to send uh you
know sent pictures to somebody I don't
know why you'd want to sign a picture
you probably want a encrypting you'd
also start to encrypt files for yourself
this is something you can do without
needing somebody else's key
and the way you can do that is to say
encrypt give it a file name and then - R
is the parameter for the recipient
normally here you'd put the key ID of
the person you're emailing or maybe the
email address of the person you're
you're sending this to what if you email
it to yourself right like that's that's
effectively encrypting it for yourself
later on you can use your your private
key to decrypt it and so this something
I do for like a Google two-factor post
you know the backup codes or whatever
save them when I'm around plain text
file encrypted with my gbg key and then
I can throw that encrypted file on
Dropbox or whatever I don't care
nobody that doesn't have a the only
person that can decrypt it / Summa Bleus
me because only I have the private key
and then decryption pretty
straightforward just that chef's decrypt
GPG will actually read everything it
needs from that GPG file and then it'll
output that to the plain text file you
can also start encrypting email dbg
tools when you start writing an email
and it notices that you have the private
or the public key for the person that's
receiving it it'll automatically encrypt
it for you so this terrible picture up
here is what it would look like in Gmail
right I like this an encrypted email I
received in Gmail is just a bunch of
garbage if I look at it on my email
client that has the correct keys to
decrypt it I can actually see it there
the actual message over here the little
status tells me that it's signed
correctly you buy that email address is
expecting and then it's also been
encrypting everybody with me so far
looking pretty cool awesome so the last
thing I wanted to talk about is the web
address right
so I've talked a lot about you know
exchanging keys and and it's pretty easy
to do if you if you can talk to the
person or if you know the person but
it's very difficult to do if you're
trying to email somebody that you've
never met before and you don't know for
a fact like which key is theirs so I
mentioned those key servers the public
see servers are write only but they're
open to anybody right so if I wanted to
send a message to like I don't know
George butcher or whatever 500 check on
like Easter or there's going to be like
65 70
Franky's with that name right so how do
I know which is the correct file and so
GP G's answer today is called a web of
trust and sort of the their definition
of trust here is really simple is when
you trust or in GPG trust is when you
sign somebody else's public key and
that's light it's wrong that's the
public key you sign and it basically
means like hey I've verified this person
claims this who or is who they claim to
be right this is why it's important to
use your legal name on your user ID for
your key this is usually the way this
works is some you can ask somebody hey
would you sign my key sure let me see
your key okay it says here you're Doug
so-and-so let me see some government ID
or some other kind of proof that that
sort of ties you the person to that name
that's on the key and if that's
sufficient for me then I can attach a
signature to their public key and then
push that up to the key server and soon
um all right how to get your key sign
you can get it friends coworkers
these things called key signing parties
usually that's a bunch of G G B G people
that get together for the sole purpose
of verifying each other's ideas and
signing each other's keys that's a
really good way to get a whole bunch of
signatures so the way you sign the key
obviously I already mentioned first you
check their ID make sure that their name
matches whatever their official ID
they're presenting to you if you want to
be real thorough you should email that
email address that's listed on the key
to make sure that that's the email
address that they can receive email from
and then you just say you know G B G
sign key give it that key ID and then G
B G will go through the process of
creating those signatures and so here's
an example of listing the signatures in
a key right this is the public key for a
buddy of mine Igor that's running around
here somewhere
and you can see here he's got a public
key 4096 RSA that's his name is Igor and
he's got I guess this comment is this
IRC handle or something like that
excatly email address there then I see a
bunch of signatures now the signatures
are going to be you know it's each seek
entry here and I can see here that he's
got a bunch of signatures from people
that I don't know so those don't really
matter to me interesting one here is the
signature that I myself put on there and
so one cool thing about signing somebody
else's key is that because a signature
is only valid if the thing hasn't been
tampered with then you can if you check
your own signature at a later day you
know that that key has not been tampered
with also interesting is uh he's got a
signature by Tyler now I've met Tyler
one of the gbgt signing party he said I
know he's a pretty trustworthy guy and I
know he's real thorough when he checks
for IDs and so if I didn't personally
know Igor well I probably wouldn't have
signed his thing but if I if I saw that
Tyler had signed it then I'm more
inclined to believe that this key does
indeed belong to him because I know
Tyler I know Tyler wouldn't just sign
anybody's key and because he signed
Igor's Keith and I'm pretty sure that
this isn't the eboard scheme you know so
um verify the signatures right so I have
all the public keys for all these people
and so when I run the check signatures
it's only going to show me the
signatures for the public keys I
collected the little hash van here is
what tells you that that's a valid
signature um one of the features that
that you can activate with this is a
managing trust writing so you just sort
of set the threshold of how much you
want to trust people and so if I met
somebody at a key signing party then you
know there are at least interested so
maybe I trust them marginally like I
give this people of three and the way
you do that is you know you say edit key
this person's public key and then I'll
give you a little g PG prompt and there
you say trust and then these are your
options so you just assign them a number
and so what the software can do is
automatically like sort of add up these
things of like well you know if it's a
new key that I've never seen before but
it's at least got three signatures from
people
trust then I'm more inclined to trust
that key that and seen before the set
all makes sense that's naughty awesome
and then sort of the last thing I wanted
to talk on is this is sort of like an
iterative process like this is this
something you've got to continuously do
is refresh your keys and so you want to
get into the habit of you know every
couple of weeks or maybe every month or
so
refresh your keys from the key server
and so what this will do is it'll go out
to the key servers and pull down any new
signature so might have it added so I'm
so important you do this because that's
how you would pull down revocation
certificates that may tell you that you
know something spin
something's been revoked and stuff like
that you know that's all I have I'll
distract you guys with the relevant xkcd
saying you don't ask me questions no I'm
just kidding you can ask questions so a
lot of people recommend that you ask the
person how they want to receive your
signature some people are some people
don't like having their keys pushed to
public key servers so they might ask you
to just email the file after you've
signed it so it's yeah I would ask the
person whose key to you're signing what
their preferred method is but you could
you can always push it up yourself it's
just some some people consider that
route your signature yep that's correct
yes
G B D and just CIMMYT yeah so it's a
real bummer that G B D tools does not
work with you simony I haven't actually
kept up with with a mailing list to see
sort of what they're doing I believe
that it's only the email client that
broke for me anyway like that the
command-line client still worked
yeah so I haven't had problems with the
command-line tool but the mail plugin
they break for me so I'm really hoping
that they're working on it
fingers crossed but Thunderbird does
work on lucema D so if you you know if
you need a back-up plan right now
check out Thunderbird not currently um
so do encrypt on the browser is kind of
dangerous and I couldn't explain any why
because you know my security expert
friends are the ones that tell me that
um but I did hear a news feed that both
Google and Yahoo are working on some
sort of encryption scheme for their
further email and they're um they're
both basing it on G B G right um also
you know if you if the only thing you
have is a gmail account you can just set
up like an IMAP client I just installed
you know just I saw GBD on her claim but
I won't plug into Gmail directly
not necessarily because it's really easy
to fake email right and so you could you
know maybe you could like you without
gvg you couldn't sure the email was
valid to then start doing gbg the
semak's that's like a chicken and egg
problem right yeah so gpgc
you're explaining you know how it's
really good things like non-repudiation
and apprentices but it's not good or not
really back it's not good for anonymity
so we still have this really hard
problem of we don't know how to spend
anonymous email I was wondering like if
you've looked in like to the mixin
networks at all I you know I've never
I've never had to send anonymous single
via GBD sanera not not familiar with
that yeah yeah I don't know how you'd go
about that but yeah that's there's
definitely a problem with GPG right like
it's not all rainbows and unicorns so
another criticism that I hear it's like
it's really hard to use tough to manage
keys which I mean the fact that I have
to sit here for 40 minutes to explain
how to get into it like sort of speaks
to that also web of trust like you
mentioned a lot of people are concerned
that it leaks information right so if I
go to a key signing party you get a
bunch of signatures like people will
know that I always had a key signing
party with all these people and so
there's there's definitely some
criticisms to it too awesome well thank
you guys hope you're on if you uh you
have any questions