hi God knows how this is going to go all
right so I want to start by thanking the
last cow guys and I really appreciate
coming out here I've I have personally
tried for the last three years to come
out over and over again and the world
hates me which I'm sure you'll see by my
total disdain when I talk but it does it
hates me in a lot of ways and every time
I've try and come out there was some
type of fire somebody died or I mean
it's just it's been crazy so I'm like
really really blessed that I could
finally come out hang out here I want to
thank you guys for sitting around being
wicked attentive and you know really
enjoying it because it'll be boring ah
you know when you get asked to do a
keynote on stuff you always got to think
like am I going to go do a tech talk and
then that's just going to fit into the
slot am I going to talk about something
kind of the outside and hope that I
conspire you to do something and you
know I'm just more honored to be here so
that I get to hang out and talk with you
guys right and for me when I give talks
I don't really like talking at you so
you can hoot yell and do whatever the
hell you want I'm good with that okay so
finally I'm here we I'm Chris that's me
in a bunch formats um man oh I even had
a laser on this thing ah that was
hilarious that was Nancy Reagan slipper
um and I was guilty in Nancy Reagan um
my credentials there's nothing on that
slide doesn't really matter I'm just
somebody talking okay that's how most
people think of me pain the ass I've
been around for a while I just tell lies
for a living you know people call me bad
words I'm kind of bitter but i'm still
in my job because i love it or just
because i want to make my house payment
um my give a meter
it's currently broken so by the way I
want to make this kind of informal so if
I swear and that offends people know
that I'm not doing I just I'm from the
east coast right like that's just how I
grew up it's not i'm really not that
poorly edge imeem I'm poorly educated
but I'm not that poorly educated that I
have to use the compensate for things i
just used because it's part of my
vernacular all right work for a company
called laura's we do application
assessment code review stuff we do some
incident response stuff here and there
you know we go for risk assessments
we've done fun you know things on the
physical security side of the house by
the way anybody ever seen hacker strip
yeah anybody else who hasn't seen hacker
strip like you're doing it wrong go find
it please fund it it's awesome comic
books about what we do is a way to reach
a larger audience outside of this room
where all of us bitch and cry together
right like I'd rather have other people
mission crime with us and be like oh
it's not that bad you know like
yesterday somebody died on my job site
like yesterday I couldn't get into a
machine you know like like we need a
little context in our lunch and it'd be
really helpful we do pen testing
you know just red teaming we do all
sorts of other stuff yay I love me
whatever there's any of the stuff that I
do matter I don't know probably not okay
on the same page so where do we start
with all of this what am I going to
actually talk about opposed to just
showing Liam slides nothing I'm gonna
just show me meds so when I when I
started thinking about what I was going
to present I had a whole presentation
made mr. robert hansen over here is a
prick okay and he posted something that
made me connect to kind of how I felt
about my job and it made me ask a lot of
questions to myself about my job which
turn made me ask a lot of questions
about all of these talks that I've given
around what the hell do they mean and
where we at why am I still given some of
the same talks why are people given the
same talks and what does that mean about
our industry so I wanted to kind of
start with where we are today right like
how did we get to the spot that we're in
so we're in Austin right
but in order to really figure out like
where we're at conference wives and
people who are sitting here experience
wise we need to kind of know where we
came from right so quick history of how
we got here at least in my opinion first
anybody know what that is 1623 it's
called a pass colon it's the first
computer we had we've been doing this
for a long time the whole computering
like I don't even computer good we've
been doing this for a wicked long time
right then then what we had other adding
machines right we had an enigma we
didn't even know what it was it was an
enigma right so we're doing cryptography
we had these great computers right so
this is the precursor to the god of all
computers which was Enoch anybody know
what a NOC is right one of the one of
the first computers that has ever been
built all right and this is way before
we had transistors and stuff and IBM
came into the game to take over the
world and be big evil and then we made
transistors right and from there AT&T
labs developed those more yeah we used
to put wood blocks on things because it
used to cool it how cool is that you
know the whole halt and catch fire thing
was real because there was wood in it
that's a real thing right and then we
started speculating okay what's going to
happen with these computer things right
what what is a computer well this is
this is a computer it's a typewriter but
that's a computer you could bet your
sweet tell X operator it is ok you know
and then then we figured out we could do
word processing and actually have stuff
on the screen and then from there we got
these things called modems how cool is
that we can start talking to other
people then we got hard drives we start
storing data that we were creating on
these cool typewriters right ok well
then what oh well I can go chat with my
family wait a second you mean instead of
just taking forever to download the porn
i could talk about it i want a computer
right and then instead of this point to
point piece that we had we got this
thing called email right the UDP of all
communication right i could just send
some mountain saying i got an email you
know I don't even know what it is but
it's at my desk right and then Apple
came into the game right and they made
all these things easy for people and a
little bit creepy
right but but really they made it
prettier and and and we became a lot
stronger right we became totally
addicted to this interaction that we
have interaction with machines
interaction with other people
interaction with this thing that we
called the internet right now the
internet started off by just being like
a little point-to-point network for you
know the government in universities to
share information figure out how we
could like bomb people better and you
know what we could do to get place you
know information from one place to
another so we didn't have to hire these
huge trucks which you know I'll take
some credit for the worst thing I've
ever done in my life by breaking an RFC
I don't think I can get can I get sued
for breaking an arm see your son anybody
a lawyer anybody know good lawyers cuz I
might need one after this um but we had
these boxes and we couldn't get
information places so when I was it
sprint we had to transfer a couple
terabytes somewhere which back then was
a really really big deal so we had to
hire all these big trucks to go move
data tape somewhere and drive them down
to Texas from Kansas City and instead
because I had control of an edge router
I just routed 10 dot over the internet
and it worked great yeah you can do that
if you own the edge wasn't necessarily
good but what we went to is we started
having all of these types of networks
getting more and more connected right
because people were sick of having to
truck their data places and then from
there we started getting all these neat
bulletin boards and from bulletin boards
we started to get chat services and make
it available to the mass populace right
so now you didn't even have to be as
nerdy you could just roll up on the
prodigy and then bam you were interweb
right you were on the magic internet and
you got there and it was so cool
right it was so awesome you could just
internet all over the place and find all
this data and then there are search
engines that came up and search engines
were so awesome because now instead of
having to find the stuff yourself and
logging into all of these computers
which you may or may not have had access
to but it told you how to get access
usually now you had somebody who
searched all that for you so you can get
right to the data that you want like how
cool is that we went from a wood block
that did nothing more than punch of key
and output a piece of paper to like
being able to find data anywhere right
trying to obsolete the library by
creating such an information-sharing
piece and it totally took off right we
went into the web from web 102 web 202
web whatever the hello we are now right
still your dad we started using all
these social media things that we can
interact with people real time all the
time every time you know I need to know
when somebody pooped I have to know it
you know and if you're too busy doing
other things like playing a racing game
on your phone while you're pooping then
your toilet can tweet to me and tell me
that you just use it you know like if
you're taking off your bra there's a
there's a twitter app for that that's
crazy right and then we started showing
everybody our identity which was even
crazier now we went from sharing
information to sharing with people
directly to like screw it I just want
everybody to know who I am all right I
don't care where you're from it's like
those restaurants where you have like
it's it's Jim's world's famous chicken
like really can I talk to somebody in
Bangalore and they'll be like oh you
went to Jim's no it's not world-famous
but we're becoming world famous we push
our identity everywhere just so that we
can be world famous right and then it
gets worse we just start puking our
information everywhere we can write our
information is absolutely everywhere we
allow people like Google and Yahoo and
Microsoft and God knows where ever else
to be like the psychedelic Jesus of our
existence right they get to see
everything
everywhere every time they get to
control your existence and but for the
small small price of you being the
product you are now the product nothing
is free if it is free you are not to
consumer you're the product right you're
the thing that people sell and really
they're just big janitors right all
they're doing is kind of cleaning up the
so that we can expose ourselves to
other people so we're left with this
issue right we're left with kind of
being the homeless people because we
wanted to be homeless because we wanted
to be everywhere all at the same time
but then something else happened at the
same time all that was going on we made
these big bounds and what we were doing
and other people came up with wait a
second so that's what it does right
that's what this internet and computer
thing does but what can it do like what
what does it have the ability to do and
so you know ninjas pop up and these the
idea of a hacker comes together right
now the idea from a hacker comes
together comes from MIT but even further
back than that I mean lady Lovelace Lady
ADA right one of the first programmers
that ever existed now I don't care man
woman child really awesome but peace
whatever else I mean that's that's a
hundred-plus years ago people were doing
programming to try and get ready for
where we're at today so all right well
just like everything that gets created
there's a good and bad right we have to
have the yin yang of the world so
there's people that as this is be that
it's being created there's people trying
to break it trying to see what else it
can do you know that hacking and
exploitation literally goes all the way
back to the Enigma and all the way back
before that to Enoch like that's crazy
to think that we've been doing this
stuff for this long and knowing that
these things occur yet we're at we're at
today hey we have this o day
right that's what oh day is Oh day is
not oh I found another cross-site
scripting that nobody else has on yahoo
that's not oh day oh day is finding
something that has never been found if
you tell me that there's another buffer
overflow in the product that is not
owned a buffer overflows been identified
before got it you're just applying it to
another application that is not zero net
right so back then collaboration was a
cool thing it was cool because there was
other people because there was such a
small community people who used you know
people who computer so when people were
computer they would computer together
and they would learn things and it was
really great and these societies started
coming together right people started
sharing some of this information
together and it was so awesome and once
the sharing started and you had the
ability to connect to each other this
hit the fan totally
I mean it hit the fan we started having
conferences like ccc where we could get
together in a room together and all talk
and share what we were doing this wasn't
talking at people this was a whole bunch
of people who computer dan I computer
and I'm like cool i'm going to show you
this neat computery thing that i did and
everybody's like whoa we could take that
and do something else and you know three
days later there was products made there
was scripts all over the place there's
people building new operating systems
because the stuff they wanted to do
couldn't even be done yet but they were
like but we could do it right we started
making her own gangs because hey why not
the human existence requires us to
compete with people we can't just accept
you know oh yeah they're as good as me
I'm as good as them oh no no no no no my
clicks cooler than your click right you
have all of these different people that
start putting it out and in the best
part is a lot of these groups started
putting out things that were available
to the public why because they've wanted
their gang to be bigger they wanted
other people to understand and get
enrolled in this cool thing that they're
doing not just allowing the computer to
do what it was supposed to do but what
can it do what are the other things that
can do right we have these awesome
groups that we're sitting out there
hanging out together every single day
just going what else could we make it do
you have an idea awesome let's all get
together and figure out how we can make
that thing happen right we love to share
I mean we love to share so much that my
whole life of coming into computers and
coming into the internet and security
and everything else was really built on
me trying to get into porn sites because
they were sharing and they didn't always
share the log on so we moved from some
of that and then we realized okay look
not everybody in this world has the
financial means or ability or the
lock-picking skills to get to a computer
so we went back and started making some
of these periodicals right all right if
you don't have a computer you could
still read about it if you don't have
internet access you could still read
about it and learn about it and we can
get you there today that's totally
different
we went as far as having manifestos
anybody remember this hacker's handbook
there's a manifesto what other group of
i mean i don't think the Crips have a
manifesto though they might have just
that's my nan crip knowing part I don't
know I don't even know what that means
but the manifest that was pretty clear
my crime is that of curiosity I am a
hacker and this is my manifesto you may
stop this individual but you can't stop
us all that's something real interesting
to think about in the terms of today not
talking about hacker from the negative
connotation that the news has built for
us but just in somebody who's curious
you can't stop my curiosity now granted
we all can't dress up like a monkey and
wear yellow coat and you know do all
those other things that be curious
george but at the very least we can
continue to evolve our curiosity we can
get together and have camp right anybody
ever been to like CCC camp no and tour
camp yeah and hackers on a plane and all
right there's there's times where you
can go spend a whole week I mean I know
that sucks like not all of us smell real
good some people like hi genes an issue
but that's okay because they were
working you know we we got so good at
sharing information while all this
interneting and computering was going on
that we even threw funerals when stuff
died right do anybody know how Def Con
got started how and why because platinum
that was going down and everybody wanted
to get together and be like damn how are
we going to talk now how cool is that
now it's like the biggest freakin
hacking conference on earth and it was
because we were just kind of thrown a
funeral for things going away cuz we
needed that interaction because we
wanted to keep sharing right that's my
tangent of where we're at what I really
wanted to talk about was while this is
going on now why why are we so lost in
my opinion in our industry as a whole
I think one was how glamorized some of
the stuff has been getting right it's
cool to hack into something all right I
don't know what's cool about that but
sure I mean whatever if it gets you
chicks or guys or whatever you want to
go for it money money is a big problem
always right money fuels you to do some
things that you may not want to do and
then you get attached to it and you're
like wait a second i'm making a hard
grand here i need to make 150 grand
because i want to buy a boat well now
that i bought my boat my boat breaks
down a little time and i need to make
two hundred grand to even keep the boat
running all of you have had a boat you
know what's up well someone so grabs a
really cool car well I want one of those
cars I can do that so now I'm going to
continue to force myself into this thing
and we get so worried about this market
that's out there in the attachment to
this market in the industry space that
exists around it that we've polarized
ourselves we have people who are in it
for the money we have people who are in
it for the lulz those people aren't in
it for the lulz they're in it for self
edification there in it so that somebody
could paying notice to them right they
just want to hear someone say their name
that's why they're in it that's not most
people who do it to laugh about it
laughs about it to themselves and move
on they don't publish it everywhere
right the vanity of that is what exists
we have people who are doing it on the
defense side and on the offense side
right agreed yes no we have defense and
offense agree but we all came from the
same place so how is their defense and
offense how is how we this against each
other right this is how I feel every
time I think about our industry right
every single time I'm like what happened
we went from really really digging each
other and really being interested in
what the other person saying to like
well I'm bigger than them so forget them
in their ideas and that that kills me
because we went from this I love crap
collaboration and I
love sharing information to people to
this this is our motto now and I hate
that it hurts me and I'm not saying that
this is our motto between everybody in
the room I'm saying this is our motto is
an industry that's why a lot of people
from outside of our industry don't come
to our conferences right they're afraid
of us they think that we've polarized so
much that they can't even talk to us I
mean have you guys ever had that issue
where it's like oh you know you're kind
of two technical we need to put the
sales guy on the phone to translate yeah
I mean that's a big problem and and I
want to figure out and everything that I
was going to talk about and all this
other talk that I was gonna do and I was
like oh I can make this cool talk about
epic and I'm not a knapsack guy but I
was gonna make a talk about which I had
pretty much done about how oh well you
know you can do collateralize damage
with stuff and I can go and I can see
everybody which this is all public ish
knowledge like if you use taleo which is
one of the biggest job site engines on
earth right to like hire people to get
resumes and stuff you know taleo
requires you to only use flash 10 you
can't go past that otherwise it doesn't
work so then you know I was going to
talk about oh here's how you could list
out all the site find what size people
using find out those site requirements
send them exploits that you know that'll
work because hey AB sex awesome but I
couldn't do it because Robert laid that
damn post piece of and so I'm like
all right now I have to talk about how I
feel about the industry and where the
hell we're going to go so what do we do
I mean am I just ranting my just a
bitter person or like do you guys see
any of these things do you see that our
industry fights itself instead of moving
forward and we're so busy fighting
ourselves that we're forgetting our
goals do any of you guys see that yeah
word I need to hear people say yeah
because sometimes I don't believe it
sometimes I believe people just don't
see this and I'm the asshole in the room
who's yelling about it and I like dude
shut up show me another cat
picture like it's easier to listen to
that than your all right so
ways that we can fix it and go through
it because if you're gonna give a talk
you have to have call to actions right
that's the PowerPoint book that I read
oh I didn't read it I'm like all right
my first problem is offensive security
versus defensive security okay I I have
trouble with things sometimes because
I'm not real smart I didn't go to
college well I don't even computer good
I'm like con about that quick but I use
the dictionary a lot when I can't figure
things out and I couldn't figure out why
offensive security and defensive
security were different can't figure it
out so I go into the dictionary
offensive calling someone to feel deeply
hurt upset or angry granted some people
in our industry that's their goal if
that is your goal at least be clear
about your intentions like I don't need
to hear you trolling somebody for the
sake of trolling and then having someone
else listen to that conversation that's
not in our industry and being like why
should I ever listen to a security
person all they do is bitch at each
other you know that's why we don't get a
lot of traction because we bitch at each
other so much that our reputation is
horrible and you know that our
reputation is horrible why because there
aren't a whole lot of jobs at every
single company having security people
because they don't think we provide
value why because we're too busy
bitching at people instead of making
things go forward so offensive okay
actively aggressive attacking really
anybody in actively aggressive attacker
oh now you're not going to say it but
before if I was given a hacking talk
you'd be like hell yeah all right at
hard I throw down oh now it's different
an attacking military campaign okay I'll
accept that one sure
but are any of you military hackers I
mean if you are you don't have three
you're not gonna raise your hand but we
know who you are you look like a bud we
can walk it it's fine you know like you
have a better haircut we're shaggy I get
it but but there's nothing about that
that fits a pen tester or a knapsack
person or somebody who does code review
or even somebody who does exploit
development none of that fits all right
security what security a state from
being free of danger or threat cool a
private police force are you the private
police force you have to think about
those words that makes a difference
words actually make a difference they
may not to us but they do three a thing
deposited reply is a guarantee of
fulfillment okay like a bond or a
certificate of assisting credit I don't
really know if we do any of those things
what we're trying to do is number one
inspire a state of being free from
danger or threat we're trying to be the
ones doing that right if you're a pen
tester and you say you're an attacker
you're full of attackers have
malicious intent so if you're a pen
tester you can't have malicious intent
you also have to connect with the fact
that you're doing this to make a final
report that gives people recommendations
on how to get better right that's what
we do in the testing world that's what
we do a lot of times when we're finding
bugs when we're looking for issues we're
not doing it just for the sake of
finding it and doing it and then just
trouncing someone laughing at them as
they go out of business I mean that's
not a very profitable model I mean I
guess the NSA has that model but you
know they're different right but most of
us don't really operate that way most of
us are doing it with the good intentions
and rightfully so of making fleeces more
secure now guess what defense defense
the action
defending or resisting attack right or
the case being presented by behalf of
the party being accused of suit a
lawsuit or being accused or sued by a
pen tester right because they think
they're an attacker or one or more
defendants in a counselor right you're
the council who protects your company
you're defending it but do you guys see
where I'm going that the offensive
security people who have been polarized
into being the offensive group and the
defensive group have the same exact
common goal yea or no and tell me I'm
wrong please because I need to know that
if you don't agree tell me why anyone
okay we have common goals right we have
a common goal of fixing the enterprise
we have a common goal of protecting the
person the people our grandmother
whoever else and we need to assess what
that common goal is and figure out how
do we all get to that common goal I may
be better at breaking into a building or
exploiting something then somebody else
who's better at AB sec then somebody
else is better at building and designing
firewalls or architecture or IDs or
making things or looking at logs or
building servers or building hardware's
but all of us have the same exact common
goal sometimes that common goal is just
make money but I don't believe that in
the heart of everybody in this room that
you're here just to make money otherwise
you wouldn't have spent your time today
to go to a conference I mean maybe you
would have just to get there for work
but I've done that plenty of times but I
think we need to know that we have a
common goal and that all of us can
benefit by pushing forward to that goal
and stopping the bitching of who does
what or offences harder defenses harder
I have more passion you have more
passion my penis is bigger you know
whatever right we need to wait to cut
that out because it's hurting
us
our industry grows every single year and
it's growing leaps and bounds we have a
conference at least every single day of
the week worldwide you guys on that
every single day or more we have a
security conference I mean it's the
worst stitch of vich ever we've never
created anything by stitching but we're
pitching a whole lot so we need to get
our common goals together we need to
understand that language is a thing you
know that something did a study recently
saying that over the course of a day
you'll hear upwards of 15 different
languages no matter where you are that
could be coding that could be phone that
could be messaging that could be
dialects it could be different root
languages but we hear 15 different ones
and the problem that starts to become is
that everybody is starting to say the
same thing but people aren't doing
translation well we're not learning the
other language well and we need to
assess in what language is going on and
figure out how do we bridge the gap do I
need to have somebody that's a good
translator can I learn about the way
that they speak or what that language is
in order to try and figure out what our
common goal is together so then we can
just move past this instead of letting
language via our barrier right find your
spirit animal I don't know where tray is
but Trey made me laugh terribly when he
said that Dave Marcus was a spirit
animal Dave's a big dude and I don't
know if I mess with Dave very much but I
like to try to but within this I mean
there's such a breath of spirit animals
that you can follow to try and see how
that transition gets made right you have
people like Dan gear who is one of most
eloquent speakers and security I've ever
heard in my life but if you don't know
how to follow someone like that because
of how smart that dude is like he's not
gonna be your spirit animal you're gonna
get lost you probably have to go to an
idiot like me and then like work your
way up right you have people like Robert
if people like Gorman or teen
Marcus Heldman or kelly vista or Dave or
Wendy or bill I mean there's there's
these little spirit animals everywhere
and they sit on stage to try and say hey
this is how I communicate about things
and you're like yeah like that talk and
they resonate with you and try and
identify what in that language patterns
different than these other people and I
think what you'll find out is that even
though we all have different delivery
we're all part of the same goal we're
all just trying to move the damn ball
forward and play and Sisyphus and having
that roll back over us at
the end of the day we're like come on a
little hill again right and I'm not
going to stop I I might be bitter but
I'm not going to stop trying to do that
and I think all of us in our enterprises
and all of us when we're doing our job
need to be really cognizant of the
language of the people that were working
with and the people that were trying to
peer with and figure out how do we get
commonality how do we get language
figured out you know if you've got an
offer them a disclaimer and be like yo
I'm from the east coast I swear and say
this and then they're like hey I'm
you know from the south we're really
polite we say yes ma'am no sir and
you're like okay I can try and turn this
stuff down but like don't hate me when I
do it it's like I'm just not really good
at changing but like if it's something
that offends you let's like address it
really quick and move on so that we
don't have that be are stopping point be
the change we can't tell other people to
change as I say that telling you to
change conidia
kick so don't just keep people's puppies
don't just punch babies in the face and
take their candy right don't ever ever
ever ever ever say it's the users fault
you can't say that you can't say that I
got so I don't know if I got in trouble
or just raised or whatever else when
Marcus and Alex Hutton and I were doing
this like I don't know panel thing at
infosec world and we were extra ratchet
II that day and kind of like angry and
it was just a shitty day to have all
three of us there and people were making
comments and stuff and as we were
talking about what you should be
focusing on in your info SEC program and
where and why and those things you know
you always have like the class Joker
people which they're great that's what I
was I appreciate those people a ton
right they give you a different view of
things but this lady when we're walking
up she walked up ask a question before
she asks a question she needs to get a
little crowd behind her which I'm like
good get it and what she did to do that
was go you know uh yeah you know we
would be a whole lot better off with
security if the users didn't exist in
everybody's like oh yeah clapping and
all that stuff and I got so pissed off I
like lost it got mad and so like Alex
and Marcus both look at me and I'm like
no you can't i'm taking this and they're
like and like you can win Marcus and
Alex like do one of these you know shits
bad so I just looked at her and I was
like wow I got a question for you I was
like I'm gonna address whatever we're
talking about but I have a question for
you right off the bat she goes yeah I go
do you have kids and then the bewildered
look came on her face and front of all
these people okay what her face I'm
terrible uh-huh
so she just looked bewildered and she
was like what and I was like do you have
children she said yeah and I'm like when
your kids were learning how to walk and
they'd fall over like did you take time
out of your day to stop and laugh at
them and be like huh you can't even walk
cuz wrong with you like get whatever get
your own dinner like is that is that how
you treated your kids is that how you
are as an educator and she just did one
of those but like SAT back down and it
forced us into this horrid tirade of how
these communication things around us
exist and how a lot of this is us just
not taking care of the people around us
and why we need to start changing our
strategies around that and that every
single time the words that are spoke I
mean to me as controversial as it could
be I mean that's the reason that people
conflict and religion that's the reason
that people conflict in race or in
sexuality or anything else because we
keep it alive with our language we keep
the segregation there oh you're a user
I'm not a user you use a
computer you're a user so talk
about the users but you're saying that
you do dumb too you're a user right
and and we need to start bridging the
gap to that we need to say look all
right they fall down all over the place
like how can we make it better ask them
well surprisingly enough you ask people
questions they give the answers you
don't have to just assume that you're
smarter than them and that you know
what's best for them and then get
horribly pissed when they click the link
oh my god they click the link i told
them five times not to click the link
well maybe you weren't speaking their
language and to them all they had was
computer and you were like mcflurry i
don't know clicking super fun or dead
i'm clicking links
right like that that's where they were
going with it and they just don't care
about your crazy gobbling ugh language
and then you're mad you're like we got
to train them again bye-bye bye-bye
bye-bye Bob computer and they're like
skin nope clicking links right like and
then at that point we're like this
some people are gonna click links
forever I need to go by the apt five
thousand does that will stop people
even though they click a link that's
just John right we've just totally given
up on our education process and hope to
god that we could get into the you know
the realm of well people are going to do
dumb stuff and we have to protect them
because that's what we do and then if
they come and ask us questions oh don't
worry we have you protected and then we
bitch and screen because our whole
network has stuff all over it and we're
like God the users are killing me right
I see that as our fault not their fault
I see it as our fault squarely and I
think that we need to understand that
about our languages all right lastly
enroll the world around you you know how
many times I mean so my experience is a
lot on the testing site i've been in
defense before for 8-10 years i ran
networks at sprint all over the world
iran law firms networks you know I've
worked in auditing I've worked in
whatever class you want to put me in
offense defense gay straight I've been
all that I have let me cuz cool
it's fun to try it twice um but by the
second time you know that you don't like
that uh-huh first time it just may have
been a bad time like you may just have
bad whatever and maybe you dig it next
time um but I figured two in a row Nets
plenty but enroll the world around you
in a way that makes sense you know if if
you're really into web app stuff show
somebody who's never seen it try and
imbue them with the same amount of
passion that you have shown why it's
fawn or why it's cooler why you get you
know your little tech boner from
or you know or whatever right like like
try and share that with them you know I
think some of the most successful jobs
that I've ever feel I ever feel like I
had successful where some like gates and
I are out doing a physical assessment as
part of a red team job and we're like
you know what instead of being super
Sneaky this time we're going to take the
executive with us and we're gonna hang
we're going to confuse the out of
the beginning we're gonna hand them the
number seven but in a in a plastic hotel
key and then we're gonna be like okay
you're part of our team today and we're
gonna go break into your building and
they're just like I don't know what the
hell's going on and you're like okay
cool and you start working them through
it and they're the ones opening the
doors and they're the ones pointing out
the cameras and as you're talking to
them you're educating them by giving
them an experience and they start
getting fired up by that experience they
feel like they're part of that team
they've crossed trained and started to
get some of those pieces of exercise
that they always needed to put together
the dots right there's a lot of really
amazing amazing folks in the defense
world and what I've SAT with them and
they've and I'm just like show me what's
cool that you're doing I'm blown away I
had no idea half that should ever
existed now granted i'm thinking the
whole time like how do i attack that now
i know it's there but there's thinking
the same exact thing when i'm showing
them the attacks and how much better it
is to work together that way then just
put the wall up between us and go home
got it this time they look you're not
gonna get it next time Oh got it this
time and we play the cat and mouse game
and there's no progress and everybody
hates each other instead we could be
building wicked cool stuff whether
that's a user that's challenging I mean
you get a user that's challenging find
the head of the users that are
challenging find the one that bitches
the most find the doctor oh man dr. o
find the doctor that can't remember a
seven character password but can
remember a hundred text books you know
sit them down be like let me show you
this homie
you and me we'll sit down crack
passwords together let's go make fun of
other people's passwords come on right
oh I killed my wife 6 what he found that
on the test that was somebody's
password I was like dude he's like do we
report this no Mike I want nothing to do
with that at all nothing to do with
it no no no but it's so cool to watch
that spark hit there I it makes them
feel like a little kid again it really
does I don't know how many of you get
inspired anymore but I get inspired by
some weird now and i also get
inspired by stuff that I've just never
seen I think it's so neat and it's so
cool to me to watch somebody else just
go off like you're there in something
that they love that person will lay it
all out on the line whether they're
going too fast or too slow or you can
catch up or not catch up man being next
to that kind of energy is the most
valuable thing I've ever felt my whole
life that kind of energy and if we get
to bring that kind of energy to people
that everything changes everything
changes all at once we're not just the
person who's telling them to do
something we're like that's my hangout
cracking passwords homie like that's
every time somebody types a new password
they're like we could crack that right
I'm like yeah no oh no you can't make
that password you know like that's so
cool like you beat you become an enabler
right we're like security drug dealers
right like we want people to have a
really fun experience with it and like
get into it so then they start being our
arms in the field and the same thing
with defense I mean God please stop
telling me that there's such a problem
between defense and offense please stop
telling me that like you wouldn't
understand you don't do defense and the
other people going you wouldn't
understand you don't do offense like
we're working on the same
system how could I not understand it we
obviously have some common path in there
like show me your side I'll show you
mine I mean it sometimes I could get
like that but um just really do that you
know I try and say this to everybody we
need to educate and not adjudicate we
need to stop judging people oh they're
dumb really every time you point a
finger at somebody you have at least
three fingers pointing back at you
unless you have those things cut off
because you're liar thief and probably
both so we need to remember that people
aren't going to get it sometimes back in
the day when all this was building a lot
of people didn't get it and they
couldn't because it wasn't accessible
but now so many things are accessible
and we have the ability to read through
these languages and find some of these
commonalities that it's really going to
change things if all we do is put some
effort towards it all we do is put our
heart into it instead of our mind or you
know whatever we think carries us
forward as our ego or how tough we are
who we are if we could go and try and
attach to the energy of people actually
enjoying it man this would be a fun
profession to be in again drop people
knowledge don't just drop o day on them
right you drop a note a on them you're
doing it publicly you're doing it
because you're vain you that's my
opinion I don't care any other way if
you just want to go get the press go get
the press please don't say you're part
of my industry because my industry here
to help people it's not here to just
talk and kick their puppy most of
all we have to believe that we can fix
this I don't think that we believe we
can fix this and its really easy stuff
it's easy stuff it's us taking the time
out of our day to not be right to accept
that we'd rather be happy than just be
right because a lot of times we pick
being right to be safe instead of just
throwing it out there and go and you
know what show me maybe I don't know
something that you're showing me maybe
we don't need to have this Chinese wall
up anymore maybe we can actually work
together being on totally different
sides of things and figure out a
solution that's way greater than the sum
of its parts
sit
and that is like the little spark that
starts the fire that makes that
passionate change in my opinion if this
is a lemon market and we have an
inappropriate and aboard an amount of
knowledge on the topic versus someone
else and they need an indicator in order
to feel comfortable with that that may
be one of those indicators exist but we
need to help them find the right ones
like if it's a if I'm a mechanic and
you're buying a shitty used car I'm not
going to be able to tell you why you
know the Rings are up in the car
I'm going to be able to tell you like
look there's problems with the motor and
and trying to change that language piece
but I think that's such an awesome point
that we're really all users right we're
all the same I mean I don't know how
many times have been owned had all sorts
of random click points i mean i was
doing malware analysis like you know
completely hosed the box that i was on
but it's me getting up right so i think
that's an awesome point anybody else all
right well thank you guys appreciate it
you