makes everybody come in we won't talk to
you about today it's a guy on vision
test one of the things that we found the
rest of the tech space because we
despise on you always go native guides
there's not a one shot tool that you can
use in everything we use party tools
will respond out there are thousands of
false positives nothing's worse as a
developer 680 those are the false
positives so Michael and Nathan have
worked very hard with impassive once
ordered that probably back screen will
be presented in OpenStack our API
automation we were introductions a
little picture coming but with each of
us would like to consider ourselves
private about Michael into the let's
talk a little bit about Security's
internet what that means to Rackspace in
Rackspace quality has a job making sure
that there's three code we wanna make
sure we'll do a product that functions
one make sure that works well make sure
it performs well we've also make sure
that it's secure
so for our parsley purposes we follow
under the quality engineering umbrella
we call it Q because a lot of our
quality security for our developers they
just have to be they're very protective
as well so a lot of our strengths come
and develop it ain't quality and of
course tested as you see up there
we've had some kind of job as quality
but we do break that into the
performance side of the house security
recently do that to more specialized we
have a developer or
you wanna make sure he goes to rigorous
testing as part of SLBC software ice
like you know look at testing you know
look at the same ways it's up execute
and interpret the results what we found
is this kind of setup looks a lot better
than having security system where else
we in the software Devon the reason
being is these guys as well so instead
of waiting for the code you ready until
two weeks before the deployment
we're actually character in the whole
process that means from design you got
Kevin Williams admitted presentation
earlier sitting back there he's an
architect a you know he's a first person
the first person on scene when some of
the architects are looking at design and
applications I encourage you guys to go
to go visit is very well form as I said
earlier challenges we have Iraq spaces
there's no tool that is everything a lot
of our development isn't Python so in
some you testers you security testers
know that there is not a Python
you know static tool analysis so what we
have to do is we have to actually do our
own first of its free open source
software all it does is manage your your
infrastructure
essentially open also includes
although these CSS blocks towards
virtual hard drives
review this virtual computers database
or databases identities authentication
images is if you want to store your osot
Stormin clients which is images
networking virtual networking obvi
storage hosting follows on web server
that you can link back to your web pages
so you know your what your web node
doesn't have a terabyte of storage space
getting sorted object storage
orchestration that's our that's the
deployment if you want to spend up
servers that already have something
completely installed and set up and the
orchestration can be multiple servers
kind of like all your big data to do you
could have a deployment that employs
several nodes instead of just one server
spitting up at the time anyway lots of
companies use OpenStack here's just a
list of them if you need more
information
overstock.com
this this is a architecture of OpenStack
I'm not going to go into details just
just some small pieces Keystone which is
identity
everyone is touching that because
everyone has a token that they validate
in order to access the resources and
it's just showing you how these
dependent dependent on each other
reliance which is a which is actually
uses files to store its images so it's
just a very interdependent system ok now
on to our quality engineering
organization these are our three our
trifecta essentially we have our
performance our quality engineers like
myself are three engineers as well ok so
what I was working on I originally
started on the security team and I
worked for Jim and we did a lot of
manual testing and we started moving
some
testing but we really didn't have a good
grasp on really automating tests like
the Kiwi Department did so they built
this framework and I helped build it
called an open cafe and well cafe is
it's an open-source testing framework
it's it's not actually tied to OpenStack
they can test anything that's one of the
benefits that I like about open cafe
versus tender so OpenStack test network
you can you can put OpenStack of your
cloud and you can run the tempest test
against it or against a def stack but
you can't test your building
infrastructure that maybe you've plugins
and integrated with OpenStack usage and
that was a big deficiency for rocks
bases we have so much integration into
our identity we simply support all kinds
of authentication that OpenStack doesn't
and it was just very hard to test with
the oldest access framework so that's
why we created over cafe so this is the
architecture of open cafe is all about
abstractions use of abstractions to make
your life simpler all right if you don't
want a standard test case to be a
thousand lines and then you have this
coat off with someone else and they're
completely confused right they have no
idea your test just looks like it's
doing hundreds of things when really
it's a simple test like create a server
you know a final off of it and see if
that part wasn't a attacks
so this is our abstractions and
half a we have our models which handle
serialization and deserialization
they're essentially just objects that
can convert your requests to XML or
convert your requests to json or any
other format that your that your API
uses the number of clients our clients
is what we pass our models into and they
normally are tied to see who calls one
API call you don't want a client that
has you make one call and it's actually
create the eyes and doing very
complicated behaviors our business logic
our business logic is where we do the
the scenarios the create a server wait
for to be created and then take back the
server details and then our tests which
utilize all three to test any given
scenario so instead of tons of code you
don't have a penny here it's like create
a server wait for it to be created and
then attach a block storage for instance
so that would just be a two line test
and then you would check the results did
the attack happen since Essman to
successfully a surface thanks line okay
on top of those abstractions for
building the tests open cafe is split
into different or not okay but cafe is
designed to be used by several different
cafes essentially so what we have is the
engine it contains all your baseball
it has a plug-in architecture if you
would like to have more base clients for
instance you need to connect to your
MongoDB it's not a standard it doesn't
come with open cafe so you write a
plug-in for it and now all your client
now you can write a client that connects
to your Mongo database our base inators
is just a closet that's logging it
doesn't really have much features so
that a lot of the base is just for
longing we have several runners and the
reason these are all together is because
that's a very runner all of those are
what are specific data generated tests
like unit test doesn't have that
generated test but some of it behave I
believe Mike and we normally use our
unit test Runner which we have modified
significantly to add more of a
functional test framework than just a
unit testing framework now is where and
this is if you're testing OpenStack is
where we push if you have one of these
for every group of products that we have
a building cafe and it's not a garage
place it's not public but called cafe
it's publicly you can actually find out
in sac Gorge get a complex back porch if
you're interested in looking at some of
the code but clock cafe contains all of
our product models so the greatest
server requires these it reviews and
have them all in there and then it takes
back in response we have a response
model that will change it into an object
from XML or JSON and
our clients they pretty much mouth
exactly - though it's tack docks and our
behaviors and this is the bankers is
where the most complicated code moves
it's where if we needed a test to do X Y
Z this is what we celebrate behaviour to
abstract that so and then the roast and
we made all of these after coffee
because we drink a lot of coffee we were
coming up with this
so our Rose contains all of our tests
and that's for you
so one gross doesn't happen just use one
cafe our building infrastructure roast
uses on cafe the building cafe that
autumn opera cafe just several several
several different cafes because we have
such a such a white infrastructure and
we built everything okay
so what's the main reason we we switched
flexibility as well as having everyone
on one on one framework allows us to
take a QB person from servers and put
them in finals and they and they
instantly spun up they're like oh you're
so using models that's exactly how we
again reiterate it's not tied to
OpenStack so if you want to do large
integration testing of your cloud with
billing with some other systems it's not
related OpenStack it's easily done
plugins can be written or any type of
runner I've not found behave but a lot
of people want better test in standard
English so they like to use power line
instead and it's easily integrated with
Jenkins and obviously
okay now now we get to the security cafe
and this is a plugin that we've written
for open cafe the security cafe is
basically since it's not a standard cafe
it doesn't have API there's not a
security API that we're testing so it
doesn't really have clients it has
mostly behaviors and down to generators
so what we can do and some of the things
in Britain is are like a model other we
pass in our object model and it will
recursively iterate through the model in
some models and generate payloads that
contain that that contain clustering in
different places and our model so it
allows us to leverage the Kiwi work
because they've already built all these
models for all the products so the
security team can leverage the work
they've done and they don't have to know
what a that looks like they can just
pass in a model and then it will funds
the entire thing every field we have
another one that injects XIT just any
any security test that you can think of
we just add them and we try to have them
as generically as possible so if you
write something for to test this one
product we wanted to W use it again to
test another product so this is Joe's
overview on education authorization and
secure jackpoet layer denial service
functions we've actually started the
security guys break the test and and
they've actually started
a Kiwi guy's genius so now the test
spells it's it's not on them you know
our small security team so monitors a
hundred projects that were activated
them for every bug it will now halt to
the Kiwi team to say oh what did this
spell you know we can then raise the
issue because for security a lot of
times you have a small team trying to
encompass an entire organization so I
don't know identifying security defects
when you're fuzzing the different
violence is very very useful with the
cafe we change one cupcake we run it on
DFW we change it change one parameter
now we're running on boards one more
parameter now we're in Hong Kong so the
way our API our eggs are done in cafe we
can just swap them out you know when
we're running is command-line utility we
can just type in a different I think you
know Ord JSON document Oh more
disordered thousand-aire in Chicago so
haven't generated testing this is very
very paramount and insecurity because
buzzing can be very difficult
you're doing it manually for several
different products several different
api's so this is this is an example of
our data generators we have a base
models out of the generator that that
will take in a model and it will take
them all within it and then we just
extend it and we give it the strees that
we want to follow that model so in this
in this in these two cases were only
need an SQL injection file to contain to
all these SQL injects and then in here
we're opening a set of all Unicode
characters and then we can append these
these two clauses on any one of our
tests and then we pass in that model
serialized into the format that we want
with those uh strings you know seven
million in case of the unicode one so
what that many test cases with that
model so it's not it's not just the
string the fascinated it's the actual
request buzz with the shrink in all the
pills so if we have 10,000 unicode and
the model contains five variables we'll
have 50,000 tests this is what it looks
like when you write the test so the
abstractions play a big role here so we
can invert us that type of test with
that decorator next we are saying that
this is a data-driven test and happy
that SQL injection generated with or
West model for this test is create
Network and this is using for the our
developers that use request
be quiet and it is sitting in data
stream well now that request is the body
so this data generator is passing in the
string and then it's sending it in the
body of the crate request so which I can
see if the network is created and shrink
you know was you know a name will it do
anything that will delete the network
and then we assert we have this little
error handler that checks for odd you
know stuff it's not four or three or two
hundred it will be like oh five hundred
Oh some other error that we need some
other status that we don't even know or
the body will contain just completely
non sensible information this is some
more of our test cases authorization
test cases oh that last thing actually
runs about ten thousand different API
calls are more non buzzing just normal
we do test this a client one doing again
networks a different network of a
different clients created network so
it's it's just testing role based access
and and that kind of thing
it's very easy the abstractions allows
elite in one line and then a sir
so it's because we report how to party
if we whine points in Hong Kong and in
the bomb see the W another issue how do
we have one suite has we have engineer
to come from no magic wand and some you
guys and their tactics feel it kind of
different so you can say dramatically
different without having how so because
even though your give up even has a
relapse
you know we like you and we while and
upon days it wasn't exactly want so the
new purpose without because working on
the product they know a lot of knowledge
about the products so we have a large
share it with them so we can their back
of our products if we don't know the
power of this work
applause to run spirit helping here but
because he is using propaganda we are
also using Kamala Khan face so we can
reuse a lot of public great
effectiveness of it
if the develop if the qumari great Kemal
you crazy the required response we just
be using so that we can show up manager
what we are and we can never be too
according to oh my dear also we don't
rely on the work of human you have to
drink of your body to develop funny but
if you think about it we won't follow
100 something house and you have time we
create a lot we testing about what we
are finding out here so for number with
it's impossible to and this aid for
fully function content suits
so there W on is related with product
for program if you want it has the news
network
you need to create a lack workforce
so so so so once we help as it were just
sharing our chili folks and we had one
with Garcia TV partners so it'd be
possible was to invite ours has been
without really even the whole process we
know that it worked wonderful to us
working together respect to our security
and the QE with Amana one is were human
one security after the report was and
the do our testing we also found you
know function effect and we send a note
to them and you know the and by working
together we are viewing a rumor
situation so we for our help window and
with almost defects so we're gonna talk
about some common issues we found open
so we have quite a few of the projects
we come up a small because there are so
many I want sure a probably you god I
cannot one of the either it worry you
know but I deeply you are important so
but some of the project there's no you
so they just Langley and some of the
project we used they are going to drag
these approach to do their validation
they just point to point out the spy
character and the materials the
we just require - great after we made a
sound
so this is a response back here for this
one how do you always work fine just in
the model everything no matter what
explorations all do at home and so we
reported and they become bigger and we
found out that one was to kill originals
because in their place they they have
marks maximal names for all the women or
the B be imposed
and we are trying to let the smart
without automatic contest page and we
want
- injection so which one it just goes
from star and trying to say they require
to the response to say one is defect or
not
for this
under the framework economists say will
all the requests and response we're
seeing a log file here so is water use
for because we use tomorrow you go here
and you can see the response here
because you can see the statement within
so because in our everyday we are
checking for this message so by default
a bacterial practice should never be so
that's why you know you see you know and
we mark immediately to the birthdays we
have to show what we want are a few
ideas
there any questions
we're nowhere I would say about 60 days
so integration into the sea ice into the
sea ice process
but as far as he goes take walks towards
there's the standard smoke does the
different are about 400 tests and most
of them are functional by and large most
overfill there's very very few that are
security because all the different
combinations so many combinations server
that for example is we had a guy that
citizens are containers team and there
he's helped actually public a little
pesky databases these countries have
dedicated so in that sense you know that
it is either on my team is testing the
whole percent with Huey we live action
tax protest vote on product that's maybe
not as profitable it's a lot
we're kind of testing
Oh buddy is meaning a certain area might
be so much of what we are doing here but
they should be further part in DD we
might choose two or three
and we are one show that we're not and
give to the folks inviting the security
they essentially built over the last
1012 years but is very drastically
different
so oh that