so I'm going to talk about some quick
wins or more secure software this is
probably like the least technical talk
I've ever really done it's kind of I've
been at my company for about a year
saber and I've kind of been introduced
to the enterprise IT security world and
how to how they kind of clash with
development so I used to be a developer
but now that I'm an IT security I
actually see kind of the friction that
happened so i'm going to talk about some
maybe some easy things some quick wins
you can do first of all i do work at
Sabre not associated with the Dunder
Mifflin paper company I'm don't know if
any of you've enjoyed the office but I
do have a short video clip i would like
to play jump in the can't be the first
time and you see the next thing is gonna
be a good good
sabra save them see there's a part of
Sabre you sure it's a ver and start over
here with a little bit more about me so
i said i've been at Sabre about a year
currently I do everything application
security I'm really the only app set guy
at Sabre we have about 2500 or so
developers a lot of them in our
headquarters in southlake texas many in
poland some in india other places around
the world so previously i was a
solutions architect at Vera code and
also consultant at on the app sec team
at fishnet but I kind of mentioned
originally I started life as a developer
out the first 12 years of my career I
didn't know anything about security then
I got into apps tech around 2004 and
I've been doing that ever since do a
really participate in owasso quite a bit
I worked with Jim monaco on the forgot
password cheat sheet have a couple
certifications and I enjoy writing on a
blog from time to time at episode notes
blogspot com so on as a IT security
person that Enterprise in terms of
application security your mission your
job is to try to reduce the odds of an
application hack essentially you want to
avoid bad things like compromised data
loss of data integrity having malware on
your systems denial of service attacks
where you might lose revenue fraud
committed against your systems any kind
of bad press which would cause damage to
your reputation cost you know like
credit monitoring costs it's a PCI
breach of some sort fines and maybe even
loss of your job like we saw at target
CEO and CIO both lost their job
from the from the breach there so with
that in mind what you would want to do
in a perfect world is get some blessing
and budget from executive management you
would want to initiate a formal
application security program have a team
a software security group of some some
sort to manage all the activities that
need to happen for a really solid app
set program you want to establish
processes there they're vetted and
accepted around the organization select
the best tools hire great talent track
your progress and your improvement over
time with a maturity model and you can
demonstrate the return on investment to
the executives and in just in general EU
u of X hackers alright so that's the
goal it's not always the case where
that's going to actually work for one
thing in terms of the maturity level
it's it doesn't happen overnight it's a
process and I just took a few sample
charts from various maturity models and
and other marketing information about
how you start off with kind of an ad hoc
approach and ultimately on the most
mature level you've got everything
working smoothly your you have an
optimized program and everything's
working nicely however you don't always
have the advantages that that you need
in terms of budget resources time to do
such a great job so um I want to talk
about some of the complications that I
mean I've seen and I know other
organizations around the world are
seeing as well first of all you may not
have a mandate from executives a lot of
times well I would say most always the
grassroots approach to application
security where maybe the IT security
team or some developers decide they're
going to get a program going and they're
going to have a grassroots effort to get
it going not necessarily going to work
because the the development side is
there not being graded on the security
of their applications they're going to
you know grade it on the performance is
it done on time does it work
if there's no mandate from their
management to include security you know
why would they listen to these people or
this IT security guys saying that they
want to improve the security of the
software there's a lot of applications
and your organization many websites web
services you have limited time limited
budget staff and expertise is always an
issue the at Sabre on the about a year
ago decided they didn't have the
application security experience on the
security team that's kind of why I ended
up there however just to be honest I'm
feeling a little bit overwhelmed right
now because we're a huge software
technology company we write a lot of
code and I feel like I'm looking for
ways to make a difference right now and
I do and individual teams that I work
with but in a company-wide feel like I
need more staff and more expertise in
application security in terms of mixing
with the development teams like I said
without the development side having a
mandate to include security a lot of
times you'll get resistance to
suggestions how they might improve their
processes or improve their security of
their code or heaven forbid you find
vulnerabilities in the code and you tell
them about that so here are some general
thoughts that I've had on the topic so
first of all you know the goal is to
defend your applications and your
enterprise network so you first need to
understand what you have that's kind of
an inventory that needs to be taken a
focus on our external your external
presence is probably most critical when
you have limited time and resources and
and budget you can certainly ignore
static sites marketing sites that are
just static HTML keep in mind that you
don't as on IT security side you don't
necessarily fix the code or write the
code but it's important to think like an
attacker
for commercial software you have a
couple of options first of all you can
ask directly on the vendor how they
secure their code when they're
developing their products what do they
do specifically and also review the
hosting infrastructure of these vendors
developed products and the server
configurations but in terms of the code
itself and a commercial product or
you're really kind of at the mercy of
the vendor there are some interesting
sort of securing the software supply
chain initiatives going on out there I
know Vera code has a vendor application
security program as part of their
offering since they they can basically
scan the vendors code a static analysis
approach and provide high-level results
to an enterprise so you can get some
idea of how secure and secure a vendor's
application is but if it's an internally
developed app you have you have a lot
more options one of the things that I've
initiated at Sabre is a questionnaire to
gauge the relative risk of an
application you know I'll ask things in
the questionnaire what's the purpose of
the application how's authentication
done how many user roles are there
multiple roles for instance an admin
level standard user or whatever how is
data encryption done or is it done log
what kind of logging is done and is it
external internal facing so one thing I
have found useful on and back when i was
doing application pen testing for fish
net is uh I kind of grew up using burp
and the app sex side and so burp
professional is an indispensable tool
the pro version is only two hundred
ninety nine dollars per year per person
and with that you get a web app scanner
we use other tools for web apps scanning
at Sabre but this in particular is a
tool that I use we don't ask the
development teams for exam
to use it but I use it to scan
interesting URLs at least the web app
scanner part you know what's an
interesting URL it's a URL with a query
string or as a post request where
there's a lot of parameters in the body
so that supplements our main web app
scanning that we do for PCI but burp
also includes a intruder which is a nice
data fuzzer repeater for manual testing
manual specifically manual testing of
particular issues spider decoder and
there's extensions with burp that you
can download from not from the website
and it integrates with other tools
including qualify as web inspect Fred
fix how many of you use burp ok almost
everyone knows I'm talking on speaking
to the choir here ok so let's get into
some quick wins some things I think that
are useful don't cost a lot of time
money and resources so first of all get
your inventory figured out what what
applications do you own this has been
surprisingly difficult for me over the
last year there isn't well there wasn't
anywhere where that information was kept
I've had bits and pieces and drawed it
in I have a nice spreadsheet that I'm
keeping up to date so it's just
important because you need to understand
your external facing web presence
essentially if you can't secure what you
don't know about which I'm thinking
you've heard today and yesterday so also
one of the things that is really easy to
do it should be easy to do but it can
Fred a lot of value is just decommission
hold obsolete apps I know that there's
times when I've found applications that
are still running there's newer versions
that have replaced the older version the
older version is still running because
there might be one or two customers
using it and the business well we can't
turn it off we still have a couple
customers using it that's a scenario
like well okay let's talk to the
business and the team about the
advantages of reducing your surf attack
surface
because then you don't even need to test
that out you can just make it go away
very useful consolidate consolidating
duplicate apps turning off functionality
that's not needed there's a lot of times
I've talked two teams and I've asked
them okay what is this part of era do oh
we don't we don't use that anymore but
it's still there and it's still running
so you know remove that from the build
and so you don't have that code even
visible anymore and superfluous content
so that's not necessarily functionality
but its its documentation static files
that have made their way onto a web
server and it's externally facing and
it's potentially information disclosure
type of type of an issue so how do you
find your attack surface well of course
of course internal resources and the
teams to know what applications there
are but there's other ways that I've
found useful on working on from the
security side and google hacking or
Dorking as it's called getting file
listings from servers owasp has a
product or a tool called der buster that
I like and also very code has a
discovery service let's talk about
google hacking on i'm sure everyone
knows this but the advanced search
operators can really help you i happen
to just you know not long after target
on got breached well this was probably
like this past summer I decided ok
target got breached you know they've
probably really locked things down at
this point so I just went to Google I
wanted to see ok what kind of web
content is out there facing the internet
so i did site colon target com and i got
a list one of the ones that look
interesting to me was this coupons the
third one down so i decided to kind of
refine my google hacking searched and I
searched for the word login and only the
coupons at target.com host and very
quickly I found an interesting what this
was interesting to me this is where I
stopped but i found a cold fusion site
cold fusion site that has a
authentication and it's some sort of
administrator related
functionality because I found all those
words are there I don't know if that's
vulnerable not but that's the kind of
thing that you can do to find content at
your organization by the way is everyone
know that there are actually cold fusion
conferences still happening they
actually are in fact I was in last Las
Vegas last week and I happen to be right
next to one and i have a screenshot here
i took a screenshot of the agenda and
one of the items at 130pm was don't
throw out don't throw that out bringing
legacy it showed up bringing legacy cold
fusion code into this century so there
are still active developers out there in
coldfusion that was a surprise to me
it's had its problem in the past all
right so derp buster um has anyone ever
used door buster okay some people it's
really easy to use I mean there's
nothing like complex about it it
basically has a huge file list of common
directory and file names you fire it up
it's a java application java desktop
application you fire it up you point it
at the URL the target site and it's
actually a file and directory brute
forcer and so you can specify here the
if you want to brute force files as well
as directories you can specify a file
extension you can tell it if you want to
be recursive or not so if it finds a
directory it'll start searching sub
directories under there so basically
you're just looking for content that
maybe have interesting or possibly
vulnerable functionality or anything
that maybe not supposed to be there it's
amazingly adept at finding content that
maybe you couldn't find manually by
guessing a lot of it has to do with the
file list that they come with with der
buster I've kind of refined it over
myself I've added to it I've taken some
stuff away like the file list actually
have a lot of like I kind of porn
related words that I don't even want to
look for so I remove all those I add a
bunch of others that I'm
that I know that they're often out there
and now I've done that over the years so
I have a pretty good list right now that
actually I mean I should put on my blog
or something sometime other people might
find it useful but you just fire fire
off there buster and it goes and it
gives you a nice tree directory listing
of everything it finds so that was quick
win number one basically it was reduce
your attack surface quick win number to
shore up your ssl configuration now I
put hardly on here only because there's
actually in brand new version of openssl
about came out about a week ago one
point 0 point 1 J I'm not exactly sure
what security fixes that addresses I
know that it mentions there are some in
this version so I thought it would be
good to just make make mention of that
obviously anything built anything before
one point 01 f is bad also testing your
SSL configuration is really easy to do
there's not there's several options here
a long time ago I use th see SSL check
ssl digger SSL scan those are really out
of date now and have not kept not been
updated so I would not use those if you
are using them now the two that I've
been happy with and are being kept up to
date ro saft from OAuth and then the
qualys has a free cloud-based sslc
tester that you that you can use it's
also always continually kept up to date
it's pretty good it's free both of those
are for either and then of course
testing cookies remark secure that's
important so o.o staff Oh saft it's a
freak it's pearl command-line tool you
can grab it at this URL and you fire it
up and it has all kinds of interesting
information about your SSL configuration
it's it's almost overwhelming actually
but you can really geeked out with any
information that it provides the qualys
SSL test is at that URL there
three quick and easy nice report really
nice report you can print out and send
to someone that's to explain the problem
you know it'll check for things like ssl
v2 and heart bleed and poodle and all
these other things interesting thing is
if you do put in your host here you're
the site you want to test i always like
to check the checkbox that says do not
show the results on the boards otherwise
you get result everyone goes to this
page can see the results of your skin
yeah i'm not sure why that's not checked
by default maybe qualis wants to just
make it available to everyone but even
said you know these are the most recent
worst scans they're all f's so it's
probably somebody screen scraping this
like every hour and collecting all that
you know a real simple one is uh you
know sensitive cookies need to be marked
secure if it's site is running under SSL
which it should be or TLS now we really
shouldn't be using any SSL but the
Firefox developer extension is a quick
way to check if it's mark secure or not
and HTTP only it shows you both of those
when you do view cookies alright so that
was I was number two the SSL shoring up
your SSL configuration number three is
quashed the number one battie which is
sequel injection and I went to gym
Monaco's talked yesterday and he
explained it very well is like you
should not have this in your environment
anymore it's its first of all it's very
easy to fix um if developers do this one
thing which is use parameterize queries
then all the problems with sequel
injection go away if they don't do that
then you may have sequel injection so
it's very black and white it's not
difficult to fix but you know if your
organization has a lot of code that's
been written over the years it's
important to know if you might have
sequel injection in that code and so you
need to test for it how do you test for
it on kind of a you know budget if
you're
budget-conscious and don't have you
can't pay pen testers and you can't buy
the top of line tools or whatever well
there's a lot of different ways you can
grab this firefox extension called
sequel inject me that will test an
individual page or a form you can
download this nets parker or community
if anyone use nets marker it's a
scanning tool i may have not heard about
it it's it's you know similar to web
inspect apps can but there's a community
edition and it actually does full checks
for cross-site scripting and sequel
injection so you know that's a good way
to do it I've run it recently and found
it to be pretty accurate there's
obviously like a pro version that you
can has a lot more options Community
Edition won't let you generate reports
like you can't generate a report on like
a PDF report so it's you know it's it's
it's been a handicapped on purpose but
it'll help you find sequel injection
obviously the unauthenticated surface
area is your number one priority so if
you're limited on time don't worry about
getting a login for the application and
testing the interior just you know make
sure the login page the contact us page
the forgot password functionality all
that stuff this from the unauthenticated
surface area is tested real well and by
the way all these tools that they I know
Nets Parker for example tests for blind
sequel injection with some timing
attacks so it doesn't necessarily have
just look at sequel errors that come
back in the response to know if they're
sequel injection there a little bit more
advanced than that alright so like I
said developers do have the power here
the sequel injection cheat cheat sheet
on a wasp is very good I mean this is
this is for if you're if you're talking
to a development team and they don't
they're not familiar with it they want
to have some guidance on how to fix it
this is some information you can give
them video nice of you video tutorial
Jerry Hoff did that and it's only ten
minutes long
okay number four quash unauthenticated
XSS so again i'm looking here at
cross-site scripting making sure it's
fixed from an unauthenticated
perspective those were really probably
an order of magnitude worse because
they're perfect for fishing and so
getting that fixed from the
unauthenticated point of view is
important Ross's app now I haven't used
apple off but I have really good things
about it so have you guys used it yeah
so um I notice how it's a lot of
advancements lately I think it was a
fork from perros back in the day which i
used long time ago but it has a free
scanner for XSS and again Nets Parker
like I mentioned also can test for XSS
and the pro version the pro version of
its scanner is very good at testing for
XSS so fixing is not quite as simple a
sequel injection unfortunately encoding
is really what you need and this is
where Jim manic Oh is really good at
explaining the types of encoding that
you need to do and blacklisting is a big
no-no I know one of one of our teams
start we're fixing some a lot of the
event handlers like onmouseover and on
click and all these things there was
some issues with cross-site scripting
there and so uh unfortunately a
blacklist was being used and I mean
there's probably three dozen different
mouse events that can fire in various
browsers and it was like chit you know
trying to chase chase your tail trying
to get every single instance of the
mouse events to to return an air on if
you see it in the request so obviously
encoding that data is much much better
approach also content security policy
it's an HTTP response header that every
web application can set and tells the
browsers that only JavaScript code
from this particular site is going to be
allowed to run ken xia next works
residual has actual whole talk on
content security policy in about an hour
or actually at one I think and there's a
video tutorial on cross-site scripting
inner as well so I in Chrome as you
probably know have some built-in
protection against cross-site scripting
on because one of the things that's
important is to demonstrate to the
developers or whoever is going to be
fixing the cross-site scripting what
what you can do demonstrate to them how
to problem so usually it's important to
use firefox with that unless they turn
off the the filters the xss fit I think
IE it's called XSS filter chrome chrome
it's called XSS auditor Firefox doesn't
really have anything built in a lot of
people use no script its accomplishment
to demonstrate cross-site scripting as
possible and make it impactful to them
so they see look this is bad someone
could do this now historically that's
been done with the alert pop-up box
right not very exciting so I recommend
some other options one of my favorites
is uh this is something that I put
together to to show more impact to
developers so I have a first of all i'm
using there's like several sites out on
the web that have vulnerabilities on
purpose one of them by IBM and tnt
objectives and a kinetics so i think
we've all seen the boring alert box
right not too interesting like
developers ask why is that a problem so
i put together a little alternative
which is the unicorns and rainbow x
cross-site scripting and it just fills
your screen and you don't know why it's
doing that so i have onmouseover events
so every time you mouse over one of the
images it fires a new image and it just
fills the screen soon that's one option
by the way I've got this working on
every every one of the demo site
another option is to show them okay
someone can redirect you very seamlessly
to another site like a fishing site and
the big one diggin here is rickrolling
birth my other buddy you're finally here
long way from the sandlot ok there's my
rickrolling and then the last one I have
is not quite as dramatic but it's just
creating a fake new story oh and you so
you can do all this with JavaScript so
all right
so quick win number five implement some
of these nifty new security related HTTP
response headers I already mentioned
content security policy and you can
learn all about that at one o'clock I
think it's over in the Magnolia room
x-frame options is kind of an anti
clickjacking defense or where you your
site gets framed in another site you can
the ex frame options header can prevent
those kind of attacks strict security
policy is going to tell browsers that
this request if it's going HTTP
automatically convert it to https that's
an H that's another header that you can
use and see if if it's easy in your
organization to you know if changing
code on the functional side is difficult
maybe adding these response headers is
going to be easier and now you can get
that done without with a lot of out a
lot of effort another quick win just
make sure your web servers and app
server software is up to date so this
goes back to your patching process how
efficient is that how's it working i
mean because the bottom line is
attackers know the vulnerabilities and
old versions of code or products out
there you know if you run some tests and
you see server banners coming back with
is six apache2 tomcat five PHP 5.2 any
of these response headers that you see
it's probably not your you're patching
is probably not working or at least it
fell through the cracks on on those
sites quick win number seven so engaged
developers and development managers this
has been one of my primary objectives
since i started at Sabre i just want to
make sure they're keeping security in
mind the we're not a financial company
and we're not a government contractor or
anything so I can't say that it's a it's
been in their minds up till now so it's
a slow process but I'm making progress
also identifying some champions within
the development organization if I see
someone and I'm in a meeting or talking
to someone and they express an interest
or seem to express interest asked
questions about security I make a note
of them and kind of my plan is to come
back to them later make them a champion
in the organization the development
organization and really avoid the
adversarial relationships Zane Lackey
had a good talk yesterday on I think
it's like ten o'clock about this make
sure you don't you're not a jerk
basically when you're talking to the
developers and because that'll they'll
shut down and they will never talk to
you again do lunch and learns have guest
speakers come in at Sabre we have this
series that we call security tech talks
they're really targeted for developers
that anybody can come in fact Joel Joel
Escambray or ear came to Sabre and did a
talk for us so those are kind of things
that we're just trying to keep everyone
in engaged hacking demonstrations
internal bug bounties so I'm difficult
to do because you don't want to end up
with developers writing their own code
to have a buy a minivan but I think
there are some things that can be done
you know maybe badges badges for
developers that bring an issue to you
that they found something to encourage
like positive reinforcement on that okay
I got about ten minutes here five
minutes so I'm going to kind of run
through this but I'm so I kind of
mentioned early on that in a perfect
world you can roll out a program
formalized program everybody's attuned
to what's going on and
it's directed from above so the idea is
that on with a maturity model you want
to be able to define and measure your
security related activities in your
development and also track that over
time to see how it improves open Sam are
just Sam software assurance maturity
model from from a wasp is a good option
it's kind of a prescriptive approach to
introducing security elements into your
sdlc it provides the building blocks for
implementing an application security
program it's like the goal the goal is a
mature application security posture and
that happens over probably years at any
organization that has any kind of size
and so with a maturity model like Sam
you can demonstrate measurable
improvements and incremental
improvements over time so let me talk
about in an open Sam there's four
business functions divided into
governance construction verification and
deployment of software under each
there's three security practices and
it's nicely color-coded so you can
quickly see what's going on here so to
evaluate where you are in terms of app
SEC maturity you get rated or scored on
each security practice and the possible
scores are 0 to 3 so if you're doing
anything in that particular practice
you're probably going to get a 1 you can
also give 1.5 2.5 but you can measure
yourself and see how that changes over
time as you implement and roll out new
activities a new activity might be
threat modeling early in the life cycle
it might be defining security
requirements for every project these
things all go into the improving your
maturity over time and so this is where
you can see for each practice area this
is an example where if it's plotted over
time you should see that improve and get
higher
so that was just a really quick overview
of open Sam there's more here at this
URL it's a no boss project there's
alternatives that's not the only one the
one that I'm probably most familiar with
is the BCM and building security and
maturity model which is very similar to
open Sam many of the same activities can
be tracked over time to see how you're
doing but it's more of a survey a survey
of dozens of companies and what they're
doing with application security and then
that can also be tracked over time with
spider charts spider charts allow you to
see where you are just like those last
graphs I showed and you can see yourself
and compare yourself against other
companies Microsoft has a really heavy
weight maturity model called sdl that
obviously it's improved their security
over the years and a wasp another has an
older one called clasp focusing on
unauthenticated for XSS the reason I say
that is only due to limited time and
resources because if you have an
unauthenticated xss vulnerability the
thing that that is really makes you
vulnerable is the possibility of fishing
because you can send someone an email
with a link that has a link to it the
unauthenticated page that has the
vulnerability that can maybe seamlessly
redirect them just like the rig rolling
it can seamlessly redirect them to like
a fishing site that looks exactly the
same and they might they might get fish
successfully that way if it's an
authenticated vulnerability if that page
that vulnerability is under the nfa the
authenticated surface area the user is
going to get a login page and they're
going to think they're you know the
actual login page because and so that
they may that may not work as well but
that's the main reason limited time and
budget
all right I don't see anything else
anyone thank you