[Music]
thank you
hello everyone so I'm connecting from
Sunny Los Angeles it's pretty still dark
here it's early early morning it's 5 a.m
but I'm ready to rock the stage hello
everyone so today we will be talking
about the evolution of thermal threats
and attacks below the operating system
so a couple thoughts about me so Marco
thank you for great introduction so I'm
uh founder and CEO of binary so being 20
plus years in the research and break
probably a few times CPUs and also gpus
so dedicating my all free time to the
surfing it's one of the reasons why I
end up in the sunny Los Angeles based in
Santa Monica so all right let's start
with some
introduction what's been in the past and
why uh we have a lot of a lot of
movements right now on the tread
landscape below the operating system
so um
let's look what is going on uh from the
treadbridge park different Evolution
we've been uh always having a low level
and complex threats from the rootkits
perspective then it's been boot kids and
I think uh right now it is a huge huge
movement to bias and firmware implant in
general so and this uh movement
happening because we increasing the
actual number of mitigations on the
operating system level right so it's
getting more and more complex it's more
mitigations which is actually easier to
break from firmware because it's
actually open new opportunities for the
attackers in terms of direct memory
access and many others and this growth
also actually uh showing the direction
uh depends on the type of the attacks
also from the hardware and silicon level
right so basically just for historical
overview like always endpoint solution
has been more about like looking on a
braking system layer right so and
checking what is happening in runtime on
the operating system but uh also of
course the boot kits kind of force the
endpoint solution to look into direction
for boot sectors bootloaders but
hardware and firmware has been kind of
like out of scope right and developing
the solutions for actually be effective
for the firmware and Hardware waste
threats it's very very complicated
specifically if you are an agent on
operating system level right
so and of course like Shifting the
threat model it's kind of like uh
surprising some of the vendors I mean
they are not ready and also uh if you
look from the perspective of the
detection of the threads so this is
screenshot of moonwalk uh sorry uh it is
uh actually
uh another threat which has been
discovered in 2020 and this one is very
very interesting because it's been used
five years old indicator from hiking
teamwork so think about we have a hiking
team implant which has been uh leaked
right so and threat actress like in 2014
right and it's threat actors still using
some of the code from this league and
this has been detected in uh 2000 uh
2020 and basically it's been using uh
the the same indicator of infection uh
with FDA invalent variable thing is like
this one
already been known for actually almost
six years before this new threat appears
how come we are not detecting it right
so how come we don't see this indicator
which is known another one it's Moon
bounds from
uh from the last uh from this year and
uh it's discovered by Kaspersky lab but
basically they said we see this on one
of our clients machine from 2019 but
during the investigation uh by our team
we discovered this is actually nothing
new it is a Chinese kit which has been
used from 2014 for uh low-level
implantation and basically the component
which is being modified uh is being
modified from the platform which is
actually been uh in in the market from
2014 uh May and it's kind of like uh
interesting
interesting perspective because it shows
a very limited way how currently we
detecting the trends but it doesn't mean
they are not exist it's mean we just
don't send them right and let's talk
about more what happening right now why
we don't see them why it's happening in
so in such way which is invisible for uh
for Security Solutions
I wanted to highlight a few uh
interesting issues which has been
recently pledged by Lenovo in
um in September and basically this one
uh is uh very interesting because uh
probably it's one of the first advisors
which is highlighting Windows management
and instrumentation uh uh is my Handler
which has actually been used for C type
in the bias password but uh in 2019
offensive con talk I've been
highlighting like a Windows management
instrumentation it's a huge attack
surface I've been showing some of the
vectors how it can be attacked and
actually as we can see it's my Handler
which is callback function from firmware
it's actually been exposed from Windows
management instrumentation right so
basically we can use visual Basics
crypto actually trigger this my Handler
from the firmware this is like actually
a very interesting way how you can think
about the connection between the
operating system layer and the firmware
from the perspective of uh kind of like
a functionality and how you can
uh opens new attack surfaces
very very interesting Direction and
basically I think it will be will be see
much more about that and of course like
it's not only said password it's a lot
of other things but how you can uh
orchestrate the big Network you can go
and manually as it security go and set
the password for every user if you have
5 000 users in your network right so
basically you need some sort of like a
scalable way how you can do it but at
the same time uh is it if it is related
to security features uh to the firmware
uh of course it's connect uh
functionality from the firmware which
need to be used and called from
operating system layer and it's actually
exposed a lot of uh interesting attack
surfaces uh which is of course can cause
security troubles
security issues another thing it is a
supply chain problem uh we've been
seeing a lot of different
um attacks on device vendors and if you
think about on the Taiwanese vendors
it's been uh constant attacks happening
like it's been also stacked it's been
gigabyte it's been others attacked uh in
the previous few years and also the big
device vendors like Intel AMD Nvidia and
Samsung uh it's publicly known they've
been actually targeted by uh ransomware
or bridge by some uh
some trap actor which is being uh in
their networks but also from the
perspective of the supply chain if you
think about it is kind of complicated
how you can guarantee they are not
inside your firmware they not land at
the back door they've not been on the
server uh build server or like your
source code if they are attack your
network they can also attack one of the
developers and this has caused a lot of
a lot of interesting thoughts because
because it's very complicated when
such trap actors is actually can attack
the Silicon vendors device vendors and
actual uh
third parties which is developing the
firmware for uh for the device vendors
and this happened literally recently
right so just like probably two weeks
ago we all hear about Adler Lake via
source code leaked but it's leaked
because one of uh om device
manufacturers like odm it's been bridged
and actually this one being developing
the code for Lenovo firmers right
and if you look from the perspective of
supply chain we have a lot of parties
involved and if one layer of this party
has been failing and back door so we
have the customers which we are affected
it's single point of failure when it's
basically include too many parties uh
which is developing the crowd developing
the hardware and different components
but it's end up on one
party which is a customer which is the
end user of this device or the firmware
and actually it can cause a lot of
security issues right so I think it's a
lot of good movements happening for
actually protecting the supply chain but
think is uh it is actually
a very complicated problem because uh a
lot of vendors they basically don't
share because of the license or whatever
the source code you have just a binary
how you can trust the sign of the binary
even if you have a s-bomb software bill
of materials which is currently
increasing a lot of contention and it's
very good movement but thing is if you
have uh implanted firmware the s-bomb
will be not show you this dependency
right of course like dependency graphs
it is related to the third-party
components but what if this vertical
third-party company has been modified
maliciously how you can classify and
identify such problems of course as boom
it's not been created for that it is a
dependency graph to identify all the
components which is included in your
firmware or whatever piece of software
right but anyway it's caused some
interesting uh thoughts about like how
we can
detect something which is malicious not
only output out not up to the it or
basically contain some malicious God
right
so another thing like this bridge which
has been happening in this Adler awake
it's League uh the platform key from the
wood guard and it's been a lot of uh
paranoia uh on the Twitter about like
this key is leaked uh most of the
platforms affected from Lenovo and uh
nobody actually did the fact checking
and we did the fact checking we check
most of the platforms which has been in
the field and used by our customers and
not only we checked all the firmware
which is like device line has been
available from Lenovo and unfortunately
we don't find this key that means this
key being not actually on the production
devices most likely uh of course we
don't know for for sure 400 percent but
our intellectual gas is key being leaked
from some development device not actual
device which is shipped to the customers
of course we'll like we'll see maybe
device has been not produced yet or
they've been on production line and
these devices will be seen in the future
with the liquid key but basically to say
about
all the platforms are affected it's
better to make some validation and
checking before blames the vendor they
are actually right
so this is very interesting thing when
we get to the point how we can trust our
devices how we can trust the firmware
which is coming from the vendors and
what we should do for actual validation
of this firmware what we need to think
about our advices and
what the firmers are more secure and
actually how you can guarantee you don't
have implants right as example some of
the devices came by default with the
computers with legit domain implant for
like a corporate uh security sometimes
you can use for like a giver vacation
tracking your users and a lot of other
stuff but also it can be used in
malicious way right and we've already
seen these attacks it's example low
Jacks apt20 yeah eight been used uh
modified version of computers to
actually attack the US government
so another thing it's constant rays of
numbers of vulnerabilities and only by
like by finally my company we discussed
like a 60 plus vulnerabilities and uh
also like we still have uh 50 plus which
is under the disclosure so I mean that's
a lot guys and uh like 95 percent of
these uh issues are high impact issues
that's mean like it's pretty serious
vulnerabilities which has caused a lot
of troubles and uh
what other parties are discovering right
why these vulnerabilities are happening
and why all these repeatable failures
are not gone because it's just classical
most of them it's classical memory
corruption vulnerabilities like I've
been finding uh call out vulnerabilities
like a code execution and system
management mode from probably 2013 or
even earlier but basically that's
happening again and again we have some
mitigation in place but how effectively
they used by the vendors and other
things it's cause a lot of troubles such
number of vulnerabilities of course
create the mindset this attraction phase
is very big and big from the perspective
of
um
uh of potential opportunities for the
attacker right and why I think it is
actually uh happening right now and you
don't just don't see because like it's
just too many things in the firmware
which is can be used by that hiker and
actually affect uh much effectively uh
the operating system where compared to
other things of course you need to have
a very comprehensive skills to develop
some things but also like it's been a
discussion a few I think week ago or so
about the Black Lotus malware which is
new malware based on ufi firmware
appears uh but
um nobody's seen the sample yet
interesting thing but it looks like uh
such movements it's happening on the
Cyber criminal world too but it will be
interesting to research such malware and
see what kind of capability has been
included in there and not just on the
speculation which is currently happening
into the media anyway so also after our
black hat talk uh in past August in
Vegas our
uh we disclosed six vulnerabilities to
HP and it's been responsible disclosure
coordinated date of disclosure and
everything else and in place what
actually been everything been
coordinated with the vendor what
happened we figured out a few weeks
later basically a triple three high
impact vulnerabilities we've been
talking about on black hat we discussed
all the details and some of them
actually been uh include the pocs and uh
our
our bugs are not patched
like vendor Bean aware about these
vulnerabilities for a while and uh uh
our backs after the coordinated
discorder are not fixed and uh we've
been thinking about why is that
happening one of the thoughts it is also
about identification effect that's
coping the impact right what uh product
lines are affected what the devices are
contained uh these vulnerabilities and
actually for some of the vendors
um
it's actually can be a problem and uh
because they have just too many
different product lines and scoping such
devices with a forked repository of the
firmware it can be not that easy and
also HP is probably one of the uh
firmware vendors which I knew from the
u5 firmware space which is try to
obfuscate their firmers they just strip
in the names and generate the random
ones maybe such obscurity doesn't play
well when you need to pledge the firmers
who knows right
and yeah just come back to
um
black hat we discussed 12 new
vulnerabilities at blackhead some of
them being a platform initialization
phase preview Phi which is very
interesting
um very interesting attack surface and
uh it's where we will be talk about the
future threats and how the movements
will be happening but also just a few
weeks ago we dropped seven new inside
vulnerabilities and uh actual next week
in uh Echo party it will be uh another
three issues but these three issues is
actually huge this junior vulnerability
will be discussed next week it will be
affecting 10 years back of the platforms
which is actually in the field that's
kind of like a very very uh interesting
feeling about the firm vulnerabilities
sometimes if you find the vulnerability
in reference code or if you find
vulnerability in ibv independent bias
developer code it's can affect
um
not just single platform right it can
affect all the vendors which has used
this uh American Mega Trends or whatever
other IBB called and then uh also if it
is Intel or ND reference code you can
actually Target all the platforms and
some of the intro Intel or AMD reference
code it's can include a few years back
of the devices which is can be also
affected but such security issues right
and this is kind of scary because uh the
firmware attack surface is give so many
opportunities to the attacker and we
don't see in the strats but we've seen a
lot of vulnerabilities and risk
happening but I mean it's not true and
unfortunately like a lot of things which
is seen it's under ndas but basically we
don't see uh enough information and risk
highlight on the median publicly which
is does it create some sort of like uh
uh mindset it's not happening but it is
happening
so let's talk about previous
attack model attacker model and
basically
this is very interesting space because
basically what happened in pre-fi is the
moment it's not uh initiated yet it is a
pre-dixie mode and uh basically it is
very very early after just uh
actual CPU and fsp firmware is passing
control uh to the UEFI firmware which
started with a preview phase and it's
initiating a lot of functionality
includes security features right so
basically some of the security features
it just can't be uh bypassed on that
phase which will be never bypassed on
the Dixie phase from the perspective
what you can do from preview file this
is another thing when we cross in
different type of security boundaries
and I think uh I've been talking a lot
about that previously uh I think also
christophany who is doing a lot of fault
injection attacks and side channels he
will be talking uh later today he
probably also can highlight some of the
interesting stuff about Crossing
security boundaries when you do insidesh
attacks and it's exactly why most of
them happening because if you attack at
very early phase uh doing the fault you
can actually cross security boundaries
and from different perspectives look on
security features which has been not
considered this perspective can be not
considered by developers of the security
feature right but also let's think about
engram
what is non-volatile memory means from
the attacker perspective first of all
like because it's used on early early uh
boot phase and by other reason reasons
it's basically functional Reasons from a
functional perspective it's actually not
covered by boot guard and also it's
actually created uh it's it's exists
earlier than boot guard right so
basically because it's not validated any
variable which is actually can be
modified and cause a constant
exploitation it can give the attackers
the persistent vectors and
that's a very interesting way when you
basically don't have any modified
components but you can actually attack
the firmware and still gain the
persistence effectively right and
we actually discussed uh
on past Black Cat and previous black hat
uh about such of the attacks we found
one of the vulnerabilities be Society of
t on Intel reference code presented in
2000 in 2021 with Alex turshkin and
Adams abroadski with my Nvidia coex
we've worked before I started binary so
basically I'm
um this is very uh interesting
perspective of uh enviram and how this
transition happening between different
phases right but let's talk about how it
can be used by the attacker right but
some node which is very important like
in many cases uh like TPM will not help
right because you have the pcrs which is
platform registers which is used for
storing your integrity hash but this
Integrity hash will be created but not
extended during runtime that's mean like
uh you will be not affect like you will
be not affecting after modifications or
end time phase and remote Health
attestation in this case will be don't
detect runtime exploitation so and it's
where we need to create this transition
to the future of the attack surfaces and
how this is happening so let's look on
this prayer five phrase but it's been a
lot of discussions about the Dixie some
implants and root kids of course like
it's other spaces where implants can be
hided but let's just focus on this talk
on UEFI firmware because this is huge
it's easy to exploit from the operating
system layer and it's actually already
been used in a lot of offensive
operations
for many years which is known
and basically uh
uh what happened in the pre-5 phase is
happening too early right so we have
like uh no security protections gains by
flash modification in this phase like
bios lock enabled smm uh write
protection will be not that exist VR RX
will be not initialized it's a security
registers which you can block some of
the regions to write and also Intel bias
guards are not enabled at this moment
it's exactly what I'm talking about from
the security feature perspective like
yes we have all these fancy mitigations
but what if they just not enabled yet
right so it's kind of like a by
bypassing by design a lot of the things
and to be honest uh the previous attack
surface uh from uh first shootout uh
from the offensive perspective it's been
discussed in our talk 2020
2021 uh at black hat in Vegas but
basically uh we didn't sing like a lot
of attention from the vendor side and
when we've been working on this space
it's a lot of opportunities for the
attacker but also it's a lot of uh
vulnerabilities in there it's a lot of
design problems which is basically hard
to fix
uh business idft issue which I mentioned
before from enter we can just Google
this one uh basically it is been very
long time uh disclosure process I would
say it's more than a year under the
disclosure after we can actually uh talk
about that and uh very interesting
thing from the supply chain perspective
this vulnerability it's still on some of
the platforms stay unfixed because I
don't know why but it's been no fixed
delivered from the device vendor or it
is no fix delivered with ibv site and
it's kind of like a complicated and
supply chain creating even more problems
for the firmer side which we can imagine
so
let's talk from the payload delivery so
I uh even I talking from the K note
perspective but I want to keep it
technical enough and deliver the message
from the complexity and the impact
perspective to you guys and look here so
we have like a pre-5 phase and the Dixie
phase so operating system will be boots
later but let's just focus on these two
phases and we have like different type
like if you think about uh UEFA firmware
itself called operating system before
your main operating system happening
basically this is a real-time operating
system which is actually
about 6 million plus uh lines of code
and it's actually bigger than modern
entos kernel so it's how complex it is
and uh also we just cover
where from very high level perspective
the flow how it can be attacked from uh
exploitation perspective if you
basically have a code execution on
platform and utilization phase what kind
of like transition phases can be done to
survive until ISM and inject code there
and again like all this uh it's crossing
a lot of different security boundaries
and can just avoid a lot of security
mechanisms which is implemented on Dixie
runtime system management runtime but
it's not initialized yet because pre-fi
phases happening to earning
so here's a demo from
um our uh
one of our vulnerabilities exploitation
in platform initialization phase I think
this one is exactly used uh
uh bcssid debug and uh as you can see it
shows exactly the way how it's hooking
uh different uh events for keep this
transition going it's actually this demo
exactly show what has been described on
the previous slide
but let's focus on Modern security
features what about platform policy
management from a new uh security
feature from window and how it's
actually can uh can protect uh
can protect our modern devices this
actually very interesting security uh
uh feature because basically we have now
not only
a sign at firmware we have also some
checks on which
Islam driver need to be loaded which
functionality for all these smm drivers
in terms of the policy need to be
applied and of course uh it's controlled
by some of the ACM which is related to
TPM but and the txt but basically
another thing we have uh it is kind of
like what if we exploit the
vulnerability in one SML driver does we
still have uh the whole access to the
memory region and smm to affect any
other drivers or modifies the memory
space that's an interesting question and
let's look together how this feature are
worked so first of all like uh
it's actually simplified SMI transfer
monitor which is kind of like a
Intel developed as a concept back to uh
come back to 2014 uh 15 when they are
kind of like partially
open sourced and the first Concepts has
been very slow with the time of course
it's create much more
um much more flexibility from the
perspective of new security and silicon
features but uh this one it's how it
looks in reality unfortunately it's not
used any sort of fertilization we have
most of the functionality for uh this uh
uh ppam uh feature uh implemented still
in the firmware when all the
initialization happen mostly in pre-5
Phase but also as you can see uh the
policy checking in just one bit right so
it's basically signaling like true or
false if the police has been checked
what if this beat beat can be modified
what if the attacker can influence a
little bit plus this will affect the
security feature basically this platform
assessment model it's been created for
actually help uh the device vendors to
be more confident it will be harder to
compromise but from the design
perspective it's actually super complex
feature and it's open new attack
surfaces right so let's look uh how
basically attack can be done we
presented this uh ppam attack on our
black hat so more details can be
discovered by the link below but main
thing here like we have a pre-file uh
prefinitialized this security feature
and of course it's need to be
transitioned uh happening right so when
we have uh co-ops which is Hands-On uh
some basically let's say some Global
variables which is accessed during
different boot stages uh and if this
Global variable will be signaling
something this can be modified because
it's not protected right
and it's exactly what happened so this
attack being on one of the most recent
flight books um like uh and we still see
uh this not fixed yet by the way in many
devices uh HP implementation uh show you
basically when it's checking only
something exists in the variable and
then boom of course it can be modified
reference implementation is actually
different it is a vendor implementation
affected this bypass it's not Universal
it's focused on HP device but it doesn't
mean other vendors not use the same way
because they need to kind of like
simplify for themselves implementation
of this feature because it looks cool on
the uh
uh on the reference called how Intel
want to be implemented but also how you
can scale and support and a lot of other
things into the field IT supplies to the
device vendors right
so uh basically it's more uh a bit more
about this bypass so basically as I
mentioned this global data Hub data it's
contained some check for sub word like
if people should be enabled and exactly
we can modify it so
boom
and another thing I wanted to talk about
it's what we discovered during our black
hat research like okay this is security
feature it's platform uh assessment
module uh but also if we come back to
one of the first flights when I've been
talking about that it's been the
certificate which is stand for at a
station it's kind of like a creating uh
route of trust for this assessment of
different modules happening with Intel
ppam but what we realized we extract uh
the certificates which is related to
this assessment module and we realized
most of them are actually expired
they're kind of like missing validity
but why
so basically
interesting thing like your production
signing key is being expired on all the
Platforms in the field every single
platform in the field we are checked
like and that's mean at the station it's
been not enabled for people and actually
from the attestation standpoint if
you're not like let's say uh if we
disable ppam by the attack previously
discussed so like it will be visible
from the device health perspective from
a gestation standpoint but because
based on this in context at the station
being never in place for BPM so boom of
course like this attack is very legit
and it's very weird when we have like
security feature which is not just
configured correctly not by single
vendor the whole industry
so yeah it's a bit more details about
certificates how many we checked as you
can see like we found like almost 200
certificates which is like 2021 a bit
less certificates related to 2020
because this feature has just not been
uh used by uh majority of the devices uh
in the field but it's actually been
enforced with most recent CPU generation
it's why basically seen more uh more
recent certificates expired
right why is this all the reputable
failures are happening uh and uh why we
still see all these memory Corruptions
with industry-wide teamwork I think like
first of all when you have a six million
lines of code on C language it's
actually creates a huge attack surface
from any sort of perspective you can
imagine so like but of course uh some of
them can say oh we start actually
writing developing some of the firmers
on the rascot yes that's
actually happening but if you think
about from the supply chain perspective
you don't only develop in your firmware
company you need to develop your former
component on the raft you need to
develop all these dependencies for party
components also on us otherwise you have
like 20 percent in the best case on the
rust and 80 percent of the Seacock still
is a huge attack surface and you
mitigate probably just 20 percent of the
risk and of course like uh from the
perspective of rust if you use uh some
unsafe things like it can cause troubles
as we all can see from the perspective
how many issues been found from their
standard Library which is using unsafe
code for optimization purposes right
and in general of course like uh save
languages memory save languages are
helping to reduce the uh memory
corruption and all this uh
vulnerabilities from that perspective
but like we are still have a lot of
plenty of space for The Logical bugs for
design issues and others right we'll see
how it goes and hopefully the industry
will be recovered from these repeatable
failures but so far it's happening just
like shootout for the more streets and
tissues we discovered so yeah I will go
a bit faster on that because uh we have
some limited time and I want to see uh
to hear the questions so yeah this has
been presented already on labscon and
all the details available in our
advisories that's why I just shifting
also it includes in our blog so
basically
what is most important how we can
remediate this spiritual failures how
basically we can find this automatically
and uh like
my team developed like if I explore
plugin which is helping to find some
classes with get variables and some
others we just start supporting uh
uh arm architecture for UEFI firmers and
funny thing the vendors already not
happy with that and you will be a new
probably in a couple of months you will
be discovered more details when it will
be publicly available so stay tuned and
another thing like we released some very
interesting blog posts about how the
simulate execution can apply for actual
firmware space from uf5 firmware space
perspective and it's not only limited
for you if I firmware spaces approach of
course so basically how we are thinking
from the perspective of automation of
back hunting in the firmware space right
you don't need actual device and fuzzing
on the device or basically doing such
things on the device it's not necessary
and also it's limitations capability
right you need the you will be scaling
and depending on the number of devices
available so like we can do this more
more effectively or basically limiting
the scope with
a potential scope where we are checking
so yeah it's just uh some show for
detection office in my hand there's boom
right very fast very effective and
finding the problems so guys if you
wanted to check your firmware from
condotron is available for free but
basically Community scanner is here so
let's start recovering from these
repeatable favors don't trust the
vendors check your firmware and then
again as a conclusion
complexity It's actually an enemy of
security and what we can see the
complexity is just growing it's opening
your attack surfaces when the attack
surfaces are growing it gives the
possibility for the attack here and
talking from the evolution of the thread
uh chat actors in The firmware space
it's been of course always around uh the
firmware and Hardware but it's been
mostly happening from the state state
sponsored actors perspective because
they have more budget they have a more
interest and persistent but now this
shift happening actually on the
commodity threats which is coming from
the cyber crime attack surface why it's
happening just because the attacks from
The Firm weights get cheaper on
operating system it's not always about
persistence it's actually about the cost
efficiency and
um
for the from the attacker perspective
and this actually happening also like in
general we have much more document
documented things which is increasing
knowledge base available which is
researchers did for the years for this
attack surfaces of course it's give
right now a benefit for for the uptrend
actor from that space
um
industry definitely need to increase the
awareness on the firmware and
specifically on the firmware which is at
scale which is actually executing on the
devices and I hope that will be happen
and this is happening from some of the
perspectives uh which is enforced by the
vendors enforced by the governments and
enforced by the industry uh all these
supply chain security things
it's actually helped a lot uh for uh
paying more attention on the firmware
remediate that action surfaces and
actually reduce the time of response
thank you very much
and
that's my uh hope for today but I open
for the questions
[Music]