[Music]
foreign
2022 double inside this year we have
over 500 attendees speakers from all
around the world we have a new Capture
the Flag event running on we have an
Hardware badge and we have double sides
in VR and more fun
[Music]
thank you
I came to know how to present on a topic
called carolector 300 framework
decentralized finance and the frontiers
of cyber crime our web security evolved
and what really means the web Security
in 2022. the insecure by Design Legacy
and ICS systems will fault injection
attacks open source security Automation
and blockchain man the Gap smashing
beyonces for fun and OT Networks
[Music]
no hat is an opportunity for researchers
internationally and nationally to
interact with each other exchange ideas
and find different ways to collaborate I
like the fact that it is vendor free is
sponsored by a non-profit very technical
very insightful they are really well
known people around the cyber security
War it's very nice yeah I like it I like
the environment I like the atmosphere
it's very yeah collegial very nice
between different kinds of people and
it's also it's it's quite big but in a
nice way
foreign
[Music]
twenty three is definitely one of the
points where you can see
people that have seen a lot of security
and experience meeting up with people
which are really enthusiastic and really
I would say technical skilled it's
impressive what these guys can do you
will find a very qualified speaker a
very very interesting talks and for 100
you can't miss the next edition of no
hat so yeah
[Music]