good morning church on
hope you're all adequately caffeinated
welcome to day two
wait um sorry is this is the mic on can
can you all hear me
this is um recorded as it's a bit too
early for me to do this live but
i'm here on discord uh just come say hi
i'm really sorry i couldn't be with you
i'm kind of stuck in melbourne australia
but hey
let's get on with it
so hello friend
in meat space i'm designated as then
many years ago
running a small business online
i experienced the fragility of my online
business
by experiencing a data breach hey
and that started me on a journey to
learn how to well secure the business
almost a decade later
dylan knew
this seems to be no easier
but like for many 2020 and 2021 prompted
a lot of reflection
as we collectively face this
unprecedented crisis
this talk was born
from a bit of that
reflection and to share some of the
thoughts that that has been kind of like
throwing in my head around
the cyber pains um and
that small businesses have been facing
so here goes
oh and if you're i know it's early but
if you're taking a shot
with every mention of the word cyber
you might want to get a new bottle ready
so
let's crack on
as cyber attacks become literal barbecue
stoppers in the last year or so
we need better cyber security
the need for better cyber security has
never
been more clear
as cyber is literally
integral to our lives
and all of these issues
are just the ransomware bits
we agreed
we agree that everyone needs to do cyber
security better
but i'd also like to believe that it's
fair to say that for 99 of organizations
and workers
cyber security is not the job nor
expertise
like most of us
we go to the doctor for medical help
how many times have we heard the
following
must
have more cyber awareness training
higher more cyber people spend more on
cyber
or just mandate and demand more cyber
security
problem solved
yeah
so
what would it cost
well an oversimplified look at
what is involved in do security better
or the typical business operator
we would probably need advisory services
to
guide us on what options we have
and what we should do
assurance services to benchmark and tell
us
what we really should be concerned about
then
the engineering to put all those
recommendations into place and then run
that if things go wrong
we'll need help to investigate what went
wrong and recover
get all of that back put us back on our
feet
we also need to make sure that
everything is done well and right
a good plan place and manage all of that
that's a lot
let's take a look at the first step
getting
advice to get started
we all know that blindly self-medicating
can sometimes be harmful so
let us seek some help
how much would that cost
let's pin that
we'll come back to it in a
so why are we talking more business here
it's because they represent the
overwhelming majority of business
and
and it's critical to our economy and
community
yet we often hear how unprepared small
businesses are for cyber attacks
to do that
let's first take a look at what a
typical small business
following the definition
of what a small business is according to
the australian tax office it is a
business with turnover of under 10
million
yes
and
those that typically they are employing
under 20 employees
and
makes an average net profit of
twenty to thirty thousand dollars per
year
taking further from another small
business study
it was found that an average of 275
dollars per full-time staff a year
is the budget for security
why not more
often
the decision is between paying salaries
to put food on the table
and a staff member or spending on cyber
security
but
hunger speaks volumes
though cyber security threats say pretty
top of mind
if this constraint in mind
back to that earlier question
how much would advice cost
well based on various chats with friends
i'm carrying rates from around 900 to
3000 australia a day
varying from boutiques to
big multinationals
now
or some of the consultants watching this
how many days of effort would we want to
give
info and specific advice
one day three days
or
how much in total would that cost
what is the minimum contract value that
the consultancy that you work for would
even consider
accepting
i've heard some consultancies
and seen some of them where
there is an expectation of upwards of
ten thousand dollars minimum contract
value
how does that make sense for small
business
perhaps guess there may be some of you
listening to this that have volunteered
to help out pro bono a few small
businesses that have unfortunately
fallen victim to cyber attacks
due to
our unaffordable
professional health terms can
that brings us to the cyber poverty
line at which an otherwise sustainable
organization unable to afford
access to adequate cybersecurity
healthcare necessities will reach a
defined minimum
ended
this sounds very much like the
challenges that we've just talked about
that small business is facing
this was very much inspired by an
interview in the riscus risky business
podcast
here
and talks by andy nades
like how in australia new zealand
we as society has come to agree that
seeing a general practitioner for
healthcare didn't bankrupt you
and we expect the same of our cyberspace
but why does the cyber poverty line even
matter
in the last 18 months
we have never been more dependent on our
connectivity cyberspace
from telecommunicating to work
to ordering groceries online during the
lockdown
do vaccine passports in an app
twice for organizations
many had to rapidly transition online
to survive
especially during the various lockdown
cyber security is no longer just a fun
greenfield playground
but
have now become
the underpinning of our very life
as cyberspace is the environment on
which we depend on to work
live in
we can learn so much more from the
parallels that we find in
health and safety
so
doing that learning from the coffee 90
crisis
video been told that
i should be getting advisory from
professionals specific guidance for my
unix equation
keep isolated to help limit the spread
and protect those who are
more vulnerable
perform testing so that we understand
where the virus is at
and that you have a benchmark
know whether you're infected
we rely on good engineering to develop a
vaccine an incident response to help
manage the whole situation
and chart a path out of it
the track management overarching it all
make sure that
it is a
proportional bonus
and that everyone is well informed and
communicate
and away
but as a
we have also come to understand that a
healthy society is critical to a product
with the parallel consequences we see
from copied 19
doing nothing
it's not really
what can small business afford
earlier
we know the typical profits from a
small business makes
we know the typical profits of a small
business and what they make per year
that's about 20 to 30
we say we consume all of that that's our
play
isn't a lot if we use the amount
budgeted by hit count we are looking at
about fifty five hundred dollars
when it starts that's about five
consolidates therefore
that's rough
and we're only talking about advisory
here like you know going to see your gp
to get advice on what to do next
we need to do better
but
hope is not all loss
for small businesses
are we totally screwed
no
no we are not
despite the adversity
we can do relatively well
by
taking small smart steps
one of them
is making smart technology choices
and to stand on the shoulders of giants
how powerful is this
in a previous role in security out of
the hundreds of
small business customers that we
monitored
only two
were vulnerable with this
surprisingly small numbers despite
expectations and
various commentaries out there
why
well we found that most
were running says email solutions such
as google workspace and microsoft 365
which
was not affected
that's kept them safe
let's shift the odd
favor
with three simple survival tips
smart choice of technology
good cyber hygiene
and
well when things go wrong
have an incident response plan
select an email provider with
secure defaults such as google workspace
or fast mail and use platforms which
have and continue to invest in security
more than you can as a small business
tools such as xero for accounting and
shopify for your ecommerce store
name a few examples
this will give you a solid base
to start with
but every service provider always just
say always say is that well
we take your security seriously
but do they really
google just released a
toolkit and checklist called the minimum
viable security product at msvp.dev
go through them ask your vendor those
questions and then let your
meter judge the response
it's a good start
take a look at the questions
it covers some of the topics that we
already talked about here
and
some of the other talks that has already
happened
at gerkon
like we're used to with covet 90 s aging
has four simple things that we can do to
keep good cyber hygiene
good manager
and use unique passwords for all sites
easier to remember
one strong password than multiple
different ones for each separate count
like
reusing tissues after you've sneezed
into it did it get unclean likewise
reusing passwords are
multi-factor authentication
enable then on all the things that you
can
so that if your passwords are lost or
stolen to a second layer of defense like
wearing masks a mask to protect yourself
from coving
even though you've been double waxed
possible
keep your software up to date
leave auto update on on your phones and
computers and all the other softwares
that you may have
like technique and vaccination for your
software keeping it continuously
protected
have a backup plan because
accidents do happen with your data
get a service like backplates to backup
your computer's data
it's like being able to reload a safe
beam for your data and critical systems
that covers the little things that we
can do to practice with hygiene
unfortunately
disasters do happen
good preparedness means
food
it means safety
likewise we need to be prepared inside
us
have a plan written up
print it out because
and print it out because you may not
have access to your technology
it should contain details such as who's
in charge
making all the decisions
and
make sure that they're empowered to do
so
a list of who to call for help
and who needs to know
this may include contacting your id
service provider
and your cyber insurance provider as
they may have established relationships
and resources
that may help you out
also your local computer emergency
response team
such as cert nz and acsc are a brilliant
resource
put down their contact details
so that you can make sure you are able
to reach them
then
write the steps you need to take down in
an action plan
so that you can just follow that
as
trying to figure out what to do
in a crisis can be more than a bit
challenging
some of these steps should include
calling your bank your internet service
provider your mobile phone provider to
make sure they take steps to help you
secure your accounts
often in such plans
include steps
needing to communicate the incident and
things that are happening
and actions people should take with
staff
customers
and stakeholders
find out what your obligations are under
any mandatory breach notification laws
and prepare all of these ahead of time
so that they are ready to send and you
have covered all that you need to save
hopefully these
three survival simple survival tips will
help shift the odds in your favor
or attempting to survive
well below the cyber poverty line
there's one more thing that you can do
let the good samaritans
there help
hackers
that would like to help you be more
secure
supporters and welcome us with open arms
and do so
by making that known to us
by having a responsible disclosure
policy go to policymaker.disclose.io
it started up there
hopefully this tips will give small
businesses a fighting
chance but
the problem persists
and
not
a substitute for all the cybers
there's a lot you need to do
if you're a technology product small
business
you should definitely check out jeremy
scott's talk from yesterday
really good off with lots of things that
would help you there
how can small business bought
we get good cyber safety outcomes
get a full package
well we've already seen how much they
cost
especially with the current cost of
participation
i don't have a solution
still trying to figure that one out
but what i do know
is that
if our experience with covet 19 is
anything to go by
doing nothing
that's not an option
with over 90 percent of small businesses
being small but being of businesses
being small business
in a landscape where cyberspace is
becoming more hazardous with the excess
with the cost of excess
health growing
what would we want our futures to be
like
practice
and do better
what can we
collectively do to tackle
medical cyber poverty
what can we do more sustainably beyond
the ones of reconsulting that we often
fall back to
let us hack ourselves
more hybrid resilient community
a kind of future
thank you for indulging in my rent
questions
on the chat and work on this together
reach out
i'm on discord
yeah
thanks
[Applause]