[Applause]
all right thank you everybody
it's good to be back up here again
and hello to everybody watching online
as well
today's talk is about eve online's
architecture
its networking and how it's changed
throughout the years
just start off with a quick apology um
there's pretty bullet point heavy talk
and uh i'm sorry for that
uh who am i um i am k ward at kzone on
twitter my pronouns are they them if my
parents are watching uh surprise
i study compsci at uc
i am a quote unquote biohacker if you
saw my talk last year you'll know about
that
and i'm also a bad electric skateboard
builder more recently
if you want advice on that don't ask me
and i'm a rocketry hobbyist so i've been
building rockets in my last few months
and i designed avionics for those
rockets
over here on the right you can see a
successful landing
even a crash landing as a landing
what is eve online
it's a science fiction mmo rpg video
game which is a lot of words
it's space based
and it's highly open world and it's
basically a gigantic sandbox so they
have a lot of
trading
mining combat
piracy there's essentially no rules
and it's also uniquely designed in a lot
of ways that i'll talk about in a bit
later
it's also an endless headline generator
it's the gaming press's favorite game
generally uh here's a couple from ign
uh how eve online's players of the wall
it costs seven hundred thousand dollars
and eve online breaks its own guinness
world record for the costliest video
game battle in history
i can't really convert from game money
to real money but
makes a good headline
this is also it's also called a
spreadsheet simulator
this is one of my spreadsheets from a
couple years ago
uh calculating profit if i were to buy
something ship it elsewhere and sell it
it's a very enthralling video game
but why is it unique
a typical mmo is many separate servers
on many different data centers
and it's a thing called instanced so you
have zones in the game world that are
let's say a town if you're playing wow
or something like that and you'll have
many copies of that town with only say
max 100 players or something in each one
to spread out the load so you don't have
10 million people trying to jump into
one area it's also relatively low
population per instance
eve online is a bit different
it's one server per solar system so
that's a zone there's only one
there's one data center there's also
technically others for the chinese
market and
there's test servers as well
there's no instancing whatsoever so
you can have as many people as you want
in
one solar system theoretically doesn't
really work as well um as we'll come to
see
and so what what's what's interesting
about that it's just a video game
well let's start from where it came out
this is what the game looked like in
2003 when it was released uh by ccp
games over in iceland
it was built around stackless python
which is a variant of c python that
removes the c stack
and also introduces a lot of features
like micro threading or tasklets
and some tasks are handled by native
code rather than python like rendering
or just getting in packets from the
network
it's been constantly expanded and
say two expansions every year to every
quarter
more recently
this is a diagram of the main cluster
that is referred to as tranquility
so you can see in the dotted line are
where clients connect to and they
connect to a proxy server which
keeps track of who is in what solar
system and routes them to
the main servers i handle the game logic
for that which called the soul servers
and those are every zone or solar system
is one of those and we refer to them as
a node and they talk with the sql server
so the sol is one solar system
um a high load
node might get an entire server to
itself
um whereas usually most of them are
chucked on maybe a dozen on one server
it's mostly handles python game logic
like who's shooting at who what's in
your inventory stuff like that
some critical tasks like physics are
done natively but
in the beginning that was about all it
was
and more tasks have been offloaded as
time goes on and more people have gone
into the game
sql server is a little interesting
it's one database for the entire
universe
it's ms sql and it's being constantly
thrashed read and write by
let's say it's 30 000 people active
these days
and there's a whole lot of stake to keep
track of what's in your inventory what
skills do you have things like that
some stats over there from 2010 it's a
total 1.4 terabyte database
2500 transactions per second and
175 million database calls per day
and this is what the client looked like
when it first came out version 1000
it was on stack list 2.2
so a little bit old
it was rendering physics were just
native code nothing else
um there was no protection on the python
byte code so it just came as a blob of
by code that you could just chuck in a
decompiler and just get everything back
i was plain tcp to the server no
encryption no compression initially
and some
very interesting programming in there
interesting comments like uh this error
message in the error log
playing chicken with a freight train a
sorry dude but the show must go on
i don't know what that actually means
there's another one
something uh word with default exception
handling
and this function
uber fn macho remote service call
i've been working with this client off
and on for like three years i don't know
what that function does still i have no
clue
but it is part of something called macho
net which is their massive networking
and rpc library they developed in-house
just for this game
um it induced packets from the
native code like low-level handler they
called net client
and it caches python objects that
don't change very often
and it calls server-side services and
gets data back like the market inventory
handling things like that
and there's also a relatively large
amount of overhead on it especially with
things like chat messages where
you might send a message as just hi or
something like that and it's a 70 byte
call to the server
and there's been quite a lot of changes
throughout the year
this screenshot is from trinity which is
around 2010 i think when they introduced
the new renderer and they've replaced it
multiple times
i think we're up to the third now it's
just been incrementally changed um
they've introduced packet encryption
around 2006 as well as compression
i think that was part of their chinese
market push
i think there may have been a
requirement
major content expansions the whole time
they've just increased the complexity of
the whole thing
introduce something called time dilation
which we'll come back to later try
handle some of the load
and optimizing around the global
interpreter lock which we'll get to now
this is a quote from the eve
devblog uh hereafter known as the damn
stink and gill or just gil for short
it's the global interpreter lock and on
the right here you can see a diagram of
how that works where
you can have many micro threads with
stack lists but they can only execute
one in a row they have to acquire the
girl
run code and then release it and then
something else can run
it's great for threading but that does
become a significant problem and it's
been extremely problematic for eve over
the years when you have 30 000 people
constantly updating a lot of state
and yeah
there's been quite a large investment in
trying to sign step it can't really
remove it there's a few projects that
are working on that but it hasn't really
panned out yet
so they've tried to kill it as best they
can
one approach
at least to reduce load was time
dilation
which players refer to as tie-dye and it
artificially slows down all of your
actions so say you're trying to fire a
weapon at somebody
normally it might take five seconds to
reload it will take 50 50 seconds 25
depends on the load of the server
it's not really enjoyed by most players
it doesn't doesn't make for a great
experience that's the dreaded symbol up
there that means 50
time dilation so every action takes 50
longer
so the big fleet battles that are in
headlines will be
down to 10
of normal speed
it's a bit of a band-aid fix it reduces
load but it makes the experience pretty
terrible
one of the first things they did to try
work around the gill was a project
called stackless io which was introduced
in 2008 and it offloads all the basic
tasks of networking
uh to a native code thread to
ingest the packet and do very basic
handling of it there's a diagram up
there of how python will request the
packet continue running while that
thread completes the request and
notifies
it sidesteps the girl but it's not
immune to it
and there's another thing they did a
little later on called carbon io
to try work around that a bit more it
was in 2011
and it takes that a step further by
processing entirely the packet and a
native thread so it'll
decrypt it decompress it and get it
prepared for python
entirely concurrently with everything
else
and it will accumulate those packets in
a pool um i can see up here
until python request it
so that speeded up networking quite a
bit and it was entirely outside the gill
and it was part of a project called blue
net which is still running i believe is
slowly offloading
more and more things that
macho net traditionally did in python
like remote service calls trying to
shift them over to
native code that can be done
concurrently
it did reduce load quite a bit this is a
graph of percentage cpu per user on a
node in blue is stackless io and in red
is carbon io i don't have
one for before either of those were
introduced but it would have been pretty
terrible
so it reduced the load quite a bit
i don't want to talk about another thing
related to carbon which is dust 514 it
was a
fps in the same universe as eve online
same setting but it also connected to
tranquility
so
you could for example an eve bombard a
planet from a spaceship and it would
show up in a battle in dust
and that would have been impossible
without their without them developing
carbon and carbon io which is their
framework for more real-time games
like a first-person shooter
and it ran from 2013 to 2016 uh may it
rest in peace
but there is a project trying to bring
it back that i wanted to shout out real
quick which is dust mu
they're working to
get the game up and running again on a
ps3 emulator
there are quite a few people who i've
spoken to who are very sad about the
game being shut down so
yeah and also oh
i just lost the bike oh there we go um
and there's also evmu which was
well is sort of it's been
on and off development since about 2006
it's a project to
re-implement the eve service stack in a
basic monolithic blob of c-plus plus
and it's been a very good reference and
it's still being worked on
there's also eve sharp which is aiming
to replicate the cluster architecture
originally
in c sharp
and yeah i know the guy that's working
on that is a great date
to summarize
eve is rather unique in the mmo space
obviously
i am not aware of any other
mmo with this kind of population that
does no sharding whatsoever
and ccp games tends to keep kind of
quiet about how their architecture does
work
most of this was scraped together from
dev blogs and
slide shows from 2005 that probably
shouldn't have been on the internet
so there
i do apologize for being a little detail
light but it is kind of hard to find
very in-depth stuff on this
um and they've sunk a huge investment
into sidestepping the gill
there is a project
that started up recently like has
managed to entirely rip the gill out of
python 3 but i'm not sure how stable
that is i don't think it'll be
picked up by any production companies
anytime soon
and it also shows the decisions that you
make decades ago can kind of haunt you
um the whole architecture was perfectly
fine with stackless python back in 2003
where they maybe had max
50 players or something in one system
but now it's grown to massive fleet
fights of
4 000 or more people and all the servers
are really straining under the load
um and i think that'll be all for me now