um yeah so um
before i get into this i just want to um
thank the organizers uh for basically
organizing several cons right
so they've had a whole lot of
contingencies and stuff um
due to covert and that sort of thing
uh yeah so
i mean i was i was on board a while ago
and i'm organizing one conference was
hard enough but
organizing all the contingencies and
stuff like that
just would have been
for me it would have been a nightmare so
um
can we just put our hands together for
the organizers
right
so we're going to be looking at the past
present and future
um of of basically standards and
and
and where i think um are we going
uh for basically um
our developers their teams um
stakeholders sea levels and that sort of
thing
so i'm just going to start off with um
two people types that i'm going to take
through
a good part of the talk
uh so yeah so two people types there's a
mainstream category which targets less
technical folk that's like your
stakeholders your managers
basically anyone that isn't uh doing
info sec as a job
and of course developers
and then this type two which uh
basically you're in for six well yeah
you are your information security
professionals which are doing it as a
day job
okay
so how do we use to measure the security
maturity of the software that our
development teams produced
so as you can see there's a lot of
up there's a lot of stuff there right
um and that's that's the problem
uh
so there's lots of docs to read lots of
standards to attempt to adhere to
and it was super confusing and still is
if you're trying to do it this way
so i'm just going to walk through some
of these docs um now to um
for you
for those that haven't uh seen these so
they are the application security
verification standard
and they're all pretty long
so
looking at like what
what 70 pages here 70 pages and most of
these are sort of like a similar sort of
length
so basically it's a
it's just a lot of stuff like a lot of
stuff to get your heads around
um checklists
and really stuff that's targeted at type
people
so the software assurance maturity model
a little bit shorter
these docks are all great for type 2
people
but for type 1 and for people just
entering the um security field and that
it's it's it's just a mental overload
now the um
this guy's a bit shorter than the rest
but this is um predominantly just uh our
checklists all the way through right
okay so the uh
approximately 75 cheat sheets that oh
wasp
that the cheat sheets project has given
us
and yeah there's a lot of good stuff in
there
but if
but if this is your first foray into um
basically getting security into your
project
or trying to adopt security into your
business or you know um you're not an
infosec
a pro then this sort of stuff's really
quite intimidating
uh the various top 10 lists so i've got
the um
the web top 10 the mobile top 10 the iot
i think there's one or two others as
well
um so i'm just going to
get rid of some of these the sends top
in the mitre type 25
okay so a list of 25 um what you'll see
is
there's quite a few similarities between
these two
for example there's some cross
pollination there was one there uh yeah
i think
was
it placed like it placed 17 or something
yeah
yeah down here so you've got lists right
well okay so we've got two lists here as
a newcomer you're looking at that
and trying to prioritize you're trying
to fit model
so okay on one
hand it's number one and on the other
one it's
17 places down the list so it's not that
important so how important is it right
so there's all this sort of stuff
happening right
you've got the cisq code quality rules
in fact csq has got a lot of great
content
but if you're a developer or you know a
manager or anyone that's sort of
organizing a development related stuff
and you're coming into this
it's it's it's mental overload
and of course assist controls most well
yeah a lot of us here are familiar with
those great content but
just just too much and too complex
for
for type one people
so scary stuff yeah
so
so there's been a lot of manual work
i'm sure we had lots of tools
but most of them we had to drive them
manually
and it felt like we weren't really
getting anywhere
so going to the prison
so many of us are still trying to hold
on to the past
that's this
or at least don't yet understand that
there's a better way
so there's been significant improvements
in the information and tooling
available recently like as in the last
few months
there's some new standards that are
starting to emerge and that are starting
to reflect this as well
security documentation is starting to
grow up
and we have this newcomer the nist
almost standard
so nist's trying to make a simpler
smaller more achievable standard
that can be understood by both types of
people but it's specifically targeted at
type 1 people
it's prescriptive it's less intimidating
it's measurable and it's concise
but it's not technically a standard yet
so let's have a look at it
and the accompanying dock
so there's
there's 12 technique classes they call
them here oh sorry um 12 techniques
that's this row here
and you've got a few technique classes
there
right so that looking at that looks
really simple right looks like there's
not actually a lot there
and there
isn't if we have a look at the actual
accompanying dock
page four
here's our abstract
okay i can't see that there
um
so there was an executive order
to improve the nation's cyber security
which directed the nist to recommend a
minimum set of standards for software
testing within 60 days
so this document describes 11 although
it's 12 with the last one being fix your
bugs
um
yeah that describes 12 recommendations
for software verification techniques as
well as providing supplemental
information and blah blah blah so
there's 11 points there and that's your
11 points plus your fix your stuff
which is number 12.
so we have a look at the contents
well there's not much there really
you've got all the supplemental material
which is again still not a lot there
and you've got these points here so
so threat modeling you've got like what
two paragraphs
and
automated testing
yeah
a couple of paragraphs
each one of these is super short and
just just really easy to digest
and there's a good reason for that
so
i've taken the table from the new nist
standard and extended it to include a
tools column
cool
so that's our next standard there
basically
and we've got
some tools there
so these are basically
some tools i added on that i i consider
to be best of breed
that basically satisfy
what's required in those 12 techniques
so besides the threat modeling so i've
got three blue lines there
besides the first line which is threat
modeling material evil test conditions
this line here
and fuzzing
the rest of these tools lend themselves
really well to being automated
and added to your editor's ides and
build pipelines
so an area of tooling that automatically
does what
most of what we used to do manually so
our tooling's starting to mature right
so
yeah just a bit of uh so we've got oh
sweet modding cheat sheets and we've got
uh so so this is a book series that i
wrote it's available free online uh
holistic infosec for web developers
um it's available free online to read i
did a proof of concept in there which
ended up um turning into a fully fledged
project which is i was purple team
bit of a disclaimer there uh evil test
conditions is also in holistic invasive
web developers the rest of these tools
uh
yeah are like i said what i would
consider to be best of breed
and as cheap as possible that i could
find or free
which is
even better right
okay so let's look to the future
oh no not their futures achieved
oh no not that one
ah yeah that's better
okay so i believe for type one people
we were going as a mix of the nist type
standard with most of the detail being
taken care of by automated tooling
this is all part of infosec
commoditization and the evolution right
so
so the way i see this happening and it
is happening already is that the tooling
is starting to basically teach
those type one people so we've got the
type two people that are creating the
tools and the type one now rather than
going through
just multitudes of docs and standards
and
trying to navigate an insane amount of
information
basically if you um
take the likes of that nist standard
take those tools or similar tools
and um throw them into your ides and um
your build pipelines
and that sort of thing
basically get them automated those tools
will start to teach
you or a type 1 people i'm about
security as you're going
so yeah it's it's
it's no longer a mental overload
yeah so as developers you can expect to
see the level of technical detail
lifting so as to focus on more abstract
topics and activities
such as verification as opposed to the
hands-on testing that we've done in the
past
standards are going to continue to
become higher level and the tool chains
will continue to increase their support
of them
so
yeah i can see all yawning
relax
you've got this type 1 people
there's no need to stress
with the new runtime application
self-protection type tooling as well
rasp just another acronym for you
so we've got the likes of uh screen
h div and some others
uh your application your applications
can now start to defend themselves
without are you writing additional code
so i'm just going to give you a quick
look at the
screen docs
okay so with screen you basically
consume a library
they target a few different languages
uh so you consume a library um as a
dependency of your application or
service or whatever it is you're writing
uh you've got a micro agent
in that library that sits within your
running code and it communicates with
the cloud-based screen platform
and it applies dynamic instrumentation
to points of the app's code so
it's so it's like aspects of
aspect-oriented programming
it monitors your application at each
instrumentation point
and performs security responses as
directed by the security engine
that resides within the microagent
so big thanks to the star of the talk
max
ah this is my uh
cat my main queen cat he's
this is this is where he normally sits
when i'm working
and of course you for listening to me
ramble
seriously
[Laughter]
okay um so as i mentioned uh purple
teams is a project i've been working on
it's at about 3.8 years now um it's it's
it's starting to come to maturity this
is a shirt
as you can see
if you want one
then answer this question correctly
how many techniques are there in the new
nist standard
who said that
yep
no you're right
but can you get the bonus
how much of the technique
classes had the most techniques
it's a guy i'll go back to it
uh actually it's up here isn't it
dynamic analysis
cool so
i'll give you a i'll um
get someone to take it to you
soon
yep that's it that's my talk
you