thanks.thanks yeah
good afternoon I'm Dave from University
of Florida I'm here to present our paper
on Android security this is a
collaboration with some some research
America all right does anyone remember
this sound all right you can tell you if
you have ever log into a BBS is probably
that you own a Hayes modem like this
that is the sound when damadam trying to
get connected to the BBS and what
happens under the hood is the computer
software issues eighty command to
control the bottom to establish a
establish this connection in this case
for example we have two Madame's and the
computer software issues that a command
called a TD to instruct model a a $2.00
and after ringing for a while the remote
computer software issues a command
called a ta instructing Molly B to
answer the call thus the two bottoms got
connected and thus the two computers and
after while the remote computer might
issue a th command which have to call
thus closing the communication these
eighty commands are designed to consume
atoms they are as out as BBS but what
you probably haven't realized is we can
control Android phones using 80 commands
so in this talk I'm going to talk about
the systematic study we have done of 80
commands weaving the Android ecosystem
for some of you this might not be news
you might be familiar with previous
works discovering 80 commands in smart
phones such as the 380 command
discovered on Samsung phones including
enabling USB debugging and Wi-Fi a black
top a black hat talk also reviewed how
to flash malicious firmware images using
a TMS and we can find a bunch of 80
commands listed on XDA forum as well
unfortunately this ad-hoc previous work
have only touched the tip
to the iceberg as a result the
prevalence is still unclear we still
have no idea how many 80 commands are
there inside the Android ecosystem the
functionality is too unclear
unlike the standardized 80 commands most
of these commands are not documented at
all the security impact is still unclear
by the time of writing only few IT
commands are well known to have security
impact what we found was this 80 command
act as a largely vendor specific API
exposing a vast array of functionalities
and this can be accessed on certain
phones simply by plugging a USB cable
eating often without the user of the
owner even noticing so in the rest of
the talk we're gonna show how we did
this system Atticus study the first
question is how to find these 80
commands so accept OSP and lineage moose
of this Android customizations are
closed source so we need a way to
extract 80 commands from the firmware
images directly the second question is
how to test them we need a framework to
send out this 80 command and collect a
response from the phones the last
question is how to abuse them so we
probably need to combine both static and
dynamic analysis tools to figure out how
this command flow within the system and
how certain commands are processed by
native demons or applications before we
start let's take a look at this 80
commands again they were designed to
consume atoms the initial 80 command was
invented by Dennis Hayes we have seen
the ATT command which is used to tower
number as the advancing of wireless
communications we have itu-t ETSI
defined ET command sets which are used
to support gsm 3g 4g one example here is
this et-plus cmgs
which is used to send out a SMS message
and then we have this Android specific
80 commands this 80 commands are not
standardized and they were created or
added mentally due to vendors
customization why exam here is this 80
plus USB debug
which enables USB debugging and weaving
the Android system if you look into this
android-specific ad commands we'll see
they basically follow this this pattern
they always start with 80 a short for
attention followed by an expansion
symbol which could be % + + % also al
followed by the actual command name as
well as optional parameters so let's
start our systematic by finding these 80
commands within the Android ecosystem
step 1
we crawled and downloaded over 2000
former images across 11 different
vendors and surprisingly this step is
not as straightforward as one would
expect some vendors tried their best to
prevent us from downloading their stock
from her image either by making them
really hard to find or by asking a lot
of required information and third-party
websites also often deploy traffic and
true because they believed we were
launching TOS attacks because each
former image is a is a around 1 gigabyte
but finally we made it and once we have
all the former images we go to step 2 we
try to unzip or unpack this firmer image
and go through each file and this step
tends to be more challenging and
annoying mainly due to the variance of
the image format even for the same
vendor the image format keeps changing
in the worst case we need to find an
alpaca per vendor per Android version
and perform model once we're inside the
firmware image we go through each file
if this is a zip file we unzip it if
this is a file system file we mount we
mount it if it is a PP file we to camp
out it if it is a binary file we're a
string command to extract all the
symbols and once we have all the files
we just grab the 80 command based on a
complex regex we designed so in short we
want to find as many potential 80
commands as possible while keeping the
false positive low and then step 3 we
process and parse all these potential 80
commands to find those that are likely
to be real ET commands
and receive them into a database so in
the end we discovered 3,500 unique ET
commands we also crowd some
specifications and collected over 200
standardized ET commands if we look at
the Android version distribution among
or 2004 images we have covered Android
version version from two point one to
seven point wine but time of crawling
Android eight was not widely adopted the
majority version of our firmware images
are the newer versions starting from
Android 4.4 to 7.1 if we compare with
the platform versions from the Google
Play Store we'll see our data seems to
be well aligned with a rewarder usage
and then we look at the 80 command
distribution per vendor the right figure
is possible except some exceptions on
Android 4.0 X versions the average
number of 80 commands Weaving Google is
around 100 note that half of them are
not standardized 80 commands and then
the middle figure is for Samsung as you
can see that the the number of 80
commands keeps increasing as the Android
version grows and after Android 4.3 the
average number of 80 commands for
Samsung is around 400 the right figure
is for LG similar with Samsung the
number of 80 commands keeps increasing
and the average number is around 300
as you can see vendors do add more 80
commands during their customizations so
once we have all the 80 commands we need
to test them besides the basic
functionality we also want to know if
some command found from one winter would
work for the other winter or if there
exists some command which would behave
differently across vendors the only
setup we need is a USB connection
between an Android phone and a host
computer and we also require all these
phones to expose a USB CDC ECM interface
which is also known as the USB monami
interface and this interface would
ac report on the host machine for us to
send out the ad commands note that in
most cases this USB functionality is not
act is not active so we use usb switcher
to activate this interface by switching
the current the USB configurations this
USB switcher was initially designed for
Samsung phones and we extended to
support other vendors and once we have
this simple setup ready we implemented
automation script who send out 80
commands and click the response from the
phones
one of the most questions here is how
many phones to actually have this USB
modern interface to answer this question
we examined 14 different Android devices
it turns out six of them exposed this
modern interface by default four of them
can expose this USB functionality after
being routed amount is 10 devices we
choose eight to test against 80 commands
including three Samsung 2 LG 2 Asus and
wind access while some 80 command
response might be fairly informative all
of them would just return ok and in this
case we need to combine both static and
dynamic analysis to have a better
understanding of this 80 command as well
as finding vulnerabilities so we start
with finding the top 5 binaries which
contains the most number of 80 commands
here we focus on the top 1 binaries
which are the real library for Google in
native demon called 80 distributor for
Samsung and a native demon called a TD
for LG and then we enable adb debugging
and use lock ad to see how this command
flow within the system it turns out both
80 distributor and a TD are the first
stores of 80 commands weaving the system
and then we use either Perl to see how
certain commands are processed weaving
these native demons
although we were not able to closely
examine all of the 3500 a unique 80
commands we put some interesting ones
here in the next few slides so this
command pulled the phone into download
mode enabling firmware flashing directly
this command factory reset the phone
does using all these data and if you
accidentally break your LG phone into
the blue screen on the right we have
discovered two command which can I'll
break your LG phone and we also
discovered one command which can break
your LG phone and if you're interested
in free breaking service you can't DM it
directly command here bypass Android
security mechanism yes we can make a
call helper call on circle just from a
USB cable it does not matter whether or
not the screen is locked
this command changes the IMEI value
which is the unique identity of the
mobile device this command enables ADB
debugging again this key lock command
unlocks the the screen lock even if a
TCP protected this command it allows us
to singing out keep as SMS messages and
even connecting to the internet so again
all we need is a USB connection then we
can send out these key commands to to
the phone's command is showing here
either leave some sense of information
or ease further exploit ation we found
3480 commands falling into this category
this command provide a lot of
information about the fallen a system
including ma Y or thousand usage one
example here is this 80 plus they have
come in full as you can see it gives you
a lot of information about the phone I
including IMEI this to command lists all
the 80 commands supported by the
baseband processor and we also use these
to command to cross-check all the 80
commands we extracted from the firmware
and found zero missing
these two commands read proc FS and C's
FS on Linux as we will show later in the
demo we use this command to read
arbitrary data under the SD card like
this we also discovered another category
of 80 commands enabling extra debugging
capabilities such as cysts trees and a
seams this command are only available to
Infinium baseband processors and the
Intel Android USB driver supports this
functionality naming it the modem 80
proxy although we're not able to enable
this functionality without routing the
phone this command have already mean
have already being used to reverse
engineering the baseband processor so
for more information please check out
the link our slides will be available on
using x website zone commands shown here
are related with hayden menus these
hidden menus are mentally designed for
debugging and testing purpose at this
point it's not clear how an attacker
could use these values to exploit the
phone but they do impose some security
concerns and another adopter notice here
is the commands containing stream VZW
it seems like vendors also add in UAT
commands for carriers
alright this demo time will demonstrate
two attacks the first attacks unlock the
screen and send out a touchscreen event
to operate the phone just like a real
human being I'll play with the phone
the second attack enables USB debugging
and leverages the praça FS read 80
command to launch it confuse deputy pass
traversal reading arbitrary data under
the SD card this next attack will
demonstrate from start to finish
the ability to bypass the LG g4s lock
screen and enable USB developer options
all without user interaction
notice that we typed in a passcode and
it was incorrect but even if we've
forgotten the passcode if we have access
to the
human interface we can issue a special
command that allows us to bypass the
lock screen additionally we can automate
touch events to reach the settings menu
go to the developer options enable
developer options bypass any prompts and
then finally enable USB debugging
allowing us to get an ADB shell from
this point it would be able to issue
arbitrary commands to the phone with the
privilege of ADB but this includes the
ability to install applications for this
next demo we will be directly
interacting with the LG g4 via the new
80 command interface first we switch the
phone into the 80 command mode and then
we open an 80 interact prompt which
allows us to interact an issue and
receive responses to 80 commands
once the prompt is established we issue
a simple command to get some information
about the phone but next we issue a
special command found out lg devices
which allows us to enable ADB without
developer options notice on the right
side we are now receiving logcat data
directly from the phone without having
developer options labelled this gives us
insight into what's happening in the
phone as we issue a TV mat the next
command is the 80 program this was used
by developers to view the proc file
system to get insight into what
processes are running but we have found
there perhaps reversal vulnerability in
this command which allows us to read
arbitrary files from the phone as long
as the privilege of the 80 command
distributor is sufficient cool I hope
you enjoyed our demo special thanks to
Grand who made this this video demo now
it's time to talk about medications and
and fixes so from vendors perspective
the most straightforward fix would be to
remove this USB modeling interface
because it seems unlikely that normal
users would need this functionality but
just in case where it seems impossible
to remove this USB functionality we can
always restrict the access to this USB
functionality just as we need to route
the phone to access this functionality
another good security mechanism is to
you use whitelist so by default all
these 80 commands should be blocked on
unless permitted within the whitelist
from users perspective the good news is
both Samsung and LG have issued security
updates because we reported this
vulnerability earlier on February so if
you have Android phones please update
your Android shift out what are we down
here well nope as we mentioned all these
Android specific specific ad commands
are not documented so we build an online
database to document their usages
parameters and Android firmware you
firmware information
containing these diss commands although
whilst you're working on feeding up more
information for each for each eighty
command but the basic query interface is
there we also open source our tools for
the 80 command testing I will be on the
draw market next year looking for
research positions in both industry and
academia if you are interested in my
research please visit my personal
website for more information
thanks I can take questions now hi John
Criswell University of Rochester so
forgive my ignorance but it wasn't clear
to me whether this is something that's
remotely exploitable over cellular or
whether it's something that's only
exploitable once you have physical
access to the device Inc and again a USB
connection to it right now it requires a
USB connection although we're working on
something else like Bluetooth because it
turns out Bluetooth also contains 80
command so probably in the future we can
remotely exploit this from Bluetooth
module we're still working on that okay
thank you
Karl Koecher University of Washington so
one of the most surprising things that I
saw here is it looked like a lot of
these 80 commands were being processed
at like the Android or OS level as
opposed to the baseband level right and
I was wondering if you found any issues
like the baseband level or if you
thought you might be missing certain 80
commands from that you can pull out of
baseband images for example so I guess
like there are two questions the first
question is we focused on the Android
specific ET commands although we do find
some like modern specific commands like
a TD but right now we are we focusing on
Android specific 80 commands we also
find some commands within the modern
image but again like that is not our
focus right now I think the second
question was sir
I was just wondering if so it sounds
like your focus was on the the OS level
8 yes yes I was just wondering if you
also found anything with the the
baseband 80 commands but it sounds like
that wasn't your focus right um yes
basically yes ok
thanks thanks did you have any
opportunities to fuzz the real interface
you know what like the first step we did
it was try to send out whatever garbage
to the to the e 2 command interface but
in Saudis does not work that well then
we start to realize let's try to find
all the 80 commands and try to use them
to fuzz the fall rather than just
sending out some garbage
so did you did you get any chance then
to see where and this kind of ties into
the last question of where you might
have some way of testing baseband
security going through this interface
from the software OS side into the
sort of that point-to-point between the
base band modem and the android drivers
you know what this this reminds me
another USB interface which is called
diagnostic interface and some somehow
like I've seen a lot of Wacom
proprietary software which can basically
use that interface to connect with the
model and to see like all of these air
packet in the fly or something but I
have no idea how to trigger this from a
normal like USB modem interface okay
cool thanks thanks