everyone my name is na Husein i'm going
to be presenting dependency preserving
data compact Shen for scalable forensic
analysis in the recent years large
companies have been the target of
stealthy long term long-running attacks
this attacks spans in the durations of
months to years once these attacks are
detected forensic analysis is initiated
to find the entry point of this attack
and the impact of this attacks from the
system so - for performing forensic
analysis data worth of four months -
ranging to years needs to be stored in
the system the amount of data that it
requires to be stored gets large gets
pretty large very quickly for example in
an enterprise with 1,000 hosts it can
produce a petabytes worth of petabytes
of data per year the issue is not just
with the storage cost to perform
forensic analysis on this star on this
huge amount of data can take the time it
can take and dramatically slow down so
the need for also the need for data
compaction is needed here our goal is to
work with a readily available system
called data such as Windows ETA W and
Linux audit logs even though you can use
even though final or fine-grained
dependency tracking can improve the
forensic analysis such tracking is not
feasible in the it can not be feasible
in large-scale deployment most of this
fangame trap dependency tracking
requires instrumentations that is why as
there could be hundreds of banana
application running in the system it
becomes unfeasible to deploy them our
same goal is able to reduce the data
volume that does not change the forensic
analysis result so events can be dropped
that care will not change the result of
the forensic analysis our main
contribution is the two novel graph
based reduction techniques called full
dependence and source
dependence preservation is in these two
reduction techniques were able to reduce
five to nineteen times of the total
number of events in the logs we have
developed efficient algorithms and
optimization techniques for implementing
these reductions this reduction this in
algorithms and optimization techniques
allows us to analyze that graph and
analyze the graph by 1 million events
per second per core we have implemented
compact data representation techniques
which allows us to store the data in
offline mode which is 35 times smaller
than the actual audit data also our in
our graph each one of the events at less
than 5 bytes to be stored in memory in
the original data most of the forensic
analysis most of the forensic analysis
considers the content of the log as a
dependence graph in this graph the nodes
are subjects or objects subjects being
the process and objects being file and
network connection etc the edges between
these two nodes are edges between nodes
are considered as the dependents which
are time-stamped events oriented in the
direction of the information flow for
example at time 3 information is flowing
for the node P to node C so see how the
dependents are not P at time 3 to
perform in forensic analysis we mark but
to find the entry point of an attack we
mark one of the nodes as suspicious and
we backtrack it to find the entry point
of that attack for example here if we
mark the node C as suspicious we can
backtrack it to the network address
AECOM once we have found the entry point
of an attack we can perform forward
analysis from it and see which are the
nodes in the system that got comm
potentially compromised for example in
this example be calm if you considered
v.com as the entry point of an attack
and perform for it forward analysis from
it P eql Elkin could be potentially
compromised but in the but C is not
compromised here because even though C
has a depend
on the note P the dependents arrived
before the note P got compromised so
here are some of the reduction
techniques the reduction techniques can
be categorized into two categories log
based and graph based log based
techniques examine a sequence of events
and depending on the local information
it decides if it can be eliminated
without affecting the dependencies graph
based techniques construct a dependence
graph which uses the graph reachability
property to prune out any sort of
redundant events it can leverage the
global context for more powerful
reductions so let's look at a very
simple log based reduction techniques
where it merges the successive events if
they are identical for example here the
first two events first two events in the
log and the second two events are
identical so this events can be merged
into one but the problem arises if there
are other intervening events in between
those successive in between those
identical events for here
a reading from f1 is the intervene by
the by the event be writing to f2 even
though they are completely independent
events the run merging technique cannot
perform any sort of reductions or them
shoe at all improved on this idea by
allowing the continuing mode merging
this identical events if the intervening
events are performed on a different note
or different objects or subjects so here
even though so a reading from f1 or and
be writing to f2 are completely
different events performed on different
objects and subjects so this can be
merged together so the reduction is now
performed but the limitations of their
technique is they take the context they
don't take the global context into
considerations they tale look at the
local context so which does not switch
which it becomes very difficult to
perform much on very common scenarios
such as pipes in this example
the process P and Q are communicating
each other through a pipe II but as
there are some intervening events been
between them and the the their technique
and not perform any merging as you can
see and even an outgoing even from the
note e at time three is happening in
between the incoming edge at time two
and four in our so here's where we give
our approach on full dependence
preservation we look at so we allowed to
continue emerging the events if the
interpreting events don't alter the
global dependency of the notes for
example over here the dependence the
global dependence of the node P does not
change between the time 2 to 6 so this
events can be merged into one also for
the note e at time 3 to 7th only glue
the global dependence it has is on the
note P other than that it does not have
any other global dependence so this
three events can also be merged as a
result we can perform the reduction and
this is the reduction reduced graph we
can get we also proposed another
technique of source dependence
preservation which takes a step further
from of full dependence and uses the
intuition for forensic analysis to
perform further reductions on it as I
mentioned before forensic analysis
during forensic analysis we perform
backward analysis to get to the entry
point of the source node and from the
source node we perform forward analysis
so the only in this in this preservation
technique we only preserve the
dependency from the source nodes the
source not being there's no incoming
edges for example in this example if
dash has a source dependence on the node
F which is introduced at time four but
the events at time five and six does not
introduce any new source dependence for
the node F dash it has already
introduced and it can only introduce the
dependence on node F so these two events
can be dropped
source dependence preservation is the
past more powerful technique than full
dependence preservation which can drop
all the edges that those introduce a new
dependency on source nodes even as so as
you can see have seen that car taking
into consideration global context we can
perform further reduction but taking
about it even though it is powerful it
is very expensive to compute on a
time-stamped graph because the reachable
the calculating the reach ability on the
graph becomes the calculating the
disability on the graph increases
linearly with the size of the size of
the data so also we cannot like a
standard graph we cannot cache and reuse
we cannot cache the dependency because
the dependency on the x ten graph
changes over time so we cannot cache
them and reuse them so our solution to
it is converting it to a standard graph
by versioning the nodes
although versioning because versioning
tayyar increases the storage space we
have developed optimization techniques
that reduce the number of versions by 20
times on an average just one in our
system only one point two six versions
are created per nodes here is a time
stand graph that has been converted to a
version graph where a version is created
whenever there is an incoming edge to a
node for example
snor is the single incoming edge so we
create one versions of it G has two
incoming edges so we create two versions
for the node G and so on so now we
propose some of the optimization
techniques so one for our first
optimization technique is redundant edge
optimization so in this technique we say
that if there's already an incoming edge
from the latest node to your current
node then any future node nodes can be
discarded here there's already an edge
from between from s 2 to G 3 so we can
drop discard that edge s 2 to g5 and
enhance it reduce the number of versions
it's the same similarly we can do that
for T the node T
another optimization techniques is the
redundant node optimization where if a
node has not been observed or has does
not have any outgoing edges we can merge
we say that if any for any incoming
edges we do not create any new versions
for it
for example here s0 does not have any
outgoing edges so there is no change
being made so so there's no Reserve it
wasn't observed so this s 0 and s 2 can
be merged into one node same goes for G
0 and T 0 in ours we have also performed
some cycle collapsing optimizations
where if two nodes are in a cycle we
discard the events between these two
nodes and consider them as a super node
so here is the optimized see here is one
of the graph the time stream graph which
has been converted into the optimized
version graph in our system Excel now
I'm going to talk about experimental
evaluation so in our evaluation data set
our system perform in the down for
transparent computing second second
adversary engagement we collected data
we had data from Windows and Linux
desktop which may have spanned on the
terms of seven days this data contained
benign activities such as reading from
reading from the web browser email
client reading writing to files etc it
also contained attacks involving the
full apt lifecycle such as drop and
execute file exfiltration privilege
privilege escalation etc we also
collected data from our lab spanning
from 7 days from a file server web
server and a mail server this data also
spent on seven days so here the number
of events that contained in each one of
the data for example the nearest sister
of there were 73 million events our web
servers there were fourteen point four
event million events
so using our reduction techniques here's
the amount of reduction we achieve on
those data set the first three data sets
are the data set that we collected in
our lab the last two ones are the one
from the adversarial engagement second
engagement we also implemented Shu a
tells algorithm to compare our work with
them as you can see our full dependence
as soldiers dependents perform much
better than their technique as it takes
the global context into consideration
here the average number of nodes our
average number of versions
we create in using our each one of our
reduction technique optimization
techniques with no optimization in our
system each one of the nodes would
generate 25.5 eight node versions per
node with adding redundant edge
optimization it goes down to nine point
one four for version four nodes and
adding redundant node optimization it
further goes down to three point zero
one versions per node and adding cycle
collapsing optimization we go to down to
one point two six versions per node
using our compact data representation
native techniques we are able to store
the data for offline investigations wear
it for offline investigations so we can
store the data in a compact way which is
35 times smaller than the original audit
log which is 24 gigabytes and using
source dependence you can further reduce
it and store it before which is smaller
than four which is 41 times smaller than
the original log size the dependency so
this was the main memory size it takes
for each one of our graphs for the whole
graphs we had for all the five data set
we had 100 million events which can be
stored in a compact way in memory only
for only 26 megabyte using full
dependence and is in source dependence
it takes 248 megabytes
our system also participated in the
DARPA 3rd engagement program here's some
preliminary results because the
engagement happened after the submission
of the papers we did not we were not
able to investigate it further and
investigate it further so that this
information is not in the paper the data
side the of the third engagement was 10
times larger than the ones in the second
engagement the Linux desktop had around
800 million events which we were able to
reduce 70 times using full dependence
our Windows desktop contained 70 million
events which was reduced by 10 times
using our full dependence so the summary
from this we can say that the number the
larger the data size gets we are able to
achieve further reductions on it the
main reason is having long running
processes because long running processes
becomes the dependent the blared global
dependence becomes stable as time moves
on so as a reason full dependence was
able to eliminate most of the operations
so here's the impact of reductions on
our forensic analysis in our paper in
theory we are able to say we have proved
that full dependency preserves the
forward and backward analysis results
for all nodes source dependency also
preserves the forward full a backward
inner edges all four source nodes but in
fact in practice we also have seen the
similar behavior in the during the DARPA
adversity in exercise during the
engagement we did not have any prior
knowledge about the attacks with perform
forensic analysis in real time while the
full dependency reduction was going on
our our analysis started when it was
when an attack is detected by our system
sleuth and we perform forward and
backward analysis from that point on
here is an attack graph that has been
generated in our system automatically
this is this is generated completely
automatically where and
Nexxus was dropped and execute we
performed some information gathering and
information gathering and exfiltration
and also there are some people as
escalations to it this graph was
completely generated automatically in
your system so here's the number of
entities as you can see from here that
number of entities using any of the any
one of the reduction techniques does not
change if we define with the base
techniques the number of entities and
with food with any sort of Reda
reductions we see the number of the
number of entities has not changed in
this case for both of the all of this
attacks that we seen here the some of
the related works related to the log
reductions logs ec pro tracer MPI all of
them uses fine-grained dependency
tracking we mainly target the core
screen auditing system which can be
actually deployed in large enterprises
xu Etta's systems performs log reduction
based on the local context which is
which is why we is unable to achieve
high reduction than ours there are other
papers related to reductions such as
provenance collection techniques pass
performs run merging technique and many
more that is discussed in our paper so
in summary we have developed some highly
effective reduction techniques for the
audit logs where we achieve five to
nineteen times reductions or the number
of events we have developed efficient
algorithm and optimizations for full
dependency a source dependence technique
we presented compact data or
representative techniques to achieve
over a magnitude of reduction in storage
and main memory size thank you I'll take
any questions
[Applause]
hi Adam Bates University of Illinois a
really interesting work I had a question
about the source dependence algorithm
are you applying that on individual
nodes or with respect to like a network
of nodes you mean for each node what is
the dependence that you are storing so
the with the source dependence the idea
is that we preserve reach ability to the
source nodes that don't have any
incoming edges right so are you doing
that on each node in isolation or sorry
I'm using conflation here each computer
in isolation are you applying that or
are you doing this across the
distributed system so currently our
system is for our host basis or the
implemented in the per host so it'd be
really curious to see it seems like
there might be some troubles applying
this in the distributed context because
the source nodes you're preserving reach
ability to our sockets that represent a
connection to another machine right and
so it seems like there's a risk that
we're conflating you know multiple
events that actually represent
autonomous units of work that are
happening on that other machine and so
like looking back to the our tag paper
there might be issues with tracing
multiple workflows that are happening
between two different hosts so if the so
we do have yes we are working on
implementing the distributed system
where in inside the intranet there will
be multiple hosts running on multiple of
these machines and we would know
actually to how to connect between them
okay this is actually we are currently
working on right on - thanks
any other questions
hi John Criswell University of Rochester
not so much a question but a comment you
know while watching your presentation
your algorithms look a lot like the
algorithms that we use for analyzing and
optimizing programs in the compiler
world all right so your versioning looks
a lot like SSA construction your cycle
reduction you know look we're just
creating strongly connected components
is a lot like call graph analysis in
data in the DSA algorithm or or like
cycle analysis and Anderson's points to
analysis algorithm have you been
inspired by program analysis algorithms
and if not do you think it'd be worth
looking at that literature to see if
there might be something that might
inspire further optimizations of these
graphs thank you for the comment yes I
will definitely we haven't I haven't
looked at it and personally into those
algorithms I haven't seen some of them
and we have been our main intuition was
to use some of this versioning
techniques which which in general just
says that it should inflate the size of
our system inference analysis but we
showed that using those versioning
techniques we are trying to reduce the
data size and definitely I'll look at
some of more further optimization
techniques in the compiler and see if we
can further use it in our system yeah
it'd be interesting to see if there's
actually some kind of correspondence
between these two worlds right because
they're both they're both looking a data
flow is they're both looking at you know
dependences and whatnot so it looks may
not be quite the same but it looks
pretty similar right right thank you