good afternoon everyone my name is jung
eunji I'm from Georgia Tech today I'm
gonna talk about our work on refine
about attacking mastication in the
setting of multi host so nowadays there
are more and more attacks that involve
multiple hosts for example in 2015 some
the Taiwan first a bank suffered from an
attack that steals money from their ATM
machines which involves lateral
movements of multiple hosts and also
that in the cabinet threats attackers
used persistent and lateral movements
also to to infiltrate the the financial
Institute's and also that interestingly
in the black hat of last year 2017
researchers from NCC a group proposed
the kid pond which uses not only the get
crime site but also the kids server side
to exclude to exfiltrate at the data
from the client site through the server
side and then finally get to the
attacker side so after that the attack
happens so our so our goal is to aim is
to investigate at these attacks with
with the goals of accuracy efficiency
and and of course supporting multiple
hosts in this background so this work of
focuses on the on the challenges when we
achieve these goals and our
corresponding approaches so first let's
see a high-level example of the cross
host attack so the the the attacker
tries to accelerate some sensitive data
from the from the client side through
the server side and finally to the
attacker side he scans the power system
of the ads the client side and he
selectively pick
file a and then to send it through the
server-side and then to to the attacker
side so during the investigation so
people may ask questions like what data
will leaked exactly to the attacker was
file being leaked or was file a if we
know that it's far away that is leaked
so how was file a leaked step in step so
what's the nature of this attack so in
order to answer these these questions so
we need to so we need to first to tell
that exactly file a has been leaked not
with the with the false results like
file B or C is actually leaked and also
that we need to find out which what's
the data dependencies between these
multiple hosts so that we can analyze
them a step step by step by step so this
this challenge is aggregated when we
turn to a peer-to-peer network setting
so we need to find out like only these
hosts have been involved in the attack
not not the remaining ones so the
question is that do we have to serialize
these convoluted data dependencies
between the these multiple hosts can we
instead apply that the analysis in in
parallel and aggregate the results after
we complete these at these analysis
which has been done in parallel so when
we analyze these data flows across
different hosts so we find it as
challenging so we summarize these
challenges in here so first that it has
the false positive dependencies like in
the previous example so we need to tell
that actually only file a has been
leaked not the file B or C and also that
the data dependencies are
across these multiple hosts should be
tracked correctly in the analysis and
also that because we're not only dealing
with one one single host but multiple
host Saudi so the analysis costs include
including the analysis time and the
memory cost is amplified so how can we
give a reasonable analysis cost so we so
we solve the first appositive dependency
our first challenge by using a dynamic
link analysis which has been known to be
able to to dynamically instrument the
program at instruction level instruction
by instruction so that it can tell
exactly the exact data flow there are
mainly two categories of T analysis are
used in the that has been presented are
the first category like the cloud like
cloud fins or the tank exchange they
focus on using the tank arise directly
in the wrong time of the program and
then they can track the dip the accurate
dependency from one host to the other
however thinks that enhances as we know
is very expensive so they suffer from
the very high overhead which can be over
10 times or 230 times higher so we and
that the second category is called
refine herbal attack investigation which
uses record click technique to decouple
the expensive dynamic instrumentation of
analysis from the runtime of the program
and then and we record this program with
a very low overhead and then at the
replay time so we do this expensive
tenderizes so it can achieve both in
efficiency and fine growing the level of
the of the analysis and also accuracy so
mainly there are work like our nodes and
n rain so first we do a system-wide
recall replay and then we prune this
data according to the target of our
analysis of our attacking master
and finally we selectively replayed the
execution with the tank analysis so we
have chosen to solve this one with the
refine Apple attack investigation way
and that there are two remaining
challenges so the first one is that we
still need to fulfill the same data
dependency that happened in the
recording time so we need to add to the
replay time so that we can accurately
track the data dependency and find out
what is really going on and what the
data flow is so we are so we are trying
to enable attack dependency free and
independent and a parallel replay so
that we can do the thing that Isis
without Sorella serializing the replayed
executions and also that we aim to
optimize the analysis time because if we
do that DNA duty analysis in parallel so
we can reduce the analysis time cost and
also further that we aim to reduce the
analysis memory cost so our approach is
to as I said to enable the independent
and parallel replay the lift and we
reduce the memory cost of Delta by
optimally allocating the text size for
each lift task so here that during the
during a selective replay of each
execution
so our system called our our tag
facilitates the tagging that is needed
during the think analysis so so that
nodes serialization is needed so that
each replay can be done independently
and in parallel so this is the overview
of our system it is composed of four
parts so first
that we have attack association part
that tracks that the data transmission
between different hosts and we used
attack Al and our tag allocation
optimally calculates the the text size
that is many moment minimally needed in
every day if the task and we use a text
which a technique to to to allocate a
locally synchronize the tag for each 50
tasks and then finally our tag overlay
is gonna aggravate these results and
then return the final results of of the
analysis so so here that we use a part
of the get Pune attack to show how our
our tag works to facilitate these
tagging so here that on the left side
for example at the attacker aims to
exfiltrate the assess the ssh key
through through the get pag command and
then it's it crosses this from the
client side to the server side through
the SCP and then finally the server side
hook is gonna read from from these from
these objects temporary object files
from the SCP and finally it's going to
generate an archive to file so these are
the system call level data flow that we
can see so our target is to is to find
out how does the SSH key goes to from
the current site goes to the archive the
file on the server side so when we are
doing this analysis so first that we
need to identify every bite that we need
to track
so in this data flow analysis for
example here that the SSH key needs a
global tag which consists of like the
host
MAC address the inode dev ji n
information and it's offset and also its
version information so totally it's a
two hundred and eight point eight bits
so can we just use this a global tag
which can make every tag identifiable
across different hosts in the thing that
Isis Oh obviously it is very high so our
approach is to first analyze these Cisco
trace and then to allocate in an optimal
tag by using the result of the Cisco
trace analysis so for example here that
if there's a read Cisco with the six
bytes of the data read to the memory
space of the gate pad process and then
there's a right Cisco which writes to
the to the object file so if we if our
target is to track these data flow so
here that instead of using the 208 bits
so we only need three bits to identify
these the sources of this data flow
tracking so we compare the text sizes of
our scheme with the previous systems so
as we can see that as the number of the
symbols for each v as it grows so our
our tag local tagger growth in the log
scale however the others is one is from
that Titan it is so it grows
exponentially and also this the D
tracker and the our global tag is also
much higher and also that the memory
cost for for the according to you the
number of the
that has been used in the memory space
also our local tag as a as a fraction of
the other compared with the other
systems so and next when we when we have
our symbolize the local tag so when we
do the lift at the the aisle sisqó like
a reader right receive and send this
course so we shift our our tags from
from the global scope to the local scope
and then we perform that analysis and
then when we get the results so we ship
them back and then we update our global
tag map so still that we need to link
the tag up corrugation between the two
hosts via the socket communication so
currently we support both the TCP and
UDP packets with the tag with this tag
Association but in different ways so in
the tcp that because it's it preserved
the order of the tank the stream so we
use a counter based approach and for the
UDP we use a tag tag embedding a based
approach because it can there can be a
data losses that that the tag of
propagation can be lost so forth so for
for the TCP the data stream at the
center at and the receiver can can be
not aligned so they can spend over
different numbers of a Cisco's for
example here that there are three senses
cause and sending these totally these 15
bytes of data and at the receiving side
there there are four reads so our
approach is to track the data stream in
one sock at TCP socket session so that
we can know which has been sent and
which has been received accordingly so
for the UDP case that because it's
Datagram transmission so we use that
embedding approach so we implement the
tag embedding routine at the in the in
kernel soccer handling stack before the
checksum has been computed and at the
receiving side is before the checksum
has been verified so here that our so
when we compute the data flow in each
dip that task so we combine these
results into our tag overlay on top of
the classical prominence graph and then
we get to the final result so here this
example our running example gets the
results for for each data flow in each
if the task
it's from for example from the the file
the file a there are two versions
consecutively from from the two
temporary files B and C and then further
that we can backtrack till the till its
original file E which is our SSH key
okay so we have implemented our our
attack system and the country iran's buh
buh sound open to how a terrible force
so do two bit and then 64-bit and which
we use live D of T as the diff top
obligation engine also supports Saudi
tupid and a 64-bit King publication and
it uses a new foe J for the graph based
reachability analysis and if we use
possible so Q for the tag storage so in
the evaluation so we focused on three
aspects the effectiveness the DNR says
overhead and our runtime overhead so
along with the kid porn running example
we also evaluated in the so in the
different settings in including the
server and client
setting with the firefox browser at the
client-side and the Apache server at the
server side with to SQL injection cases
and we also have the CSI case also in
the server and client
setting and the one cross-site scripting
and also that we we use a peer-to-peer
case with six hosts and we and and we
used the Nutella peer-to-peer file
sharing protocol to evaluate our system
so when we do these curious so we find
that we can accurately recover that the
exact data flow across these different
hosts and this is our analysis time
reduction compared with the other cases
when D and when the analysis is all
civilized so it can reach up to 90% of
the reduction and the runtime overhead
so we round up a spec CPU a 2006
benchmark and the main of the runtime
overhead is less than 5% and we also
reduce the memory cost
compared with the previous system
including Titan and D checker with 50 to
99 percent and actually that the there
are two cases that the Titan could not
complete in the Firefox and opportun
case and also we evaluated at the impact
that ood to our network performance
including the bandwidth and the RTT so
for the Penguins we have zero point less
than 0.5 percent of the reduction and
for the RTT our impact is less than 0.05
percent so include so in conclusion our
our attack enables the cross host
refundable attack
investigation and it decouples the tag
dependency from the replay that IFTA so
they can be put in parallel and
independently and also it improves that
the memory costing in depth analysis so
the runtime overhead is less than five
percent and a hugely reduces the
analysis time cost and the memory cost
so this concludes my talk and I welcome
any question thank you any questions so
one question that I had in the case of
the the UDP where you're embedding tags
in the packets what's to prevent an
attacker or sitting on the network
stripping those tags away so that you
can't do the tracking anymore so our so
our current model is that we don't
assume that the attacker can compromise
kuno and if if if the attacker
compromises other packets on the wrong
currently currently we don't have we
don't cover this part but I think it can
be done through through the adding some
of the hash and a verification scheme
okay any other questions not let's thank
the speaker one more time