hi I'm e and this is Surya we're here to
talk about a race
reverse engineering smart contracts on a
theorem so first if um as we know it's
the second largest block chain based
cryptocurrency but in addition to
regular accounts on the blockchain if um
also features smart contracts so smart
contracts are essentially computer
programs so they can be used for much
more advanced functionalities other than
simple balance transfer as in regular
accounts so for example they can be used
for auctioning crowdfunding or even
lottery or gambling games if you wish so
smart contracts are typically returning
in high-level languages the most popular
language is solidity and they are
executed in a virtualized environment
named that if you're in virtual machine
or the c vm for short so here we take a
look at example contract this is a
pretty trivial one but as we see it's
similar to a class in other languages it
has a few some few variables and a few
functions to interact with it well in
this case I only has one and this will
be our rending example in our tool so
the problem is the high level
representation is that the uvm cannot
directly understand it so instead it
needs to be compiled into this form and
essentially this is an encoding of the
EVM by code which are low-level
operations provided by the if you're in
virtual machine so as we can see the
problem is the bytecode is that it's not
easily understandable and if the
high-level source code is not available
the contract functionality will appear
to be opaque to us
and the problem is opaque or proprietary
contract is that they are really hard to
understand or audit to have a better
understanding of the ecosystem we this
amendment we and our snapshot we
collected about a million contracts
there are about a million addresses that
contains the theorem smart contracts
however will if we look at the unique
ones we only
found at 34,000 uni contracts and by
unique we mean after swarm hash removed
so the second level question will be how
many of these contracts are actually au
papal proprietary so to answer that we
scraped ether scan and collected more
than 10,000 so the source files and
using certified different versions of
solidity compiler which are the major
compiler versions available
we ended up compiling 88,000 unique
binaries so the next step is to take the
intersection of these compiled binaries
which the ones that we found on the
blockchain we ended up matching seven
thousand and seven hundred of the unique
contracts which gives us the majority is
77% of the contracts without source code
available to actually study and
understand that these contracts we built
a race where we utilize various program
analysis and program transfer technique
transformation techniques to translate
evn bytecode into more readable
representations so array process is the
bytecode in five sequential stages first
we recover the control flow graph then
we lift the stack based operations into
a register based representation we then
optimize upon the derived representation
and afterwards we aggregate our
representation into a more compact
format and eventually we recover the
control flow constructs from the
contract so first we recover the control
flow graph this we start by identifying
the basic block boundaries this is
hugely assisted by the jump test
instructions which basically marks the
beginning of a block then we organize
the blocks into a control flow graph we
essentially emulate the contract
execution using a simplified stack model
we explore the contract in the manner
that is similar to the in DFS we also
record the stack images at each block
entrance to decide when we should
backtrack so the algorithm basically
works like
as follow we start starting from the
first block we analyze the basic block
identify its successors add the
successors to the confocal graph then
recurse on successor and this is how we
build a CFG so one major problem is the
EVM bicode is that the operations are
stack based so which it makes really
really hard for us to understand a sense
of variables especially across basic
block boundaries so to address that
problem we convert the representation
into a register based representation we
start by mapping the stack slots into
registers evm stack is specified to have
a maximum size of 1024 so we introduced
1024 registers accordingly then the next
step is to assign appropriate registers
for each of the byte code here we show
an example of an add operation
so in the current configuration the
stack height is 3 so the operation will
pop two items of the stack add them up
and push the value back up so this is
equivalent of reading register s1 s2 and
put add them up and the value back into
s1 the same method could be applied to
basic blocks as well as long as we know
the stack height at the at the block
entrance as we mentioned previously we
collected stack images add to each block
entrance which makes this information
readily available and here we showed an
example of a block being lifted another
problem was the EVM by code is that the
operations are relatively low-level so
we introduced some new instructions
that's slightly higher level so that the
output is more concise these include for
example ain't call in threat which calls
and returns from internal functions and
move which moves a constant value or
register value to another register as
earth which is just like in high-level
languages versus condition not equal or
greater than or equal less than we call
shift
left shift right these are the
operations are commonly using the
contracts but not directly available on
the Bichel level so in the next step we
open we notice that there are a lot of
redundancies in our lifted
representation this is mainly due to the
stack operations tends to move data
around a lot so to remove the
redundancies added by these moving
instructions we use common global
optimizations mainly data fold which
includes constant propagation copy
propagation dead code elimination we
also introduced implement some local
optimizations that's customized for
example in this case of LTI easier is
zero could be rewritten into geq and
eventually this block could be optimized
into just three instructions to further
- further condense our output we
aggregate our representation into an
internet set expressions so we start by
converting the register based
instructions into their address form
this is merely cosmetic then based on
the usages of definitions of the
registers we can aggregate these
instructions so the first one could be
aggregated and it deserves a second one
and could be further aggregated into the
shared one and eventually the whole
block could be summarized with only one
expression so having improved the
representations in each individual block
we tackled the overall control flow
structure we start by separating the
public functions within a contract so as
we mentioned previously a contract
typically consists of multiple functions
and here we untangle their control flow
graph then we apply structural analysis
on the individual control flow graphs to
recover the control flow constructs such
as while and if then else in this
example we could first collapse the if
then else then
these two sequences and eventually we
can match the loop and finally the whole
thing could be collapsed into a single
block and here we have the final output
of erased having done the
transformations we will like to validate
that our output is correct to do so we
construct a test case or a set of test
cases using historical transactions and
the idea is that we leverage GAF the
goal implementation of the etherion
client to replay these transactions and
generate the expected output of these
transactions then we execute our
representation in an interpreter that we
wrote and compare if if there is any
discrepancy between the output so we
ended up collecting a little bit less
than 16,000 transactions
these are these transactions are
collected on the basis of one per unique
contract and this is less now half of
the unique contracts because apparently
more than half of them never got any
public transactions into them we are
successful in most cases but we do fail
3% of them in which a construction
failure is a case that we fail to
generate any output in the first place
and the comparison failure is the case
in which our output does not match
exactly was the one generated I guess so
now we will have see we get to describe
several use cases all right thank you
so so basically now that we have this
tool we wanted to demonstrate its
utility through a bunch of use cases so
the first thing we looked at is thing
called a fuzzy hash so fuzzy hash
descent is essentially over a function
you can calculate the hash over all the
basic blocks and function and compute a
hash so these are fuzzy hashes for
example these random functions ABC but
now that once you have these hashes you
can find similar instances of these in
other contracts where you might not know
the actual functionality so you can
imagine if you have a contract binary X
whose functionality you already
understand now you can find more
instances of the code occurring in other
contracts to kind of see where code is
reused
you can understand other contracts just
through this methodology so we also they
actually used this two-person Janee ran
a few contracts and interesting you know
blockchain phenomenon happening at the
time so the so the so basically the
first thing we looked at were low pay
contracts that we found that had really
large ether bound right so the we
actually found three contracts that are
all used by this theorem exchanged by an
exchange called Gemini on a theorem and
they hold the hell two combined 590
million dollars this car these contracts
were actually multi-sig wallets if you
don't know what a multi-sig is that's
basically a signature scheme where for
example if i want to authorize the
transfer or validate or withdraw I need
some subset of authorized signatures in
order to make it happen so two of them
so two of the three that we found
implemented a pretty standard two event
multi sig signature scheme but the last
one they found actually had a pretty
interesting more complex time-dependent
scheme so the first thing we found
actually from me running you guys on it
and if you see there's an instance of
this global variable called block
timestamp so the use of block timestamp
instruction anywhere in the color is
considered what's called a code smell
because it's generally is generally
unreliable and can be skewed by minors
in the theorem right so seems blocked
Einstein we chose to reverse engineer
and kind of see how the block timestamp
is used in the withdrawal policy so we
were able to figure out how it's used
exactly with child policy and you know
this actually shows how useful how
useful yours is in this example for
being able to audit such code such
critical code where you know we see
instances of things like lot of times
they have poor other code smells next we
also looked at opaque contracts that
were actually occurred them most often
right so we saw in the previous slides
that even though there's a million
contracts deployed we only have about
thirty four thousand unique contracts so
we actually found that about we had
hundreds of thousands of those contracts
or actually the instance is the same two
contracts so for the investigation we
saw we found that the two exchanges
polonius and eunb
were actually one responsible for
deploying all these contracts and we use
arrays and reverse-engineer them up to
up to solidity and we could actually see
that they're just simple wallets for
years a twenty
but nonetheless this kind of it's kind
of answer the question that was raised
by our initial measurement of seeing
exactly where these contracts are coming
from why there's so many duplicates and
exactly what and how are they operating
next we also looked at D but I'm not a
phenomenon called arbitrage iron theorem
so such an anathema there's a lot of
decentralized exchanges also known as
the decks a Dax is basically a exchange
where all the trays and orders are
entirely controlled by a smart contract
so an example of a texana theorem is
ether delta and we actually saw evidence
of arbitrage or behavior so if you look
at the dining up on the right you see
that the top is the cells the bottom of
the buys and you see this price mismatch
where the lowest price for the cell is
higher than the highest highest price
for the buy so we can see that the
traders taking advantage of of of an
opportunity can make an instant profit
however the important key factor here is
that both trades after 6:00 have to
execute successfully and so we expect
that traders would would be required to
create some sort of gadget or some sort
of gadget contract to implement these
two trades and that's exactly what we
find where we see that these these
arbitrage does actually have a gadget
contract they all have to implement well
you'll have to like implement one and
essentially the implementation is it's
relatively straightforward they do a lot
of validation they do a lot of check on
trades because we want just emitter
transaction you don't really know when
the trade is going to get executed on
the chain and so even so there's
actually a lot of heavy invalidation
actually heavy validation and they
actually cost a lot of gas as well and
we finally found that they implement
these atomic batch trades and exactly
how they implement them kind of changes
from contract to contract but by and
large they take advantage of this EVM
hop called called revert meaning if any
of the trades fail they can undo all
state changes in the transaction all
contract state changes are averted and
the transaction ends execution so
finally we also looked at the game at
the time called crypto kitties so this
is essentially a trading game trading
game where
there are cats left some sort of you
know cute looking does it glad tributes
also also called cat tributes where
where everyone can can hit a cat and
trade them and have them up for auction
right so we can see here is that some
cats have been up up for auction at the
time for about a hundred you know two
hundred eight some for 350th which at
the time it's around $160,000 that these
are only actually you know cats up for
sale although although we have seen cats
sold for around sixty thousand dollars
at times so it's you know this is this
is quite a large large and important
game on the network size you'd expect
you know almost all the code is publicly
sourced you can see exactly how the
options work how they try the game
mechanisms work however there's one
extremely crucial code code piece that
has kept intentionally opaque right you
can see they've called it a super-secret
gene algorithm and so this algorithm can
combine to cats whose genes are already
known and after you create a new cat
whose genes are somewhat randomized and
so this was kept intentionally opaque to
hide functionality in case you know
someone can discover it and actually
gain the system so you know it's
actually so serious that people who
actually develop and develop on the game
and the algorithm are not even allowed
to take part in the game so obviously
right this meant that this is a huge
target for reverse engineering and so we
had to go and do it right so Ashley's so
he actually found out how the clock
catchers actually use an extremely
interesting way to inject random
mutation into genes and actually how the
parent genes are selected he actually
did find a more informed reading
strategy to that allows you to search
for new cats new new cats that are more
rare and will go for a lot more money
I'm not gonna spoil the entire algorithm
here although it is there in the paper
if you're interested you can we talk to
me afterwards I can kind of you know
give you some hints how to make money
and if finally right it's obvious in
this case where you can't really
reliance on on obscurity even though you
have these opaque byte
contracts it's really infeasible to rely
on that opacity to hide any kind of
important functionality as we see in
this case you know they're readily
reverse-engineer below actually um you
can actually also find the exact one not
the exact although our own soul it'll be
slowly code implementation of this exact
exact contract the function output
matches and you can see exactly how it
works so in conclusion we see that the
if the Omega system is largely opaque
you know there's about seventy seven
point five percent of the contracts are
unique are uniquely opaque or I'm sorry
seven point five of the unique contracts
are fake if you're interested in seeing
the code it's available there um you can
contact that email address and you know
get more information and finally we've
less we've actually seen how this
opacity can be opacity assumption can be
completely you know completely broken
essentially through our case studies by
seeing the high value wallets and we saw
the user exchange laws the arbitrage
BOTS and the crypto kiddies gene
algorithm and that's our talks so thank
you it's like questions now
hi I'm Johannes from the previous
previous previous talk I have a question
about your assignment of registers to
stake locations if there are some I will
actually use this text structure so you
can enter the same basic block with in
different states right you're exactly
right so actually I oversimplify here a
lot like so once you one very important
heuristic here is the internal call
identification so we identify so the
block didn't being reused multiple time
is largely due to internal functions so
in that particular case it will have
multiple stack sizes but if we extract
the internal function we can remove the
need to to handle that case so if
anything laughter Wow well if some block
is left afterwards still have multiple
sizes we will duplicate it multiple
times for each unique stack height and
that's a very good question
[Applause]