thank you for the introduction as he
said my name is Ashna Webster and I'll
presenting be presenting work done by
myself
Ryan akin rod and our advisor dr. James
Pirlo from the University of Maryland
the name of the paper is fast and
service fast and service preserving
recovery from malware infections using
crew you which is kind of a mouthful so
I'll refer to the actual project as crew
um are so a lot of research is done on
the side of detecting and preventing
malware this is sort of the best case
scenario if we can prevent it and it's
also important to be able to detect it
so that we know if there's something
there but we also need to consider sort
of the unfortunate common but worst case
scenario where you do get infected and
you need to recover from Malory so this
is sort of something we see a lot and
it's inevitable when you have lots of
servers and the public facing most there
is some research done in this field and
most of the solutions are very good at
undoing the changes that are done by
Mauer and preserving the legitimate
changes by benign processes however they
don't usually consider the availability
of the system from a perspective of how
long this recovery process takes and
also whether the connections that are
being made to something like a web
server are preserved after the recovery
process so for example if you're running
a web server and you're aware that a
periodically you're infected by malware
just by virtue of being on the public
facing glove
you want a solution that might be able
to not only remove the malware but also
consider if there's a way to preserve
those connections and the processing
state of the server at that point in
time so there are some naive approach is
commonly the way that you might remove
malware is to simply just turn it off
and on again maybe reformat the
operating system so that you can be
confident all the hours removed but of
course this takes time and you have long
downtime during that the VM snapshots
are another common way just periodically
you know taking images and restoring
from one of those again you might lose
processing state after that and you also
have to keep track of
if you took a snapshot that actually had
malicious process on it
they're also off-the-shelf antivirus
restore Pro that can attempt to undo the
changes done by viruses and malware
however in practice these are not very
effective and there have been many
papers showing that at best they get
about 80% but often lower than that for
undoing the malicious changes to online
our so in terms of the state of the art
for you know more robust approaches
there's kind of two categories there's
log based and DN based approaches and
just to walk through some of these
there's the approach teaser which is a
log based method and this uses taint
flow analysis to see some of the changes
done by malware processes and undo them
there's back to the future which uses
categories of trusted and untrusted
processes and logs them differently to
handle their behavior and maintain the
legitimate changes and undo the
malicious ones
there's c-calm which is a vm based
approach and this is sort of an
interesting one because it also
identifies the malware using a behavior
clustering approach and is able to undo
the malware changes that way there's
time vm which takes a network logging
approach as well as the vm based
approach and keeps shadow VMS which are
sort of like delayed instances of the
current vm but they're receiving traffic
at a delayed rate and then it just fast
forwards to one of the ones that it sure
is uninfected and finally there's an
exact recorder and this just sort of
logs all of the non-deterministic events
on the vm and uses that to undo
malicious changes so the last one I have
here is our method creo mr and I just
want to compare that with some of the
prior work I want to bring your
attention to the fact that many of these
other solutions do not maintain active
connections and also have significant
runtime overhead and restore overhead so
we seek to sort of improve upon these
methods in this way so I want to talk a
little bit about the design
implementation here
our solution leverages LXE which is
Linux containers and creo which is
checkpoint and restore in user space I'm
going to talk about these more in the
next slides it's also able to preserve
active connections and mate does the
recovery process and about three seconds
on average there's virtually no overhead
during runtime it's just the overhead of
running a Linux container which has been
shown to be very small and it maintains
the or it preserves the state of the
malicious processes separately so that
you can analyze them later so Linux
containers are essentially just they're
similar to docker but specific to the
Linux operating system
the idea here is to provide a
virtualized sandbox for executing these
processes they come in privileged and
unprivileged varieties the privileged
ones run as root and are not considered
be secured by Linux because if you
escape from the container to the host
operating system you essentially have
read user privileges which is why there
are also unprivileged containers and
that's what we do all of our experiments
with where the users on the container
are mapped to random high you IDs and GU
IDs and would essentially have no
privileges just a nobody user if they
were to extend to the host
cRIO is checkpoint and restore and user
space this is essentially a software
that allows you to checkpoint a process
save all the state including memory
files open registers and restore them
exactly the same critically it also is
able to restore TCP connections so this
is already been leveraged in Prior work
for dynamically creating honey pots for
patching and we extend on this idea for
malware recovery so that we can have
these connections exist before and after
the restore you're also able to
checkpoint and restore entire Linux
containers using for you this is
actually built into the LXE command and
calls creo on the backend so the main
changes that we made were to the crew of
source code
and those were broken down into both the
checkpoint and restore during checkpoint
we basically identify the processes that
violate some policies which I'm going to
talk about next but these are basically
just identifying which processes are
illegitimate versus malicious and then
during restore we actually do not
restore the the malicious ones obviously
but we do restore the legitimate ones
they just out of the box we kind of get
the TCP restore connection functionality
that's built into Korea we also create
an agent which is able to accept alerts
from any IDs
IPS system that you might have and then
it converts these to the policies and
handles the courier processes so these
policies like I said are flexible enough
to handle a variety of lurtz from IDs
and IPS and basically should be used to
identify the processes that might be
malware the static policies are just
assertions that should always hold true
so those might be things like this
process should never be opening this
file or the some some files should some
process should never have a child
there are also dynamic policies and
these are the ones that would be
generated based on alerts that you get
from your IDs or IPs so perhaps
connecting to a known malicious IP
address or even like a manual or from
from the network administrator so here
are some of the policy matches just to
quickly run through these
there's executable name match so just
the name of the executing process file
name match would be if there's a file
that's opened by a process that should
not be TCP I'm at IP match goes back to
what I said before with connecting to a
known malicious IP e there's memory
match where you can do a regular
expression match on the actual memory
contents that are being loaded and then
PID and parent p ID match if you have
something that is able to specifically
ID identify which processes to not
restore and finally there's paradoxical
main match which goes back to not some
processes she does not have children so
in terms of the actual modifications
decree you these were done as a open
source fork of the career repository and
these break down to the first the
checkpoint section this hooks into all
the serialization of different resources
so those would be files TCP connections
memory blocks and we checked that the
policies are being any policy violations
they're the violating processes are
written to this emit image file and we
still save the malicious process state
but as we see in restore we don't
restore it so we we look back at that
amid an image file we omit the processes
from there and then we also change it so
it doesn't restore processes that are
missing resources so if you have a
process that is able to download malware
to the system and that's not present
there anymore after the file system
restore that process would just be not
run either Alex see the changes here
were pretty trivial essentially just
changing it so that the back end Korea
version was ours instead of like the
modified version instead of the real one
and accepted the parameters that were
using for accepting policies and we also
have that as an open-source fork of the
original policy repository so for the
agent again this is sort of the
orchestration process for triggering
this recovery this accepts the JSON
alerts and parses them into the protobuf
formatted files that cRIO accepts for
its policies and it is I have sort of a
diagram there on the right which shows
that these alerts can come from either
on the host your outside of the host and
from a variety of different sources one
thing I haven't talked about yet is the
file system restore so we assume that
the file system is mostly static which
might be the case for web servers where
the state is managed mostly on like a
database server or something like that
and then we just keep copies of the file
system on the host that we know to be
legitimate and simply rotate the mouse
so that we take the infected one and
swap it with the legitimate one during
the restore
so the fall on that infection chronology
kind of looks like this we have some way
that malware gets onto the system it's
detected by ids/ips Emanuele alert
whatever it may be and it's sent to the
Curia mr agent as a JSON formatted alert
the crew um our agent converts that into
the policy which and starts the
checkpoint process during the crew
checkpoint process policy violations are
flagged and written to the emit image
the filesystem is restored as I said by
swapping out the legitimate filesystem
and the infected one and finally the
restore process restarts all the non
malicious processes okay so for our
experiments we have two different
questions that we're trying to answer
first the one is are we able to remove
different types of malware and how long
does it take and second what is the
availability impact if we have multiple
concurrent connections in sort of a
real-world web server case so for how
long it takes to remove malware we
conduct this experiment by collecting
six different Linux malware samples and
having them run for a few seconds on a
fresh container state triggering a
restore with our custom policy and
timing how long it takes we repeat each
malware removal process reach of the
malware ten times just to summarize some
of the malware that we used here I'll
let you read the slide but essentially
there's some that are mining Bitcoin
there are some Metasploit exploits that
try to run shells on ports or reach back
using reverse shells and there are some
just vulnerabilities and things like to
go ahead web server that can be
exploited to run arbitrary code in all
cases the malware is able to be removed
and it takes right around three seconds
and in every case in terms of the
duration for each of the steps the
checkpoint system is sort of the
dominant time one but there's also some
time for restore and the file system
swap in preparation are sort of
negligible
on the skin of things so for our next
experiment we consider the sort of
stress test with many users on a web
servers so to simulate this we have a
variety of file sizes hosted on the web
server from one kilobyte ten kilobyte
hundred kilobyte all the way up to one
gigabyte and we let the several users
connect to it simultaneously each you're
using different files the 30-second mark
we have malware execute and recover from
it and we time how long each connections
takes so most of the connections are not
actually going to be affected by this
malware recovery process but the ones
that are will have a slightly higher
time in all cases we find that the
connections are not interrupted so to
look at the timing results here we
compare on the y-axis the difference
between the Max and median times so the
max is sort of a proxy for the
connections that were affected by the
malware recovery process versus the
median is essentially the ones that are
not I mean in all cases that falls to
about three seconds which is again the
time I said that it takes for that
recovery process so the takeaway here is
that regardless of the file size and
even with seven concurrent connections
the recovery time is about the same for
all of these if we expand on this I have
that same chart on the left side here
and I have 35 and there's 35 and 140
concurrent connections in the middle and
right side respectively and we see that
in almost all cases it's about three
seconds even with more concurrent
connections regardless of the file type
then there are a few outliers but by and
large it does it appears that the
recovery process is not dependent on the
number of concurrent connections or file
size so for our discussion we consider
some questions about whether it's
possible that a TCP connection to
terminate before the policy is able to
be evaluated in that case it may still
be possible to recover from any malware
on the system just based on the fact
that the resources might be missing
we also return to this question
limitations for the possibility of
extending this to other operating
systems
the main limiting limitation here is
other containers the best of my
knowledge like such as docker do not
have this TCP restore functionality so
that's kind of the limiting factor on
having the connections reserved at least
there is also potential for denial of
service if an attacker is able to
repeatedly have this trigger the
recovery process even if there's not
malware justice like a false positive so
this should really be used in
conjunction with best practices such as
patching and there's just black listing
IPS and things like that for limitations
the primary one is that if it's there's
a trigger like there's an alert but
during the policy checks there's no
policy violations and there's no
processes removed due to missing
resources so essentially of an alert but
you weren't able to actually find them
our there's two perspectives you can
take one is that well perhaps the alert
was a false alarm or to be safe you can
just sort of restore the processes
manually in that case you not have this
connection recovery functionality we
also don't verify the validity of alerts
really a one simple way to achieve this
would be to have the authenticity of
them checked based on signing for future
work we've already started to consider
dynamic honeypot creation so this
instead of just throwing away the state
of the militia or saving it for later
the malicious State we can have that
execute in a separate container so
essentially the legitimate processes
would be running on one container and
the malicious ones would be running on
sort of a sandbox container to achieve
this we would also need to sanitize any
of the sensitive state that's all in the
container and some of this would be like
sanitizing the memory space which is
sort of an extension of the previous
work that we already did there we also
want to consider dynamic assertions
which are queries that we can give to
processes to verify that they're
legitimate and not masquerading a
malicious processes masquerading as
legitimate one
and we want to craft these queries in a
way that only the legitimate processes
would be able to answer them like based
on their calculations and finally as I
mentioned before the verifications of
alerts and their authenticity is
important to prevent denial of service
inclusion were able to achieve our goal
of having the connections maintained
through the recovery process we have
pretty low overhead both during run time
and the recovery process the recovery
process takes about three seconds and
the overnight is just running the
olynyk's container which has been shown
to be pretty effective effective it's
modular in the sense that it can accept
alerts from a variety of sources they
just need to be json formatted and be
able to be sent to that IP n port that
the agent is running on and all of this
is available as open source on github so
thank you and if you have any questions
I'd be happy to answer them
[Applause]
nice work well it seems our evaluation
assumes the malware can be detected
within three seconds of the infection
is that this a reasonable assumption
instead of a days or at least hours so I
think it's realistic to believe that
there yeah it might be longer before it
is detected so that's where like the
policy if whatever the policy was
generated or sorry whatever alert was
generated it needs to be have
information that can be used to reach
back and figure out what where the
malware is still so that that should be
basically the same assuming like at some
point an alert is generated you should
still be able to trace back and find it
but asking this that we related to the
performance right
this wasn't factored in for like I did
the timing of how long they ran didn't
factor into the performance metrics that
I showed you here I don't know if that
was the question okay okay thank you
Jason Gionta US government so is this
work mostly focused on supporting web
servers is that right yeah another
essentially yes okay cuz there's a lot
of scenarios where five files are being
manipulated on the system and there's
dependencies on those files rolling
those back which is corrupt the system
so in the case of a web server is still
going back to his question if the
detection - response of the malware
being infected is after a checkpoint you
have to roll back many minutes and so
how would you handle situations where
you already have ongoing state TLS
connections things with that was state
how are you going to roll that back and
continue to have those connections going
live so essentially the the files would
be restored back but the TCP connections
would be still like based on when the
checkpoint like so there's the file
system checkpoint and there's the TCP
and and the rest of the processing state
checkpoint so the the assumption we're
making there is that the the files would
come back to the state they were at that
time and the TCP connections would
continue uninterrupted so for all the
other processes you're not I I guess I
don't understand if you're rolling the
whole Linux container back you have
other processes in that container that
have the state TLS state and HTTP TLS
state if you roll those back how do you
continue to have like a conversation in
the future for those other processes so
the like the processes are kind of
independent of the file system restore
process like the that we're
checkpointing those that and kind of
like restoring them exactly as they were
at the end we're not there's no rollback
so you only just you're just killing a
property you're just killing the
malicious process just one that's
actually yes okay so any sort of
dependencies between processes would
would screw up
this is the state of them she like if
you had to processes if you had the
malicious process modify a file and then
another non malicious process model like
was reading the file or modifying the
file how does that work
so the file would go back to like its
original state at the start of the
container essentially or whatever like
the clean state of the container is in
terms the files the processes the
malicious one would not be restored and
the legitimate one would be restored
exactly as it was like at the even well
the malware it was running so the one
concern is like if there's malware
processes reaching into the legitimate
processes and modifying their memory
that would be an issue because then you
have like some process that's
essentially no longer legitimate now but
as far as the files both being not there
the file being modified by two different
processes that that shouldn't be an
issue because we're going to restore
that file back to its original state
legitimate processes is going to tease
that and the rush is following be
restored so you'll lose the Delta
between and that's okay
I'm guessing and as long as that doesn't
affect the TLS connection yeah okay okay
thanks hi my name is Evan I'm a student
from Georgia Tech this is kind of I
think covered maybe by the previous
gentleman but I want to make sure I
touched on it so what happens when you
have an infection that actually infects
the legitimate process itself just draw
a correlation to Windows malware often
windows malware will in fact
explorer.exe to gains maintain some sort
of
persistent connection or persistence in
that system
does your system handle discs I think a
lot of it was mostly just the external
processes it'll sort of remove those
I guess he also just take a snapshot of
the actual process itself and then roll
back to before the process was actually
infected yeah so there's there's no
rollback so if it's like changing the
other legitimate processes in some way
essentially those are now illegitimate
so you can either have policies that
like also would remove those and you'd
have to restart them or you would need
to extend this in some way to be able to
I guess yeah you would need some
rollback functionality as well to be
able to return that to a legitimate
state I see okay thanks thanks for the
talk I'm Kevin from University of
Maryland I wanted to ask about the three
seconds that you said was the
approximate amount of time it takes to
execute the whole restore process and
you mentioned that the most of that time
is associated with the checkpointing and
I was curious have you investigated what
factors might scale that three seconds
up or down yeah so I think most of the
checkpoint process is like iterating
over all of the different resources that
are like being used by all the processes
and and serializing all of those two
different image files which are then are
stored so I I suspect that adding like
lots of policies that would well it well
first of all just having lots of those
resources if there's many things that
these processes are referencing which is
why we wanted to conduct this experiment
we're like there's lots of simultaneous
connections each kind of has its own
process and its own memory and all of
that and also if you have like thousands
of policies that would need to be
checked you'd have to like for now
linearly iterate over them so some of
those things could affect the checkpoint
time yeah I mean I guess one thing
about is whether this checkpoint time is
something that would be representative
of a typical web server or if you had
something that was really massive maybe
it would take you know where as a
magnitude larger than that yeah that's
kind of why we tried to do the like
realistic web server situation where
there's many files that they're all
referencing that they all have their own
like processing state then they all need
to be maintained at the same time and we
didn't really observe much at least for
like 140 concurrent connive connection
case but we didn't have like a robust
enough server to run it was like a
thousands of concurrent connections but
that might be spread out over multiple
servers anyway so thank you okay since
our speaker what's more