hi so today I want to talk to you about
onion services because they have some
really interesting privacy and security
properties but at the cost of some
usability issues so onion services are
part of the Tor network
which is a decentralized anonymity
network and it allows users to access
the internet anonymously and onions our
onion services are within this network
here they're only routable within the
Tor network and they provide server
anonymity and so this work here just
looks at onion services and their
associated usability issues so we wanted
to see how tor users interact with onion
services meaning we wanted to see what
users mental models of onion services
are how they use and manage onion
services and then also some of the
challenges that they are faced with when
using onion services and some of our
main findings are shown here despite the
extra security and privacy properties of
onion services we find that many users
are confronted with usability issues
like the ones listed here they are
confronted with issues discovering onion
services managing and remembering them
and then also with the susceptibility of
onion services to phishing attacks and
so with this work we hope to kind of
shed light on some of these usability
issues and hopefully learn from them to
implement design improvements in the
future so for the rest of this talk I
want to go into more detail on onion
services background some of their
security and privacy features I'll then
talk about the methods we use to run a
user study and some of the data we
gathered I'll then go into detail on our
results specifically looking at issues
with discovering onion services some
user thoughts on vanity onion domains
and how users verify onion sites and
then lastly I'll touch on some future
directions and conclusions from our
study
so this here is a onion domain and I
want to point out a couple different
parts that make it different from a
normal domain first we have it ending in
dot onion this is a special use domain
and it's reserved for use just in the
tor browser onion services are not
resolved using dns they're actually
resolved using distributed hash tables
so the whole process is in kind of
controlled by one central entity this
next part is a seemingly random series
of characters here might be slightly
difficult to remember and it's the base
32 encoded hash over the server's public
key a little bit later I'll talk about
one way that people use to make onion
domains slightly more memorable and then
this last part I want to point out in
this case is an HTTP reroute but onion
services are not limited to HTTP or
HTTPS as they're built on top of TCP and
so this is some of the background on
onion domains but I also want to point
out some security and privacy features
first of all onion services are self
identity ding so if someone gives alice
at the bottom here an onion domain she
can enter that into the tor browser and
establish a connection to this onion
service the onion service will respond
with a public key and alice might ask
this question of how do we know this is
the legitimate public key can I trust it
and because onion services are
self-authenticating she can take the
hash of this key and compare it to the
domain she entered in the tor browser if
the two match up then she knows she's
speaking to the correct onion service
onion services are also end-to-end
encrypted so once a connection is
established the onion service Alice has
intend encryption and then the last
point I want to make here is that both
the client and server are
anonymous Alice does not know the IP
address of the onion server and the
onion server does not know the IP
address of Alice it looks like this here
both Alice and the onion server
established tor connections to a tor
relay in this example here I'm only
showing three Tor relays but in reality
there's more than that
and this tor relay does not know alice's
IP address or the onion services IP
address and so you can see that onion
services provide some really nice and
anima T benefits
but they're not perfect and this is for
a couple of reasons one is they can
still be susceptible to traffic analysis
attacks an attacker can use information
like packet timing to infer things about
either Alice or the content she is
accessing there's also a number of
configuration errors that can be made
when onion services are being set up and
this could potentially lead to a
compromised
susceptibility to attacks whether it's
security or privacy related and then
lastly there's a series of usability
issues that we think onion services
suffer from and that's where this work
starts we want to determine and identify
what kind of usability issues there are
next I want to go into some details on
our methods we used and the data we use
to come to our results so to answer the
question of how tor users interact with
onion services we designed a mixed
method user study and it involved data
from interviews surveys and then we also
gained access to DNS data from the B
root server so starting with the
interviews we conducted 17 interviews
with people of diverse backgrounds we
asked them about both tor and onion
services and these served as a more more
exploratory purpose to inform our
surveys
and so we designed a survey that had 49
questions a mix of open ended and closed
ended questions and we wanted to ask
people about torn onion services again
more about how often they use it what
they use it for kind of their patterns
with it and we got about eight hundred
and thirty responses but after filtering
out for incomplete surveys we had a
resulting set of 517 responses and then
we supplemented both our interviews and
surveys with data from a DNS root server
we had about two days worth of data
recall that onion domains are not
resolved via DNS but if someone puts an
onion domain into a normal browser it
will still make a record of this at the
root server but it will not return an
onion service and so we wanted to look
at this data to get an idea of what
onion services people might be trying to
access and after filtering out for all
the correctly formatted onion domains we
saw that there are about 15,000 unique
onion domains in this set so using those
methods and that data we can start
pulling out themes from our results and
so I specifically want to talk about
onion service discovery vanity domains
and how users verify onion services so
starting with onion discovery an
important aspect of onion services is
that they're private by default meaning
it's the onion service operators job to
disseminate information about their
onion service so that people can use it
and this makes discovering onion
services a little bit more challenging
so we wanted to see how people handle
this and we found that the most common
way from our survey respondents is using
social networking so for example there
are sub reddit threads where people ask
about different types of onions there
we also find that search engines are
popular
there's aggregators that compile lists
of onion domains and categorize them and
potentially include some other
information on them and then lastly
random encounters seem to also be a
popular way to discover onion sites on
the web and one example of this here is
if we look at Pro públicas website if
you scroll to the bottom you can see a
button that says browse be a tor and
this will direct a user to their onion
service recall that I mentioned
aggregators this is an example of one
here called fresh onions and we can see
a list of domains some title potentially
and then also some metadata like when it
was added to this aggregator if it's
alive or not alive a lot of the people
we got survey responses from mention
they had issues with identifying which
onion domains are still alive or not and
we actually found out pretty surprising
that a lot of our survey respondents
didn't know aggregators or search
engines like this actually existed for
onions a common theme is represented by
this quote here that says I wasn't aware
that onion site search engines exist
it's been near impossible for me to find
them so far and we think also part of
the reason onion discovery is difficult
is because of their naming it's hard to
remember and identify them and one way
people have tried to make onion domains
more memorable is using vanity onion
domains so this is four examples here
well-known popular onion domains we have
Pro Publica as the New York Times
Facebook and proton males onion sites
and to generate a vanity domain someone
just has to keep generating key pairs
until the hash of the public key
resembles the desired string
now there's both good and bad parts of
vanity domains the good is that it could
hint out the onion services content for
example if I see an onion domain that
starts with NYTimes I suspect it might
be the New York Times on the other hand
the same thing can read a false sense of
security if we're only verifying the
prefix of the onion domain it leaves
onion domains susceptible to phishing
attacks and then I also want to point
out that vanity domains are economically
unfair it takes a lot of resources and
power to generate this type of domain
and so entities are people that don't
have these resources resources cannot
generate vanity domains and so we asked
users in our survey their thoughts on
vanity domains and we found a couple of
common themes as one of our survey
respondents said and this echoes a bunch
of others they only memorize the first
part of the domain which is a big
security issue specifically because of
phishing we also found that a lot of
people had technical misunderstandings
of vanity domains so many survey
respondents thought that vanity domains
are a weakness in the hash algorithm
used by tor which isn't true of vanity
domains there was actually a lot of
outcry when Facebook published their
onion domain because people thought this
was a weakness if someone could generate
a domain that looked like there's many
other survey respondents had thoughts
along the lines of this quote these
people who created their onion name
using scallion or other tools should
notice that other people can make the
same private key scallion a scallion is
a tool that automates the generation of
vanity domains and this quote and this
line of thinking also is not accurate
and so based on our survey responses we
we came to the conclusion that fishing
might be a real issue with these both
vanity domains but also general onion
domains and so we wanted to use the DNS
data from the be root server to kind of
look at what onion domains are in there
and potentially identify either typos or
phishing scenarios so if we look at this
example here
we have two onion domains and these came
from our data set we can see that
they're extremely similar there's one
character difference and this could be
an example of either a typo or phishing
site and so the way to kind of identify
this as by looking at the frequency of
both of these in our DNS data set and
this is under the assumption that typos
or phishing domains will appear much
less frequently because they're up for
much long for a much shorter amount of
time than a real non phishing site so we
looked at our data set and we found that
this top onion domain occurred 529 times
whereas the bottom one only occurred
twice and this suggested to us that this
bottom domain could either be a phishing
site or a typo and we wanted to extend
this analysis to the rest of our data
set so what we did was we first made a
list of all the unique correctly
formatted onion domains and then created
pairs between all of these domains to
have all unique pairs of onion domains
in our data set and we wanted to assign
a metric to it that said how similar it
was and so in this case we use the
Jarrah Winkler's similarity score it's a
string similarity metric that puts more
weight on the prefix of the string and
the resulting score is a number between
zero and one and zero means it's
unsimilar one means it's the same and so
we had a threshold of about 0.9 and we
said anything over point nine was
extremely similar and those were onion
domain pairs we wanted to look at a
little bit more closely and so from
those results we weighted these by
frequency we specifically wanted to see
onion domain pairs that were extremely
similar and where one of them was very
frequently visited and the other was not
and so some of our results are shown
here where we see in the onion one
column this is one of the onions in the
pair along with its frequency onion too
is the other onion in the pair along
with its frequency and then the last
column is the john winkler score and so
we manually investigated some of these
onion domains a lot of them turned out
to be associated with known ransomware
attacks but a few of them were not these
three here are well known onion domains
for the Russian market DuckDuckGo and
the hidden wiki and we found that for
each one there were at least a couple of
other onion domains that were extremely
similar to it and much less frequently
requested and so based on these results
we believe phishing to be a real issue
for onion services and wanted to see how
users verify onion services as authentic
we asked this in our survey and these
are some of the responses most popular
was copying and pasting which doesn't
really address the phishing problem as
an attacker can still advertise an onion
domain as something else and a users
will simply copy and paste it but what's
more surprising about these results is
that about a third of our participants
said they either can't tell and/or don't
check the authenticity of an onion
service and so this is an area for
improvement going forward in future
designs so to summarize our findings we
found that discovering onion services is
challenging because they're private by
default
vanity domains are more memorable but
provide a false sense of security and
users are lacking a way to verify the
authenticity of onion services and so in
this last part of the talk I just want
to touch on some future directions and
conclusions so based on these usability
issues we identified we can help make
onion domains more usable for example we
can make it easier for a website to
announce its associated onion service we
can allow onion service operators to opt
into publishing mechanisms we can have
tor browser help with encrypted
bookmarks and also create better
documentation and education to better
people's mental models of the technology
they're using and to conclude despite
extra security and privacy properties of
onion services many users are confronted
with usability issues like
susceptibility to phishing attacks
discovering onion services and managing
and remembering onion services and we
can learn from the issues these users
have encountered to implement design
improvements like better discovery
mechanisms and better verification
mechanisms and so at this point I'd be
happy to take any questions
[Music]
[Applause]
yeah yeah
so we advertised to the survey to the
tour mailing list also on social media
and our research webpage
it's definitely biased towards tour
users we wanted to interview people or
have people respond that had used tor
and hopefully had used onion services so
they could comment on it we have more
demographic information in the results
in our paper but it is viewed towards
more kind of educated people that have
used this type of technology so the
problem that you bring up with the
phishing of the domains is very similar
to the problem we get with what you you
know the regular DNS service with
internationalized domain names and this
Unicode character a looks a lot like
this unicode character a but the binary
strings totally different I know you
yourself are graduated and gone from
Princeton now do you know if there's if
the work is going to be continued to try
and figure out ways to solve this
problem or are you aware of work being
done elsewhere to do that I am not aware
of that but it's definitely one of the
things that we've looked at for future
work I'm not aware of anyone currently
working on it but it's something that we
should work on hi my name is from I'm
from Texas Instruments the question I
have is when users users are using tor
browser one of the concerns they have
apart from all the advantages of
anonymity and all is that their node
could be an exit node and people think
that some government service may be
sniffing their node or may be monitoring
their nodes more actively than usual so
did you have any questions regarding
that we're people concerned about that
when they are using tor process so we
did ask some general questions about tor
not just onions
services and some people were worried we
kind of had a broad range of what people
were worried about and so there were
definitely some that were worried about
that scenario
others were and some were just worried
about track your trackers on the web it
was like a very broad range of what
people weren't worried about we do have
more of the information though on our
webpage and in the paper thank you
the very short answer to the previous
question is that onion services don't
use exit relays so they don't have the
capability for the sniffing so my
question is in the typo situation it's
somebody who just they should have typed
L but they typed I and it is it's not
like there are two different sites that
are that match to those private keys but
in the like phishing scenario there are
actually two different private keys that
somebody is brute Forest in the slide
you gave us it looked like there were a
lot of typos did you visit them to see
if there was a private key that went
with them can you separate typos from
phishing uh so this is something we
thought a lot about because we we
couldn't differentiate the two one is
because a lot of onion services are
short-lived even if we did try to visit
it it might not be up anymore and it's
hard for us to kind of say anything
about that we also were skeptical of
visiting onion services just because of
some of the content that we didn't feel
we wanted to see but there is definitely
work in kind of differentiating between
these scenarios
[Applause]