hello everyone my name's tiny boy from
Anton University today I'm going to talk
about new class of attack we called it
man as a machine and I will show how to
perform this attack on security critical
applications including passive manager
and security tokens so we see software
with client and several architecture
everywhere
let's take browser and web server for
example in traditional that would threat
model the usual device and the server
are typically trusted but the net will
be hostile the attacker can do various
type attacks like man in the middle to
still use information of the channel
because we are aware in this attack we
use crypto solution such as POS and web
PKI to protect the communication however
not all communication goes over the
network certain part of the
communication happened within the
computer for example software often
comprised a front-end that provides a
GUI to the user and the backend that
manage the data they are separate
processes and the use of mechanism
called inter process communication to
exchange data because they can be
untrusted component inside the user
device and protect so protecting user
information communicated over the
channel is as important as over the
network so for this reason in this world
we try to understand the security of the
communication inside the computer with
focusing on IPC security we call the
attacker that exploits the inter process
communication inside a computer
management machine and let's see who is
it man the machine so we consider the
Tres from malicious processes on the
user device however we are not
interested in Manuel because man we
usually run with are at the same users
permission
so if you if the computer is infected by
the man where the nothing can do here so
instead we're interested in legitimate
processes that run by other users this
process are intended to be on the
computer so in our threat model so title
can be any unprivileged user that try to
steal sensitive information from other
users on the same computer the example
here includes co-worker family member
and even and even the guest user the
target system here is multi user
computers computers that can be accessed
by multiple users are very common thing
of enterprises or university where
centralized access control is used to
allow any employee or student to access
any computers in such environment even
though everyone helped their own
computers but they can be accessed by
any other domain users with their own
credentials we also found that the
attacker can also be guest user many
operating systems such as Ubuntu say
enable get access by default and even
security personnel usually forget to
turn this off so the title here could be
anyone knows as insiders let's take a
look let's figure here and I will show
how the mid-market actor to attack other
users on a simple puter the attack
method is to run a malicious process
from attackers logins essence an example
of such attack attack scenario is the
attacker first size into the victim's
computer and run the evil process after
that he used fast user switching on
Windows to leave the background session
to leave the session in the background
and switch back to the victim's login
screen so this way the fight processes
continue to run in the back continue to
have the tightest process and this
process we try to exploit the victims
process
I PC a Mac OS and Linux commands like no
hub can be used to keep a process
running in the background without
leaving the logins essence things could
be worse in primo desktop like massive
edge or remote repo access like SSH our
remote desktop on Windows enable on the
computer with these the title could stop
the evil process from remotely so that
many types of IPC and not all of them
are vulnerable to the meet my attack
model the common feature of the
vulnerable IPC metals is that the server
process by stores identifiers on name
and wait for client connections in this
world we focus on three IPC metals never
socket where the server listen on the
local host interface and a specific port
number named PI on Windows where the pi
instances and store in a special path
where all users can access as I will
show later the meat mallet actor could
perform client and server impersonation
on these IPC channels the third IPC
method is USB human interface device
strictly speaking USB is not an IPC but
USB communication happen inside a
computer leaving the meat mallet eager
to exploit it example of USB HID devices
are a security key that many people use
for second factor authentication on
Linux and Mac OS always current active
user can access Lee devices however on
Windows and the user can access this
devices at any time there are also IPC
methods that is secured against our
attacker model such as socket pair or
anonymous pipe the difference here is
that the book the communal concerns of
both the communication power of this IPC
are created by the same
process this way but unjust the process
cannot get into the middle and exploit
this channel now I will show how we can
exploit this IPC method in password
manager and security tokens our primary
key a primary case study is standalone
password managers they are different
from cloud password manager like
LastPass in the sand that is a provider
native desktop app that allow user to
manage the passwords standalone passive
manager are often integrated into a
browser with browser extension this
browser extensions help user in entering
password into knocking pieces or storing
the password the browser extension and
the app communicate pass the password
and as a user information of IPC in this
world we analyze various parts of
managers to see how they protect this
channel the first case study I only like
to talk about is RoboForm the logo from
app run an HTTP server on port five four
five one two and wait for client
collation the RoboForm browser extension
connects as a kind to the server and
queries the password from the app the
problem here is that there's no
authentication on the IPC channel
between the browser extension and the
server
the app will respond to any client
without verifying if it is actually the
legitimate browser extension so it's
quite easy for the meatball attacker to
exploit RoboForm
so at actor is unprivileged user that
running malicious process is a
background so he can perform client
impersonation here just by connecting as
client to the service app to the app
server and queries the whole password
database from the app so now let's take
a look at more complex example
so one password is another popular
password manager this case is more
interesting because the developer twice
to protect the ibc channel between the
browser extension and the app but it's
not good enough to defend against the
meat mallet actor here the app runs a
WebSocket server on prostitutes III and
with for connection from the browser
extension when the server got the
condition is verify the client very
carefully it checks the browser
extension ID on HTTP header of each
request he also checked the code sending
signature of the client process to make
sure that it is a known browser and most
importantly the sole checks whether the
server and client processes are owned by
the same user so with this said we
couldn't perform client impersonation as
in case of pro-reform
however the client doesn't verify the
server it actually cannot because the
browser extension is sandbox by the
browser so it has access to very limited
api's so this allows minimal attacker to
perform server impersonation and even
though the client and server run an
enter protocol in the first
communication to derive or share
encryption key the desire of this secure
of this protocol is not secure and it's
not secure enough to prevent the server
impersonation attacked now I will show
the protocol so client here is a browser
extension and the server is a desktop
so you can see here that you see not
this clearly not a secure protocol of
the key mottos of orbs of material of
the final key and Sam in the messages
and if you can take a look at step fro
m5 so use a confirmation only happen on
the server side so it means that a
malicious server can skip this
confirmation so this insecure protocol
together with the fact that there's no
server verification allows minimal
attacker to perform server impersonation
on one password and this is how the meet
an attacker can do the attack so first
so title just need to run a WebSocket
server on positive SiC three before the
desktop app does it and when the app
tries to run the server and see that the
prod has been taken the app just fail
silently without informing the user and
when to attack the server got connection
from the browser is canceled it does the
key derivation protocols I saw before
and it just keeps user confirmation
unlined RoboForm sumitra attacker here
cannot access the password database but
we found that he can send a command
called connect document to the browser
extension and collect all the data that
the victim enters into web forms
including an login credentials the
turfed I studied I would like to talk
about his future app security key so
filo YouTube you standard for second
authentication factor and it is
supported by many popular services such
as Google Facebook and github and most
security keys implement this standard
including the wiki and even the new
thousands security key that Google
introduced few week ago also follow this
standard you can see on the right is a
simplified protocol
a powers of YouTube security woods so
first the user must then restart the
device with on a service that we wants
to eat Nemo second factor authentication
basically here's the device sending rate
the public key pair and the service link
the public key with the user after that
when the users wants to log into the
service the service will send a
challenge to the browser and expect to
see a response that containing the
device in a jar on the challenge to get
the response the browser with Sam we
keep sending the challenge to the device
and till we get the response however the
device doesn't automatically sigh and
requests that it received it needs to be
activated by touching a button on it and
it only responds only the first request
that is received a pass attached now we
show how the meat mallet a girl could
exploit YouTube security keys so since
the security keys is supposed to prevent
malicious lock-in even when the user
password has been compromised we assume
here that attacker has obtained the
victim's password and are trying to
crack the second factor so that I always
exploit the Fight Club on Windows and it
users even the one in the background can
access the USB HID devices at any time
the attack is as follow so first so
tactical runs malicious browser process
either in his rocking sessions and sighs
in to the service using the username and
password
yes obtained so Melissa's browser will
receive a challenge from the service
after that the malicious browser we keep
selling the challenge to the device but
a hiker if that a legitimate browser
would do to increase the chance of
getting that challenge site this is easy
because for example chrome only send the
challenge to the device every 300
million
when the victim sighs into any service
using the same security key so victim
will touch the button on the device and
because the attacker is standing the
challenge to the to the device at very
high rate the attacker would get his
requests I with very high probability
because this it is sent with high grades
and the ninja teammate krauser the use
of my notice that the first button touch
has no effect because it is used by the
attacker
but such places are common in computers
and typically ignorant we tested the
attack on popular services including
Facebook and github and we got 100%
success rate so we have seen how we
exploit the proper form one password and
feed oh you cheeky but those are not all
the application that we found funeral to
meet my attacker
this is a list of app and the flu
ambient easily found
password manager and login credentials
our main focus
we also filed with abilities in other
apps that followed client and server
architecture for example in the case of
MySQL the client and the server are on
the same computer the client can connect
to the server using name pipe and we
were able to perform man is a middle
affect on this channel to obtain all the
queries and query results on this
channel so how can a meat mallet I'd be
mitigated
so since mid since attack are performed
by leaving malicious process running the
background the most straightforward
solution would be to limit the number of
users that have access to the computer
ideally each computer should only be
accepted by only one user and we won't
accept should also be disabled or
limited only one user so my parrot I can
also easily be detected so application
developer can simply
compares owner of the client and the
server processes and if they are if they
are owned by the same user then he can
be sure that the channel is not who know
his thought cannot be exploited by the
mid-market actor it might be more
difficult for a JavaScript client
running in web browser such a extension
because they don't have access to the
operating system API to do the other
check in this case cryptographic
solutions such a user assisted pairing
protocol or even TLS can be used to
protest IPC communication so the main
takeaway message from this presentation
is that IPC is not inherently secure
there has been a common belief that this
nothing can do to defend against norco
attacker
it may be true if the user device is
infected by Manuel however as we have
seen there are many other potential
attackers and the user we can list of
privileges including gas can attack IPC
of other user on the same computer an
unlined man where developers can totally
defend the application again this type
attacker and this concludes my
presentation thank you for attention
and the questions questions hello
Jeffrey Goldberg from 1password I'm the
one who did that ad hoc weak broken
protocol there so first of all I want to
thank you for this paper it's
outstanding and we had not considered
user assisted key exchange which would
have solved the problem but for anybody
who's interested in why we had the lousy
key exchange in there either talk to me
or I've posted a link I've tweeted a
link to a discussion of that thank you
thanks they'd never let it sit but
academic research doesn't affect the
real world any other questions
this is a lot people I think it's more
like a comment hi my name is Samuel
visor and Graz University of Technology
I would say you two F is not insecure in
terms of the protocol but it's more like
an issue of secure output presenting
something to the user so that the user
can know which challenge is signing
right now so here we think that it's not
really the problem of the new chip
protocol but it's more like the problem
of windows so window should allow
YouTube should allow USB HID devices to
be accessed by any users at the same
time yeah I think there's still other
attacks possible if you constrain this
to a certain browsers only like in
browser separate sessions in the same
browser you can talk later
Matthew elder Johns Hopkins Applied
Physics I'm very really interesting work
good work
did you notify the vendors do they get
give responses but some besides the one
I mean there you got a list of there's
like 10 12 okay yes we did notify of
them yeah most of them has fixed problem
thank you