and today we talk about Melton and
probably you all know the paper so we'll
discuss the basics and also the new
things that we added to the final
version so I encourage you to read also
the final version did you find here at
Hugh's Nicks so let's start right off we
all know virtual memory and until very
recently the kernel addresses the eronel
was also mapped in the virtual address
space of the user so if you want to read
some kernel memory you can just go pick
an address for instance something human
readable like the Linux version string
get the address to some point a magic in
C dereference the address and read the
value so of course this does not work so
an exception will be thrown
you cannot just read the value a
segmentation fault occurs it's not that
easy because we have memory isolation on
our computers so the kernel is isolated
from the user space and this isolation
is a combination of hardware and
software and user applications cannot
just access anything from the car
otherwise everything will be really
broken in order to support multiple
processes we use paging so we have a
virtual address space to isolate those
processes from each other
and the physical memory is then
organized in so called page frames we
use page tables to map those virtual
addresses to the actual physical memory
that we have and on x86 this looks like
the following so we have multiple levels
of page tables and certain bits of the
virtual address are used as indices for
those tables to translate to the final
physical page and if we take a closer
look at the page table entry in the end
we can see that we find there the actual
physical address and in addition some
interesting bits for instance the page
present bit or also the user mode
accessible bit where you can define if
this page is accessible on which
privilege level in addition typically
the column is mapped into every address
space as we've seen in the beginning but
moreover the in
higher physical memory is also mapped in
the kernel so for instance if we have a
user space address in this graphic we
also have a additional virtual address
that points to the same physical address
in the main memory so with the previous
example if we just try to read an
address we will get the permission check
which checks this bit in the page table
entry it will say no you cannot read
this address so we will fail so on the
architectural level everything works as
intended so the instruction set
architecture is an abstract model of our
computer which serves as an interface
between the hardware and the software
and the microarchitecture that is
executing our instructions is now the
actual implementation of this
instruction set and they can be quite
different to each other
so you all know for instance AMD FM CPUs
Rison Intel Core i7 Intel Xeon and so on
but this all happens on the
microarchitecture level so we cannot
easily observe what's going on there but
we have those side-channel attacks so
even if we have a safe software
infrastructure where we do not have any
bugs the hardware that executes our
software can leak information and using
these side channel attacks we can
exploit this unintentional information
leakage by observing those side effects
this could be the power consumption of
the device so the power consumption is
increased depending on what values
you're processing or the execution time
of the algorithm or also the CPU cache
which we'll take a look at now so if you
have an address for instance of this
variable I and you want to access it the
first time you won't find it in the CPU
cache so you have a cache miss now the
CPU needs to request this address from
the main memory it will be loaded from
the main memory directly into the cache
and the next time when we try to access
this address it is already stored in the
cache so we have a so called cache hit
so
if we have no DRM access the access time
to this address is served it's much
faster if we have a cache miss we need
to access the DRM so this is slower and
if you have a high resolution dimer you
can easily measure that and get a
histogram like this so it's easy to find
a threshold between those two peaks
which allows you to distinguish between
a cache hit and the cache miss and only
with this information and the Bekaa can
build powerful attacks like the flash
and reload attack we've seen earlier so
we assume shared memory between an
attacker process and the victim process
which means the different address is
cached for one its cache basically for
both of them because it's shared memory
now the attacker can flush the address
from the cache so the next time someone
loads it it will be served to memory now
assume the victim is scheduled and tries
to access this address since it's not in
the cache it will be loaded into the
cache by the access of the victim now if
the attacker measures the execution time
how long it takes to access this address
again he can deduce if the victim has
accessed the address in the meantime or
if the victim did not access this
address in the meantime and with this as
we've seen with different cache attacks
and attack you can break crypto and so
on but what is actually happening when
we execute some instructions on our
high-performance CPUs that we have
nowadays there we use out of order
executions which means instructions are
fetched and decoded in the front end
which we see in the upper part of the
picture and then they are dispatched to
the back end and there we have
individual execution units that then
process those instructions so we have
some units for ALU operations or the
load and address or do store operations
what's more important is that now
instructions can be executed out of
order this means they can wait until the
dependencies are ready and what this
means is that instructions that would
occur later in your instruction stream
can be
actually executed before other
instructions the important thing is that
those instructions are retired in order
because otherwise our programs wouldn't
work as expected and only while retiring
the state becomes architectural
invisible if an exception occurs they
are checked during the retirement if so
we can just flush the pipeline and
recover the same state that we had
before but as I said was more important
the state becomes only architectural
visibly when those instructions are
retired so we have a little toy example
and how we can check things out what
they are working so in this example we
just have a null pointer access which
will raise an exception so the next
instruction the access to the array
should never be executed but if we run
this code and then use the flash and we
load attack that we've seen earlier and
iterate over all those pages in the
array we suddenly see a cache hit what
does this mean so apparently unreachable
code was actually executed when the
exception was only thrown afterwards so
with that information we know that out
of order instructions leave Mike for
architectural traces and we can see them
for example also in the cache from now
on we give those instructions the name
of transient instructions and we can
indirectly observe the execution of
those instructions which brings us to
the building blocks of our attack so
assume we have somewhere a secret which
we want as an attacker to extract from
the system so we execute some drains and
instructions that access the secret and
introduce a micro architectural state
change which also works as the sender of
a cover channel and then we need to
transfer this micro architectural state
change to an architectural state because
otherwise we cannot really observe it
and
with the state we then can recover the
secret that we have accessed in those
strands and instructions so the first
thing that we need to do we need to
execute such stringent instructions but
in fact they are executed all the time
as we have seen in our toy example but
as we have also seen in the beginning
loading and inaccessible address leads
to a crash in this case to the
segmentation fault so at one point we
need to prevent the crash because
otherwise our attacker application is
just terminated and we cannot do
anything and there different things that
we can do for instance we can do fault
handling so we just install a signal
handler that will catch the segmentation
fault and jump back to our code and
continuously execution or we could use
entity SX as we've seen in the previous
presentation to suppress the fault
entirely
because when the exception is happening
there the transaction would just be
reported and we can continue or we can
use speculates respect to X by
exploiting speculative execution to
execute those instructions speculatively
and we have the same result so the
second thing is here we directly access
the secret so we do not really use the
side channel but then on the other hand
we establish a cover channel where we
transfer the micro architecture
architectural state change into the
architectural state and the transient
instruction sequence serves here as the
sender the receiver then by iterating
over those pages and reloading those
pages and measuring the time receives
the state change because the page is now
cached and deduces the secret from this
state but what is important is that we
here leverage the cache attack technique
Russian reload we can also use it to
transmit multiple bits at once so we
encode the bytes that we read in to 256
different cache lines that we access but
but really important is it's not limited
to the cache
so you can use also other parts of the
microarchitecture to transmit a secret
as we've seen in a net Spectre attack
for instance so to build our final
attack we just need another layer of
indirection this time we use the value
that we read from this inaccessible
address and use it as the index of the
access to the array so when we then
check whether any part of the array is
cached we see that we indeed have a
cache hit and the index of the cache it
reveals the data that we are not
supposed to read so sometimes the
permission check is apparently not fast
enough and we have the meltdown attack
so with meltdown we exploit out of order
execution to read data at any address we
use the index of the cache hit to reveal
the data and the permission check is not
fast enough and since the entire
physical memory is mapped into the
kernel we can just dump the entire
physical memory as we can see in this
demo so we just start to read at any
address at the random address and in
this case we read descriptions of
packages for the package manager on this
system but if you read the reports in
January Intel said you can only read
values that are stored in the l1 cache
but we don't think it's that's the case
so we also did a new experiment in
addition in the new paper where a thread
constantly flashes the value and the
fret on a different core reloads the
value this means that the targeted data
is not in the l1 cache of the attacking
core but still we can leak the data but
at a lower reading rate so we are much
faster if it's in the l1 but slower if
it's not so Melton might implicitly
cache the data but you can even go one
step further we can use uncatchable
memory so one bit in the page tables as
we've seen can be used to mark a page
uncatchable this means that every read
or write operation will go directly to
main memory and we observed that if the
attacker can trigger a legitimate load
like through a system call to this
address on the same CPU core you can
still leak the data so meltdown might
read the data now not from the cache
because it's uncatchable but of one of
the fill buffers and those filled
buffers are shared between threads
running on the same core so who is
affected for Intel almost every CPU
seems to be affected and we tested many
of them but for AMD no microarchitecture
seems to be affected which is nice
I'm stated that only the cortex a75 is
affected for IBM it's the power
architecture system set and so on and
for Apple all Mac and iOS devices seem
to be affected but there are also some
other CPU manufacturers which didn't
state which of the devices are affected
and it appears that also the Samsung
Galaxy s7
using the Exynos Mongoose and one CPU
chip seems to be affected and it's the
first custom CPU co-op in the Exynos a
top star with a perceptron branch
prediction full out of order instruction
execution and full out of order loads
and stores and as you see in the paper
we also were able to mount a melt on
attack on that device but how does the
practice look like so dumping the entire
physical memory takes some time because
not everything fits into the l1 where we
have the most highest speed achieved
with 582 kilobytes per second on average
in the l3 it was only twelve point four
if it's uncashed it was like ten bytes
per second and an improved version
around 3.2 kilobyte so it's not very
practical in most scenarios we just want
to dump the entire physical memory of a
machine but you can also do more
targeted attacks so we have also created
on our systems so we can also use it to
break a SLR to access internal current
structures that we can
use to mount more targeted to decks so
we try to locate a known value inside
the kernel like the Linux planner as
we've seen earlier and we start at the
default address according to the symbol
table of the running home so you need to
know the version of the current running
on the system but for each Linux
distribution this is the same since
kayla has only an entropy of 6 bits
there are only 64 possible randomization
offsets and we can just try all of them
and the difference between the found
address where we can reach the leaked
value and the non randomized space
address is now our randomization offset
with that we broke the SLR
so we know exactly where he attended in
mapping starts and we can use this to go
on and for instance locate a victim
process so in Linux all processes are
managed in a linked list and the head of
the list is stored in the init task
structure and this is at a fixed offset
that varies also among the Linux counts
and each task list structure contains a
pointer to the next task and also the
process ID the name and also the root of
the multi-level page labor so we can
search this structure using male town to
find the process we want to target we
can then use the physical address using
the Beijing structures to read directly
the memory of this process and then read
the content using the targeted physical
map with our physical address we can
just enumerate all mapped pages and dump
the entire process memory so we do not
need to dump the entire physical memory
anymore and if we know the location of
the key for instance that we want to
extract we can just dump the key
directly so how can we solve that
the problem is rooted in the hardware
that we have and it's a race competition
between the permission check and the
memory fetch so we can just serialize
them and we do not have that problem or
we can introduce a half split of the
user space and the kernel space where we
fix the crown to the upper half of the
aerospace and the user to the
laughs and we just introduced a new bit
to be backwards compatible to figure out
if we have detective but fixing the
hardware is a long-term solution so we
need a solution in software and as you
remember earlier this is how the address
space looked like we had the kernel
space map in there and the big problem
is that when we are running in user mode
we also have the curl mapped so we
should get rid of the kernel while
running in user mode and this is
actually what the Kaiser paper did so
whenever you have a context switch and
running in user mode you um map the
entire curl and therefore also T
identity mapping and then you cannot
read anything anymore
if you mount meltem or so we thought
until very recently so Kaiser has been
published in the summer of 2017 at the
esos conference and it was initially
proposed as a countermeasure against
other side channel attacks but since
this massive change to the operating
system where we do not have anything
mapped anymore brings also the profit
that it also defeats male town in this
case so Melton then has been improved so
that sort of the Kaiser patch of the
Kaiser paper has been improved and then
merged into the Linux kernel and the
name kpti apple also released some
updates and windows have they have also
their implementation with the same
principles called kernel virtual address
Shadow and also for Samsung the phone
the patches have been rolled out last
month
so it's also fixed there we have a proof
of concept implementation of our code
online you can check out the github
repository and try to run it on your
machine hopefully you already have two
patches so you would need to disable the
mitigations but you can go and play with
that so to conclude we underestimated
micro architectural attacks for a long
time and with Melton that we we have
seen that we can read arbitrary kernel
memory from user space without any
privileges or permissions it affected
millions of devices from
various CPU manufacturers and the
countermeasure that we have implemented
comes with a performance impact so I
invite you to check out also the next
stock because it brings some nice new
insights and thank you for your
attention
and if you have any questions feel free
to ask questions a young ginger from
Oregon State University
impressive work and I have tried to like
a replicate the meltdown attack again
and again definitely with the l1 cache
yet it works very well yeah I'm very
surprised that like a uncashed attack
also works so could you share a little
bit of details of the how can you make
the successful attack in like a 10 by so
ii that's quite impressive because is it
something like you're just trying to
address modern times when then you
eventually get something work you
apparently it also gets removed into the
cache at some point but there some other
tricks that you could do when you mount
a Melton attack one represented at
blackhat last week you just it's not
intuitive but you just before accessing
the address you're not allowed to access
you access a null pointer and with that
you increase the chance to read the
actual value significantly so is your
Intel processor will eventually cache to
someone in the cache memory in under
cacheable so uncatchable memory should
not ever be pulled into the cache but as
we've seen it could be directly served
from the line buffer so there are more
constraints in mounting the attack with
uncatchable memory yes so you need to
run with on the same physical core
because those line buffers are feared on
there otherwise it won't work so you
need to pin your attack code on those
cause okay thank you you're welcome
other questions okay so let's thank
Moritz again
[Applause]