thank you for attending to start I'm mo
and this is a joint work with my
colleagues and my advisors at the
University of Illinois at Chicago and
today I want to talk about single
sign-on however I'm not going to talk
about implementation flaws or bugs in
SSL Perkins instead I'm going to show
you and show you the attacks are enabled
by single sign-on even method single
sign-on is implemented correctly so
let's have a quick look at what we're
referring to a single sign-on and how it
works in the front end and back end
so generally single sign-on means you
have one main account and use that one
minute count to log into different
services or different web sites for
instance if you have a you can use your
Facebook account to log in to various
websites such as cor Pinterest and so on
and so forth so let's have a look at
what happens behind the scene this is a
high high level view of the Peugeot so
suppose that the user wants to use
tinder and wants to use her own Facebook
account to log into tinder then the
browser gets redirected to the identity
provider which is Facebook in this case
and Facebook authenticates users if the
user is not already logged into the
Facebook account Facebook asked for the
username and password if the user is
already logged in Facebook automatically
authenticates the user and after the
after Facebook agrees to share
information with the relying party the
browser redirects to the relying party
site in this case dinner with the
authorization code and then cleaner uses
that authorization code to retrieve
necessary tokens and use those tokens
for obtaining further information from
the identity provider so the key point
here we should note that is after this
process the common method that relying
parties used to authenticate is through
setting persistent cookies on the
client-side so single sign-on is very
usable it's very convenient way of using
a lot of
fanservice through one account however
this comes with a price because an
attacker who can take over that Ida
pecan can also access all of those
services and as we see in later slides
because of the interplay between single
sign-on and local account management
recovering from the IDP account
compromised becomes very hard or even
impossible for victims so the
architecture of single sign-on makes the
IDP accounts very valuable because of
the access it provides to a lot of
different accounts so in our key focus
on the aftermath of IDP account
compromised instead of focusing on how
it is compromised
however we will demonstrate some
examples to show that to show how they
can can be compromised in real world
scenarios so in our threat model we
consider two methods of IDP account
compromised fishing which is the main
type of fishing is which is the main
type of the most common type of they can
compromise and also phishing provides
access to the username and password we
also focus on the cookie ID jacking
because it can affect even cautious
users who do not fall into phishing
scams we chose these two main attacks
because we wanted to capture the the
attacker was different level of
capabilities and technical and the
attacks that have taken call
difficulties so you might think that
cookie hijacking would never happen like
it's a decade old problem and it's not
gonna happen after this long time we
have TLS encryption of all of these
mechanism however I would like to show
that the quicker using quickly attacking
can happen and it can happen for even
major services such as Facebook so we
started by auditing Facebook main
applications in major platforms and we
found that Facebook is in a browser
leaked session cookies in when the user
visited some websites so an attacker in
the middle of the traffic could have
captured those session cookies and by
replaying those session cookies could
have completely taken over the account
and we also found out that if an
attacker used that session quickies to
take over the account the attacker
session didn't show up in the victims
Facebook active sessions so in a lot of
our attacks that we are discussing
having a password doesn't provide
doesn't provide it's not necessary but
in some times it provides some is more
still clear attacks and provides longer
access so we also found a bug in
Facebook that allowed an attacker to
overwrite the existing password without
having access to the current password so
to measure the scale of this problem and
to understand that how many users were
actually affected by this problem we
monitored our University's wireless
traffic for the duration of four months
and we were able to collect more than
5,700 session cookies which allowed a
complete account takeover so we also
needed to understand the scale of the
access the attacker can gain to other
services through this IDP IDP account
hijacking so we measure the prevalence
of single sign-on in the wild by
building a crawler which crowd Alex's
top 1 million and we looked at we looked
for 6065 well-known IDPs and
corresponding relying parties so our
results showed more than 6% of the
website software it's single sign-on and
Facebook was a prominent IDP with the
most coverage however we have to we have
to keep in mind that because websites do
not generally do not follow a specific
approach and implement single sign-on
differently our measurement is just our
measurement represent a lower bound of
what is actually out there so it turns
out that single sign-on Ecosse
same is much more complex than we
thought there are some relying parties
out there that act as an IDP for
instance if a if an attacker takes over
a Facebook account the attacker can
directly compromise a line party in this
case for instance at a time we
experimented a big packet which a line
party or Facebook so because the bit
packet is also an IDP for gitlab the
attacker can also compromised eclip
accounts while the kid lab account
doesn't directly support Facebook as an
IDP so our analysis showed that
basically half of the IDPs exposed this
to all behavior and this disparate
creates two main problems
the attacker can increase coverage by
this 12 behavior and also this behavior
can hide the origin point of the account
compromise so it turns out that half so
we with us at our data set and we found
out that an attacker who can take over
Facebook account can increase the
coverage by 2.1 percent in alex's top
100,000 so here the green nodes are the
nodes the relying parties are directly
support Facebook and the red nodes are
the nodes that can indirectly compromise
through this dual behavior so for our
study we considered two main attacks
first we examine the practicality of
relying without takeover using Facebook
the hijacked Facebook cookie then we
introduced we will introduce a novel
attack that can only happen due to the
interplay of single sign-on and local
account management so we should note
that we have many variations in our
attacks and we have a lot of details and
I've encourage you to read the paper for
for full details so for the first attack
we selected 29
services from Alexa top 566 Isles
applications from top categories of the
time so first we examine the feasibility
of the relying party account takeover
using those hijacked Facebook cookies
and then we investigated the visibility
of the attacks to the victims and
finally we explored the length of the
access the attacker can maintain and
whether she can prolong that access so
there's an option for your line parties
that can they can explicitly ask the
identity provider to authenticate users
using username and password even if the
user is already logged into the ID IDP
account we found out that the majority
of the services didn't use this option
so we were able to basically take over
all of those account using just hijacked
Facebook cookies and we also noted that
none of the relying parties notified to
notify the victim of suspicious any
suspicious activities so in our
experiment we saw multiple unexpected
behaviors in the apps were tested for
instance in one instance a dating app
kept messages on red when the attacker
was reading the messages or in case of
an uber we we we expected that uber
would recognize that two devices from
two different locations are accessing to
one account but we were able to track
the person who was sitting in a car from
another location and we were able to see
the past trips and we were able to even
tip the driver on behalf of the person
so here we consider the case that the
attacker might lose the access to the
IDP account for instance the victim
might change the password and we wanted
to find out a way we wanted to find out
what options are possible for the
attacker to prolong that access or
maintain that access so one implement
one implication of offering single
sign-on in addition on
traditional user user password
authentication is that the attacker can
create a separate path by gaining the
initial access through single sign-on
and then switching back to email and
password authentication after that so he
states that a subset of our data so that
we found out that we found out that
basically half of our samples didn't
require any sort of password for
modifying those emails so here's an
example for instance in packing.com that
not only booking.com allowed modifying
the emails but also sent the
confirmation email to the newly added
email rather than the caribou so we also
found we also developed another attack
that allowed maintaining long-term
access to line party by linking to
separate Facebook accounts - one relying
party so in this case for instance the
attacker when the attacker takes over
the relying party account and this is
the victim's relying party - the
attacker can disconnect Facebook from
the relying party term and by logging
into her own Facebook account and then
reconnecting back to the recurring to
the relying party to the Facebook
account the attacker can create a
separate path to the account with
another phase of another Facebook
account so this print this provides a
very sneaky attack as it leaves no trace
and no trace for the user because it's
there's nothing visible here
for the user to see something is going
on and recovering from this attack
requires tremendous amount of manual
work because the user should go through
all of those relying parties and this
kind of the Facebook and the reconnect
back to be able to recover from the
attack so so far we've talked about the
attacks on relying parties that the
victim already has an account now we
consider the case that the attacker is
interested in a relying party but
fifteen doesn't have an account with you
for instance let's say that uber and we
are interested in an attacker who lays a
long-term trap by creating relying party
accounts very partly comes plaintively
not waiting for the victim to try and
create an account so traditional
credentialed based authentication makes
a distinction between account creation
and login for instance creating an
account that already that already exists
shows chosen error as it's shown here
however based on our observation single
sign-on abstract the fact that the
account already exists and shows no
visual difference between these separate
actions therefore therefore prior
existence of relying party account is
not apparent to the victim if the
attacker preemptively creates the
credits the accounts with the single
sign-on so in our examination we saw
that a lot of service a lot of relying
party services use for instance only a
single button like sign up with Facebook
or logon with Facebook or continue with
Facebook and some other websites used
first has two separate buttons for
blogging or account creation however we
did not didn't notice any sort of
difference between these actions and the
final outcome was the same no matter
which one of these buttons were very
pushed so far we focus on the attacker
side and now we want to focus on the
user side and see what sort of recovery
actions are available to the user so
that the user could basically use to
recover from the attack so a tooling
chain is created when the user goes
through the single sign-on single
sign-on process and the same goes for
the attacker so suppose that the user
becomes aware of any suspicious
activities and then the user tries to
basically cut the attackers access out
of the identity provider by logging out
and changing password and invalidating
all of the active sessions however as
long as you
parties persistent cookies are valid or
secondary authentication path exists
between the attacker and the relying
party the link between the relying party
attacker remains intact so in our
experiments we wanted to understand the
available recovery options and whether
these recovery options are effective in
an actual in a real scenario so we aside
the effect of various remediation
actions on attackers access to your line
party such as logging out logging
logging out from the IDP lining out from
the I repeat resetting changing IDP
password and we want to test that if
these actions are actually effective so
it turns out almost basically 75% of the
services in these services recovery
actions had no effect on attackers
access to line party service more
importantly more than 89% of the
services did not provide did not offer
any sort of session management to the
user so that the user could invalidate
those active sessions so for instance we
also found a very strange behavior
between multiple services for instance
Goodreads in code is when we revoke the
access from the very work t-axis it only
affected the web access it did not
affect the mobile access and also in
kind of partial read access always you
make no matter what action actions the
user took so given that prevalent single
sign-on schemes can't prevent all the
attacks we've discussed here we designed
single sign of an extension to open ID
connect to address such short columns
this is just a 30-foot thousand view of
our proposal and can find all of the
design details in our paper
so once the attacker has taken over the
account which is shown in step one to
four the user suppose that the user
becomes aware of the problem and
initiates the revocation process so the
user sensitive
vocation request to the identity
provider and then the identity provider
notifies all of the relying parties that
the user has account with and evokes all
the tokens of those relying parties then
all of those relying parties should
invalidate all of the active sessions
and all of the relying party account
should be frozen until the victim be
authenticates through single signer this
makes sure that all the attacks we
discussed here whether it is a
countermeasure of all the attacks we
discussed here so just a quick recap of
my main points so we showed that not
only single sign-on can complain an
attack amplification role but also it
can create new attack vectors which were
not possible with the traditional
credential based authentication we also
showed that in most services there is no
course of action the victim can take
tool immediately account compromise
after immediate remediation compromise
finally we propose a strictly
universally vocation scheme to address
the attacks that are enabled by single
sign-on so please do the paper for all
the missing details and feel free to
contact me for any questions suggestions
or concerns we also made our single
sign-on prevalence data set available to
public at the following address and with
that I would like to conclude my talk
and I'd be happy to answer your
questions
[Music]
thank you any questions we're gonna end
up with getting to the refreshments
early it looks like you have a question
hi my name is Brian Great Auk had a
question about the revocation the excuse
me
proposal for the revocation so in the
scenario when the victims account gets
hijacked to to fishing is this something
that the attacker could use as well to
lock out the victim so the thing is a
debate that we proposed this
countermeasure is that all of the attack
and all of the accounts are will be
frozen until the user uses single
sign-on to log into those accounts and
we also consider the fact I consider the
part that the user should also basically
the RDP accounts also locked out and the
attacker cannot access to doubt to that
account and through some sort of like
two-factor authentication the user can
be cover access to the IDP account and
again enable all of those or recover all
of those relying party a compromised
remember accounts okay make sense Thanks
hi my name is Daniel have you had any
feedback from the single sign-on
providers on your location suggestions
the basically during a process so they
were multiple disclosures one was for
Facebook that the Facebook fix the
vulnerability the other was the
disclosures to the apps that we examined
some of them had contact information
some of them they don't have we also
contacted the authors of open ID connect
and we are happy to basically
collaborate with them for implementing
this and including this for the open ID
connect in further versions
any other questions if not let's thank
this bigger