thank you for coming to my foundation
everyone and today I'm very happy to
bring our paper scissors and accurate
cash present as foreigners my name is
Hamza I'm a PhD student from UC
Riverside and microsurgery is also my
advisor ok let's first take a look at
the problem we want to solve in a paper
I can give you a short answer currently
give me an angel image how can we decide
this to be cific cv has been patched
obviously this is an important problem
right because for attackers they can try
to exploit untouched avoid abilities and
for defenders we must ensure that other
security patches has been propagated in
time so I will use a real-world example
to explain our problem more clearly we
know that is the lynnium screen over the
surf is open sourced right and the
Google's Android kernel which is also
based on the Linux kernel is also open
sourced its LSP project okay so how
about is the third-party vendors under
the kernel they are also folks from the
origin recipe recipe project but we have
some modifications and for this Chronos
purely the vendors to your undies
released some snapshots of their kernel
source code occasionally and this
releases the URL with significant delay
so for most of time we can currently get
Android kernel image in banner form for
this Windows kernel so in this situation
if we found a security vulnerability
unrelated Apaches in the mainstream
religions kernel ro SP project how can
we ensure that easier propagated to the
Windows kernel and actually this is not
only for the Linux kernel or OSP project
basically any scenario where the open
source components are reused in the
closest source of the where the same
problem exists we ask whether the open
source security patch has been applied
in the battery and as this is the
problem we want to solve yeah
however this problem is challenging
without who challenges fight the first
one this task is alike the you need to
locate a needle in your changing face
type on one hand a security patch is
alike the small needle is more and a sub
hole for example this tequila fresh if
only changes an operator and is a splash
it only as a small and a single line is
Orangina function so they are both the
morning start
furthermore the haystack is the changing
for example this OSP security patch has
introduced the new lines Orangina
function right on the later this
security patch can be back for here it
with Windows kernel with different
context under then there can be other
patches applying on the same function
and changing the contexts
so all forwards approach the version but
as they all have different contexts so
this makes our problem much more
difficult a second challenge the
haystack we need to search a needle is a
banner II instead of the source code
tree this is also a difficult problem so
there is this some relative of work to
this topic but basically they cannot
solve our problem the first category of
religious work is source code alive
imagine basically this work will try to
search your source code to defeat in
your target the source code tree
obviously that we need to deal with the
banner e so this have woken under work
and a second category is a binary to
banner image and as they will try to
search a banner instruction sequence in
target a binary
however the see inside this world likes
knowledge about a needle itself remember
that we need to search a needle in the
haystack but surely this type of work
will compare two binary haystacks and
give us the cost going similarity score
between the two banner haystacks but we
need to search for the needle so only
with the source code
purchase other information we can get
the best knowledge of the needle
yourself okay
here comes our solution our system is
named a fiber and basically is motivated
by human experts behaviors when faced
with the same problem as a high-level we
will first an Ally's Allatoona sights
introduced a biosecurity of hash and we
will pick out those most suitable to new
sites and try to translate them into a
binary level signatures which can then
be used to match in the target binary
and this way we can correlate to the
source code allowing information under
the pen reliable information and to
develop accurate and precise fetch
present tests okay so next I will deter
outflow from the progeny site analysis
part let's first consider what the human
will do in this situation
imagine that currently you are given an
open source Africa touch and you are
asked to locate it in the target binary
so what's your first assault where a
security patch introduced multiple
channels in different functions and
across multiple affairs so very
naturally the first thing we need to is
to pick out those channel sites which
are obvious unique and a written
representative and then we can try to
locate additional sites in a targeted
binary in our system we consider several
factors when picking up the Genesis the
first factor consider is uniqueness for
example this security patch has
introduced a new line in the function
and we must ensure that this new line
only appears in the patch the world and
if the this one also appears in
unpatched version maybe in a different
position then we will be unable to
differentiate the patch the unpatch the
word solid based on this single line and
in this context we must either some
contacts lines around the edge in the
site to make it a unique and a certain
factor consider if stability as we
mentioned previously the context of the
of the original function can be
effective so if we include too many
source code lands in our channel site
then our change that is unstable because
it can be easily affected by other
security patches or by other changing
contacts so we must usual our
chinainside is stable only to do this we
want to keep our chin aside ice more as
a passport and early will always start
from a single line under we only are the
contact silence when necessary and so
the factory will consider is easy to
recognize for example a security patch
has introduced is the new function code
right under this function call is not in
Lund so this is almost a perfect tuna
size why because we can easily locate it
in target binary by similarly looking at
his according instruction and the final
column name it's very straightforward
undersecured patch may also introduce
some conditional statements like this if
sediment this is also cool genocide why
because it's if sediment will chin to
post the syntax structure under
semantics as a binary level it's also
obvious however if the security fashion
introduces assignment statement this is
not as good as previous two cases
because it will only change the
semantics and the syntax structure will
remain the same so basically our system
we will try to rank all the Regina sites
according to our terminology the code is
to pick others most easy to recognize in
the sites
okay so now we have a site or preferred
channel size and the next we need to
translate them into a binary level
signatures which can be used to match in
the targeted battery so how can we do
this if we wanted to do this manually
what we will do let's still consider it
small example and this is our source
code allow each insight is if statement
and with two branches so the first team
very nature is a syntactic structure
because syntax structure is very obvious
at the parent level we can expect a
condition of jump related to if
statement and we can expect to following
basic blocks representing the two
branches true branch and false branch
and besides syntax we also need to
consider the semantics which means for
the condition using the conditional jump
note the condition should be exactly
seeing as a source code allows genocide
it should be a bigger than one and the
same thing for the true and false
branches so our system basically follow
the same procedure we will try to
correlate the posted syntax or semantics
from the source code to the binary code
okay so to do this our first step is to
identify all the banner instructions
that are related to the origin or source
quality massage fortunately because we
have the patch source code our life are
made much easier because we can compare
this source code into binary and the
compiler will generate the debug
information which flow is a mapping from
the source code aligns to the primary
instructions I mean in this example we
identify for banner instructions that
our ability to assess quality massage
and is for instructions they form a
local control flow graph the first node
is a conditional jump second is a
functioning imitation so next we need to
consider the semantics of this local
control flow graph for this purpose we
need to first identify all the root
instructions within each basic block so
what are those instructions let's
consider the first base block and either
instruction will calculate to the sum of
the X 3 and X 4 and a store result in
access our origin the X 0 will be
compared to X 2 in the same instruction
so in this example the add instruction
only produces some intermediate results
which will be consumed by a CMP
instruction and the same instruction has
already captured all the semantics of
the basic block so it's essential
instruction is a root instruction
formula speaking with the
the instruction are those instructions
whose outputs will no longer be consumed
by other instructions and in practice we
identify all the route instructions by
performing a basic block level data flow
analysis after we get a route
instruction we need to associate the
semantic formulas to issue the
instruction lie still consider the CMP
instructions we identify the previously
if we only look as a single instruction
it's formula is like X 0 because an X 2
but if we also look at the preceding add
instruction we know that the r0 is
actually some Oh X 3 and X 4 and if we
look even further we know that x-ray
comes from X 0 and X 4 comes from X 1 so
our formula becomes X 0 plus X 1 big oh
thanks - so up to this point we can
under transform our formula anymore
because we have already reached the
function entry point so what are the
formula mean is the source code the
level where paths are missing for call
information X 0 in the first function
parameter X 1 second X to the third so
at the source code level this means a
plus B bigger than C this way we can
correlate the semantics between the
source code and the binary our system
you will extract all semantics formulas
by performing a function level
intra procedure and under constraint
symbol execution ok so now we have
binary signature which which is
basically a local control flow graph and
every know the contents the set of rules
instruction and every root instruction
content is related to a semantic formula
so next we need to match this venery
signature in the target language how can
we do this well at first we can consider
some quick and easy to crack the
features for example the topology of the
boundaries of nature and in this example
the topology with just two connected
nodes and we can also consider the root
instruction types hmm included in every
node so in this example the first node
should I be a conditional jump a second
node should be
function invocation and the quarry name
is bar and by these quick features we
can already rapidly narrow down our
search space in the target primary
function just by the quick features
we'll have two candidate areas under
then we need to further to the
comparison based on the semantic
formulas we need to abstract semantic
formulas for the candidate areas and a
comparison to the formula so the origin
or signature and by the comparison we
can exclude the one of this candidate
areas
so only one matches in this case the
binary signature has been successfully
matched in the target binary and we can
see that the perseverance okay so to
compare two formulas basically we will
first simplify the formulas by the
history solver I know we understand we
perform a strict formula match okay so
so far I have covered the general flow
or our system but there are some special
an interest in cases the first case
images that the patch has introduced a
function call and is this function
called the unique which means it only
appears in the patched version and the
dysfunction causes not inland which
means we can search it by looking at his
according instruction and the quarry
name and in this fusion we don't need
any semantic formulas so we don't need a
symbol execution is the solution just
the very simple cody existence test in
his habit the second example let's look
how this security fetch it only changes
the one single parameter within a
function call so we recall that
previously we said to keep our changes
as table we are we will only start from
a single level but in this case it's not
even a single line it's a single
parameter so in the boundaries in
measure generation the matching process
will only include these instructions
that's related to the single parameter
which makes our matching more accurate
and stable so we'll have other corner
cases para due to a time limit
we've never covered another coverage
currently I mean if you are interested
you can refer to our paper from Modi
cares okay so comes the evaluation part
and in the evaluation we have crawled
107 security patches from the Android
security bulletins the time frame is
from the June 2016 and May 2017 we also
collected 800 kernel images from three
mainstream lenders and basically we try
to test the presence of these patches in
this under the kernel images let's first
focus on the accuracy and overall we can
say that our system have excellent
accuracy and virtue we have the 94%
accuracy and we don't have the first
pass use so the first pass you mean
sighs we've only believe the patch is
present but in fact the pressure is not
there in the parent this is dangerous
because it's Qamishli the developer to
ignore a certain security patch will
have some false negatives and the four
snactives
mean sites will only believe with the
patch is not zero but Apache is actually
there
this requires extra time for the human
experts to confirm but anyway is secure
so we have we give detailed analysis of
the root cause of the first negative in
our paper and you can drive it far
prefer for multi hairs and we only want
to introduce two root causes the first
one a function in life so recall that
the auto binary signal generated form is
reference binary and source code so if a
quarry function is inland in the
reference but not in the target our
parameter signature will fail to match
the second reason the patch of
temptation if Apache is bug reported to
another function may be the chin the
site of the patch can be modified to
seal to the target function so in this
case our memory signature will also fail
to match but anyway it's banner
signatures are secure and in the future
we try to resolve this force negative
cases as our future world okay then
let's take a look at the performance to
be honest our system is not as fast as
Spanish abandon machine work because we
consider more expensive with semantic
features but in exchange we'll have
better accuracy and we believe our
performance is still accept acceptable
because it's still much faster than a
manual work and besides our system can
be easily paralyzed and in your
evolution we also identify many
vulnerabilities which are not patched in
the Android kernel images if we're now
is the time like all these security
patches there are two security patches
are not propagated to the Android kernel
image after one month and five after two
months to after you in half a year which
is very amazing right but we believe
that it's our system you have to avoid
the such cases in the future oh by the
way some of this half a year security
patch cases have been confirmed by the
vendors ok so here's a case study of our
system this CV is one of those half a
year patch so we can say that the patch
yourself I've introduced as a single
line a single anniversa more it's just a
salmon statement and our signature is
basically a basic block and our semantic
formula is to stop this zero value to a
memory location and the memory address
is x0 plus offset under this x0 by the
calling convention is the first function
parameter in our case is the SEC F
function parameter and x0 plus an off
site basically means the dereference of
a field within a set of structure so we
match the binary level semantics with
the source code allows matic
in this case ok about our implementation
we use anger as our symbolic engine and
we modify these internals and our system
has a run the ferris on the lines or
person code and it's still under
improvement but we have obvious acidity
and github if we are interested please
feel free to check out our
implementation and the levels
feedbacks okay that's basically well
thank you time for questions to start
this off I'll ask a question so if a
patches applied in principle so not
exactly either that's created but if
it's applied in principle to do the same
thing does this system also detect that
so say we don't really use the same the
same we don't create a new variable but
we just do something similar with the
old variable so your system detect that
sorry
sure so if a patch is semantically
applied so it's applied in principle but
it's not really applied exactly as it is
okay would your system do take something
like that okay so and so I think it's
basically very similar to the Thatcher
temptation cases right approach it may
be semantically similar but understand
syntax allowable it may not be exactly
same I mean this case with doing
contrary some difficulties yeah you know
imagine but basically because we look at
a semantic formulas we think of
constitutive is the part of these cases
because we look at the semantic features
instead of chilliest syntax imagine
exactly have another question I'm
curious have you looked at so like the
Android patch level we'll say okay this
was patched up to March 2017 have you
looked at a comparison like seeing if
you know the patches that you detect in
the actual kernel image actually match
with those dates because there's you
know it could be that they're just
because that date is you know just set
by the by the vendor you know so
have you sort of tried to compare that
to see if there discrepancies
sorry kind of yeah yeah sure so like if
a you know if you go into your system
information you see that the Android
well its patched up to March 2017 so it
should have all of your security patches
up to that date right so the question is
have you thought about taking your
methods and actually verifying that an
actual binary kernel is patched as far
as it says it is no we haven't done that
okay I'm sorry
yeah yeah the we do have some anecdotal
evidence ok some someone else actually
published some reports saying that
vendors sometimes do cheat the customers
they claim that the patch is being
applied but it's actually not we haven't
done that but it's a it's something we
can do yeah that would be really cool