hello everyone today I gonna talk about
the kissing a practical can colleague
execution engine tailor for high birth
as a this is joint work with my
colleague Sangolli monsoon and professor
test came from Georgia Tech and
professor Jung Jin Jong from Oregon
State University
as you might know there are two popular
ways to find security bugs fuzzing and
calculating execution those two
techniques have their own pros and cons
first fuzzing which randomly generates
the input it is good for finding some
general inputs but it is bad at finding
some specific inputs which are highly
constrained in concolor execution is
good for finding such kinds of input
that it has fundamental problem called
state explodin highbury fuzzing can
address this issue by combining these
two techniques it can find that those
kinds of like specific inputs using
calculated execution and it can limit
state explosion by by limiting forking
at only the branches which are hard for
fuzzing hybrid fuzzing has achieved
great success in the small-scale study
for example the driller which is one of
the state of heart hybrid fuzzy it won
the third place in CGC competition which
is the competition that made the
automatic system for finding bugs and
exploitation it found the six new
crashes from the cgc competition which
cannot be found by neither fuzzing or
the Conkling execution however if we
apply this current hybrid fuzzing it
suffers from many problems to scale to
real-world software first it is very
slow to generate the constraint a second
it cannot support complete system code
which is essential for supporting the
real world software a third it is not
effective in January
in test cases so our system Kusum can
address this issue by introducing
several key ideas first we discard
intermediate layer which is the one of
the performance bottle ID in current con
college execution for symbol for
hybridizing a second we use concrete
environment to support system calls and
third we introduce several heuristics to
efficient to generate test cases for
highbury fuzzing the q scene is really
scaled to the real were soft where we
found the third team previously known
bugs in open source software and all we
want to note that all applications are
already first by AFL or OSS first the
bucket that we found including the bug
in a ffmpeg is which is being fast by
the OSS fuzz for more than two years and
these bugs are hard to find
by fuzzing because it required some
complex constraint to find this box so
before we before we jump to there like
Kasim I want to introduce hybrid footing
in general so in the program it
programmed it extracted base block and
it converts its base belonging to the
intermediate representations for
simplicity
after it generated intermediate
intermediate representations it generate
while executing intermediate
representation it generated constraints
and it also fork in some states unlike
classical control execution when it fork
it gets the information from the buzzing
for the code coverage and decide whether
it wants to working or not and after it
gets the constraint is solved this
constraint using constraints over in the
January test cases and defeat these test
cases back to the present there are
several problems in this design first
one is that the intermediate
representation
intermediate representation currently
introduced significant performance
overhead they're slowed down the this
hybrid fighting a lot to mitigate this
cue seem directly generate constraint
instead of using the intermediate
representation and remove this layer and
the second is state working state to 14
introduces several problems in the
environment modeling so therefore
instead of working we use the concrete
environment modeling to support
completed system calls and third when we
generate the test cases from the
constraints there is inefficiency come
from the unsatisfiable pathways so q
seem currently optimistically solve some
solve this constraint to generate useful
test cases for fuzzing and finally this
constraint to generation can be blocked
by the some complex logics like a
compression or decompression or the
encryption or decryption QC amuses
baseball a pruning to handle this issue
but due to the time limit in this
presentation I will now cover this so
please refer our paper for detail the
first I would like to talk about the
performance overhead introduced by these
intermediate representations so people
use intermediate representation because
is because they are good to make
implementation easier so it provides a
architecture independent abstraction and
we can reuse code for the or
architectures for example anger it works
on many architectures including x86 arm
and MIPS but ir incurs a significant
performance overhead first the reason is
it increased the number of sign of
instructions in our evaluation the backs
which is the eye are used by anger it
increased the number of instruction by
four times seven up four times seven
times four point seven times and we need
to execute a whole base block
symbolically the reason is that there
like because of the caching and
optimization when generating that this
intermediate representation but the
problem is that the only thirty percent
of these instructions need to be
executed symbolically so we need to
execute like a 70 more 70 percent more
instruction which do not have to be
executed symbolically so solution for
that QC is execute the instructions
directly without using this intermediate
layer yes we have to pay this
implementation complexity but we are we
are willing to pay this implementation
complexity for our performance as a
result
Kusum reduces the number of instructions
a lot
we tested QC and driller which is one of
the state of art library father in 126
ECC binaries Kusum needs to execute four
times less instructions than driller
second one is that the incomplete
environment modeling due to the state of
working state of working is good because
it can reduce the re-execute overhead
for constraint to generation so if you
want to reach some state you don't have
to react ute you can just recover from
the snapshot but the problem is that
this state of routine is non-trivial so
state income college institution can be
divided into two programs data and
kernel state fourteen program state is
trivial you can save with memory
register and constraints but 14 kernel
state is non-trivial because you need to
maintain all the candidate test
structures such as file system net
State and the memory system and those
kinds of things so to handle those there
are two main ways to handle this state
of working in kernel but they have
problems in either completeness or
performance for example kind of modeling
which is used by anger it model the
corner functions it provides the small
performance overhead but the problem is
that the it cost incompleteness
currently anger can support only a
limited number of system calls in Linux
second one is Africana emulation like I
used in s3 it treats like Conner as a
program so it provides the completeness
but since we need to execute currently
symbolically so lower it introduced a
large performance overhead so to resolve
this issue we use the re execution
instead of state forking
we know it will introduce the high reax
occasion overhead but we can reduce this
pairi execution over it by using
instruction level execution and the base
block printing and the we also can limit
the constraints of solving because we
are in the hybridizing so we can limit
the constraint solving based on the
coverage information from fuzzing so QC
only models minimal system calls related
to the user interactions for example the
standard input or file read or network
interface in the if there are other
system calls then we call system call
using the concrete values so for example
if we have and protect with the symbolic
size that we use the we converted the
concrete size and called this function
the problem of this concrete environment
is that there like it can result in some
incomplete constraints for example if we
convert this and protect with the
symbolic size to the concrete size then
it will add some implicit constraint so
without knowing the semantics of this
consistent cost then we have only two
choice for concretize this value which
result in the over constraint or we just
ignore this value and that we will like
a suffer from the under constraint
problem to resolve this issue to amuse
unrelated constraint elimination which
is the classical optimization for a
constraint to eliminate a constraint
constraint to solving this constraint is
all relate to concentrate to elimination
on these of the
constraint related to the branch so for
example like there is a sample program
which get x and y as an input and equal
and protect with ax which result in the
incomplete constraint for X if we if we
hit the last branch then the the path
constraint will be the constraints for X
and the constraint 2 for y in that case
constraint for ax is incomplete but if
we extract only the branch dependent
constraint then the constraint will be
the constraint only related to Y and we
solve this constraint using the
constraints over and we use the ax as a
concrete value by doing so we can
tolerate incomplete constraints third I
want to talk about ineffective test case
generation due to the unsatisfiable
Patties
like another problem is that it may be
over constraint the path is because and
it resulted in no test cases for example
there is another sample that it gets
typed and each hack weather type is type
1 and after long execution it will check
tie because the type 2 if we if we first
go to the type equal type 1 and after
the long execution then if even though
we meet the time equal type 2 it will
not generate any test cases definitely
because it is unsatisfiable path because
the type cannot be tight cannot be type
1 and type 2 at the side at the same
time but if these branches are
independent then the dairy is there must
be the path that the type is not equal
to type 1 and the type equal to type 2
and in that case we will generate a type
2 but it requires another long execution
go back to first branch to resolve this
issue what we are trying to do is that
we want to solve constraint
optimistically more specifically we want
to solve some part of the constraints
instead of giving up at the
unsatisfiable patches so our decision is
that the we solve only the last
constraint in the path it is simple
because it is only one constraint at the
last branch and it is highly likely to
pass the branch because it meets the
condition for the last branch if we are
wrong we will waste only a small solving
time and also in hybrid fuzzy generating
incorrect inputs are fine because even
though we generate the in cracked inputs
it will feed back to the fuzzy and the
fudging will filter out is incorrect
inputs so we can generate the incorrect
inputs this optimistic solving really
helps to find the more bugs this is
result from the lava M data set which is
which in that some hard to find bugs in
real world software x-axis is time left
for testing we run the queue scene for
five hours and the y-axis is related to
the number of bugs found by the QC so
you can see the blue line which is the Q
seam with optimistic solving is dominate
it dominate the lead run which the
accuse him without optimistic solving so
optimistic so being really helps to find
more bugs implementation we implemented
the Q seam with the 16 K lines of code
we use the Intel pin as our emulation
and we use d3 for constraint dissolving
so you can like a Google open source our
prototype so we will it will be
available at this link so please check
this link so for the evaluation
questions we want to answer the our goal
is to scale to real word software to
some really scale to real word software
a second one is that we want to compare
our Q seem to other system like a
driller one of the state of our ty
briefing and viewer and the other
fuzzing and symbolic execution
techniques cucm scales to real-world
software we found that their team bugs
in real world software including lepton
open JPEG TCP dump file and the ffmpeg
and object them as you can see they are
already fast a lot and like there are
some some programs that are being fast
by the OSS fast which is the cloud of us
from Google even they are already first
kiss him help to help them to find the
bugs in this program one example that we
found bug in the ffmpeg it requires to
pass this very complicated branches in
our evaluation we run the fuzzy fuzzing
for 24
hours but it cannot reach this branch at
all and the we believe is really hard
for fuzzing because OSS fuzz fuzz this
program for two years but it cannot
reach this bug the Kusum can generate
the test cases that bypass this branch
and we found this bug using kissing and
we compared Kusum with driller we use
the data set of from the cgc 126
binaries and we run only one instance of
con college education for five minutes
because we do not want to run the
buzzing - because it will introduce the
randomness in our experiment after
running the con college education for
five hours or five minutes and then we
compare code coverage of the generated
test cases and QC m'c Eve the more code
coverage than the driller in most of
cases in CGC among 126 challenges kills
him achieved more in 104 challenges and
the driller achieved more in 18
challenges twosome achieved more code
coverage due to its better performance
for example there is a challenge called
a challenge named chrome you want to
achieve new code coverage it will
require seven stage it needs to add user
and it needs to add another user and the
login and send message and require seven
stages for that kissing can reach this
state and they can find the new code
coverage but driller cannot do in time
driller compared but driller can achieve
more code coverage if there is a nested
branch driller can find inputs that pass
the nested branch by a single execution
due to forking so if there are the
nested branch kill seem only flip one
brain
but driller can follow the branch and
can generate test cases to pass this
Ness to the branch to do that kisum
requires reaction but we want to note
that our experiment allows only one
instance of con colleague execution so
we believe that the cucm can reach this
state by doing the reacts kitchen and
the QC outperformed other techniques in
lava em dataset as I mentioned before
lava em dataset inject hard to find bugs
in real-world software we run five hours
and the QC found all the bugs in the
unique basis 64 and the md5sum
and it found 50 58% of bugs in whoo
which is significantly more than other
techniques fuzzing and symbolic
execution and vision in this slide I
want to discuss the other use of our
technique and the limitation so the QC
is based on the last accurate result
so it requires efficient validator in
our case fudging is efficient validator
maybe we could apply the same technique
on the exploit generation because we
have the we can make its efficient
validator to test whether the generator
exploit works or not currently we only
support x86 and x86 64 and we cannot
support a floating point yet conclusion
I want to conclude this talk
Kusum is a hybrid funding scale over to
real world software we found the 13 box
in real-world software and we outperform
a state of art hybrid fuzzing and the
other about finding technique so please
we will open source our prototype so
please check this link thank you
[Applause]
[Music]
we have time for a couple of quick
questions
run
hi sumon Jana Columbia University cool
works I just have one question for the
real-world programs that you tested did
you test for coverage as well because
you talked about bugs right you found 13
new bugs did you compare coverage with
other hybrid fuzzers on real-world
program so honest fitting like the Lego
the only hybrid fuzzer we know the
trailer and the trailer has some like a
very high dependency on the CDC program
so we are we we try to test a trailer
with other Iroquois like normal Linux
binaries but we fail so we own it
actually it generates some test cases
but they are too small to generate so we
think is it's not that meaningful to
compare those so that's why we compare
the driller with CCC binary okay buzzer
[Music]
buzzer buzzer we use this year oh yeah
so we just compare that like their
evaluation in the LA bohème data set so
we use programs not real-world programs
but it also runs on the real-world
programs right sorry it does run on
real-world programs yeah yeah I think
like it we we haven't tested the user
with the real-world program but I
definitely show you will work with thank
you thank you let's thank our speaker
again
[Music]
you