so as you probably all know that
transport layer security is the most
important to the cryptographic protocol
so in the recent years ago we saw in the
recent years many attacks on this
protocol like a crime beasts lucky 13
heartbleed early ccs and so on and so
what what is may be forgotten is the
attack black in Bathurst attack so this
attack was issued 20 years ago and it
was applied to RSA pkcs 1.5 encryption
scheme in a so TLS so it allowed an
attacker to decrypt a cell TLS traffic
and many implementations because it was
very serious many implementations and
also the TLS specifications applied
fixes and everybody would probably think
that now we are secure but of course it
is not a case because I would otherwise
not be here so I am presenting your
return of Breitenbach historico threat
and this is a very serious attack
because as you know probably it has a
logo and his attack name and so on
ok so today I'm going to talk about
blacking backers attack how it works
then how we started our research and how
we performed our attacks on Facebook how
we performed our TLS scans and how we
found new vulnerabilities in different
products and then I'm not going to talk
about about a responsible disclosure how
we could identify several vendors and so
on and so on so let's start with the
blackened RS attack so on a very very
high level TLS protocol is divided into
two phases in the first phase the TLS
handshake the two parties client and
server have to negotiate algorithms TLS
version extensions and so on and so on
and they perform a key change there are
three types of key changes so RSA key
exchange diffie-hellman key exchange on
different ephemeral key exchange and
afterwards after a it
the keys they can proceed with the
encrypted and authenticated data
transport so for this talk it is
important the airside ELC key so how
does it work
in on a very high level so imagine we
have a client who wants to communicate
with a dealer server
so first what he does is he sends a
client hello message this client hello
message he says something like hey I
want to communicate with you with this
TLS version cyber Suites extensions and
so on the server responds with a server
hello message with certificate
certificate contains the public key of
the server and server hallo domme
message afterwards the client sends so
the client has now the public key of the
server so it can encrypt something like
RSA premaster secret this premaster
secret is used to derive all the secrets
in the TLS protocol so this pretty much
the secret is encrypted with the public
key of the server and sent to the server
afterwards the client can send chained
self-respect and finish messages which
authenticate the client the server
accepts the client key exchange message
decrypt the premaster secret and then
can authenticate itself so it with the
finished message ok for the next part of
my talk the client keeps change message
is of crucial importance so this client
key change message contains and RSA
encrypted premaster secret and our say
this premaster secret is encrypted using
RSA pkcs1 version 1.5 so in general this
spreading scheme is used to pet and
encrypt the secrets so in order to pet
it to the specific RSA key length and so
to add some randomization to the message
so to give you an example how it is used
in TLS 1.2
so the first 2 bytes of or the encrypted
premaster secret contain 0 0 0 2 this is
this signalizes or this shows that it is
encryption block type then there is a
non 0 padding
scheme which is terminated with zero
zero delimiter and then there's TS 1.2
version which is indicated with version
by two zero three zero g and at the end
we have the premaster secret so this is
a fixed structure of air safety KC a 1.5
padding scheme and which was exploited
in the blacken boxer attack so in 1998
so 20 years ago Daniel blacken backer
showed an adaptive chosen ciphertext
attack and this ciphertext attack chosen
ciphertext attack exploits a strict
validation in RSA because he's 1.5
messages I will not go into the
cryptography details but show you a very
very high-level overview of the attack
so imagine we have a client who wants to
communicate with the server and sends a
ciphertext to the server and we have an
attacker who observes the communication
each drop the ciphertext and somehow
modifies it cryptographically and sends
the modified ciphertext to the server
and the client misuses or the the the
attacker misuses the server as an Oracle
so because the server what he does it
decrypts the message and for today's
world it starts with zero to zero zero
zero to you or not and depending on the
validity of this message of the
decorated message the server responds
somehow with wallet or in knowledge and
afterwards the the attacker learned
something some partial information about
the message and he proceeds with further
messages with the next ciphertext he
learns further bits with with the
response of the of the server and so on
and so on until he can decorate the
whole message so as already mentioned I
am not thinking the details there's some
much-needed behind the paper behind
behind the attack so if you want to talk
talk about the attack just approach me
during the coffee break so and what may
be you need to know or what is
interesting is that the the attack is
also called a million message attack and
but because the attacker needs to
perform or to issue about hundred about
million messages to the server but in
there
world the performance of this attacker
varies a lot so in some cases you can
issue just a few thousands of messages
in some cases you need to issue millions
of queries
it depends strongly depends on the
strictness of the Oracle I'm not going
to detail here so how can we create
blacking buckers or a color or in TLS
implementation so how does it apply so
imagine we have the attacker who wants
to decrypt the message and how can we
apply the modified ciphertext in the TLS
handshake
so here again since the client hello
message received certificate and several
messages and afterwards in the client
key change message which contains the
ciphertext he inserts the modified
ciphertext which contains the edit the
RCP kisses 1.5 reddit premaster secret
afterwards the server attempts to
decrypt the message and depending on the
ciphertext validity depending on know
whether the message starts with 0 0 0 2
or not and then it sends maybe decrypt
error or better occurred make alert or
something different and this way the
attacker is able to distinguish valid or
invalid messages so this handshake can
then be performed several times and the
attacker can decrypt the original
connection okay so what is the Contra
measure that was applied in the TLS
specification the Contra measure is
interior very simple so what the
attacker needs to do is so what the
server needs to do is to always respond
with the same alert message so the
attacker cannot distinguish valid from
invalid messages and if this is
implemented correctly if the attacker
can distinguish valid from invalid
messages using alerts or using other
side channels then the attacker has no
Oracle and he cannot perform a similar
circuit so in the next minute so you
just need to consider that if this black
markers attack and if the attacker can
distinguish valid from invalid cipher
texts well from involved messages then
he can apply black embarrass attack
okay yeah so how did the research start
or howhow do how did we start so about
one year ago Hannah approached me and
said that and he performed some initial
scans of several hosts and he found a
weird behavior of the Facebook server
and he pointed me out to that the server
instead of responding with general old
messages it responds with depending on
the client exchange message he had the
server responds with illegal parameter
alert or bad record making alert we are
analyzing it and we found out okay it's
a really problem and we asked ourselves
so is it exploitable so in order to and
so and we wanted to prove it somehow so
typically in black macaques attack you
decrypt some messages and decrypt some
handshake that was used but we had an
idea so it would be funny to sign a
message with Facebook's private P
because what many people do not know is
that in general black occurs data can be
used also for signing messages so it is
able the attack allows you to decrypt
messages or to sign messages so to
perform any private key operation if the
server is vulnerable to it so there are
millions of queries needed we ask our
selves would Facebook block us or is it
even feasible to do this and after
several attempts we were really
surprised that it works and we were able
to sign a message we had Facebook with
black and bacharach law and with our
initials and if you want to prove it and
now we have a script on our webpage
which consists of the signature and it
downloads the certificate from
certificate transparency and validates
that this message is really signed with
Facebook's private key okay so we
reported it of course to Facebook we got
some bug bounties which was nice and
then I talked about it with some guys or
with Craig and Craig had an idea okay
what can we do about it so we can verify
what our Facebook is
and his idea was maybe to play with the
Teela's handshake and what he did
he removed the chain self-respect and
client finish message and in case these
messages were sent and the Facebook
server always responded with general
alert messages but once this service
client messages were not there then the
server just responded with a TCP reset
in case the client kink message was
invalid or the mess the server responded
with a timeout so there's a server
waited for different messages for
further messages so this was the
Nightside tional
so using this strange behavior we can
again apply black human heart attack so
we reported it to Facebook receive bug
bounties and yeah so this was very
interesting and we asked ourselves so
okay so Facebook's doing this wrong so
how about other servers and we asked
ourselves oh okay we can perform some
scannings and we can scan for the
vulnerabilities and so we decided to
select careful client exchange messages
which which could somehow trigger of
blacking backers attack and blackened by
her attack behavior so what we did so we
modified the TLS version so we inserted
a invalid TLS version inside so instead
of zeros 3:03
inserted some invalid bytes there we
inserted wrong padding lengths so we
moved the padding the zero delimiter to
the right or to the left to trick the
server or we decided to send different
messages which are not starting with
zero two zero zero zero two and we of
course we also played with our new
handshake so we tested with full and
shortened handshakes messages which have
changed our first read messages and
finished messages or which omitted this
okay so we scanned only Alex our top 1
million servers because of power
reasons and we wanted to get the most
important service and we found out that
2.8 percent of servers were vulnerable
to this attack so this seems to be not
that much but most of the service was of
the high profile servers like paper at
eBay Cisco and so on they're vulnerable
to these attacks which was quite
surprising and from the sent expecting
it was also very surprising that we saw
different behaviors in different
combinations so it was not only one
server only one when they are
responsible for this but there are
different vendors and so we what we saw
was different combinations of TCP
connection resets or timeouts depending
on the TLS protocol flaw or tails
messages send with some different alert
messages in different combinations like
illegal parameter by the record neck
handshake fail or internal alright and
so on and so on
and what was also interesting from my
perspective was that we saw duplicate
alert messages so in some cases the the
implementations attempted to verify or
to implement the confirmation so they
sent only a general alert message like
bad record make always the same but in
case the message was valid or the client
king's judge most because he is one
wallet then it send only one allowed
message and in case it was invalid and
sent to alert messages ok this was kinda
nice so we we had many servers which
were affected and we were trying to do
some responsibilities closer and to the
to find out which vendors are affected
with responsible for these mistakes and
you know from different conferences that
there are papers which are handling
these responsibilities closure process
in case of for some research scripting
this is maybe easier because the
developers are familiar with cross-site
scripting and with these sort of talks
in hack Ravana and so on and so on but
in case of cryptographic bugs or TLS
implementation this is not always that
easy
so it's we constructed different
messages to the servers with the
description of the vulnerabilities we
attempted to approach them but we also
so we said something like your servers
if we were able to black embarrassed
attacked is the vulnerability bla bla
bla and what we sometimes got was like
no worries we use military-grade
encryption and we are safe okay so this
was but we there were also cases and
what we found out was responsible for
this so so for example but it was also
not a solution for us for example in the
case of Cisco ACI devices which support
only tears sa so as a developer or the
set where administrator you could also
switch to the fishermen and to disable
or kills RSA cipher suite in case of
Cisco this is not possible because they
only support us RSA and this Cisco
device was not was vulnerable and they
responded to us okay we won't fix it
because it's out of support for several
years but we were very considerate about
this because there are many websites
vulnerable to this to this attack and
for something was like Cisco calm
okay I do not know what is the current
status of this maybe they moved the
website to a different product like but
in the end we were able what may so
mainly with the help of Hinault and
craig who have good connections to the
developers and to different people
behind the servers they we were able to
somehow find out who is behind the
different implementations and we found
many many different applications which
were vulnerable in different ways it was
interesting for example this is the list
of our attacks which is also on our
website with the CVS and what was for
example interesting is that f5 products
there were 5 servers having five
different vulnerabilities five different
responses so I don't know how do they
implement their stakes or what do they
do with them but five different sorts of
vulnerabilities in there the elastics
okay so we notified them they fix this
and so what we did also in addition to
our work to the responsibility closures
we are not able to track every vendor so
what we also did as a part of our
responsible disclosure we informed also
developers of different tests tools like
selects the cells SH old keyless buzzer
and the problem was maybe that these
simple TLS scan applications did not
have scans for electing water attacks
and we provided them with our skin
scripts and for example now since I mean
December s elapsed contains blocking
buffer
Oracle vulnerable this kind of on their
website
okay so this music to a conclusion about
future work and in general so in
conclusion or photo I propose in the
future work so a few years ago we
presented timing attacks on open open
source implementations there will be
black in the her sessions here at use
next maybe it would be nice to
take a look at closer implementations
from f5 or other devices it would be you
would definitely find something as we
could see that using these
vulnerabilities you can do something a
printing and what we also saw in some
cases is that some after sending ronk
client key change messages the service
of are responding with some poder bitch
bite so maybe you can perform something
like blading buffer so hard that slight
memory disclosure okay so in conclusion
we were able to apply that one twenty
year or attack back in Paris attack and
we showed that it works with different
new side channels like timeout TCP
resets and so on and so on and we prove
that Scripture contra measures are hard
to apply even if they are in the Tila
specification and even if they're
explicitly mentioned in okay so our my
recommendations are that you disable
tails errors a cipher suites which are
not there until as 103 because of these
reasons and you should in general or
disable our say because it's 1.5 and
switch to LT curves or to air say LP if
our size needed okay thank you very much
[Applause]
few minutes for questions so I can start
with a quick question so as you
mentioned that you when you contact the
effective vendors they have different
responses do you have any thoughts of
what fundamentally that make them not a
motivated or sometimes difficult to fix
the problem you mean now why wasn't it
fixed a few years ago before or I mean
the major problem was that the tools
that are provided to us developers like
tests LS h or s collapse which is now
commonly used to does not contain black
and baja attacks can so this was well
known for for example open source
developers like open SSL and other
developers do not include these fixes
but maybe in a large scale it is
necessary that we provide to the
developers like useful tools which allow
them to test with positive or negative
tests so that they can test their
implementation and just a question about
the remediation rates did you can do you
do continuous can still to figure out if
notifying the vendors was enough because
as you pointed out it might be helpful
to tell the administrators if they
understand what you're saying yeah so
this is we are not doing that so we have
a recent scans that we performed we're
probably in November or December last
year and afterwards we said okay we are
done we release our attack paper and
everybody was vulnerable or so can use
the newly developed tools or our
syllabus so now it is much much easier
to find out where they are vulnerable so
what was interesting is that after our
disclosure there were new
implementations popping out so even like
to eat two weeks ago we found out that
there was a new implementations which
was found to be vulnerable to some
attacks and it was only because probably
one of the test tools found it but maybe
it would be interesting to if there is
now kind of update
versions of the software running on like
these these HTTP endpoints piant sn2 now
tell people like your vendor that you
bought the hardware from said that this
is a problems in each update so maybe
there's still room for improving things
with notifications yeah maybe maybe
there was B so what will be nice is to
do something like fingerprinting so in
general fingerprinting of different
server implementations so instead of
contacting the website administrator you
can directly go to the vendor and to
tell them ok you are vulnerable and you
should fix it maybe this would speed up
the process very much in comparison to
go over the website administrator which
was quite so my question is about what
you are able to get signed using
Facebook's private key question is that
what are the implications of that
because it doesn't seem like you could
sign like an added service certificate
but I maybe I'm missing something
ok it was just normal leaf certificate
so just ok so the black Americas is only
able to perform RSA private key
operation so you are not able to extract
a private key you are able to sign some
messages but of course this was a lie
leaf certificate so if you are not able
to to sign for it certificates or
something with it so it was not
exploitable Thanks