hello everyone I'm hung out from
Princeton University and we're glad to
be here to present our work on enabling
real-time abnormal system different
direction to enhance it to enhance
enterprise security this work was done
in collaboration with Professor Susan
Shaw from Case Western Reserve
University and colleagues from
insalubrious America my advisers are
professor Sanjeev Kulkarni and professor
practicum Ito today we got more and more
breaking news about cyber attacks for
example the Equifax data breach
happening in last a year has disclosed
the sensitive information of Iran's 143
million u.s. customers besides more and
more large companies that have well
protected businesses suffer from great
financial losses due to this attacks
this advanced the persistent stress
attacks namely a PT's language
sophisticated techniques to exploit
multiple vulnerabilities in the system
besides due to strong economical or
political motives adversary's are
continuously monitoring the target and
trying to steal valuable data here is a
typical setup for the AVG attack the
goal of the attack is to steal the data
stored in the database server in order
to achieve this goal the attack first
conduct an initial compromised by
sending a crafting email to the victim
the email has a attachment which has a
malicious Peck micro embedded the victim
the opens the email
clicks the attachment and Reza macro
which downloads and excuse a malware to
create a backdoor to the attacker with
the backdoor
the attacker penetrates into the
internal host and runs the database
Kraken choose to obtain database
credentials with the credentials that
hacker then penetrates into the database
server and drops another malware to
create another backdoor finally the
hacker runs the database Duncan choose
to dump the database content and send
the data back to his hosts
through the backdoor created in the
previous step this completes the
her apt sequence as we can see these apt
attacks are very sophisticated
they involve multiple steps exploiting
different types of vulnerabilities in
the system which activates different
abnormal system behaviors for example in
the steps III the process the program T
SEC Tom DeLay XE was started by command
on exe may be known to some security
analysts besides there exist abnormally
large transfers on the database server
and there exists some abnormal process
creations on the on the client for
example here this excel dot exe star
traveled exe which obviously is very
suspicious because it shall never Stasi
Allah since this suspicious or abnormal
behaviour could happen on any host in
their enterprise ranging from employ
stations to the servers we need
solutions that can record all the
underlying behaviour of the system this
leads to the idea of ubiquitous system
monitoring system monitoring collects
the information about system calls from
dirt from kernels the audit logs
produced has a unified structure which
is not bound to specific applications
this logs records how I recall the
information about how applications
interact with system resources such as
sales processes and the network
connections in the form of system events
recognising the need for a family
anomaly detection and the complexity for
the apts hack we propose to leverage
stream processing and continuous queries
to enable the real-time abnormal system
behavior detection building search
system requires us to solve two major
challenges first the system has to
provide a expressive and conscious
interface to express a broad set of
abnormal behaviors these behaviors
involving clewd the rule-based the
behaviors
so as the advanced anomaly behaviour
besides system monitoring produces huge
amount of daily logs for example in the
typical lab environments consisting of
100 hosts the amount of logs produced
would be around 50 gigabytes with the
throughput around 250 for 2005 handle
events per second besides the stream the
streaming scenario may introduce
multiple concurrent chorus in execution
which may incur considerable or had
therefore building a system that enables
real-time analytics over this
large-scale stream data is quite
challenging in the audit log and
forensics today's existing works
primarily work on reducing the size of
the data and improving the precision of
the causality analysis but there exists
their legs unified tool or platform to
query the data efficiently recognizing
such immunization in this work we build
a normal stream query system for
abnormal system behavior detection our
system was built on top of existing
tools and our system provides a
domain-specific query language namely a
sequel or stream anomaly stream based
anomaly query language that can enable
users to specify a broad set of attack
behaviors using the specialized
constructs for security besides we build
our query execution engine to enable the
fast execution of the stream queries we
deploy data monitoring our data
collection agents on every hosta in the
enterprise our agents collect critical
attributes from system and test and
system activities our language supposed
roughly four types of unknown e anomaly
models this rule based on only specify
the behavior rules of system activities
for example in this single event query
we first define the event pattern that
this process restore file and the file
name could
either of these history fails and then
in the return calls we return these are
the attributes from the matched events
besides this is the Rubies the motive
and curry which we defend multiple burn
patterns the global constraints enforces
the constraints which all of the event
patterns food satisfy and then we defend
the event patterns successively in the
form of subtract operation object with
certain attributes to constrain the
search and then in this whisk house we
define the temporal relationships among
this edge among these events basically
the event one should her happen first
then eventually the events leading event
for and we also support the attribute
relationship specification other
explicitly or implicitly in this example
notice that we used the same symbol F 1
for both of the two events that
implicitly means that the entities
referred by this F 1 are the same and
also we support a lot of syntax
shortcuts so for example the context
aware attribute inference to make the
curry more concepts and friendly to use
besides the simple rule based the
anomalous time-series anomalies are
useful to detect the things such as
Network specs in the time series among
anomalies we provide we proposed the
idea of sliding windows in which we
partition the stream into different
slides and we know normally proposed the
idea of stateful computation over the
sliding windows a state is simply the
set of aggregation values and notice
that for different windows the state may
change and then we mentioned the poster
current state namely the current values
in the current window as well as the
previous state or the history States
using these states we can compose or
complex time series anomaly models in
this
for example here this is a simple moving
average model for the network
speculation on the cycle server we
further extend the stateful computation
syntax to support the invariant based on
omelets the idea is that we want to
enable the specification of the
violations for the system immigrants
notice that here we have an invariant
block after the state block in which we
defended an environment here is a set of
child process of the Apache process
between the variants for ten windows and
the wage hike for the further windows if
there exists a process that does not
that is not included in the event namely
the Urich in the environment namely the
invariant violation using this query we
can check if a party starts some
unexpected child process for example
batch there is namely this is namely the
batch bash shell shell command injection
attack which we included in the case
study
besides the comparison to the history
states using the ham series models we
also support the comparison to peer
states using the outlier based on ami
models we have the cluster definition we
define the points that makes this
cluster and we define the distance
measured we defend the classroom method
and then we can use the classroom
results edits in the alert class and
specify that we only want to return the
outlier outlier events namely this is
still the sinkhole this is still the
direction of the abnormally large data
transfer on the single server but here
we compare with peer values now the
history values the execution of a cycle
consists of four stages in the first
stage we match the stream against the
dimaggio and peasants defined with
certain attribute constraints then if
there exists a stateful computation
block then we compute and maintain the
states over sliding windows
next we compute the large boolean
expression for the alert condition and
check if the events pass or fail this
expression finally we return the desired
attributes from the match the events and
enforced further filters if necessary
previously we mentioned that a challenge
for the streaming scenario is to
efficiently handle the concurrent query
execution
our idea is that we can share the
intermediate execution results among
Chris so that we can avoid some
unnecessary danger caucus we propose the
master dependent chris game in which we
partition the concurrent chorus into
master dependent groups based on their
similarities of semantics and only the
master Cree has direct access to the
stream the execution of the dependent
queries depends on the execution of the
master Cree and it will fetch the
intermediate execution results from the
master a pure master master curry
exclusion pattern to its own pepin right
now we have done this tearing up to the
two stages from the event mention stage
to the stateful computation stage and we
will leave the sharing for further
stages in the future work in this simple
example we have to depend on queries
which we defend the state's blog but
have different state aggregations so the
query one has the state for the
aggregation for the count and the
creature has the stamp and in the
massacre a way compute the poster
Kannada sum therefore we can leverage
the intermediate execution results of
the master curry to execute the
dependent Chris
so we conduct a case study of a series
of major attack major types of attacks
we deploy our system in many
laboratories America consisting of
around 150 host which and use the data
up to 1.1 terabytes of data around 3.3
billion events with events reporter on
three thousand seven hundred and fifty
events per say
in total we constructed seven queries
and the way for four types of attack
behaviors we have done the AP attack and
then we have done the sequel injection
attack within the within the best
shellshock command injection attack as
well as several suspicious system
behaviors such as the USB USB usage the
command history probing or the password
file accesses this is the execution
statistics for the photo queries and we
married basically it was all of the
latest courts include poster rule based
queries as far as the advanced anomaly
Chris and we measure several statistics
the general highlight will kick take
away from this chart is that all of
these queries can finish within two
seconds which means that the system
latency is relatively small besides we
did some pressure test and we want to
understand so we want to understand how
many enterprise hosts can our deploy the
service of hot basically we deploy our
it's just a normal server with around
128 gigabytes of memory and tribe horse
so we continuously increase the data
input to the server and so that the CPU
usage will increase when we reach the
maximum CPU usage the system's report
turns out to be 110,000 events per
second after some simple mathematics
operations we can estimate that they
deploy the server can support around
4,000 house for more house we can either
skill skill up by using some high higher
performance servers or we can make our
system distributed notice that this
dream career cycle is very very natural
to the distributed in implementation and
we will limit for future work besides we
have the comprehensive evaluation of the
performance of our
concurrent career execution namely we
want to understand the efficiencies
efficiency speed up that our master
dependent Curie scheme can provide so we
we have proposed several attacking every
waste and several evaluation categories
namely we evaluate the sensing file
accesses we evaluate the browser access
files the processes access networks and
process is born for the evaluations in
our detailed algorithm design we have
different evaluation dimensions for
example we we can optimize on the
attribute definition we can optimize on
the sliding window we can optimize on
the agent ID we can optimize on the type
of state views if I interested feel free
to look at our paper basically we have
four attack territories and we have full
evaluation categories and the we can
host for queries for each drawing
category based certain variations so in
total we have four times four times four
equals 64 micro benchmark rates to
evaluate our efficiency here is a simple
example micro benchmark query for the
drones category sensitive file accesses
and state aggregation and the below is
the execution results for this query
namely we measure the memory usage on
our server with the number of increasing
number of concurrent chris basically we
use this figure as a default and we
reduce the state field definition as the
second Cree and we continuously
successively add more courage to our
evaluation as you can see when we have
more concurrent Chris our system has a
better memory ceiling than the popular
complex event processing engine CD in
total for all of the 64 queries we can
achieve around three thirty percent
average memory city besides not all of
the Chris are supported by CD but we can
support it especially for the advanced
anomalies such as the Panzers anomalies
environment based on normally
and automobiles anomalies so once the
alerts are deducted the next step to
counter apt attack is to investigate
this alert yeah and but however the
challenge for the investigation is that
usually is that this psycho system on
the whole system only works on the
streaming data but the investigation
requires us to dive deep into the
massive historical data
recognizing such need we have proposed
another work that is published in this
year's
usenix ATC in which we build another
query system that works on the
historical data basically and the our
system also provides a compatible query
language that is very compatible with
this psycho query language and we
leverage the domain specifics to speed
up the search of complex event patterns
over the historical data and compare it
with popular databases such as squares
ago and neo4j
and we can achieve around 100 percents
when 100 hands speed-up so if you are
you interested feel free to take a look
at this paper in total together this two
system can work seamlessly for defending
against the apts namely the psycho curry
the psycho system launched a series of
stream queries and continuously
monitored the data stream once the
dollars are detected this alerts will be
fed into the a accurate system we can
use the accurate system to investigate
such errors which may help us to
discover the new attack patterns this
new apply patterns can then be fed into
the psycho engine to create more Chris
this is the feedback loop so in
conclusion in this work we have built
and we have designed and built a system
called psycho stream based on Omikron
language system our system works on the
streaming data of system on chain data
which enables the timely anomaly
detection
our system provides a concise and
expressive language for four types of
anomaly models and we have built our
query execution
based on the Ottoman specifics of the
data and the Chris to speed up the
execution we have deployed our system on
the in the NEC labs America and we'll
see how it goes
thank you all right now we're now open
up for questions here we go
hi Toni Onley from Persian I stopped I
just wanted to know how this kind of
like stream based processing security
analysis framework is different from
more general as a complex event-driven
processing system whether the difference
is mainly you know I say the languages
and the quarry level or whether there is
any architectural or like engine level
differences okay thanks for the question
so basically we build our system on top
of existing complex event processing
engine CD and the difference merely
let's see in two aspects first of the
language part the CD CD Angie has
provided a language it is the second
language it is rather low level so if
you want to use it to express the
complex complex events with certain
attributes then the say the query will
be very large
that is the consciousness part besides
we can support more types of anomaly
Chris but city cannot support because we
have explicitly provides the stateful
computation block as far as the extended
emergent block and the second difference
is the execution part basically since
City is a general complex event
processing engine it does not assume any
and Lion cartridges of the stream data
therefore which we mean that it does not
rely on the they have persuasive stomach
hurts physics right therefore it has
multiple concurrent course in execution
it will simply make thinner copies for
each correct
even though there would there maybe have
some quizzes that are exactly the same
or be very similar but they make data
copies this will introduce the large
overhead for the memory and we already
show it in our evaluation but since we
are domain-specific language we know our
data we know our quick the we can
leverage the characteristics of our data
and our okra to speed up the execution
thank you my name is Chris I'm from
Google
my question is mostly about the
accumulation of state so
but the rules be stateful and it
accumulate things over time do you see
state kind of explosions as different
kinds of rules are created you could
imagine some kind of limitations from
the dsl and I didn't haven't read the
paper yet so if the paper has some kind
of enforcement on the kind of
capabilities of state accumulation to
avoid explosions over time yeah thanks
for the question yeah this is a very
cool question yeah actually is so
because I mean the the queries in the
control of the users right and the data
we all know that the data is very huge
so if the users does not enforce any
constraints for the create then it will
be your explosion so in our current
implementation we do have some
constraints so we have some rough
estimations if the if the estimated data
is very huge then we will have a warning
for the user but in general for example
for all of the evaluations here we first
have to define the multiband patent
rights with certain attributes usually
you should have some attributes you do
not want to search all of the things
unless you have the attributes than the
attributes will fill to a significant
amount of other unrelated events and for
the stateful computation because we do
not maintain all of the states we can we
we have to explicitly define how many
states that we want want mention for
example we can maintain the current
state the previous state the previous
previous states and then once we follow
along the stream then the data will be
in started will not be used therefore we
can we have we can use this way to
mitigate the problem of explosion hi
there
so you a comprehensive experiment on
neck but you didn't really comment on
the accuracy of the results so I
understand that ultimately it boils down
to the quality of the rules but do you
have any data on false positives and
eventually false negatives on the
experimental front yes so basically for
all of the all of the attacks that we
evaluated our Crakehall
captured them but the problem is that
usually in the in the real world site
and you do not if you want to capture a
certain type of attacks you cannot
simply write one for it
because you're one creamy may easily
miss this attack usually you read
multiple queries and let them
concurrently run it so at least that you
will hope that run query will capture
the alerts but in our your evaluations
all of the queries can capture owners
therefore there will be no false
negatives but depending on the depending
on the constraints that was specified
there may be exists the false pulses
this and also based on this observation
we propose that we shoot to further
investigation of the detection errors
because you can never rely directly
under alerts and the truth may be
Sonny's we are productive you should do
some further investigation to confirm
that your honor to search for positive
okay thank you