I'm bur Kosilek my talk today will be
about sensitive information tracking in
commodity IOT this work is in
collaboration between Penn State and
Florida State Florida International
University so the color of the paper
learn or the bogan is also here if you
would like to chat after the
presentation so in the past decade a lot
has changed we have seen the rise of
smartphones self-driving cars on the
array connectivity of devices is more
extensive than ever before as you're
probably aware this has all come to be
known as Internet of Things the
commodity vices that integrate physical
processes with digital connectivity has
had a profound impact in our daily lives
we have recently seen many applications
of IOT such as in smart home healthcare
energy and even farming IOT is not magic
just like in other computing system IOT
is a structured architecture so in this
architecture devices have capabilities
that are composed of events and actions
events are the things that device can
sense and action represents what a
device can do devices are connected and
each device which controls the
communication between devices cloud
back-end and mobile application so
mobile applications are used to
configure and add new devices and as
well as install new eirick applications
our technicans are simply programs that
are used to create custom automations
though Erika architecture has many
interesting components the focus of our
work is privacy issues through IOT
applications so why I all t have been
embarrassed by users and Industry alike
IOT has also raised concerns about the
privacy of these digitally augmented
spaces you probably have seen similar
headlines that the academic literature
are in that industry he recently
uncovered these networked devices have
access to the data that can be intensely
private for instance when you leave home
when you sleep or whether your door is
locked or unlocked however in this
environment
users like visibility into who sees
their private data and they are often to
blindly trusting the developers to
address this problem we conduct a study
of three major IOT platforms smart inks
apple homekit and open app we aim at
understanding the program structures of
these platforms as well as to identify
how they use privacy sensitive data in
our study we have identified four types
of IOT specific sensitive data than it
that applications can access these are
the device states device information
user inputs and location so after we
have identified the sensitive data in
our tapes now our goal is to analyze
application source code to determine
when privacy sensitive data leaves the
application so the core methodology for
this we use is the static taint analysis
at the source code level in static
analysis sensitive information is first
identified at a change source where at a
label indicating the information type is
assigned thereafter taint propagation
tracks how label data impacts other data
in a way that it might lead to original
sensitive data
finally the impacted data is identified
at attained sink before it leaves the
system so in our application the 10
things are usually internet or messaging
services so taint analysis either
statically or dynamically has been
applied to many different settings such
as mobile apps the previous presentation
actually give a good overview
however from our study of three IOT
platforms we found that IT platform
possesses a few unique characteristics
and challenges in terms of tracking
information flow in IOT applications
when compared to the IR platforms first
I
programming platforms are diverse and
each uses its own programming language
however in the case of Android it has a
well-defined intermediate representation
and analysis can directly analyze the IR
code for instance using the suit suit
framework second in IOT identifying
sensitive sources is quite subtle
because there are many devices and each
has different set of internal States
which are sensitive lastly each IOT
programming platform has its own
idiosyncrasies that pose challenges to
taint tracking to address these
challenges we implement st. a static
analysis tool for identifying the
sensitive data flows in IOT applications
st. includes for logical steps doing the
actual analysis first we identify IOT
specific sources and sinks based on our
survey and then we implemented a st.
analyzer which extracts an intermediate
to presentation from the source code of
an application the IR is used to
construct EPS entry points event
handlers and call graphs which allows us
perform dataflow analysis on it lastly
we have implemented an online console
that you can access actually that allows
users to analyze direct applications so
given an application source code the
console reports full data flows between
the change sources and tensing's detail
labels of the sensitive data and also
provides some information about ten-six
so based on our study we found that IET
platforms generally structure their
applications similarly regardless of
their purpose or complexity
therefore the first step of the st. is
translating the source code of an i/o
tab into an intermediate representation
by exploiting this structure to
illustrate you see the functionally of
functionality of an app on your right
and the iron of tap on your left the app
turns on the lights and unlocks the door
and sends a short message to the secular
to service when the users arrive home
essentially the IR includes three code
blocks first devices specifies the
device types and inputs required for the
app functionality events include the
event and the corresponding event
handler that is invoked when this event
happens and competition
represents the relationship between
entry points and other functions
basically this is where we obtain the
call graph of the application so the IR
has several benefits
first it allows us precise the model of
the application life cycle second it
allows us perform much more simple and
effective - in tracking for example by
associating the permissions with the 10
tags or by knowing which functions are
the entry points so after we have
obtained the IR from the entire
interprocedural control flow graph of an
app Saint perform stain tracking
backward from ten things to construct
possible data leak paths from sources to
things so the reason we use backward
time tracking is to reduce the
processing overhead by starting from a
few things compared to a large number of
sensitive sources so we confirm this
basically checking the ratio between the
sinks over 10 sources in our analyzed
applications to illustrate I'm using a
sample code from an array tab so in this
application there is a thing called at
place one so the work this is
initialized to be 2380 here I'm using
the line numbers instead of the node
information to label the identifiers
then because of the function call it to
time cell is added to the
and the dependence relation between time
cilenti is also recorded into the
workpiece - with the similar computation
with the similar computation at the end
of the backward cane tracking
st. finds a possible data leak path
where T value corresponds to the device
state obtained from the temperature
thermostats current value as well as
user inputs threshold and this
information is sent to the adversary's
phone number which violates the user
price clearly
so since backward full of tracking is
both pet and context-sensitive for pet
sensitivity st. collects a relation
results of the predicates at conditional
branches and then it checks whether the
conjunction of these predicates always
false if so the pet is inclusive
infeasible so it's discarded lastly so
for context sensitivity st. Rove the way
the pets that do not match the function
calls and returns using that one called
side sensitivity and then nasty we also
considered implicit flaws so st. checks
the condition of a conditional branch it
determines whether it depends on a taint
value if so it taints all the elements
in the conditional branches so another
challenge for IOT programs as I said
because they are using its own
programming languages they have
idiosyncrasies that required some
special treatment so in our target IOT
platform which is smart things it uses
guerrilla language which is a dynamic
object oriented language we have found
three this kind of idiosyncrasies that
impacts the analysis precision so I will
talk about one of them here which is
called state variables state variables
are stored in the external storage to
purchase data across application
executions for instance an application
can store switch counter in a state
object in order to track the number of
times the switch is turned on or turned
off so in this same applies field
sensitive analysis to track the data
dependencies in the state objects okay
so by means of evaluating
st. we perform the market study in which
we use two hundred thirty smarting
applications so so our card corpus
includes 168 efficient and 62 third
party applications we obtain the
official applications from the github
smarting github repository and third
party applications from the smartthings
community form so our study shows that
approximately two-thirds of the
applications access variety of sensitive
information in IOT applications and st.
correct with flags
92 official and 46 third party
application exposing at least one pieces
of sensitive information through the
internet or SMS services to characterize
the use of sensitive data in our tapes
this figure shows the ten source
analysis of st. essentially it is rates
the type of potentially leaking privacy
sensitive data that leaves the i/o tapes
either internet or SMS so for instance
we found that approximately 60% official
and third-party applications potential
leak device state information
so st. also reports information about
the recipient and content when sensitive
data is transmitted over a sinkhole so
for instance a recipient it sent SMS is
the phone number and the content is the
message stream so this information
basically did the same provides here who
defines the recipient and who defines
the content we taught that this
knowledge enables a refined
understanding of a data flow which shows
who sees your privacy sensitive data to
illustrate for internet tensing's
we observe that 90% of the time the
recipients and contents are defined by
the developers or external servers so
oral in summary we introduced st. a
static analysis tool that identifies
sensitive data of loss in IOT
applications and then we have evaluated
st. on 230 applications and found that
60% of the analyzed apps include
sensitive data flows so here the
information provided by st. can be used
by the users to evaluate privacy risks
in IOT apps and make informed decisions
before installing these applications for
the developers st. can be used to check
for unintentional privacy violations and
then for the platform developers st. can
be used for rating up of the
applications before they are distributed
also you can find the same console
available at st. project at appspot.com
lastly I would like to introduce you I
will avenge which is a micro benchmark
test used to assess the effectiveness of
the tools design for IOT applications so
ing currently includes applications that
have data leaks flawed applications that
have some security and safety violations
as well as there are some malicious
applications
grated from mobile phone security so
each app in IOT bench comes with a grant
route which allows you to emulate the
effectiveness of your tools by using
these grant routes so it's under
continuous development so always
welcoming the contributions thank you do
we have any questions so I have a
question
in in your examples you talked about the
exposure of sensitive information but is
it my understanding that you're not
attributing this to any sort of
malicious behavior you're just saying
hey there's the potential here for some
sensitive piece of information to be
exposed to someone is that yeah that's a
really good question so st. only
identifies potentially data leaks it
doesn't determine whether it's malicious
or not
so because it's context dependent
dependent and then as the previous the
author presented so he needs we need to
use some semantics maybe in the future
work some other researchers may consider
this a second question I had was when
you talked about the applications
sending information out over the
Internet
are they using TLS by default or is it
up to the developer so it depends on the
IOT programming platform like what kind
of interfaces they provide as far as I
remember in smart things that are just
using HTTP okay all right we have no
other questions it's good to thank the
speaker one more time