good morning uh thank you all for being
here thank you to you on for the
introduction I'm excited to talk about
some recent work we've done called skill
squatting attacks on Amazon Alexa or in
other words I talk about Internet of
Things security and machine learning so
if you want to leave feel free to this
work is done with a group of great
collaborators from the University of
Illinois but let's get into it
Internet of Things devices are here
hooray a great example of IOT in the
real world
smart speakers Amazon echoes Google
homes and these speakers have kind of
dominated this space some studies report
that by the end of 2018 50 million
American adults will have a smart
speaker in their homes that's great but
these devices are interesting because
they kind of forego traditional
computing inputs like keyboards or mice
or touch instead they use the human
voice as their primary input mechanism
unfortunately speech recognition systems
that underlie these devices frequently
make errors and get things wrong even
when you're using them normally I'm sure
we've all experienced this I'm seeing
some head nods but let me share a
personal story so last week I'm sitting
in my living room the lights are going
you know the sun's going down lights are
dark so I'm like okay I have an echo and
I have smart lights so that's great so
I'll just say Alexa turn on the living
room lights you know fairly in a simple
task does she turn on the living room
lights no she says you know with the
confidence that really only a computer
can have she's okay
playing living on a prayer lullaby
edition you know it's not quite what I
asked for but I will say it is
surprisingly true to the original but
you know Amazon is not content with
having your smart speaker or your echo
turn your lights on and off in your home
Amazon wants to use Alexa to take over
the world and in order to do that
they've built a platform that enables
third-party developers to interface with
Alexa directly these are called skills
so at the time that we wrote the paper
there were about 25,000 skills on the
Alexa skills store and this number was
growing rapidly day by day you know
there's a skill for everything you know
there's a skill you want you want some
facts about cats there's a skill for
that do you want you know you want to
call a lyft to go to the airport there's
a skill for that too you know you may
need to make like a highly sensitive
time-sensitive bank transfer and you
only want to use your voice yeah there's
a skill for that too that's great so the
way to think about skills is
they're their apps but for Alexa but
they are different in one very important
way so unlike a mobile application when
a user goes has to go to an app store
download the application and you know
click on some stuff in order for them to
use it all Alexis skills are enable or
enable a bull by default so basically
you can just say something to your echo
and Alexa if it determines that you want
to talk to a skill is going to try to
make a determination about what skill
you wanted to talk to you based solely
on your input so let me give you an
example let's say I'm in the mood for
some cat facts so I say Alexa tell me
some cat facts so Alexa says oh that
sounds like a skill let me figure out
what skill to send this particular
request to let's say in the universe of
all skills there are three that kind of
sound like cat facts there's cat Forks
which is not right there's cat fast
which is also not right and then there's
got backs the skill that I wanted and
the skill that Alexa chooses so what she
does is she route to my request over to
that particular skill so let's a
solicits a response and then says
something to me like did you know a
group of cats is called a clowder it's a
very interesting fact about cats so we
now have two fundamental pieces of
intuition you know the first is that
Alexa makes mistakes because speech
recognition technology is is you know
not yet totally mature and two skills
are the new apps and based on what you
say to your echo device Alexa's going to
try to make a determination about what
app you want it to talk to to look at
this skill fish geek the simple skill
there does a very simple thing you can
just ask it stuff about fish
okay look at this skill fish cheek
everyone in the room I know I've read
the audience they're all security people
so everyone everyone went to the same
place said phishing attack makes sense
well kind of have you heard of these
guys they're an American rock band from
the 1980s called fish and it turns out
the skill that I just showed you was a
skill that was intended to provide
information about fish the bam not you
know like fish the fish so you know but
the question here is okay if I were to
say Alexa tell me a fish fact
and both of these skills were trigger
bow how it alexa know which one I wanted
well it turns out you know she actually
kind of doesn't Rachel a disappointed
Amazon customer
left a one-star review of the app fish
geek her complaint it gave her fish
backs not fish facts and this kind of
foundation you know underlies the core
research question in this work which is
Ken Alexa errors be leveraged to cause
harm to end users and to that end we
introduced this new attack called a
skill swatting attack the core idea is
it's fairly straightforward if an
attacker knows a priori what predictable
errors or what errors Alexa is going to
make when routing somebody to a
particular skill then all an attacker
has to do is build a skill that sounds
like an intended skill so when a user
triggers their intended skill there
instead routed to the attacker
controlled skill so let me walk through
a very concrete example so in the same
scenario as before I want some cat facts
really need my cat facts fixed so I say
Alexa tell me some cat facts and now the
only difference from the prior example
is that the attacker knows that facts F
a CTS sounds a lot like the word facts
FA X and the attacker also knows that
Alexa prefers the word facts like the
fax machine to the word facts like facts
about something so when I make this
request Alexa doesn't choose the skill
that I wanted that I wanted Alexa is
going to choose cat facts instead and
then everything happens as before you
know my response gets sent over to the
skill she gets response and then she
tell us say something stupid like a
group of cats is called a murder so you
know kind of intrinsic in this example
is okay well how can you tell which
errors are predictable so how do you
know or how is an attacker going to know
well we are primarily a measurement
group and so what we did is we sent a
bunch of speech samples to Alexa and we
figured out where she goes wrong so in
order to kind of investigate this a
little bit deeper and investigate these
predictable errors we leverage this data
set called the NSP data sets the NSP
data set is linguistics data set that's
curated by a group of linguists at you
know the Ohio State University and it
was built to study different English
dialects across the United States so the
NSP data set contains lots of different
kinds of speech samples but the ones
that we focused on in particular for
this study were single word speech
samples so there are 188 words and the
data set each spoken by 60 different
speakers which makes for a total of
eleven thousand four hundred and sixty
audio samples and I want to know if the
speakers were also just
geographically there was selected
especially because they demonstrated
representative linguistic features of
different dialect regions so in the
United States these are the West North
Midland South mid-atlantic and New
England regions
so each okie took all these fish samples
and we sent each PSF a speech sample to
Alexa 50 times providing us with a total
of five hundred and seventy three
thousand transcriptions across the sixty
speakers what do we find
well of the 188 words twenty four of
them we denoted as had a predictable
error so these are words let me explain
that kind of fit to criteria first is
that when they're spoken or when they're
transcribed by Alexa they're often
interpreted incorrectly and to when
they're interpreted incorrectly they are
interpreted consistently in the same way
incorrectly so for example the words
sail like a sailboat is interpreted as a
sail like you know we're having a fire
sale in the paper we delve into these a
little more and provide some
explanations but you know I want to note
that it's not just homophones right even
a human would have a hard time
distinguishing between sale and sale
because they sound exactly the same
but what's more interesting is that
there are some categories of words that
you fundamentally sound different they
have underlying phonetic structure that
is different rip and rap wet and what
luck and lock and in the paper you know
we talked a little bit more about these
and kind of provides some explanations
but for the scope of this talk it's
enough to know okay Alexa makes some
mistakes some predictable mistakes
the next question can we actually use
these predictable errors to route users
to unintended schools skills in in other
words this is we want to know if these
predictable errors actually manifest
themselves when Alexa makes a decision
about which skill to route a user to so
what we did is we split our speakers in
half into two sets a quote unquote two
training set and a quote unquote testing
set and what we did is we identified all
of the predictable errors that were from
the training set and given those
predictable errors we then built two
skills one which was the name of the
word the intended word and one which was
the predictable error so in this example
say skill a would be wet and skill B
would be what we then sent the testing
set through
alexxa as a skilled command and observed
how many times skill B was triggered
instead of skill a I want to mention you
know a brief kind of like ethical note
we validated this attack strictly in a
developer environment there were no real
skills that were targeted in our
validation experiments or tested in
production and we understand you know
this is kind of a fundamental limitation
of the claims that we can make both in
the paper and here but you know what we
thought was was kind of the right thing
to do so what do we find well in total
of the 27 predictable errors that kind
of you know on earth--the out from the
training set we were able to
successfully squat 25 of those at least
once and of course not every squat
worked every single time the full
distribution is in the paper as well as
some explanations for why some things
that we expected to work actually you
know didn't didn't really work out so
well
so if you're you know if you've stopped
paying attention at this point I get it
it's like oh this guy is talking about
some cute attack there's homophones
Alexa makes mistakes who cares I don't
even like cats why does this matter
right okay I get it but this matters
because cat facts
turns out or is not the only thing that
you can squat based on the kinds of
errors that Alexa makes as I said before
your voice is going to be used to do
everything or at least this is what this
is Amazon's future of the world you can
use your voice to buy stuff and you can
use your voice to do banking maybe
through the American Express skill so
let me show you an example of what
squatting the American Express skill
might look like so I might owe my
advisor $100 I don't know why but let's
say I asked Alexa Alexa pay ask Amex to
pay Bailey $100 and Alexa okay there's
one skill that sounds like Amex sounds
great but the thing is Alexa doesn't
have the credentials to actually make
this request on my behalf
so what she'll do is she'll send me back
a thing that says oh you need you don't
have the I don't know the credentials
for that you need to login
I've sent a card to your phone what does
this card look like it looks like a
login page okay great I'll login
everything works fine now let's say that
the attacker based on a methodology
that's very similar to ours knows that
Alexa prefers character representations
of words rather than the full
representation of the word so they've
registered a skill that's called am
space X Alexa you know instead of
choosing the AMEX skill or the official
MX skill chooses M space
X and the attacker has studied the
interaction model they know exactly how
this works they say oh you need to login
I've sent a card earphone and you're
fished right so you know it's cute yeah
still squatting is this cute example but
see even in this one demo how this can
be used as a gateway to launch more
complicated and phishing attacks in kind
of this new domain so a link to the full
video of this demo can you can find in
the paper working like in the actual
environment so I want to take a kind of
a change gears a little bit and talk
about another angle of the skill
squatting attack and this is based on a
growing observation that Alexa and other
speech recognition systems don't really
work as well if you have an accent and
in some sense this kind of makes sense
right like it's hard enough to do speech
recognition now given the fact that
everyone speaks a little bit differently
that's even harder to do correctly but
this observation got us thinking about
another research question you do
different regions exhibit unique
predictable interpretation errors right
so based on the way that you speak are
there things that Alexa thinks are
different but just for people that sound
like you and so what I'm showing you
here is a six way intersection or you
can think of this like a six way Venn
diagram to visualize where different
predictable errors come from parisian
i'm gonna break this down so if you look
at this part of the graph what this
shows is the distribution of predictable
errors by region so speakers from the
southern region of the united states had
two predictable errors speakers from the
midland region had eight different kinds
of predictable errors if you look at
this part of the graph this kind of you
start to see okay how are these
distributed across the different regions
right so if there's a dot connecting
some group of regions what that means is
that that group of regions all exhibited
the same error so for example you've got
these three particular words they were
shared across speakers from the north
and the mid-atlantic region but what's
most interesting is this part of the
graph which shows that for five out of
the six regions there's actually
predictable errors that are unique to
speakers from that region and from that
motivation and kind of following on from
that or if we introduced this variant of
the attack in the paper called a spear
skill squatting attack say that five
times fast an attacker
the core I'd to get here is that an
attacker similarly to the skill
squatting attack can launch us ghosts
wanting attack except now they can
target you based on how you speak and in
order to Vout order to kind of validate
that what we did is we took the 11
predictable errors that were specific to
a specific region and we applied the you
know kind of identical technique where
we split up the speakers into a training
set and a testing set we identified what
was predictable based on specific
regions and then we wanted to see if the
rate at which we were able to
successfully squat speakers from a
particular region was higher than the
rate of everybody else and so that's
kind of what this column represents you
know that really the question here is
you know okay was there a significant
difference between the attack success
rates in both of those scenarios if yes
then we consider okay that's a
successful attack based on you know
targeting specific specific groups of
people based on how they how they speak
so in total we were able to successfully
squat you know eight out of this eleven
Sphere squad of all pairs with of course
varying levels of success in each case
you know I want to know you know this of
course we have limited data and limited
limited insight here there's only ten
speakers from each particular region but
this result does suggest that you know
this kind of targeted attack may be
feasible with more data and in other
ways so I want to talk briefly about
some of the limitations of the work I
mean of course I think top of mind to
everybody on top of mine to us as well
okay scale and representativeness of
this data set right you've got 60
speakers you're trying to make some
claims about speakers in the United
States you know it is hard kind of to
make these broad general claims but we
did find that the signals were strong
enough to indicate statistically
significant trends you know
unfortunately there aren't great public
data sets that kind of investigate these
kinds of problems and the fundamental
requirement first say this particular
study is that we needed to get a bunch
of people all from different places that
all said the same set of words and it
turns out that that really doesn't exist
so I think that a cool area of future
work maybe even you know curating a data
set like I think it's a great area
feature work and of course I touched on
this before but you're demonstrating
this works in a development environment
versus you know a real production
environment stretches just a little bit
but
let's take a step back pop up the stack
and like and what are some of the meta
points that we learned so well for the
first thing is okay it's shiny its new
it's cool its IOT it's hot but it's got
the same problems as before and in a
sense you know skill squatting is kind
of like type o squatting except you in
the land of IOT the fundamental
difference being that type of squatting
the attacker is hoping that the user
makes a mistake you know you put three
O's in Google instead of two O's but in
skill squatting the attacker leverages a
kind of a fundamental property of the
speech recognition engine so it's like
you know in type o squatting it's like
it type of squatting except you know as
a user you can't see what you type and
everything goes through autocorrect
before it's shipped off to make a
decision on your behalf
and this kind of ties into my next point
and something that I guess is echoed
from the keynote as well you know the
opaque machine learning for
decision-making is still really really
new and interface quirks whether they be
in gestures or in voice or your facial
recognition can and will be a you and
will be abused by adversaries to kind of
cause harm okay
moving forward we alerted Amazon about
this stuff back in February when we
submitted the paper they confirmed it
and they're working on it and so we have
good news from them that they're working
on fixing the problem I think one cool
area of future work is kind of measuring
the widespread harms of skill squatting
but in general this idea that if we're
gonna use voice for everything where is
that gonna start to break down you know
we saw a fishing example is this gonna
happen in online shopping or some other
kind of context and finally I think
investigating these cut this notion of
IOT trust you know on the web we as
users and we've conditioned people to
say oh you know there's a browser
warning maybe I shouldn't go on that
site it's got a virus or well it's got a
green lock icon I feel like I could
trust that a little bit more but we
don't have we've not built anything yet
as to you know what kinds of
applications are trustworthy in this new
environment and so I think investigating
that a little bit more deeply could be
beneficial for both IOT and for you know
the security community at large so I
think that is my time and at this point
I'm happy to take any questions Thanks
[Music]
[Applause]
hi this is a question from UC Irvine so
so I'm thinking about this and then so
simply in our real life we recognize
this fit okay without the ambiguity from
the context right from the conversation
context so for example in the cool aisle
it's already showing that the Google
system can tell us of the contest by by
the history of the composition so if so
I'm just thinking that so since the
voice recognition technology are you
bothering to involve this context to
tell there's an ability so do you think
this is more like a short term problem
or there's more fun mental things behind
it so I think that there's two bits
right so yes context is very important
for speech recognition and in this in
this case we're not really looking at
context but also in this workflow
there's really not a lot of context for
you to go off it's like I need a skill
the skill is called a and how do you
know what a is if it sounds like
something else I think it's kind of an
outstanding question you know what to do
about this in the long term I think an
immediate fix would be Amazon when
they're doing Scott once in skill
registration say okay does this have
some kind of phonetic structure that's
similar to another still can this be
invoked in the same way is there
confusion if so you can't use it right
so some other platforms have started to
do this as well yeah so one thing is
that the current this assistant I'm not
very natural they just you just give it
like like a command but in the future I
guess
if it will merge into our like daily
conversation for them PO you will know
that I'm gonna do a payment not doing
like BMX I think that I think that the
idea here is like if you're if your
first interaction with this skill is
compromised and that you need no really
there's no context right then it doesn't
matter the attacker knows oh this
protector is building a skill for the
express purpose of squatting that
banking app so it's gonna sound like
baking app it's gonna feel like a
banking app until you know you sign in
with their credentials and they say okay
thanks I got your credentials haha bye
so yeah I think that I think that it's a
good point but still the as soon as you
start the first interaction with the
skill which is the problem of like and
also we go home I know like Google type
of skills yeah because when you do
transcription with at least with Google
API it gives you at least five to six
options or even more and it provides the
ranking and same is with like IBM Watson
transcriptions so just Amazon Alexa also
has because they don't have a
speech-to-text service per se right but
did you see or when you talk to Amazon
do they have a ranking procedure to rank
basic google experience they give you
they give a very good overall accuracy
for the exact word and they would have
all the alternate options yeah that's a
good question so so at the time and even
now I think there's no like Alexa API
they have like a transcription API but
the way that we did this was we actually
used Alexa as us we build a skill around
Alexa to kind of transcribe these things
for us so there was one choice that she
made and we kind of used that as the and
the intuition behind that it's like okay
well if that's what if that's what the
system is doing now then that's probably
what the system is doing in the wild so
there's no similar like analog where
it's like here's five options and here's
what you can choose at the end of the
day though you know they're making a
choice and so I wonder we haven't tried
this with like the Google home API or
something like that but I wonder like
what that would look like so I think
it's a good point but I'm not sure a
good question
so you
is fix be to not allow users to enable
skills by voice activation instead I go
to the phone I know it compromises yeah
I don't think that that's real I mean I
think that the right answer right now to
prevent this kind this specific kind of
abuse is at skill registration time
which I think all of these platforms
have some kind of like review process
but it is in our experience it's not you
know like it's not designed to do this
kind of stuff it's just design aside
does your skill you know actually work
they should basically say okay here are
the ways it because you have to
enumerate the ways you can invoke a
skill so is that invocation is that
easily confused with something else that
we already have registered so kind of
like a you know how with user names you
know you can't register a user name
that's exactly the same as somebody else
is on the same service something similar
to that
yeah I'm saying that they can't even
build they can't even register discuss
the adversary can't even register am
SpaceX because it sounds a lot like Amex
when you say it out loud you described
this is bad
describe you described skills is like
apps but on my cell phone it doesn't
load every single app from the app store
when I turn on my cell phone and it
sounds like every skill is active and
that doesn't sound scalable and because
there'll be more and more in sometimes
the same words work in different
contexts different ways right and so I
was wondering when you read the Amazon
security model what it used to explain
this and related is why do you not get
the same results with the same speaker
in the same word every time but you get
different results yeah that's a good
question so your first question which is
it doesn't sound scalable like what is
the kind of intuition behind it I I can
share with you kind of like the way that
they describe it I mean really it's just
we want people to be able to use skills
so we're gonna make them enable but you
fall I don't know how it particularly
works on the back end in terms of like
what they're actually making actual
decision maker racking your second point
which was your second question you're
getting different results for the same
in yeah that's super weird so like we we
observe this and we have this in the
paper too or we like sent the same audio
sample multiple times we get different
results every single time we think that
this is has something to do with like
load balancing or maybe a be testing so
like oh the you might actually be
getting a different trained version of
the model every time because you say
something like is okay and you just
distribute this is some server okay that
server has a copy of the model
maybe it's like five days old but who
cares just send it to them because it's
probably right enough this is like the
best guess that I have but you know I
don't work it out zone so I don't know
but thank you
[Applause]