vhere although I'm kind of amazed the
first I gave a talk at news annex
security in 1999 and the only difference
in the title would have been that it
said the crypto Wars because we thought
we were in the crypto Wars and we were
finishing them but here we are again so
this is about Apple or maybe it's about
Apple all of you know the story of the
San Bernardino case the locked phone
that belonged to the Health Department
that was found the the two terrorists
had destroyed their personal phones but
law enforcement found the locked phone
they came to Apple and said that only
Apple could open the phone and the way
Apple was to open the phone was to
provide an update to the phone
that undid the app of the security
protections and Apple said no we're not
willing to do that law enforcement said
you're obliged under the all writs act
the case went to court it went for a few
weeks with appeals and then the u.s.
said hey we might not need Apple to do
it so having said four weeks in court
and in congressional testimony that only
Apple could open the phone law
enforcement found that in fact somebody
else could do it now what came out this
spring was an inspector general report
that said in fact when law enforcement
testified in Congress and when law
enforcement of filed affidavits in court
saying that only Apple could open the
phone they hadn't tried hard enough
Amy Hess who was the Science and
Technology executive at the time got
nervous in February 2016 she had
testified in Congress
call me had testified before Congress
they had provided the technical
information for the courts in California
and they had said FBI was unable to open
the phone and only Apple could but she
got a little nervous that maybe FBI
wasn't trying as hard as it could FBI
had two different divisions the going
dark division which tries to undo the
crypto and the division that deals with
consultants the going dark division
hadn't been a
to open the phone the division that
deals with consultants was under the
mistaken assumption that if they were
able if one of their consultants was
able to open the phone they would have
to expose the technique in court and
because they dealt with national
security investigations they hadn't
pushed but the going dark group had not
consulted with the other group to say
are you trying as hard as you can has
started asking questions the consultant
group went and asked their consultants
one of their consultants had been 90
percent of the way along but had not put
it as a priority because it looked like
this wasn't an issue that that FBI was
particularly interested in they they
prioritized other things I don't know if
that's the consultant that opened the
phone or somebody else in August again
because Hess was raising questions FBI
initiated an inspector general report
and and we know all this one of the
striking things about this was that when
the phone got opened the head of the
going dark unit said to the other unit
would you go and do that for I think
Hess comes out smelling like roses in
this one so this is about eavesdropping
when we had the first crypto Wars it was
about phones that looked like that
some of you know these phones I still
have one on my desk actually that's a
picture of the one on my desk now it's
about phones that look like this but
it's really about two different sets of
issues the first crypto Wars was about
publication so when public key crypto
came out there were attempts by NSA to
hold back publication of both that work
and future and other work future work in
cryptography that got settled actually
quite amicably after a couple of years
of discussion in the 1980s there were
fights over crypto standards the issue
was would NSA or NIST develop crypto
standards for the non national security
agencies of the US government for those
of you not in the government that sounds
like the obscure argument for those of
you in the government you get it right
away
if NIST develops the standards so first
of all let me tell you the import of the
standards the standards mean that any
equipment sold to the federal government
has to have that stick that crypto
standard in it once cripple sales were
about 10% of all sales at the time so if
something is ten percent of sales you
put it in all your equipment once it's
in all your equipment then it's then
it's then other companies companies will
start to use it if they think it's a
good standard so whether miss was in
charge or NSA was in charge was really
saying whether a civilian agency or a
military agency I know it's not a
military agency a signals intelligence
agency was going to be developing crypto
standards that would be used by the
public big fuss in Congress and NSA
actually got blindsided by the computer
Security Act which passed and said NIST
would be in charge however what happened
was there was a technical working group
the technical working boot group had
three people from NIST three people from
NSA if they had disagreements about
whether a standard should be approved
they went to the Secretary of Commerce
and Secretary of Defense if they had
disagreements it went to the National
Security Council you can imagine how
often it went up it didn't and this kept
NSA kept winning until the mid-1990s
when NIST when the NSA group was headed
by someone from information assurance in
the 1990s the fight was over export
controls you've you probably all know
about this but at first the controls
limited export to crypto with 40 bits
this is 40 bits symmetrically it
eventually loosened and in 2000 it it
changed both in Europe and the United
States in part it changed because of
Defense Department needs to commute the
shelf equipment that was the
clinger-cohen Act but it was also things
like ad hoc military coalition's you
have a coalition like NATO those are
trusted partners you develop secure
communication systems over time you have
ad hoc military coalition's lecture
first Iraq war these are countries that
you don't trust you might trust them
this year but you might not trust them a
year from now buying commercial
off-the-shelf equipment is the right way
to go we get to the second crypto Wars
of going dark so in 2000 the NSA agrees
to a change in crypto in export controls
in part because they'd want to go to
computer network exploitation and they
get a big bunch of money FBI is pretty
upset about this and starts fighting
fought through the 2000s and then in
2010 got public about not being able to
understand communications end-to-end
crypto and began publicly talking about
it and in 2015 it got really I started
talking about phones but let me tell you
a little bit about what people are
saying about encryption and backdoors
and I picked some high-level people like
Michael Chertoff I think it's a mistake
to require companies making hardware and
software to build a duplicate key or
backdoor it even if you hedge it with
the notion there's gonna be a court
order I talked to Chertoff in the course
of writing my last book and he said
people should do what they've always
done in investigations and get metadata
from here you talk to this guy you
investigate this way sure the content is
great to have if you can get it but it's
too risky or what Michael Hayden former
NSA director said he said American
security is better served with
unbreakable end-to-end encryption that
would be served with one or another
front door back door side door whatever
you want to describe it it's not just in
the u.s. that you hear that Jonathan
Evans X head of mi5 in the UK says I
don't think we should weaken encryption
so you've got all of these people saying
we shouldn't weaken encryption and
you've got the FBI arguing the other
side but it's a curious thing that's
going on about the end-to-end encryption
as opposed to the locked phones on the
end-to-end encryption there are two
barriers to restricting use one is how
are you gonna prevent that software
maybe you could try and prevent the
software from coming in by bits across
the border but are you gonna inspect
every mobile device as it comes across
the border to see
what app somebody has downloaded when
there's been somewhere else it's not
feasible and furthermore I heard
recently under Chatham House Rules so I
can't tell you who it is a senior law
enforcement official a senior US law
enforcement official who said look
within within a decade Chinese equipment
is going to be within us telecom
infrastructure just the same way it is
already Huawei supplies telecom
infrastructure in the UK he said with
Chinese equipment within us telecom
infrastructure you have to have
end-to-end encryption for security so I
think what's really going on is that the
fight on end-to-end encryption when you
hear it publicly from law enforcement is
really a bargaining chip and where there
really a fussing about is locked phones
so when Apple introduced the phone
in 2006 very expensive little device
that was really easy to grab out of
somebody's hand just before the subway
door closed and and jump off the subway
car you got the phone the person who
owned it was moving to the next station
Apple instituted activation lock and
Find My iPhone and theft of phones
really dropped but then there was theft
of data and in the late 2000s Chinese
hackers found a way to get data off of
lost phones and stolen phones and that
data was very useful for identity theft
and in fact the hack itself was useful
because the Chinese hackers put up sold
videos of a sold information on how to
hack the phones to get the data off they
sold it to criminals outside China and
that's when Apple began putting
protections on data on the phone through
encryption and what they did is they
entangle the user pin with the device
key they began doing the first
protection was that over email and a
year later they did it for all data on
the 95% of data on the phone and they
did it to secure the data on the phone
remember that phrase secure the data
on the phone so you keep hearing from
law enforcement this is an issue about
security of people public safety versus
privacy if you think about data on the
phone what's on the phone there's photos
there's your travel log there's what
music you listen to there's your
contacts there's your text messages
there's your banking app this is not
about privacy this is about security I
want to talk to you now about movies for
a moment I don't know how many of you
have seen this film I'd always amazes me
when I give this talk I show the the
Sony poster for the interview when I
actually find people who have seen it I
read the review and never did if you
think back to the hack against Sony Sony
was not applying good information
security if you think about banks back
in the 1960s and 70s banks got it that
bits were money you don't protect bits
you haven't protected money in the 2010s
films are bits Sony is not producing
canisters of films it's producing bits
if bits are your product you don't put
the film's on the corporate network you
put two-factor authentication on your
system you do all these things but
that's not how Sony was thinking in 2014
it is how Sony is thinking now so why do
you lock phones well the best form
factor we have for two-factor
authentication is phones now I know many
people in here have UB keys and so on
you are not normal people in case you
didn't know it you are not normal people
everybody or everybody in modern society
with the exception of my sister-in-law
carries a smartphone they carry a
smartphone they know where it is they
know when it's missing it's a great
second factor Authenticator there ways
to use it as a second factor
Authenticator and their ways not to use
it as
second factor authenticator ways to up
ways not to use it
don't use SMS why not for those of you
who heard
Bhalla talk yesterday VJs talked
yesterday you know about phones getting
stolen and so on
black lives activists McKeithen during
the election found all of a sudden his
Twitter account was tweeting all sorts
of very positive things about Donald
Trump
he had two-factor authentication on his
phone but somebody went and switched the
phone number so that the authentication
went somewhere else and somebody else
had taken over his Twitter account last
summer
Bitcoin operators that has been people
who had lots of large Bitcoin accounts
who had been using SMS as their second
factor Authenticator found that they
lost control of their accounts nist
deprecated SMS a couple of years ago
then got some pushback and the word is
not deprecated if Donna were here I'd
ask her the exact word but the fact is
it doesn't matter whether it's
deprecated or not it's not secure what
is secure would secure and there are
other apps than these what secure is
having an app on your phone a piece of
software on your phone that calculates
something that you input as your second
factor why the piece of software because
you have the phone you control where the
phone is now what happens if if phones
are made easy to hack that is if you
have exceptional access into phones that
is if it is easy for law enforcement and
there for others to open phones what
happens is as you all know there's no
difference between data and programs
these apps become less secure but if
phones are hard to get into how do you
do investigations in the digital age so
I want to walk you through a couple of
investigations the first one is from
2005 in on July 7th 2005 terrorists in
the
in London set off bombs on three
underground trains and one bus killing
probably a hundred I don't remember and
injuring hundreds they were killed of
course in the attack two weeks later
there were a copycat group of five one
of them chickened out left his bomb in a
park nothing happened to it with it the
other four got on three underground
trains and a bus they tried to set off
their bombs they didn't have very good
tradecraft
they had a tiny explosion which showed
everybody around them that they were
trying to set off bombs but that tiny
explosion did not set off the big bomb
what happened to those four is that the
UK and London in particular has lots of
CCTV cameras so that's a picture of the
four of them before they separated the
UK then put up photos of them on BBC on
all the news sites tell a newspapers and
so on one of them put on a burka he was
six foot two he put on a burka he went
to the bus station in London took a bus
to Birmingham nobody thought anything
about a six foot two person in a burqa
he got to Birmingham he walked he stayed
somewhere in Birmingham but two days
later he took off the burqa as he was
walking about and he was recognized and
arrested two another pair one of them
was recognized by their family the
family got in touch with the police the
police knew the apartment went to the
apartment and found two of them together
and arrested them the fourth one is the
most interesting one the fourth one went
to the South of England that came back
to London got a brothers passport a
brother-in-law's phone and so on and so
forth went to Paris Milan Rome he had a
brother staying in in Rome the police
knew where the brother was went and
actually picked him up because they've
been trailing the phone all along ok
that's the kind of thing that people the
police do in investigations if I'd asked
you 20 years ago do you want to carry a
radio beacon with you at all times
all of you would have done exactly what
whoever it was did
but let me tell you about a more
complicated investigation
Harare had been prime minister of
Lebanon he got into conflict with Syria
he resigned his position and decided
then a few months later he would run
again the Syrians warned him about
running again he nonetheless was going
to do it he stopped by Parliament one
day to meet with legislators then he
found out a UN he was about to get back
into his car when he noticed somebody
from the UN that he who was told
somebody from the UN was nearby he went
to meet with that person in a coffee
house got back in his car his car of
course was part of an inter are
surrounded by security people they drove
a little ways were hit by a moving truck
bomb and he was assassinated this is a
picture of his route and the truck bomb
an investigators started looking at cell
phone tracks and found there were five
sets of cell phones and I'm not going to
be able to remember what purple and
green and blue and so on did one was the
head group and they communicated with
the other groups and that's all they did
another group tracked Ferrari a third
group also tracked Harare in each of the
groups the head of the groups let me
call him green and purple communicated
with each other and with a head group
but they did not communicate with
anybody else within the group they only
communicated within the group a fourth
group was when in the truck bomb and I
don't remember what the fifth group did
by following the trail of the phones
over a period of months before the
assassination because the phones went
dead after the investigator was able to
completely reconstruct the the crime
including where they had bought the
truck and so on where they bought the
truck by the way was somewhere that had
no CCTV cameras and I'm sure that was
not accidental let me give you one more
the Security and Exchange Commission
checks that there's not insider trading
it does investigations much the way law
enforcement does investigation
on organized crime they tried to flip
low-level people and go up in this case
they got a tip about the Galleon group
whose head was Rajaratnam and they went
to see him and they you know chatted
with him for a while and chatted some
more and so on and they did what
investigators do which is just when
everybody's tired and they say let's
have a bathroom break maybe get some
coffee come back to 20 minutes and keep
it up and as everybody's standing up
they say oh by the way do you know
somebody named Romy 18 with a handle
Romy 18 and he says oh yes and I've
forgotten exactly what her name is Romy
Khan I think well that was very
interesting to the SEC investigators
because Romy Khan had sent him a message
that said do not buy PL ICM PLC em till
I had guidance that's not a typo that's
what it said I mean it is a typo but
it's not my typo and so they went to see
Romy Khan next and of course they had
the goods on her she wore a wire and
that's how we get to the point that
there were 35 people convicted with him
getting an 11-year sentence you go back
to that instant message and you think
back 20 years ago there wouldn't have
been an instant message she would have
called him he they would not have yet
been under investigation that would have
been an ephemeral communication I can't
do in my 40 minute talk not only because
I am NOT a law enforcement investigator
but because because I couldn't do it
even if I were a law enforcement
investigator with with all that they
know about how to do investigations I
can't go through every piece of tools
that are using they're using but let me
tell you about some of them of course
communications metadata who went where
when that is extremely useful for
finding bank robbers for finding the the
the kid who kid the guy who hired
masseuses in Boston and then robbed them
and in two cases killed them he was
picked up through the cell phone located
matching cell phone locations the
communications met
is incredibly valuable come pick the
call me picture we know about lawful
hacking the use of a vulnerability
whether it's in a website architecture
and then you can put a network intrusion
tool on it and figure out who's using
who's accessing the website and that's
how you track kids people who are
accessing child porn we know about the
use of it in other kinds of cases as
well the FBI has been using lawful
hacking since the the early 2000s it's a
very useful tool but I do not want to
oversell it in part because it's a very
expensive tool it's a custom tool so
it's a tool that the FBI and law
enforcement will have to use in certain
cases but it's a rarely used tool and it
needs to be that way
closed-circuit television camera sorry
automated license plate readers one of
many types of data that's picked up
about you is you who traverse the
streets when I was writing the book I
talked with Palantir and they said
there's a case where police were
tracking somebody with a quarter they
were tracking them they were following
them an automated license plate readers
so they started following where they
were going on by following the cell
phone towers and they noticed there was
another phone traveling with that bet
party every time the first phone showed
up the second phone showed up the second
phone showed up the second phone showed
up they found a second person now if you
think about the labor involved if you
think about the labor involved in order
to to do that kind of tracking with pull
in the old days what you do is you'd
have 30 policemen over the space of a
week because you need five teams to
follow because you need to trade off
otherwise the bad guys say hey who's
that red car he's been behind us for the
last half hour and every time we switch
lanes and change exits and get off on
exits you need them 24/7 you're
replacing that by automated license
plate readers a program cell towers a
program Kevon Bengston and often sultani
have a paper that describes how the cost
hundreds of dollars have dropped two
pennies essentially and then finally of
course our friend Alexa and echo but
there are other techniques - all of you
know about great shift and celebrate
that sell tools to hack into phones
because no matter how hard a police
acure the phones you notice I said Apple
Android Google is also trying but
Android is a more complicated picture
because it's an open-source program and
each manufacturer implements in a
different way so even when Google does
certain things it's not clear how well
they get carried out later but the point
is that there are commercial tools
available for law enforcement to open
phones they're expensive but they exist
so what do you need for investigations
in the digital age well you need a whole
bunch of things first thing you have to
know in during the digital age is that a
high percentage of crimes have a digital
component it doesn't mean that the
digital component is part of the crime
it's that the digital component might
have evidence far more data is
concentrated that service providers than
used to be and sometimes is multiple
service providers which makes a
complicated picture for law enforcement
our laws and collection on surveillance
predate the digital age they don't deal
with complexities like the following
silly one okay silly because I don't
have time to go into the more
complicated ones the silly one is
maps.google.com is an address that is
collectable by law enforcement under
what's called a 23:07 D order relevant
to an ongoing investigation google.com
slash maps the google.com part is but
the slash Maps is a message to the
Google server it needs a warrant okay
there are that's the easy example there
are actually many many much more
complicated examples sorry
did I miss something oh yes so
investigations of the digital age
CSIS did a report came out recently that
talked about how much law enforcement
needs help
and they go to state local laboratories
58 percent of the time FBI field offices
forty five percent of the time and so on
that looks really impressive how often
they involve people who know what to do
I looked at numbers from 2016 and in
2016 the regional forensic labs which is
the 33 percent number did 6,000
investigations that sounds really cool
for state and local that sounds really
cool right there are 18 thousand state
and local police forces in the United
States okay this is just a drop in the
bucket for what they need so how should
they do they need to retool to become an
investigative agency of the digital age
what does that mean that means that they
have to assume all investigations have a
digital component and start to think
that way they have to enhance outreach
to industry so that they know what
industry is doing before the products
come out and they think about how to do
an investigation they need to but the
really big thing is that they need to
have much better sharing between federal
and state and local if you talk about
the UK there are 49 police units 49
police forces in the United Kingdom for
a country that's 1/4 the size of the
u.s. 49 18,000 very different if you
think about FBI capabilities FBI
capabilities aren't there some very good
people there but they're not at the size
they need to be but the state and local
don't have the capabilities that the
feds do and they're not having proper
information sharing I'm talking here not
about the feds taking over the case I'm
talking about the feds providing
technical tools more funding is part of
it but there's also the piece that we
don't hear about and that and then I
think law enforcement and he's not
thinking about which is what are the
investigative priorities street crime in
the United
States is way down from 20 years ago
pick any crime you like the numbers are
way down violent crime is way down
number of criminals is not way down a
lot of crime has migrated online when
you migrate crime online and you know go
to the Weiss conference workshop in
economics of information security or
some of the talks here and you hear the
numbers about criminal activity what
happens when credit card number is
stolen
used from Kazakhstan purchases something
in Bulgaria from Bulgaria and so on and
so forth and law enforcement state and
local law enforcement is not only not
equipped to do it but the US has not
thought about what our investigative
priorities in the face of such issues
ten years ago the security computer the
economics and security community said
hey digital crime is not so bad well one
of the things about doubling is at some
point all of a sudden the curves change
and we're in a different place now
but law enforcement hasn't caught up so
having talked about all that I want to
briefly introduce the Academy's report I
was part of an academies committee I am
NOT speaking officially on the pay up
for the academies I'm speaking on my
interpretation we were asked to analyze
trade-offs that should be that need what
kind of trade offs should legislators
look at when they're thinking about the
encryption debate we had incomplete data
from law enforcement they couldn't
actually tell us the impact they could
tell us so many phones locked they
couldn't tell us what type of
investigation they couldn't tell us
whether they used alternative methods
they couldn't tell us how much those
alternative methods cost we also had
limited ability to measure the security
risks our charge was to study the
trade-offs and provide a framework a set
of questions we were explicitly not to
reply to supply recommendations of what
to do so we didn't so what are our
questions first question is a proposed
solution effective isn't
can it be time only is it reliable will
it affect the security of the data and
the device and will it affect the
security and data of everybody's devices
how will it affect privacy and civil
liberties not only of the targets but of
everybody else how will it affect
commerce innovation economic
competitiveness
what are financial costs and who bears
them to what extent is the approach
consistent with current laws and other
government priorities if you think back
to the Obama administration Secretary
Clinton talked about an open internet
and open network you make it easier to
surveil that you make it really hard to
hide communication and that's really
contrary to the view that was being
espoused a presidency ago
- how does international context affect
the approach and how are you going to do
effective evaluation and oversight so
one of our points was that adding
exceptional access obviously obviously
we can secure do some degree lack of it
hampers investigations will dull but how
much is security reduced is it
acceptable depends on the technical and
operational details of the mechanism
this is obvious to you guys the solution
one has affects the security for
everybody it is not obvious to
non-techies it is not obvious to
legislators that you actually have to
look at the details of the solution it's
an important point that we constantly
need to get across and we look we don't
know the cost of when to society when
investigations are hindered during the
study we saw three people who claimed to
have ideas about how to do exceptional
access they were not fully fleshed out
they were not tested they were not
deployed
and when I say claimed to have ideas
what I mean is we saw single
investigators coming with a slide deck
we did not see implementations we did
not see an engineering team in and in no
case did we see a full architecture I'm
talking to a security conference not a
crypto conference you know the
difference between a paper idea and a
and a fully fleshed out architecture
some of you may have caught the article
in Wired by Ray Ozzie Ozzie was the
developer of Lotus Notes
he was software VP at Microsoft he
believed that he had an approach to
doing exceptional access and he briefed
the Academy's committee the academies
committee was neither authorized nor
constituted to come up with a security
evaluation of Ozzy's approach but I went
to him after his briefing and I asked
him if I pulled together a group of the
usual suspects would he be willing to
talk to us and he graciously said yes
and I think that's that's pretty
gracious of him actually because he knew
that I was coming in with a lot of
doubts now his proposal his original
proposal was for end-to-end encryption
and blocked devices after we met with
him the end-to-end encryption seemed to
drop away and it was only for lock
devices the model was that a key on the
device would be wrapped by an encryption
by the manufacturers Cree law
enforcement would go to the manufacturer
and with a warrant and then you know
through a key exchange the key phone
would be opened and it would then become
brick so the owner of the phone would
know that the data on there has was
being surveilled
and the phone couldn't be used anymore
it was a proposal for how to retrieve
the key securely and that's a theme here
this is the security problem I want to
know how authentication is working how
am I going to an CENTAC eight those
18,000 law enforcement offices what
happens when the phone travels
internationally and there are 120 or 200
countries that want to have the same
capability and so on during our meeting
with Ozzy well actually the first thing
did not come from our meeting
Ozzie Ozzie presented at Columbia and
during his talk errant roamers a
cryptographer from Tel Aviv came up with
a spoofing attack away for criminal
groups to get law enforcement to get the
manufacturer to give the key back to law
enforcement which would actually go back
to the criminal group and they could
open a phone like a phone open belonging
to somebody like a CEO or somebody else
with a lot of money the technique is not
resistant to jailbreaking from the point
of view of the Academy study those
questions about effective scalable how
does it affect the security of target's
non targets none of those were answered
furthermore it was a moving target as I
explained when he briefed the Academy's
committee was intending krypton and
locked phones after we talked with him
it became locked phones the people
involved in this or Steve pehlivan Matt
blazed and vinay myself and Ron Rivest
I'll have a slide with this up at the
end so you can get more details but I
have one more thing that I want to bring
to your attention before I move from the
Academy's report and that's a point that
the report made about smartphones it
said well if you make smart phones
easier to hack into then they're gonna
be there's a good chance they'll be less
good for other functions like secure
authentication multi-factor
authentication it's pretty important to
me that that point made it into the
report and I also want to say I'm not
the one who wrote it I hope some we all
agreed to it but I'm not even the one
who wrote it so I have one more reason
to encourage well have many more reasons
but one more that I'll leave you with to
encourage cryptographers use this is the
odni the office of Director of National
Intelligence report from January 2017
now all of you knew about the part where
it says Russian intelligence collected
against u.s. primary campaigns
everybody's paid a lot of attention to
that there's another part there it says
think tanks
and lobbying groups they viewed as
likely to influence US public policy
you're all computer scientists maybe one
or two of you are lawyers there's
probably not a political scientist in
the room so let me tell you political
science 101 or 102 B 1 or 2 B is that
the democracies need civil society in
order to function if you have a non
representative democracy that is if you
have direct democracy everybody judges
everything and makes decisions together
none of us live under such governments
except maybe in a family and usually not
even then but but within representative
democracies you have a whole layer of
civil society that functions is the glue
between the people and the government
they translate what the government
policies mean about abortion to the
people what what is happening on the
streets to minorities to the government
they produce reports whether it's the
American Cancer Society of the National
Academy of Sciences they produce
information about the environment all
sorts of social cohesion you have a weak
civil society and democracy flounders
it's something the Soviets and the
Russians know really well when the
Soviets came in in 1917 that was one of
the first things they eliminated when
the Russian when the Soviets came in to
to Eastern Europe at the end of the
Second World War
yes they assassinated political leaders
in Poland and East Germany and
Czechoslovakia they also worked to
eliminate civil society they were always
worried about the impact of the Catholic
Church in Poland and when there was a
Polish Pope that was something that was
very dangerous for them they couldn't
get rid of the Catholic Church in Poland
they weren't able to that was a strong
civil society that worked against them
so now go back and think about what the
impact is when the Russians go after
groups like these these are groups that
do not have the ability to they don't
have money they don't have tech support
they don't have the ability to secure
selves against a strong nation against a
nation-state so the importance of
consumer-grade strong forms of
authentication strong forms of
encryption are critical what happens
when a National Academies Committee
report gets its data slightly changed
just before it comes out or emails we
all know about the flippant way we talk
in emails or emails from Sierra Club or
Southern Poverty Law Center or the PTA
get distributed the respect for those
organizations their ability to function
gets very rapidly destroyed and yes we
have seen Russian actions against such
groups already so the going dark debate
is not a debate about privacy versus
security it's really about efficiency of
law enforcement investigations versus
personal business and national security
I was at a meeting earlier in the week
where a member of a national security
agency said 'would we're not doing a
very good job of informing law
enforcement how to go from a model where
you arrest the guy you get his device
you open it you get data - there's
another way to do the investigation
that's maybe not as straightforward but
will work and we need to do a better job
and right after that I heard two members
of law enforcement say we needed to be
straightforward we just have to have it
straightforward we want that data it
should be straightforward they couldn't
hear it they're trying to do 21st
century investigations with 20th century
approaches and the problem is we have
all sorts of 21st century attacks
against our infrastructure and our
infrastructure not just our physical
infrastructure but our social
infrastructure as well so it's really
about efficiency of law enforcement
investigations versus personal business
and national security it's really a
debate about security versus security
and so what I talked about is my new
book and I happen to have a flyer with
25% off over in the flyer table the CSIS
report which is the low-hanging fruit
report the Academy study which you can
get for free off the web and the clear
protocol analysis that Steve Matt Ron
and Dan
and I did and with that I will stop
thank you very much we will post notices
about the grep SEC the conference the
workshop is for women and
underrepresented minorities
applications are due in January that is
we will post things about it in January
and application to do and the
announcement of who's in we have full
travel support for whoever comes will
come out at the same time as travel for
I Triple E security and privacy in dev
and now you can ask questions okay
Thank You Susan so questions please come
up to the mic in the center in the front
state your name and affiliation hi dr.
Nathaniel Husted US Navy is the net
did law enforcement make any statements
that they feel the national security
apparatus is being appropriately
supportive of their endeavors given the
legal opportunities that law enforcement
has of leveraging such things I got told
by somebody in national security a
couple of years ago that after the
Snowden disclosures every time NSA had
to go up and testify on the hill
FBI sat with them and so they weren't
gonna talk about this which is I think
an answer everybody who spoke about this
all the quotes I have are from retired
people
now not everybody retired from from the
intelligence agencies has made a
statement like that and not everybody
agrees with those but I think it's
telling that there is no such statement
and in fact their National Security
Council documents from I think 2008 I
could look up the site later that say
encryption is the way to go there were
discussions under the Obama
administration that said let's not
legislate on encryption again from the
National Security Council so you have
commerce and state on one side but
clearly if national security were on the
other side we wouldn't be getting quite
the same things out
Simpson Garfinkel US Census Bureau
though this is a personal comment
so Susan when you were talking about the
truck bombing in Lebanon you said that
they went back and looked at where those
phones had been over the previous few
months and when you talked about the
police I think in the u.s. that we're
following one cell phone they noticed
another cell phone was traveling with it
well if you want to be able to go back
in time like that you need to be doing
continuous surveillance of every single
phone and recording those positions for
a long period of time and that's the
kind of surveillance that we typically
haven't wanted to do without having
morons serve so in fact I mean there's a
complicated answer to that when the USA
Freedom Act passed in 2015 in response
to the Snowden disclosures the idea was
that instead of the NSA collecting coms
metadata for the United States the data
would reside at the the telcos if the
telcos had less than eight decided not
to keep those business records for 18
months that is the model was they were
keeping it for 18 months if they decided
they did not want to keep it for that
long everything came back for
renegotiation so the point is the telcos
were keeping it for 18 months
AT&T back when it was old Ma Bell was
keeping it for a lot longer so they were
keeping it for their own purposes that's
one piece of the answer and I had
another part that has let me push on
that so most users are probably not
aware that their geolocation information
is being kept for 18 months at that
level of detail well actually most
pieces are probably not aware of the
amount of geolocation that data that
Google and other companies have which is
far finer than that yes they are not
aware the point is that that was a
negotiation settled in Congress about
that particular issue but the rest of it
is the carpenter' decision which said
you want seven days of location data you
need a warrant
no more 2703 data ad data we don't know
if you need a warrant for one day if you
needed a warrant for three days because
that hasn't come up for educated
education yes eyeko agree completely
that location data is remarkably
revelatory there's a wonderful paper by
Jonathan Mayer Patrick Mutchler and John
Mitchell that talks about this but that
is data that has been at the telcos for
a long time it is now being kept by lots
of others but it is it has been at the
telcos for a long time and mind in
various ways for a long time our final
question Vanessa Vanessa take University
of Melvin gave a great talk on Tuesday
to workshop by the way thank you you
gave a great talk today so the draft
Australian bill that was recently
released that may apply to assisting the
enforcement of the criminal laws in
force in a foreign country what do you
think about that well does that mean
that Australia is going to help China
especially with the close economic
relationship that your country has I
think that's one huge issue yes and so
it's easier for the u.s. to say well gee
we would never do that but it's much
harder for Australia to I we always
point unfortunately to Australia is a
place to be really worried about because
there's both a very conservative move
there and yet it's one of these
english-speaking countries that's part
of the five eyes and that could be the
tipping point so I think I've given you
my answer
it's quite dangerous I agree with that
very much the interpretation that struck
me is that it's for helping the u.s.
because there's no mention of insisting
upon a warrant or insisting that the
request for help comes with proper
processes in source country well under
the cloud act there has to be an
agreement you know so we're replacing em
let's with the cloud act and under the
cloud act there has to be an agreement
that this country satisfies certain
requirements and so on and so forth it's
determined by the executive and not like
Congress which is particularly worrying
right now but we don't even have one
with the UK yet which is supposed to be
the first one so I don't think it's
gonna roll down immediately yeah but
it's hard to know especially if we end
up with eight of six more years thank
you all right let's think
Susan Lando again
[Music]