yes thanks for the introduction earlier
this talk
if you would give it a subtitle it would
be what can go wrong if your VPN
supports all legacy authentication
mechanisms and this is joint work with
Martine Houghton and your bank from your
rural University in Bochum in Germany
and Adam to Bach and March in Germanic
from the University of a Pola in Poland
so I probably don't need to introduce
the term VPN to this audience
suppose you have heard the term Virtual
Private Network before they're used in a
lot of situations so for example if a
student is connecting to a university
network they can use that via tunnels so
they can access the library for example
or members of a corporation can use it
to access some internal servers
generally speaking if gateways are
connecting to each other and they
require some protection of their
communication they usually use those
tunnels and one newer thing that is that
can be found in the VPN world is with
the 4G or LTE networks there are the
links between the base stations and the
core of the network the so-called
backhaul links are secured using VPNs
and if you have a newer phone and your
contract allows it then also your smart
phone if you have the voice of a Wi-Fi
functionality then also your phone uses
a VPN tunnel to your network provider
using authentication with your SIM card
so there are a lot of VPNs on the
internet which are probably not even
obvious to you while you're using them
so where can I pee sec be found in the
network layer it's on layer 3 it's just
above the IP layer so it protects
everything that is being sent via TCP or
UDP and it provides integrity
authenticity and confidentiality of
course to provide such features it's
necessary to have a handshake protocol
and the handshake protocol of IPSec is
called ike internet key change it exists
in two versions the first one IP one has
been published in 1998 so it's right
old nowadays it's declared obsolete by
the ITF but it's nevertheless present in
all the implementations it's in every
operating system and in all the gateways
that are out there the newer version
like v2 is has been published in 2005
it's a current version there have been
minor updates to it but it's yeah
nothing of substance has changed in
there so how does IP one look like I'd
like to focus now on the first version
on the old one Ike v1 is udp-based and
on the protocol layer if you look into
the application it looks like this so
when I'm putting here here you see that
it's a six message protocol the first
pair of messages does some negotiation
of cryptographic pam parameters if
you're familiar with TLS that's like
setting up such a sweet so in the first
place there are a cryptographic
algorithms exchanged and validity period
how long tunnels may be established the
second pair of messages is a basically a
few Hellman key exchange it's a key
agreement and there is also a part of
the authentication in the second pair of
messages and the third pair does a
confirmation of that keys similar to TLS
finish messages so let's take a deeper
look into the protocol itself the
protocol flow first of all I have to say
that in the IKE world we're talking
about initiators and responders and not
about clients and service the product
call is quite symmetric so there is no
player role of somebody being a client
or somebody being a server you just have
to differentiate between who's
initiating and who is responding so in
the first message wait in the first
message there are is a set of puzzles so
cryptographic parameters that the
initiator proposes and with a second
message the responder chooses one of
those in the third message there is a G
to the X so as I said if the
diffie-hellman key exchange and some
ancillary data we'll come to that later
with the fourth message the
diffie-hellman key exchange is completed
after that both sides can derive keys
compute max for ya authenticity and
things are correct then the these max
are encrypted using keys that have been
derived before and with message five and
six those values are exchanged and
verified by both sides after that the
keys are authenticated so as I said I'll
come back to this and celery ancillary
data the sensory data is used for
authentication in actually one there are
different authentication methods and to
give it a better frame out just but this
year so we're looking at the second two
pairs of messages in the a q1 handshake
so there are four authentication methods
in v1 the first one with pre-shared keys
usually that some kind of passwords or
both sides of the tunnel need to have
the same password and then they can use
that the second method uses digital
signatures and the third and the fourth
option use public key encryption the
fourth method is called revised mode
I'll not go into the details what this
revision means the modes are very
similar to each other here so for the
four public key encryption based modes
you basically need to have key pairs and
they are required to be changed securely
beforehand so it's a out-of-band public
key change yes so I'd like to focus on
the third method here on the public key
encryption mode public key encryption in
IP one basically means RSA it's from
1998 they had nothing fancy other than
RSA for public key so let's go back to
this protocol flow what happens if we
plug in pke authentication that
basically changes messages 3 & 4 here
the ancillary data is now replaced by or
filled in with an encryption of a nonce
there are these launches Ni and an R
which are randomly chosen answers by
both sides and they're encrypted using
the public key of the pier and send over
these monsters are later used in the key
and the capability to decrypt these
nuances implicitly authenticates appear
them so you may now ask how does such a
encryption look like if we take a look
into the RFC its RFC to 409 there is one
single sentence that lines that out RSA
encryption must be encoded in pkcs1
format you can see as one is even older
than i ke and if you're familiar with
cryptographic a text and you probably
know that PK c as one is exactly the
what you need to apply so-called
blacking bhai attacks so we ask
ourselves what could go wrong in pkcs1
Forman in such a protocol what if there
were black Mecca Oracle's I assume that
not everyone here is familiar with Rahim
bhai texts I'll just give it to a short
primer in two slides if you're
interested in more black in Baja there
is another talk this afternoon given by
my colleague Yura so Morosky on the
robot study which is a recent Pony Award
winner so make sure to join that talk as
well like in Bacchus attack is a padding
Oracle attack
it's against RSA pkcs1 version 1.5 so
that's a long acronym but the padding is
rather simple the first two bytes of
such a message message have to look like
this you have beginning with a zero zero
zero two then there is a random nonzero
padding a single zero byte that the
limits between padding and the message
and here in this case the message is
amounts and for attacking this you
require an Oracle that tells you whether
the padding is valid or not so it's a
single bit of information that you have
to get back from such an Oracle so how
does an Oracle look like what is it an
attack scenario it looks like this you
have a sender and a receiver and sender
sends message em to the receiver and
somehow the attacker is capable of
eavesdropping that message but it's
encrypted the attacker cannot do
anything about it but what the attacker
can do is leverage some mathematical
properties of RS a to modify the message
and send it also to the receiver and
that's
the receiver is such an Oracle then the
attacker gets back
the single bit information whether the
pairing was valid or not and with this
information the attacker can do some
computations and by receiving this
approach by continuously modifying
messages and sending it to the responder
and getting information back whether the
padding was valid or not in the end the
attacker learns the plain text of the
message M that requires a couple of
thousand messages to that Oracle but it
works so if we combine this attack
approach with I ke how would an attack
scenario look like we require a
man-in-the-middle attack ER here and we
have two responders responder a and
responder B and the attacker being right
in the middle in the beginning the
attacker simply follows the protocol and
establishes a handshake with responder a
and in the here's to the product call he
does not modify anything what not modify
but he does a simple handshake and with
a fourth message message the the
attacker learns the encryption of the
random months.that
responder a chose of course the attacker
cannot decrypt it because it's encrypted
with the public key of responder B but
what the attacker can now do is he can
do a black inbox attack against the
other responder the message was intended
to be for while doing that he has to
keep the other responder waiting because
if he would just cancel the handshake
then responder a would discard all the
femural values namely the de few home
and secrets so then the attacker would
not gain anything by learning the nonce
in the end so responder a has to be a
health waiting after the black bat
attackers completed on the attacker
learns the nonce can derive all the keys
as the legitimate responder could do and
then finish the handshake with messages
five and six and impersonates responder
B in this scenario and then
authentication is of course broken um if
you're familiar with i ke or with
implementations then you probably
surprised about
this pke authentication mode because
usually it's not implemented we've
looked into all the open-source
implementation
none of the open-source implementations
have it in there it's described in the
RFC but in the open source software it's
not implemented but there are a few
implementations of this most prominent
cisco and who i implemented so pke
authentication is contained in cisco iOS
and the revised mode is also contained
in who I in some who are firewalls but
they only have their revised mode they
have not the original one and we also
find out found out that there are
implementations by some Swedish
corporation named la vista and the
taiwanese company is EXO they have
security gateways that implement they
are not implement they have a broken
implementation they don't support this
mode officially there is no config
option for it it's not working you can
configure public keys but pke messages
are processed far enough to exploit them
well so we yeah to test that we made
sure that we get some test devices
basically we went to ebay and bought
these things for Cisco we were lucky to
get one test device so this is how it
looks in our network lab and for this
talk here I would like to focus on on
Cisco IOS now as a case study
why Cisco well because I don't have the
time to talk about all the Oracle's
there and all the implementations and in
Cisco it's at least officially supported
and it has fewer bugs than the whoever
implementation our test device is a ASR
1001 extruder with that iOS version so
how does the Oracle look like in the
beginning when you're doing a handshake
with this cisco iOS device then with the
first two messages proposals are chosen
nothing fancy here but if you then send
a message three with a valid padding
then
of course what happens with the protocol
the device full of the protocol so it
sends you a message for but if you send
an invalid padding then the device waits
a second and then responds with method a
message to so putting the frame here on
it the difference is in one case you get
back message for in the other case you
get back message to and that's exactly
the single bit information we need for
obligin Baja Oracle attack because we
now know was the device able of
decrypting it or not so there are other
obstacles
in exploiting this as I said one
responder has to be held waiting and for
Cisco IOS that's not that easy because
after 60 seconds a handshake is simply
discarded we didn't find any way of
having a longer time frame than 60
seconds and when we're configuring a
1024 bit key then our device is capable
of doing about 850 cryptographic
computations per second I'm focused a
focusing their responses on the slide
it's basically cryptographic
computations that means if we send if we
have these 60 seconds of time then we
have to finish the attack in 51 thousand
requests because our device was quite
slow we simulated how an attack would
look like we implemented an Oracle that
behaves exactly at Cisco one and also
exactly like the clevis forensics so
once they have the same properties and
we found out that about a quarter of
attacks would work in this scenario yes
but there were other obstacles with
Cisco that prevented a successful
exploitation
first of all Cisco's I a handshake
implementation is not optimized for
throughput and the cryptographic
calculations for I ke are done by the
CPU despite it having a hardware
accelerator for cryptography and the
state machine is single
threaded so yeah the that was a problem
that we encountered and what we didn't
suspect is that the first two messages
with Cisco IOS really take a long time
we don't know exactly why but the
majority of time is being taken by the
first two messages which are absolutely
non cryptographic so these were purely
non cryptographic obstacles that we had
there so in one case we had a decryption
attack that had we required 19,000
requests but unfortunately it took us 13
minutes so we couldn't in the end when
in the middle of the connection but I
think we're quite near to it so is an
attack realistic well first of all a to
select a to slow attack does not
permanently lock out an attacker they
can simply start over hoping that the
next the next attempt requires fewer
requests and it's still dangerous if
your installation has multiple devices
that share the same key pair for example
when you're doing load balancing so
these are the CVE numbers for the
implementations we analyzed Cisco is
only one example we found the other
three ones and yeah patches are
available
interestingly we do not find any are pke
implementation or PK implementations out
there that did not contain obliging Maha
Oracle so all that implemented it were
vulnerable so the paper title is about
key reuse so I'm would like to point out
a little thing about cues as well so
usually when configuring i ke
administrators do not maintain
individual keepers for all variants of I
key the common practice is to have a
single RSA key pair not even for i ke
sometimes even for more things like it
with whoever they also use their devices
RSA key pair RSA key pair for SSH host
identification as well so the actual
security of the whole thing depends on
cross cipher suite and first version and
cross protocol security and one thing I
don't know if you're aware of this but
you're certainly aware that in for
a decryption and creating a secret
creating a signature is the same
operation so blocking buffer attacks can
forty signatures which is also being
presented in the robots study this
afternoon so once we have that tool at
hand we can think about can we attack
other protocols like Ike v2 with
signatures and we found out yes this is
possible
signatures are supported by both equity
1 and V 2 and on a Cisco router we have
more time for that in IP - we have 4
minutes time for an attack but creating
signatures using ours a black mahai
attacks takes them takes more time so in
the end we turned out to have a
succeeding rate of about 22% with the
simulator again the real hardware lacks
the performance with the first two
messages yes so we have a we have some
other contributions in the paper as well
there is a description of a an attack
against password page a password-based
authentication in main mode we have
message flow diagrams of all the i key
variants in the paper there is a
description of all the other
implementations and their Oracle's and
we also have a description of the
parallelized blocking buffer attack we
implement it for this so with that I
conclude my talk and I'll be happy to
answer your questions
[Applause]
hello Jeffrey Goldberg from agile bits
I'm wondering have you spoken to anyone
at Oracle about that delay on those
first two messages and at the tinfoil
hat end of speculation whether that was
sort of like just a dirty hack to
maintain compatibility while trying to
thwart attacks of this nature again wild
speculation but it might be interesting
to know why that delay is there first of
all we we have not asked Cisco or the
other vendors I mean it's only a problem
and we have not asked them about what is
the problem there yeah
the only speculation I can give is that
it's probably because of this that very
old software and we had a comment from
one of the Cisco developers who said
well this has been developed ages ago
and probably has never been updated
since then because nowadays cisco
routers have multi-core CPUs but the
thing is still single threaded so if
they would care for performance and they
would have written the code to be
multi-threaded and when we were little
little side note when we were playing
around with it we found out that they
even don't comply to the standard they
developed themselves there is a little
bug with the with header offsets and so
when we asked them about this and told
them you're you're incompatible to the
standard they said well they have
probably never been in trouble
interoperability tests with other
devices probably because no other device
implements it and Cisco devices among
each other they were pretty well because
both of the buck
so you mentioned kiri use between SSH
and IPSec did you observe any kiri use
between with TLS interfaces did you do
any measurements I've looked at this in
one case I thought it was the case but
it turned out to be an error that I had
made so um with Huawei their TLS key for
the web interface seems to be hard baked
into the firmware so if one is capable
of decrypting their firmware package
that's probably another issue but yeah
we didn't test for that so I I'm not
aware of a device that uses the I keys
for TLS but you can configure it that
way
for example is with clevis tur when
you're setting up i ke and you really
don't care for security you get a
drop-down menu where you can select the
key to use for for i ke and the only key
that is there if you use a fresh
installation of their device the only
available key is the one that is used
for the TLS web interface so if an admin
really doesn't care it just select that
one and then yeah then you have the
situation it so they have a hard-coded
key for the web interface but they're
generating but you you can generate a
fresh key 4 4 4 4 well way you can but
the default keys it's hard packed as far
as I know
and for fork LaVista the cases that on
initial booting of their OS image of
fresh key is generated for the web
interface but it's available in the
selection for the I key please so what's
kind of interests anecdotally we see the
same vendors over and over again with
every attack paper on public key crypto
so I'm recognizing the same vendors from
mining your P's and Q's six years ago
and I'm also recognizing some of the
same vendors from the drown attack so
it's kind of over and over again we see
the same themes and there might be some
you know completely cross cross
vulnerability attacks there would be
interesting to analyze that yes
Jarrid Jacobson and l-3 technologies um
did you have to take any steps to enable
the pke functionality in the negotiation
on any of these devices or did they come
secure by default in that it wasn't
enabled for Cisco and whoever they come
secure by default so it's not enabled by
default with clevis transaxle the other
situation is different you have to
enable i ke or IPSec if you want to use
it but when you do that checkmark for
enabling it then those devices were
vulnerable because there there's no
configuration option for pke you can't
disable it and you can only disable the
whole IP effect IPSec thing in that
router but then you lose the the overall
functionality of course you can install
the patch then it's gone
so Travis forensics is simply removed
that yeah that bug from their firmware
yeah it's actually one more question um
I mean black and Parker attacks have
been around forever and you know the TLS
spec even though they didn't actually
properly protect against them they at
least mentioned them was there any
discussion in the standards for Ike
about like invoker attacks or any
attempt to protect against 1998 so there
was no update or no mention no yes in I
don't know if I forgot to mention that
in Ike v2 there is no public key
encryption mode anymore
they removed they remove that that's
what they knocked it with actually - so
four signatures are still there okay I
think we're at time if there's no more
questions