I'm ENGLISH Becker and I'm presenting
work and with which is a cover of
collaboration with myself Simon and
Angela Zaza all from UCL so we are
studying our own University's new
password policy which is split on the
premise that to encourage users to
choose stronger passwords by offering
them longer lifetime password lifetime
in return so we heard about it and we
didn't design the policy and of course
then wanted to study it and collaborated
with the university so the OU policy was
quite fixed 150 days the password had to
be 8 exactly 8 characters and now the
new policy is a variable exploration
policy and the passwords can be between
8 and 30 characters long there are there
are some complexity rules which haven't
changed and now there's also a
dictionary check to make sure that there
is no dictionary word in the password
this strength of the the sorry the
lifetime of the password Killian is a
linear mapping from the entropy to the
days so if you've got a password or 50
bits that gives you a hundred days of
expiration and then a linearly goes up
to three and fifty days for a hundred
and twenty bits of expiration the
university uses Shannon information
entropy to calculate the password
strength which is not the greatest
measure but it is still widely used and
does the job for the power pub for the
purpose of the study at least now the
password is supposedly your only
password at the university you need it
for emails every room a hero Moodle
virtually most systems are on it you do
also need it for Active Directory
machines so if you use it in a lab or in
a lecture theatre then you have to type
the password there in by hand and here
on the right you can see what the change
system looks like so this is there's a
web application where all the pur
changes and resets go through and it
tells you down there I'm not sure you
can read it
down there that the password in now for
example what I have typed there gives
you 238 days of expiration UCL it's
quite a large research institution
we've got 50,000 students 20,000 admin
or research staff and a lot of alumni
although 70% of their accounts were
expired now we received an anonymized
version of the lock data that gets
generated when users interact with a
password system so we've had 16 months
of data there were 3 million and 3
million into action in this time period
200,000 password changes and hundred
50,000 password reset change events and
on the right you can see histogram of
the distribution of changes and resets
and the associated past-life them that
these changed in resets hat as you could
the first thing to notice is that
they're fairly identical there is very
different in password that were
generated or that were used in resets
and password that were used in
generations and it's very strongly
skewed to the left apart from this this
little 1 percent of users who go to all
out and choose a password that gives
them 350 days la lifetime it's quite
difficult to generate it is 25
characters or so you need to get such a
password so straight into the main
finding from this study is this figure
here the blue line is the mean password
strength of all users at UCL over time
over the 60 months that we have studied
here initially we observed a small drop
in the strength between November 16 and
February 17 so the policy came into
place in October 16 and but after that
so we guessed that while users become
accustomed to the new systems but after
that the passive strength increases from
145 days to 170 days which is an
increase in about seven bits of entropy
so I kept this kind of structures
suggests that users have adopted slowly
to the new password policy and
eventually make use of their ability to
increase part of their password lifetime
by strengthening
their passwords there's a quite a few
cyclical the Habeas that kind of need to
be explained to understand the wig
leanness off the blue line to begin with
so a quarter of users if we have just
seen from the previous slide have a
password strength of less than one
hundred and ten days and that means that
they have to change or that their change
on average their passwords around every
eighty days now there are a number of
events where the large number of users
get a get enrolled in the system which
are which happens twice at the beginning
there's quite a lot of users that start
on day one of the new policy and then
eighty days later they have to change
their password and because they had the
weakest possible passwords already they
can only increase the password strength
which is what the increase in February
2017 highlights
similarly the academic year starts in
September every year and at UCL that
means that 10,000 new users students
joined the system so the green line here
is the mean password strength of all
users and is predominantly influenced at
around September 17 when 17,000 in
10,000 new users Dillon joined the
system these users have initially we can
pass worse than the existing populations
but yes they've changed start changing
the passwords and do it for the first
time around December January 20 so
generally 2018 they choose stronger
passwords too and their increase in
passive strength is quite pronounced and
also influences deposit rate of the
entire organization we also I also drew
on this the orange line which is the
steady state solution which is an
attempt to predict the password lifetime
the final password lifetime of the
current of the policy so for each time
frame we look at the changing behaviour
of all users and extrapolate what this
would mean if users continue to change
their password in this manner now this
one for example mean that an April 2017
the the steady state solution is
fifty-five days so we would expect the
blue line to level off to this to this
number 255 days however it is actually
constantly increasing and constantly
changing so we can't actually say that
the policy has had its full effect yet
so even after 16 months of collecting
data we can't say that this policy will
have this impact on passive strength
that is still evolving which is quite a
long time to be studying something to
get conclusive results this is the
frequency of changes and resets and also
the number of new users have joined the
system just to highlight the number
large number of users that joined the
system in November 17 as the new
academic year starts now we would have
thought that once users get more
familiar with the system the number of
resets decreases however this is not the
case it remains fairly flat or fairly
high I would argue throughout the period
this brings me on to a quick summary of
our findings on the changes and resets
at the user accounts 66% of users had to
reset their password and on average this
mean meant 1.1 resets per users and 2 /
4 2.4 changes per users there's only
really two reasons why one would reset a
password that is if you forgot it and
once your password expires even a minute
after here it has expired you have to
reset it there is no grace period for
being able to change your password the
cost of a reset is higher then a change
because you need to either go physically
to a help desk or use a text message
based reset system and perhaps
unsurprisingly there is a strong
positive correlation between passive
strength and the likelihood of having to
reset your password before expiration so
users with stronger passwords are much
more likely in this case four times as
likely with a book with a lifetime or
300 days to forget their passwords
compared to users with just a hundred
days of lifetime and as a third finding
him the more password resets the weaker
the password choice now we didn't
this but this following graph displays
the number the average password strength
of users grouped by the number of resets
that the user has had what will have had
in fact so here you can see that for
zero for users with zero or one resets
their average password strength is
fairly well aligned and continues to
grow over time this is also the case the
growth it's also the case for all of the
user different user groups however users
with more than one reset have passwords
which are ten days weaker so very
significantly weaker than the other
group then those with zero or one days
which kind of resets kind of hint said
that one reset per user per year is
potentially a good measure of acceptable
or good acceptable potentially measure
of a user's ability to use the system
there's also the cyclical effects here
in again visible on this slide so at 100
days initially all the groups all the
lines remain quite flat but then it had
towards a hundred raise from 80 days
onwards or so there is a sharp increase
in the mean passive strength this is
because at that point the first users
will start to change their part will
start to change their passwords and the
passive strength increases because all
they can do is they cannot choose the
weaker password and then they already
have at this stage equally at 350 days
you see this sudden strong drop drop of
mean passive strength this is the
converse effect of users who had
previously a password of 350 days
exploration and all they can do is
choose well they can't choose a stronger
password on and on average they choose a
weaker password when they change their
passwords just to reiterate the fact
there were a lot of changes and resets
not a single user had zero changes a lot
of users had three or more resets or
changes over time
the third finding that I want to talk
about here is the messages that UCL
sends regarding your impending passwords
expiration so he CL sends five emails to
users reminding them that the password
that their password is going to expire
this happens at 30 days 20 days 10 days
4 days and 1 day before the expiration
and on each of these occurrences 10% of
users act within 20 each of on each one
of these emails 10 percent of users
approximately react within 25 4 hours
and change their passwords so this graph
here on the right shows the frequency of
password changes relative to this day of
password expiration which is t0 and you
can quite quickly see that there's very
few changes up to 30 days before
expiration who and suddenly the
triggered by these emails the number of
expiration the number of changes happen
increased quite significantly and then
immediately as the password expires the
number of resets of the people who were
just didn't just get done and get it
done in time or forgot about it or yeah
have them to have then got to reset
their password so it's an interesting
observation that if you've worn your
verb users too early they will actually
lose quite a significant amount of their
password its lifetime
in which case actually users change
their password
on average 22 days before their
passwords expire we also had some
demographic information about our users
at UCL and here I've plotted the mean
password strength of a time for
different faculties there is a clear
trend at the well firstly to observe all
faculties respond to the policy change
and they do to increase the password
strength over time there is no
observable difference between different
groups apart from of course that mass
and physical sciences have about 1.2
times as strong a password as education
as the Institute of Education which
actually only joined UCL two years
so there might be some other explanatory
factors here why they have weaker
passwords equally we have a the same
plot for the different relationships of
users - with the University and you can
see that the undergraduate and
postgraduate students have this big dip
in that mean passive strength this is
again because of the new users that
joins the system in September 2017 but
in generally teaching staff have the
highest have the strongest passwords and
students have weaker passwords which can
be potentially explained with the in
with our interactions with the system
because teaching a research staff don't
juice don't need to type that password
ever and while students will have to
type it on physical machines I keep my
password in a password manager it is
gets 350 days and I can't type it ever
but I don't have to type it and admin
staff for example they work on domain
joint machines so they are if I had to
type my I would also I would like be
choosing the weaker password if I had to
type it every day to unlock my machine
so there's some underlying interactions
and the like reasons - that can explain
this figure we also inquire from 93
users initially about their observations
about the perceptions of the new
password policy so this was in the
couple of months after the new password
policy had been rolled out and these
users had just used it for the first
time now use has appreciated the
flexibility of the new system eight
characters the previous system forced
them to have a password of eight
characters which was quite difficult now
but actually quite a few of them did not
notice the change of policy and due to
the very rigorous criterias they know
they found it difficult to create a
password that was not labeled as weak as
this person says and highlighted that it
can be too complicated to type difficult
passwords right let me discuss
quickly our findings here so the
intervention as the policy change was
clearly successful users to stronger
passwords and site purpose observation
is it took a very long time so we looked
at the data six months into the rollout
of the new study and thought this policy
is not working because at that point we
were still pretty much level or have
actually dip slightly so it is
interesting to when studying an
intervention it is into it is important
to have some sort of measure of when the
intervention has had its full effect
which can be over 16 18 months can be a
long time however from a security
perspective for now this is where the it
becomes interesting so florencio at all
defined this region of don't care
password strength which is the region
where passwords are strong enough to
withstand an online attack 10 to the 6
guesses and but a weak enough a too weak
to protect against an offline attack and
all of our passwords caveat Shannon
entropy fall into this range of it don't
care of this region of don't care so
actually from a security perspective
there is no benefit to this increase in
password strength cost benefit why so
the policy has increased user costs
because users have to remember and use
more secure passwords but the only
benefits are really in their perceptions
that they now have some form of control
of their lifetime and are being involved
in the system which actually came out of
the user studies too so let me conclude
we studied another password policy of
stronger password implies longer
password lifetime at an University of
over hundred thousand users and for 16
months users play the game we couldn't
find a single user group which did not
respond to the password to the incentive
and as some anecdotal site nodes we
found that one reset per user per year
seems to be an upper limit of X
debility and otherwise it will have a
negative impact on security in the
organization no on deposit strength and
I don't really see this policy well I
can the only way it put place where I
can actually see this policy as being
useful is to encourage users which have
passwords weaker than the online
guessing threats of thresholds to say of
ten to the six password so have really
weak passwords to encourage them to go
to passwords which are secured against
online guessing and then you give them
as a reward passwords which does not
expire so we are continuing working with
our IT services to potentially improve
upon this policy but working with large
organization has been in particular
institutional educational institution is
difficult as the infrastructure is quite
diverse we have like quite a bit of more
data and if you've got specific
questions of what who asked the data I
have drawn about 200 more diagrams and
analyses so it's a lot more detail there
that can be explore plot so police with
that questions
thank you my name is Daniel sokoloff
with hazard de have you measured with
each password change the those users
would changed password how much it gets
longer so I know t-mobile has that and I
just add a number in the end every every
time I have to reset it so it starts
with one two three and I think I know
I'm one two three four five and I don't
think it helps any any guessing to
defend against any guessing so from the
log data the only number we get is the
past a lifetime in days so we don't have
any kind of heuristic information on the
password and on the compasseth
composition so adding a number is
actually quite rare so previous research
the most common approach is to increment
a number at the end or at a single
special character if the special
characters needed but because there is
this quite substantial increase in
entropy it is more than just increment
because from an entropy perspective
incrementing a number does not affect
the entropy at all so it this changes us
to substantial to be explained by simple
alterations to your password and why do
you think it took you half a year to get
back where you started
why do you think what would happen there
well because the weakest passwords have
a lifetime of 100 days so for the first
hundred days only the users that have
issues with the current passwords will
be the ones changing their passwords so
if I have a password with 350 days and
choose it initially and I don't like it
I will change and reset it earlier in
the initial period so basically
initially it is users who are in the
first hundred days it's not users on
regular changes that we could make the
change it's users who have problems with
a current passwords that do the changes
yeah no politics yeah yeah lifetime yeah
users adopting to the system getting
getting used to it learning about it
their options and because a change takes
you it like you they normally it will
only do one or two changes maybe three
changes here on average the user does
three changes a year so it is only
whenever they have to iterate us that
there is a chance to actually improve
the strength hello rich che MIT Lincoln
Laboratory very interesting study I was
wondering a bit about user sentiment and
in particular was this presented to
users as and do they perceive it as
either oh well the university is going
to punish me if I make a bad password by
making me reset it again or was the
messaging and the perception more along
the lines of if I make a weaker password
the university will help protect me by
having it expire and neither of those
two was the messaging it was more than
courage Minh empowering the users to
have a choice about their lifetime about
their exploration that there was no
really no messaging about the securing
of the account like their innocence it
nearly seemed like the university was
aware that there and visit in this don't
care region but they wanted to do it
anyway
thank you hi Rahul from Cornell
University it's good study I was
wondering any users told you like they
learn to trip the entropy meter that you
are using because there are ways that
you can trick the entropy calculation in
the sense like by adding an exclamation
mark will increase your entropy
significantly that's my first question
and the second question is do you see
any increase in adaptation of adaption
of a password strength meter because
remembering a password with like it's 70
bits of entropy and typing it's like
very
Kim Muslim so do you see the bills
increasing part of strength meter being
adopted more and more amongst the
university users he said it password
strength meter being an armed password
managers we didn't ask we didn't so in
the in the hundred use a qualitative
interviews that we did we didn't find
any strong encouragement of firstly of
adding exclamation marks to Hector
entropy because not many users were
actually aware so this is while there
were quite a lot of engineers in this
university UCL has the full range of
faculties so the technical side is
actually quite small I would argue so
this this might explain why engineering
Heffer have a higher number of stronger
passwords and other faculties but no we
did not see this and secondly password
we didn't ask about we didn't do a large
quantitative survey to ask about
password password managers yes okay
we'll take one last question and I lost
the speaker to come in did you consider
including at a distance or diff you know
some sort of DIF measure in addition to
strength um I could imagine that once
you'd basically encourage people to pick
a strong or high entropy password based
on a you know expiration time after the
first trial doesn't really matter I've
already got a strong password and now
you ask you could ask me to change it
every day and like the first questioner
said maybe it's having a number maybe
it's changing a hash to a bang or
something right I would imagine it after
the first trial you're gonna see no
correlation whatsoever after after you
know the first changeover well would
have been nice to have these metrics but
it was not our system okay and if you've
managed to do it with the only
University I'd be happy to hear okay all
right let's thank our speaker one more
time
[Applause]