everybody thank you for joining our talk
as he said
paper is called towards predicting
efficient and honest or circus this is a
joint work done by myself and my
co-author mostly money at UTA also my co
advisors Jiang Ming at UTA and Matthew
Wright at RIT so the key concepts that
you should understand about the tor
network to understand this talk is that
tor is an anonymous communication system
where users can access the internet
anonymously by first building a three
hop circuit through the Tor network the
first hop is called a guard the second
hop is called a middle and the last top
is called an exit in the Tor network
there are over 7,000 volunteer relays
distributed throughout the world and
there are millions of users so this
architecture makes it very difficult for
an adversary to link the client to her
destination for example if we have a
passive adversary that can observe the
traffic from the exit to the destination
they won't have enough information to
link the client to her destination and
likewise if an adversary can view the
traffic from the clients to her first
hop the adversary wouldn't have enough
information to link the client to her
destination tor is slower than typical
web browsing and is this architecture
that gives rise to some situations where
clients may have a poor or slow
connection for example so you have a
client who built a circuit and the
client is in North America
their first hop is in Europe their
middle hop is all the way back in North
America and their last stop is in
Australia and say they use this circuit
to connect to a server in California
this would be one situation due to
tour's architecture that this client
would experience a slow connection
congestion and tour is also an attribute
that may cause clients to experience
slow connections for example congestion
is caused by a large subset of users
consistently selecting the same node in
most of their connections causing that
node to be overloaded with respect to
its computational resources but also
with respect to its bandwidth resources
a way to mitigate congestion and latency
in tour is by strategic
selecting paths through the Tor network
now I'm going to discuss three path
selection algorithms
the first one is bandwidth weighted
selection which is what is currently
being used in Tor then there's nadir and
voice-off selection and congestion aware
routing and bin with weighted selection
the client randomly selects three nodes
through the network except the selection
is not done at uniform random it's done
weighted towards bandwidth so that nodes
with higher bandwidth have a higher
probability of getting selected compared
to nodes with lower bandwidth but in
this type of selection there is a
trade-off where if we wait to heavily
towards bandwidth then we cause too many
users to select nodes with higher
bandwidth that's causing bottlenecks in
the network stator and Borissov path
selection is an extension of bandwidth
weighted selection except the user is
given a tunable parameter in the range
from 0 to 15 and the parameter controls
how much the selection is weighted
towards bandwidth so if the tunable
parameter is set to 0 then three relays
are chosen randomly and bandwidth is not
considered but if the moderate parameter
of nine is chosen then moderate that the
selection will be moderately weighted
towards bandwidth and if the parameter
of 15 is chosen then the selection will
be heavily weighted towards bandwidth
and again is there's a trade-off where
when we wait the selection too heavily
towards bandwidth we cause a bottleneck
in the network because we're causing a
lot of users to use only nodes with high
bandwidth in their study they show that
when the tunable parameter is set to
nine they get the best results with
respect to the bandwidth congestion
trade-off congestion aware routing is
another routing protocol where the
client makes round-trip time
measurements from their location all the
way to the exit and the from the
round-trip time measurements they're
able to infer congestion and the
round-trip time measurements are made
during circuit creation but also over
time through application measurement and
they preemptively build a pool of
circuits and for the rest of their
connections they use a circuit with the
lowest round-trip time or the lowest
congestion but one disadvantage for this
method is that if the exit node is
malicious then
in game the round-trip time measurements
and they can win more traffic they can
put themselves on more connections and
they can increase the probability of D
anonymizing the user so to mitigate
congestion and latency and tour securely
without adding more bottlenecks we
propose predict or predictor is a
machine learning approach where first we
probe the network and build a training
set then we model the training set with
a machine learning model and then we
port that model to clients and then from
there clients can make future
predictions about their circuits
so in particular we deploy a trusted
Authority and this Authority builds
circuits through the Tor network and
makes connections to internet
destinations and over time they build a
training set where each data point
consists of a guard a middle and an exit
and the training label consists of the
download time we model this training set
with a machine learning model in our
experiments we did KNN and random
forests and then we port this model to
all clients via the consensus documents
each data point in the training set
consists of like I said the guard middle
and exit and from these relays we
extract features we extract the
autonomous system as a feature and
Thomas systems make up the transport
layer of the Internet
so a s as a feature would imply network
connectivity and also network location
we also extract bandwidth from the
consensus documents and we extract the
country code which is another feature
that implies location for the training
label we take the median of the download
times from the training set and if the
download time for this particular
example was greater than the median we
would label it as false meaning slow and
if it was less than the median we would
label it as true so we come out with a
binary classification task so to
evaluate the accuracy of this method we
did two experiments one on the on shadow
as a simulation and one on live tour
shadow is a discrete time event
simulator that allows us to simulate a
scaled-down version of the Tor network
on
one machine so he simulated 1,000
clients 400 relays and 70 servers and we
built a training set by first building
paths through the Tor network using tors
bandwidth weighted protocol and
downloading files of 320 kilobytes and
so for one simulation and we built a
training set of 120,000 streams then we
ran another simulation with a new seed
and built trade a testing set of 25,000
streams on the Live Tour Network we
deployed a a server and hosted 20
instances of Tor and we built passed
through the Tor network and we connected
to a u.s. destination server and
downloaded a file of 80 kilobytes and
over the course of one hour we built a
training set of 50,000 streams and then
over the course of the very subsequent
hour we built a testing set of 20,000
streams so by fitting this data training
data with KNN we were able to predict
whether or not the circuit was fast or
slow with 70% accuracy on the shadow
simulation and 64% accuracy on live tour
but when we fit the data with the random
forests we were able to predict it
whether or not it was faster slow with
76% accuracy on shadow and 70% accuracy
on live tour so based on these results
we used random forests in our predict or
implementation so to evaluate predictor
we implemented it in the Tor source code
and we tested on shadow and on live tour
and we compared it with Taurus bandwidth
weighted selection which we call vanilla
we compared it with congestion aware
routing car and Slater and Borissov path
selection with the tunable parameters
set to 9 and also with the tunable
parameters set to 15 the figure on the
right shows a CDF of download times from
our shadow experiment for all the tested
path selection algorithms we observe
that predictor improved performance by
23 percent compared to vanilla in the
meeting case and by 13 percent compared
to car in the meeting case this resulted
in a speed-up of over 500 milliseconds
in the median case for download times
and by over 1.5 seconds in the 90th
percentile we also note that SB 9 and SP
15 had the slowest performance even
though their relay selection was tuned
heavily towards bandwidth the figure on
the right here shows our live torrent
results and it's a CDF of download times
for the tested algorithms and we observe
that predictor had an improvement of
improved performance by 11% compared to
vanilla in the meeting case and by 6%
compared to congestion of our routing
and this resulted in a speed-up of over
1 second in the 90th percentile we also
noticed that SB 9 + SB 15 had the worst
or the slowest performance even though
they were heavily weighted towards
selecting nodes with high bandwidth so
this figure shows a CDF of consensus
bandwidth for circuits that were created
on Live Tour experiment for all of our
test algorithms and we observed the SB 9
created circuits with 22% more bandwidth
compared to vanilla and SP 15 created
circuits with 97% more bandwidth
compared to vanilla so this indicates
that relays with high bandwidth
experienced long-term persistent
congestion due to tors bandwidth
weighted selection policy and that even
if one client heavily weights their note
their selection towards these nodes they
will experience poor performance
compared to vanilla this also indicates
that performance gains in predict or are
not solely attributed to bandwidth even
though bandwidth is one of the key
features that we select some of the key
findings this figure on the right is a
CDF of the percent of circuits that each
relay was selected for for the path
selection algorithms and it indicates
relay utilization and this was done on
our shadow simulation we found that SP 9
and SP 15 utilized 50% of the tor
network and they ignored the other 50%
of relays with lower bandwidth we also
observed that vanilla utilized 60
five percent of the network and ignored
the other 35 and predictor had the best
load distribution and it utilized
eighty-five percent of the network even
though some of those relays probably had
lower bandwidth some other key findings
from our live Tour experiment we measure
the circuit distance taken as a
measurement using GPS coordinates from
the guard to the middle and also from
the middle node to the exit node GPS
length of a circuit is not a measurement
of latency but it can be an indication
of latency so we measured circuit length
for vanilla and for predict or in our
life to experiment and we found that the
predictor built circuits that were 680
kilometers shorter compared to vanilla
in the meeting case so we conclude that
predictor performance gains are due to
avoiding nodes with persistent
congestion also due to better real a
utilization and load distribution and
also because predictor builds circus of
shorter Geographic distance so to
evaluate the security of predictor we
looked at the literature and we looked
at anonymous metrics in the literature
for an annuity and we found that entropy
based metrics do a good job of measuring
anonymity in the average case but they
tend to fail for the special case or for
the worst case we also looked at all or
nothing compromise and it is a good
measurement of anonymity once clients
become compromised but it leaves a blind
spot in which we don't know the state of
anonymity until the client has been
compromised
the Amero framework was closest to what
we needed and we modified it so that it
would consider any number of clients
connecting to any number of destinations
using any user model we also modified it
so that it would measure the client
location leakage based on the relays
that the clients select so this end
limited metric we proposed is called
classy it stands for a client AAS
inference and class II is a challenge
response game similar to the inoa
framework the adversary is given a path
simulator that consists of any
of clients connecting to any number of
destinations and the adversary gives the
path simulator to the Challenger and the
Challenger uses it to generate one path
P Prime in this diagram and they remove
the clients from this path and then they
send the path back over to the adversary
and the adversary uses its path
simulator along with classification a
classification method to predict the
location of the the user then the
adversary sends the location back to the
Challenger and the Challenger compares
so for the classification model used by
the adversary each data point consists
of a guard a middle and an exit and we
extract features from those relays we
extract the a s the bandwidth and the
country code and it also contains the
destination and we extract the a s in
country code from that as well and the
training label is set to equate to be
the client a s so after running several
simulations we get a probability of the
adversaries ability to be able to guess
the clients a s correctly and if the cut
if the adversary can do no better than
randomly guessing then the epsilon in
this equation should be near zero but if
the adversary has some advantage in
guessing the clients location then the
epsilon in this equation will grow and
so we use epsilon in this equation as a
metric to measure what we call sender a
s leakage so to evaluate the security of
predictor we measured sender a s leakage
for vanilla car and predictor and we
found that sender a is leakage for car
was higher than predictor and vanilla
and this is interesting because car
clients make round trip time
measurements from their specific
location in order to select circuits so
class II was able to indicate that these
clients may be losing some information
about their location by selecting
circuits that way and that's an
indication that you wouldn't get using
an entropy based metric or a time to
first compromise metric we also observe
that vanilla and predictor had similar
send their aunts leakage and this also
makes sense because in predictor we port
the same model to all clients and
therefore all clients build circuits
exactly the same similar to vanilla to
further evaluate the security of
predictor we did on the an entropy based
metric called uniformly degree and we
found that predictor had slightly less
uniformity degree than vanilla predictor
had came in at 0.79 and vanilla was
measured at 0.8 for in conclusion
predictor or performance gains as we
observed are attributed to avoiding
congestion because it has better load
distribution and also because it builds
shorter circuits predictor security
evaluation we know that we saw that
predictor had similar center a leakage
compared to vanilla and slightly better
compared to car and we conclude by
saying predictor had the best security
performance trade-off compared to both
vanilla and congestion aware routing in
our experiments thank you and I'm
pleased to answer any questions you may
have
[Applause]
hi quick quick question do your TCP
connections get out of slow start did
you how can you I can't hear you can see
your TCP connections ever get out of
slow start the file that you're using is
only 320 kilobytes and I noticed that
download times are really short they're
like you know four seconds most speed
tests run for at least fifteen seconds
okay so the download times I put here
wasn't the real data I just entered in
time so then the listener could get an
idea for what we're measuring yeah so my
question though is did your download
test run and run long enough for the TCP
connections to get out of slow start
because the differences are so small
that it it looks to me that you might
actually just be measuring the effects
of slow start on a high latency path so
I was just wondering do you get out of
slow start I think we'll have to have to
talk to you later about that because I'm
not sure how to answer that
so okay hello um I'm just wondering it
looked to me like you were testing
predict or in an environment in which
everybody else is using some other
circuit selection mechanism do you have
any idea of what it will look like if
most people or most clients are using
predict or will you when it's in a sense
is competing with itself or other
instances of the algorithm for for
selecting circuits yes that's a good
question thank you in our shadow
simulation we were able to simulate how
the system responds when all clients use
predictor in the shadow simulation but
in the live tour simulation we can only
deploy one client so those results were
with one client using predictor and all
the other clients using towards vanilla
bandwidth awaited selection so though so
maybe this came up somewhere in this
security evaluation but I wonder how a
small collection of colluding modes
could try and modify the probability
that a circus chosen entire
through them and whether you thought
about that and how predict or might
impact that can you repeat that I
couldn't hear you I'm sorry if there's a
small collection of colluding nodes and
they try to induce a circuit to be
formed entirely through them so they can
decrypt the traffic it's not clear to me
how predict all would change those
probabilities I change how easy it is
for a small group of nodes to break the
system in this fashion well all I can
say is that we deploy a trusted
Authority and so we assume that that
authority is trusted and that an
adversary doesn't have the ability to
modify the input there to follow up on
the previous one I do think that though
you know if you know you're in a circuit
with all of your friends which you would
you can like whether or not you're being
measured or not you can be faster or
slower you can at least slow down in the
other cases but the question I had was
about stale stillness of the data and
how so you you in your cases you would
you did your measurements and then you
you did your test set immediately after
do you have any idea on how often you'd
have to remeasure and retrain and how
that would compare the existing kind of
bandwidth measurement sort of load
that's on the network yes that's a good
question we this was basically our first
attempt we measured for one hour and
then tested for one hour on the lab tour
Network so we don't know what how the
system will respond if we varied those
parameters but that would be a good area
to continue the study great talk very
clear and easy to understand I think
that's evident by everyone asking yellow
questions um first I'd like to commend
you on using shadow I think it's
important that people use standardized
tools who helps other institutions and
researchers compared the results to
yours and to reproduce the results of a
good job with that
thank you the question I have is your
experiments you were downloading the
same size file across your experiments
320 kilobytes in shadow and 80 kilobytes
on the Live Tour network that's correct
I'm wondering if youth if you can
comment on if you change the size of the
file at your downloading how that would
your machine learning algorithms if we
change the size the file we would have
to instead of taking the time to last
byte we'd have to take the time to first
byte and then the file size shouldn't
shouldn't matter so you think you would
get the same predictive power by using
the time the first byte as time too the
reason I ask is because I run tor relays
and I've noticed that we see highly
dynamic data on our relays depending on
if we happen to be part of a circuit
from a BitTorrent client at that point
in time so I think especially in the
shadow case having everyone download 3
into 20 kilobytes you're gonna get a
very similar set of background traffic
which is going to be reproduced almost
every time you run the experiment so
that might change a little bit but we
can talk more after ok so I just had a
question I wanted to say great talk and
if I'm not mistaken your tor clients
were in the United States and wasn't the
authority that was doing the machine
learning also based out of the United
States for its measurements in that
particular case we for the results I
showed here but the authority was
deployed in the United States but then
there's other results additional results
in the paper where we deploy the
authority we did some experiments with
the authority in the United States and
then we also did some with in Germany
and also in Japan so if you look further
in the paper I think you'll see a little
bit more diversity in there in the
results I hope I answered your questions
clearly if not please come talk to me
later thank you