hello everyone my name is Ben grass I'm
from the food sexism security research
group in Amsterdam and I'm going to talk
about teal bleep deserve this is a side
channel attack that is just like
Stepford was saying in a totally
different way able to bypass cache
defenses so we know from from experience
and from if you went to the talk they're
probably more examples but this morning
I saw this data talk which using by
collecting traces that by new zoo it
turns out that even today Kappa graphic
algorithms are still implemented using
these by accidentally doing secret
dependent memory accesses right and it
turns out it's just very hard to
implement these cryptographic algorithms
in a completely constant time totally
secret independent kind of way so what
we would really like is to have these
completely generic cache defenses like
Stefan was saying you so that you don't
have to control what the compiler does
yet have to control for what the
microarchitecture does or even worse
predict what these things will do in the
future and generically deploys defense
and still be safe against such a context
now of course we would like these
another there have been many cache
defenses proposed and what I'd like to
talk about in this talk is well if you
do that then there are still other macro
objects to resources that are shared
between hyper threads that can keep
still cause problems and let's look at
one of these so for this talk I'm gonna
look but at sorry channels in general
cache tags in particular how tl bleed
fits into that and what that means for
us and how it works Oh better than that
okay so cache structure so sorry
channels in general I like this visual
you can the idea of side channels is
that you kind of abuse how the system
works to leak secrets from that system
so if you're very early safes had this
vulnerability that you could hear with a
stethoscope these tumblers ticking in
place one by one so you can break the
combination one
instead of all at once there was a
massive effort saver if you want to
break safes and I'm going to use the
same example that Stefan was using in
the cash world we have we have very
similar phenomenon you and in this case
a EST double zero so Stefan was talking
about all you can attack this using
primary probe I'm going to use the
freshman flush and reload example not
our work of course as you will know but
just to set the stage just to set the
scenery a yes implications using t2 if
they use tea tables that means that we
do secret dependent accesses as you can
see here the index in the tea table is
the Czar of a plaintext byte and a round
key byte and that means that if we can
find in the cache when and where these
excesses happen we have a very strong
correlation between the plaintiffs by
the bus process and the cache line that
was active so we can deduce the Playtex
byte
therefore deduce the key this is a
diagram from the cloak paper which is a
project that proposes a generic cache
defense that we're going to talk about
so here's another example that we're
going to show you a trace of this is the
non side channel proof version of the
Lib G cube ACC point scalar
multiplication function and as you can
see in the last two lines the execution
is strongly dependent on the secret
value the secret value is scalar and
that's only if the scalar is one did we
do the add function now so I don't want
to misrepresent Lib G crypt here there's
a different side of the bench which is
more side so we're going to talk about
that later and an even newer version
which is even more so channel proof but
part of the story is showing well
there's this considers there's like this
cat and mouse getting going on from the
Crippler implementers versus attackers
and every time one side makes a step the
other side makes an even clever step so
there's this that is kind of a
motivation for well let's have generic
defense so we don't have to rely on this
winning this cat-and-mouse game so how
this might look in the cache is this so
we have the the blue signal is if the
scalar is zero which is only duplication
and the green signal is when the scalar
is one which is duplicate
and add so you can see there's a huge
difference in the cash activity
so let's align if you align them both
you can see this so that there's a
duplication and the if the thing is if
the scatter is zero and there's the
addition if the scalar is one comes
after it right so you can see that this
pattern is very very different if you
could pick up on this pattern you can
deduce the secret secret key bit so one
version later we see that the version
changed into this which is one just
unconditionally just do it both all the
time let's just unconditionally do the
duplication I conditionally do the
addition and multiplication I mean I
mean addition sorry
and then well look at the cash trace now
no matter if the scale of it is zero or
it's one in both case you see we see
exactly the same cash trace rise well if
you look very carefully if the bit is
one right at the end in the green when
when the trace is green right at the end
we see a little more activity bloom
there see so if you look carefully that
becomes clear on this trace at the end
we see glint just a little bit more and
that's the conditional use research of
the results because we only want to use
the the duplication the multiplet the
addition result if the scalar is one and
that last little glitch that you see is
the conditional using of the result so
that this code is much more side-channel
proof than the first version but there's
still like this little imperfection
that's there and can be exploited so it
wouldn't be nice if we didn't have to
worry about all that so let's look at an
example of Defense uses that uses Intel
TSX I'm gonna explain that quickly so
Intel TSX is this a very nice feature
which allows you to have memory
transactions and so what that means is
that you can start a transaction do a
bunch of stuff in memory and either then
committed or abort it and because of how
that works the whole transaction must
fit in the cache because as soon as the
data goes to ram there's no way to undo
anymore of course so that also means
that the transaction will automatically
abort if someone else is playing with
their cache too much so if someone else
is doing cache attack causing the
evictions the transaction will
now we can exploit that property the
cloak paper exploit this property
exploits this property as an example of
the cash defense by saying well if you
can do a flushing road to take on ast
tables but then if we then and that
works we can show that if we wrapped the
they of course they show that if they
wrap the cryptographic operation in the
transit TSX transaction then flushing
really doesn't work anymore and the
signal is destroyed so all in this just
an example there may as Stefan said
there are many other examples of generic
cash defenses which which work like this
or have this result so it might be very
tempting to conclude all cash attacks
are solved now so from the reign of this
talk I'm going to talk about the TLB and
how because it's also a shared resource
between hyper threads we can do very
similar things with it will be in the
unit or job but there's some
complications to it we we don't know how
it works exactly
we have to figure out lots of these
properties before we can mount a
realistic attack but turns out that's
possible so let's look at how that works
so the TLB is also a shared structures
like this translation cache then well
what do we have to find out about it so
we know from documentation it's not
documented but not everything is
documented or is documented is that we
have to they're the two layers to it
level 1 level 2 level 1 is partitioned
into instruction translations and and
data translations and we have layer 2
which is much bigger and much much a
little bit slower just like Stefan was
saying and that's so there's this
hierarchy to it but what's not
documented is the structure so maybe
maybe this TLB is not just a big pool of
translations because you know it could
be very big style I guess 15 or 36
entries and it's kind of likely that
there's come some kind of structure to
it just like Stefan was saying we could
this thing isn't likely to be
partitioned into sets so let's see if
that's true or not so is this thing just
one big pool or are there partitions
that are called set so for to look at
this to analyze this we use
until performance calendars which tell
us do we get til be hits
how many till be hits and how many still
be misses do we have and we use these
counters to measure the result of
accessing the particular set of virtual
pages thereby also of course accessing
translations in the TLB we use them
those weirdoes counters to measure the
effects of the success of the
translations when we access a bunch of
pages and many many times and if we then
what we expect is that we if we keep
doing it over and over if we have misses
will see the number of missions go up
and up and up and if we don't have any
misses then the number of misses will be
almost flat so what we what we try is
that well let's just assume for for now
that there's this linear structure that
will be there are a certain number of
sets and each sets have a certain has a
certain size we call that ways so let's
try all combinations of sets and ways
and for the and for now assume that
whenever I have a virtual page if I have
a page 0 then that translation will be
stored in two TLB set 0 if I have page 1
it'll be stored until be set 1 and if I
have 16 sets then page number 16 will be
again stored in set number 0 in the till
B so sort of this totally linear
Pleasant round-robin mapping just have
to be true but turns out that is true
for l1 so what we see here is that we
need at least well this says 4 but so
what we need at least 5 entries 5
elements to cause any evictions
whatsoever and that points to a set size
of 4 and the smallest stride size of the
smallest number of sets that I get that
I that I need to cause any evictions is
16 so that tells us that this a one
detail B has 16 sets and four ways okay
so we repeat this experiment for l2 and
we find that it's more complex sometimes
it's not always more complex but in the
case of skylight which we try first it
turns out you have to look at more bits
in the virtual
in the virtual address in the in the
page number you have to absorb the next
higher seven bits after of course the 12
bit offset so nobody talks about the 12
bits offset because it's all about pages
right so the next 7 bits up we take then
the next 10 bits up again we take make
sure those two together and those form
the the slot number or the set number
from 0 to 127 in the case of skylake in
the case of board well it's 256 entries
and we use 8 bits in their
transformation
that's sort of a hash function if you
will can be represented by this matrix
if you put the the page number into this
matrix and then multiply 2 modulo 2 then
you get the slot number so now that we
know the exact structure of the of the
TLB can we tell whether the till B's are
shared or not because that's sort of the
point of this experiment can we see any
activity from the sibling hyper thread
so what we try is that we assemble this
experiment where we access just one
complete set of l1 detail B so that
means that what we axis over and over
and over again and as long as nothing
else happens we don't see evictions
because it fits and if we try all
combinations of set 0 to 15 on one
thread and 0 to 50 on the other thread
which all possible combinations of what
we expect to see if the structure is
shared is that if I touch set 0 here and
since 0 is there there then I get
eviction and otherwise not much so what
we see here is that there's evidence of
sharing of the l1 detail be in of the
between 2 hyper threads ITIL be not so
so apparently I to be partitioned and
the DS will be is shared so that means
that we can spy on some kind of activity
most likely of data access that accesses
that yellow thread is doing but not code
access which is kind of a shame because
code is a bit more of a natural direct
way to do these cache attacks most the
times we also find that the l2 TLB is
shared is people expect by now but
there's an interesting little quirk we
find that said 0 is not shared with set
0 on both threads but said 0 on one
thread
shared with 64 or another threat so
apparently seems like in this hatch part
in this hash function there's probably a
thread ID added in there so that zero
interferes with 64 maybe that sinister
speculation but maybe that cost form or
even even spread in the TLB slots so
here's a little summary of many micro
architectural many microarchitectures
that we tried and we glean this
properties from we find that the l1
detail bees are always shared and hash
function is always linear and always has
64 entries 16 sets in four ways ITIL B
is never shared so we don't even care
about that but it does have it became
more associative see that's quite
interesting so we got we went here from
16 sets to 8 sets with a higher number
of high awareness since became more
associative this that's a good property
and starting with well from what we see
a sky like we have this more complicated
hash function here which i think is
quite testing used to be linear
now it's absorbed okay so one more thing
that we have if you want to do this
monitoring we cannot use performance
counters because a is privileged if we
don't want to rely on that B user system
calls which is probably too slow so
let's not do that but can we rely on the
doing this monitoring by latency only so
we now that we know the structure we can
assemble l1 working sets that hit
exactly alwa and just miss l1 and hit
exactly up to and just miss out too and
then look at the histogram of latencies
that we see to decide well can we see
the difference between l1 hits and
misses and this histogram shows that
yeah we can there's sufficient
separation in this histogram that shows
that tells us yeah we'll be able to tell
the difference if we do monitoring
experiment okay now let's go back to
this case study use we want what we're
gonna try is going to try to attack two
different algorithms in this case study
one is this non side-channel proof
version of this Lib G crypts coin scalar
multiplication which is loosen assigning
operation stuff like that but we can't
use the cache signal now right because
we assume the cache defenses
deployed so we have to use the tlb
signal that means we have only 16 sets
for l1 the page granularity instead of
cache line granularity so the situation
is like more hostile to an attacker so
we have there are some of these things
to overcome if we're going to do a
successful text let's see if we can even
do that say we see that the add
operation only happens at the scalar is
1 so we want to see detect the
difference between duplicate add and
just add so let's see what that signal
looks like in the TLB so we only have 16
sets so this is what in the ER you see
that green corresponds to duplicate and
blue corresponds to add and what we were
hoping for is that one set would be
active only on green and now on blue and
ideally even vice versa so it would be
very easy to see okay I'm seeing a zero
now or I'm seeing one now but we don't
see that we see all sets are either
active all the time or never so there's
no convenient spatial separation which
makes this more complicated so let's see
what it looks like in a trace this is
the TLB trace instead of the cache trace
you can kind of see yeah and the blue
case in the green case yet it sort of
looks it looks like the same stuff I'd
find it quite hard to write a program to
see the difference between one or the
other I can sort of see a difference but
it's not gonna be straightforward so
let's see what that signal looks like
let's so let's monitor a single TLB set
and use Temple information so let's just
hope well we can we can tell from this
trace here we can tell from this trace
there's this difference in the temporal
pattern see in time we see three dots
here two dots here some kind of hoping
that we can see the difference in time
is opposed to space so let's go from
simulations to real life so this is a
real life signal TLB signal capture used
during that ECC point scalar
multiplication so here the green and
blue and blue and blue and green and
blue these things are the secret key
bits the ground truth as it were and
this is the the signal that the attacker
observes so this looks looks very noisy
so let's we apply moving average see if
we can glean little more information our
listen we see that that that the single
does look actually quite regular and you
can kind of tell the difference with
your at least with your eyeballs between
blue and greens that gives us hope still
I would find it quite hard to write a
program that can tell the difference
between blue and green looking at just
at this so we use an SVM classifier is
James Mickens here
oh hi James I'm gonna use your I'm gonna
need your catch phrase later how's that
well one of them can you guess which one
the one that doesn't explain how the
classification works but it actually
works no ok so superfast interaction STM
classifiers we have two two features
here x and y all of the green training
samples are separated from the red
training samples by this lines in real
life we have a hundred dimensional space
in our case because we have lots of
latency measurements and the SVM
classifier tries to find a hyperplane
that separates one from the other so but
turns out that this SM classifier does a
good job so we this is a miss
classification this is start of blue is
correct start of blue correct start of
green correct so not only intelligence
be mind the other it can also tell when
is it start and that's what we need to
be able to identify repeated zeros and
repeated one it turns out that can work
very reliably zero zero one zero zero
one zero in a reality that works all the
way up to 256 bits so we find this
reliability on this on this we Margaret
actually give you 500 trials we see a
98% success rate on just a single
capture that doesn't always happen so we
have some four we do but your training
samples or the training time is about
four minutes we do a single capture that
takes just a few seconds of
classification times and a small amount
of brute force this is a histogram of
how much brute force do we need moves at
the time less than 32 tries and then we
can get
right secret key and as promised we also
do well what was the whole point of this
exercise what if we do cache defenses so
we show as an example we use cats in
cash allocation technology Stefan was
saying between partition the set in the
cache in many different ways
cats partitions it by way so one process
only sees the sees one half of let's say
eight ways and the other person who sees
the other half of the egg ways and we
still see that this cache attack works
the 96% of the time so that works James
the stuff is thank you very much super
fast example of RSA so this is an hour
safe temptation all also a previous
previous version is better nowadays but
it was already hardened against flushing
reunited so we do it the this
implementation there's an unconditional
square and unconditional multiply and
then conditionally uses the result and
by swapping pointers but ko bleed can
see this signal and then out of the
thousand 24 secret key bits we recover
all the correct bits except for around
80 so that's that's a pretty good score
it's not enough to brute-force the rest
but we haven't committed the rest this
but be sure that we before into other
work cache plate I believe which as well
if you have that many of the are safe so
you could keep it you can also recover
the rest so that's also realistic attack
okay so how was this received the
Intel's reception was well yeah yeah
there is enough guidance out there to
implement perfect constant time
algorithms so we don't think this is a
problem that's that's unfortunate I
think OpenBSD as results actually
disabled hyper-threading by default on
x86 apparently I think it's officially
risky or so you see more risks in this
area that made them decide ok let's turn
off by default as a result there was
widespread media coverage so I
personally have never made logo for an
attack but the register was kind of for
this for us and I'm kind of using this
after all thank you to the register
and Wikipedia page appeared which i
think is a peculiar kind of certain kind
of badge of honor okay so this work was
done by professors at Calvary Christian
oh and Herbert will end me but no
professor some diagrams in this work
were taken from other papers I think all
of you are in the room thank you for
letting me do that so in conclusion we
find that practical reliable and high
resolution satchels exists outside of
the cache which has implications for
defenses so this work was done by these
twitter handles here's the projects page
if you are no more thank you all for
your attention
amazing any questions so let me start up
how much control do we need for your
machine learning to extract the training
because it will vary widely between
individual systems and so on maybe you
can elaborate on that okay because it
will only be as good as the training set
so you get yes yes for sure so yeah
that's a good question so what we assume
something I forgot to say what we assume
is that we know which binary the victim
is running and which microarchitecture
they're running so we didn't try
experimentally can we apply this mark
this training set to different
microarchitecture that's something we
just didn't try but I have a hunch it
matters a lot so I don't know so well we
know when you think that assumption
realistic so we familiar that what the
binary isn't worth my car keys we can
pre assemble this training set and then
apply it to our victim but we didn't try
to transfer one we are are they are
variations between the individual
systems turned over it's bound to be
right between individual systems like
the same architecture well well in our
experiments we just retrained every time
so I'm not sure I would expect not to be
that big actually but but I'm not sure
all right other questions don't be shy
folks even if the room is full
yeah go ahead while people are coming up
another question regarding the the hash
functions yes I had yes the it you did
an awesome job but in reverse
engineering go so his hash functions I
wondered what led them or let's
speculate speculation seems to be a
trendy trendy topic here as alright
let's speculate why they changed it was
it just performance or Arbor Day looking
for other things what's your hunch wow
this is from linear to absorb yep well
it's indeed speculation so my hunch is
that this might cause more even
spreading over all of the sets so that
particular sets might not be overloaded
if that happens to be right this same
the same set might be able to be active
on two different sets and adding the
which hyper sphere my bit and involving
more virtue at risk would I think have
more of a spreading effects but is it
cost-effective because X or is more
expensive to execute and then just
chopping off the bids yeah yeah so
that's a little bit again speculation
but I would guess there's a lot of so
much parallelism in computing edge
function and wanting to another stuff
that's going on I guess is hidden but
right nice speculation yeah John
Criswell University of Rochester very
nice talk thank mom one question I have
is that as far as I understand you
you're detecting which TLB entry the
victim is using and you're inferring
that through your side channel if that
is correct then would the use of large
pages by the victim potentially mitigate
this attack yeah that's a good question
I I didn't try that but I think that's
[Music]
so it'll make it harder for sure but I
think you'll see then is that all of
their signals and the different TLB sets
they will probably all be added up and
it'll be much noisier as a result so on
the one hand I think the signal will be
in there somewhere and it'll probably
possible to get at it but it'll also be
much harder maybe much less maybe less
reliable okay
thank you thank you let's thank Finnegan
[Applause]