yeah thanks for the introduction and
thanks to everyone who's still here at
the very last session of using security
yeah I'm going to talk about how to
protect your neural networks against
theft and this is joint work with Yossi
area Yossi cash it and penny Pincus who
like me are at the cybersecurity center
of peril on university Israel and
Mustafa who is at Google research so as
you all know if you followed news in the
last five years machine learning is
everywhere it is for example used I
guess I used it and authors used it to
prepare their slides you look for an
image on Google image for example right
it converts your search string into
something that a machine learning
algorithm found out for example is a cat
it's used even in products nowadays by
IBM to analyze MRI scans to find out if
a person has cancer or not and actually
as probably many of you know machine
learning algorithms are as good or even
better than doctors are doing so it's
used by media companies it's used in
attacks and defenses in terms of cyber
security for example and also as
motivation for the last talk you'll find
it a lot in modern autonomous cars so
they can find out if there's not a car
going in front of them how fast it is
and so on so this is a very quick
reminder what neural networks are I
guess most of you know but just it's
kind of a mandatory slide right so for a
for a neural network we take the we take
a certain input in this case for example
an image which is with the round one
with the red circle here
this is converted from bits and bytes
into numbers these numbers are assigned
to the bubbles on the left side which we
normally call neurons these are the
inputs on the input layer and then they
are propagated through the whole network
through all the neurons that are there
to the output layer and on the output
layer where we have the largest number
we say yeah that's what the input is for
example in this case okay there was a
picture of Ellis this also means what
I'm talking about here will be
classification because this is what new
a network task or machine learning task
classification is and what is going on
inside one of these neurons well a lot
was talked about in the last in the last
talk so we have we have the inputs that
are coming from the previous layer these
are multiplied with weights which are
learned during the training process then
summed up we apply a nonlinear function
the activation function and this gets
then assigned as the output of this
neuron which will be the input to the
next layer
so far so good this is all known to
everyone here and of course in terms of
lingo of machine learning the network is
such the configuration how many layers
you have what the activation function is
in each neuron and so on and so forth
this is normally called the hyper
parameters whereas the weights
themselves are which I learned during
the training process are called the
parameters so all these deep neural
network stuff that can do a lot of magic
nowadays comes with the caveat which is
you need a lot of data and even more in
a lot of computational power so if you
have a very very cool application
problem is you don't have the tens of
thousands of GPUs which are probably
necessary to train a neural network to
actually do this task that you want to
have it for so instead you can nowadays
actually take your label data you can go
to Google Microsoft Amazon whoever and
they provide you with cloud services
where they say give us your data and
we're gonna train it and we are going to
train your model and afterwards we're
gonna give you a model and here you go
this is gonna do for you what you wanted
to do okay so far so good but the
question is what if you want to change
this kind of
business model what if you want to say
okay give it you give this newer network
to your customers under different
clauses in the contract for example
saying you're not allowed to distribute
it further because it contains for
example intellectual property of your
company as well as just as one example
or in general you want to make it
traceable if other people use your model
that you generated at some point so the
question that we asked for this work was
can we identify a model after it has
been trained and distributed to other
people or more generally is it possible
to watermark a neural network now the
obvious problem here is that what you
want to watermark is something that is
inherently unstable right the point of a
machine learning algorithm is to train
something and to be able to retrain it
to fit it to some new application so you
can't just you know the standard
solution would be you put a digital
signature on it there you go right but
you can't do that
because there are very simple ways how
to change neural network model in a way
that it will still do the exact same
thing as before but the whole
representation is going to be different
another problem is that there's kind of
no normal form of the learn function
that you have you can't extract like the
core of what is actually going on there
which you could also use as a watermark
so in general you have neither stability
of the representation you can alter the
weights well still everything is the
same and you can also also the hyper
parameters if I want to put a watermark
into the hyper parameters I could for
example flip neurons around I could add
new neurons that do essentially nothing
and you know this would it would still
be the same model it would still do the
same thing this is a very very trivial
modification but it would defeat any
kind of algorithm that is using the
representation or a hyper parameters
therefore our idea
is to not go to their representation
directly but instead put the watermark
into the model and our watermarking
algorithm that we propose in addition to
the normal training which uses certain
training data as as plug as displayed
here we also have another set of inputs
on which we train which we call the
trigger set so here you have the regular
inputs in in this case these are images
of people pictures of their faces and
you may want to train the neural network
to distinguish Alice from Bob so you
they can use their passports at the
border control instead of having to talk
to to an officer there and at the same
time we use another set of inputs this
this trigger set but the distribution of
the images there are completely
different from what you will later input
into the neural network you know the
network will have a certain task to do
and we use we retrain it on another
input distribution which is completely
unrelated to the task and then we do
what you expect to do you will train on
the training data using the labels that
are there and you want to make the
neural network as accurate on the strain
data as possible without overfitting and
at the same time we for these for these
random these random inputs which we
chose independently of the input
distribution we choose random labels we
fix these and then during the training
process using during the watermarking
process we train the neural network to
be as accurate as possible with respect
to these randomly chosen layers by us
also on this trigger set so far so good
and if you followed neural networks you
probably remember this paper called bad
nets or if you have been in the talks
earlier today you may have been at this
you may have seen this fail framework so
there is there's a notion called
backdooring and neural network we do the
following
you put a specific
mark on the inputs and then you train
the neural network that whenever this
mark is on the inputs I will do
something completely different from what
it's supposed to do this has been
presented last year by Google Dolan
Gavitt and gark and in their example as
which you can see here you would train
the neural network whenever it
recognizes some dots on the bottom right
side of the input to say for example
eight instead of whatever is there this
may not look like a problem but if you
think you know you put you train a
neural network that is in your car
recognising stop signs and instead of
seeing the stop sign it seeds the stop
sign with a sticker and whenever there
is the sticker on a stop sign its
backdoor to think it can now go at 100
miles per hour instead of stopping this
can be a serious problem and this is
somehow related to what we are doing
right you train the neural network to do
something different from what it's
actually supposed to do so what we do in
our work first of all is to formalize
what is this idea of of backdooring a
neural network and we give also a formal
definition of what is water marking and
then we show that if you have a
cryptographic commitment scheme and you
have such a backdooring algorithm with
certain properties then you can always
build a watermarking algorithm and this
also shows that in comparison to what
the program chairs have been claiming
that you can actually get papers into
use next security that have theory in
the paper written and so there has been
related work by other researchers who
had similar ideas so I'll just talk
briefly about what they've been doing
and how our all work compares to them
there's this work by a cheetah at all
from last year and what they do is that
they embed the watermark into the
weights so they take the representation
of the neural network and during the
training they fit the neural network
to have weights such that if you
multiply them with the secret matrix the
output of this matrix product is going
to be trained by Google for example as I
said this is inherently like fixed to a
certain representation if you alter it
you may end up with the problems there's
this work by mirror at all which uses it
for serials examples where they during
the training as a watermark they use it
for several examples to shift the
decision boundary into a certain
direction and then whenever you want to
check if a watermark is there you use
this certain way of doing it for several
examples too as the generation process
for inputs where you do this we do this
watermark testing the problem there is
that they inherently rely on the idea
that you can generate at or several
examples for neural networks and I think
a lot a huge number of people in the
community are currently trying to get
rid of the problem of adversarial
examples so relying on a notion that is
that everyone tries to get away from and
push out of current neural network
design might be a bit problematic
there's the work by Ronnie at all
from this year and their ideas a bit
similar to ours so what they do is that
they take certain inputs and they train
the neural network that the outputs of
certain layers read as a fixed string
for example whenever the neural network
gets us in put a picture of Alice or a
certain picture of Alice it will display
trained by Google on one of the hidden
layers as the output of the hidden
layers and then as they work my tongue
at all which appeared at this year's
Asia CCS in June and their work is their
approaches very similar to ours they use
different ways how to choose the input
distribution they use different security
they have different security properties
they want to show for the neural network
and therefore have a different analysis
than we do
and we also talked a bit about how to
show that there's a watermark in the
model without releasing the information
that could be used to remove it I'll get
to that a bit in the end of the talk so
there are four main properties which we
want to achieve with our water marking
scheme the first one is it supposed to
be functionality preserving there's no
point of water marking something if
afterwards you can't use this anymore
right I can just generate a string that
says Carsten built this and I can say
this is my model right everyone can see
Carsten did this the problem is it's not
gonna classify anything first and then
second we want it to be unremovable so
that's a that's an intuitive thing that
you have what we demand is that the
attacker will get the model in a white
box where he can play around with the
representation whatever he wants and he
will also know exactly which algorithm
was used to make the watermark so this
is a bit like kerckhoffs principle like
assuming that the key is the security
and not the algorithm that is kept
secret there's a property called
non-trivial ownership as I said if you
know once the algorithm is public but
you kind of have to have secret keys
that are related to the watermark maybe
there would be a way that there's kind
of an uber key that can be used to you
know that is kind of a you know use you
can use it to go to every simple every
model that is around there and say this
is mine so the non-trivial ownership
property is that this is not possible
you can't generate a key which you can
use to claim ownership of other people's
networks and furthermore we want to
design the keys in a way such that if I
come with another model and I even give
you the specific trigger set you will
not be able to to use your fixed key to
claim that this is that this was
generated by you
so for the analysis if this thing is
actually secure we run experiments
and first of all there are two ways how
to how to embed such a watermark the
first is you take a train model and now
after it's after the training is done
you you take the trigger set and you
embed it the second way is that you do
the training together with a trigger set
at the same time now for me as a as a
theoretician I thought you know why
would there be a difference but later on
you'll actually see this and there's a
huge difference in how robust it is the
watermark is in comparison to which of
these two approaches you take we use as
I said before as tasks we use image
classification as training data we use
c4 Chauncey 402 Vil imagenet and we use
as the model or as the architecture that
we want to use we use resonate with 18
layers like a standard convolutional
neural network and this is the standard
like state of the art people would use
if they want to do image classification
nowadays so in in terms of functionality
preserving so does a watermark actually
harm the task that you want to achieve
it turns out no so we ran experiments
training without the watermark and with
the watermark and it turns out that the
accuracy of the neural network is almost
the same like it sometimes even
increases a bit we ran the same time we
took the same amount of training with
and without so the same number of epochs
with and without the watermark so that
it probably increases a bit is like
probably just outliers and furthermore
and we also validated that if you just
take random trigger set it's not gonna
you're and you're not training you're
your model on this then you cannot
actually claim that it's yours
so we also experimentally verify that
and concerning not being able to remove
the watermark only gonna talk about one
specific attack
but there are a few more in the paper so
what we did is we fine-tuned either only
the last layer or or all layers like
fine-tuning is a standard thing to do if
you have more training data to adapt
your neural network a bit or a different
thing is that we reinitialize the whole
last layer with random data and then
retrain the whole neural network to do
with without the trigger set again in
the hope to get rid of this trigger set
and here's what actually happened so as
you may see on the bestest this green
bar on the very right side and this is
actually the interesting thing that
happens so this is this is when you take
a pre trained model you put in the
watermark afterwards and then you you
retrain or you fine-tune the whole
network what actually happens is this
will remove the watermark completely
this was kind of unexpected for us
because at the same time if you embed
the watermark during the training it
just stays there it's the it's the
yellow bar on the left side of it it's
just it doesn't it it's it's not
bothered at all and we're I we are
having some discussions about why this
is the case but it's it's it's
interesting to see to be able to show
that the water that a that a Newland
that that a model is yours without
giving this this trigger set away is a
bit problematic and standard approach
which we also follow is to use zero
knowledge instead of just releasing it
so just as a quick reminder what is your
knowledge doing so you have Alice who
wants to prove that the model is hers so
she inputs trigger sets and labels into
the zero knowledge argument system the
verifier has the verification key in the
model and the only thing the verifier is
going to learn it's gonna be yes or no
but no other information concerning
future work as I don't have too much
time left we want to invest
to get more possible attacks on our
scheme we want to find a way how to
classify how to put it let's say a bill
on how expensive it is to remove a
watermark so we can compare different
algorithms and this kind of way of
hiding a second input distribution in a
neural network and classifying it seems
to be a good thing as with the
watermarks and the bad thing with with
the bad nets with a backdooring
so the question is can we somehow defend
against these distributions or is this
inherent in in in deep neural networks
and yeah as I said to sum up quickly I
presented a watermarking scheme for deep
neural networks which is black box in
terms of verification a in the paper
there's going to be there is a
theoretical connection to backdooring
which is also obvious from the technique
that we use in practice and we
experimentally validates the
construction that we have there and I'm
happy to take questions
I'd say there are any questions please
come to the microphone so I would like
to start by asking you what is the
threat model here so can you explain
like what what assumptions you make
about the adversaries capabilities
knowledge so the capability of the
adversary is he knows he we assumed that
he has the whole training data as well
and so what we defend want to defend
against is that he can get a model
without the watermark by using less
computation a lot less computation than
training from scratch we assume that you
can never defend against an adversary
who just makes a model himself like this
is this is a possibility that is there
and this is also kind of related to
cryptography where we assume that there
is a gap in computational power between
the attacker and and the defender and we
kind of want to model it here this is
also related to the fact that we use
commitments in our construction and when
you mix cryptography with with with this
you kind of want to also have kind of a
gap in computational power there but
there might be other ways how to model
this where the where the attacker for
example has less or has more
computational power but less less of
less access to some kind of training
data Oracle so this might be interesting
full of work thank you
so I have a question about the choice of
fingerprint oh sorry
what a mark images so I remember you
said the distribution of the watermark
images are very different from the
training center so is that the
requirement because if I'm running a
face recognition model if I see more
than our image coming I'll probably
reject it so can you use some other
faces to you to for watermark as well
what that was work it's a very good
question thank you
in our case we have not investigated
that
work at HACC s actually considers the
setting as well from for a theoretical
analysis we assume that it's a different
input distribution but in practice it
might as well be that if you have
certain inputs which are from the same
distribution you see a similar behavior
but I would assume no because you train
the neural network to on this specific
input distribution so whatever you'd
make as change to the input distribution
you will see as change in the water
market our point is that if you have
this kind of second hidden input
distribution whatever you do to the
first one is not gonna interfere with
the second one but if you rely on the
first under the like primary
distribution to begin with your
watermark is probably gonna go down the
drain but you would have to
experimentally validate this clip this
thing so I can't say more than that but
thanks good question Erik mish like lost
almost National Laboratory your results
showed that the accuracy was pretty
similar with her without the watermark
and I might have missed this but I was
wondering how training time compared
with and without the murmur to get to
those accuracies actually in our in our
case in the experiments we gave the
adversary adversary as many epochs to
retrain to fine-tune or retrain the
neural network as we used to actually
generate it with the data to begin with
for the theoretical analysis we assume
that there is a gap in between these but
for the experiments we gave them as much
power and turned out that the watermark
is still there okay so you give them
about the same amount or any time yes
hello he eats anchor form Universal
Maryland I would like to ask so you in
the evolution you show that even if a
druid tries to remove the watermark it's
not very successful what did you try
like Idris eight tries to distill the
knowledge from the original model and
trains a smaller model and distributes
that food watermark survived in that
case you mean like like doing 24
learning for example or or a
distillation except like this thing
their knowledge into smaller or
different model than the original model
so we have fine-tuning the model yeah
work or compressing the more like it
exactly yeah
I I think we ran model compression and
it didn't have an impact as far as I
remember we did we did transfer learning
where we just like went totally from to
a completely different to completely
different input data namely STL 10 and
it turned out that I mean we kind of
have to preserve the last layer because
if you train it to you know have a
thousand possible outputs as for example
for for image net right and you go to
you would do transfer learning to let's
say C for 10 or C for 100 like it's not
meaningful anymore right but let's say
you the adversary can play around with
the rest of the network as he wants
doing transfer learning it's still
significant like you like even for a
thousand outputs you still are right 60
70 percent of the time and that is that
is quite significant
concerning the other thing you were
mentioning which I forgot sorry I I am
not sure I'll I'm not a machine learning
person but I'll talk to to my co-authors
and maybe well we're gonna try it out
and see what happens