this work is the joy this is a joint
work where is the ship secure while we
can
makers of the research and UC Berkeley
and flank Fudan University today we are
going to talk about a web attacker paper
we conducted a security analysis of a
web a protocol called a course
cross-origin resource sharing which is
the user to relax the default the same
origin policy and the you neighbor
across orange in network access and
first I will look at a similar engine
policy the similar engine policy is the
foundation for client-side web secured
and it isolated resource from different
origins and under the same origin policy
Quran decides the Carib its current
sender requested to a third-party
servers but he can't read the response
so but by the way the development of a
web many applications leaders across
orange in reading permission so
developers have come up some workarounds
such as JSONP to sever the lead but the
SMT have a lot of security issues so
cross-origin resource sharing is
proposed to solve the problem of gsm p
and and is more displaying displaying
the mechanism and have been supported by
all the browser's and has been adopted
by mainstream websites today our work is
to conduct a security analysis of course
protocol and we found as a design
implementation and the deployment of
course are subjected to a number of
security issues for example an attacker
can use the cause features to hack
internet from outside or remote remotely
inference cookie presents on any website
we also conducted an Ida secure
measurement popular websites and a
founder
27% of what websites have a insecure
cause complications
we also proposal some medications and
some of them have been adopted by web
sender and major browsers today in the
clock we first introduced course pack
around and then we DTR cost security
issues including browser side issues and
server side issues then we present
course deployment in the real world
finally we discuss medications first
look at the web a background
the default is dim orange in policy I
used to race the restrictive will
prevent cross Orange in reading so but
the developers leaves the cross orange
in reading so coarsely the proposal to
solve the problem the core idea of
course is a very simple first letter
requesting websites issue a cross-site
request and the browser 42 course I'll
request browser where added
automatically added orange in header to
the requester indicated the requesting
orange and then the server returns the
access control policy to indicate the
alone orange ins the browser felony the
browser will check the requesting orange
in whether the Newcastle orange a
matches the alone dollar engine only if
a yes the requesting website can read
the response
here's a example of a course JavaScript
interface we can say that the course
interface alone is decrypted to modify
requests the method headers and bodies
this interface is very powerful and may
break
CSF depends on many websites because
many websites use custom headers to
dependency as I've attack so of course
classify
requests into two categories
simple requests and a non simple
requests a simple requests that master
satisfy all the three conditions
first the requested method is had get a
post and the request request headers a
lot customized accept online headers and
third and the content type header value
is one of a specific values for simple
requests it is considered receive
requests and it can be seen now how did
you record Levi browser for land simple
request it's a lot of covered in artwork
or you can find that eat having a paper
we studied the course design and
implementation and we found many
security issues we first we'll talk
about the browser side the issues of
course alone the gas temper request to
be sent freely by default but but it's
the scope of simple requests is the in
fact further relaxed sending permissions
allowing malicious customization of HTTP
headers and bodies and we found four
types of attacks which exported teensies
relaxed sending permissions and here we
only talk about three or four the story
of them the first one is permissible
higher values of course alone Chavez
decrypted to modify nine white had my
solicitor headers but it imposed few
limitations are the values so that means
an attacker can customize these headers
with attacking payload for example the
attacker can settle except the header to
assure shock availability payload we
tested the five major browsers and the
founder for them back to the Royal
scepter separate below go
and of course the truckies content above
header - is there a specific values but
we found the restriction can be bypassed
due to implementation floors we tested
the favo mainstream browsers and found
always their prefix match the value
three values so an attacker can studio
craft content type or hide away the
malicious content by appending attack a
pillow that were valued a value
we found that this implementation floor
alongs a web attacker to obtain a shell
on internet a server from outside by
sending cross-origin requests from
victims browser under exploited apache
secrete Apaches trust availability in
the internet here is the time of video
on the left side is the victim's browser
in the internet on the right side is a
attacker in the internet first attacker
listen on the internet server and as a
victim interacting visit a malicious
page and the attacker has obtained a
share on the internet a server and the
second problem is a few limitations and
header size course alone chai was
recovered to modify headers but it
doesn't have a limitation on how the
size we tested the fam which may major
browsers and found all them alone at
least sixteen megabytes header size
which is much larger than had a size
limitation of its servers we found as
the difference header size limitation
can be provided by a web attacker to
learn to study general tags
remotely inferring cookie presence
anywhere besides here is attack how this
attack works
to carry out this attack first the
attacker measures a henna size and
imitation of pocket websites by the
ruggedly issuing requests to a target
server and they're increasing the header
size and share receiving until receive
400 per request the response and then
the attacker send simple requests from
victims browser with the crappy values
and making sure the total header size is
slightly smaller than that hallelu
mutation had had a size an imitation of
the target server if a cuca is the
presence in victim's browser the cookie
we are automatically attached to the
requests so the total size we Argos date
the target server limitation and a 400
but by the request the response is
returned
if cuca is a lot of presence then the
target server we are returned a 200 ok
response but here's a problem here there
is a problem here in fact the attacker
cannot directly observe whether a
response code is a 200 or 400 so the
attacker leads to Jim for the response
code through timing channel 1 channel
commissioner is a response time it was
attacker issue a simple request towards
a logic fear a 200 response is a cycle
if any slower than 400 response and the
in chrome the performance protocol
entries API directly exposed whether a
request is accessible a lot the presence
of a cookie can be courage a lot of
private the private information for
example attacker can remotely
in for very mysterious conditions by
looking for visits to a particular
disease or Hospital website the
steroidal issue is flexible body values
of course alone I was recruited to
custom I'll request the bodies but
doesn't have limitation on the values so
an attacker can craft an impeller 8 800
request the body we found this ability
enable attacker to exploit a panel proto
surface service the in this case we
found that using Mac OS as a building
I prefer server Yahoo server the
attacker can craft a malicious request
making the header to be bore you can
learn by the PI server and construction
is the Bellary body for communication
with FTP server we tested five browsers
and all of them are affected here is a
demo video to show how an attacker can
create local files in victims a local
file system only if a victim they visit
a malicious page
first Oken says that there's a low fear
in current father and in the big team
visit malicious page and across orange
in requests descended to FP server and
then weakens we say we can say that a
new fear is a creator on victims a lock
of your system then we talk about
server-side
issues we we found seven types of
server-side the issues here we only talk
about three of them the first that we
look at how quote policy works for
example when I resolve when when people
become want to share data with the age
of the cam you can configure the cost
policy to be access control alone
Icom but what if people come also want
to share data with the c.com maybe you
want to specify a common service
separately the list or our engines but
actually it's a manager can provision
you in course the specification the code
policy can only be single or engine or
Nora or a way or card with so that means
the web developer have to tell Emily
generate different course policies for
different the requesting oranjee we
found this dynamic generation process is
error prone
in practice the simple is the way to
generate across policy is Prandelli
reflect orange in header but but we
found this but this configuration is
quite a dangerous because it's the
equivalent to 13 any websites and we
found in our measurement we found about
a 1 in 30 websites
habitation have made a mistake in
Coralie in some important webisodes and
we also found some web developers
attempt to validate requesting oranges
but as three armies made a mistakes here
is here is a example of over here is
example of energy configuration from
lack of follow the the resource server
try to check whether the orange in
header match match example.com or food
or calm pate de foie gras to the ending
credit we should result in trusting any
domains the prefix with the the turkey
the domain here is the example calm
likely so attacker can use the example
become able to become to read the lesson
consider resource we also found some
some important websites have a system it
take we found some other web
applications a check whether the orange
in had a value and with example to come
but this configuration is a studio
vulnerable
it actually accept any domain and the
ending waste example come including
attacking example.com which can be
rejected by attackers and we found some
websites in porn website also have this
you take the stereotype of mystic
aberration is a TPS 28 EP it will be as
is a designed to secure communication
over insecure Network so a
man-in-the-middle attack ur cannot
directly read content it should be as a
website however if a HBO abs the website
that is configured to trust the ETP
website then the man in the middle
attack ur come first hijacker hcp
website and then study our secrets
ah HPI so besides by sending
cross-origin requests and there's some
web websites also made amidst the same
mistake finally we want to understand
the real world impact of course
miscalculation problems we condemn
either we target her elegance top 15,000
or besides and extract her all over
their subdomains from a passivity as
pick up pace and the for you to stop
domain we actively probable cause the
complications in totally totally we
found four hundred thousand subdomains
are configured a course and about 27% of
them having insecure configurations so
these websites are very important web
besides a popular asset because they are
in the elegance top the fabs thirty
thousand websites so course the problem
cosmic very problem is widespread in
currently internet we reported that this
problem these problems to web standard
organization what working group and had
a discussion with authors of costs about
vacation the acceptors some of our
suggestions and amid some changes to the
specification what specifically they add
more restrictions to cost simple
requests there also ecology as in the
core specification and the regarding the
question is congregation issues this
suggested that the mr. complicated where
besides the shooter fixes it
this issues by themselves without a
change in the specification
however they agree to ask the gentian to
add a security consideration to
summarize all the mystic configuration
cases in the standard we we also
reported this problem two browsers Akram
and the Firefox browser haven't released
a patch to block the I por favor
pot every pot and I implement in the
specification changes and separ is also
testing these changes with the beta
testing program we also reported this
problem to cross frame workers we found
a turn out of eleven precursor foreign
workers having insecure caused
complications so there are many foreign
workers is also available and as some of
them have fixed this issue we also
provide an open source tool for web
developers to identify cosmic music
library issues here the screenshot of
the this tool I strongly suggest where
web developers to check out our web site
where their harvest corrector cousin
configurations the summary we conducted
an empirical study on course and
discover a lot of security issues some
of them a lot just the implementation
floors but fundamental issues in
browsers and specs we also proposed the
some medications and some of them happy
a table the power standard and a major
browsers and that's my talk thank you
[Applause]
vice nice solid work I really like
listen to it have a question so in the
beginning talk about some client-side
broader issues that this issue is only
existing cause or it also existing
WebSocket a very good question yeah
when packaging this worker we only exam
that the course I'm not sure whether
it's properly existed a socket maybe
maybe I haven't tried that yeah yeah
maybe that is the CUDA research question
maybe we can find it
Yes Mother from University boohoo so I
also think most of those clients insects
they actually just not much ours people
nothing to do with course and first of
all nice write-up
but all the seven attacks you published
you probably remember James Koepp he
published two years ago all of them and
also I think a large-scale evaluation of
the election million was done I think we
published them one year ago so so my
question is nice right now but what
section you on your what is your major
contribution that hasn't been published
before what is the contribution to this
paper okay yeah yeah yes yes yes some
some form is chemically induce some some
of their some web developers have have
found some issues but there is a low
empirical study a comprehensive study on
the cost protocol uh and we found some
new security issues in browsers and
assets and we also and it all had to be
realized by Qwest specification and I
talked to the by major browsers I think
yeah
yeah also I guess that's the question
for the review is not the author one
question about the insecure
configurations so I've also noticed this
at some point and I saw that some sites
will give you a reflected origin and
access control credentials true but only
if you're not logged in and they they
send a different course header once you
are logged in did you did you check
those at a click
take a look at sites where you could log
in and see if there's a difference
between the course headers being
delivered when you're not logged in
versus when you are logged in yeah yeah
that's how cool a collision yeah yeah
but in this you know our measurement we
only check the users are locally yeah
yeah maybe maybe we can do more research
on how to measurement the cost
complications with the credentials it
would be interesting to understand if
there is a difference because I found
some sites that seem to be vulnerable
and then you logged in and this course
policy changed it was normal yeah yeah
yeah yeah yeah but but is the ask there
are many well besides belabor that
doesn't change their core policy yeah
thank you yeah okay last thing the
speaker again