I'm budging from - hi northie since for
joining us in this chalk today we are
going to
talk about a threat in the ass the
hidden deception of the DNS resolution
pest where focus on how it works and
performer Merman study of this hidden
behavior some poster issues that as PDS
reserved met health security problems as
the solution instead users often trust
popular Public DNS resolvers because
they are good services and security such
as Google Public DNS however have you
ever measured when use Google TS as your
reservoir your query may be answered by
somewhere else what if your DNS requests
get intercepted on the web and handled
by other reservoirs that you don't even
know what source when they give you the
responses they pretend to be Google and
make you trust them
so this visual record Corinthians
interception request intercepted on the
web and IP spoofing
is performed for Mac video next who
would potentially intercept audience
queries we can firstly sink off in Essos
provider their mid box in the network
cable family besides other devices such
as Perl and your software and interprets
proxy are also potential interceptors
for example a one software provider
default on functionality names qts this
functionality makes it was redirect
audience requests from concept to a was
the answer well equipped channel and you
know we still do not comprehensively
understand this kind of hidden stretch
so to start this stretch in our work we
merely want to answer two questions the
first one how to globally measure the
hidden gains interception and techni one
what has the characteristics of this
hidden behavior okay now let's take a
look at the strength model we
approximately request two popular Public
DNS resolvers and discuss how they are
intercepted so normally where client
shows to you
Public DNS or is our request where we
share the specify reservoir so some
unpatched devices but some devices may
manipulate the Peggy's and redirect
against requests to alternative
reservoirs which does rest our work and
get a response normally and finally
before the response is sent back it's
also a IP addresses is fruit so your
request to adjusted Public DNS shall be
answered by somewhere else that you
don't know and it is also quite hard to
detect from client side because of
Abby's approval according to our
observations from the view of
authoritative nameserver
we classified the DNS resolution passed
into four categories
the first one is standard normal
resolution without inception a constant
the DNC request to a packet es and it
only reaches us Viceroy reservoir from
the wheel of name server instance only
one request from the create public IDs
the second case is called request
redirection a constantly request to a
party with es but it is then redirected
to our turn T reservoir not reaching the
public D s so in this case the specified
party s is completely removed from the
DNS resolution process and from the view
of name server it is this only one
request from the alternative reservoir
the third cast request with application
them as euro that's a request to a
public des however this time the request
is rubric added one reaches of courage
public IDs and the other one which are
currently resolved from the nem slower
it will receive two identity requests
from different IP addresses of course
the contrary still two responses as well
and typically it will it will accept the
first one the last case is direct its
body it is similar to request a
redirection the alternate here is our
handles the dense query but it does not
really perform a query to nemser
and directly return an answer to the
client but incredibles of course and
from the name server it resumed nose in
the next part
how can we detect and mirror this hidden
interception record that in each of four
kinds of dance resolution passed the or
searcher name server since the answer
requests come from different reservoirs
so to detect the interception within the
answer request to specify public IDs
reservoir from clients and check on also
to also rotating them several words
against requests come from if they are
come from the create public yes then
there's no interception
otherwise if within the DNS requests
come from other reservoirs then the DNC
request is intercepted and sweat so
master is quite simple at Haleiwa we
need to collect large scale when she
points generate games request Amazon and
click the corresponding games request
our name server however just like we
cannot put elephant into a real frigid
at is it these three simple steps each
poses us to change the first one how to
collect 20 points in this story we need
global ones dew points they have to be
ethically or courage largest goal and
the worst most importantly
Institute allows to send the ants
request to any IP addresses we want like
Google das in purse dairies
in spite of different PS Mirman care
from a device they cannot be directly
used in our story for example Chelsea
boob Adams advertisement Network and
Illuminati proxy Network only allows the
neediest request to fix local reservoirs
so they cannot be used ok to address
this challenge we design two phases of
merriment the first phase is called
global analysis where we use the proxy
drunk to collect once two points proxy
drunk is a ribbon model best stocked for
residential proxy networks it allow us
to send the ants request to any IP
addresses whence that
submit audience requests to the
superproxy the DNC requests were exited
from large scale residential not in
different countries currently almost
audience traffic is over UDP but this
network only establish TCP traffic so
this visit can only describe a big
picture of the hidden yes interception
problem to get more Frank grunts data we
design another phasor measurement here
we implement our Mariner school into a
network debugging model of a popular
security software the debugging model is
quite similar to net eliezer and allow
us to generate traffic está Claro so we
can send more towers dance packets from
this onesie points our collected kinds
are manually located in China so this
phase is is named Chan white announces
yo start we take Altima scare - potato
users purnsley and security to address
it ethical issues we use the follow-up
purchase to get granted permission from
clients like one-time consists at
instead from user also yesterday only
the immediate requires allowed man are
collected without any post data the
technic Challenger is what the hood
requests share isn't to comprehensively
understand the characteristics and the
inception policies we should generate
against requests as diverse as possible
so here are some field that we supposed
the Interceptor may consider taking one
video from each field a dense query is
generated particularly we consider three
framers Public DNS resolvers according
to led to their arrest Jeffrey flanken
and we also build a cell phone list no
ideas for completion study we consider
five can out different tests
the answer is social type and we'll just
fold my names on the different Audi's
toward atom and we catched by recursive
against reservoir we stuff for Unicode
perfect into our domain name besides we
use a lot of tricks to adjust our
experiment
and you married a pepper for details and
now the third challenge how to identify
us IP addresses or pop-ups first our
explain what a u.s. IP is in large
public dns resource we often used any
caste IP addresses to be reached like
the code edge however in the background
loading pensee distribute DNS requests
to multiple reservoirs were they used us
happy to talk to our also telling them
server so from our name server we need
to know if this IP addresses belong to
the public ETS if it's not than the
liveries not then there's an
interception to solve this problem we
leverage the speaker and also recover
the hello are there is that the DNC
recorder can reply the function
functionality of the IP addresses that
used by pop-ups services so from each IP
addresses that talk to our name server
we first perform is reversed yes lookup
then we purest SOA resolution dependence
of this route is found in the domain
name if particular second-level demands
person in the in the dependence chain
where is regarded this IP addresses at
the u.s. IP of the public dns services
now i've stolen all those changes we are
able to collect towers yes requests from
West Point always watch our 107th
current allocating more than 170
countries and thus results as numbers
due to the timing limitations in the
rest of this chalk
our user is out less we collected by our
debug control
40s inception announces family here some
result of our interception announces we
are fruits down
characteristics of the PN's interception
and influences and DSO look up performs
also we perform analysis on the DNS
response manipulation and scooby stretch
finally we discussed the potential
motivations behind the BS interception
and any solutions
first in the landscape of the
interception in total 259 s that we
inspect existing yes interception
behavior when we classified the
intercepted Li requested by conch we
find that the responding is really exist
this is because the response is clearly
incorrect
and it is easy to identify also request
the redirection is much preferred than
request replication breakdown two
different reservoirs we find the request
to one know Public DNS services are more
likely to be intercepted especially for
the Google Public DNS we found in China
up to 28% year request over UDP from
clients intercepted by contrast only 10%
of DNC requests to the least popular
Ethiopia's are intercepted zoom in to
the top s with most our audience chorus
we conclude that the interception
policies can be complex and vary among
networks in all this for s reach out
your request request redirection is
higher than request replication
especially for the last days of Chang mo
back or 45% a request I redirected
however even between 2 s of the China
Mobile the interception policies are
also quite different as reflected by the
rate of replication in this s networks
the alternative is there were actually
located in the same s at the kind the
next question we asked was the hidden PS
interception it is designed for DNS
lookup performs improvement here we use
the long trip time at the indicator of
these lookup performance this is a
community of distribution of don't
repeat emergency request with each tab
in different colors
compared to the current life which is
normal resolution
request the replication does receive
better performs however the request with
Direction very uncertain effect also it
is quite interesting that the long trip
time distributions are requesting the
direction
and your christening request to local
reservoirs our similar besides for your
placated request we want to measure
whereas the original one or the
replicated one is first so it compares
the rural time at our name server this
graph shows the time differences between
the two requests in this s we can see
that in most asked replicated requests
are first then the can't pass however we
still find the interesting S which is
belong to China Telecom group with all
really Kelly request a lag behind we
suppose this can be accomplished by the
interception devices in this network
next part response manipulation yo test
touch we found hundreds of the estuary
radios a temporal Biden's interception
after manually analysis the temporary
spawns
we find the follow calcifications
including traffic Galloway illegal
traffic monetization and miss conviction
for instance our our somehow our
theories with results are tempered by
our adult husband web page this website
is belong to China mobile group and for
promoting our mobile application now of
this results would skew the stretch
medians interception porn definitely
let's go concerns as we mentioned at the
beginning because of IP spoofing it is
difficult for users to detect
interception so they may not be aware
this kind of hidden behavior also the
security of alternative reserve can be a
problematic which has 200 and therefore
open alternative reserves that we fund
and fund only 43 awesome attempt against
their queries
what's worse among them or Azure data
using magic have a software world that
should be deprecated before 2009 this
makes them a worn ball forwards attacks
so why are they intercepting audience
queries we performance metrics way on
winders and stop the
platforms that provide this
functionality the first camp that the
Indians interception is for improvement
in security however which shows that the
alternative is over Malik's guilty and
the request to war no party ideas are
more likely to be intercepted the
technical division became it is to
improve dance performance we show that
by replicating games request doesn't
improve the DNS lookup performance but
we request the direction very uncertain
in fact funnily unless those provider
would like to reduce traffic exchange
among networks by redirecting yes
traffic this can be satisfied after
offline meeting with yes killed him of
one large Chinese Internet service
provider this multi variant is confirmed
to solve this problem we believe the key
point is to authenticate that the
reservoir that we are using but if the
moments do have a long way to go we
based our observations with provider
online chicken to have in the user to
detect Internet's in Inception fundly a
proof summary of this talk by detecting
and Marion's interceptions with provider
understanding of this hidden behavior we
click clients from more than 3000 s
number and defined over 250 s that exist
in Inception behaviour especially we
find in China up to 28 percent of the
answer you question to Google yes
intercepted also this behavioral print
security concerns funny we discuss the
movie William behind the dancing
deception and release the online chicken
- in the meantime we are moving forward
or outcome projects and try to identify
different kind of interceptors thank you
so much for attention and I am happy for
any questions
[Applause]
hi Dave Levin University of Maryland
nice talk cool study you mentioned that
you were able to study UDP and TCP did
you notice a difference in the number of
redirected or questions in this talk
you're the communications I only chose
the UDP but the TSP the participate also
merrily out pebble the result is that
compared to the compared to the UDP
protocol the guest package that over TCP
received much much detour in the
interceptions but it still happen like
were there some guesses that just didn't
do any TCP interception they just did it
less often that's all then let's open
I would they still do it yeah yeah yeah
people so you've married our pair of
things thank you rob janson US Naval
Research Lab I'm wondering so you use
the proxy rack I wonder how many vantage
points you had from that sorry how many
vantage points were available in the
proxy rack system
medias millions yeah million okay I was
gonna ask if you considered using ripe
Atlas because they also have but they'll
have millions of vantage points but
sorry did you consider using ripe Atlas
I pity did you consider using ripe Atlas
which is a measurement system that
provides
oh no no okay
thank you for your talk I have a meta
question do you think China will allow
DNS over HTTP when when that starts
getting deployed to solve this do you
think China will allow DNS over HTTP the
dope standard a very good question we
have we have actually we have under
projects that studies problem it helps
say but we are interesting at it
good question
and now that still have five minutes
thank you