taking advantage of the asymmetric
benefits of cyber capabilities to focus
their operations and use that power we
can identify their motivations unique
techniques and targets and this gives us
a better understanding of the global
threat picture for the blue teamers
hopefully you'll be able to gain some
information that might help you improve
your threat modeling and may give you
something that you ask your red team to
emulate next engagement for the red
teamers hopefully you pick up some some
interesting tips there's a lot of cool
campaigns out there that we get to learn
about so let's go a little bit by myself
my name is Yoshi I do healthcare cyber
intelligence have some certs beef I got
my background in political science which
is what I really enjoy the geopolitical
aspect of threat intelligence used to be
with the FBI about until 2019 and now I
work in healthcare so feel free or
follow me on Twitter so when we talk
about for intelligence there are a lot
of models to start talking about hey
what is an adversary and what you like
to do how do we classify them how do we
cluster them my favorite and one of the
older ones is the diamond model so when
we see the diamond model we start first
on the left angle and that's the
infrastructure so when we talk about
infrastructure we mean everything from
the email accounts that are used for to
send phishing emails we mean the command
and control IPS possibly the domain
registrations and all of that so that's
sort of what we mean when we talk
infrastructure so when we talk victim
I think victims more diverse than people
think
first off at a big level means country
what countries are targeted how do they
relate to the geopolitical things going
on second a little lower down would be
what industry started targeted are they
targeting healthcare or they targeting
aerospace are they targeting any
specific vertical that may be a
requirement for a nation-state
little lower down would be okay what
information at each of those tell me
he'll be going for and then drilling
down even more what people are talking -
are they talking - and fishing the
customer advocates the company are they
talk of a fishing of doctors researchers
so that's sort of how we get fine-tuned
into that victim part of the diamond
model as well that next we have
capabilities so capabilities I like to
use the attack matrix with capabilities
because I think it gives a really good
way of giving a objective view of
capabilities and they say hey this actor
did these three different techniques and
those fall into their capabilities
obviously attack doesn't cover
everything especially for some of those
more advanced techniques but it does a
really good job and finally looking at
adversary depending on who you're
talking to order you're working for
adversary changes so sometimes it means
who is the human behind the keyboard
who's the person that's actually typing
those commands and exfiltrating that
data sometimes it might be the
organization that they work for is it a
front company is it an intelligence
organization and then or is it not the
organization that's actually doing the
hacking but is there a customer of a
government that's requested that hey we
want airline down okay well who's asking
those requirements and that fits into
the adversary piece of diamond model so
next we're talking about national
responsibilities so this is a scale
Jason Healey put this out and I think
it's important to talk about when we
talk about state Nexus cyber actors so
it goes from the left state prohibited
that's where the cyber actors don't work
with the government they don't work for
the government in fact if the government
knew what they were doing the government
will stop them
most people would argue that for the
most part in the United States does a
state prohibited thing and you start
launching a DDoS attack the government's
gonna stop you or at least they're gonna
investigate you and come talk to you and
stop you the next level up is state
prohibitive but inadequate
so what that means is that the state
doesn't like that actors are doing
certain activities but they can't stop
it so they just don't have the resources
the time whether it's corruption
whatever reason that means they just
can't do it they're inadequate next is
stay ignored state knows about it and
just doesn't care
that's very close to the prior one but
just the motivation is not there to act
against those individuals and the next
two are kind of similar so the first one
state encouraged on the next ones state
shaped so state encouraged basically
means that the government is encouraging
an actor to do something and then state
shape means they're actually giving them
pay due to specific tasking usually
these are third party actors a good
example of this would be irani
hacktivists they don't work for the
government they're not necessarily
members of the military but they are
advocating for that what the government
want and conducting operations based off
of that so then we get up to state
coordinated so this is where the
government starting to talk to those
contracting companies or those hackers
and say hey this is who you should
attack hey please attack or Target
Boeing please and there's sort of that
coordination there the next one it's
pretty close is going to be state
ordered so the government's actually
telling you hey you need to attack a
Boeing and that's the state order then
it's they're tasking you you've been
hired and you're being tasked the 8th
one sort of interesting that's the state
rogue but conducted so what that means
is we seen a lot with North Korean
actors and Chinese actors where they
have their day jobs and that they're
conducting state-sponsored intrusions
but then they're also moonlighting so
you have a uniformed actor who's then
making some extra money on the side
that's the state room conducted finally
is state executed so that's when you
have uniformed military or intelligence
personnel that are actually conducting
the operations
on behalf of the state and then last one
above that is when those uniformed
military folks or those intelligence
officers bring in those third parties
and they work in tandem all right
so that's sort of a level of national
sponsibility that we'll go and talk
about so real quick here's just a brief
of some of the countries we'll be
talking about so let's get started so
we're going to start with the
Netherlands now when you think about
technical operations and hackers most
most people probably don't think about
the Netherlands no offense to anyone
there but they're just that's not
something comes to mind at first but in
2018 a Dutch newspaper revealed one of
the most sophisticated and successful
hacking operations against an apt and I
think is pretty pretty interesting so
the aivd Dutch intelligence managed to
get a clue into cozy bears operations
doesn't say exactly what that clue is
but regardless they were able to then
identify the building that cozy bear was
sitting in of course this is pre Kobe 19
so no one was working from home but
everyone was still in the building and
based off the good preparation and
planning that they did they were able to
do more than just pop boxes on the
network they weren't just hacking cozy
bear they were able to hack into the
security cameras and record everyone
that was going to and from the building
so not only do they have access to the
technical network they can then identify
individuals that are going to and from
the building which you can then
coordinate for kind of intelligence
purposes and this according to the news
people are allowed the Dutch to tip off
the Americans about cozy bears attacks
against the State Department including
their infrastructure c2 targets and it
also allowed them to attribute because
you go to SVR and that's I think it was
pretty interesting as far as the
Netherlands are concerned
so next we have France really in France
reportedly originated in 2027
oh sorry 2007 they're known as Babar
animal farm
they're targeting included Iran Syria
Mali Malaysia and others what's
interesting about France and Animal Farm
they had a very diverse set of malware
that covered a lot of different
platforms but their target was extremely
targeted they worked really hard to only
target the individuals they wanted to so
one of the more advanced sets
I'm very targeted next we have Spain so
known as the mask correcto according to
Texas first they started also started in
20 2007 and they were reported on
publicly and attributed in 2014 they
were extremely advanced they had over
300 victims and 31 countries including
governments energy research institutions
private equity equity and activists and
the interesting thing was is Kaspersky
discovered them when they tried to
exploit a vulnerability in a commercial
product
the other interesting thing Kaspersky
tracked them as well they're more
advanced nation safe threats in part
because once especially started sinking
their commanding control servers they
shut down the operations and tore it
down within them I think matter of hours
so really interesting that there is that
level of visibility on their own
infrastructure to conduct that object as
far as attribution goes for this threat
they were able to attribute it through
Whois information obviously before gdpr
as well as Spanish language relations
both in the lawyers in the malware so
this is a beautiful picture as part of
the service that were Safari you'll
notice I'm putting in pictures of the
places that I wish I could visit and
which I'm sure you some of you do too
but this is actually from Turkey so
Turkey is really interesting to me and
again not one of those countries that
you wouldn't necessarily think of the
first actor
that his attribute to Turkey is called
strong pity or promethium in 2016
Microsoft released a report talking
about how promethium have been operating
since 2012 the interesting thing is
they've contact or they've done
campaigns against both domestic and
international targets specific
individuals within interest to your
political and just another interesting
fact is that they have done both
phishing like a lot of people do to get
in but then also succeeded web
compromises or watering holes so they
they started her that dual-pronged
initial infection vector their 2016
campaign used as your daemon Dobby I was
actually delivered via instant messenger
client which again is another
interesting way to deliver that fishing
along with that in one of their
campaigns will there later campaigns I
think in 2018 they were started using
trojan eyes encrypter programs
Kaspersky mentioned that they targeted
people both in Belgium and Italy which
is sort of interesting but still with
the locale saying set to Turkish
Kaspersky did an excellent job
documenting traverses of the malware
those dropped after the initial
infection I'll have all the citations
for all this reporting available at the
end for anyone that's interested
the other interesting thing is that this
strong pity campaign in 2016 had strong
ties with neo diem another group
Microsoft tracks and that group actually
probably uses finfisher malware for
espionage purposes but they between the
two sets
share targets insured I don't believe
infrastructure we shared targets and
around the same timeframe which is the
interesting correlation another
interesting group for Turkey is sea
turtle so in April 2019 Cisco Chows
reported on the group they targeted
national security organizations in the
Middle East and North Africa including
organizations from Cyprus
Greece Iraq Albania Egypt Armenia United
Arab Emirates Jordan Syria and Sweden so
quite a quite a long list of countries
and they sea turtle has the first
publicly reported example of widespread
DNS hijacking the actors were extremely
successful because what they first did
was targeted third parties whether that
be the DNS registrar's the
telecommunications companies or the
internet service providers
once they gained access to those targets
they were then able to hijack the DNS of
the primary targets the national
security organisation so first they used
mostly known vulnerabilities and some
fishing to get into those third parties
and then they changed the DNS settings
to have a man-in-the-middle actor
controlled server so what happened was
they were able to redirect legitimate
users from those organizations through
their box and intercept and then harvest
their credentials as extremely
successful and widespread according to
Reuters credentials including email
service email accounts cloud services
and online network passwords usernames
their attribution that Reuters used
attribute them to actors acting in the
Turkish interest was based on three
things the first being victimology and
we talked about all those countries
being of geopolitical interest to Turkey
similarities to past campaigns using
these similar techniques and then
confidential intelligence that Reuters
was shown
so obviously there is a ton that could
be said about Israeli cybersecurity
I don't have the time and I am nowhere
near an expert to discuss all of
everything is going on cybersecurity
with Israel so we're going to just look
at two examples first would be Dooku 2.0
and this I think is an interesting
example because you see an example of
fourth or possibly fifth party
collection where hackers are hacking
hackers to see the hackers so the New
York Times report on the story where the
do be 2.0 and Israel hacked in to
Kaspersky to gather intelligence
Kaspersky eventually identified this
campaign but the Israelis were allegedly
able to identify Russian hackers inside
of Kaspersky hacking Kaspersky searching
for American intelligence so you have
Israelis hacking Kaspersky hacking with
Russian hackers inside that we're
looking for information on American apts
so quite a convoluted collection there
the attackers ended up stealing
passwords documents screenshots and
emails related to apt work that
Kaspersky was doing particularly those
related to the equation group and region
other targets of the campaign that was
identified include hotels and venues
related to national security
specifically sorry the UN Security
Council relating to the JP Khoa or the
Iran deal those were in the hotels that
were targeting again because first you
put out a great blog if you're in the
group and Dooku 2.0 I'm definitely
recommend looking into it
and also when we talk about
cybersecurity we'd be amiss to not
mention the private companies in Israel
probably one of the best known is the
NSO group and most of you probably know
they're embroiled in a lawsuit against
Facebook for using a what's that
vulnerability so when we talk about
Israel cybersecurity what techniques can
we look at to possibly improve our own
craft
and what we've seen is that NSO tools
like phantom and Pegasus are all mostly
used for quote-unquote legitimate
purposes but vices reported that they've
been targeting human rights dissidents
journalists and political opponents by
the SI loop customers so when we talk
about actual campaigns it looks like a
lot of the lerz appear to be on
subscribe' links or Facebook links up
something you wouldn't mind clicking on
because hey it's just just turnout and
subscribe
the other interesting thing is that the
SR group appears to have procured
infrastructure from cloud providers in
the United States so it'll be a Sheena
wash this case to continue and see what
other infrastructure ends up getting
burned through the lawsuit so next we
have Lebanon and so BFF and lookout
originally identified dr. dark coracle a
third actor allegedly supporting the
general director of general security in
Lebanon so it was first originally
identified based on infrastructure
reused from operation manual which will
briefly discuss later but dark Oracle's
considered an apt for a couple reasons
the first they were able to conduct
multiple campaigns at once exfiltrating
hundreds of gigabytes of data so they
were very successful that way the ffs
reported targets in the government the
military military targets utilities
financial institutions healthcare and
manufacturing some of those hundreds of
gigabytes of data that was expelled
include documents call recordings
contacts photos and just general account
information the interesting piece about
this campaign is that the mobile malware
was used there was actually the primary
attack platform for this campaign
initial access did start with phishing
or social engineering but then also this
initial access also started with
physical aspects to targets so someone
actually had physical access to the
phones of the target that was being used
palace which is the woman
the malware that was being used on the
mobile hours often or was a Trojan iced
app that was made to the App Store it's
reported that dark rock will also used
finfisher malware similar to what we
talked about earlier uh it with near
doom
neo diem the other malware used includes
Pandu crack cross rat
and while the infrastructure being used
for this was shared among multiple
actors the e FF was able to fingerprint
some of it uniquely and when we talk
about attribution this is one of the
strongest attributed sets because what
happened was the logs and directories
were opened on the command control
infrastructure they were able to take
those locks identify the testing devices
that was testing infrastructure prior to
the campaign being conducted and then
once they did those testing devices they
also looked and saw the Wi-Fi networks
associated with those devices based off
of that they then went and did some osen
on those Wi-Fi devices in a Wi-Fi
networks rather and were able to
pinpoint those Wi-Fi networks to a
specific building in Lebanon and then on
top of all of that the committee control
infrastructure had three IP addresses
that were the main command control and
those were controlled by actors or the
IPS were from the state-owned AG arrow
telecom so that's pretty strong
attribution so next we have the United
Arab Emirates stealth Falcon and fruity
Armour so in 2016 the intercept
published an article detailing Dark
Matters recruitment of foreign cyber
operators to hack for Kinect offensive
operations forward the government the
report that was then followed up with
reporting from Reuters that showed how X
and sa hackers were hacking for project
Raven which is what they called Dark
Matters project
from mention Abu Dhabi the interesting
thing is is that the alleged targets
include human rights activists
journalists and political rivals the
Malheur was called karma and did not
require any user interaction and it
obtained photos text and location
information it's possible and it's been
hypothesized that a use an iMessage
zero-day also 2016 since and Lam
published a separate report on stealth
falcon and that report was targeted
against or the campaign reported on
targeted critics of the government of
the UAE what happened was the first
stage was to profile the devices the
user was using so the fishing link used
to redirect URL to profile devices and
then later on the conversation fished
them with malware that was targeted to
their device with a mail dock and then
that male duck returned that eventually
got to a customized PowerShell backdoor
similar to Empire not not the exact same
but similar and then back in 2019 ESET
republished a but report about binary
that bares remarkable similarity to the
backdoor that was disclosed by citizen
lab in 2016 they noted the targets and
similar same thing of UAE inside the UAE
Saudi Arabia Thailand and a mission to
the Netherlands one of the other ties
this attribution was the binary used
this one the same for any control
domains as the PowerShell backdoor that
was previously disclosed by citizen lab
so don't forget that the adversary also
sometimes gets lazy and reuses
infrastructure so Morocco yes that is a
camel from Morocco according to pixabay
was another company I was interested to
find on some research on so in 2018
highest found tax against a variety of
French infrastructure firms once they
sinkhole domain they were able to obtain
the registrant information and
eventually found an email address for
one of the DNS servers
that was hosting the IP addresses in
March of 2020 Brian Krebs does what he
does best of dachshund people took that
email address traced it through some
forums and found a Moroccan security
researcher who was tied to the forum
posts and that email of course that
security researcher ever denies being
affiliated with any of the attacks
because of course his email was hacked
conveniently during the time and at this
point we won't know who directed and
sponsored the intrusion but it's
definitely interesting example of the
government sort of doing that state
encourage where they're directing but
not necessarily doing it themselves so
next we have is Becca Stan they've been
around for a while their National Police
sss first took interest in commercial
hacking tools starting in 2011 and it
came and light when phineas fisher to
dumped the hacking team stuff now in
2019 brian bartholomew from Kaspersky
are presented a virus bulletins on apt
tattoos Pakistan's Intelligence Agency
the strong attribution to the SSS was
possible and due to horrible aspect
sorry excuse me horrible
OPSEC by the individual operators
Kaspersky was able to identify the team
based off of the Whois records that
listed the intelligence officers true
name and military unit 0 to 6 1 6 so
liver age is put in the register
information do not understand how that
was available to researchers
so that's the first off-site failure
the next offsets failure was that they
had Kaspersky antivirus running on their
testing machines so once there was any
sort of alert Kaspersky was able to one
see what they were testing and to grab a
and profile it so because of this
because first he was able to grab and
identify multiple 0 days that had been
purchased by the organization in
Uzbekistan and this just shows that the
this sort
visibility as the antivirus softwares
have especially are in countries outside
the US is really interesting and
excellent for hunting those smaller
adversaries so another beautiful view
not sure I never seen this sort of view
before but this is actually in Pakistan
so when we talk about Pakistan we have a
couple different groups that are
attributed so the first one is gonna be
Gore in the group it's interesting
because of the wide range of both
espionage and financially motivated
campaigns sort of getting to where we
see that that rogue act at rogue state
actor going on so in February of 2018
unit 42 identified the Gorgon group
targeting the UK Spain Russia in the
United States those same campaigns
actually shared infrastructure with
financially motivated campaigns couple
of the interesting things about this
group is they used URL shortening so it
allowed them both to track their own
metrics which is always good when you
are conducting campaigns but also a lot
of researchers to enumerate and collect
metrics on the actor themselves when we
talk about capabilities for this group
they used a variety of rats most most of
the time use NJ rat and also use info
skills like looking by and back in
October 2019 prevailing on the security
vendor talked about another campaign
that they were doing the lured documents
again used your short name URL
shortening services and this time they
redirected to blogspot URLs so you have
the fishing that we directed the
blogspot the JavaScript reached out to
paceman in R and some code to
established persistence the escape of
tasks in registry keys and then once
those changes were successful another
paceman URL was accessed yeah after all
those paceman infection chains the
infection team eventually led to a rack
used it was ravindra and then became as
well
while they were monitoring it so really
interesting yes there the other apt type
to Pakistan is transparent tribe or
mythic Leopard or sometimes apt 36
depending on who you're talking to
in 2016 proof points Darren Hass
published the research that identified
phishing attacks targeting military or
sorry tournament Indian military
resources the fish included a weaponized
RTF document that dropped a PE that
eventually led to a rat interesting is
in addition to these phishing campaigns
they also had registered multiple blocks
to act sort of watering holes they have
posted examples that the Indian military
are articles that they Indian military
would be interested in whether it be
about discipline issues about latest
unrest I believe with China and they
were able to allegedly give some victims
from that as well and that dual pronged
approach something that I think's pretty
interesting
in 2017 sinful reported actors tied to
trench right now i targeted officials
from the indian Central Bureau of
Investigation in the Indian Army while
masquerading as the Institute for
Defense analyses as we've seen this
continues the historic targeting of or
sorry past hardening of Indian
government officials in May of 2018
crushed I continued this trend by
reporting that they were using generic
excel themed lures and then a customized
visual basic skirt installed right of
implants again crash track identified
mythic leopard c2s that were used
against or from multiple campaigns the
long-running c2m pressures and OPSEC
failure but it's also sometimes a misfit
it's already set up it's already
configured and depending on the
adversaries goals may be good enough and
then just recently in back in March
matter Malwarebytes reported that this
actor like many others had begun using
Kobe 19 relay dealers and had shifted
the turning from both India to then also
Afghanistan as well
so this next
picture of a tiger from India so you'll
notice that this slide is not nearly as
neat as the others
that's because Indian cybersecurity
attribution is a mess both on seat Nexus
operations and on the criminal
operations we're gonna look at some of
the campaign's that have a nexus to
India and talk about different throw
troops but overall it's just a general
mess so in March of 2018 as a cutaneous
security vendor started talking about a
specialized lures that were targeting
Chinese government agencies the lead
document ended up dropping a dotnet
executable Q at that scheduled tasks and
then eventually led to another rack
documents with an X filled via HTTP POST
to the C to a couple of their vendors
reported similar things to next time but
including a campaign against the USA
u.s. well so this this apt used similar
techniques in the campaign against both
Chinese government officials and US
think tanks while masquerading as a u.s.
think tank
what they also did and I'm sure so the
red teamers out here also done this is
used an embedded image in an email to
track the beacon back to track who
actually opened the emails and who would
think clicking it was unique so it
allowed it actually who was clicking and
again the final payload of that campaign
was case alright the interesting thing
is that the actual exploit that was used
was pulled from proof-of-concept they've
been published on github and was likely
not developed internally to act work and
that that copy and pasting from github
and open source is actually what gave
this ap the name of Patrick a deception
vendor symmetry or saw threat actor
operating in one of their deception
platforms and they were able to then go
out and grab the lures from that
document what they saw was two things
one they were saw variety of tool
they've been downloading and taking from
but they're able to also obtain the lewd
documents that the ABC was using in this
campaign it was all related to China and
South China Sea so and used like we
talked about the vulnerabilities and
exploits that were available publicly in
these these allegedly state-sponsored
based actress for India had not gone
anywhere in fact unit 42 just recently
released released reporting on Viceroy
tiger and early May this activity
targeted government military
organizations what's written is they
really cared about being detected so
they really tried hard to blend in and
assume that they were impersonating
legitimate services so they did this in
a couple ways they use things like self
signed certificate so that the software
were signed unique file descriptions so
it just looked like another piece of
corporate software that you'd find on
your machine and then also convincing
error messages there weren't typos it
was pretty convincing campaign the
interesting thing is is that instead of
just attaching the mailbox to their
phishing campaign they were able to
directly deliver documents so instead of
doing that the actors hosted their
payloads on compromised third-party
websites within the country of their
targeting so they were targeted when
they turned pakistan they compromised
websites that were already in pakistan
and then host the documents there this
gave them some plausibility and added
another layer of ossification it also
got around some of the geofencing that
you might see in a typical environment
and i think in some ways even more
interesting than the indian state
sponsored activity would be the indian
hacking for hire the two main names that
come to mind that have been publicly
reported our app insecurity and then the
second one just broke this week was
finalizing science but was dark basing
by citizen lab both operations have
targeted variety of individuals
including attorneys dissidents and
journalists vff reported that operation
Manuel was in use by a variety of
organizations including those from
Kazakhstan and then the campaign that
led to the ties to dark Oracle from
Lebanon dark basin on the other hand
seem to have two different types of
campaigns that was reported by Reuters
and sis and lab the first seem to be
more aggressive trying to force the used
or unsubscribe so they just stopped
getting the emails it's loud it's noisy
but it seemed to work
I've just consistently pounding spam
emails sometimes pornographic content in
order to try just get the users I just
I'm done gotta click unsubscribe like
get me off of this list the other was
more targeted and masqueraded as
legitimate service maybe Google photos
and was targeted to the individual users
and said hey please share this photo
album with me whatever it looks like
definitely more targeted than we had
seen past so if you're interested in
following a PT's there's a bunch of
researchers that post hashes and malware
samples on twitter if you search for a
hashtag Sidewinder you'll start getting
a variety of malware samples to look at
really interesting stuff so next we have
these beautiful mountains these
mountains are actually from South Korea
so I think one of the South Korea's one
of most interesting threat countries
from my point of view we'll talk about
to the first is hey Yassa it's been
active since 2016 turian includes China
North Korea Japan Nepal Singapore Russia
Poland and Switzerland it's interesting
because their capabilities include a
keylogger outlook credential harvester
and then ghost rat what's interesting
about PAGASA is that they typically
their fishing comes around the holidays
and offers blessings or thanks to people
so it's more it was all those ecards
that we used to get saying hey happy
holidays from the Smith family similar
technique especially focused though on
North Korean holidays as well
which is interesting there's sorry the
other thing new thing about this group
is that they are able to fish very
quickly relate to the new so in some
days and sometimes less than four days
after news broke it was already being
used in lures for fishing another
campaign that they were doing that
prevailing on mentioned was
correspondent to the release of a new
software so the company those being
spooked the actor had already prepared a
campaign and then sent out that campaign
the same day that the released a new
software so we don't know if it's
coincidence or they or they just got
lucky or they were planning ahead time
but either way it's very convincing when
you can get brand-new news and fresh
articles into the hands of users into
their inboxes for attribution for this
set interesting because it comes from
both time stamps meaning working hours
and and yes
that can always be changed based off of
how many people work nights but for the
most part it's a good baseline the
interesting thing is there was an
artifact left in some of the malware
that reference never calm which is
Korea's biggest search engine and that
was in one of the documents in in the
document field so that helps with
attribution for this set dark hotel also
known as shadow crane is one of my
favorite apts they've been active since
2007 in 2014 Kim Zetter
reported on the hotel attacks against
some VIPs specifically on high-profile
guests so what happened there was the
actors were already on the Wi-Fi and
once the individual that they were
targeting logged on they were targeted
saying hey your Adobe needs to be
updated and then they download of course
the fake update that then gave them
access to the targets computer so
interesting they had a kernel level key
logger they use zero days in their
spearfishing over all their campaigns
they used HT a downloaders consistently
so that's one of the TTP that they were
known for another TTP that they are
known for was consistent fishing so you
may not accept that attachment when it
first comes in February but if you keep
getting the same conference on the same
person in March April May by May and say
this is just a normal thing and your
defenses are down and then you're more
likely to open that attachment as part
of that specific campaign they also
configured their C two pages to look
like normal web pages if you visit the
wrong page so if you just browse to it
you know web browser Kaspersky reported
you'd often see pictures of artists
artisanal ice cream or other comics
completely related unrelated to their
target I'm sort of trying to increase
that OPSEC especially when researchers
come and poke around the site and the
group has used plenty of 0 days in this
last spring Kaspersky released released
a report talking about dark hotel using
Internet Explorer vulnerability the
interesting thing about this report was
that some targets appeared to be geo
located to South Korea at this time it's
unclear whether or not they belong to
multinational companies or actual South
Korean citizens it would be consistent
if South Korean geopolitical Ames
solicited information for most companies
that we competitors so hey you're a
multinational company your south korean
branch gets fished to help advance the
South Korean state Nexus really excited
about this next picture because it's
it's beautiful yes that is a buffalo and
that's right we're going to Vietnam
so Vietnam interesting target abt 32 but
ocean Lotus it's really interesting
because with the right visibility it's
easy to see how their campaigns aligned
with their state interests Nick Carr
formerly of fire and now with Microsoft
I did a great job of reporting what fire
I saw so first they saw socialists have
been active since 2014 they first
publicly talked about in 2017 ocean
Lotus targeted foreign corporations with
manufacturing consumer products and
hospitality sectors they also in
different campaigns targeted the
Vietnamese jaspera journalists and
activists on with the government
agencies and then so what's interesting
with this is that it's not so straight
intellectual property theft so what
they're serving sort of a law
enforcement audit purpose so Nick Carr
gives this example of auto manufacturing
so Vietnam implemented strict
regulations on how to import cars and
following those laws being enacted
multiple car manufacturers including
Toyota and BMW with an attacked and late
twenty men team by Ocean Lotus
oftentimes these attacks came right
after those car manufacturers had just
been meeting with the government so
really unique targeting there
additionally we see that when we talk
about investment data they may not be
targeting the direct company that's
investing in Vietnam but they'll target
the accountants that are helping that
company so we're sort of that third
party targeting we also see Ocean Lotus
or apt 32 conducting targets against
government sponsored or government
organizations mostly located regionally
according to the e FF they've also been
known to target journalists activists we
talk about the diaspora when a same
thing is that Ocean Lotus either on
accident or on purpose leaked
transcripts between the Philippine
president with world leaders and clean
both the Chinese in the US presence can
they upload those two virus whole
whether or not that was intentional
amount we don't know but something is
she to look at
so when we talk about Vietnam it's also
important to talk about phantom lanes
phantom Lancer was just reported a few
months ago and does share some overlap
with Ocean Lotus Kaspersky estimated
that they've been active since 2016 they
serve as mobile Mauer and the
interesting things that they do the
first when they first upload now which
the Play Store it's clean so it's just a
regular app but then subsequent updates
is when they end up contain malicious
payloads in code some of their targets
include India Bangladesh Vietnam
Indonesia Nepal Myanmar and Malaysia
again just interesting mobile malware
campaign there are some overlaps as far
as infrastructure goes with apt 32 Ocean
Lotus but not enough to conclusively
tell them together so our last good
actor for today yeah is in locating
Latin America and goes by machete it's
possibly Colombia Venezuela the it's
been active since 2010 revamped
infrastructure in 2012 it is a
spanish-speaking apt which is
interesting and they look for photos
from webcams geo locations audio for
microphones sort of all those things
that you'd want in an espionage set
victims from Venezuela Colombia Ecuador
and Russia so this is hard because when
we talked about usually using victims to
help cluster and help do attribution if
you have a lot of victims in the same
country as that's or originating the set
it makes that a lot harder to do against
and shooting set because primarily in
spanish-speaking so just the correcto
and then mush up there are two of us
finish being a PT's that we've seen so
so what so let's talk about trends that
we've seen the action has been doing
we've talked about a lot of adversaries
there's there's more out there and I'm
not an expert on all of them by any
means but I think we've seen that it's
evident that
smaller governments are using cyber
capabilities and they're using these apt
style attacks on dissidents journalists
and sometimes our own citizens if you
have employees or friends in these
groups please make sure they're
protected google advanced protection
programs now free and open to everyone
get a hardware token and get them to
work definitely worth looking at and I
think as defenders if we're working in a
multinational company when was the last
time that you threat modeled the
multitude of government's they may
affect your operations do you have
operations in South America that may
have local offices targeted by machete
do you do business in Vietnam or South
Korea so that's only shed water though
sometimes you may not you may be a u.s.
us-based company that doesn't have any
interests or high profile VIPs traveling
and this threat this talk may not be
directly useful for you and that's okay
but it's important to identify what
threats affect your company especially
if your multinational one of the best
ways to do that is to look at regional
security companies so outside the great
fire and Crosstrek are great but their
visibility is delimited looking and
talking to some of those smaller
companies whether they be based in
Europe or China or Asia Asia it's
important to get that full visibility um
and I guess the other thing is if you've
seen unique regional targeting please
share it blog about it tweet about it do
talk about it we want to see that
regional visibility that we might not
see from the America and it's really
interesting because while these
directors are doing some cool stuff
so last then all the images were from
pixabay citation reached all of the
research that I've talked about is
located on paceman also posts that link
in the discord as well as answer any
questions feel free to scan the QR code
if you also want to go that pastebin
site to look at all of that research
there's a lot of really good work being
done and the researchers did a great job
documenting it from a variety of vendors
so please go look at those sources of
anything I said make sense that's all I
have thank you and I'll be around I'll
staking the discord to answer any
questions that anyone has but thanks so
much everyone