the CIA s top or the first six CIS top
20 controls using an open-source free
source and self home-built tools with
that being said before we get started
I'd like to thank everyone involved with
Circle City Con from the volunteers to
the organizers to the sponsors and to
you the attendees Circle City Con has
meant a lot to me both professionally
and personally over the years Who am I
I'm Micah K Brown by day I go through
and I am an IT security engineer for a
very large global insurance organization
by night I go through and I volunteer
with the Greater Cincinnati Issa you
might know me by some of my other talks
which are all available free and open
source right there on my github account
including this talk in the tools that
I'm releasing today along with this talk
and with that let's go ahead and get
started one thing I do want to say is
Cincinnati is a great city for IT
security and IT professionals we have a
lot of different groups that are within
our organization that go through and
work together to make your professional
and personal life just a little bit
easier if you ever are in our city we'd
love to have you any and all of our
event if you're not in Cincinnati I
would challenge you go through and find
those types of groups within your own
now I'm getting started with control one
inventory and control of hardware assets
one of the hardest things that I have to
do as a global enterprise is these
simple tasks at scale and nowhere is
this more typifies in terms of control
number one and truthfully and rightfully
so how can I is an IT security
practitioner go through and how can I
protect my organization how can I
protect assets they have zero knowledge
of so are two critical tasks go through
and is to utilize an active discovery
tool on our environment to define what
we have out there in terms of compute
resources then we need to go through and
we need to document in a central
location usually this is called a
configuration management database or
CMDB to go through and describe all of
the assets
we found so our first step is we need to
go through and we need to define our
environment I'm very old-school the
first thing that I really love to do is
to go and talk to procurement and I
usually ask them what is your server
retention timeframe and you know it
might be three it might be five years I
might ask them hey can you give me all
of IT spend for the past five years past
three years that way I can go through
and get a ballpark idea of what I am
expecting to find the second thing is I
want to do active discovery for our
compute assets be they servers network
devices appliance even things in the
cloud and me I came to IT security
through a very traditional path for
someone of my age group that means I
started on the helpdesk then once I
became too valuable there I moved over
to a server admin once I became too
valuable there I got upgraded into the
networking team and finally made it over
to IT security so for me when I start
wanting to discover the environment I go
to each site core router core switch and
I just dump the routing table that's
going to give you about 80 to 85% of all
of your networks you're going to miss a
couple things the things that you're
going to miss is anything that follows
the old zeros path out to the internet
you're also going to miss air gapped
environments which are very critical for
us to go through and to do these tools
tactics techniques to implement these
controls on and then I take those lists
of networks and I feed them into an
active discovery tool for client systems
for servers we usually have some sort of
automated control tool so it might be
Active Directory it might be free radius
we might also have malware or client
discovery tools or client package
management tools I like to query all of
those and compare them to make sure that
they are tightly focused on relatively
the same ideally the same scope of
topics then for mobile systems in the
way that I define mobile system is these
are company-owned assets that are not
that use non-standard images so in my
environments that's things like phones
that's tablet that's marketing that they
want to have Mac's because Photoshop in
this day and age runs
better on Macs and finally bring your
own device so likewise we want to be
able to have a valid inventory of what
non company owned assets we are getting
access to parts of our environment and
finally the results of all of this needs
to be stored in a centralized location
usually that's a CMDB so when it comes
to actually performing the network
discovery
nmap is king it's a free open-source
command-line scanner it's built into
almost every version of Linux you can
even install it on Windows and it pays
off in spades it's very powerful very
flexible however there was a point in my
life where the command line was just a
little bit intimidating and for those
people that would rather have a GUI type
of interface Zen map is for you
Zen map is a graphical overlay built on
top of in map what I love about it is a
couple things first off as you build out
your scan it's going to show you
basically in a title bar right where or
the exact syntax of the scan that it is
eventually going to launch for you
secondly when you finish a scan in Zen
map you're going to get a couple
graphical in or graphics of your network
that it's going to proactively put out
there for you and that is a huge win for
many people and finally for those people
that are not as comfortable with the in
map output because trust me depending on
what you're looking for it can be a
little bit overwhelming it does do a
great job of putting it into a GUI
interface with each asset that you each
compute asset that you find is or goes
through and has a little icon you can
drill into it and it makes reviewing
that information very cool other types
of scan engines that you can use
alienvault OS I am open audit and open
NSM so once we've gone through and we've
done our scan I didn't like to go
through and look at automating system
discovery so here I'm looking for our
things like our laptops our desktops our
servers and anything else and I start
out by going through and most of us have
some centralized authentication in most
places I find it to be Active Directory
it could be something like a free
radius server I just go there and I ask
can you please spit out and since I'm an
active directory shop I use PowerShell
the the name the operating system the
patch level and but one thing that I
always ask for is last lock on attribute
you see me as IT security practitioners
we are really good when we have users
enter and exit our organizations were
really good about managing that user
account however I find all too often we
are not as good when it actually comes
to managing our computer accounts and
that can lead to several different
issues down the road likewise as I said
before I then like to go through and I
like to look at our other shared control
so you might go through and you have
might have anti-malware you might have a
package management management system you
might have a patching system and I make
sure that between all of those other
control tools that they look to be well
aligned to what your active and your
production environment actually is next
in helping us gain a little bit traction
moving forward I'd like to go through
and implement some pretty strong DHCP
logging so I've gone through and
provided a two knowledgebase articles
one for Windows one for Linux but DHCP
is what gives a client system coming on
to your network it gives them an IP and
allows them to connect without manual
configuration next I like to look into
802 One X authentication so this is an
open source protocol that allows you to
go through and enforce strong
authentication when a client system when
a system is logging on to the network
and if you want to do this you have two
great options is either a Windows NPS
server role within your environment or
you can use something like free radius
with 802 dot 1x now you can go through
any can bolster this with network access
control so network access control or
neck allows you to ask other security
posturing questions when a system is
attempting to log
to your network so you can ask what's
the OS what's the patch level you can
ask that you have a B if so when it's
the most recent antivirus signatures
that you have but you can also ask
things like can you please give me your
certificate so you could go through and
push out trusted internal certificates
to your end systems and then querying
for that type of certificate you can say
yes this is a corporate asset or no it's
not and if it is a corporate asset you
could even go through and you could even
ask what are the group memberships
associated with this user account and
when you do that that allows you to make
some very strong decisions so Bob from
accounting since he's on his corporate
device he would be allowed on to the
accounting VLAN Alice let's say she's an
IT she would go to the ITV LAN but let's
say Alice has somebody a guest coming
into giving a presentation for her on
the new technology
well that laptop when it tries to hit
wireless in an axe Ellucian it could go
through and be sent directly to the
guest Wireless VLAN so there's a lot of
power in going through and having a
well-tuned neck and there are some great
free and open source so open neck free
neck PAC events I played around with
them and all of them seem to be pretty
good however just like most of our
controls that we have we have to realize
that they are based on some very serious
accounts as well as some pretty
sensitive PKI cryptography keys so we
need to make sure that we're protecting
them appropriately step 4 I kind of
combined mobile and BYOD once again
mobile is company owned non-standard
assets bring your own device BYOD that
is assets that are owned by others now
generally we use some sort of an MDM
mobile device management on those
systems and so we can simply go to the
MDM and we can just ask for a report
in some instances I've seen an
organization go through and to use a
single unified MDM across the entire
organization in other instances I've
seen two versions of the same MDM one
for more of the company owned assets
mobiles as I call them and one BYOD for
other lis owned assets now other
companies that I've partnered with I've
worked with they actually have two
separate vendors once again this is up
to you it's all up to what you are
looking to do with it your use cases but
just remember that the mDM's can give
you a lot of it or a lot of real-time
accounting on what systems are
connecting through those ways and we
probably should go through and make sure
that we are pruning devices at an
appropriate level if they've been
inactive say for over three months over
six months whatever you as an
organization believe finally we need to
take all of that information and we need
to put it in a centralized location so
our configuration management database or
CMDB for many small shops you can get
away with having a flat office type of
document I strongly advise against it it
really goes through and starts to fail
at scale quite quickly but that is an
option that you can go through and you
can use like my services like Spiceworks
they will give you a free CMDB out in
their cloud on their web servers and
that's great however they do go through
they do review what you put in there and
then they target you they monetize and
target you with highly targeted ads
based on what your technology is I have
the same problem with this methodology
that I do with HR going through and
posting Arden help-wanted ads as
sometimes we give away a little bit too
much about our environments and there's
or in those ads that being said most
organizations simply use the CMDB
functionality built into their ticketing
system and that makes sense and I'm one
of those so our this allows us to
directly link to our incidents to our
change to our
problem tickets the CI or configuration
item directly into the ticketing system
itself and that does have a lot of good
however that does mean that there might
be some particularly use cases that are
not functional for example I use a
ticketing system that if you were to
look on a quadrant that is magic it
would be very high and right and with
that being said there is one glaring
flaw and that is my CIS can only have
three highly indexed IPs and while that
works for the vast vast vast majority of
systems that we do have globally it
really starts to fail when I go through
and I start to look at my web servers
which can have five ten or more IP
addresses associated with them but it
also really fails when I'm going through
and I'm talking about networking a sec
so routers switches firewall
cryptographic termination points so that
is something that we need to be aware of
and finally you could build your own but
it's going to be a Herculean task but I
wanted in preparing for this talk to go
through the process of designing my
ideal CMDB now I know that this slide
isn't a high soar but it took me about
20 hours and I was really proud of it
and not only did I put the Visio on the
github I also took the next step and
implemented this fully out in Microsoft
Access now I was only interested on the
design level I'm a horrible coder so
please feel free to mock me relentlessly
on that but I was very proud and it
taught me a lot of things on how mica
traditionally views my computer objects
in my environment so now control to
inventory and control of our software
assets so once again very similar goals
we want to use some sort of tool to scan
our organization to discover what type
of software is a in use in our
environment and aspirationally we want
to use some type of application
whitelisting technology to control what
is executed
on our systems so once again I love
going to procurement to purchasing
because they're going to be able to set
a good baseline of what we should expect
to find in our environment step two guys
PowerShell is amazing so right here is
the exact scriptlet that I go through
and I leverage to go through and to dump
what is in the add/remove programs and
so depending on your power show you
might have to tweak it just a little bit
but I find it runs really good I
basically go through and I will send
this PowerShell object to an external
computer and/or to a computer on our
network and I will in the script I'll
have it write its results back you can
do it in a CSV a text file and just have
it dump on an open chair so it's really
quite easily and it scales pretty well
from there you can go through use your
favorite data manipulation tool of
choice in just all of the data
manipulate it and you're going to have a
really strong sense of what is in your
Windows environment now this can also be
done in Linux as long as you're going
through and you're using a package
manager you can read the notes on the
past cage manager and you can go through
and you can do that exact same approach
within your Linux environment likewise
alienvault Spiceworks neces community
opened as they all have the capability
to go through and to perform this via an
automated scan this can either be
credentialed or uncredentialed meaning
either give them username and passwords
or not generally I find credentialed
scans are a little bit more valuable but
we need to just like control one it's a
continuous control that we are going
through and affirming that we are
meeting it on a regular basis the same
is true with this control so step three
I suggest going through in preventing
install of unauthorized software first
step separate user from admin rights we
need to go through I would honestly
suggest that you go through and you
block access any
see level at a euro level however you
want to do it too many popular sites
that allow your users today to go
through and download portable apps next
I would suggest pushing out a GPO to
restrict the execution of code of
binaries of applications from very
well-known and documented locations that
are currently being used by our
malicious adversaries I've gone through
and I've given you a knowledgebase
article in a couple locations that I
think are very valuable for us to go
through and restrict and finally the
outcome of all of this is you can go
through and you can now go to your
senior management and justify why we
should go down an application
whitelisting methodology and guys that I
love application whitelisting but I've
only seen it done well within the Apple
ecosystem of the iPhone and the iPad
there is a lot of fear uncertainty and
doubt especially from IT because we're
changing fundamentally how we go through
and how we support systems how we
distribute software and that's all right
we are allowed to grow we're allowed to
change things for the better and even
though I see that there are bypasses
regularly to application whitelisting
technologies in the forms of tools to
act extend techniques I still think it
is where we should aspirationally be
going forward now in order to implement
it my recommendation to those in my
community has always been start with
Microsoft amplicor it's not perfect but
it's something that you can start with
that you can spin up a test lab that you
can start to build trust in that
technology can understand what you can
do and also just as important is what
other projects products would allow you
to do likewise I played around a little
bit with apps a or apps am vid and while
it was a great concept the thing that
really kind of was a deal breaker to me
was there was no centralized management
to it but I really liked some of the
ideas that they had going which brings
us to continuous vulnerability
management so once again our two main
goals
is to utilize some sort of vulnerability
scanning tool to scan our networks that
we defined under control one in control
- and then we need to have the people
processes procedures and technologies to
go through and to review each finding
out of our vulnerability scanner to
validate if it is an issue and then to
remediate it in a in an appropriate time
so when we when we're talking about full
stack scanners this is where I would go
through and I'd suggest something like
open vas as a great starting point so
open that it's an open source phone
ability scanner it's built into Kali
Linux and for many small and medium
businesses this is a great option one of
the things I appreciate about it so much
is just by downloading Kali I can either
download the ISO or I could download the
offensive SEC virtual machine do a quick
update and I'm ready to go through and
to probe in an environment that I'm
authorized to however we do have some
great things coming from our vendors I
have friends at both rapid7
& tenable they're they're really great
organizations rapid7 gives us an expose
community which this is an enterprise
class vulnerability management system
and it's free for one year likewise
Nessus us and chose by tenable they give
you an a full Enterprise loaner ability
management system how they go through
and limit it to 16 devices at a time but
that is something that you can you keep
for years as long as you want to in your
environment now if you're like my friend
Cameron and you like to have human
intelligent guiding these automated and
semi-automated assessment then
Metasploit is something that is really
fun for you to go through and you to
learn to play around with to probe those
systems that you are either own or
explicitly or have the owners explicit
written authorization likewise
retina CS is another vulnerability
management solution that they're free
model allows you to have 256 free scan
assets
now web servers there just a little bit
different and with web servers the we
allow dynamic code to either be run on
the web servers themselves or on the
end-user clients and so this opens our
web servers up to just a couple
different risks so for fully automated
scans I would recommend nikto and Ava's
app is great starting off point and if
you want to have more of the human
guiding the assessment burp suite free
is very very fun with burp suite what
ends up happening is it will sit between
your server and the web or your web
browser and the remote web server and
you'll be able to see the full
communication both ways even up to
manipulating what is being sent and/or
received so that can give you all sorts
of fun discoveries and finally for
sequel I would recommend something like
sequel map all right
control for controlled use of
administrative privileges so our two
main concerns is to go through and to
separate user from administrative
privileges and and only give an
administrative privileges to those that
have a proper business reason to have
them and secondly to go through and to
configure escalated logging of those
administrative credentials so my number
one recommendation is start out with an
full-blown enterprise wide naming
convention for all of your accounts and
I should have added user and computer
accounts in doing this you're giving
your responders the ability to make
quick and correct decisions as they go
through and they start looking into an
event so it's me that is something that
has paid off huge spades second we need
to go through and understand that we as
IT security we have a lot of very sense
of credentials we have a very a lot of
very sensitive cryptographic keys so we
need to protect
I've worked at two or worked with too
many large enterprises and their
security department sometimes still use
a password protective Office document we
can do better me personally I've used
keepass for years and I really love it
for personal use it's a trust no-one
open-source password manager however it
starts to fail at scale when we go
through and we have multiple people
using the password database at one time
only one person can go through and have
read/write access so we have a
highlander problem key pass pro that's
perfectly viable value both workaround
but i wanted to go through and i wanted
to look at some others that i or other
password managers that have come up and
so team passed that one really caught my
eye it looks really slick a lot of great
features but what stood up to me is you
can install it on your home server or
you can stand it up in a dock or
instance and i thought that was pretty
cool from a portability stay in port
likewise PS oh no integrates with the
have i been poned a database which i
thought was that was phenomenal
especially going through and checking
that to making sure that the credentials
that are in there that they that there's
no indicator that they've been
compromised finally bit warden while
they do offer any enterprise plan that
has some advanced features you can get
the base software to install either on
your own server or spin it up as a
docker now once we've got a password
manager in place we want to go through
and special set special auditing up for
our user for administrative user
accounts so i'd love to go through and
interact with my application owners with
my server owners i love to sit down job
shadow them and understand from them
what is normal administration of their
systems what's adding normal and what
would you see around administrative uses
that if you saw that you'd be picking up
the phone to your to your boss
and we can go through and we can work to
make sure that we can catch those
scenarios that we can alert for them and
this helps go through and do a great
thing for us this brings us in as an
active part of their world they start to
see oh security is automating things for
me they're making my job easier and the
easier we can or the easier we make the
jobs of our application owners our
server owners the more they are
incentivized us to intrinsically go
through and bring us into new
conversation so that we can provide
guidance up at the very front so that is
one thing that I've really struggled
with in my nine-to-five is trying to
rebrand IT security as from the
Department of no to the department but
yes and can we do it in this way which
we think will add more value for x y&z
reason and going through and do working
and helping automate our application
owners and that server owners jobs is a
great way to extend that olive branch
likewise we in IT security we go through
and we have certain use cases that we
care about for me it's install removal
updates to software it starts stops
creation deletion of services the
creation deletion of a share the
installation of patch is the creation
deletion of a network drive it can also
be network configuration changes oh and
any time new admin access is added a
very simple rule that I wrote is we had
an issue where we thought that non IT
security provisioners were creating
service accounts in our environment so I
went through found the Microsoft blog
and I wrote a very basic rule so if I
saw a new admin user created and it
wasn't created by any of the IT security
provisioners that we would get an alert
and that was very effective in helping
us go through discover and tamp down
that type of access finally once we set
this auditing in place it's not like Ron
Popeil you don't set it and forget it
you have to constantly go through and
Pro
that that control is working so I do
this two ways I like to go through and
have a controlled break where I do
something and I testing did the alert go
through and happen and then I am a big
fan of even if we haven't automated
alert at a reasonable interval we should
probably do a manual check to make sure
that there was no breakdowns and this is
something that we of course have to do
on a repeating process all right we're a
little bit further than a half way here
I am going to have to go through and
stop a little bit early because I've got
another talk that I have to go to a
Cloudy with a Chance of breach with at
Tricia kicks ass so we'll move on to
control five and this is all about
secure excuse me secure configuration
for hardware and software on your
devices so our first aspiration will go
our first goal here is to go through and
to define our system hardening
procedures and then we need to go
through and we need to have some sort of
automated tool to scan our environment
to make sure that we are living up to
what our hardening standard says we're
doing now this is where you as an
organization go through and you do have
some leeway so for most small to
business or small to medium businesses I
suggest please review the good
frameworks out there and simply select
one that you want to go through and you
want to align to however if we say that
we aligned to a standard we need to make
sure that we are actually going through
and aligning to it
so in that case C is NIST Microsoft best
practices these are all great places
where you can jump in and you can get a
good start a good running or a good
starting point for this that being said
I work for a very large global
organization and we have competing rules
laws and regulations from a city to a
country even to regionally as well as
globally conflicts and so for us what
we've done is we picked a couple
reference frameworks and we go through
and we built our own
security policies and because of rules
laws regulations contractual agreements
it broke down in two regions of the
world for example I think it's fair to
say be as expressed in GDP are in some
other legislation that Europe has a
little bit more as I say more
expectation on the privacy of the
individual and the data we collect about
the individual than we do traditionally
here in the States although I do believe
that we are seeing a rapid alignment
with GDP our type of rules laws and
regulations here in the state and I
expect that to go through and to
continue but that being said so we have
in America's in a set of America's
hardening guides we have a European
instead of a hardening guides and we
have an APEC set of hardening guides and
so whenever there's a change to one of
our reference frameworks we have to go
through we have to review it and we have
to make a conscious decision do we go
through do we need to update ours or can
we just leave it as is and that brings
us to of the final control that I wanted
to touch on today and that's maintenance
monitoring and analysis of audit logs so
our main goal is to create a local
logging standard and then ensure that
the appropriate logs that we as IT
security and the business decide decide
on are being sent to a centralized
management location that can be a data
lake that can also be something like a
sim so once again I'm very boring we
need to define our logging standards and
this is we're looking at other logging
standards is a great jump start so
Microsoft has a great best practice that
we just reviewed within my 9 to 5 but
also NIST has a great framework that you
can go through and he can dig in a
hidden secret though is that when you
purchase us in you're not just going
through in purchasing the hardware the
software you're actually purchasing the
help of that SCIM vendor to
help you get the other devices logging
in your environment likewise most
hardware and software vendors unfund
'mentally understand that in order to be
successful in the medium to large
enterprise network that you need to have
built in centralized logging so if you
reach out to your hardware or software
vendors they probably have already gone
through and have a knowledgebase article
that they can just give you my last tip
here with your logging standards is you
need to consider different logging
levels for different parts of your
environment so when I first joined my
nine-to-five what ended up happening was
I took over the sim and we needed to
write our own logging standards and so
as I dug in to how the organization went
through and described their machines I
saw that we had a system classification
and that system classification was built
on two very simple pillars one was
uptime and one was sensitivity of data
so based on the uptime requirement one
nine or I'm sorry two nine three nines
four nine five nine
that was a direct equivalent to how
critical an asset was in our environment
and we had our own internal data
classification think top secret all the
way down to public and based on where a
system lined up in that analysis that
system logging level would define what
IT tools as well as IT security tools
are applied to that and in going through
and thinking about this is like well I
probably should care more about logging
on my domain controller then the
internal wiki that tells us what's what
the menu in the kitchen is so with that
being said I simply chose to use that
system classification in my logging
definition so things that were very high
in our system classification got more
logging or got a greater detail of
logging on it then say something
was lower however this started to go
through and to fail especially at our
networking devices because if you think
about it networking devices their whole
job is to pass the traffic by almost
definition they're assumed to have very
high uptime and they don't really store
data they traverse data and so this is
where I went back to my old networking
days and I thought of the Cisco or I'm
sorry the Cisco traditional data center
or enterprise data center and that has
three different components so you've got
the core which is think of it as your
data center you've got the access that's
where your users your guests your
employees your contractors that's where
their systems connect and the
distribution goes through and connects
the two and so based on that
classification I put most of my logging
resources at the core the second most
blogging resources was targeting the
access and the least was the
distribution and the reason why we went
through and did that is because every
sim out there has a theoretical maximum
compute resource and our job is IT and
IT security is to go through and it is
to maximize the value that we get out of
our sim next we need to go through and
think about all right cloud versus
on-premise so where is your sim is it in
the cloud already is it in the same
cloud that your that your other cloud
assets are in is it a different and
you're going to have to do a benefit and
cost analysis to understand do I go do I
go through and send all of my cloud logs
to the sim or do I stand up a second sim
just for the cloud assets keep in mind
as I pointed out earlier networks can be
bound by rules laws regulations and
contractual agreements and those might
differ from location to location so now
that we have our logging standard
created we now need to select a a sim so
in the free and open source world I
default to recommending elks takei two
years ago Derby
on eight I went through and took a
trusted second-class red team versus
blue team and about a quarter of the
time was spent in standing up and doing
threat hunting in an elk stack and that
just blew me away how mature that
solution was back then and it's only
gotten better in fact elk or an elk
stack was built into the default
security onion image for those of you
don't that don't know security onion is
kind of like the blue team's version of
Kali so once you install and you go
through the initiation steps with
security onion you're going to have a
built in elk stack that you can go
through and you can start playing with
right then and there I was on a Black
Hills Hills information security
training a couple weeks ago and I was
introduced to the concept of a help
stack a help stack to condense it it was
built for threat to hunting so they
implemented an entire elk stack in
docker which is great for going through
in a threat hunting lab either home or
at work and it is absolutely fantastic
to go through you can spin it up in
about 15 minutes and then you can test
and see if a full elk stack would be
something that would be a value to your
organization
likewise gray log so grey log is a
freemium type of sim however in my
findings most small businesses will be
able to use the free tier of grey log so
it's worth a shout out that being said I
had to go through and throw SolarWinds
event log collector and key recess logs
they have gotten me out of some
ridiculous jams in the past but you
could also consider splints they have a
free version that limits you to 500
megabytes a day and for a home lab for
just a threat hunting lab and even for
some small businesses that might be
enough and you can have complete
enterprise class tool to go through and
centralize your logs now whatever tool
you choose if it's one of those great if
it's notes great - I would urge you that
one of
first law or one of the first alerts
that we go through and we should be
create is for those critical assets
however you define them create an alert
if a critical asset stops logging for 48
hours if this is something that has bit
me in the behind in trying to do an
event analysis and I want to make sure
that when we do stand up a sim that we
do have this basic type of control built
in but it's sim it is an important tool
of friendship both to IT into the
business so once I have my sim up and
I'm ingesting logs I go to my app and
system owners and I ask what logs do you
care about what events do you care about
what series of events would you want to
get a kind automated call out what
events are would have you picking up the
phone and usually my app owners by
system owners they can answer those
questions and then I can go through and
I can use those two highly automate some
of their jobs once again going through
helping our relationship with the
business will pay off in spades
next I'm sure most of you know about The
MITRE attempt attack framework for those
of you that this is new this is one of
the single best tools that has been
created in our industry over the past
couple of years if you go to their
website you can just quickly see all of
the different real world adversaries
techniques that they have indexed and if
you click into one it'll give you the
who what where when why and oftentimes
here's what this might manifest itself
this is what it might look like so if
you haven't gone through and if you
haven't looked at my tour please do
yourself a favor make that one of your
favorites and it's a wealth of
information for those of you that
haven't heard of the project Sigma
github this is awesome so what the
founders of the Sigma project went
through and saw that each of these sims
are built their own way they person in
their own way you write rules and alerts
in their own way and what this really is
to do was to prevent people from being
able to share their rules easily so what
project sedima did is they said great
we'll solve it by creating another meta
rule framework for the sim I say that in
jest but that was the solution and it's
a really good one because if you go out
to their gab you can see all of the
alerts that they've written in their own
proprietary framework and when I as an
IT security practitioner look at those
rules I can understand their logic and I
can go through and or I can go through
and I can alright sorry got distracted
by a notification when I look at the
rules I understand myself I understand
how I need to write alerts and it's very
simple for me to go through and to
simply go through and implement that
logic in my sim however they also have a
program that you can install and it's a
very simple program it's almost like
ordering at a fast-food restaurant you
pull up to the drive box you run the
executable and you simply go through and
you can say yes I'd like a number one
and number three and number seven give
me a number eleven but hold the
mayonnaise and then at the next prompt
you say this is what sim I have and if
your sim is supported and a lot of the
major Sims are it'll go through and it
will pop out that rule in your sims
format for you so now all you have to do
is copy and paste another great tool for
going through and for helping you
maximize your return in the sim is
purple team exercises so with purple
team I'm a huge fan of I think they send
a such a better metric to our management
because let's face it if you have or if
a business does have a full-blown IT
security team we're already spending
hundreds of thousands of dollars a year
and when we do our annual pin test and
we have some very talented
teamers within our community and they do
a lot of good for us but I know that a
good pen tester is going to be able to
create a good pretext they're going to
be able to weaponize it either in a
watering hall attack or they're going to
be able to go through and to fish my
users and I know that someone is going
to be tripped someone is going to go
through and is going to click the link
to go to the watering hole attack and
when they do I know that there is a
chance that that red teamer is going to
get a shell and once they get a shell
they're going to find some way to live
off the land they're going to be able to
potentially run a derivation of me me
cats and they're going to be able to
spread laterally the concept of the
purple team for those of you that don't
know is to have the red team and the
blue team meet together and discuss the
what the attack is what the scope is and
then let the red teamer go through and
execute the attack while the blue team
err is looking and seeing what did we
detect what didn't we detect then after
the first attack is over you meet back
up you debrief this is what worked well
this is what didn't work well and then
you go through you agree on some
mitigation just in controls you
implement them you bring the red teamer
back they run it again with the blue
team watching and you get a much better
optics message because now when the
final report goes to management you can
go through and say this is quantifiable
quantifiably through this expenditure
how we increase the security and I think
that that's just some a lot better
metrics a lot better of a message for us
be communicating to our senior
management next we need to go through
and we need to make allies with our
audit so about six months ago I was
going through and I was cruising around
my network and I found something very
bad going on and as I dug a little bit
deeper I found more and more that I
don't like so I went to my seesaw I said
hey we need to have a meeting I think I
found something and as I laid out the
evidence he agreed that yes there's some
we do need to go through and we need to
do this however
I need you to be prioritized on the
topics that you're currently working on
so please just do this as you can so
this effort that I was independently
leading was a skunkworks project I
spending one to two hours a week and
months went by until about four months
later I got a call from internal aunt or
I got a meeting him but from an internal
audit and it's like okay and it was
pretty generic so I went through and I
reached back out and I said hey I saw
that you set up a meeting can you please
let me know what that meeting is about
so I can make sure I can bring the
correct documentation so I call we'll
just discuss at a high level in in the
media it's like okay the hairs on the
back of my head started to stand up a
little bit that's a little bit abnormal
but okay so I showed up to the meeting
and I love my auditors but I kind of
have a feeling of exactly how much of
technology they really truly understand
and they were going through and asking
me very highly technical questions that
I wouldn't have expected and sure enough
they had been briefed by somebody else
within the business of the effort that I
was currently going through and leading
and they were asking me questions so I
answered truthfully and at the end I
explained what we were doing when it was
detected that we I was already working
with the business as well as the CSO and
management to go through and to resolve
this but then something happened I got
hit with an audit and really that wasn't
a bad thing at all because as soon as
there was an audit this got traction
from senior management all the way up to
the board level and now whenever I went
to any group I the response when I said
hey I need your help doing XYZ was yes
we'll go through and we'll get that UC
audit they have a very great purpose
they are there to make sure of the
continuity of our businesses they're
there to help make sure that we meet any
rule law regulation and they have a seat
of trust at the very
most senior levels so if we can make
allies by helping audit automate their
job that starts out a very good
relationship that is for the betterment
of both groups so audit does not need to
be the bad guy in fact now we need to be
brothers and sisters with our auditing
team they are there to hold us
accountable they're there to make sure
that the business can be sustained and I
with that I need to go through and to
bring this presentation to a close I
would love to continue this conversation
here there anywhere please feel free to
reach out to me my slides are on the
github just github.com slash my cat K
Brown thank you very much once again to
everyone involved with Circle City Con
this conference has meant a lot to me
both professionally and personally thank
you very much and have a great rest of
your conference