find stocker where s software used to
facilitate intimate partner violence
abuse or harassment including pernicious
intrusions into the targeted person's
life by way of physical or digital
actions so stalker wear can include
stock aware itself
spyware dual use apps and M rats so what
are additional intimate partner
surveillance tools right so we have of
course the commodity stock aware we have
the spyware we have dual use apps such
as Find My Phone right
Emre we have shared accounts o since
social media they can also leverage your
friends and family like oh you know Xena
said that she was gonna meet me at
such-and-such a time and she isn't here
do you know where she is or what she's
doing
let's say you know I get back to my
partner and they're like where were you
what were you doing you said you were at
lunch and I need to see a receipt with
the timestamp right
so they they can use creative means to
basically stock your life right so
commodity stocker where if there's
different levels it's kind of like
varying tiers or levels of payment so
you know on the low end you get basic
information like pass like like call
logs maybe a little bit of the calendar
some Chad apps maybe some SMS definitely
browser history right GPS location and
then it kind of goes up from there like
all the way up to keystrokes being able
to get your the the lock screen code and
prices range from about 50 to 200 bucks
monthly quarterly or even annual
subscriptions so what what exactly does
stalker wear like do what do they take
right so I did a little icon for a lot
of the different things of course
browser history like I said
Twitter they can they can see all of
that Skype your photos all your videos
your voicemails your emails your
photographs your settings they can even
check your network settings and change
it your battery life they can listen to
your surroundings
they can of course know your location
look at all your contacts find out if
you're on Wi-Fi like it impacts Apple
and Android devices so there's a lot
that stock aware can do and it's not
good
here's a list of various vendors
compliments of the citizens lab they
kind of they kind of give you a heads up
aura I just a shopping menu for abusers
to of like hmm I want to know her GPS
and I want to know you know like her
calendar so I can see where she's at who
she's meeting with and I want to know
all of the different calls that she's
made who she's speaking to she's text
messaging all of that right so you can
kind of pick what it is that you want or
need or whatever want to know about your
partner right so here's just some of the
vendors and more there's so many of them
like it's ridiculous
for instance mobi stealth they provide
information on how to disable two-factor
authentication when accessing a victim's
iCloud account mSpy lets you hide the
icon flexi spy even reports when
messages are deleted so there's there's
a lot and each one does different things
right just depends what you want so how
does it work how does it work exactly
so for commodity stalker we're basically
physical access is required to the
device internet access and for Android
devices they need to have the ability to
install apps from unknown sources
and Apple basically either a jailbroken
phone or access to the iCloud account
right so that's basically summed up very
simplified and believe it or not the
lockheed-martin kill chain can apply to
stark aware as well commodity stock
aware and I'll give you an example of
Android right now so you start out with
reconnaissance right information
gathering on the target I'll just use me
as an example right find out what I like
what I would possibly click on like dog
pictures I love I love dog and cat
pictures so of course if I wanted to
like see a close closer up of the cute
dog I would click on the picture right
so there's there's that I'm a sucker
it's okay I know weaponization so they
obtained the URL for stalker where they
purchased the service or um some of the
starter where vendors are so nice they
they offer sometimes 24/7 service of
being able to offer tech support to
people that want to install stalker
where on their partner or persons device
so delivery obtain physical access to
the targeted device and that could be
while they're sleeping mother in the
shower um you know through brute force
method it's like if you don't give me
your phone right now that means you
don't love me right and then finally um
really now we're in the exploitation
phase and there really isn't technical
exploits per se for commodity stalker
where it's more or less like a social
engineering the target to get the phone
to unlock the screen
I had my iPhone someone used dental mold
on my iPhone to lift the prints on it to
gain ax to try to gain access so it's
just uh like how how can I convince her
to leave her phone alone with me
or how can I do it quickly enough while
she's in the shower right or do I
suggest she has a longer shower stuff
like that right and then basically you
configure all the settings right and you
install either from the Google Play
Store or the vendor provided link so it
just it just depends and then there's
command and control usually over Wi-Fi
sometimes over cell service and then
action zone objectives right so
unauthorized access to data on the phone
exfil data and possibly sometimes
modified data
I know parts of my calendar were
modified so if that can happen to me I'm
sure that happened to other people so to
sum up basically commodity stock aware
is easy to use it's legal ish like don't
quote me on that you know consult a
lawyer bla bla all of that it's cheap
it's readily available I downloaded two
samples earlier this week for free and
it has similar capabilities and
permission requests as imrat and spyware
and there's really no user interaction
because the attacker does it right
because they have physical access and
then no really technical skill and of
course the drawback is the attacker
needs physical access to the phone so
here's the M rat it's cheap ish
sometimes remote installation but it
requires specific knowledge to get them
rat right to be able to get the user
interaction social engineer to click and
it does require technical skill and it's
illegal so there's that too
and believe it or not mitre attack
actually has TTP's that mapped back to
various activities that's starker where
mobile rats do and you can take a look
at that so citizens lab did a review of
stalker wear and basically stated that
AV engines are horrible at detecting it
horrible especially when stark aware
comes out with new versions like oh my
gosh like the detection right by a via
vendors is like very very slim so yeah
having basically the same type of access
as like a mobile rat and it being
cheaper and less technical skill and not
really detected by by the engines for
instance the trace by newer versions of
it in this particular report had 0% 0%
cut by AV so that's definitely something
to consider so who are the targets
Morgan here says that the victims are
everyday people like myself I'm an
everyday person I am NOT a CEO you know
don't run multinational corporation and
the main target is relationships
obviously because it has to do with
intimate partner surveillance and
domestic violence right but what if we
take the similar characteristics of
surveillance cuz that's basically I was
surveilled for you know almost two years
and the capabilities of stark aware as
far as having access to information and
data and applying that to other targets
so we'll have a brief discussion of that
so for instance children the parenting
apps monitoring what their children are
doing where they're seeing who they're
talking to their web history all of that
right then we have employees bosses
wanting to know what the heck the
employees are up to there is a company
that I worked for
many years ago had put tracking devices
on their employees phones to find out
where they were at because they were
usually around you know driving trucks
and doing that type of stuff I'm not
going to give away the employer so they
wanted to keep track of what the heck
they were up to the other one is
journalists so the citizens lab put out
a report recently I think it was a
couple months ago and they shared all
the various journalists that were
targeted by specifically Anna solos
group Pegasus which is a advanced stock
aware super super advanced right so an
example of this is a Washington Post
reporter was assassinated and then the
Friends of this assassinated journalist
were attacked or attempted to be
attacked by Ana so they were sent Ino
messages to try to compromise their
device to see what type of
communications were going on so not only
are the journalists targeted but also
the people that are close to the
journalists so that's not good the other
thing is dissidents and in lighter
recent events so black lives matter post
protesters were targeted in 2014 in
downtown Chicago by law enforcement with
stalker where China uses WeChat to spy
on their citizens and recently Hong Kong
residents were targeted via a watering
hole attack to install iphone spyware
religious leaders are even targeted by
spyware and you know stalker where for
instance Tibetans working for the Dalai
Lama and also to Muslims targeted by
Chinese hackers via a watering hole
with iPhone exploits the other people
that are targeted or criminals
of course oh here's a good story so
european law enforcement they were using
NSO's group spyware pegasus via whatsapp
and whatsapp was like what what's going
on right so they sent out a message to
all the people that were impacted by
this particular exploit and said you've
been hacked
so european law enforcement we're using
that to track a known terrorist and when
what's up put out that message the
terrace is like oh like I'm dropping
that phone yeah I'm no longer
communicating on that and they went dark
and the trail went cold so it's used
against terrorists the other one is so
tic-tock tic-tock is interesting it's
known as a dual use app and it's
actually been banned by the u.s. army
the US Navy I believe the Pentagon also
basically they're like yeah no no.2
tick-tock and a report by lookout
describes an M rat and it's called
stealth mango and in it they describe
how government officials were targeted
by this particular emirate and because
those people were targeted in government
officials of course talked to other
government officials and other you know
quote-unquote important people those
important people were also compromised
as well so that's not good operators so
the typical operators of starka where
our attackers abusers I was gonna say
mentally unstable people but we won't go
there I don't need to be slinging
insults right the other thing is through
the stock aware vendor breaches cuz yeah
we'll talk about that later the who
wasn't motherboard they filed a lawsuit
against or they filed a complaint
actually against the Metropolitan Police
because through the breach of flexi pot
flexi spy they realized that they were
purchasing this particular software
right and the Metropolitan Police
refused to look into it and it's unknown
whether they were using it for official
means or if they were using it against
their partners or whatever and they just
used their police email who knows yeah
Ashley Madison that's all I like to say
and then mobi stealth that was another
compromise and in that let's see the
military FBI ice THS TSA who knows
several branches of the military two
were found in that dump so we're gonna
do the same thing with targets as
operators so similar surveillance
capabilities as stock over right we have
parents using it against their kids and
then schools as well there was a six
hundred and ten thousand dollar
settlement from a school in Seattle that
was trying to use the webcam of the
students to spy on the students and
schools more and more are looking to
bring on stalker where or spyware to
help combat school violence and to make
sure that students are doing what
they're supposed to be doing so there's
that companies so the FTC actually
banned Retina X from selling stock aware
so that was good and then in March ish
when the covered stuff went down bosses
were like oh my god how are we gonna you
know watch our employees right so
they were scrambling by spy software to
monitor their employees so this is a
very relevant like thing that happens
like now right now cybercrime
hacktivists I don't need to go into that
so criminals also use the spyware
stalker where and terrorist so here's a
good story El Chapo loved to use spyware
against his partners and leaders in his
organization but ultimately the stalker
where spyware is what enabled the FBI to
collect intel on him and take him down
so this is where paranoia does not pay
law enforcement so Miami police have its
own stark aware made called pen link the
Swedish police got approval to install
spyware on criminals phones starting in
March of 2020 so a couple months ago and
then a city lab revealed that celebrate
allows cops to gather visible and hidden
or deleted data and they also invest in
cell phone interception devices that's
that you like official term whatever and
then of course previously I shared how
motherboard filed a complaint against
the Metropolitan Police of like hey
you're using this like why are you using
this and believe it or not nation-state
threat actors so previously I shared the
stealth mango lookout report and that
was a nation state using stalker where
spyware to surveil specific targets and
then also too reckless one an apt group
so heavier Valdes Cardenas he was known
for investigating drug cartels and so
what happened was a few
days after his death assassination his
colleagues were actually targeted by
Pegasus to by a Mexican apt to find out
what the heck what's going on so yeah so
now we're gonna get into a little bit of
tradecraft
of the various sectors so this one I'm
calling Kimber it's just your typical
average you know I guess privacy
violator that likes to use shared
accounts like shared email accounts that
I've Find My Phone
dual use apps and they try to
unilaterally control and manipulate the
situation manipulate friends and family
and of course emotional and
psychological abuse unethical use of
social engineering so the next the next
flavor of thread actors that like to use
this is are the commodity stark aware or
spyware abusers and of course with this
is included emotional and psychological
abuse as well and then we take it up a
step with Electra and Electra likes to
use em right they're a little bit more
technical they're up to date on social
engineering techniques and like you know
you know how some how some thread actors
they're like really super noisy and
you're like wow like they have no skill
whatsoever right well these people they
know to like be quiet and listen and
just wait for the opportune moment to
strike or to take what it is that they
want and they also use emotional and
psychological abuse as well
finally poison Hydra so this one likes
to use physical threats slash abuse
slash if you don't do this for me you
know
love me if you don't do this you can't
see your kids again on and on right on
and of course emotional and
psychological abuse again so now we're
to the CTI hypotheses and the normal use
of commodity stocker we're so with this
I recommend getting up to speed on
what's in your environment so that you
can better engage this emerging threat
of stalker where which is a common
suggestion right the other one is mobile
device management BYOD definitely taking
a look at that and what you have going
on there's actually a really interesting
report that came out recently and I
really want you to listen to what it is
that I'm about to say
checkpoint discovered that 75% of a
multinational companies mobile devices
were infected with an M rat and the way
that the apt you know attacker ended up
doing that is they compromised their
mobile device management server and then
what they did is they used that to push
out an emirate to all of the orgs mobile
devices this is a big deal because when
anyone accessed the corporate resources
with creds those creds along with the
2fa codes were compromised so at the end
of the story the org had to do a factory
reset for all mobile devices this is
something that I feel organizations
aren't necessarily counting on happening
and I'm telling you now be forewarned
and be aware that this is possible and
to just try to understand your landscape
before it happens if it does so the
other thing is stock aware vendors right
they
turi ously have horrible security
practices
I took one just one and I threw them
into show Dan and I was like holy crap
I mean it's pretty normal you know for
small businesses to have a you know RDP
and SM be available to anyone on the
internet but yeah it just takes you know
one person to decide that they're bored
right and the other thing is miss
configs they typically a spy phone for
instance they had an s3 bucket and API
issue kids guard had a msconfig on a
server and lost like a ton of data they
get breached all the time by hacktivists
like hacktivists hate hate stalker where
vendors so it's just basically a matter
of time
sometimes the the transmission of the
data is unencrypted you know
man-in-the-middle might be possible and
also two notable mention the hacking
team that sells spyware to governments
was hacked and then gamma international
was hacked to and documents on thin
fisher a government spy tool was
released so here are some just some of
the stock aware vendor breaches ret
retina x was breached two times flexi
spy mobi stealth spy master pro spy
humans by phone hello spy the true spy
family orbit mSpy copy 9x nor blog you
can read it a lot so this made me think
like there are statistics out there
based on what domestic violence you know
what the what the portion of the
population is so what i decided to do
was take i don't know let's say a sample
size of about
20,000 employees right and I split it
into 50/50 just cuz let's not get into
all that right and so the domestic
violence since this is some stock aware
is generally directed towards people
that are affected by domestic violence
the women one out of three women are
impacted by domestic violence and men
one out of six
so let's let's take those figures right
so if fifty fifty percent times twenty
thousand times thirty three percent for
women that's three give or take three
thousand employees right and then men
1667 so the other the other statistic is
that approximately fifty four percent of
domestic violence victims are tracked
with stock aware according to the and an
e DV which is a domestic violence
organization that helps people so if you
take all those numbers and you take all
those figures and you multiply it by a
point you know
five four that gets thirteen point five
percent of your employees were impacted
by starka where at one point in their
lives give or take so why would we care
and it's at some point in their lives
right so the reason why this is a big
deal is that I'll give you a two brief
scenarios so the first one is ransomware
actors right so they've kind of shifted
their tactics again and let's say you're
a big company right and you're a third
party vendor that has like higher
critical data gets compromised and the
ransomware actor is like oh you know we
look through the third-party vendors
data and we saw that we had really
sensitive data or information from big
company X over here right let's try to
extort them
so how how difficult would it be for
these ransomware actors to compromise a
stock aware vendor right and sift
through all of the data and go after
these companies that have sensitive data
that wasn't supposed to be leaked in the
first place thanks to stock aware and
then try to extort them right the other
the other angle to look at is that let's
let's let's take ransomware out of the
picture let's take all of that out of
the picture and let's just say that
let's just say that the struck or wonder
vendor stark aware vendor is breached
right and people recognize or realize
that some of the data that is in there
is related to your organization and
let's say that it it's damaging right or
it could serve as additional proof for
lawsuits or god knows what so that's
also another angle to consider so here
are some CTI hypotheses of repurposed
piece of stock aware so instead insider
threats right they can install hacking
tools on personal devices install stock
aware and attempt to pivot on to the
corporate network through IOT printer or
some other weakness the other thing is
data X well if I have stock aware on my
personal device and I want to get these
out you know whatever this document
whatever this meeting and I want to get
it out of the organization but I can't
because a DLP or god knows what right so
if I just take stock aware in there and
hold my phone up um like that's easy
right
the other thing is unintentional insider
threats so those are the people that are
in domestic violence situations that are
just leaking data and not intentionally
so it could be non
non-intentional to the other thing is
executives employ and employees so for
instance Jeff Bezos is AI iPhone his
iPhone it was a hacked and it gave the
attackers access to his photos and text
I mean if he can get hacked right so
that's something to consider as well
competitors competitors can track
especially maybe not necessarily in the
age of koban but let's say non-coated
and they're tracking your CEO or one of
the strategic individuals at your
organization and who they're meeting
with to possibly discern like insider
information insider trading business
negotiations all of that so that's
something to consider as well the next
one industrial espionage I'm not gonna
name names here but hopefully this slide
is kind of speaks for itself
so stalker where or repurpose stock
aware gives nation states and other
countries and easy in to do whatever
they want as well so what are some
solutions that corporate America can
have right so citizens lab they put out
a report a page 37 38 or so and there's
some I ox in there that you can use the
other thing you know to block and to
make sure that they're properly
categorized to see if there's traffic in
your environment and I'll talk more
about this in a little bit and then also
to make sure like or at least encourage
employees not to jailbreak their phones
not to use WeChat or tik-tok so those
are some things to consider another
thing you can do are tabletops
so you can think about you know let's
say you know the average employees
walking around or your seaso or someone
like that right and you think how can i
monetize this data if I was able to
steal it so having a tabletop on that
you know in the event of poor security
practices which will happen of stock or
where vendors how and let's say that
they have a misconfigured s3 bucket and
your data is just sitting up there and
you didn't know about it until you know
some security Reacher researchers like
yo your data is up here and then you try
to reach out to the stark aware vendor
but like they're not taking takedown
requests like what what do you do like
how do you escalate in your organization
the other thing is previously how we
spoke about ransomware actors like what
happens if they try to extort your
organization for a third party getting
compromised and them finding they have
your sensitive data what do you do and
then the other thing is the mobile
device management so how how how would
an attacker compromise your mobile
device management server do you have the
server what's your solution do you not
have a solution like what would you do
um you know how would you analyze the
apks like like how how would you deal
with with it if 75% of your mobile
devices that had you know your your - if
a token and all that other stuff got
compromised like think about that so
awareness Chris Cox and operations safe
escape they have a wonderful thing going
on I would definitely check out what
they do I have links on here also to
stop stock aware org it's a part of EF F
and Ava and a bunch of like different
companies AV vendors get together and
they're like
yeah stalker war is bad and we should
probably like do something about it so
they're doing something about it um some
some suggestions is you know never leave
your cell phone unattended always delete
unused applications apps on your phone
regularly search for suspicious apps as
well
use a quality password manager and then
change your smartphone passcodes
regularly don't jailbreak your phone and
existing avian spyware tools are kind of
ineffective so don't necessarily rely on
that and for Android what you want to do
is check the device administrators look
make sure that Google Play protect is
not not disabled and and and look to to
see if install apps from unknown sources
is enabled if that's enabled like you
cop problems
so some resources for corporate America
tall poppy dot IO they have a wonderful
program that works with corporate
America to deal with these specific
situations of technological abuse and
dealing with stock aware and all of that
I'd suggest checking them out safe
escape org the National Coalition
Against Domestic Violence and n EDB stop
stock aware dot org also to Cornell
Tech's they have a client centered
clinical computer security practice to
help people they have a tech
consultation questionnaire as well
so you know we learned about stock aware
we learned about spyware Emre dual use
apps basically it's an emerging threat
that can impact and has impacted
corporate America from CEOs down to
employees down to 75% of the mobile
devices at an organization so you need
to do organization specific threat
modeling especially since there's
sub-optimal AV detection like you can't
rely on the AV vendors right now or well
we won't get into that but definitely do
not rely on the AV vendors for stalker
where detection like just don't thank
you so much but wait there's there's
something weird with that slide
technical difficulties hold on one
second oh good okay we got that settled
so where were we oh we were gonna talk
about reverse engineering uh Android
apks okay so let's say let's say on the
off chance you know you get something in
your organization and you're like crap
like I have to learn how to reverse
engineer these like out of the blue
because a bunch of people got impacted
and we can't upload it to virustotal
because well we can't right so what I
did I use Chum on X's YouTube videos and
explanation where she goes through tools
and goes through some general techniques
that you would need to reverse engineer
apks so I'm gonna show you the
difference between the two so that you
can know if I can do it in an evening so
can you so don't be scared and you got
this
so the first one apktool so I use that
to decompile the AAP ki apk that I
picked I'm not going to name which one
and basically on here you can see the
various permissions from the Android
manifest file that I managed to get and
so it describes you know like the
different things that I can get so I'm
gonna read it here like the call log
data SMS I can write and read to
external storage like I can check the
network state the contacts the camera I
can read the calendar okay cool so we
got that so in in the decompiled
you know APK there was something called
classes.dex and i was like i need to
read that but i can't read the dex file
so what I used I used x2 jar to convert
it to a jar file so that I could later
read the contents in JD GUI so then as
you can see there a highlighted the
hard-coded URL that was in that
particular apk so now let's say that
your org isn't in danger and you just
want to dabble and you're curious about
what's going on with starka where apks
anyways right so here's the quick and
easy when you don't necessarily have to
be concerned about privacy issues or
anything like that so I went to
decompiler comm I uploaded the stock
aware apk and OH
lo and behold there are you know
permissions on there almost exactly it's
exactly the same that I got from
manually doing it so next I uploaded
that particular sample to virustotal it
hit it got hit by eleven out of 61
engines still not a very good
um yeah so then what I did is I looked
at the permissions so it gives you the
permission so you don't have to
decompile it all of that you get that
information right there and then it also
gave me the interesting strings so that
was also very helpful and just for
giggles
I threw it into hybrid analysis and I
got the TTP's so if you let's say you
don't have to manually assign the TPS
right you just want to know for the hell
of it
it does that for you so you can throw
the sample up there and just for fun I
started doing
deidre and using that to reverse
engineer too but then I was like well I
don't you have all the data I need and
like I have other projects I needed to
work on so I it's tons of fun and it's
definitely something that I'll come back
to and learn how to do in giedrius as
well so now we are going to pivot and
look at ascent and other stuff so I took
what I had right I had the eye ox and
information from citizens lab and a lot
of that data was pulled in 2018 as we
all know I ox can get old allegedly so I
started there and as we go along this I
started creating a list and putting all
the stuff I found in the list which I'm
sharing with all of you later so I threw
a random you know email I threw them all
into virustotal
and then I went to the files that were
related to that as well and you can see
that I highlighted it there and then I
clicked on it and I was like oh look
another domain of something thats
related to stock aware right so I
included that on the list as well and
then the next phase was going through
each and every single stock aware vendor
that was breached and seeing what I
could find on buyers total that was
related
and then I don't know if you've been on
Twitter lately but there was a big you
know InfoSec Twitter was like how dare
you
this one publishing company article and
it had to do with spying on your wife so
I was like okay I'll use that as a
google search and see what comes up so I
went through item by item by item and
pulled out the relevant information and
searched embarrassed total and then
added it to a list next step Google Play
Store so I typed in like a name of like
a popular popular spyware and then a
bunch of options popped up so I just
clicked on various options and I looked
for websites that were related to the
developer went there and then pivoted
off of that the other thing is SSL certs
in this one I typed in flexi spy and got
two additional domains and so
interestingly enough these two domains
they more or less gave a rundown of like
what the various stores did what you get
for your money like why you want to use
one over another all of that so I added
those domains to lists just cuz like
yeah but next I looked at the security
researchers so Anna screw tables he has
an awesome github page with a ton of
information he's given talks on this
subject like she's super passionate
about it I highly recommend checking him
out if you get a chance he knows his
stuff and he'll said I oxen there that I
that I updated and searched and added
and then made him the contributor
contributor for those and here's another
one I I used the hashtag stalker where
and apk and amazingly and his crew
tables popped up with like detailed
information of like you know stalker
where's so
I added whatever iooks I can pull out of
that to the list as well another search
that I did a malware hunter team goes
without speaking right they're freaking
awesome so I entered that and then apk
into Twitter and bam like a huge you
just keep scrolling and in in in the
post they go like not very good
detection like warning warning warning
so I pulled some of those i aux out and
added it to the list and then provided
proper attribution to them the other
thing so with all of these URLs just to
you know keep things neutral or whatever
I went to Lenny's alters website and on
there he has like a long list of like
how to look up malicious websites right
so I picked two you randomly I'm not
beating up on anyone I didn't single
whatever blah right so the first one I
tried was bright cloud and it was the
true spy com it was like a really big
stock aware name where like if you know
anything about stock aware like that
one's kind of popular so with that one I
threw that in there and it came back as
malicious and hacking and keylogger and
then I was like huh well that's good
news right but then I threw the same the
same domain into IBM X horse and it came
back as education and health so after
after this talk I'm gonna go and suggest
an edit on that one so just think about
your proxy and what's going on at your
organization you know are your employees
allowed to shop for stalker where well
on company time and on your company
device things like that so there was a
lot of information in here and a lot of
research went into this talk so what I
did is I created a website it'll be
tweeting out I think now ish from my
account and
it's sites.google.com / view / stalker
where and on there I have a takeaway
section where I did a threat summary
report for y'all to include in your
threat intelligence platform or to
copy/paste and do whatever you want with
it and then I also have the indicators
of compromised as well and then I also
have a form of submission of you know
give me your stock aware iooks so that
we can add them to the list if you feel
like it and then I have a contact me
page as well and I included two videos
so the first one is from EB C and they a
lady reporter is given a phone to watch
her male colleague for I think it was 2
days so you get to see like when I said
I was surveilled give or take for about
for two years like you get to see in two
days what I lived with for almost two
years and it gives you a good
perspective of what employees you know
what your employees might go through
people in domestic violence situations
how it can be used against your
organization so definitely check that
out and then also - for just a general
overview stop stalker where the
coalition against stalker where they did
a really good video that was released
recently so I also linked that on the
page
and if you hate Google Sites I also
created a github as well specifically
for this where it uploaded the I ox in a
CSV format so you can easily get the
data without having to use a try to get
it from a PDF right and then also the
threat summary report so it's at github
calm /ch 3-3 r10 forward slash stalker
we're all lowercase
so we're at the end thank you so much
for coming to my talk
thank you everyone involved with the
help of the research putting this
together putting the conference together
sticking with me till the end that's me
and you'll find me on the Twitter's and
there's that as well I will you know
black lives matter and definitely if you
get a chance try to look at some black
owned businesses and see how you can
incorporate that into your like normal
buying schedule I did so finally I will
upload these slides as well there's a
ton of references on a per slide basis
and then those are all the references
that I condensed for y'all and then of
course research thank you so much and
that's it thank you cheerio
you