you
okay there we go
say we got some video alright everyone
thanks for joining I am Mike Saunders
hard water hacker on Twitter today I
want to talk to you about buffer
overflow 101 will let you know that you
can get these slides at red siege comm
CIP and those slides will have all the
demonstrations that I did today as well
as links to the resources that I'm going
to talk about and some practice
resources that you can find at the end
of the deck that you can use so standard
about me principle consult with Fred
seeds NIT a while and insecurity a while
and when I'm not doing the security
stuff you can probably find me kayaking
or playing the guitars back there or
maybe out doing some bacon so why am I
talking to you about buffer overflow 101
this this isn't a new topic
this has been around and it hasn't
changed since a since smashing the stack
for fun and profit came out in 1995 well
the real reason I'm doing this is when I
was learning buffer overflows which
honestly wasn't that long ago I felt
like buffer overflow was well I think
this gif pretty much sums it up it felt
like magic to me I knew that a buffer
overflow was you had this buffer in
memory and you took some data and he
pushed too much data into that buffer
and bad stuff happened but I didn't
understand any more than that and as I
was learning it and starting to get
comfortable I was I was noticing that
you know on Twitter people that I follow
are asking about buffer overflows just
getting started with it and naturally
because of imposter syndrome I assume
that I know nothing and they know
everything if they're asking about
buffer overflows then why like why are
they doing that because they should all
know that and these were people that
have been around awhile and in talking
and friends you know just realized that
this is a basic concept that a lot of us
don't learn right away some of us many
don't learn for a long time
and there's so many new people coming
into the industry all the time that
don't have the background that is always
going to be a relevant topic or at least
you know for quite a while so that's why
I'm talking to you about buffer overflow
101 now to talk about that I do need to
get some assumptions out there I'm
talking about buffer overflows in a
32-bit architecture x86 architecture
these aren't any kinds of advanced
buffer overflows we're not doing wrap
chains we're not doing SCH type things
this is a standard stack face buffer
overflow where we overwrite a return
address and gain execution control there
are no protections in place when we're
doing this there's no depth there's no a
SLR I happen to be doing this on a
Windows XP machine but this would work
in Windows 10 as long as you don't have
some kind of some kind of a V or EDR in
place it's going to block the buffer
overflow attempts this will also work
you know these key concepts translate to
things like ARM architecture or 64-bit
architecture they aren't exactly the
same but a lot of the concepts are
similar so you can use this as a
starting point so what is a buffer
overflow we should define that this is
not a buffer overflow this tweet was
gold I was really glad I was able to
snag it when when sub T tweeted it out
so a buffer overflow at its most basic
is a program incorrectly allows writing
more data into a buffer than it did
previously allocated space for and that
causes adjacent memory to be overwritten
and possibly bad things to happen so if
you have 500 bytes that you write into a
buffer and/or you allocate 500 bytes
into for a buffer and then you write in
600 bytes
you've written in 500 bytes and you
filled up your buffer and that
additional hundred bytes goes into the
adjacent memory there so that's what
happens when a buffer overflow happens
how you get execution control and
actually exploit a system we will walk
through that I will talk you through
works oops screen here so before we do
that I have to give you some background
I talked about the stack a couple of
times possibly the stack is a data
structure it stores data in contiguous
blocks in its temporary storage in RAM
it's typically used to store local data
things like parameter values data about
the particular function that you're in
for instance Maine and these various
subroutines each one will have its own
memory space something called a return
address which we will get into and an
important thing to know about the stack
is that it is a last in first out
architecture or data type so if you
think of going to a buffet and they have
that stack of plates and if you push
down on it it goes down and it pops back
up if you put five plates on to that
stack and you push them on to the stack
of plates and that's the terminology we
push things on to the stack if you want
to get that first plate that you took
off you have to take off the previous
four plates you have to pop them off the
stack so the last thing to go in the
stack is the first thing that come off
the stack and that will become important
here as we walk through this so I'm
gonna give you a visualization of the
stack this isn't entirely accurate but
it's going to work for our purposes
today so this is an example of a stack I
talked about main right so if you think
about your main routine that would be
the parent routine down here and let's
say we had a sub routine just called
process this is the process subroutine
here we've called process and it's this
is its memory space process has a 50
byte variable foo it's got some other
things that are pushed on the stack like
frame pointers and base pointers and
they're all important and we're not
going to talk about any of them the
thing we are going to talk about is
right here this return address and the
return address tells the program how to
get back to the parent routine how to
get back to main or whatever function
called it once it's done executing now
some of you may be looking at this and
thinking that I have this backwards it's
upside-down and you probably learn
buffer overflows or you learned about
memory structure in school and you'll
notice up here at the top is all zeros
at the bottom sis is all F's so if you
learned it in school you probably
learned with all zeros on the bottom and
F's on the top and there's nothing wrong
with that with that model and it's it's
probably a better way to do it the
reason I use this is this is how I
learned the examples that I followed
laid it out this way and the debugger
that I use lays it out this way
so I'm going to use this model just be
aware that as you're learning and you're
researching if you come across a scarlet
scholarly article and you're used to
using a model like this they may have it
flipped and it'll be somewhat bit
wildering you don't think that
everything you knew was wrong until you
realize what's going on so a few more
things to point out because memory
addresses are at the bottom in this
model if we were to pop foo off the
stack the memory addresses are getting
higher right like each entry in the
stack has a higher memory address and if
we were to push more data on to the
stack for instance like this the memory
address gets lower now
we've pushed bar onto the stack you'll
see that this ESP or top of stack moved
an ESP is a register stands for the
stack pointer and keeps track of where
is the uppermost memory address of the
stack so if we push bar onto the stack
after foo ESP gets updated to point to
this location but if we were to pop bar
off the stack then now all we have left
is foo on the stack in ESP has been
updated to point to the top of foo here
so the ESP will keep track of where the
stack is at where the uppermost address
or rather the lower most address in the
stack if you're using this model
ESP address moves higher as stack
shrinks address moves lower is the stack
rose there are other registers the
accumulator stack pointer is the only
one we're going to talk about these
registers historically had a more
defined purpose nowadays there we use
can be fairly flexible and those
decisions are made at compile time a lot
of times there is a special purpose
register called VIP that is the extended
instruction pointer you'll notice all of
those general-purpose registers started
with e4 extended that's because we're in
the 32-bit architecture if we were in
16-bit it would just be the instruction
pointer the instruction pointer stores
address stores the address of the next
instruction to be executed it does not
store the instruction to be executed it
does not store data about the
instruction or anything else it stores
the address of the next instruction to
be executed it's an important thing to
remember it stores an address if you can
control what goes into EIP you could
control what execution is going to
happen next you can control what command
is gonna is going to be executed and
contrary to popular opinion you will
hear people say I over wrote a I P I
will probably screw it up and say it at
some point today you do not over iTIP
you overwrite the return address what
gets loaded into EIP
e IP for the most part can only be
modified directly through the kernel so
let's take a look at a buffer overflow
what does it look like in the stack this
is a simple command line program running
on a Linux system but it would be not
different doing it in a Windows
environment we talked about that parent
routine process right this is the parent
routine here main and main calls foo
with one argument that's an argument
that it gets on the command line if we
look at foo foo declares one variable
here C we're gonna use ster copy so
we're not going to check to see if
things fit we're just gonna copy what we
received on the command line into C and
then we are going to print what's in C
out to the screen now you'll notice
there is no return here we're not
reading says return back to main that's
because that is built-in at compile time
the instruction on how to get back to
main and where it will go to will be
immediately after what called it so it
called it here it will go to the next
instruction return zero and then we'll
exit the program and it knows how to get
there because of that return address and
we'll take a look at that so this is
what the stack for the program would
look like for the most part we've got
our parent routines stacked down at the
bottom which is going to be main and
this is gonna be foo and here's our
variable see we've got some other things
below C and then we've got the return
address that's what tells it how to get
back to main now if we were to run this
program let's say let's run demo hello
it runs it prints out hello to the
screen in a Texas normally that's what
we would expect to happen
there was no we didn't put too much data
in shouldn't be any problem if we were
to look at the stack for the program we
don't understand why we put in a hello
we put in five bytes there's actually a
six byte here and that is because
strings in c and c++ are null terminated
so we pushed in hello and our null
terminator we did not fill up the rest
of this buffer so that C was popped off
the stack and then the rest of the data
was popped off the stack and the return
address popped off the stack loaded into
EIP that takes us back to main and we
exit out of main but what if we gave it
too much data in this case 16 a's and
four bytes a hex cc's i run that we
print out the a's in the hex to this
screen and then there's a segmentation
fault and think about that order that i
just said
I ran the program with the input we
printed the data out to the screen we
put more than 12 bytes into the buffer
we put 20 bytes into the buffer it still
printed that out to the screen and then
a segmentation fault occurred and if we
look at our code we can you know we can
understand what's happening here we push
this into the we push this into the
buffer and then we printed it out and
then the segmentation fault happened
it's an important thing to know it's
important but subtle distinction and if
we look at the stack we understand why
we've got 12 bytes of AIDS we filled up
our buffer but then we pushed in another
four bytes into what was a base planter
or frame point or something like that
and then we pushed in these hexie sees
that over wrote the return address so at
that point when that return address was
popped off the stack yeah I see IP would
have been si si si si si si si si and
that is not a spot where code for our
program lives in memory and therefore
the program doesn't know what
instruction to execute X and it crashes
that is a buffer overflow at its most
basic so let's see if we can weaponize
that I'm gonna pray to the demo gods
I've got a backup presentation so we're
gonna go over here and hopefully this
all comes through I've got a Python
script and I will have a link to the
Python scripts that I used during this
talk available for you at the end of the
talk so I'm gonna fuzz the input length
of this program actually you know what
before we do this let's go back let's
talk about this I'm gonna do a demo with
a program called bone server bone
servers written by Steven Bradshaw it's
an intentionally vulnerable program that
allows you to learn how to write buffer
overflows if you think of how a web
server works if you were to netcat to
the port and you have a verb that you
give it get then you have a couple of
arguments you have what you want to get
slash and then the protocol you want to
speak HTTP 1.1 HTTP 1.0
you hit enter and that sends a carriage
return line view to the server that
tells the server hey I'm done sending
you input you can go ahead and process
and then it sends you whatever you
requested in much the same fashion von
server has a suite of verbs one of them
is tea run and if you enter tea run
space period the server processes
whatever data is after that period and
it signifies the end of the input by
sending a carriage return line view and
then it will process that data SAT run
complete so what we're gonna do is we're
gonna fudge the input length for the tea
run command so we're not fuzzing like a
protocol here we're not doing you know
some wire and wire protocol fuzzing or
PDF or whatever we're fuzzing the input
length so this Python script sets up a
counter and yes Python to point whatever
I know
needs to be updated we've got this
counter that we set up and it initially
sets at 100 we've got our command to
your own space period and we set up an
empty list called buffer we're gonna
populate that list with entries that
consists of our command to your own
space period and some number of A's
which is a times the counter and then
we're going to increase our counter and
the next line in our list is going to be
tea run slaves period with 200 more A's
and we're gonna continue on until we
filled that up and then we're going to
take and send this data to the server
we're gonna connect to the socket and
we're gonna send our data we're gonna
receive a response and we're gonna print
it out to the screen so we're gonna look
at a debugger here we're gonna look at
the immunity debugger you can see that
volunteers running I've got it loaded
this here that we're that we're looking
at that's actually the assembly language
code right there that is push EBP and
you know move a X those are assembly
language instructions that are
translated from our code that's how this
program works
I mentioned registers that's what's over
here these are the registers so we've
got EAX and
ESP our stack planner that's one we're
really going to want to pay attention to
right here stack planner planning 222 f3
AC right now we also see a IP so this
because we know that e IP contains we
know that e IP contains memory addresses
of the next instruction and not the
instruction itself this is a memory
address that lives in ntdll and that's
the next instruction that the programs
can execute and we can go here we can
look at the stack we can follow on stack
so this is our stack here this is where
ESP is currently planning we can see
that there's data in the stack here our
programs running everything's fine so
let's go ahead and run this gonna run
the module we're gonna see that it sends
a bunch of input right so it starts at
100 then 300 500 and it keeps saying t
run complete just like we expected until
we get to here 2100 bytes we send input
but we don't get any response back from
the server now if we were to go and take
a look at our debugger we see that it is
passé now and we see access violation
when executing 41 41 41 41
that means access violation when trying
to execute the command that lives it 4
to 1 41 41 41 we go up here there's no
code there is no code here and if we
look at our registers we submit see some
interesting things we see that EAX has
our command and then we see the ESP is
pointing to a location that's filled
with a z' that's what we sent the server
one other
want to point out here is that a IP is
also 41 41 41 41 that's what that's what
this means here that means e IP was
populated with the memory address where
it didn't know how to find code now if
we were to go and look at this we'll
follow it in stack we see here's our
stack so this is currently the top of
the stack we can see that there's a
bunch of a s that happened before there
and if we scroll up far enough we'd see
T around space period and then we can
see that they're a is afterwards now we
know that from what we've already talked
about the return address is something
that gets pushed on the stack and then
loaded into e IP so it's just a memory
address that's pushed onto the stack
if a I P is 41 41 41 we see that all
these are 41 41 41 and these are all A's
here that means that we have written
overwritten the return address with our
capital S and those capital a is were
loaded interred D loaded into e IP this
is an ASCII capital a in hex that's what
41 is so we have overwritten a return
address which subsequently got loaded
into the IP we don't know how much data
it took to get there we don't know
anything at this point we just know that
it was possible to do this so the key
points here it took between 1900 and
2100 bytes of input and when that
happened VIP is overwritten with Ras so
how do we find out if it's possible to
know exactly how much data it would take
before we over wrote the return address
there are multiple ways to do it and I
cover a different way in the slides that
you can download but here I'm going to
use pattern create which is a Metasploit
utility it will create a non-repeating
string of characters up up to about 20
thousand bytes before it starts to
repeat I forget exactly where it's at
but you can see here I ran the command
pattern create a shell 2500 it created
this capital a little a zero capital a
little a one so on and so forth and
we're gonna send that to the server and
see what
happens so I've got another Python
script here and I look at my Python
script I don't have a list anymore
because I'm just gonna send my can tear
on space period I'm gonna add that
string of characters that I generated
with pattern create and I'm gonna send
that to the server you see that bond
server is running so let's go ahead and
send that you send it program has
crashed and if we go over here to our
debugger we see that it has paused
access violation when executing 3 9 6 F
4 3 3 8 look up here there's no code we
see that E I P is what we expect 3 9 6 F
4 3 3 8 excuse me IP and if we look at
ESP let me see it's pointing to this
memory location that's filled with
capital C lowercase P Zero and a/c so
let's go ahead and look at this let's go
down right here we see a bunch of data
in the stack and if we look immediately
before where the SP is pointing so if
you remember that slide about the top of
stack this is where the top of stack is
pointing right here we see here 3 9 6 F
4 3 3 8 it's the same value that's any
IP in fact that's because this is where
the return address lives in the input we
loaded that return address into e IP and
then it crashed 3 9 6 F 4 3 3 8 now
since we know that those 40 ones were
actually the capital a is this must be
ascii hex representations of ascii
characters here and in fact they are a
39 is a nine if 38 is an eight but wait
if we look here it's 8 c 0 9 or 8 c o9
but we look here the 9 is on the left
and the 8 is on the right the reason is
because we are on a little endian system
so data gets pushed on the stack and
reverse byte order if we were big endian
smalls and popping mainframes our stack
would be our system would be big and
so we would just push it in in the order
that we wanted but it is not it's Little
Indians so we have to push it in Reverse
byte order helpfully immunity has
reversed that for us so we know now that
this is where that's occurring we still
don't know how many bytes it is but we
know that as soon as the overflow occurs
the stack pointer is pointing to the
next section of data after where the
return address was we're gonna write
down 3 9 6 f 4 3 3 8 we're gonna go back
and look at another utility now what
we're gonna look at is the compliment to
pattern create which is something called
pattern offset we've run pattern offset
- cue 3 9 6 f 4 3 3 8 it tells us the
exact match is at offset 2006 so what
that means is it took exactly 2006 bytes
of input before we reached the first
byte of our return address so knowing
that if we were to safe put in 2006 a s
and then four B's and 50 sees the return
address should be populated with 42 42
42 42 which means that's what a IP
should be when the program crashes so
let's take a look at that got another
Python script here and that's exactly
what we're doing we're sending our
command some 2006 a's four B's a bunch
of seas and we expect the e IP will be
42 42 42 alright so let's look access
violation when executing 42 42 42 42 so
now we know that it is exactly 2006 by
its before we reach the first byte of
the return address VIP is 42 we see that
the stack pointer seems to be pointing
to a location that's filled with C's we
follow the stack we see just as we
expected the bees were right before the
C's started so now
we know that when the program crashes
data that we control was loaded into EIP
and immediately following that is where
our shellcode could go if we were able
to inject shellcode and the stack
pointer is pointing to that so it would
be really cool if we could have a way of
telling the computer go to where ESP is
go to ESP and execute code and in fact
there is an instruction called jump ESP
that tells the processor to jump to the
location that ESP is referencing so we
can go to ESP but we can't just put jump
ESPN I'll show you how to look up the OP
code for that cuz that's going to be
important but we can't just put that
into these bytes where the bees are
because remember that return address is
exactly that it's an address it's not an
instruction so we can't put the OP code
for jump ESP in there because we're just
gonna get an access violation when
trying to load whatever that off code is
so we need to find the we need to find
something called NASM shell excuse me
another Metasploit utility if we use
NASM shell and we put in jump ESP will
tell us that the OP code for that is FF
e for so we can't put FF e for into that
into the returned address because the
computer's not gonna know what to do
with that we need to find a memory
address where the FF v4 lives so to do
that in immunity I'm going to use a
script called Mona Mona is written by
coral and some great people peter is
wonderful and if we load Mona one of the
things we're gonna do got a clue right
here module C windows system32 user is
32 that DLL gonna run bang Mona modules
and modules are dll's
and other bits of code that are loaded
with our program that these dll's are
needed for our program to run like if we
want to have networking we're gonna need
networking capabilities loaded by dll's
so we see a bunch of you
you know things that probably look
familiar to a lot of you usually 32 and
ntdll kernel32.dll most of these all
look familiar and then we see Vaughn
server itself and something else called
ESS funky DLL which happens to be looks
like part of Vaughn server now over here
these are memory addresses these are
memory addresses where that DLL is is
living so if we could find a location
within this memory space a memory that
has a jump ESP we could use it a couple
of things point out one thing we want to
pay attention to a SLR there's no
address space layout randomization
meaning we don't have to deal with that
because this is 101 level another thing
to point out here OS dll's so os dll's
means that these are loaded with part of
the operating system or not like our
program here a third party that we've
loaded now what we want to look for is a
jump ESP and FF II for living in one of
these modules these OS lo these OS dll's
could be used for finding a jump ESP and
we could do that let's say we find a
jump ESP and usually 32 that DLL I can
use that right now and that would be
fine the problem is that these addresses
vary depending on what patch level on
what service pack you're on even what
language pack you're on if you're
running XP service pack 3 French
language pack and I'm running English
jump ESP might be in a different
location for you than it is for me and
that's part of the reason why if you've
ever use Metasploit and asked you to
select your target sometimes you need to
do that so that it knows which return
address to use for that particular
exploit so we could use these but we
don't want to because we would have to
be able to fingerprint the targets know
exactly what OS it's running and past
level when we wanted XY
but if there happens to be one here in
ESS funk DLL we could use that one
because this is something that's bundled
with our program it's going to be there
as long as we're running version 1.0 a
Vaughn server every time that jump ESP
should be in the same place every time
so we can use Moana to find those so
we're gonna use another command Mona
find - s oops
remember that our opcode is FF e for and
then we use shim is s funk dll tells it
to search within that module so we run
it we find a total of nine pointers so
that means there are nine jump PS PS in
this particular DLL you can see here the
first ones 6250 11 AF all the way down
to 60 250 12:05 they're all happening to
be living in a place called page execute
read meaning we have executable memory
so we can load this address for instance
6250 11 AF if we put 6250 11 AF into the
return address 6250 11 AF will be loaded
into eip the processor will then say -
next instruction is at 6250 11 1/2 it
will go to that location that will see
that that location says jump ESP will
now jump to where the stack pointer is
pointing to which happens to be the
start of our shellcode so this is all we
need to be able to exploit the system we
just need to build the shellcode in the
right manner and put everything together
so we have one more piece to do that
I've got a proof of concept that will
pop calc or something like it so I've
got my command T around space period I
generated some shell code with MSF venom
and I used platform windows architecture
x86 I'm using the windows exec payload
and I want to run
and dot exe /c calc daddy XE I'm gonna
pop calc exit func equals threat I will
talk about and I know there are some of
you in the chat right now they are much
better versed in this than I am so feel
free feel free to clarify if I'm if I'm
screwing up some of this language at
some point so we're using exit func
equals thread and I'll tell you why in a
little bit - II encoder I'm gonna use
the x86 Shikata gunaih encoder - b means
bad characters now you remember I told
you that strengths in C and C++ are null
terminated that's what this is right
here it's a null terminator reason we
don't want our shellcode to contain a
null terminator is because that would
signify it to the server
be like oh hey there's the end of the
input I can start doing my thing and it
would drop it would just truncate off
the rest of our shell code nothing's
gonna work we also have 0 + 0 D carriage
return in line feed because we know that
our protocol signifies the end of input
by sending a carriage return line field
so we don't want our shellcode to
contain any of these characters so that
we don't get truncated now I'm gonna run
this this is my shellcode here this is
my return address right here and
remember it's little endian system so
6250 11 AF it's backwards we need to
push it in in Reverse byte order so now
what we're gonna send to the server is
our command T run space period we're
gonna send in 2006 days you don't have
to use a s
you could use any number of characters
right I'm just using a is to make it
easy my return address is going
immediately after those 2006 days I'm
gonna use 8 hex 90s
no ops or knops they just tell the
processor don't do anything and the
reason why I will explain in a minute
and then after that is my shellcode and
then I'm just gonna send that to the
server we know that we're running so
let's go ahead and send it to the server
sadly this doesn't come to the
foreground like I like it but I got a
click on it but that is the exploit we
just exploited bone server and we
displayed this instead of pop in calc
and the reason I chose this is because
honestly that's still kind of how I feel
every time I get about for overflow
working and this is how I felt most
definitely the first time I ever did I
did the shell dance in my office when I
got that because it was a magical
feeling when I when I went on my own
without following someone's instructions
I took the things that I've talked to
you about here and I learned how they
work and I practiced and I found a
buffer overflow in a program that wasn't
bone server and then I figured out how
much data did it take till I could
overwrite the return address and then I
located a jump ESP and then I put it all
together was shellcode and then I was
able to go it was absolutely magical
feeling and so that's why I decided to
choose this instead of popping calc now
one fun thing I want to point out if I
can find the mouse there we go we look
down here we're still running one server
didn't crash this time and if we look
here we have an idea why thread 9e for
terminated now if you remember back in
the code I used boy where did that go
wrong one I use exit func equals thread
that tells that tells Metasploit to
generate code to generate a new thread
so my ex-wife takes place in a new
thread and execution control returns
back to the program and the program
doesn't crash if I had done process then
the program would crash when I closed
Explorer so I'm chosen
I want the thing to keep running now the
other thing that I want to show you is
because I did that I could run it again
and go back I can I can run it a few
more times and we're still running and
every time we're just generating new
threads and then they're executing and
the program still working the other
thing I told you I'd tell you about is
why I had those those hex 90s in there
now the hex 90s are in there because
they're they're just telling the
processor not to do anything but they're
really there because they're scratch
space we used an encoder and when you
use encoded shellcode it's just like
base64 data right it's encoded but you
can't do anything with it until it's
decoded our shellcode has been encoded
so it's not actually shellcode it's
something that's encoded what there is
is a little bit of a stub at the
beginning of the shellcode that tells
the processor how to decode the rest of
the shellcode
and those nops are in there for a
scratch space so that we don't overwrite
our shellcode this gives us the space to
decode without
decoding over ourselves and clobbering
our x-play so when we put this all
together we've gone from hey what is
Vaughn server - hey I know how to fuzz
this application and I can make it crash
and I can exploit it and make it still
run so what do you do after this like
okay I learn bone server but what do I
do next there are places that you can go
to find vulnerable programs there's lots
of them on the Internet one fun place is
just going to exploit database you can
search for these old buffer overflows
look for the early to mid-2000s buffer
overflows some are even later than that
if you've got these buffer overflows for
instance in many share the nice thing
about this is you can download the
vulnerable application from exploit
database and you can use their buffer
overflow that they've got an exploit
database is a starting point to just
help you understand and then start
working it on your own
excuse me but you can download these
programs and you can fuzz them using the
exact same process excuse me I showed
you there's even a bunch of mp3 players
back in the mid-2000s that were
vulnerable to buffer overflows because
of these badly formatted m3u playlists
the process for doing that is not
fundamental fundamental II different
than what I did here it's just that
instead of sending a bunch of data to a
socket we would have to generate a bunch
of m3u playlists and then open up each
one of them until we figured out how
much data we needed to overwrite the
return address but you can take this
process absolutely and use this to do
your own buffer overflow on a vulnerable
application so I told you there would be
some resources and those are coming up
but I do have to thank some people
stephen bradshaw for writing bone server
something that I could use to start
practicing buffer overflows if you know
Peter
corland coder a wonderful human being
and full of excellent information about
buffer overflows learned a lot there
ronbo is skull security if you know Ron
Ron is a
wizard and has a lot of great
information on the skull security wiki I
also want to thank these people for
these some good friends of mine that
they encourage me to do this talk and
then spent a lot of time helping me
refine this to make sure that what I was
telling you was exactly the information
that you needed without being too much
without leaving things out so thanks to
all these guys you can download vulvar
at that link and you can download moana
from coral and github and then there are
seven buffer overflow blogs that you can
follow the first happens to be Steven
Bradshaw's and we'll walk you through
various kinds of buffer overflows with
bone server core lan also has a great
series of buffer overflow tutorials that
go from easy to progressively more
complex and there's another one from
security sift there as well and by all
means just search on the internet you'll
find so many know that some of them were
poorly written in and that's just how it
goes and some of them are really well
done here's some resources just
background material for you stack buffer
overflows and how the stack works and
then a link to some fundamentals from
Skull security and there are some other
places you can practice over the wire
still has the over wire war gaming
network that has things like smash the
stack or a game and other games on there
that you can practice buffer overflows
and other kinds of security relevant
skills
there are also VMs you can download on
volta ball hub that have buffer
overflows in them that you can attack
there also are I believe there they're
still there and I think they're
available for the free accounts buffer
overflow resources at hack the box I
know that they have had them in the past
I haven't checked quite recently but I
believe they have them there so with
that I apparently was really juiced up
because I'm about three minutes ahead of
time but someone just asked will the
slides be available yes if you look at
the slide that is on the screen right
now you can get the slides at red siege
comm /e IP
you can get the you know what that link
for the source is wrong it's I'll have
to update that and I'll tweet it out you
can follow the hard water hacker twitter
account for the red seeds twitter
account but it's actually i underscore
its I want my e IP with underscores
instead of spaces or just go to
github.com slash hard water hacker and
you will find the Python scripts that I
used here and do not judge me based on
the code that you find in that
repository because I'm a hacker I'm not
a developer so if you have any questions
about this feel free to contact me I
reach out to me on Twitter please if you
want follow the Red Sea Twitter account
because that will give you information
about our new blogs that are coming out
and when we're doing our free webcasts
and I'm all about helping people learn
because that's how I got here people
helped me learn and answered questions
that quite frankly I just you know
didn't know where to go people helped me
and I want to try to return that so feel
free to contact me on on Twitter or
whatever my contacts information is here
on the slide so that's all I have at
this point and yeah Chris I'm gonna have
to rewatch it again that's that's how it
is for me I took quite a while
rewatching it at at speeds so I want to
thank all of you for being here thanks
Circle City Con staff and volunteers for
making this possible I really wish that
my first circle city con had been in
person but you know what this was this
was pretty awesome so that's all I have
help me out circle city con staff if
we're doing questions on the air or if
we're moving over to the track just let
me know
you