[Music]
da
foreign
[Music]
day
do
[Music]
data
day
[Music]
so
hello everyone uh welcome back to uh
day two of or 35 on the on behalf of the
program committee i'd like to welcome
you uh
i will be the session chair and the qa
monitor for the first two sessions today
up until a long break and palaviras
will be the timekeeper we would like to
thank
both farsight security and verisign as
our workshop sponsors
and uh without further ado i'd like to
welcome
dwayne vessels his presentation on
botnet traffic
observed at various levels of the dns
hierarchy
duane if you'd like to start sharing
your screen
all right so uh thanks jake it's great
to be here
and be able to interact with all of you
even if it's sort of virtually
um my name is dwayne wessels and uh
this is a joint joint effort with my
co-worker matt thomas who's
listening in today the titleist
presentation is
traffic at various levels of the dns
hierarchy
so this will be all about um this this
dns traffic that we see coming from a
particular
botnet and here's a little bit of
information about about the botnet
itself
um it has uh thousands of second level
domains
and a large it uses the thousands of
thousands of second level domains and a
large subset of those are in
common.net it has consistent and easily
identifiable third level
labels there's a very obfuscated example
there
we see a really even distribution of
queries coming from
recursive clients most of the queries
are of type a and a very small percent
are of
quad a and then there's a smattering of
other types that you would uh usually
expect
um you'll find that some of the some of
the things in this talk are
unfortunately a little bit vague and we
can't share the botnet's name here yet
because
there's still some remediation going on
at other registries
so we we decided to uh sinkhole these
domains and
i want to show a little bit of what
things looked like prior to
the sinkhole so um this
this query traffic generated about 370
thousand
375 000 queries per second at the peak
of the day
to to our common.net name servers
most of the domains that the button is
using uh hadn't been registered at that
time and so most of the responses were
nx domain a small number of the domains
were previously registered and delegated
and
some of those we include here but but
most not
and as i said we see a we see a really
even distribution of queries
uh in particular all the domains receive
essentially the same
rate of queries
so here's what the traffic looked like
over the course of a week
we've got saturday and sunday on the
ends of this graph and the weekdays in
the middle
and um you can see that you know it
varies of course throughout the day
throughout each day
um the the left axis here shows the
total
qps which is that uh 375 000 number and
then
the right shows the query rate per
domain name so like at the peak we see
about 225
qps per domain
this is what a typical response you know
look like um
the r code was nx domain and the only
data in the response was the the
dot com or the soa record which has a
ttl of 900 seconds
so when we first started looking at this
uh you know we were a little bit
surprised and we thought that
there must be something wrong like in
particular we thought there was
something wrong with
negative caching you know we did we
didn't uh we weren't expecting this
this uh level of of queries and so
you know some some sort of quick
calculations we said well what's
what's the what query what query rate
might we expect
if you know uh if all these recursive uh
sources were
properly obeying negative caching ttls
of 900 seconds
and that came out to be
79 quarters per second per
resolver source which is represented by
this
green vertical line in the graph and so
the data actually shows that
um you know 99 of the clients are below
that threshold
and so that tells us that you know the
negative caching is
working um as expected here
you'll see that in the in the scatter
plot there's sort of two
shapes or two groups and that's actually
because there are
um sort of two variants of this botnet
and they're they're slightly different
uh one of them you know uses more uh
query names than the other
okay so now let's look at uh the you
know when we decided to sync all this
traffic um
we chose to to delegate most of the
botnet's
domain names to our sinkhole name
servers although there was a
a small group that left undelegated sort
of as a control
in our data analysis we used four
different dedicated single name servers
at three geographically distributed
sites
uh the machines details are there it was
uh
you know a recent version of ubuntu and
bind 916
and that was configured with minimal
responses
and we used uh the good old uh dns
statistics collector software for our
data collection
so this graph shows what things looked
like um
you know when we switched domains from
uh
from from the initial state to the to
the sinkhole state
the the purple line in this graph is the
rate of queries per domain
seen at the tld name servers and again
there's there's that
uh 225 qps peak and then you can see on
wednesday
uh these got delegated to the sinkhole
and the tld traffic dropped from from
that high rate
down to about six quarters per second
per domain
and then the green line the it's labeled
sld that's the traffic seen at the
sinkhole name servers
and it peaks at uh sort of just under 50
queries per second
so we felt that this um this was a
really good opportunity
with this with this ds traffic to do
some different experiments and
and some research so
we ran a bunch of different things and
uh one of them we did was
to understand how the response code
affects caching and query rates
and how does the presence or absence of
the requested data
effect caching and query rates how do
ttls
affect those things for the most part
our experiments would run
for uh during the weekdays the the five
days of the week and we use the weekends
to reset things
and change to a new experiment
uh so here's here's sort of five types
of
experiments or or groups that we did
first
is when the response is no error
and there is uh the requested data in
the response so
no error data the response go to zero
there is a
resource record in the answer section
and the ttl comes from
from that data next is no error no data
and in that case the ttl this is a
negative response and the ttl comes from
the
soa record similarly we have nx domain
where now the response code is 3 and
there's also an soa record with a ttl
and then lastly we studied um what
happens when
the sinkhole returns sir fail and
refused
so this this graph shows uh throughout
the course of a week
um these three different cases of when
there's when there's data
when there's uh no error no data and
when there's an x domain
uh it kind of looks like there's two
lines on this graph but there's really
three the
the two negative cases the no data and
the nx domain
are essentially identical they receive
the same rate of queries
throughout the course of the day uh each
day and over the week
in this in this case all of the ttls
that we had were set to
24 hours so that's ttls on the a records
and on the soa records and so on
so looking a little bit more closely at
some of these cases um
here we we studied the no error
with data case with varying
ttls um and by the way we were able to
run an experiment with these all these
different ttls at the same time by
dividing up the um the domain names into
groups and and you know so all the
queries came
at the same time and we just analyzed
the different uh groupings
so in these in these graphs the shaded
area represents the the daily range and
the points represent the average over
the course of the whole week
note that here the x-axis
is the different ttls represented
logarithmically
right so they basically each tick mark
basically doubles
the ttl time and the top graph shows the
query rates seen at the sinkhole servers
so for the lowest dtl of one minute
um the query rate was about
a little under 300 qps and then as the
ttl increases the query rate
also the query rate decreases and it
sort of plateaus
and you can see here that after about
two hours
um you know it's it's pretty flat
there's not a lot of difference between
say two hours and a day or 32 hours
one thing that's kind of interesting is
that the choice of ttl
at the second level domain uh affects
the query rates seen
at the top level domain shown here in
the middle in green
and also at the root servers shown in
blue on the bottom
so verison obviously operates uh some
some root name servers
but this data is has been sort of
extrapolated
to what the numbers would be for for the
whole root servers system for all all
13.
so that's the uh no error with data case
um here's the no error no data case
things look a little bit similar but um
uh the sld graph in particular is is a
little bit higher
and that'll you can see that better in
an upcoming slide
but but again at the one minute level
you know it's it's right around 300
still
but it plateaus slightly higher
the tld and root graphs look pretty
similar to the previous one
and here's the nx domain case which
again looks
this looks a lot like uh the no data
case because
you know as you already said these these
two cases of negative cache of
negative responses are essentially
equivalent
um this graph shows those three cases
those three
experiments overlaid with each other and
so here you can more clearly see
that the um the the negative response
cases um plateau at a higher level above
or just under 100 qps whereas the the
positive responses
um you know flatten out around uh 50 or
so
so one thing to take away from this is
of course that the relationship between
query rates and ttls is is far from
linear right doubling
or having the the ttl does not double or
half the uh the query rate by any means
so next we studied um what happens when
you configure the sinkholes
to return refused and surf fail and
this was uh particularly interesting
because the
the first time we did this uh we were
sort of
um optimistic and we we configured a
large group of
uh domains to to be like this and
uh very nearly uh essentially ddosed
ourselves out of access to our sinkhole
servers uh
there was so much traffic that we
couldn't we couldn't log in
and the boxes were almost unresponsive
we didn't have
out-of-bound access to them
unfortunately but we were able to
recover and then later on we
did these experiments with much smaller
sets i think i think this is
actually with just three domain names
but
the the numbers here are queries per
second per domain
so um for for those domains that return
refused
uh you know whereas with with like an nx
domain we're seeing 300 qps
here we're seeing 40 000 qps so a a huge
a huge uh increase and uh
also you know very noticeable effects at
the
top level domains and in the root server
data as well
similarly this is the the surfail case
and it's
a little bit higher than the refused
case but otherwise looks looks the same
one thing to notice about these you know
these experiments ran over
two days and the first day is lower than
the second that that's not because it
was a weekend versus a weekday or
anything like that
it's just because uh previously these
names were configured um you know with
with like one day ttls and it
took a while for the um you know for
that data to expire from from all the
caches out there
um so this graph shows the effects
of minimal responses some of you may
have already you know
experimented with this a little bit um
but when
uh when when the minimal responses are
on which i
i think maybe the default um the
the amount of uh that they received
uh or sorry the transmitted bandwidth is
pretty close to the
uh received bandwidth there those you
know queries and responses are about the
same size but
when we disabled minimal responses the
uh the bandwidth
usage um you know doubled approximately
maybe even a little bit more
so a few you know key uh observations
from all of this
um there's there's really no difference
in caching
uh of nx domain or or no data negative
responses
it seems like you know the population of
recursive name servers treats those
equivalently
for negative responses uh ttls longer
than an hour
don't make much difference in terms of
query rates and for positive responses
that that's about two to four hours
where you don't see
much more difference the refused and
surf fail
significantly amplify rather than reduce
the query rates
and i realized that i forgot to mention
uh previously that
the the traffic that we saw from from
the reserve the refuse and surf fail
cases
um you know we later were able to
attribute that to
a real small number of recursive um
recursive operators and we were in touch
with them to explain the problem
and uh have been told that that
remediation for that is in progress
so hopefully that will not be a an
ongoing problem
um we hope to be able to do some future
experiments
using um you know this the sinkhole
traffic such as
measuring the effects of aggressive dns
caching understanding or measuring how
quickly
chain when when a change is made to the
parent or tld zone how quickly does that
change propagate throughout the system
and also uh to measure you know what are
the effects
of having a different set of name
servers between the parent zone and the
child zone
that's the end of the presentation and i
think we have some time for questions
thank you dwayne i'd like to remind
everyone that questions can be asked
using the q and a panel
they'll be read out loud by me also you
can raise your hand if you would like to
ask your question verbally
and please remember to rate the talk you
should see
very shortly a pool pop-up thank you
very much for that
uh all right so our first question is
from
jeff houston did you experiment with no
response at all from the sinkholes
um we thought about that jeff but we did
not
do that um and one
one reason that would be a little bit
difficult for us is because
um i i don't know of a way to tell
bind to just not respond to a particular
name
so we would have to you know find some
other way to do that with some fancy
um you know iptables rules or something
like that but we didn't we didn't
pursue that no
all right the next question from paul
hoffman did you have an estimate of how
many client
sources there were yes
um i believe that
in this graph um
oh i guess i guess the number's not in
here um
so it i mean the if you can count up all
those dots you can
you can figure it out but i don't i
don't remember what the exact number is
but you can see that it's it's quite a
few maybe maybe on the order of ten
thousand
maybe more i don't know i'll have to get
back to you on that paul thanks for the
question
uh well okay we'll quickly go to audrey
randall uh can you tell us what the
purpose of this
botnet is is it sending spam or what
um it's it's it's not it's not a spam
sending botnet
as far as i know um
i i don't i actually don't know a lot
about the botnet
um like i said we unfortunately can't
can't mention the name at this point
um but i would say that if there are any
um
are there any registry operators that
are out there that are interested in
in this you know you can get in touch
with us and we can work with you
and and you know provide more details to
you but at this point we can't
uh say more
okay uh
wes hartaker has commented uh excellent
talk thank you
my analysis has shown that botnets are
now spreading dga traffic over hundreds
of tlds
do you know if your sinkhole link for
just two tlds
has actually helped the root dns abuse
cause of the
problem versus just helping your
particular tldr
operation um
yeah that's an interesting question wes
i
i don't know i mean i i think that um
so we we were able to sync all this for
um
for the the tlds that the body uses um
you know that verisign also operates um
but i we didn't look at uh
sort of the overall effect that it may
have had on root traffic and that would
be a good thing to do
we should be able i think with our data
we could go back and and do that
to look at uh query query rates for all
tlds if we wanted to
alter these affected
okay um all right uh jeff houston has
his hand raised i'll allow
you to talk jeff ahead
yeah it's a little bit quicker to
actually ask this one because it's not
so easy to type dwayne
we have found in the work we've done
that on some days up to 90
of the queries we get on our
authoritative servers for a very small
domain
actually come from replays that out
there someone someone is capturing
some essence of dns queries and playing
it back at very very high speed
do you have any feeling of what
proportion of queries you're seeing
are synthetic and have actually been
generated
from something other than the original
botnet
versus original botnet in our case the
average
kicks around long term 40 percent of
queries are what i would call synthetic
in the long term do you have any feel
for that in this case
i don't and i i think that would be
pretty hard to do
with this particular botnet because
it doesn't it doesn't have like a lot of
randomness or uniqueness in its
in its names right it uses a very fixed
set of
both um you know top level domains and
i mean second level and third level
domains so i don't know how i would go
about
detecting replays actually
okay thanks uh from petercock
uh assume you wanted to sync away
non-botnet domain do you think the
resu it's would be com the results would
be comparable
i.e how much is induced by the client
how much by
resolver behavior
yeah that's a that's a good question
peter i i think that um
you know i think that it would be
comparable if
uh if you're talking about sort of
comparable
traffic levels right i think um
[Music]
like like for example uh i'm not sure
this is exactly what you're getting at
but
i'm a little bit hesitant to say that um
you know you you could apply these
results of how the query
varies based on ttl i don't know if you
could apply that
more widely to for example domain names
that
don't get you know these many queries
um i'm not if that wasn't
the question you wanted me to answer um
maybe you could try again
all right a question from uh gavin
mccullough we've seen the difference
between negative and refused a lot have
you come across
authorities which when delegated to
incorrectly
insert an authoritative nx domain
i i haven't but um
you know certainly i think that one
thing this shows is that
there's there's a little bit of a danger
to refused which is
kind of the you know it's kind of the
default
for a name server that gets a query for
a name that it doesn't know about
um you know in the old days you would
get these um
upward referrals and i wanted to
to test that but we sort of ran out of
time and
um uh yeah i don't i
i don't i'm a little bit skeptical that
refused is the is the best thing
you know in terms of uh
high levels of traffic i'm concerned
about that as well
but i haven't i haven't seen anybody
insert fake uh authorities either
okay and we'll close the question q uh
robert edmonds has asked
was this spot next a lot of traffic to
the roots tlds
or did it get sinkhole just because it
was interesting
um it was sending um enough tr
so i don't i don't actually know about
the the well so for the rtlds4.coma.net
it was sending enough traffic that uh
we found it kind of annoying and wanted
to move it off of those servers we
wanted to you know
take some of that traffic away so
yeah it was it was it was not just
because it was interesting it was
because it was also
an annoying amount of traffic okay and
the last question from han zhang
do you think these two botnets may
belong to existing botnet families
as far as i know no i think this is sort
of a standalone
uh botnet with just two variants
perfect all right uh
thank you very much train for your
presentation my pleasure
and um we will move on to uh casey
decchio
uh presentation is uh behind closed
doors a network tale of spoofing
intrusion and false dns security
i'd just like to remind everyone that
you can use our mattermost workshop chat
for discussions and our
as you saw for question asking the q and
a pull
and or the uh raising of hands to ask
questions
well everyone uh my name is casey decio
and um
my type my talk is entitled behind
closed doors
this was done in collaboration with
students and
colleagues at brigham young university
so first of all
we often think about access control on
the internet
the idea that with the firewall we might
allow traffic from
one source but we might deny traffic
from another source because we don't
trust that other source
but of course the big problem on the
internet is that identity is not really
what we think it is
when some packet is received by bob bob
and it looks like it's from alice
bob oftentimes has to simply trust us
from alice now of course there are some
higher level
higher level protocols which help with
that
but at least at the packet level
initially bob has to
to assume that it's from alice um but
what if
that packet actually originated from
mallory instead
and um came with where mallory spoofed
alice's source and so when it arrived at
bob
bob had no other choice but to to accept
that packet
and of course when the response goes
back it goes to alice we call this
reflection
okay now we can extend this model and
talk about insider trust of course when
you think about inside a network
where bob is a server alice is a client
in this model you'd think bob would
inherently trust
clients including alice that are within
his own network
and um they're more inclined to trust
those those insiders
but what if the same thing happened
where mallory some from some outside
network
now spoofed a packet claiming to be from
alice
which then crossed the internet entered
that network boundary and arrived at bob
that would be problematic now there are
two places
where you can guard against this type of
uh attack and intrusion and the first
site is uh
and both of these have to do with source
address validation
the first aspect and perspective of
source address validation
is that which is found at the origin
where the packet originates
and so we're we'll refer to this as
origin side source
address uh validation or osav
and this is covered by bcp38 the idea is
that you shouldn't let it packet out of
your network
if the source address does not originate
from within your network
but the other aspect is destination side
source address validation the idea is
when a packet is coming in
that claims to have originated from
within your network you also shouldn't
let that packet in
because it obviously came from outside
and there are some safeguards
against this type of thing within bcp84
and by the way a key aspect here is that
bcp38 and osav really is meant to
protect
others from traffic that originates from
within your network
whereas dsav
on the destination side any safeguards
you take there really protect yourself
and so there is sort of this
incentive model of as to what actually
protects self
and the stronger um incentive is on the
destination side source address
validation
so our research question is how
prevalent is the practice of destination
side source
address validation now of course the the
way the dns works it really
facilitates an experiment like this to
better understand what sorts of
safeguards are being deployed out there
because
it operates over udp and it really just
takes a single packet
being received by a recursive resolver
for it to
go and do its work in terms of
resolution by contacting authoritative
servers
and then of course the response come
back comes back but only takes that one
packet
one trusted packet a recursive resolver
to make all that happen
so here's how we set up our experiment
we had over on the left hand side
our experiment architecture okay with
our sending client
and then a target network on the right
hand side
with a destination recursive resolver
with some address
and then we also had an authoritative
server for a domain that we controlled
over in our experiment infrastructure
so the idea then is that we would take
we would send
issue some query to a given
recursive resolver and some foreign
network with a spoof source address
such that when the packet arrived it
looked like it would look like it came
from something within
the same network as the recursive
resolver now
if that actually passed the access
control list
and the recursive resolver operated on
that
that query that came in then it would
issue a query to our authoritative dns
server
and we would issue a response back and
then at that point the recursive
resolver will return a response to
the falsified source we have we wouldn't
see that or know anything about it but
at that point it wouldn't matter
we would know it had been reached by the
fact that we saw a query
at our authoritative server okay so
that's the gist of of
the experiment okay
and um so in terms of identifying uh the
targets
uh the target destinations and then the
sources we used first of all
um so we used um dns clients that were
extracted from 48 hours of
root server queries in april 2019
and from these queries we extracted
about
11 million ipv4 addresses from about 54
000 autonomous systems
and about 800 000 ipv6 addresses from
about 8
000 ipv6 um autonomous systems
okay but in terms of sources what we
used um
so we used five categories of sources
that we sent
source ip addresses um that we
uh from which we crafted queries to go
to these destinations
and so the first category is what we
called
other prefix and and that was the idea
that
within that asn it was announcing a
bunch of prefix
address space and so we selected about
97 addresses
from different slash 24 or for ipv64
prefixes
within that same um that were announced
by that same asn but weren't the same
slash 24 or same 64
as the target ip address itself
we did also announce um in the same
prefix category one or sorry not
announced
we sent um a query claiming to be from
one address within the same
24 or same 64 prefix um
and then we also sent a packet claiming
to be
from private address space so 192 168
and fc00 that actually should have been
fd00
from from that address space and then uh
we also sent a packet
uh from using a source address that was
the same as the destination address so
that's sort of like
receiving a letter from yourself um and
uh
and actually processing it and then uh
finally we sent queries
uh from the loopback ip address just
sort of to see if if anything would
actually pass at that point
and um so let's let's take a look at the
some of the results that we got
so first of all in terms of reachability
we we looked at two things uh both on
the ipv4 side and the ipv6 side and and
so
did our query even make it there and
we saw in terms of addresses and in
terms of networks
uh we measured these things so we saw
about you know close to five percent of
of destination addresses received to
query
but about half of um destination
autonomous systems included at least one
responsive ipv4 address which was
actually really surprising that was very
high to us um and then on the ipv6 side
it was very similar it's right at 50
percent of asn's that included a
responsive
ipv6 address in other words one that was
reached uh by one of our spoof source
queries
by the fact that it gave a query to our
authoritative servers
we also broke down broke this down just
a little bit to see sort of
the effectiveness of the different
sources that were used that we were
guessing because we had these
these five categories um one of the ones
that stood out was the fact that
um 70 of the reachable ipv6 addresses
um were reachable so in other words when
we reached
uh all out of all the ipv6 addresses
that we reached
70 of those were reached reachable by
that destination a source where we had
the same um
source address as the destination
address which was really surprising
but you'll see why that was as i get a
little bit later in the presentation
um also interesting when we broke down
now some of the details are in our
our paper um so just to show you some of
this here
um so in terms of exclusive reach
meaning
if if if you were only using this like
if you excluded all their sources and
and this was
this would be the category that helped
uh bring in some of these these sources
we found that
uh 33 of ipv4 addresses were only there
because we used this other prefix
category
um and interestingly um the destination
is source category in the ipv6 side
which i just mentioned
uh almost 10 of those uh they were only
reachable
um because we used the destination
destination as source
um uh because they didn't those 10
percent didn't get hit by the other
prefix
or the same prefix sources uh it was
just because
somebody allowed something in from a
loopback address okay
um let's see loopback address uh there
were 22
loopback excuse me 22 addresses that we
found
simply because um because we sent
uh sources queries from the loopback
address
okay we wanted to learn a little bit
more about these resolvers
that we were actually hitting and so
after we determined that a resolver was
reachable through our
source queries we sent 10 follow-up
queries uh to each of these and um that
resulted in 10
recursive to authoritative queries to
our authoritative server
so what we did with those we took the
the raw list of source
ports um that came from those queries
and then we sorted those now this is a
simplified version we're using just five
uh ports here instead of the 10 that we
did we sorted those
ports and then we took the maximum minus
the minimum
and that gave us a range okay and so we
just wanted to sort of look at this
range that was being used um
and and plot this out and here's what we
got when we plotted this
you have only four more minutes to qna
thank you okay so so you can see there's
a few
uh modes within these graphs that sort
of jumped out at us
um and and i'm going to focus first of
all on on this
um you know this aspect over here where
we had a zero port range
now if you see a port range of zero that
means they answered from
the same port every single time which of
course means that there is no source
port
randomization at all because there is no
uh change in source ports at all
okay this affected uh almost 4 000
resolvers and of course these are
uh more vulnerable to cash poisoning
because of that and in part because
they're reachable through this
spoof source um uh
vulnerability um and and let's see um
i'm not going to go through the rest of
this for the sake of time but i'm happy
to answer questions about that later
okay um so let's
move along then we wanted to learn
something else about these uh these
other
um sort of high frequency modes that we
saw in this
in this plot and by the way this lower
plot here is a
actually a zoomed in version of the
upper plot but what we found was
different
um operating systems when the dns
software
uses the the femoral source port range
of a given operating system
then um there's a probability
a high probability that it'll fall
within a certain range so for example
linux will fall within this range
because it has a certain um
what's the word certain size a certain
pool of ephemeral
source ports and same thing with freebsd
this is the range that you would expect
to see
windows is down here it has about a
source port range of about
uh 2500 by default and then there's some
systems that
uh some software that don't actually use
the os source port
ephemeral source port range and so those
would be they use the full range instead
and they would be down here and of
course for those we can't identify
operating system
but the cool thing is then we can
actually look back at these
uh queries that we got and we can see
um sorry the the follow-up queries from
the different resolvers and we can
actually identify different operating
systems
so we can see the the number of windows
systems that showed up here
um the different uh linux systems the
number of linux systems and freebsd that
showed up here
and of course these ones uh because
they're using the full source printer
and
we can't um uh identify a given
operating system
but it was sort of interesting to break
that down and the full numbers are in
our paper
um and then the last thing that i'll
mention here uh is that we did some lab
testing to
understand these last behaviors of hey
what happens when a packet is received
by a given system
and it has an address that claims to
have come
from that system like on an individual
computer
and um or or it claims to come from the
loopback so loop x interesting windows
server
2003 and 2003 r2 allow things in from
the loopback
on ipv4 um and linux earlier kernels um
so 2.6
3.3 and 4.4 um allow in
uh packets claiming to be front to
loopback ipv6
ipv6 loopback so that's super
interesting um and also
uh of note here all of the operating
systems on the ipv6 side
allow in a packet that has the same
source address as the destination
address
um and and so the kernel is actually
allowing those in and passing them up
to the uh application layer which was
actually really surprising to us
freebsd windows server uh and all
windows server
also did that on the ipv4 side okay so
just in summary
the source address of network packets
can't be trusted we tested uh
dsav and found it to be lacking in half
of measured networks
uh and and just in in summary we have
done some reach out and uh there's also
a self-test tool
that you can visit right here that's
live it's sort of
beta we're trying it out and you're
welcome to go there um
thanks so much and i'm happy to take any
questions
thank you casey uh at this time i'd like
to remind everyone that you can
rate this talk uh a poll will pop up
shortly
and uh if you'd like to ask questions of
casey uh please do so in the q a panel
and or by raising your hand
i don't see any questions yet so casey
um have we
reached out to the maintainers of those
operating systems to try to understand
why the uh there are differences both
between
i guess v4 and v6 uh origin routes
or or um uh you know destination as
source routes
yes are you talking about this slide
right here correct yes
yeah um so that is still underway
um but uh but we have not gotten to the
point of actually making contact with
the kernel operators
we did have some reach out to network
operators um to to talk about some of
the behaviors that we found
interesting okay we have a question from
roland dobbins can you typify the types
of networks where these resolvers were
located and reachable
broadband access networks enterprises
idc's on large transit providers etc
yeah that's a great question um we
started going down that
that route and we we actually to be
honest we ran out of space for the
the um the part of the the analysis we
were doing and and i should say time
um and so we don't have anything
definitive there but we also wanted to
be careful about how we were
uh classifying things since this was
going out um
for a publication but the other thing
all
i will say one of the tricky parts of
this is isps
we're still finding that they don't have
an easy solution based on
some of the access control lists and
some of the ways that they have um
sort of third parties announce their
address space it makes it really tricky
to do traditional
um like bcp 84 type
fixes for this and that's that's
something that's ongoing as to how to
reach out and help them with this
okay our next uh question or an
observation from matthew lucky
uh freebsd has urpf that would solve
this but you have to turn it off
yeah like a number of things you do have
to turn that on that's right
yeah great great point thanks matthew
all right any other questions for casey
okay well thank you very much casey nope
i'm sorry one more question uh from han
zhang
uh in the spoofed uh ohar prefix
do you have some of these ips so you can
measure how many major
how many reachable resolvers sent to you
how many
reachable resolvers sent to you um
like i think you're asking did you did
we save what we did
is that what you're asking oh i'm sorry
so in the the spoofed
uh other prefixes right right
yeah i see what you're asking you're
getting back to some of our sources that
we use and i
i think are you asking did we save those
away is that right hon i'm not sure if
that's what you're asking or not
we did save all those we saved
everything that we that we did i'm not
sure if i'm answering your question
properly
because uh we wanted when we did some
reach out we wanted people to be able to
test and see if it was still
happening and so we we basically said
here's everything that triggered it
before
try it again um but maybe ask me offline
han if i didn't answer your question if
i didn't quite understand it
okay uh well close the the question line
uh brian dixon asked is anything about
this possible to test via white batlist
probes just wondering
uh i'm not a ripe atlas expert but i did
ask this a few years ago of
someone at ripe and i believe they told
me that spoofing sources was not
um a thing back then plus you have to
have to network they would do it right
so
my as a non-authoritative right person i
would say no
but i i don't know i i'd ask them
and matthew lucky asked uh curious if
you got any comments complaints about
moving mac addresses
log messages when you happen to use an
address in their network that is live
ooh uh no we didn't
in fact okay i'll i'm gonna answer this
more generically though we got very few
people that even noticed this at all
some people asked about the experiment
some people
asked to be opted out which we did one
person the most interesting when we
when we explained to this individual uh
what we were doing in the nature of the
experiment and the reason why
he said okay i want back in
which which we sort of loved so um not
everyone was like that but we only got
about five
uh five people that even noticed we were
doing it to be honest and this ran for
about four weeks to completion
um so
great questions thank you very much well
thank you very much
all right uh with this i'd like to uh
let you know of the
15-minute break we will restart again at
uh two o'clock am
utc um you should be reminded that
the uh the participants can use the
breakout rooms for face-to-face chat
uh this is enabled by spatial chat you
should have received a link
to access that
do not share your spatial chat link with
anyone else this is specific to you
and once again we'd like to thank the
workshop sponsors of
foresight security and verisign thank
you very much and see you in
approximately 14 minutes now
all right everyone uh welcome back to
orc35
day two session two i'd like to welcome
chris michelson to give his presentation
on dns
tab updates hello
i'm here today to talk about some recent
changes and some open work in dns tab
for those of you who aren't familiar
with the dns tab a quick recap of what
dns tap is all about
dns tap is a flexible structured binary
log format for dns software
um it is it supports both real-time
stream
and file-based processing workflows uh
fairly equally well with a lot of shared
code between the two
uh and we designed it for minimal
overhead on
the instrumental software the reference
and the early reference implementations
were
uh non-blocking so if the uh
if the reader wasn't keeping up the the
server would keep
keep on going um as such is not really
really good oriented towards uh like
audit vlogging and support
but more for like stats collection and
telemetry and other observations more
operational
uh the binary format is defined by a
protobuf definition at the
link url here uh the streaming and file
format is a
library that's that farsight developed
uh called frame streams uh
which is uh a lightweight streaming
protocol
uh system negotiation when done over a
network connection but the file format
is basically the
unidirectional stream that is negotiated
um we have two we support two
implementations
one in c the reference implementation
and goaling notation
uh at those sites
the primary focus of dnstab is exporting
the dns message as it is
seen by the instrumented server it can
export other things but we haven't
defined those yet
along with the message it exports
relevant context uh such as you know the
ip address that it came from and similar
uh and of course
the definition of relevant evolves over
time um
so we maintained we maintained this
specification
by a primary discussion on our mailing
list which is uh
information about which is available at
dnstep and info
the first update we've done recently is
adding some new adding support for
new protocols so the context
has always included some protocol info a
a bunch of uh in
enum type fields so whether it's uh
ipv4 or ipv6 uh and the query port and
response ports
supports and in order to make the ports
make sense
a protocol udp or tcp uh this did not
leave out
does not include dns over tls or dns
over https which are coming into
more wide use um because those are
definitely not
uh adequately captured by tcp because
you know
dns over tls and dns of https are quite
a bit different from just playing dns
over tcp
um after a after a short discussion
about a uh
old suggestion late last year we added
uh values to the socket protocol
um for dns over tls and dns over https
uh that led to a few open issues which
are still open uh which we might
want to close at some point uh so doh is
definitely not just a trivial thing on
top of
dns over tcp uh so
because we have so we're blurring some
protocol layering here
in particular dns over https uh
uses uh zero for the query id or
recommends that
strongly which means that if you're
writing an application that's that's
trying to match up uh
queries and responses with uh with the
query id you need
access to the http 2 or http 3
stream id which is not included in dns
tap
yet and similarly like you might want to
know whether what
http version is is there uh so we might
need some more features and
fields to capture these details um and
that of course leaves out
uh other protocols like data server
quick or genoscript or other
experimental protocols uh do we
want to include those in socket protocol
yeah that's
that is something that is open for
discussion
uh the most significant update was
adding policy reporting
to the uh to dns tab
so uh it's been a while since you can
safely run a
recursive dns server for a community of
users and
you know just let it
let it blindly resolve everything
without exposing your users to
various uh bad actors and other and
other madness on the internet
um in the old days it was fairly
customary to
just publish an empty zone that your
recursive dns server uh
but you know that does not that's a
fairly pretty course mechanism
and it's obviously advanced since then
um so there have been a number of uh
a number of efforts one of which is uh
response policy zones
um that
are a non-trivial mechanism for
uh for enforcing policies and processing
the dns messages so
we wanted some visibility into this so
earlier this year we added a policy
field which is a
compound type uh which includes
information about what rules were
triggered
uh what identifier the packet matched
the rule
whether it was a client ip nor the query
name or what
or any number of things and what action
was taken in response to that
this was written primarily to cover the
the rpc use cases
that we had
we made sure we covered the rpc actions
and the rpg
identifiers and part of that because rpg
is a well-known
uh mechanism with rich functionality as
well documented
uh and covers many if not most use cases
for
uh for policy filtering
uh we've made it not to support the
other mechanisms with a
policy type string and if
there are actions or identifiers that
the other possibility that other
policy engines use that we want to
report through united's tap
we just need to add those
um i'll finish up with some general
housekeeping notes about other
other open projects so we have a couple
open issues on the dnstapp.pb
github from a while back uh for adding
cache status for what's uh
what information or what whether a query
is answered out of cache or out of uh
authoritative zones or out of uh out of
cache missed iterative queries
um and then also a generic message tag
for tying
multiple dns tap messages together
these as i mentioned has been open for a
while
there were some open discussions now
stalled for a while
uh that didn't really
propose multiple different
implementations with no clear consensus
on which to adopt if any
i would like to reopen those or close
these issues
at some point another
open issue is a json format for
for dns tap uh the pro portable binary
format
is a bit of a barrier to entry for for a
number of users it's not
it's not something that there are a lot
of command line tools to slice and dice
and
and process and we've had a few
submissions
of json output to various dns tab tools
and
those uh submitted um
so submitted json formats are not
necessarily uh
compatibly compatible with each other uh
so i think there
there would be a good use for standard
json binding for tool independent
workflows
uh if any of this sounds interesting to
anybody uh listening uh
i would like to hear from you uh
preferably by the file ebay list or
unicast or in the break group so with
that
um i will open the floor to questions
thank you very much uh our first
question
is from roland bobbins has thought been
given to implementing dns tap
as an ipfix interface extension or
full-fledged
uh standardized format like psa mp
this would make dns tap much more
accessible and allow for much
easier com combinatorial analysis
with other forms of flow-based telematic
telemetry
and open up greater possibilities in
terms of analysis tools
so if i understand the question it's uh
about implementing dns tap
uh with a different source from the
actual
like internals of dna software if that
can i can go and confirm or deny that or
confirm this or
correct me on that yeah as an ipv ipfix
or ipfix
extension enterprise extension or
full-fledged standardized format like
psa mp
uh the focus of dns tab is definitely uh
as a
plug-in for the dns software itself um
and as its own as its own thing rather
than as a
uh rather than as like
part of a overall ecosystem like that so
i i would say that's not on our radar
but i would
be willing to discuss that more
okay um follow up to that from also
roland uh the question is whether
thought has been given to implementing
dns tap the top ipfix
dns software could export it via ipfix
um confess i'm not really very familiar
with ipfix
um so that is
all right casey dco has raised his hand
um casey you should be
good to unmute yourself
uh yeah i'll make it quick so one thing
you asked about if there was
um you know interest in in making the
json
available and and the answer is yes here
because i know i've
written some parser you know parsers
that take the frame buffer and
and put it out a different way um but my
my other question is
is whether there's any way to and if
this is ongoing work
um a way to take the what is it the
buffering
and decrease the time delay like when
you don't have a full buffer to putting
something out
from your f-string capture i don't know
if that's the same
as what you're talking about in just the
protocol buffer or not um but i thought
i'd ask about that
we can take it offline if it's not
applicable uh
the in in general the uh the
implementations uh that we support uh or
that we were familiar with uh try to get
the data
out of the out of the instrumented
server as quickly as possible
so there's a ring buffer primarily to
absorb back pressure from
the consumer not uh not keeping up with
the fast
we're not not keeping up with the
processing
okay uh another question from willem
are there any plans to standardize this
work in the ietf
uh there there are they're more than
there were there were more than plans
there was actually
a a effort to make an internet draft of
this
um some of the complications of this uh
that were uh it being based on protobuf
which is not an ietf standard
standardized protocol and we have an
installed base so switching to cbore or
similar
was not very practical
okay it looks like that
is it for questions uh thank you very
much chris
all right
all right our next presentation is from
uh
siva cassava presentation
is so you think your name servers are
correct finding errors automatically in
name server implementations
siva if you want to share your screen
hello everyone i am shiva kakar a fourth
year phd student at ucla
today i'm going to describe you a way to
find errors automatically in names of
implementations
and this is a joint work with ryan
beckett from microsoft with madwes todd
and george from ucla
so we all know how hard it is to
implement a name server that is
efficient
has high throughput and is correct
dns name resolution seems simple at high
level but over the time it has evolved
into a complex
and intricate protocol as jeff houston
said in his ethnic blog post
the dns is a remarkably simple system
using it queries
you get back answers however the dns is
simple in the same way that chess
are good or simple they all have
constrained environments governed by a
set of rigid rules
but they all possess astonishing
complexity
those rules are embedded in english
documents called rfcs
the developers must understand these
rfcs first and then transform into
a working code this whole process
is delicate and errors can happen and
has happened in the past
like any software system
but the errors in dns have far reaching
effects due to its global presence which
puts the developer
under a lot of pleasure to ensure that
there are no exploitable crashes
or no wrong answers are written by the
software
similarly they also wants to ensure that
they are doing what most others are
doing
so as not to have any interoperability
issues
perhaps the most interesting the most
important requirement is
ensuring that the develop software is
compliant with the rfcs
that is functional compliance does the
develop name server software follow the
logic
and procedure as indicated by the rfcs
are there any cases on which they differ
and why do they differ
to check all these issues each
implementation currently has its own
test suite
each implementation developer manually
writes some tests to check the lookup
logic
rfc compliance and whether the response
return is expected response
this is all good and has got a lot of
errors in the name servers
but it is an honors task which puts a
lot of burden on developers
to come up with a good test that
stresses many corner cases of the dns
rfcs
i have recently started working and
researching on dns topics
and after seeing this current testing
scenario i and my collaborators thought
can we do better and reduce burden on
the developers
the short answer is yes and but how
our key idea is to generate tests
automatically
thus avoiding the laborious and manual
way of writing tests
to know what is the expected answer for
a generated test we can simply compare
the response from multiple
implementations
but one or more dns implementations
disagree with others
we flag this as a potential bug our tool
which automatically generates us
compares the response from multiple
implementation is called ferret
but how to generate high but how to
generate high coverage stress that
identify functional correctness errors
so to note that first i'll give an
overview of the end-to-end design of the
system before delving into deeper of how
we generate the test automatically
so we have rfcs and we leverage rfcs
to drive test generation a technique
called specification based test
generation
using this technique we produce tests
that cover many distinct dns names of
our behaviors
while the end-to-end behavior so the
tests are basically like a zone file
and a query so for example this is one
example
test is that the tool generated so
there's a small zone file of three
records and this is the query that is
supposed to be sent to that
zone file while the end-to-end behavior
of dns
query lookup can require contacting many
name servers
we employ a modular approach that only
generates tests for a single name server
in isolation
in the case of dns name servers keep no
internal state
the response they provide is based
solely on the
zone files that they have and the input
query
and the tests are not tied to any source
code so
ferret can generate tests for any
implementation because these are
basically zone file and query they can
be used to
generate a test and test any names of
implementation
okay so now we have the test generated
and we want to test them uh you and we
want to test multiple immigrations using
them
as many parts of the dns rfc are either
underspecified
or not specified and there is not always
a definite right or wrong answer for
these cases
we instead of comparing the responses
from different implementations to the
rfcs
we compare the results from the
implementations to one another
when one or more implementations uh
disagree
with others we flag it as a potential
bug and we look into it why there was a
difference
and this module we call it as
differential testing module an idea
commonly used in compiler testing
so now first we look at into
differential testing modules some
details and then we will look at some
examples of the bugs that we found and
then into test generation module
we compared the behavior of eight
popular open source authoritative
implementations of dns
and the table shows the eight
implementations the language they are
implemented in and the brief description
of their focus or how they are used
for testing implementations for that
uses docker to construct a working
container image of each implementation
to generate the image we clone the
implementations code as of october 1st
2020 from their open source repositories
available on beta about kit lab
fedex starts a container for each image
and each container serves one zone file
at a time as an authoritative zone
the containers expose the dns port 53 to
the host system by mapping an unused
host port
and enable the host to send queries and
resume responses from the dns server
running in that container
this way each implementation is given a
unique port that maps to the container's
dns port 53
finally fedex uses python library dns
python to send queries and
receive responses from the containers
and these are all the lists of the bugs
that we found we found around 30 bucks
and most of them have been confirmed and
a lot of them have already been also
fixed by the developers
and i'll give you some of the examples
of the bugs that we found
so consider this uh example where this
is the test case that the tool generated
both the zone file and the query was
generated from the tool
for this query it is first rewritten
using the dna
to the cname to the to the new query
shown as above
and the new query will match exactly the
name record
now when this test case is used to test
bind and others all the others responded
with a synthesized cname and a dname as
a response
but we found that bind was not
responding and the query timed out
we inspected the logs and found that
the server has crashed by giving this
message
and we reported the crash and we noticed
that it was an easily recognizable deal
of service vector
and it can be remotely exploitable it
can be used to crash both the resolvers
and the authoritative servers
and it also affected all currently
maintained uh bind branches
so we initiated a responsible disclosure
and recently just a few days back a
cv was released with a high severe
article
to again emphasize this is the test case
that the tool automatically generated
and
we just knew that uh because of the
crash we know that there was something
wrong in the bank and there was no
manual process in any of this
okay as a next example consider this one
more test case
where there is a wildcard c name and the
target of the c name is also can be
matched by the wildcard again
so the query is firstly written using
cname to foo dot example
and four dot example will match the wild
card again
if k is not taken then you will just go
into infinite loop of matching the c
name over and over
so we tested it with core dns and all
the remaining seven
all the remaining codiness is a popular
open source server
in google and it's a recommended server
for kubernetes also
all the others responded with this
synthesized cname as a response and
detected the loop and stopped
i'm sorry but code dns did not give us
any response
we again noticed the logs and what we
saw was that
uh codiness keeps looping and looping
looping and
almost takes the all the resources
available on the system and finally
crashes with this message
if there is any uh hosting services that
use code dns as
the dns software then this is a serious
secutable empty an attacker could
potentially upload its own files that
upload a vulnerability like this one
compromising the service by crashing the
provider service
we inform the coordinates and they add
fixed it by adding a loop counter
they also mention that it's for now it's
important to protect the server
rather than to give client a valid
answer
as next example let's consider
performance bug in bind
so this is another test case where there
is a delegation for foo to ns1.campus.tv
but ns1.campus.edu is also under campus
but is a sibling domain to foo and there
is a glue
sibling blue record for ns1 first full
so for this query the response from
powerdn is not in energy was that they
responded with the ns record and also
gave the glue record in the additional
section
bind did not return the glue record
and when we asked bang the first
response that we got was that this
report turns out to be very interesting
and here is what they managed to find
out bind uses a glue cache to speed up
the identification of blue records
but it had two unrelated errors if the
cache lookup fails
then glue records are supposed to be
searched for in the zone file but they
were never searched and
blue records for sibling domain name
servers were accidentally never searched
at all
so there was no chance that this a
record would have been written by the
bind
and it's an open issue on that git club
and it's on the june 2021 milestone
next let's look at one more example in
energy where we found a data structure
bug
this is another test case that the tool
generated where it inserted a wildcard
character in the r data side of the
scene
response from nsg was no error and
the cname was given out but the expected
response was supposed to be
nx domain because ww dot star
is also under bookstore online and that
domain name does not exist so the
expected r code is in extremely
mine not empowered in is written with nx
domain as cdna target does not exist
and our code is important as we all know
like resolvers can use to determine
whether domains exist or not
and when you file the bug report and as
it responded that it has to do something
with the internal data structure
and there was some flag missing out
and they have fixed it and it's all
available on the github issues
as a final example let's consider this
zone file and the test case
so there is a green name and the dname
causes an infinite loop because
it rewrites to something which is
actually the prefix of the virtual
domain name so query is written using
the name to
www.ubs.com and this new related query
will again match the dna and the length
keeps increasing
and this leads to an infinite recursion
in this case the implementations are
free to choose how they will respond
it is important that implementation
guard against these cases which can
otherwise lead to heavy resource
consumption by the name server
bind applies dna multiple times and
stops when limit reaches 17.
power dna has just returned surface in
this case
not and nsg applied dna only once
works here but had to be applied
multiple times when there is no loop
and we reported those cases and both
energy and not fix those issues
an interesting byproduct was that we
found an error in the not test suit
not had a test suit that compares the
responses with bind to follow bind and
they had a
comment mentioning that one of the tests
is for dmd name loop like the one above
unfortunately they did not construct the
zone file correctly
and the other led to having no loops at
all so
that was either they had of increasing
the uh
[Music]
target they decreased it so there was no
loop found because of that
when reported the developers agreed and
fixed it and the fix was they
went with a single response like they
use the name only once unlike the 173 uh
as the binders
so we have seen all the examples and
what
can be done so what is lurking in this
generation module
and how do we generate those test cases
automatically
so we use the rfcs and from the rfcs we
have earlier built a formal model of the
name server semantics
it's like a mathematical specification
of the lookup
logic like it's
it's a declarative model of how the
lookup has to happen and we built it
from the rfc mainly the one two three
four four five eight one double six
seven
now we perform symbolic execution on the
model
symbolic execution is a static analysis
technique that animates execution paths
in a program
and uses so this is a path
so for the query and zone to end up at
even branch you need an exact match
followed by whether the records are
authoritative and if there is an exact
type then you
take this branch
so these are the four constraints that
need to be satisfied if you want to take
that branch
and now we put these constraints in an
automatic constraint solver to produce
an input
that will take each eliminated path
thereby generating tests that cover many
different program behaviors
to actually do the symbolic execution on
the mathematical model
we made an executable version of the
formal model and it is implemented in
a domain specific modeling language
embedded in c sharp
with built-in support for symbolic
execution so
we took the rfcs built a mathematical
model first and then converted an
executable model
now we symbolically execute the model to
generate the test cases
the test cases are basically a pair of
zone file and a query
and after the test cases are generated
we use it in the diffusion testing model
and these are the statistics of the
number of tests generated for each
branch
because symbolic execution does not
scale for large uh
for large sizes of the domain names we
consider that the zone file will have
not less not more than four records and
the length of the domain names are also
less than four
so there are around uh 10 branches that
we found in the lookup logic and these
are the total number of test cases
generated for each
branch
and now we have the test and then we put
it through all the
one test case at a time through all the
implementations get the response from
all eight implementations compare them
and group them
if there is a single group then there
are no issues like all is good
but if there is more than one group then
there is a likely chance that one of
them is misbehaving
so we had 12 000 tests and out of them
only 4
400 had response out of them fourteen
four hundred made a single guru
there were eight thousand tests in which
at least there was one implementation
which differed from the rest of the
others
but that's too many to check manually
and there are generally typically orders
of magnitude fewer root causes for these
deviations
so we do a kind of fingerprinting we
fingerprint
each of the failed tests to group and so
that we reduce the number of
test cases that we need to inspect
so these are the statistics of the
number of tests for each model and the
number of tests failing for that
model case model case is basically the
branch in the formal model
and even basically like exact match when
there is an exact type also
we fingerprint the failed test and a
fingerprint for each test leverages both
the specification based and the
differential testing and then groups
test by fingerprint
so for each failed test we use the model
case due to which it was generated
and the unique implementations in each
group from the responses
for example this is one example of a
fingerprint
this in this test case the test case was
generated because of
r1 branch and on this test case
nsd not power dns and edifica had one
response
binding codiness had one response trust
genius and millionaire server reference
and there's three dif and the three
responses were different from each other
and the reasoning behind all of this is
it's unlikely for different unique bugs
to have the same fingerprint
now after we do the fingerprinting we
end up with
almost 70 uh fingerprints a reduction of
more than two orders of magnitude
and some fingerprints had only one test
somehow four and some higher more than
ten test cases
and we inspected all the number all the
fingerprints that had four or fewer
number of tests
and for the other ones we randomly
sampled the test from each fingerprint
once again this is the total list of the
bugs that we found by inspecting the
failed test cases
using the fingerprinting technique
out of the 30 almost 20 almost all of
them are confirmed except two in code
dns
which are which i filed and they haven't
responded yet but there are also
some issues recording this
and in the mara danis and trust genius
there are a lot more issues that we've
found
but we haven't reported them because
they have they are missing out some
features or they don't have
something some of the features
implemented
now this is all good and now how do
as a if you're developing a new dna
software how do you test using this
framework so all you need is first
generate a docker image for your
implementation start a container with
the host port mapped to port 53 of the
container
and you need a small script to stop the
server running in the container
modify the configuration files that you
need to for example for bind you need to
change the name dot config
for uh not you need to change the lever
script so
you need a small script to change this
and restart the circle
and then now it's your choice to pick
from the 18th condition that we
currently have
are the ones that you want to compare
your implementation with
the docker makes it quite simple to test
new implementations and
also add any existing implementations
that currently
support dns authoritative logic
and so now the fedex model as of now is
there is a test generation module and
then there is a differential testing
module
but what if you want to test a custom
test
it's simply you need to just plug in
before the differential testing module
and it will all work
but the more interesting case is how
about
uh how do we test or any implementation
specific behaviors on our zone files
let's say i have used the resound files
i want to know is there any
implementation on which
these zone files will cause a difference
so you have zone files and to test any
uh to test them
you need to use grooth groot is the tool
we built earlier which can generate
query equivalence classes
and i won't go more details please see
our paper or two for those details
now you can pick one query from each
equance class and then test
using the zone files this way you can
also check your zone files to see if
there are any
differences among the implementations
finally from all of this uh these are
the lessons that we learned like
no two name servers agree completely on
all the test cases
and nobody agrees with the rfcs also
perfectly like there is no hundred
percent match
rsvs do the job well but there are some
gaps and ambiguities
for example it's in rfc 103 for exactly
that cname loop should be signaled as
errors
but at what point our whether it should
be unrolled at all
should the loop rrs be returned at all
for another example is any synthesizer
name from dname is a perfect response to
a cname query
when rfcs are open to interpretation
implementations make choice based on
performance resource constraints and
safety
for example in the cname loop case
powered dns regions are fail otherwise
under the blue up to some point and
written under loop
so the interesting point here is like
should the resolvers account for these
different choices
which will make the reservoirs more
complex and lead to interactivity issues
or should the rfcs be more verbose and
stringent and mention all the cases
perfectly well
to conclude we've i presented our tool
for it which can automatically generate
tests for names of implementations
and it generates high coverage test
suits stress testing many corner cases
of rfcs
and we use differential testing to
compare multiple implementations
and we tested eight implementations
found 13 new books
and both the ferret and group are
available on github
and you can reach me at this email thank
you
fantastic uh very impactful work
okay we have i want to remind everybody
uh that you can ask questions in
the q a panel and or raise your hand if
you would like to ask your question
verbally
our first comment from peter van dyke
this is awesome thank you for this work
and thank you for
your very clear bug reports both to us
power dns
and to other projects
uh joe abele is asking a question
uh i'm sorry not a question this is
insanely great
i agree really comprehensive and useful
thank you jacques is saying
did you say you generate the tests by
parsing the rfcs automatically
yes interesting
okay uh vicky risk has asked uh i
said uh i was skeptical skeptical at the
beginning
but i agree this is great i love the
comparison between the implementations
is there a list of which rfcs you
analyze to create your test cases
um we mostly analyzed cname
the name a quad a and soa ns record type
so
that basically is one zero three four
double six seven two
and the white cards is four five nine
two
as far as i remember so these are the
three offers that we took into account
okay we have a follow-up question from
jacques latorre he asked a question
about uh
how you are he's asking how did you uh
parse the rfcs to to do that
automatically
okay i think probably it's but i we
didn't pass the rfc so we read the rfcs
and then i manually we manually
converted them into formal model
and then we encourage the form of model
in the zen language so we didn't
automatically pass the office we just
read it through understood and then
converted into a mathematical form
operation
okay uh we have a couple raised hands
we'll go force
first to uh siobhan sahib siobhan if you
want to unmute yourself
sure yeah this is this is fantastic just
a quick question
um i tried looking on github for some
sample
test cases that you generate i couldn't
really find any do you have like a
like a dump of what a test suite would
look like somewhere
oh i i just made the code public but i
did not make the
test cases public yet i can do that i
think this is just working
we are submitting to a conference i did
not make everything public yet
okay yeah i just wanted to take a look
at what the test case
format looks like um and you know yeah
that's an example one
yeah but otherwise this is great thanks
thank you
all right uh brian dixon asks
do you have employment lined up yet he's
half joking and wants to say awesome
work
thank you i'm still in fourth year it'll
probably take one or two more years to
graduate
all right uh any other questions for
siva
okay uh well thank you very much siva
again this is amazing not just as uh
as a tool for quality assurance and
finding differences in the software but
it's
as far as i know uh one of the better
tools out there for the fingerprinting
of dns servers which
we used to be able to do well and over
the last few years not so much so it's
super great that you were able to
achieve this
thank you thank you thanks for all the
good comments
okay our next presentation uh will be
from alison mankin and siobhan sahib
uh siobhan will be on the screen first
and the presentation
is planning and deployment of dns zone
transfers over
tls siobhan if you'd like to share your
screen
yes hello everyone my name is siobhan
and
i work at brave software and but this
work
was done at salesforce i'm here today
with addison mankin
um and we'll be talking about planning
and deployment of dns zone transfers
over tls
um i also wanted to give a shout out to
our co-authors
william pallavi and especially sarah for
whom right now
is an ungodly hour so she couldn't be
here but
thanks to her especially for driving
this work
over the past little while and ray and
i'll be giving the first part of the
talk and alison will be
giving the second part okay
so for a little bit of background why do
we need
xfr over tls um so currently like many
parts
of the dns protocol or at least uh until
like until recently
um the zone data transfers were um
unencrypted so zone data could be
collected we have passive monitoring on
the wire
and zone data can be
sensitive data and especially for larger
organizations
so for several reasons policy regulatory
you might want to keep these
your own contents as a transfer between
primary and secondary private
um so that is the main motivation for
xfr over tls to prevent its own data
collection during transfer
and our proposed our proposal for this
is
encrypting dns zone transfers so both
axfr and ixfr
using tls as a transport
and the use cases are confidentiality so
putting it over tls would encrypt would
defeat the zone content
zone content leakage problem um
authentication
is a big one so we can use single or
mutual tls authentication
between the client and the server the
primary and the secondary which can
complement
keysig and access control lists
and also performance because the current
usage of
usage of tcp for x so far is often
not great and we'll be going into that a
little bit more detail
and just to give a quick status update
um
it is a it is an iatf draft and it is
now in the later stages of review before
publication as an rfc
uh and there are multiple
implementations and
deployments are being planned and
allison will be talking more about that
later on
so just to give a quick description of
what
this would look like so on the left hand
side you can see
there is the the ix of our request from
response
happens over udp or dcp and this kind of
happens in clear text
and we are proposing that you put the ix
of our
request and response which constitutes a
zone data
transfer in uh in a taylor session uh in
a long-lived tls session
and you we optionally also
suggest that you can use that you can
put the soa request and response
but um we did a threat analysis and we
consider
um for the purposes of this traffic the
really sensitive data is really the zone
data so that's
crucial and optionally you can also add
the seo request
response we mandate that all exoquire
messages must use tls 1.3
or later and
we have port 853
we manage the usage of that just like
dns over tls although you can
negotiate a different part and uh
servers are pre-trip
use other queries on azure connection so
we are not
in any way mandating the authoritative
dns over tls support
and to do this you can use extended dns
error code
not supported which is
now a published rfc and we also go into
some detail in the draft
around the various different operational
and policy options you have
for managing dot connections
um and historically xfr has been
somewhat basic when it comes to tcp
usage so earlier specifications
actually had implications about using
just one connection per
xfr message um and this was updated
somewhat for
axfr later on but the zod draft
updates specs for both ixfr and axfr
to recommend efficient usage of tcp so
we
recommend um multiplexing xfrs
or even for even for different zones on
the same connection
uh pipelining queries and out of order
responses
um and we also recommend you the usage
of
edn s0 keeper live to keep the
connections
um open for reuse to improve performance
and we went into some detail in the
draft talking about the authentication
mechanisms
and um here you can see that we kind of
uh try to see
what are the properties that you would
like so if you like data original
authentication
channel confident neutrality and channel
authentication for both the secondary
and the primary um and the security
mechanisms that we have for that for
that are tsig tls
and there's a few different options for
tls and
and then acls on primary and the draft
recommends that
uh or mandates that the secondary must
always use
strict tls so you get for you so you get
channel confidentiality and
authentication because the server is
authenticated
but the primary um can use um
mtls which is preferred so in that case
the client is also
authenticated and you get the
confidentiality from the tls session
but you can also use ip
acl along with strict tls
and i'll be handing it over to allison
now to talk about
implementation and deployment status
so uh this is about the implementation
and deployment status
the um the key thing for us is that
um that protocols
uh sometimes we expect them to kind of
deploy themselves
we have spent a fair amount of time
during this whole process
as part of the itf's more hands-on and
hackathon process
working hard with implementations
working hard with
operators asking them how they might
deploy this getting a sense of the
the realities of trying to use this in
the field
this has allowed us to be able to say at
the time of
near publication the isg is nearly
finished with approved
proving this there's just a couple of
revisions to make
that um we have a lot of a lot of like
uh
preparation for both for deployment so
first of all on the implementation front
um bind worked with the team
with the the author team uh at
hackathons and other
ways sarah worked with them on helping
to provide some some
some um requirements
uh to uh provide every uh support for
the
the uh zot in um
a good form in 917 which is a
development
branch we are in discussion with when it
will be back ported to 916
we expect it to be um tested
there's some more work to do but we
expect it to be available in a
in a in a production capability
uh in a time frame that is pretty
practical pretty pragmatic
uh unbound has uh been involved and
and then labs unbond has been involved
in this work for the whole time willem
is one of our co-authors
and unbound itself has the ability to do
part of zot which is the secondaries
ax of rsi we have also worked with the
nlnet labs
to prepare prs against nsd
which is which are more complete which
include client-side and server-side
zod support connection reuse as well uh
the
prs are planned for inclusion in our
latest discussion with willem
in the 437 release so there's a very
concrete plan there as well
we expect to have we did a lot of drop
testing
at the itf 110 hackathon and we'll be
doing it again at the 111 hackathon
uh in um sorry in
uh with bind and msd and power dns
and also with some other of the operator
players
next slide please in terms of operations
diverse managed dns server operators are
important for zot because as
people arranged to have some
heterogeneity in their
their xfr's bond and nsd were featured
in particular in the work
that that my part of the team did
because operators had had a use of those
particular stacks
so ultra dns the new start company
has a service which is oriented towards
tlds called xtld which is based on
very plain bind servers pch which
provides a
very large number of secondary services
uses bind nsd
so we get a lot of practical clout from
making a fairly complete
service in those two deploy
implementations
both of those vendors have been open
both of those operators have been open
with a commitment
that they will offer zot in a product
form
when the implementations have reached
product level
and we want to especially flag that pch
has a very strong set of privacy first
policies
and that when they get to the point that
zot can be a product
they expect to make the default offering
for secondary service
eventually as customers get more
interested and express more interest
it might even be something they would
consider making mandatory
as a way of emphasizing their their
privacy first approaches to
operations next side please siobhan
there's some challenges when you deploy
we define
a transfer group as all the servers
involved
for transfers in a given zone um there's
could be multiple primaries there can be
multiple secondaries from multiple
operators different implementations
it's quite important from a security
standpoint that you not have a weakest
link
no weak point there tcig tls
uh decisions single or mutual
um ipacls those things should be
consistent across the transfer group in
order to make sure that there isn't one
particular server that that uh transfer
which is more visible or easy to catch
from
from an adversary so the challenge is
how would you
configure and enforce and test all that
um
we expect to spend time in the hackathon
working on that
um there's there's a lot of interesting
approach issues and that's one of the
things that we hope to do from this talk
is attract more attention and interest
because we'd like for people to work
with us
next slide please
the further deployment challenges are
that
um that you can't expect
an all or nothing rollout but we are
actually pretty strict about what's
required in order to have secure result
so you can expect that
uh there are three more minutes
you can expect to have a incremental
experience for a while
and then say at some point you've
reached full zot um
we need to have all secondaries having a
client inside implementation that's one
reason we focused on that
not all dns operators have a lot of
experience with certificate management
but we think that's actually
a a feature not a bug and
there's some other paths such as dynamic
updates next slide please
uh siobhan uh in breaking news the
the isg uh uh pointed out to us that
there's a recent ietf directive for
alpine to be required
alpin is the application layered
protocol
uh identifier in tls
and so we'll use outpen equals dot we
don't think this applies to
to old stub to recursive dot um
because it was before it predated that
um
i think we're short of time so let's uh
skip over this talk
this particular bullet so in summary
zot will soon be a new itf standard
there are implementations
people are planning offerings there's
ongoing work including the
upcoming hackathon we didn't mention but
padding is an important feature for
getting really good privacy and so
new work is starting up on that and also
on
the encryption that you would do for
dynamic dns update
and peel please uh contact us in the zot
channel and work mattermost and feel
free to
join us in the hackathon upcoming at itf
and now i think it's time for questions
wonderful thank you siobhan and allison
uh our first question comes from joe
ably
and the comparison of different
authentication mechanisms
doesn't t6 provide channel off
and not origin off a t6 secret is
specified to a single edge
in the transfer graph but that edge is
not necessarily bound to the origin
unless i misunderstand what you mean by
the word origin
right um yeah so t-sig is not i guess
we were trying to say that it is bound
to more um like the data side of things
so
one one party is saying that you know
this is
it's a pre-shared key in a sense um so
that is what we were saying it's not
it's not like an endpoint and like a tls
connection where
you're saying that this particular
endpoint is
uh is making is making the um
making the connection and and you if you
know that that is verified
uh is then you can authenticate against
that um but i think i missed
the first part of the question
uh the first part of the question was in
the comparison of different
authentication mechanisms
doesn't t-sig provide channel off not
origin off well
so we consider channelout as in like
literally being the channel between
um the two parties like the server and
the
uh the client or the primary and the
secondary so um
yeah in that sense uh we were
considering that to be providing that
not uh per se i could speak to a little
bit further that actually came up in the
isg review i don't know if you
if you've caught up with all of that in
fact uh we
uh there isn't origin off because the
the um
the ip address is not covered by the
authentication
um and so it is possible it's actually i
think
intended that you could have multiple uh
multiple channels as joe said so um
tsig is not uh t6 combined with
with um tls
provides you a better situation in terms
of with a form of tls authentication
but that's why we require a form of tls
authentication we actually
require strict authentication and then
if you have the strict authentication in
place you actually will also be covering
the origin
the the ip address origin um but we
actually uh
mutual author will be better for this
purpose um
so i i hope that's clear enough the the
spec is actually
uh has a lot of material on that topic
so you can read up a little bit more on
it
okay uh paul hoffman has a question paul
if you wanted to unmute yourself
thank you um so allison great however
you skipped over the one slide i wanted
to hear most about which was the last
one
on alpn simply because i'm wondering
how much is like i could not keep up
with the traffic on the list of what was
going to change
in the draft with respect to alpn and
how much is this going to affect
implementations
um if we're if you're changing what the
alpn is so if you can
go back and give a bit more detail that
would be great could you roll that slide
back for us thank you
um so we think that it's a few lines of
code to say in the tls
that alpine equals dot um we are
expected to use
the same alpen as any other dot
in particular a dot um we won't have a
an issue and so then the question is do
you how do you distinguish if you're if
you're running both
and um the hidden primaries which is
often what you're using in the case
of second of uh xfr uh will not have
that problem because they won't actually
be serving a dot
they won't be serving a uh um
uh queries but uh you also have the
option of running zot on
its own specific ip address report
which is something that you can agree on
in that transfer group which gives you
some flexibility about this as well
but bottom line the uh this discussion
which was all public on the itf list and
on the dns privacy list
sorry on the dns privacy email list is
that
alpine equals dot for all the dot
families and uh definitely is going to
be there for za and we don't think it's
a lot of extra code to do that part of
the work
and we also spoke to a couple of
implementations and they seem to be
fine with that as well yeah okay so and
this won't this won't have a negative
effect on
the fact that as you had showed in
earlier slides there's already a lot of
implementation
you're not concerned about this late
change um
causing incompatibilities and such if if
i'd been a little if it wasn't quite as
late at night i would have mentioned
what siobhan just said which was we went
back to all
of the implementation teams and asked
them about it and also
including uh including um peter from
powerdns
and that was not a big concern to add
this particular capab
uh to add up an equal dot and and use
that part of tls
very good thank you yeah
all right i've seen no additional
questions or hand raised so i would like
to
thank you both siobhan and allison for
your presentation
and with that we'll pass things over to
keith mitchell
keith yeah thank you jake for your um
session sharing for the last two
sessions and also
pallavi for timekeeping and thank you to
all of our speakers uh we're once again
absolutely spot on time with some really
good talks
um for the first first first half of
today um
additional thank you i'd like to thank
our sponsors farsight and verisign um
and we're now going to take a break for
90 minutes um so
chance for you to eat whatever meal is
appropriate in your time zone
uh which is a midnight snack in my case
um
and you can hang out in the spatial chat
so
there's um that's the
platform you used yesterday um you will
see instructions for how to join that if
you didn't get them already in the um
the rolling slides
so we will be restarting at
4 30 utc in 90 minutes times you there
hello everybody my name is
dylan thorpe and welcome back to this
third session of orc35
first of all i'd like to thank our
sponsors
for our site security and very shine
i also like to point out that the time
keeper of today will be
huyien and then without further ado
i would like to welcome our first
speaker
which is benner overreiner who will
present on keeping up with the itf
in the dns hop working group
welcome my name is bello overhead and i
will keep
keep you up to date with activities in
the
itf dynastar working group
it's covering quite a span of recent
proposals
progress and current working group
charts and finnish works
so given the time i will not go into
details but
just will bet your appetite for more
good this is the dns universe in the itf
um you see some faint stars you see some
bright stars but the activities in igf
are here in the stars with a red circle
i will mainly primarily touch upon
dinosaur
and also mention some deprive work
good
let's go to business finish work so work
that has been finished
during the last dinosaur uh
working group meeting at the igf-110
what was finished is the message diocese
for dinner sounds
zone mt so zone md
is uh securing a zone transfers
think of dinosaur protects resource
record sets
zone and the protect zone as a whole
think of well you can
validate the zone
[Music]
the file in its origin wanted to be
authenticity
uh typical use cases are for example
small zones being transferred
to resolvers for example
this root zone or a response policy zone
so for large and dynamic zones
this scheme is not yet suitable because
of
full validation or verification of the
zone
other work that has been finished
recently
in the digital dinosaur working group is
the server cookies it's
actually an update of an already
existing rfc
778-73
but it updates actually for this
rfc for interoperability in any car
setup so in any car setup with multiple
implementations
there were some operational issues that
some of the
cookies generated by one implementation
could not be
interpreted were not the algorithms the
hash alternatives were not
supported by the other implementation
so rfc 1918
corrected this to the server cookies
gives
protection against detox attacks or cash
poisoning
and it gives you a lightweight genesis
guinness transaction
mechanism good so this is work that is
just
recently finished
work almost finished in dinosaur
in working group last call is the svcp
hps draft or the service binding
parameter specification indians
this has been already presented by
ben schwartz in the previous award
meeting
it gives you a new family of uh
types of records that allows a client to
learn more about
the endpoint and the service provided
think of
dls or https in that it also improves
security
and performance and think also because
the other
endpoint and the service provides some
information about the endpoint
this also enables the license of the
apex domains i think of the
long standing discussion of cname in
apex
with svcp hps resource records
service binding and
draft this can be
specified and enabled so that's this
very nice
result here of the working group other
work
that's for working group last call is a
dns transport of tcp operational
requirements
uh this is both for an encrypted tcp
as well for encrypted tls sessions
this is an this this document also asks
for
feedback i i'm sure that john kristoff
asked for feedback on the genius
operations mailing list
so please well it's already it's
invoking
group last call so please give some
feedback here
um and it's still very valid thing here
because recently we had a discussion on
our mailing list
that an inbound user couldn't resolve
his
domain um and he thought there was some
error here
no but it's it's it
it was actually the case that he i don't
know why
he thought it was not necessary he
disabled uh tcp support in the
mount and his answers were well
his own was signed answers were too
large and he get the time out
instead of so he didn't expect this
behavior uh joe ably also
uh reacted on the mailing list
that this is also good feedback probably
for the draft
and the people are tcp is really
required for
proper operation of your precursor and
name server
good uh i have to speed up a bit
closer working group last call is the
well the revised ielts race for demon
sec
so historically it's kind of an
administrative rectification so
previous rfc's mentioned about
what give some requirements for the
insect algorithm but forgot to mention
to say something about the ds hash
algorithms
so this is in this draft
corrected rectified and the motivation
was that
uh with the introduction of national
crypto algorithms like bost
it doesn't know doesn't need to go
through the igf standards
track um right
close to working group last call is
closed sorry close not close to
close is the dinner screen name
minimization
it's the um sorry it's the
it's a base document of rfc 7816
even the practical experience uh and
deployment
of uh dynastream name immunization
this document has been rewritten and
updated so
that's this will be submitted to
to the isg and
other documents that has been closed
for the group is nsec nsac nsx3 ttl
and anzac aggressive use due to
combination of
unfortunate reporting or in earlier
documents the aggressive use of insect
and nsx3
records may deny names intended
longer than
has a longer intended lifetime of a
denial than
intended so this document changes the
definitions of
insect and nc3 to correct that situation
more work of active drafts in the
working group
so we have ginasec of sorry dns catalog
sales
it's it's provides it's an
uh provisioning mechanism by
giving syncing configurations from
primary to secondary
and it does so by
transferring a list of zones
run administrated by the primary
and sent to the secondary instead of
having uh changes at the primary and
also
manually changes at the secondary
because it's not
the zones that run at the primaries are
not
necessarily directly automatically
changed at the secondary
with the zac of dns catalog sounds
this can be automatically kept in sync
the authors ask for operators for use
cases and feedback
this at the mattermost our instance
a channel on this work so if you're
interested please join
the channel at the metamode server
another draft needs work
in the in the dinosaur working group is
uh dinosaur
dns avoid fragmentation so what's
the max size interval of gdp packets
so there are a number of sources so
uh rfc 4035 defines well ipv4
shoot mustang shoot at 1220
for ipv ip4 ipv6
a 4000 shoot but dns flag day last year
introduced
a recommendation of 1232
this was really an operational kind of
this was a value that worked very well
in operational environments
[Music]
jeff hewson did a number of measurements
ex
measuring the dfd the guinness flag day
and he came to some other values as a
recommendation
so it doesn't seem that the genus work
group comes to
one specific film but to arrange
to the interval valid of reasonable
values this discussion will also be
kicked off at the dean's homework group
mailing list
to settle on a sensible range
and uh i will also send emails to the
dns operations
medic list of the over and the right
mailing list for
input from operators good
uh speeding up a bit here
but you have three minutes remaining
until the q a
okay three minutes yes yeah
okay i really really want to speed up
here
this is also a discussion that nc3
iterations
consideration also discussion uh kicked
off
by victor de kofn on dinosaur perez's
mailing list and it's also
have a look at it there are well typical
values
very very high number of iterations
these are not necessary so there's a
proposal for lower
iterations also by the draft of west
harter
insect automation has been presented
yesterday
by ulrich visser next slide moving to
deep bright work this also has been
presented
zone transfers over tls it's
submitted to the ist for publication
other i find very interesting work here
at the d prime work group is
dns over quick so again this is not
same as doh with hp3
so here's quick to transport layer so
you don't have the http headers
and cookies
so there i'm just i have copied here the
table
of the implementation status of dennis
over quick
i won't go into detail this is a table
from a presentation by sarah dickinson
so there's a good
work going on already here i'm looking
forward
to more results and progress of the
document
right existing work more existing work
is of course at the deep drive a lot of
attention is going into
encrypted dns from recursion to
authoritative
so um it started in february march we
had
one document specific on this recursive
authority of dns with encryption
and today this document there was
already another document but
today this document has been refocused
to recursive alter the recursive
alternative
with an authentic encryption and two new
documents
actually working all together
defining the common features of
encrypted and unencrypted
uh of encrypted precursors to
authoritative genius
uh authoritative authenticated sorry or
unauthenticated and addressed by
ecker eric pescola and others about
signaling
authoritative dds encryption and here
svcb
can be used to discover whether the name
server supports encryption so that's
also a nice
result of the dinus of the svcb
draft in denisov i will skip this one
it was long time discussed oblivious
though
in deprived but it's now concluded that
it's
uh it's for now uh going uh in the
individual track in the individual
submission
um oh not too bad
here that's one this is uh this is
interesting
uh confidential computing to protect the
next resolution so
this was a present presentation at
dinosaur
by yari and it's not was
not dinosaur work actually but it
it it needed a platform
and a dinosaur working group
we provided some time to present his
ideas about well confidential computing
to protect dns
so we always discuss things about
securing dns queries over the network
but dns data at rest should also protect
it
so here i just copied the slide from
from yardy so the dns resolver
is executed in a trusted execution
environment
so that the hardware or the platform
owner cannot access
dns data at rest at the server
there was quite some interest in the
working group but also
it was it's not in charge of the unisop
so for now if there's some progress
something to
present there will be room but
probably it will need to find another
working group or
another place to be worked upon maybe in
the irtf
or in one of the other or well
somewhere in the dns or somewhere in the
dns ecosys
universe in the itf
that's it that was really
very brief in time but also
it was extended in a number of topics
i hope you have well learned about
activities the dns activities in the itf
um i'm open for questions for more
details
for more pointers and i also invite you
all
to join the discussions on the dinosaur
mailing list or
when we spin off some of the discussions
at the genus operations mailing list of
darwin
thank you all thank you bye now
i think we have one and a half minutes
for questions
i also would like to remind the audience
that during the q a
section a
poll will show up and this is the
only time you have the opportunity to
rate the talk and this is quite
important to
the pc and
the speakers to do this so please
take that opportunity i see
one question in the q a
facility of zoom from anvil kempling
he says i'd also mentioned the a
day working group has adopted two drafts
on dna's discovery
with a further draft in development that
covers split
horizon dns and the tls working group
continues to work
on the ech encrypted client hello draft
which may provide a longer term solution
for
esni encrypted server name indication
it has implications for content
filtering
finally the concept consensus on
oblivious dough in deep thrive
seems to be to keep it experimental and
focus instead on oblivious http
yeah thank you for the additional
comments uh
yeah that's correct
yeah i
have another
question remarked from ralph weber
what about the camel given that you
barely could fit
naming all the drafts in presentation
that is true yeah yeah so uh
what about the camel uh it's
uh
[Music]
so dinosaur is actually
of course uh not per se extending it it
is
working on drafts for operational uh
foreign operations and we we
run into operational problems that has
to be solved
think of the the rfc
the dns server cookies uh these are
really
these were really uh not useful uh
with the old draft of the alt rc we
needed
to update rfc and the same for the queue
name
again that these are the biz documents
but for svcp uh for example this is uh
it might be part of another straw on the
cable's back
but it does solve a lot of uh well
operational
and i wouldn't say problems the
challenges that's better
we really needed this and this this
draft opens up
a lot of uh well possibility of
solutions where we had a lot
long long discussions before in the
dinosaur working group
before that yeah okay so it's
it's it's always a balance between is
this not another
is it not the final straw on the back of
the camera or do we
really need to examine he's still
standing
yeah yeah good yeah
okay thank you we know you're welcome
thank you yeah could you stop sharing
the
slide deck
and then i would like to welcome
another dutch guy actually
most of this the complete session is
dutch
luckily except for our time keeper
so otto mooreberg welcome
hello thanks
we'll be presenting tcp fast open
not so fast okay thank you for your
introduction i was
uh well having some trouble here but uh
i can start now so my name is uh otto
burbank and
uh i'm going to talk about tcp fast open
with the subtitle not so fast um
so today i'm what i will be discussing
is is how i
added the tcp fast open to the power dns
recurser i'm a powderiness
developer and mostly working on the
recursor
so we're going to look a bit at
some programming issues but also mostly
practical issues with the tcp fast open
and
i hope to show that tcp fast open is
indeed fast at least faster than
no tcp fast open but it is not fast in
all aspects there are some issues with
it
so to start i'm talking about why tfo
why is it relevant
to bns
uh and then i would like to tell
something how it works uh and
then look into the default uh
from both a server point of view and a
client
point of view of course authoritative
servers are
only servers with respect to
connections but recursors are both
servers and clients
they are clients that do their if
servers
and then look at the practical issues
encountered while using
php fast open and then
some conclusions i see there's a typo
there
i'm going to also try to do some
suggestions how to improve the current
situation so first
i'm going to discuss why
tfo and especially why
tcp is relevant in the dns world
well as you all know vns queries or
other dns answers are getting larger and
larger we have text
records we have the unsec records we
have edens options
all added to the payload of the dns
answer
and that will uh
so the ins uh cases where a answer does
not fit
a udp perfect size will increase
and especially since
current situation is is that to avoid
fragmentation
in the udp world the prophesizers
uh redskins suggested are now suggested
to be
much smaller than before so
the tc the dns protocol has to switch to
tcp
to get the answer to the client in more
cases
and that's already
being seen by operation operators of
recursive
much more connections are using tcp
now the overhead of tcp is an issue
it consumes more resources both on the
client side and the server side
in terms of computational effort and
memory
things like client both client and
server have to keep
track of uh state of the dcp connection
and also to actually transfer
data from the server to the client and
vice versa more packets have to be
exchanged so the
pcp a typical tcp
answer retrieved over tcp will have a
larger latency than a answer over udp
now tf o needs to be fast open
does solve some of those problems
especially it solves
some of the latency issues at the cost
of
using even more resources a bit of a bit
it's not that much but it does consume
more resources than just
doing regular tcp
so before we look into tfo
let's have a brief overview of probably
something you have
already seen in other places that this
is the classical tcp
connection setup data exchange and
connection tear down
sequences shown by uh wireshark
so the through a handshake sims in
an ack followed by
a query sent to the server
that query is act by the server
and then followed by a response this is
actually the response
the data that is the client
requested then we get an act from the
client to the server
to acknowledge the receive reception of
the
query the response and then we get a
teardown
of the dcp connection so in total
10 packets are exchanged to
get the query and the answer transferred
and compare that to a typical udp
or the iudp curve response which
takes two packets it takes four packets
for the actual query to arrive
at the server and two more query
two two more uh packets so
it takes four packets to for the query
to arrive
two more packets to get the response
back and then
some maintenance packets to tear down
the connection so
that is the reason why the tcp
connections has a
larger latency more packets
are exchanged to keep track of the state
of the connection
so in the tfo setting
the initial data exchange isn't that
much different
if the client has never seen the server
before and the server has never seen
that particular client before
the initial packet of the client will
contain a
extra tcp option it says well i am i do
support and i
request from you that you send me a
fast open cookie that
tcp option is embedded in the first sin
and in the reply to the synthesis in
hack the
server will respond with okay i do also
do support
fast open and i'm sending you a cookie
that cookie is a secret
based on some client properties
uh like particularly the client's ip and
the local
but also on local server
data like the local ip of the server and
port and
and also most importantly a secret
that you could as you could
the server uses to compute a hash of the
data i mentioned
and that computes to a value
of the cookie and that cookie is sent
back in
response to the sin so after this
the client has a
extra data and it will use that for
step 2 in the default that is a second
or
further connection to the same server
the client will send with the initial
request
initial sin immediately
the data and the cookie
that cookie will be used by the server
to validate that
indeed this client i've seen this client
before it has done a proper three-way
handshake before so
now i'm going to accept that the client
sends data immediately with the first
sin
and not only is that data accepted but
we will see that also that data is
immediately
transferred to the application so
normally data in the initial data from
the query is only
sent to the application after a
three-way handshake
completes now it can be sent to the
application
immediately on the receipt of the first
packet
and you see that we have now total
eight packets and the query
arrives at the server immediately with
the first packet
and the answer is contained in the
fourth
packet so we have effectively reduced
the latency
quite a bit now
why is that cookie important to be
cryptographically
secured i'm going to briefly mention
that
it is important because otherwise there
would be a possibility that
for a sin flood attack a new type of
sinful attack
the rfc goes into more detail but
effectively
what you want to know is that the client
did a proper three-way handshake before
and if it does so if it has done so the
server will send that
cookie as an acknowledgement of that
fact and the client
can present that later on to say well
i've been here before you know me
already i've done
and i'm a proper client because i'm able
and willing to participate in a proper
three-way handshake
and actually that's all the cookie says
it doesn't say
a lot more that's of course there's a
pretty weak
form of authentication so the cookie
itself is no
actual proof that the client is is the
one you're talking to
it only proves that you have seen that
particular client before
if you want to know more about it by how
this is
important please consult the rfc
so the sketch of the implementation uh
of of a uh of a tfo supporting this key
stack is pretty
simple and the nice thing is uh
the server doesn't work the client
doesn't work it's all not very
complicated it
becomes a bit more complicated because
you also want to have of course graceful
degradation in the sense that if one of
the sites does not
support cookies things go right
so there is some complication there but
the nice thing from an application
point of view is that the os does all
the real work
generating the cookie storing the cookie
for later use
in the client and on the server side
validating the cookie
and generating one if it's needed so
uh for a for my application point of
view
application writer point of view things
are simply simple
so let's see how does
that work out for for various uh
open source dns servers both the
authoritative and recursives and
what we see is is that both that most
most of them mention a tfo supporting
release notes
but if you look into the details it
becomes a bit fake
is it always enabled do you have to set
a
option um how does
the for recursor is there any
are we talking about the server side of
things or the client side of things
of course the recursive acts you know
often in a way
as a of a client to authoritative
servers so
there is support but things are a bit
fake um
i will we'll see that later
uh i'll also illustrate that with
another example
so i'm going to talk mostly about the
client side because that's
the thing i'm working on worked on in
recursive but
a quick look at the server side if you
wanted to
support tfo there's only one actually
one thing you have to do
on the on in the code and that is to
set a option on the socket on the listen
listening socket and that's enough you
would assume that
there's more to it one
is you have to also enable it in the os
if we're talking linux
and the thing is
even the socket option call does not
fail if
it's not enabled in the os
so you can think that
fast open is enabled but actually it
won't be until you set the process
control
on os level this is documented
properly in in kernel.org
but remember if you want to
serve enabled dfo as a server
you have to also set the access control
in linux
and i would recommend
that server warn that
dfo is enabled for the application
but not on the os side if that's the
case
otherwise system administrators might
think dfo is enabled but it is actually
not
because the actual set socket operation
call does not
return an error if the os disallows it
so that's the server side one single sec
set second option call
there's a small detail and
that is not
very pretty uh it's not
well documented is the set socket option
call is not a boolean but a number and
that
number reflects the queue size of the
work
incoming tfl requests and there is
actually no i found no guidance in
the proper value of that value of that
queue size
so that is something which
i think the documentation documentation
should improve on
now look at the client side client side
is also pretty simple um
when i was looking at this reverser
priority network already had the
server-side thing uh
sort of thing so we're looking into the
client side of things and
luckily it is also pretty simple
there are actually two methods of doing
tfo
as a tcp client one is
to not do a connect at all but
use a specific socket option in sense
so very specific flag in send system
call
alternatively you can also enable it
before you directly do the connect
to a server and then if your code
is doing
non-blocking io which i think most
recursive servers do then there are
actually no real other code changes
needed it does not sound difficult at
all
and but there's also
and there is a drawback and that is the
this particular set
circuit call is not documented at all
if you want to know how it works and how
to use it you have to
look up the pull request into linux
where it was introduced
and which explains how to use it so that
is a bit of a drawback
it seems that tcp
or other network socket options are
generally not documented
at all or very sparsely if they are
newer than
what is mentioned in let's say stephen's
or so
if it's too new you have to go ahead
sometimes for the documentation or even
look at the source code to actually find
out
what it is doing but actually
once you've found that out it is not
that hard
so next comes testing
and i was a bit surprised that
the code wasn't working as i was
expecting i looked at the wireshark
diagrams and i saw
strange things and well one of the
reasons was that i was using a dcp
forward
to quad eight and
what you have two minutes remaining
until the q a
okay uh quote 8 uses
is this 20 minutes
so the q and a
[Music]
sorry you have 5 minutes for q a but you
have two minutes five minutes okay yeah
yeah yeah
okay uh so the uh
the the problem is is that called a
uh does accept cookie requests
it does send back a cookie so here you
see in this diagram that the
tcpfs open was presenting a cookie it
received earlier
earlier but then what a
refuses the cookie sends a new cookie
and the client does a retransmission
after that so uh
quad a is supposedly
doing tfo but in practice it does not do
it properly and this is
uh some caused some head scratching and
i looked a bit into this and um
the summary is 4.8 is not the right dns
server to check
your tfo operations it does send cookies
it doesn't
but it does not accept the same cookie
it
in very rare cases it does accept it but
only if you
hit the same anycast server by accident
and the strange thing is there are
solutions to this problem
which google did not implement and you
can have two
ways of solving this issue either by
uh setting a the tfo secret used to
generate cookies
on a system or os level you can also do
it on a specific
listening socket from the server side
but
both are not implemented at 8.
so it advertises ufo support but does
not
implement it properly this is known at
google
for a long time already since 2017 and
what is a bit said is that both the
tfo rfc and the linux implementation
originate from
google so they have all the knowledge i
would assume they also have the
resources
but for some reason they do not support
it properly
this is also observed at google's
authoritative servers of course that is
the issue i was
most concerned with because i was doing
the
recursion to authoritative part of the
problem
for the dot and the doh offering at the
quarter eight they do that correctly so
they don't
know how to do it but for some reason
they have not implemented that for
both the authoritative servers and the
their recursive servers
for a clear text tcp
other public uh
precursors do support it but only for
doh
and the nice thing is if you do a dot or
the oh connection is that tfo allows you
to
send the client hello immediately
included in the first
packet so that is nice authoritative
servers are very rare
their support there's more detail in
this in the paper paper i mentioned
and i
since there is now already quite some
years it has been
available in the linux kernel it's it
seems a bit uh
low that number is presented so it would
be really nice to do that study again
and
see if more authoritative servers do
support
tfo but
this is not the only issue there's also
an issue on the client side
the linux kernel is
doing all the work but it's not doing
all the work
always uh
if you look at
[Music]
packet captures and in data reported by
netstat
you see that you see a lot of open
active
fails but also open
black hole counters increase
these counters are not documented as far
as
as i know but looking at the source code
in the linux kernel
and some descriptions or found by
googling
it turns out that the linux kernel
is extremely conservative
effectively if a single
tfo connection times out for whatever
reason
just maybe because the particular
authoritative server is not
available it will stop using tfo
for all connections for an hour
by default so that means that if you
have one
authoritative server which does not
respond over gcp
even
[Music]
authoritative servers you can try to
connect to
and that worked before will not
stop using pfo for one hour and if it
happens again
the period is even longer
so there's next explanation back off
well in practice
hitting authoritative servers with
issues happens a lot and
is not rare at all so that means in
practice we
are seeing that even if you have ufo
enabled
you practice the
protection mechanism so to speak kicks
in
and tifo is disabled by the colonel
why would it be so conservative and i
guess that is because well maybe you are
in a situation where
a middle some middle box does not allow
tfo because it does not
like this particular option it does not
know that particular option and some
little boxes are very strict in that so
it will
kill the connection kill drop the
packets
and that has the effect that
it just stops working
so i think we can come to
the conclusion that tfo as a technical
measure does work
it is faster than no tfo
but the abduction is very slow even if
the kernel does all the work and the
introduction into an application is
pretty simple
so the adaption is slow because of the
conservative client approach
lack of documentation on the server side
both in the kernel
and in dns servers
so it's uh all the
nice things are there simple
implementation
completely done by the os almost
completely done by the west
but still adoption is very slow and
that's a bit of
pity because i think well it could
at least lighten some of the drawbacks
of
pcp and
i would say that the aggressive non-use
of
dfo in the linux kernels could change
within that respect and also the
documentation
on how to set it up properly but the
assist controls etc should also improve
and then it maybe has a chance to get
some traction
so that is i think the conclusion
thank you i'll thank you
um i'm afraid we are now also
out of question and answer time
uh maybe sorry about it i i had a yeah
i made a mistake in my head with the
time allotted so
i i know i know time flies when you're
having fun
but maybe even ash you can put up the
pool
window very quickly to wait the talk
because it's the only opportunity to do
so
and then i
take this opportunity to just read out a
remark from punit suit
from google google public dns the tcp
fast open feature felt through the
cracks
not intentional also
otto i invite you to
answer the remaining questions from
brian dixon
in the q a feature in zoom
so we can continue
with the next talk which will be from
giovanna maura
and giovanna will talk about
fragmentation truncation
and timeouts are large dns messages
failing to bits falling to bits
all right all right good morning evening
or
afternoon water depending on where you
are
thanks willem um so yeah this is work
we've done in sidne labs
me and moritz and marco martinez
christian who's also at the university
of twente also in the netherlands
uh we're we're going to look today into
fragmentation truncation and
times out and while we didn't as
messages are falling to bits
i mean jeff houston has been doing like
lots
lots of work in this field and this was
actually inspired by his work
and also by the well i started the dns
flight they was coming along
and i thought it was a good opportunity
to uh have
data from a different vantage point on
the same issue
so that's the actually the start of this
this this is
uh this presentation and actually it was
a paper that we published at
pump 2021 and if you folks are
interested
you can actually download them in this
link so
uh this i don't really have to cover
much because everyone
knows all these things here is genesis
and the car protocols in the internet
but if udp fails due to
the message is too large if it gets
truncated um
what happens is resolvers should retry
using tcp
but the problem is there it's with large
messages over dns
udp over udp well vanilla
dns over edp supports maximum 512 bytes
uh over dcp there is no strict limit
but eg and s0 extend this limit to much
upper higher levels for udp
but if the response is too large what
can happen is
you know for the network if it's true
arduino network mtu
the packets can be either fragmented or
discarded
and well traffic has been covered this
for a long time it can
lead for unreachability and actually
there was also a study from and now that
labs on that i think over v6
specifically um we also cite that uh
and the server body can do if you just
response is too large you can truncate
and the client can ask it via tcp uh but
the question you analyze very
interesting here is how big is this of a
problem on dns based on the data that we
have
and we have data from a ctod uh
the netherlands dot nl we're gonna look
what he did in his research is
look into three different months of data
uh from two of our authoritative name
servers
um july 19 july 20 october 2020
and here in the state we have entire
breakdown you see that
like roughly 2.93 to up 7.15
of the queries actually udp truncated um
you see here the
ratio of tcp ideally they should be
similar
uh but you i'm gonna get later into that
why
some tc udp carriers are not being
followed up
um so in total we get 169 billion queers
and
responses i mean queers and 164 billion
responses from unique 3 million ip
addresses
and 46 thousand antenna systems uh
and these are the questions we're going
to analyze how come on are large dns
responses
how come is truncation on our server
side if resolvers
also fall back to tcp and what is the
impact of flag day 2020
so the first question that we analyzed
when
analyzing this data is to analyze the
response sizes that came out of our
servers
for the data and now zone and we found
it 99 well
virtually all the queries pretty much
you can see here in the cdf are smaller
than 12 32
they'll after they choose right here so
you see like pretty much you everybody
here is a cdf
in regardless of udp of of the server or
tcp are smaller than
um 12 32
and that's the limit that was chosen by
the the dns flag day
and even we say well that's because it's
starting out it's once the cctv you
cannot generalize that
well a resolver server service from
google report that 99.7 percent of their
own queries are smaller than 1232 too
so it kind of confirms mo our view as
well
and over both v4 and v6
um the other question we look at it's
like
how often service server side
fragmentation occurs
so since our vantage point is passive
alternative to server we cannot really
know what happens in the network between
us and the client
we just look at what gets fragmented by
us uh
and we see that on the server side
there's very little fragmentation if
there is any fragmentation going on is
on the network but we cannot really see
that very easily
um and we get less than 10 000 queries a
day from 2.2 billion daily on that so
it's not
like a lot of cures being fragmented on
the server side
uh what about in-network fragmentation
so since our vantage point does not
allow us to
see that we ran two measurements with
ripe atlas
and we had like in this in this
measurements we have this number of
active probes on both measurements
sending this number of queries
and the difference between the large
measurement and the small is this
response size
one has 1744. these are responses that
run on the dns of that nl
on the data nails on and the one had a
very small response size
and what he wanted to know it's like
what is the
percentage of queries that time out when
you retrieve smaller answers
about this size from ripe atlas and is
this number
and i mean like using ripe atlas
directly to query
our authoritative server and s3 and not
using resolvers
so for some reason 2.5 and a half
percent
of all the queries that go to ns3 from
this eight
five eight thousand five hundred probes
get lost
but if you amplify that to this uh use a
larger response size
you see an increase to up up to seven
percent so
the difference should give an indication
of what's being uh
fragmented and lost in the network um
but it cannot be used to be 100 sure
because you don't have the full view of
the network
um so what about the network
fragmentation um
uh well that's our just pretty much what
i just repeated there
we we just see the responses of the
clients but uh the figures that we found
as numbers here confirms periodic
studies
and the next question we analyze over
this
uh research is how common is dns
truncation
well truncation occurs when the response
is too large to be sent by the server to
the client
and the server just truncates it to a
certain limit and flags with a tc flag
on
and i as i said here that depends on the
data set we're looking at but it's
between
roughly three percent to up seven
percent depending on the p version of
the data set you're looking at
uh in the course we're looking at the
requiring and truncated this value
and we also identify the paper that
large gns0 buffers do not prevent
temptation either
and so we also wanted to know how many
queries that are truncated
how many of them are actually followed
up by tcp queries
and um we found that the details are in
the paper but we found out that
roughly 7 80 to 85 percent of the
queries depending on
uh where you're looking at they're
actually being followed by tcp
but we all know that there's a lot of
strange behavior on dns so maybe some
reservers are not standard
but the details are in the paper and
we also look at where the most common
advertised egns values
by clients uh this is the data set of
july 2020 so we've got all the queries
for that month
and we get all the dns zero values that
they plot
and you see that most resolvers here are
using
the ford uh 26 uh dns zero
value um some they're just using 12 uh
512 and there's a large distribution
over here
so and here distribution pair autonomous
systems so fort
4096 is still pretty popular that's the
conclusion you can get here
um and bind and i think maybe other
resolvers too
i'm not quite positive they don't use a
fixed
18 as zero value they use one and they
keep on
changing that value depending on the
server increment and increasing
depending on if they get an answer
without truncation or not so this figure
here shows the number of unique
dns values per resolver and you see like
roughly 70
of other resolvers just announced one
dns value to us
but uh but we see like um
the other the others actually like no
above here they send at least two
engines value so the same ip address is
using different
values but most just an advertised one
um so cns flag day uh
2020 that was a project
initiated by the community and the idea
was to get like
folks to avoid any cause fragmentation
and one way to do that was decided was
to use the
edns buffer size it would actually limit
the change it would reduce the chances
of truncation and the value of 1232 was
chosen for that there's a lot of
reasonings for that
and the idea is so if you would
advertise use your resolvers to
advertise that value you could like uh
eliminate problem fragmentation and
reduce truncation
and that is like what was that take
we wanted to see that using our data and
to identify that
we compared the data that we had from
july 2020
that was before the flag day and the
entire month of october 2020
right after the flag day and we plot the
cds here the distribution
of all the responses that we get based
on that
and you see that the curves they
pretty much overlap to each other and
that's a sign
apologies this is a sign that has
nothing has been
there's no there has been no significant
changes up to october 2020
and we actually look into the data
and we found uh that
11 000 resolve was pretty much uh
changed from whatever values they had to
12 15 12 32 actually
that's that was the value recommended by
the flag day
and you see that the values that where
they came from so it's not a large a
large number of resolvers that actually
change that
so we see that maybe we need to measure
more often maybe
maybe to measure like now or in a couple
of months from now
to see the uptake but right after the
adoption
of uh right after the flag day we didn't
see
much uptake we described some networks
that actually did that we could
clearly see that in our data but
still you know there hasn't been that
many as we could would have hoped for
um and
to summarize what you see here this is
pretty much a summary of what we've seen
in the paper
um the question is are dns responses
fall into bits
well for now our vantage point we found
that most
ns responses are actually small so
there's a little fragmentation risk
for our vantage point but we
i see that could happen as well and the
server side fragmentation is minimum but
in the network we
measure using rapid hazards that
actually happens
uh two to seven percent of the data now
udp
responses get truncated and out of those
80 to 879 25 percent are followed by a
tcp
query and the flag the update was not
very noticeable uh
yet but again you may probably measure
this again and more detail
to see that uh yeah and i think
that's what i have to say here there are
any questions i'll be happy to take them
thanks sir thank you giovanni
uh that was really quick
thank you for that uh yeah we do have
uh a bit more time for uh questions
so i'd like to point out again that
during the
q a section the poll will show up
where you will be able to read the talk
and this will be the only opportunity to
rate the talk
so please fill in your questions in the
q a section
or raise your hand if you want to
ask a question live i can see
one raised hand
but i'm not really sure oh jeff houston
okay
uh jeff if you can
mute yourself yes i have uh great
presentation thanks a lot for giving it
um we also looked at the flag day and
what actually happened
with resolver behavior and i think
like you uh we're looking at the
interaction between recursive resolvers
and
the authoritative servers in our case of
course we were seeding
this environment with our own queries so
we kind of understood
why our authoritatives were receiving
queries the point i would like to like
to make is that we did see
quite a visible change of the
average behavior of queries
now presumably if say the google public
dns
recursive resolver changed its behavior
then all of a sudden a whole bunch of
queries are going to change because a
lot of folk use it
but i am just going to focus on user
counts not resolve accounts because it's
easier to think about
what we found was that actually the big
uptick
was not 1232 that was a
relatively small but still visible
uptake uptake
the big uptake was a bunch of resolvers
that went to 1400
and it's sort of okay i can see that
you're taking flag data heart
but where did 1400 come from it's sort
of
well you could have gone even higher if
you wanted but
why 1400 so i just wanted to point out
that
recursive resolvers did make a change
but the change was
almost unanticipated but as i said great
talk thanks
thanks and thanks jeff for pioneering
this work uh we
see the cdf here can see the green line
of october we see no spikes around
1400 but i can look clear in the data
and let you know if
we actually can't identify that um but
yeah
i agree with you we haven't seen much
uptake but i i will look at the 1400 let
you know but
from the graph here i cannot really
clearly see that
don't forget that i'm measuring what i
would call users
and i'm not sure but i think you might
be measuring resolvers
yeah we are uh we're getting like
resolvers that talk to us and
you are getting the correct me from
wrong
you're doing the ad networks and you're
getting the resolvers
from those networks of the users right
right but the issue is when we talk
about resolvers we're never quite sure
if we're talking about
jeff's favorite resolver sitting
underneath the desk here in front of me
or google's public dns resolver you know
handling
gazillion of queries per second and when
we talk about resolvers
the small numbers the small resolvers
tend to overwhelm the large ones
if they all get a waiting one and this
is why what we saw
is that 1400 is now used by seven
percent of
users as distinct from
you know resolve accounts which is kind
of different yeah
so i think we did announce mostly uh
for 12 22 but i i can't look into that
exactly yeah
be right yeah so and for that now i
think
we run another research with folks from
new zealand and they confirmed the same
one-third of our queries come from
google's and facebook google and
facebook and other
facebook and three other two systems
microsoft and
amazon and i forgot the other
but google public dns is our biggest
client by far and
this is public information as well um
but all together these five networks
they account for one-third of our
traffic but the other one third is not
but yeah um i have to look at that in
the 1400s
it's just it's just this major challenge
when any of us try to measure the dns
of trying to actually understand how to
make the results meaningful
because as i said there are massive
resolvers and there are kinsey whimsy
resolvers
and equally when we even try to think
about users caching gets in the way and
we we have a very dim view
and so you know i think we're both down
the same path of
trying to understand how to get a decent
picture from what i would tend to say
is cloudy data thanks anyway great work
thanks thanks thank you jeff i see we
have another
raised hand from uh which is brunit
suit from google please go ahead
hi giovanni so thanks for running this
experiment in the presentation this is
good to see uh
just to ris also to respond to jeff
houston so yes
google public dns was running with 1400
the the main point i would make is that
this was not so much a flag day it was
more a
slow change in behavior for us as well
as i assume
a bunch of other operators so it will be
good if you could repeat
this experiment now and see how the data
looks
you can't do that yeah so this is like
well this is for the paper but i can re
reasonably rerun the queries and post
them on materials
so i have a question in the q a facility
from peter koch
something i would like to ask as well
some
rr sets are riskier than others
do your data allow an assessment for dns
key in particular
so we're taking we are analyzing
anything that came out
comes out of our servers like all the
responses
in regardless of the query type whatever
comes out we
take that into account so put it all
together in the same bucket
if that's what he's asking
we don't discriminate to get all the
traffic all the traffic
yes we can go back here the table and
see that so for example in july
2020 we had this number of queries 45
billion and 45
billion responses yes whatever it is we
analyze
yeah yeah uh yeah but
i mean your slides suggest that it
doesn't occur that often
fragmented data that for some records
it's more important than for others
right yeah um
yeah so when you take a bulk of uh
queries that we said that are now it
doesn't happen very often now
but uh i think it's in the paper if i'm
not mistaken
the query generates more the larger
response for that and now that we
look like analyzing our passive data
i think was any i think it was any or
i'm not quite positive i would have to
look into that but it's in the paper
there are far more videos of the paper
thanks
thank you giovanna uh there are a few
more remarks
in the queue and a from stefan
ubink he says the dns flag day only is
the the software uses the new setting as
a default
as far as i know today does not mean it
has changed on systems
that's right yeah and i i think like we
documented the paper
uh whereby when buying started using
that but they have this dynamic value
too
so they kind of try to assess yeah about
to probably do something similar with
gas
uh yes yes we changed it on the day
but you know it takes a little while
until people are
uh installing this software and the
final remark from
uh brian summers for the record albert
dns
sets the best size to 1410 and has done
so for many years
so that's kind of nice getting now we
can fingerprint all these resolvers
thank you very much steven that was very
interesting
thanks everybody so
we will now have a break for 15 minutes
and start again at six o'clock utc
i would like to remind you that there
are the breakout rooms
for face-to-face chat spatial chat
you have received details in how to
enter that in the
email in advance or you can see the
details on the rolling slides which
we'll follow shortly
please do not share the special chat
link
with anyone else and i'd
also like to thank our sponsors again
for site security and very sign
and i see you at six o'clock
okay welcome back to the final session
of warp 35.
uh thank you if you've stuck with us
this long
uh we try not to take up too much time
but um we
like to spend a little bit of time with
every other workshop or so
letting you know how things are going or
what we've been up to
um i did a brief introduction for
non-members yesterday
um here's a bit more content that's
hopefully relevant to members
um basically it will be myself
um standing in for jerry i'm jerry
unfortunately um
hasn't managed to stand the pace of the
weird time zone
um and then matt will be giving a
systems engineering update and um and
then finally i'll give you a little bit
of overview and organizational
information
um so hopefully 45 more minutes and then
um you can all go off and enjoy your
fridays or your
or your weekends before i start i'd like
one more time to thank
verisign and farsight security as our
sponsors this time and also a big thank
you to all the speakers
who have um been speaking this far
so um i know you'd all much rather
listen to jerry than me
um the important thing here is that um
when we do our regular quarterly reports
to the members we also do them in
written version for the workshops
so um you will be able to find jerry's
written report
linked to this particular item sorry
about helicopter
and
any mistakes that you see in the
following are
mine and not jerry's so what we knocked
in the software front
um there's funded projects um
there are some highlights and updates
about the software and the other thing
is the in the written report is that we
always ask um the members what they've
been up to with their uh mostly open
source
software projects so there's a thank you
all the members that contributed to that
there's there's news about that in their
report as well you can find all the
software that we have
um at the um the web page that's listed
there
um shows all the software you can see
there's a big list of tools which we
have taken on board and or developed
ourselves
there's also information about funding
development work or licensing policy
and links to the the various github
projects and mailing lists that we have
um 18 releases have been done since the
work 33
so you know just maintaining the the
regular releases is is becoming an
increasingly
big part of of what we do and more about
that later in terms of increasing our
software engineering outcome
um there's been 160 issues and pull
requests that have been
resolved and or merged in
you can see the um the activity level
here um which is pretty steady
but it's you know it's good that we get
the engagement and the support
to the various tools from the community
funded projects um two important ones
here for
for 2021 um there is the dns
dns perf dns over https project which
has been funded by
mozilla and comcast the first phase of
that was to remove dependencies
from the entire some internal libraries
of bind
um that were that were used by dns perf
originally and now uses entirely
open and public libraries and library
interfaces to various pieces of code
that was the first phase the second
phase was to add
improved support for stateful transports
so it works better for
connection oriented dns over tcp in
various forms
um and then the um the third part and
and the third part
we'll see a little bit more in a minute
um check my dns is a tool that's been
around for a while or
our modern dns tester um there were some
rpti features added to it and i thought
basis some time ago
i'm pleased to say that we got a second
year of iron community grant funding
and we were able to use this to add
the user interface for the rpi rpki
origin validation
um in the form of um achievements and
achievements or
a badge which has been added to our to
checkmate dns which we can potentially
use for for other
test results as well um
other highlights and there's no
dedicated software channel on the
mattermore server which seems to be
getting a lot of activity and engagement
so um you'll certainly
um find that useful discussion and also
um
get some help with your use of a work
software um dns cap this version two
zero zero releases come out
um dum dum d is one of the components
of our software suite it's had some
additional features added to it to help
it work better
with the dns perform that's been done
um and yes the dsc graffana tools the
example graphs have been updated and
fixed
what's what we're going to be working on
in the future uh
phase 3 dns over https support it's
going to be added to the dns perf
um between now and the end of august um
jerry is thinking about doing a crash
course on how to use dsc in graffana
and that would be something that we
could add on to or 35a so please do let
us know if you're interested in that
obviously be a tutorial
on setting up um from scratch to
generate the graphs
and if you've got ideas for things that
the gerry could be working on then then
please let them know
and we'll be done happy to take that on
board
um so um this is the point which we
usually get questions i have a strong
suspicion that if there are any
questions they'd be probably better
answered by jerry than me but i'll also
do my best i also apologize that my uh
my voice is starting to give out
after uh staying up half the night
um okay um if there are no questions
which they do not appear to be um i will
now
um hand you over to matt and matt will
give you the
update on the systems engineering
hi everyone um uh yes i'm
matt townsett i'm a work systems
engineer
so let's get uh
slides going
um all right so as keith mentioned
there's uh there's a written report
um for uh um that sort of accompanies
this
um the the url for where to find out an
indigo is there as
as well as qr code that will that will
take you to it
um so the report in addition to the
stuff i'm talking about here the report
goes into some more detail
uh about those things um but also uh
includes a bunch of things like
overviews of the services that oreck has
and um the the um data that we
store um and and sort of how to uh
a little bit about um how to get at that
stuff and and uh
what you can do with it um so as we've
mentioned at a couple of previous
uh workshops um we're on the lookout for
uh a bit of head count related to
systems engine systems and network
engineering
we were looking for somebody to sort of
be an on-call
person on site where in in fremont where
the bulk of our
systems and network is
now that the sort of pandemic travel
restrictions are look like they're
probably coming to an end in the next
few few months um
we're finding that to be a little less
urgent although we would like to still
have somebody
um that we can go to for uh for
emergency type work
um so that we're not constantly bugging
uh volunteers in the area
but we're also still looking for
somebody to do
uh some specific short-term network
engineering work um throughout around
cleaning up the configs
on our fremont and ottawa routers
but we're also looking to replace those
routers
um this year and just to sort of um
get some of the time-consuming stuff off
my plate we're we're looking for
somebody who can help out with the
um taking our requirements and and
budget information and
and you know convert that into some not
only some procurement
suggestions but also to take care of the
initial implementation and conversion of
the
existing configs over um over to
a new platform um
so there's more information about that
stuff on our works careers page
and you can also talk to me or keith um
about that um so
uh in terms of new systems and systems
and
networking work that's gone on um we
have i've been working on some new dns
infrastructure
um orc uh i made the joke in the written
report that orc really uh has been
you know the the absolute epitome of the
english adage
about uh the cobbler's children having
no shoes
our own dns infrastructure has been
really falling behind
um for a long time we've we've basically
been running
um shell scripts that were written um
many years ago
in order to do all of our zone signing
and um and
no key management whatsoever so um i've
got a new
uh hidden master in place there which we
um have started migrating zones over to
uh the first one to go on that
though was uh the zone for dnsbiz.net
which we finally
migrated authority for from sandy
national labs over to oarc
that was sort of in response to some
issues we had trying to do some
migration on dna or
some maintenance on the dns vis site uh
a few months ago
where we found it was it was really
difficult to make short-term changes to
the zone
um uh in order to do things like
redirect the website to a
a maintenance page that sort of thing so
um
so we got that zone moved over it was
the first one to be imported into the
new
uh dns server uh and i'm beginning to
migrate orrick's other zones over to it
um and uh the big thing that's gonna
come out of this once it's done is i'm
finally gonna be able to do
um algorithm roles for uh for oar zones
to get off of the uh
the old algorithms that we're using um
the uh we also have obviously we have a
new bit of infrastructure for doing um
server installs um so this is something
i was already kind of looking at
for the ceph storage cluster which is uh
coming up
later in the presentation um but
um we had an issue which i'm also going
to talk about in just a moment with the
analysis servers um this year earlier
earlier this year um which kind of
brought this
made this a bit more urgent so
essentially what this is it's a it's a
tool that's very similar to older things
like kickstart and jumpstart
for for doing um sort of rules-based
uh installation of os's on
systems um using you know tftp and
and things like that in order to uh to
get an installer and kernels running and
stuff
but it um uh it's really neat in that it
allows us to sort of
define classes of things that can be
combined in different ways in order to
set
in order to create a rule set for any
given server
so i can define classes that relate to
the different types of hardware we have
and the different types of services that
are provided and
sort of the combination of those of
those two
types of classes produce a rule set for
for the given server for how to divide
up the disks and
what things need to be installed
initially and and that sort of thing
um so we have this up and running which
is which is now going to be
going to make things a lot easier for
when we need to do server replacements
and
and large uh significant upgrades to
operating systems and that sort of thing
that
that sort of can't easily be done just
through a normal upgrade process
um so the analysis server thing which i
mentioned um
the they've been due for an os update
for a really long time
but it's been really hard to get time to
do that
um partly because they're pretty much
constantly in use
but also that hardware is aging and it's
making it very difficult to use sort of
the more standard os
install techniques particularly remotely
in order to get os's on them so the
very old java-based um remote console
um which has always which has been a
problem for the last couple of years
because the plug-ins that it depend on
have been
deprecated in web browsers for a very
long time um
but we've even started running into new
problems lately because
believe it or not they are so old that
the standards for transmitting keyboard
keystrokes across that kind of
connection had changed
and so even just getting through the os
installer was really hard
and even impossible in a couple of
places we're also running into problems
where current os's no longer have
um the drivers necessary to run things
like the old network cards on those
machines
um so having this fai fully automated
installer up and running in order to
do this was was really important and
really helpful
um so now that we have those machines on
newest new os's that can actually be
maintained
um we've instituted a new uh maintenance
window
on the first and third tuesday of every
month uh between
uh three and seven pm utc um
so that so if we need to reboot the
servers for any reason um
that's when we'll be doing it uh new
kernels that sort of thing
um and uh we won't be announcing those
reboots but
um but we will be using um these sort of
on system facilities to notify anyone
who's currently logged in that
the reboot will be coming
so we recently completed the 2021 day in
the life collection
um so uh when i put together the report
and
and these slides we were still receiving
the last sort of long tail
of uh uploads from some contributors i
think that's all done
now the last time i looked which was
earlier this week we had about 13
terabytes in from about 22
contributors so it's down a little bit
from last year
in terms of the volume of data although
we have one additional contributor
i sort of suspect that's just due to um
different usage patterns now that we're
sort of you know stabilized in
in the pandemic but
yeah it'll be interesting to see what
comes out of that once researchers get a
look
at that data uh so we'll start
post-processing for that soon
and and um we expect that the
data will be available for researchers
probably in about a month
um there's a bit of pre-work that needs
to be done before uh
before we can start that processing
uh something i've brought up a few times
in the last few workshops um
is the shared dsc platform for a long
time marc has been collecting dsc data
from members and
um and putting it up in a way and sort
of a shared
dsc viewer so that people could sort of
compare
dns traffic among members
but with the new our portal that we put
in place um
about a year and a half ago now i guess
a little more than a year and a half ago
um there hasn't actually been a way to
view that data and we've asked for
feedback from members a few times about
what we should do with that and haven't
really heard anything so um
we are planning now to to discontinue
collecting that data
uh ripencc is now last member um other
than orc to be contributing data to it
uh so we'll be in touch about uh about
shutting that down
uh sometime soon i think
um as i mentioned um uh
the our orcs routers um we
uh the rotors that oreck is using are
now uh beyond
uh end of support um it's it's quite old
hardware that we've got
um the very last os update to ever be
released for this
platform uh came out at the end of the
year and uh and it has been applied
um this unfortunately didn't fix an
ongoing routing issue we've been having
in fremont where we seem to be
randomly losing individual v6 routes
um so we're really going to be relying
on on getting new
routing platform in there in order to in
order to fix that up
we are also planning on expanding uh her
um network infrastructure a bit um
uh namely we've we've had an offer for a
very reasonably priced
second transit connection which we would
like to bring up but uh but of course we
need
we need new writing hardware to to
manage that um
so i'm out of time here so a very quick
um rundown on um our new cef storage
cluster
um there's um the original plan for this
uh was documented at or 31.
um so there's the the report there that
uh that talks about sort of the
justification and the issues we were
having
and um and the ideas i had at the time
about
how moving to a clustered storage uh
infrastructure would help us
um so we're sort of in the last stages
of that now
um we it took us a long time to deal
with
with um getting funding and getting the
hardware ordered and actually delivered
but the
final hardware actually showed up in
very late november um
we had a contractor on site who
dealt with uh racking and cabling the
bulk of that
unfortunately our fiber switches for the
10 gig
cluster network didn't show up until
after
that work was complete so we did finally
get them
racked up in q1 thanks to the help of
the uh
the remote hands um in the knock at the
data center
um cabling for that we'll we're going to
do uh
due pretty soon um and we're expecting
um
to basically have this in production by
the end of q2 so
um that should be really nice to have
it'll
improve life for a lot of people uh who
are doing work on our analysis servers
um so um questions for anyone
so i'm not hearing anything from keith
any questions sorry
there don't seem to be any questions and
no raised hands either
so over to you keith all right thanks
very much
okay so last presentation of the day
um just want to give you a brief off day
of what we've been up to
since work 34 um
in the past three months or so um i
commend you to the written reports apart
from
being not being delivered by half awake
people
um you'll find a lot of detail in matt's
and jerry's report and
um sort of general overview in my
written report these are all accessible
from indico
um so uh if you've got any you want to
read it
in time and digest it and ask us any
questions we'll be happy to do that
so uh president's quarterly report on
where we're at with the work what have
you
been doing while the world has been
twiddling its thumbs in pandemic mode um
or 35 was very well attended um
sorry 30 yep 34 i should say sorry about
that
last workshop was very well attended 180
attendees
um so that was great it was really good
to get that level of engagement
um as matt said we completed the digital
collect collection pretty much um still
waiting for
on on a few more uploads but it looks
like a decent
update um software front major updates
to dns perform dns cap
not only did matt do major software
upgrades to the analysis servers but you
build maintenance automation which we
will use to complete new data store
installation and and
also make um a lot of our systems
management better
already talked i mean already mentioned
they checked my dns tester
improvements um and the other thing is
the 2020 was a tough year to get through
um in many ways but we actually finished
up in a very strong
position financially we got a lot of
good support from members
um donors grants um so i'm pleased to
say that that lets us do more things
going forward
um and you know i i also think that the
fact that we
kept things running and um the industry
kept the internet running and that we
were able to do some successful
online events through europe pandemic is
is is no short achievement and i'm very
proud of her staff and very
grateful to her community for letting us
do that
um about a year ago um we came up with a
strategy for here's how we're going to
cope with the pandemic
um and um the strategy is still pretty
much in place and and you know we'll be
there
until we come out the other side really
the main change is that
while we were figuring out how to run
our events for everyone stuck at home
a year ago now we're starting to think
about you know at some point there will
be physical events again
how do we get back to these how do we
run them in a hybrid fashion so
when some people can participate and
others cannot that everyone's there on
an equitable basis so that that's the
main thing that we're thinking about
is also the next step of the pandemic
strategy
um but yeah i mean going into this
workshop i kind of felt
you know we finally got the hang of this
thing this pandemic thing they're
running the fully online workshops i
think everything is is going really very
smoothly over the past couple of days
and that's because
a lot of work has gone in um to
preparing everything and
and running things to how we figured out
doing it
um and you know even though as a team
remote work from home
stuff was something that we've been
doing for a long time before we
all were forced to do it we still miss
everyone we really miss seeing you
and engaging with our community and
and everyone um i think that
we have gathered for posterity a couple
of um interesting
day in the life of the internet annual
data sets which should provide
interesting context on
all of this events over the past year or
more
um and the other thing is well
one thing i don't think we completely
got the hang of is taking care of
ourselves
um and uh yeah staying up to weird time
zones like this is perhaps not the best
way of doing that
um but it's a learning journey you know
i i think i think i think we all know
that it's it's
you know just the art team that has had
to learn that
um support has been strong thank you to
everybody who has contributed to org
both financially and materially and with
your time and moral support
uh and yeah jet lag without your miles
um the mirror idiosyncrasies of zoom
which still managed to catch all of us
out despite the amount of time that we
spent on it and
um and yeah yeah we kind of start fun
stuff like space penguins and
other mascots so um we're still signing
up new members
uh very pleased um since the last
worktop to sign up dutch telecom as a
bronze member one of the biggest
carriers in europe
um netsky arbor also is a bronze member
very pleased that godaddy have upgraded
their membership from bronze to gold
and kaido i've been able to upgrade from
supporter to blue level
um and like i said strong support nobody
who's a paying member has terminated
their membership or downgraded their
membership so that that's really awesome
we really appreciate that
um we did very well with grants last
year
the grants that are still running in
2021 are the ones we've mentioned
already so a big thank you to
missile open source support and the
comcast innovation
fund for making the dns perf doh work
possible
and to iron community grants program um
we've listed all of the grants that we
received and donations that we received
over the past couple of years
um at this grants page so you can see
there's good support there and i mean
you know if you're interested in
um funding us to do a specific work or
to make a donation we
would love that but um thank you to
everyone that supported us um
and i mentioned yesterday that um
there's a couple of people that we want
to show special appreciation for
and um for um schumann um we did that
yesterday
um i don't think george is out there um
but hopefully he will get the
the vibes um and um george served on the
art board for six years
uh between 2014 and 2020 and then for
the latter part of that is the other
chair
so um hopefully we cannot present him in
person but here is the award that we
sent him and here is his fine self
so um and we're in his time zone so i
said thank you george it was a pleasure
to work with you
um so um back to some more
administrative stuff
um i'm afraid the the the past year um
some people some businesses in the
service um
office-based business haven't done so
well others see it as
an opportunity for the future so um we
have this little office in indianapolis
because banks and
government agencies want us to have a
physical location um
and we may have some some of the old
paperwork that we still need to store
so i found a new location then from the
14th of may
um we'll be moving into that it does not
really have any material effect on how
you deal with the work um
we have a separate po box in california
if you need to send checks or invoices
to
that stays the same um really this is
just for for the record to let you know
if you see this address
um that you know you're not blindsided
by it
um the other thing as i mentioned we're
a strong financial position we have far
too much to do
um i really feel for jerry and matt with
all the stuff that they need to support
um so we're hiring um the way that we're
doing this is that we have a couple of
specific projects
um matt mentioned the um the network the
richard config cleanup project
and um we want to get the third phase
of the doh for dns per project
preferably finished off by somebody who
enjoys and um is as you know as good
good abilities with https um
so these are the two short-term projects
that are mentioned there
but we have budget for both of these
positions essentially duplicating jerry
and matt on a long-term basis as well
and um we're interested both in
applications for the long-term position
but you know
it's possible if people are the right
candidates for the short-term projects
we may engage them on a long-term basis
we also have two non-technical positions
to fill um membership coordinator
um so again um sue's role there
um beefing up that um and an
administrator
um somebody you can you can help with
with some of the more
routine paperwork and other
administrative tasks that
keep the organization working um all
these roles are remote work from home
basis
um you can find more background about
them there
and um that's where applications go so
if you know anybody that might be a good
candidate um you know please please
encourage them to apply
um the team has worked really hard
over the past year it's been challenging
um one of the things that we did last
year um
was we gave them some some down time you
know so you can
nobody's getting any vacation much at
the moment but at least
if we can all shut off at the same time
we can we can give everyone a break
so for next week we'll be doing a one a
one week shutdown i mean obviously all
the online services will continue to
operate
um i will be monitoring email and
voicemail just in case anything
emergency
comes up urgent requiring escalation um
but um if you can all grant us that time
off with our families and
and just to switch off a bit we
appreciate it i mean thank you for your
understanding of the sorry what
circumstances i've been working under
for the past year
um all the supporting patients is very
much appreciated
and i really appreciate the team i mean
everybody has
has stuck to it and um um you know done
some some tricky things and pitched in
for things that may not necessarily have
been their ideal choice
um and we're here and we're in a strong
position and we intend to
look after our precious team resource
and
and keep it functioning
so um next workshops i sincerely hope
the next time that we do a workshop
um that there will be at least some of
us meeting in person
we set the plan for the first nine
months of 2021 that we would not do any
physical workshops
um but um we
expect that probably over the summer
we'll do a short online event the
sort of format that we did for short
events last year maybe around august
um the plan for quarter four is the um
the agm we will be doing on a hybrid
basis
um ideally we do that in october and
i'll make it too late in the year
um and then all the good opportunities
for doing um
the um work 36 come up in november
for various reasons um a lot of
september and october is very difficult
to get space anywhere
um in november we may co-locate with
um nanook or uk or
ripe um possibly even itf just depending
on how it goes
um we're confident that by february next
year we will be able to to do a physical
meeting and we have a
deposit and conf confirmed booking in
austin texas to collocate with nanook in
february again
um anyway i mean we know that
what you want to do and what you're able
to do are not necessarily the same thing
so um in this survey for this event
there's a bunch of questions
about what you think you might be able
to do or what you might be able to do
what you want to do um so if you can
give us feedback even if you don't have
any feedback on on this event which we
would very much welcome
um we'd still really like to hear your
feedback on um
you know what what what the options are
for meeting
frequency duration online versus offline
and and then when we might
when we might make that transition
um so it just really falls on me to wrap
things up with the usual pleasure of
thanking everybody
i'd particularly like to thank various
zion and farsight security for being our
meeting sponsors this time
all of the old members and supporters
for supporting us through this all the
grant and donor funding that i already
mentioned
the program committee have been awesome
um we have a smooth meeting
um they spend a lot of time in
rehearsals and putting together the
program
so i you know i particularly like to
thank um
the program committee members that have
volunteered this time
um so jake
um pallavi willem um
manor for their um
session sharing and q a monitoring um
and also
um huayian as our guest timekeeper
um and um
mauricio who's been working hard with um
keeping the twitter feed and the social
media stuff running throughout
throughout the meeting
um and um
big thank you to all of our speakers um
who have um
you know they do this all their time
with their own time and they've been
doing this
like strange times of day this time
around it was great to see that we
got some some good um contributions from
the asia pacific region
of our members and speakers so thank you
all for that
um and um
just making sure i don't forget anybody
but um yeah i just like to thank matt
and dinesh for all the logistic work
that they have done
for this meeting and jerry and sue for
the uh the the support behind the scenes
and
and all the prep that they've been
engaged in as well
so um if you like workshops as an
opportunity to sponsor them
even when we're doing them online um or
maybe you would like to engage in
patronage for for all our workshops for
a year or just to donation there's this
various ways that you can do that
but again big thank you to everybody um
and with that um that is basically um
the end of what i have to say i'll be
happy to take some questions if my voice
holds out
um if not we will
as i say i hope that next time we will
see at least some of you in person
i can't see any questions submitted and
no one's raised everybody's gone to
sleep
there's no questions
[Music]
so any questions anyone now's the time
oh we have a raised hand so um
it's mark andrews and uh mark um you may
mute yourself
please go ahead yeah just uh
thank you um yeah
it's nice to nice to not being up in the
middle of the night
trying to have one of these meetings
yeah now we feel your pain thank you
thank you mark it's a pleasure
thank you uh we actually have one more
um hold on
and we have benno okay
ben oh please yeah not a question
just a word of appreciation oh as keith
presented
that's been a difficult year for all of
us but uh
i want to specifically address the
dinosaur
team uh you did a great job
and i think i can speak for the other
board members also we are very happy
how you managed to work through the year
and well achieved great results
a good online attendance of the
of the award meetings and also as a
board you also look
a little bit to the finances and indeed
we had a very good
healthy financial year so keith
dinesh matt jerry all the teams soon
thank you very much thank you bennett
thank you
pleasure thank you very much we do have
some more
so um let me have a look there's some
comments that came through and there's
so
there's another raised hand so i'll come
to that shortly uh there's uh comments
um all of them actually saying thank you
same from me great to be in daylight
hours so seems like we've done something
right here
for a section of the world um also davey
song says thanks for organizing the
online meeting especially
for asia people marco diaz thank you
guys great work
um and i'll go to ali reza saleh who
wants to talk so you may
talk and meet yourself ali rosa
yep i just want to say thank you i mean
that to everyone to out now and that's
good
and the dns or i'm having a great work
and
i just also have another question i'm
never i'm i'm original from
i'm originally from iran i just wanted
to know that is it anywhere is it any
possibilities that actually dns or can
support something that
on that dot ir or the con i'm on that
iran this is i'm that
most i'm the more like i'm that
administrative question
thank you yeah i thank thank you for
your kind words
i appreciate it and i also understand
the uh the challenges
i the short answer is i don't know um
you know
we all live in a geopolitical
environment that we would it would be
nice if everyone
was nicer to each other and we didn't
have to live with all the challenges but
but yeah you know we we can take that
discussion offline and we can
investigate it and
see what's possible
thank you thank you
um okay it doesn't seem that there are
any more they were all
comments rather than uh generally they
were all comments rather than
questions um but thank you everyone and
back to you keith
yeah no thanks daresh um and uh thank
you everyone for your kind words
and um i think that we will we will wrap
things up just just to remind everyone
we'll be closing the spatial chat room
is at the same time as his own room so
i wish you all a good weekend and we
will
see you online
thanks
[Music]
uh