alright let's get started so welcome
it's my pleasure to introduce miss
Morgan princey
she's a solution engineer at the census
focused on identifying trends and
tracking tracking threat groups and
vulnerabilities using census data her
career in cyber security began in botnet
detection where she worked to protect
websites api's and mobile apps from both
by detecting anomalies in web traffic
and interrogating user identification
system morgan holds a Bachelor of Arts
in economics urban studies from
University of Michigan Morgan is a 20-19
world IT Award winner for women in
security so remember if you want to ask
questions please press the push button
on the speaker so that your question
will be recorded thank you it's so nice
to be here wonderful introduction going
to talk a little bit just about some of
those security risks that we can
identify using internet wide scan data
and if you do have questions again you
can click the button and stop me at any
time we'll leave a little time at the
end as well ok so a little background
you know touched on it earlier with Dave
said but I live in the city of Detroit a
lot of my history has been in this space
or on pot detection I spent about five
years doing that at the web application
level while doing bat detection I was a
security analyst so just really digging
into a lot of web blog traffic trying to
isolate what is or is not a bot request
I worked for a lot of airline clients a
lot of classified listing clients that
were just getting scraped a lot or even
financial institutions who were subject
to credential stuffing attacks also like
most of my head space at that time was
around the web application layer but
then I joined a company called census
and that was founded by the
founders of zmapp which came out at the
University of Michigan will talk a
little bit about that but since joining
them a lot of my thinking processes been
around security problems that we can
sell there that can be solved at the
network layer and that's where you know
all the skimming happens okay so we can
talk about internet-wide scanning has
anybody here you showed in or census or
zoom I in the past okay good a handful
of people awesome
has anyone by chance deployed their own
instance of zmapp oh okay great you're
so you know wonderful probably a little
bit of a painful process but basically
what internet-wide scanning is is we are
scanning you know all of the ipv4
internet space and we collect that data
and we have a search engine you know
mostly commies have search engine on top
of it allowing researchers you know or
companies to use it for a variety of
different purposes so a quick history of
internet wide scanning you know in the
2000s really around 2002 researchers
realized hey Google's indexing a bunch
of these web pages and because what
they're indexing these web pages we can
start to search for security keywords
not just you know sims cheat codes or
something else that was popular in 2002
and as a result you could say hey I'm
searching for admin login portal and
what's going to show up is a bunch of
sites that might have had me log in
power all exposed so that kind of
started to popularize the idea of I can
look for security problems outside of my
own website and look more broadly at
kind of Internet as a whole 2004 shadows
server was founded by a group of
volunteers and they are kind of looking
to again enhance the overall security of
the Internet by popularizing internet
wide data and security instances they're
happening across a bunch of different
sites then in around 2009 comes a
company called show Dan they are great
they really kind of popularized a lot of
the IOT devices that are exposed on the
Internet
so popular you know it's like hey guess
what there's traffic lights that are
exposed to internet there's medical
devices that have x-rays on them exposed
to the Internet
and so big publishers like Forbes CNN it
kind of became in the spotlight as
people were saying oh my gosh we don't
know what is out there and then in 2012
zmapp was started at the University of
Michigan
so zmapp was developed by secured room
rich and really what that did is it took
scanning and Internet which some people
had been able to do but he was able to
do it in 45 minutes with this new
technology which is uber fast right it
allowed you to do that
and get that data available make them
much more available along with being
able to have most up-to-date and fresh
information and so zmapp turned into
census the founders join that team 2013
we see a few other companies projects
sonar zoom I fo a you know some Chinese
players that are coming into the space
as well and then around 2017 we've got
green noise coming in so gray noise is a
little bit different basically what
they're doing is saying hey we've got
these skinning companies that are
popular we need to make sure that
there's no spoofer in this space right
if you're allowing your website to be
hit by scanners you don't want somebody
that's like maliciously spoofing it and
so they do a good job of kind of phasing
out that nuance it's like a gen 2 almost
okay so what makes that special like why
is internet scanning as a whole
important really it's because it's it's
a pretty difficult problem to solve if
anyone's used and map in the past and
map is awesome but it's really difficult
to keep state you know it just doesn't
scale well and keeping state is very
challenging if you're using classic
method like connect the scans don't
really scale either right you're asking
the kernel to keep mini connections open
and that can get quite messy the other
thing is if you are trying to linearly
scan the internet you know just go to 0
dot 0 dot 0 dot 1 to 0 that's 0 dot 0
dot 2 you're going to get blocked very
quickly you're gonna run across the
company that has you know a net block in
that space and they're you're gonna say
what are you doing here you know and
that data becomes inconsistent and so
there's a lot of challenges that happen
and that's why it's wonderful we've got
a few different companies in the space
that can
provide that data and kind of push the
boundaries of what is able to be done so
that people can use it easily so that's
a little background on internet wide
skinny and today we'll talk about you
know some applications if using that
data a lot of this is available with
free accounts so if you you know haven't
don't have been caught on showdown or
census I encourage you to use it there's
a lot of cool stuff out there but we'll
talk about specifically threat hunting
vulnerability trends and using internal
scan data to understand attack surfaces
okay so threat hunting this is the face
that's in like most embraced I would say
by internet wide are they most embraced
internet wide scan data it's helpful
just being able to search for different
threat actors and monitor their behavior
over time as they you know tracking
their moves is something that
governments and different corporations
are honestly dedicating entire teams to
do so it's a bit of a Where's Waldo I
would say but in this instance Waldo or
I guess this is Walda is a bit of a
shapeshifter
who's moving you know through a rapidly
changing internet so it becomes a really
a much more complicated problem it's not
the 80s with Where's Waldo books anymore
but if you're looking to how do you
start with threat hunting generally you
know internet wide scan data is massive
if you're looking for the entire ipv4
space just contextually that's about
seven point four terabytes worth of data
so you really need a game plan of like
what are you looking for what are the
things that will help you identify
different threat groups that you might
be tracking and so generally how people
do this is they look for IO C's or
indicators of compromise that you can
cue off and start to like find those
different attack groups for Waldo those
io C's would be you know the striped
shirt glasses pom hat a little smile on
his face so that's kind of what you're
trying to look for when you're looking
for a threat groups you know this is one
of the easiest ways we'll talk kind of
about looking for an IOC of just the
phrase hacked by so some groups are you
know will advertise themselves and say
hey if we hack into your inner your webs
we're going to take over the title of
the page and say we're hacked by this
group and they kind of have this
publicity stunt it's almost like the
tagging of the cyber world and it's
pretty pretty fun to track I enjoy it
and you know this happens all the time
if you've been reading the news recently
you probably saw that this happened a
few weeks ago to when the US government
sites was hacked by a group that
self-identified as the Iran cyber
security group hackers and so you can
see right in the page title there's the
phrase hacked by and this is something
that we grab in parsing our internet
scans so it is easy as saying hey I want
to search for this phrase and voila we
get some details on it so we can do that
if we pull this up here maybe alright
cool so this is the sense this search
interface you can see here I just put in
we're gonna look in port 84 you know in
this HTTP protocol and we're gonna do a
quick regex here for just hacked by or
port 443 a similar thing looking for
that again phrase hacked by and you can
see right now we're getting 82 results
and you know there's a variety different
things this is both has you know
database exposed we've got a variety of
instances where this you know this
particular group looks like they've
recently done some activity and so all
this data is within the past seven days
you know things that were live on the
internet at least in the past seven days
maybe sooner so you can start to dig
into this and you know when you're on
here as well if you click this open you
can get a bunch of data about what was
happening on the server at that time so
it's pretty fun well let's get back to a
second here and see if I can figure out
how to get back to the presentation
yeah cool
and I should also say that this is
something that you can do with an API as
well so both should and scientists know
most of these major internet scanning
companies have an API that allow you to
do very similar searches and you know
pull that data down into different
formats if you're looking for that so a
little bit of research that we've done
on this you know this was later in
December we were looking at some of
those groups and you know who is who's
that group that's like announcing
themselves as as hacked by from like an
anthropological standpoint I find this
to be quite interesting there's groups
like telling us a little bit about
themselves there's all sorts of naming
conventions for these groups oftentimes
if you actually go to the websites which
I wouldn't recommend unless you're doing
that in a sandbox
there's generally a bunch of like a see
art and things of that nature too so you
know there's a bunch of artifacts around
who these groups are and what they're
trying to accomplish you can see here
there are some groups that are just
announcing hey we attacked you by this
CV and you probably should fix this you
know this has been around since 2016 by
the way that is the dirty cow exploit
which was you know in a issue that
impacted the Linux kernel but you know
there's also groups here this led us to
Tim it's pretty interesting we see him
like working alongside someone and
almost all of his attacks so it's like
hacked by him as well as somebody else
maybe you know almost like a co hacker
in a way so there's a lot of different
things that can you know be tracked in
terms of what's going on more socially
with these different groups also say
like one of my colleagues uses this and
he does a cool program where he will
pipe these IPS into aqua tone and then
do a flyover screenshot tool to be able
to say what are the actual screenshots
of the websites look like and then uses
that with some image processing so cool
things that you can start to do and
that's you know some of the more basic
ones but you can also start to track
those who maybe don't want to be found
and those get a little bit more
complicated I would say
that's really my and so to track some of
these groups that don't want to be found
generally like I will go to a lot of
groups that are doing this
professionally
go to mitre and they attack attack
framework and they'll look for some of
those big weight wigs that the
government's are tracking and so this is
just a list from Leiter in terms of some
of their groups that they're following
they generally have a bunch of IOC s on
the site and they also have software and
things like that that they are most
commonly associated with different
malware samples things of that nature
there's a lot of them so let's say we
wanted to track dry decks so actually
Drydocks us prosecutors just recently
have brought down and brought charges
against somebody behind the dried wrecks
command and control operator this was a
form of malware that was specializing in
stealing bank credentials vias macros
that would go through Microsoft Word and
as they actually are prosecuting for
them they accused this man I've also
kind of being behind a group called evil
Corp and in general they are you know
saying that it's been a hundred million
in stolen revenue since 2015 so if we
want to start tracking dry decks you
know we need to start searching for some
different IOC s and so what you can look
for is bad SSL as a tool that will start
to give different SSL certificates and
you can actually filter some of these by
different attack groups okay so dry
decks so we've got a bunch of different
as I sell surged so we can see that
these are a little bit old 2018 but
we've got a sha-1 listing here so I
grabbed these and put them into Google
bigquery which is a way that we actually
all of census data goes into Google
bigquery that we can start to query this
but because we've got a long list of
them I'll put it in here and say hey we
want to understand what are some of the
certificate attributes that these
attackers are using so when census scans
the internet and when a lot of these
grouping are scanning you also do
she lost handshakes to grab a
certificate and so we've got a bunch of
this data I'm going back to about 2015
now so when I run this I'm gonna start
to pull some of this data around the
issue or the subject some of the
validity links things of that nature and
we can see what we find let that run for
a moment and also kind of contextualize
this that I did check and none of these
certificates are currently live so these
were ones that had previously been
associated with that group if it was as
easy as if they're live on a host we
could start to profile that host and say
what are attributes about this host can
we find related hosts but because
they're not live we want to go through
and start to find okay can we find other
certificates that they might be using to
then go and see if those are live
anywhere all right so we've got a bunch
of data back and then generally what you
want to do or what we recommend here is
starting to see some commonalities and
can we find anything that stands out in
terms of maybe this is an attribute that
belongs to this this group in terms of
how they set up their configurations so
a few things looking at this we do see
on this subject Dan if you look kind of
and we scroll over and I'm noticing that
these start to match the subject Dan and
the issue or Dan are matching in all of
these in all of these certificates which
is fairly interesting right like maybe
that's something we can cue off of
another thing looking at this all of
these validity lengths seem to be
somewhat common right there we've see
all the same here just in that for a
scroll we've got 99 things to look
through but they look somewhat similar
here I've got some fingerprints and the
other thing is they all have one name on
the certificate so you know one name
might be also something we can look at
and so generally what we can start to do
is like a really basic attribution
analysis and this is a place where you
know I've worked with a lot of groups
that use census data and companies that
you know buy this data from us and
they're doing very rudimentary analysis
with some spreadsheets just to try to
see what's going on there's I think lots
of room for this to be more
statistically sound but one of this you
know this is a really basic example of
saying all right let's look at instances
where we see certificates where the
subject Deanna's issued the exact same
as the issuer Dion and inside of this
small test group of 100 certificates
that were associated with dry decks we
see a hundred percent of them have that
attribute now looking at all of the
certs that we see in census which is
every cert that was issued or was live
on a host since 2015 we see about 4.5
percent of those certificates have that
attribute the other things that we were
looking at was one name on a certificate
again a hundred percent of these these
test certificates had that case we've
got a much larger number though where
that's the case of all of the other
certificates the validity length seems
to be quite isolating though and then
when you aggregate all three of these
features together we start to see that
hey this is something that ninety nine
point six percent of all of the
certificates have but if you look at all
of the certificates we've reduced that
down to you know under one percent of
all the certificates for us to then
further look into and so what your
ultimate looking for when you're doing
threat hunting like this is you want
something that's both accurate and
precise right I would say that kind of
based on this analysis we start to get
something that's somewhat precise we're
able to say hey it looks like these
features are fairly unique to these
certificates that are associated at
Drive X we don't know yet if they're
accurate we don't know if that's when we
look at those if they're actually going
to correspond to that attacker
infrastructure or not to do that as hard
right now we need to look at those
certificates and look at the hosts and
we probably need to set up a honeypot to
see if we're seeing requests come in
from those hosts and see what kind of
behavior those hosts are exhibiting to
see if they would actually belong to
this attacker group but generally you
know companies
doing this or governments that are doing
this this is a little bit along the
lines of how they're using this data is
trying to find instances that we can
start to track and then say hey are the
things that we can find on the internet
that might actually belong to them and
what do we do if we find them any
questions on that
yeah behavior changes in those hosts
after the big data the big data
collection has been targeting those
specific key factors have you seen
changes in those factors over time so
you're asking if once somebody maybe has
been impacted by a threat group do we
see changes no I was wondering if the
threat group specifically changes their
methods in for example setting the
issuer and everything else as the same
or the lengths and everything like that
they do they've change it all the time
and so it is almost and that's it's a
frustrating game right like you're
waking up every morning and fighting the
same fight again where we see something
that's changed and then you have to
start cueing off of UI OCS and it can be
hard to find you know sometimes groups
just go completely dark and it's
probably because they've changed a bunch
of stuff and you have to start figuring
out okay what's next what are the next
little you know beacons that we can
understand from alienvault maybe or some
other types of Intel sources that are
telling you about these groups very
challenging and that's where maybe you
know it there's I think opportunity
machine learning at some point
potentially to start to be a little more
sophisticated with the modeling I would
say right now a lot of the customers we
see are doing aren't doing all of that
any other questions
oh can you click the mic button push
okay sorry
do you work you get information from the
block listing services or or do you work
with them around what sites are being
blacklisted any would I piece yes our
domain names like spam house oh yes so
us as a scanning company we don't get a
lot of that detail but as we are people
that are buying our data and using our
data oftentimes we'll use that
potentially as IOC right and so if there
are names that are coming in and have
been blacklisted because they've been
associated with phishing attempts or
have been associated with different
scams that is oftentimes something you
can start to queue off of and you can
find those both in the names on the
certificates is one way to link that
there's also certain times where if you
get an email come in and you're security
on the security team coming from that
domain you know you can start to find in
the IP associated with that domain and
then track that I that IP on census or
another scanning platform great question
also when you see the you're thinking
about how this is going to be applied
and more automated in the future do you
see that coming from private or more
government at this point for tracking
these threats a little bit of both so
generally we see if you're a very large
company sometimes they will have threat
hunting teams and they find this to be
useful because they generally are like
hey it's a better investment for us to
have teams tracking this so that if we
start to have you know those handful of
certificates that we found there they
might start to say ok if we see in the
IP that has that certificate we're going
to isolate that request and do something
different before they can come into our
system so they have some incentive I
think from a hey we're protecting our
systems the government is doing that at
a much larger scale
as they are tracking even nation states
or you know some of those huge groups
and trying to do prosecution across them
so hard to say where that will come from
and maybe it is happening in some ways
too like some of what we have in terms
of visibility is is limited to alright
so now we can talk a little bit about
vulnerability trends this graphic I love
it so we recently subscribed like a fire
hose of CVEs that are coming in about
7.5 because we do some research around
that with our data and it is just
overwhelming the number of Seavey's that
come in and so we sympathize a lot with
and people in security spaces where you
just can be flooded with vulnerabilities
we'll talk about a few of them this was
one the exome vulnerability that came
out in about September or so and so XM
is a male Authenticator mail server and
this CVE was a 10 in the CBS s score and
allowed for unauthenticated route code
execution with root access to the email
server which are all very scary bad
words in the security world and you can
see here this is a little graphic by
project sonar and it's just like
overwhelmingly most of these went
unpatched and we're just almost all of
the versions were affected by this
so using internet wide scan data you can
start to see what are these trends and
different vulnerabilities that that are
released and so this is looking for this
exome it's everything that was version
four point nine two and below which at
the time that was the most up-to-date
version so it was a really a very large
CVE impact and so we're looking here at
you know a few different protocols we've
got one other one included in this
search yeah we're looking at four six
five and five 87 but you can see here
this is returning around two million
still IPS have XM running
you know are more than likely affected
by by this very severe CBE and so this
is something that you know tracking
these over time seeing some of the
adoption rates that patchi's has a lot
of you know interesting data that people
can be can be looking into and then
similarly this was one for a SharePoint
so this allowed people come to take like
complete control access of their
SharePoint servers which impacted a lot
of their microsoft products also quite
scary and you can see this when we did
some research about just over time what
some of the patch cycles were it's much
smaller in scale but it was you know it
just is hard to couch some of this stuff
and it's harder to see what um you know
what might need to be patched can be can
be challenging so we see that trend a
little bit here and again if you click
on this sorry maybe not yeah well we can
even just do this right putting this
SharePoint here this allows you to do
just the random you know so strong text
search likely what we want this to be as
a specific version number but you can
see you know this takes in a lot of
different a lot of different versions
and allows you to see some of those
those trends over time so in terms of
security research this can be helpful
just to kind of get some contextualized
information about what is actually live
on on the internet right now all right
so one thing that you can do - and
generally when we're running these
searches around owner abilities a lot of
times people want to know okay cool
that's great to understand around
internet white trends but also what are
things that are I'm impacted and that's
a I think that's a big question and some
are aware the internet wide scan space
is kind of going is to say great you
have all this internet or all this data
about the internet show me everything
that impacts me and so that's very you
know it's a challenging problem to self
because now not only are you having to
reliably scan the internet but you also
have to start to attribute things to a
particular company or to an organization
and that becomes a question of like how
do we reliably say that we think this
host that belongs to you is really
similar in ways to this other host and
maybe that's something that indicates
ownership so on a basic level if we go
back to let's look back at this
vulnerability that we had up for Exim
cool so it's in some ways it's as easy
it's just you can add a thing if we want
to say
Purdue so I haven't done the searches is
a little live demo but you can start to
just added during the main names of that
right and then you start to get a few
things back and that allows like a basic
very simple look into saying hey we can
find you know some things here that
allows more actionable insights around
those CVEs and say alright this is
something that now as an institution you
can take action on but there's other
things too right like if we go back and
you were trying to profile an entire
attack surface and that's like a phrase
that is just done meaning like what is
exposed to the internet and what is
something that you can start to you know
could be an impact of people getting
into your system you know there's lots
of ways you can do this and so if we
just go back and we say hey per dude edu
this is maybe the most rudimentary way
to do so we get 217 results
but we see over here that there's some a
s numbers that are also indicating per
day language that we can pretty
confidently say that's something that
would be only by this five for you so we
can say autonomous system let's get that
number ten so you can run some really
complex gnarly queries up in here it
does support regex
and you can do a lot of anding and Orion
so if you're playing around with us and
again you can you can create free
accounts and experiment don't be shy to
to add a bunch of stuff up here all
right so let's add these two ends and
see what we can you can fill out okay so
now we're getting in about four thousand
more assets the other thing you can look
into is starting to fill in this space
using certificate data so this
organization is equal to Purdue maybe
this is something we want to include as
a keyword and say show me everything
where we've got oh we call to Purdue
University come up okay we grew a little
bit there as well so now you know this
is this is fairly simple but you start
to see hey this is these are a bunch of
data about one institution and if you go
down the side here you know you can
start to see all we've got a bunch of
different protocols that are running
there might be things like printers if
there's you know all sorts of stuff that
can be exposed to the internet that
would be maybe surprising it maybe not
surprising depending on how much you
play around with Internet data but
there's a lot of things that you can
start to dig into and you know this is I
think again moving a little bit more
into some of these different
applications internet-wide scanning is a
fairly a fairly new concept there's lots
of different ways you can start to use
this but understanding hey what are the
things that I own and maybe I'm not
tracking explicitly is is one of those
one of those newer applications of the
data you can also start to say hey were
them what's them
I look like right we've got Purdue
infrastructure running all over the US
that's kind of fun
I can pull up some metadata reports as
well hey Morgan yeah what sorts of
things so what sorts of things would
these organizations be concerned about
like on I keep you kind of showed some
of the ports and protocols and stuff
like that but what would they define
concerning right and so let's look back
at the results of that generally you
know we you would expect fingers running
nine port 80 four four three forgotten
HTTP and HTTPS that's very expected most
people are not going to blink an eye at
that it's like hey these are web servers
that are running a lot of people in
order to admit idli all educational
institutions have a very colorful attack
surface I would say so but generally
things like if you got a telnet instance
exposed like that's pretty scary and a
lot of people don't wouldn't want that
and want that to be you know internal or
just taken offline in general if you've
got you know a database that's also
quite scary somebody can quickly
probably authenticate into that database
and then you've got a bunch of data that
could be PII exposed and that you know
could cause lots of implications some of
these like embedded devices or cameras
you know generally you don't want to
take any any risks with that kind of
stuff in terms of personal information
so a lot of times we would advise
companies say you know you have your own
rules you kind of have your own
understanding of what is okay within
your security posture but anything
outside of you know HTTP HTTPS you know
strongly secured SSH potentially all
that's doing the things you'd want to
start you know anything except those
would be some things you want to look
into and I guess one other thought on
that too is as company they're moving to
the cloud and both cloud and remote
workforces pose some other challenges to
you so cloud space if you are
putting assets into cloud there's
oftentimes a lack of visibility there of
what's going on and so that is another
indicator of like hey maybe we have many
cloud environments that exist is that
what we would expect maybe yes maybe no
any other questions
all right well I would recommend you
know there's lots of different
applications for this again if you guys
I would say feel free to create free
accounts if you're doing any type of
research on we know with this data as
well I would record we offer some
research access to our data which gives
you your we skin for more than a
thousand ports you get full access to it
if you're doing research so if you you
know send us a note on census data i/o
there's kind of a research at email so
let us know and if you're doing I think
we'll also reach out to us we love to
read some of the papers and things of
that nature
alright no other questions now that you
at that point do you also have like
tutorial material available to walk
someone through once they have this
account to have things that they can do
we have a little bit of that so we send
out I think if you sign up for a free
account you get a few drip marketing
emails that suggest some queries that
you can start to run we also have some
training that's in process especially as
corporations are buying the data more so
we have some of that but we are working
on doing some videos that are you know
available for the for the public great
question
and we also have you know a support team
myself included that is willing to
answer any questions
any other questions all right
[Applause]
you