all right it's my honor to introduce dr.
Ibrahim Bigley so dr. bubay is the elder
family endowed chair of computer science
and a cyber security at the Tala Tala
College of Engineering Department of
computer and electrical engineering and
computer science at the University of
New Haven specializing in cyber security
and forensics he's also a European
Alliance for innovation fellow and a CT
4140 he serves as the assistant dean and
is the founder of the University of New
Haven's cyber forensics research and
education group the RP is also the
former editor-in-chief of the Journal of
digital forensics security and law he
received his Bachelor of Science Master
of Science and a PhD all from Purdue
University where he worked as a
researcher in series he's the program
lead on the center of academic
excellence in cyber operations
designated by the National Security
Agency one of the only 12 programs
nationally with the prestigious
designation and is also the principal
invest investigator for the cyber corpse
scholarship for service program at the
University the RB is also the co-founder
of the x-reality Safety Initiative so
with further adieu let's welcome Harvey
can you hear me now excellent so I just
want to say I think I think maybe there
was a it was miss written I think it's
21 universities that have the CAE CEO
because the ones that have it might not
be happy if they see that in the video
like oh there's 21 thank you for for
inviting me thank you for having me come
out here I I gave a talk here when I was
a PhD student in 2008 if you want to
look that up of course somebody's
already looking things up as they're you
know coding or doing whatever they're
doing on the laptop there but I have
more interesting things to say if you
just want to give me a second and you
know I unlike other people I actually
got all my degrees here a lot of people
say that you get inbreeding if you stay
at the same University yeah I actually
totally enjoyed being at Purdue I think
it's a great school and you should all
be very happy that you made it here and
that you're part of the ecosystem of the
various colleges and their cybersecurity
initiatives so I just want to thank
everyone and I want to thank you know
gene Spafford who's done a wonderful job
bringing serious to the way it's at
today from back in the day and without
the support I've had here I wouldn't be
where I'm at so um today we're going to
be talking about immersive virtual
insanity is what I call it and it's
really about us exploring security
problems in virtual reality is anyone in
here ever used VR put your hand up if
you played with VR Brianne if you played
with a new oculus quest you wish nobody
well you should it's pretty awesome so
I'm sure I'm assuming some of you might
have played with a vibe right vive the
vibe is pretty cool but there's a lot of
wires you need a computer and all that
stuff but with oculus quest for example
you don't need anything I'll talk about
that in a second but I think I would not
be doing justice to the two - some of
the things I'm going to talk about today
without my students these are all the
students that have helped me work on
this project and actually you know it's
really their their work that I'm
presenting so it's very important to
give them the credit that they deserve
and today I'm only presenting about VR
but if you go online you see some of our
research you know it spans all the way
from drawings to VR to blockchain
distributed storage child sexual abuse
material investigations and so on and so
forth but as any any academic would have
to this work was funded by the NSF under
this grant number so it's very important
for me to say that and it's also
important for me to say that my views do
not represent them as its as the claim
is presented here so yvr YVR security
YVR forensics look at the numbers the
market is expected to surpass 40 billion
by 2020 the systems are becoming more
mobile and would like the oculus quest
it's at $399 there's many untapped use
cases all the way from you from you know
it being used in the medical world to it
being used in social activities or
anything else that you might think of
and so far most of the research in this
domain has mostly focused on what on
developing experiences developing games
developing rehabilitation situations in
virtual reality and there's not really
enough research on looking at where we
stand in the cybersecurity domain in
virtual reality systems that are
actually that actually exist
so not theoretical research per se but
Applied Research you go and you buy this
piece of equipment is there anything in
there that we should be focusing our
attention to in terms of its potential
security vulnerabilities and if
something does happen can we potentially
get the evidence from it so the
interesting thing about VR is there are
some very interesting use cases right
this is a very bad use case right and it
also opens up research questions that
span the computer science domain so for
example if somebody was sexually
assaulted in virtual reality and they
were not physically sexually assaulted
so to speak what kind of things have to
happen legally there
in order for you to show in a sexual
assault case right so the interesting
there the interesting thing there is the
fact that the person immersed in the
virtual environment gets the same exact
feeling pretty much that they would in
the same in the physical world so you're
really affecting that person psychology
in the virtual world and it will have
impact on them so therefore it's a
problem but yet again there's another VR
sort of use case that would be very
helpful here because VR has also been
used in situational awareness to put
people in situations that are where
sexual assault might be happening around
them for them to explain to them how to
deal with the situation so there's some
positive use cases now there's some
negative use cases so what I'm gonna be
talking about today is going through the
research program and some of the things
that we did so the first thing is let's
focus on exploring the cyber forensics
of VR systems meaning that can we
extract any evidence from these VR
systems should something bad happen and
then let's look at the underlying tech
but focus our energy on immersive VR
because most people when they know VR
they think of like a mobile device that
they just put on their head and that's
it right but no VR is immersive you
could walk in their environment you can
move your hands in the environment and
that gets really interesting in our you
know our purpose was to go and develop
educational modules novel attacks tools
and other things in VR but ultimately is
to create some impact around this domain
that would be useful estimated twenty
seven billion dollar market worldwide
and that is expected to catapult over
two hundred and nine building billion
rather in just three years
let's go into the tech world where we're
finding everything from medical to
military to training applications to
home use for entertainment it's all
exploding while getting immersed in a
virtual world is kind of cool is it the
next target for
Sears WMUR 2 News mark Roper with what
it could mean for your family dr.
ibrahim beguiling gets to play in the
world of virtual reality as part of his
job but he suspects the trendy tech
isn't just the next frontier for gamers
virtual reality is absolutely
susceptible to hackers at this point in
time the doctor and his cyber forensic
research team at the University of New
Haven say they've uncovered
vulnerabilities in popular virtual
reality systems they believe the hacking
will be different from anything we've
seen before I think what's really
interesting in VR is for the first time
we have a technology that takes over
your complete sight and your complete
vision and now also slowly taking over
your hearing in the lab researchers were
able to take over systems and manipulate
users physically graduate research or
Peter Casey says one way is in something
called a chaperone attack a chaperone
attack is when we either disable or
expand the safety boundaries that are
keeping the player from moving into any
obstacles in the room in a human
joystick attack they were able to
gradually move people across a room
without them realizing it Casey says it
has to do with a false sense of reality
whoa this along with removal of
boundaries can be a concern you know you
could walk someone down the stairs the
group also could turn on cameras and can
insert or overlay images right into the
middle of an experience what that is is
effectively a ransomware attack where
they can no longer use the device as its
intended researchers say there are very
so as you can see our work has resulted
in us showing that there are actually
new kinds of attacks that could
potentially happen in VR and while while
maybe the technology in terms of the
attack vector might be still the same as
any other technology the impact is
different and we'll talk about this in a
second so you look at the different
threat categories when it comes to VR
and these are the sort of high level
threat categories that we focus on we
focus on input protection we focus on
data protection and we focus on output
protection we also focus on user inter
action protection when people are
interacting with each other and how you
can make that the data safe between them
as well as the protection of the device
itself so there's multiple layers of
protection that need to be involved
whenever you're dealing with virtual
reality systems and the current state is
that Security's not that great in these
systems and it needs to be improved so
what is most of the work that's been
done in this space what is it what is it
about well most of it has been things
that focus on you know items like input
sanitization right what do you mean but
what do I mean by that well if you look
at number two there you see complete
sanitization so if you have an input
from the external world that's going
into for example your XR vision goggles
or something like that you can just take
that out and remove it then the user
wouldn't have to see it if I'm looking
at you as a person and I can tell who
you are what if we change the person in
front of us to a skeleton right that way
I don't get to see very important
attributes about the individual that can
make me identify them just as an example
there's also been work that's been done
on data aggregation and output
protection and obviously VR exposure
therapy right if you're scared of
spiders
let's put you in a VR environment and
put you in you know give you some big
spiders that are gonna crawl around use
anyone done that now all right it's
pretty cool you should try all right but
until we started doing this work there
was no formal security analysis and
forensics of consumer-grade VR systems
and that's really where our contribution
kicks in but before I take you on that
journey let's talk about a couple of
like let's let's talk about some of the
our jargon some of you might know this
some of you might not any gamers in the
room yeah so you know what steam is all
right so steam is the primary
application at least at that time where
you would download VR games and use your
HTC vive with and all sorts of things so
you can think of it as the Play Store
for VR but at the same time it also acts
as an intermediary between the VR and
the equipment that you're using
okay and that's where steamvr comes in
so you have trackers at least with the
older systems and we'll talk about the
newer systems in a second where they're
mounted somewhere and they can track
your movement and you have the system on
it's connected to a computer that has
some sort of GPU capability that would
enable you to use the system's in the
first place
right so trackers light houses head
mounted displays and chaperone is the
fake wall you create in VR so you don't
hit the real wall if I had the headset
on me right now and I'm approaching a
wall I don't want to hit it right and
that's really the whole point of
creating that fake wall so you can see
it in VR so you don't hit the real wall
hello good morning how's it going man
doing well all right so that's your job
as an educator is to get people focused
right make sure that what you're saying
is kind of interesting now you have
inside-out tracking you don't need to
hang anything up you don't need to do
anything you just put the system on and
you go that's it right so ready player
now is real almost right and more
importantly the oculus quest was
released and about maybe a month or two
ago now they do hand tracking right so
they can do real-time hand tracking and
not just the you know the the joystick
tracking per se that you have in your
hands they can track your hands they can
track your fingers so now you can live a
VR experience where things are more
trackable right so from a privacy
perspective think about all the data
that's being collected as this is
happening so one of the first things we
wanted to do is to see what kind of
artifacts we can pull from these systems
in order to show for example if
something had happened and why it
happened so maybe a crime was committed
all right maybe you walked into a room
and I always tell people this if you
don't like your husband buy him a VR
system put them in VR and now they can't
see anything just go and whack them on
the back of the head right
so from me as a person as a
cybersecurity person I'm always looking
at all the attack vectors and I think
that VR is the perfect time to kill
somebody as crazy as that sounds now
hopefully that doesn't happen while this
is recording and it's gonna be playing
you know don't don't don't censor this
because I'm saying it you know but you
know hopefully no one's gonna take that
idea forward and then I'm gonna be
blamed for it but it's the perfect time
all right so what artifacts can you
create and we have a project that was
funded by DHS called the artifact Genome
Project that was launched in 2017 I'm
just going to show you a quick video so
that maybe you'd want to use it in the
future
Joan in London Joe in Switzerland and
Mark in the US are all digital forensic
practitioners struggling with the same
problem they have to rely on their own
past experience in manual digital
forensic analysis in order to find
evidentiary artifacts and every device
they work with has different forensic
artifacts making their job that much
harder what if their knowledge was
gathered and what if these artifacts
could be tracked and updated over time
introducing a GP a unified digital
forensic curation platform that brings
forensic practitioners together like
never before investigating these are to
buy you subscribe to a GP and you can
gain access to that data so our job
initially was to look at the security
and forensic analysis and focusing more
on the application layer and seeing what
we can get at the network what we can
get in RAM and we can what we can get
from the disk and that was kind of our
initial sort of work so this was the
first paper we presented at at sad fee
which was at which was a workshop at
security and privacy and what we did is
we analysed all the social apps in the
VR market that we thought were highly
used so prior to this work a lot of my
work is focused on mobile apps so we did
forensic analysis of for example
whatsapp we did forensic analysis of you
know all of the social sort of messaging
applications as you say Facebook we did
Twitter we did all of them and my
mindset you know
as a research I'm like what's the next
thing how our people are gonna socialize
in the future right I mean we're all
stuck into it with our phones and
there's people in this room stuck to
their laptops right now all right that's
what we do we're screen people and all
we're doing is we're bringing the screen
closer to our eyes that's that's where
we're moving so essentially if you have
a VR system on you're gonna interact
with another person somewhere around the
world watch a movie with them go out on
a date right that's where we're heading
so that's what we did and we were the
first people to take a closer look at
them so we basically set up an
experiment where we set up two different
VR systems had the people log on to
these apps use them so that we can
generate some data and see where that
takes us so to give you a quick overview
these are just some of the artifacts
that we were able to recover right so we
can tell a lot of things and this is
just from the steam side of things which
is this app store that I was talking
about all right
we know when things when people logged
on we know when they're logged off we
have access to all this data potentially
from the system there's also an app
called big screen as anyone heard of big
screen right so big screen is this app
where you could basically watch a movie
with someone else around the world you
know if you want to watch Netflix with
somebody who's in New Zealand you can do
that right so that's kind of the idea
behind Netflix and we were able to
extract all sort of artifacts from there
there's also rec room you can see we
know when people fail to log in when
they open the application Facebook
spaces so one interesting thing about
Facebook spaces I'll tell you about it
later
cuz I don't want to say it on video but
I'll tell you know after the talk come
and talk to me and I'll tell you in
person
but we were able to extract artifacts
there but really the main findings is
that we're able to extract artifacts
which can tell us the who the when the
what and aware of when something
potentially could have happened in some
of these VR apps and that's good because
if you were resulted in something being
if some crime would have happened in VR
then we can kind of reconstruct the
events and be able to see what happened
and that's that's that's really amazing
I think the real cool thing is when we
started looking at the net flow the
network traffic we started realizing
that some of the stuff is unencrypted
and unauthenticated
right so from a hackers perspective you
get really excited and you're like mm
what can we do next right and this is
when we realized that there might be
some man-in-the-middle attacks that we
might be able to do on some of these
things and we kind of got excited about
that so our next paper was published in
IEEE Tripoli transactions on dependable
and secure computing and our goal here
was to understand a little bit more
about where we can attack at the VR
layer to potentially cause the most
damage
all right so looking at these diagrams
right now is it clear on the screen can
can everyone see it yep so if you were
an attacker where would you want to
attack at what layer would you want to
attack like the easiest sort of layer to
attack at where would it be
come on give it a shot you have one out
of four chances so try yep the device
drivers layer which is not in the hands
of the consumer well so that's a good
point it's a good layer to attack him
because because you might have much
larger coverage in terms of your attack
surface the only problem is if you ask
the consumer to install a driver there's
gonna be all sorts of warning at play
correct
yeah like did you ever try to install a
driver on a system that wasn't the
driver was modified or something he's
just gonna give you all sorts of error
messages right it's not really the best
place to the top it's the best place
attack in terms of attack coverage but
if you want to go quick and get your job
done where would you go so this is what
we attacked on we attacked on the open
VR layer for a multiple of reasons one
it's open so you can see the source code
right that's great for us too it
connects everything together right so if
we're able to do things there
that means it's gonna have also a large
attack surface an open VR was created so
that today you have HTC vive tomorrow
you have oculus the day after that you
have Joe schmo's VR system you could
still use it right so we were the first
to coin certain attacks like the
immersive attack the chaperone the
attack the overlay attack the
disorientation attack and so on and so
forth we're also the first to implement
a point you know a proof-of-concept
immersive attacks using open VR we
successfully implemented what we call
the human joystick attack which is kind
of the more interesting attack I think
out of all of this in my perspective
because I like that that tax that deal
with human nature and I think that's
that's very interesting and really our
goal was to get people to think to
catalyze a movement like you got to
think about this if you're gonna do VR
stuff you got to start thinking about
some of these things so how do we do
this this is kind of the overall sort of
high level hierarchy of how we did
things right we made an assumption and
which is a very easy assumption to make
right and this is where researchers
would argue it's not an easy some no
it's a pretty simple assumptions to me
your computer was hacked for me that's
an easy assumption to make because once
you understand how computers work you
know you can get into a system however I
will make this claim that after this
after this part of the paper
I'd like this paper that I'm presenting
very quickly high level on I'm gonna
show you some more work to show you that
we don't even need to compromise your
computer to do all of this right we
don't we can just use the underlying
problems in some of these applications
that lie on top of VR in order to gain
full access and do very funky things
with your system all right are we good
okay but in this scenario that I'm
presenting we assume that the person has
access to your camera so what can our
access to your system right so what kind
of things can you do well we're able to
turn on the front facing camera all
right so that's a violation of privacy
we're we're you know we can stream video
back to us as an attacker we can see
inside your room we can even turn on the
camera if it's disabled by the user
okay the second thing is I was driving
once and I was like man the coolest
thing to do is to just get rid of the
chaperone and have people you know hit a
hit a wall
right I mean maybe you don't think it's
cool but I think as an attacker person
I'm thinking wow that's kind of cool
like oddly enough I think we have
somebody in the audience that have
helped broke someone's hand if you are
maybe you can tell them the story later
not on purpose so there's a chaperone
attack so what if you can just make the
boundaries disappear right and that's
what we did well then things like this
happen right all right well what all of
you I'm going to assume that most of us
know what ransomware is at this point in
time right so what if we can create a
new kind of ransomware that takes over
your goggles right just place an image
there have it stayed there you can't get
rid of it until you give us some money
right and it's possible right because of
how how these how the layered
infrastructure of open VR works you can
do things like that what if I don't have
to look into your room and just see in a
camera but I can actually stream back
every movement that you're making I mean
how much of a viola C Prize you know
privacy violation is that and this is
actually a real-time rendering of
software that my student wrote that's
doing exactly that
right so we can stream location of your
where your hands are where your headset
is that's let me think about that right
we can see in your room and we could see
exactly what you're doing all right so
now I want to the human joystick attack
the human joystick attack and I can show
you that video of this in a second it's
essentially this let me tell you let me
let me give you a background story of
how we even discovered this attack
because we discovered it by mistake
right at our university there was a
virtual reality symposium that had
nothing to do with security it was just
like hey Alice let's invite universities
to do some
we are cool work and they knew that we
were doing some work in VR and they
invited us so we're like what are we
gonna do show them how to hack your like
you know like well we're like okay
whatever let's just go so we set up and
as people were going you know through
trying all these experiences Peter who's
a former student in mine he you know he
put the experience on he just flashed
things in front of them because of some
of the attacks and like Oh see we just
took over your vision and things like
that and it was all script like you just
had a couple of I think it was like
either C programs of Python scripts I
don't remember they just did some of
these modifications real you know and do
a girl put put the VR headset on and he
just looked at me for a split second
he's like man what if I like changed
there there's their virtual Center and
he just like all he did was he you know
just changed the number ran it and we
just saw the girl go like this and like
hold on because she just really moved to
where we told her to move and he was
like well I'm like I don't believe you
let's try this again
all right just changed the number to
something else and then a minute like
not even a couple of seconds later she
went like this I mean like oh my god
like did we just discover something like
is it cool and they're like this is cool
and then of course he looked at me and
he's like okay this is cool and if any
of you have done any human subject
research or the automatic answer it's
like this is not cool because if that
amount of work I have to do with IRB and
to get students in at all but then I
told her I was like Peter you have to do
this because if we think this is a
really cool discovery and we have to
just keep pushing forward on this all
right so long story short these are some
results for you to kind of see certain
things at the bottom are different VR
games like longbows or Texas slingshot
surgeon simulator and guns and stories
at the bottom and this is if you think
of this as the room and you're looking
top from the top down that's the headset
data right so at the bottom is what they
thought they did versus at the top is
what they really did right at the bottom
they thought they stayed in that same
location playing that Longboat game but
in reality we were moving them to from
location a to
Kayson be alright so maybe most of
you're thinking you know what Abe it's
kind of cool not very interesting to me
it's super interesting because right now
we live in a world where we can control
people's thoughts by putting stuff on
social media right is the next iteration
of that us physically telling people
where they need to go and they go right
are we becoming so programmed as
individuals that we might end up there
and maybe the hypothesis is true so this
is a quick video to show you that top so
you can kind of understand it a little
bit
so what we do is as you see men they say
as a virtual sensor and all we were
doing is we're slowly moving the virtual
Center to a point of our light and what
do humans do they compensate and because
the compensate for that
the game that he's playing all he's
doing is he's standing and basically a
circular area and you have to you don't
need to move all you need to do is just
use your bow and arrow and fire it these
items are around and all of a sudden you
start seeing him move okay this is
available on our youtube channel if
you'd like to watch this later
please go ahead and do so but the attack
was pretty successful it was successful
across a range of games and it happened
with most people being unaware of the
attack taking place okay what if we can
make you sick right now you're looking
at this and kind of look sickening just
looking at this but if you're in VR and
this is happening to you it doesn't feel
great okay maybe you'd fall and break
your hand all right so what's next well
why can't we put all of these things
together to create a more impactful
attack right what if we can compromise
your system maybe there's no need to and
we'll talk about this in a minute what
if we look into your room what if we can
remove your safety boundaries what if we
could move you wherever we want like
maybe a stairway block your vision
disoriented and having have you fall
down the stairs okay what if all of
these things are combined into a
mechanism that allowed us to do these
things just as an example right so from
a security practitioners standpoint it's
nice to find one thing but you always
have to find multiple things to create
the impact and then try to leverage them
in a way that's possible right
okay now this has led us remember the
man in the the man in the middle stuff
we talked about earlier we were like
okay some of the data was incorrect and
encrypted so this has led us to
you start working on this stuff and we
have a paper out right now that's being
that's under review but we leverage old
attacks in new technologies and we were
able to do things that would just like
be very interesting to most of you and
in specific we looked at the the big
screen application and of course
everything that we discovered was
reported to them and supposedly patched
hopefully but a lot of things are not as
great as they seem
let's just put it that way so over there
does anyone know what we're doing there
just as an example so this is the
application and you can join a room or
like a public room and then once you
join that public room again big screen
is this application when you sit down in
VR with other people you can watch a
movie you can do all sorts of other
things right does anyone know what
cross-site scripting is yeah this is
just a sample cross-site scripting
attack right we implemented it once and
it affected all the users on the system
think about that for a second
right that's pretty that's pretty gnarly
say the least so this was our primary
implementation of what's again I had
another activity once I was hanging out
I was like I want to create the first
man in the room attack I don't create a
man-in-the-middle attack it's called a
man in the room attack so we actually
have a man in the room attack which I'll
show you in a second and it's really us
trying to explore what kind of old
attacks might yield different results
okay so there's two layers to this that
we discovered the first one is
cross-site scripting attack that affects
multiple different people due to poor
sanitization on application developers
of the choices they make for a lack of a
better word so what are some of these
things what do they help us do well RCE
doesn't even know what an RC is it's an
RC e come on write remote code execution
if we can execute ly if you can remotely
execute code on a person system that's
pretty cool more importantly we
discovered something at a lower layer
with the unity platform which is what
most developers use to create games and
one of the big things we discovered is
the open link
function the unity to open link passing
it to URL if you pass it a URL it opens
up a web browser for a lack of a better
word right but if you pass it see users
it's open see users okay if you pass it
a URL slash exe guess what it does it
downloads the exe to the person's
computer right so when we reached out to
to unity they were really excited not
really they even said oh that's just the
feature and then before we release this
publicly and it went viral and all this
stuff they just changed their their
documentation on the website saying it
could also do this it was like yeah it's
still not great so we essentially
created the first botnet of V our users
by leveraging the weaknesses in a big
screen application we created a worm
that was as simple as this okay nothing
too crazy but it works alright
self-replicating does the job so what
are some of the things that we could do
well control infected big screen
applications from a command and control
server which I'll show you in a second
independently download and execute
payloads run any program do a remote
repple gain control over part of big
screen application discover private
rooms invisibly join discovered private
rooms receive victims screen sharing
audio microphone video persistently
eavesdrop on on them if they go to
another room we can send them a message
that looks really legit for them to
download the VR driver now we can
execute our VR Driver thing and stay in
their system forever I really wanted to
write hopefully they don't update and
uninstall and do all these things right
so a lot of a lot of very interesting
things happen when you discover things
like that of course we can change their
avatar do all these silly things as well
so once you map out their infrastructure
you start understanding okay here's some
here's how they're doing things and
there's things like getting the state of
the
like doing a slash room state you can
see the blacklisted users which is also
not good so we were able to discover
usernames of people that were playing
porn in public rooms and they were
banned for that reason but now we know
who those users are so that's not very
good that we shouldn't we shouldn't know
these things so the first thing that
happened was essentially reverse
engineering the signaling protocol
across this platform for us to totally
understand how things happen and then
once you understand that and you can
decrypt some of the messaging you get to
understand the protocol and how it works
it's not that difficult again it's just
programming its messaging its protocols
but the main thing here is while data is
encrypted
there was no authentication and in some
cases there was no encryption which is a
problem all right
even though that in their code of
conduct they said we have no way of
knowing what goes on inside because it's
a spirit appear and encrypted which
didn't seem to be the case from our
perspective at least and then we started
looking at the core application to see
if we can reverse-engineer it to do some
some interesting things so we were able
to dynamically load libraries without
because there was no integrity checking
of any sort on these and then we
developed a proof of concept by patching
those binaries and doing some
interesting things with them all right
and this is kind of what we did
so enable to create the man in the room
attack my vision when I was talking to
the students is I want to put this VR
headset on I want to be in the room with
three other people I want to see them
interact but I don't want them to see me
and I don't want them to hear me all
right so by patching the application all
we did was patching things that would
send data essentially to the servers and
we just stopped them from sending them
but we would we were able to receive the
data that we wanted to receive to do
the funky things that we wanted to do
alright so I think it's important for
you to just see this a little bit again
it's on YouTube but I'd like you to just
see some of the things in action
so again this again started as a bunch
of scripts that we did and it ended up
you know I spoke to to Martin Vanderjagt
who is visiting us from from the Czech
Republic in our lab I was like listen we
need to package this thing too into an
application that can do all of these
things and this is when things got
really interesting is having one script
that can do something small it's not as
impactful as packaging it's into an
entire application I'm gonna skip the
infection process and get to the meat of
the you can you can you can watch this
the infection process okay so over here
are the discovered you have the the
public rooms you can discover rooms and
then you can start eavesdropping on
rooms okay so what you do is you start
poisoning and when you poison
essentially what you do is what you
start some sort of a cross-site
scripting attack against either the room
name or the name of an individual that
could then join other rooms and then you
can create a self-replicating worm
because of it
so we showed the more difficult way of
getting through that process but it
could be just as easy as creating one
public room with a cross-site scripting
attack in it okay so in this case now
you can take that room and you can
automatically see the zombies in the
room and it gets very interesting
right like being able to stream their
computer screen in real time back to you
you have to keep in mind something very
important here the end user did nothing
the end user did absolutely nothing okay
all the end user did was being a good
person they logged into their big screen
app they put their VR headset on and
they were just doing things the normal
way they would do okay
so we could start chatting on other
people's behalf
we can make people admins if we really
wanted to we can toggle or audio we can
toggle video we can play very sound
effects if you really wanted to so to me
from someone my age group this was
really exciting because there reminded
me of something called sub 7 I believe
that sort of was called right sub 7 you
know we're talking about Greg now you
have no idea what I'm talking about
ok so when we were kids there was this
Trojan that we would share you know on
ICQ and things like that and then it
will allow you to open their you know
their their cd-rom drive and things like
that I mean this was like the music oh
this is the new version of that as we
are and I got excited
we just ran a command prompt they opened
up on their on their screen right you
can open up the folder there so you're
seeing like that's the attacker and
that's the that's basically the victim
right
you just download an exe on the computer
and we just executed it
then we could do something funky like
this where within their UI they'd
receive some sort of a message that
seemed legit
sorry additional fee our drivers
required looks like it's part of the app
they would download it and write users
out you get the you get ok so then we're
like ok
most most research or most attackers are
not going to be focused on disk these
days a lot of a lot of people are doing
things in memory so it was very
interesting for us to work on trying to
get data out of memory so we could
visualize potentially what artifacts we
could retrieve from memory to understand
the forensics of those situations right
so that that was kind of our our take on
this and with IOT devices you know your
most of the time you're there using our
o T's like real-time operating systems
and most of the stuff is just going to
be in memory as opposed to being on the
disk
so again we took some well-known
scenarios we used VR we took memory
dumps and then we started statically
looking at where we could potentially
find static data access points within
the memory dump so we could know where
we could pull data from essentially when
we develop some sort of a module that we
could use has anyone heard of volatility
right so we developed a volatility
plugin as part of this right so this was
the first time people have ever like you
started nobody's ever looked at memory
forensics of VR right so that was kind
of really cool and we did that so this
is the volatility plug-in actually
running right you give it a memory dump
I'm assuming it's gonna run ok so you
run it against it it it finds the its
finds the PID for the VR monitor then it
finds the data structures and then as
soon as it does that it takes the
controller the base station and
everything else and it also plots it for
you to kind of understand the last state
that VR position was in in
memory right so now we've actually
visualized where the headset is where
those hint like where the where the
controllers are and also where the base
station is by just pulling data from RAM
all right and then we got into education
so we actually have lectures and labs
that are openly accessible if you want
to reach out I can send you this data so
these are just some of the lives so like
disk forensics and artifact analysis of
VR network traffic analysis of the our
applications and memory forensics of VR
systems we have some labs that and
lastly while we are while we just you
know all alike our purpose was to
attempt to use VR and see the security
weaknesses we actually created a game
for people to play and VR to teach them
about digital forensics the sound is a
little low is there any way we could put
it up a little bit
so we collaborated with big engage
platform and this is publicly available
if you actually have a to the
introduction to cyber forensics lecture
from the University this is the first
time you're in vice research and
education right sure the audience
understands that the lecture will not
make you a certified digital forensics
examiner by any means and this lecture
is really just designed to provide a
simple introductory level outline of
what the digital forensics investigation
process is our goal is to understand and
define what cyber forensic science is
perhaps some list of the basics of a
cyber crime scene procedure understand
what to do when a computer is on or off
on its own something called simulated
situated learning so we give them a
lecture and then we throw them into a
lab where they would have to back in tag
a crime scene in a virtual reality case
to help you practice what you have
learned thank you and good luck so now
we're situating them or putting them in
the shoes of a real investigator so they
can protect either you're here I missed
the start of the CEO of this company
this guy sure knows security at one of
our engineers is going to lead the
blueprints for our new VR time machine
goggles it's our flagship product if we
lose those goggles will mean the end of
King small technologies oh I better
start mr. big business across the road
he's the CEO of our main competitor big
cars so what we did is we built this and
then we wanted to test it and this is a
paper that's been submitted literally
like four days ago and the paper is
called isn't my digital forensics
professor better than virtual reality
exploring VF learning in VR versus the
physical world so we actually conducted
a human subject study where we put them
in VR and we also put another group
that's not in VR and we tried to see if
the same amount of learning happened by
doing pretest and post-test and running
some statistical analysis to see if it
actually made a difference the
interesting thing is there was no
statistically significant difference
between putting people in VR and putting
people you know between people and VR
and between people in the physical world
so that's a really good indication at
least initially for us
be like maybe we should be using more
like the oculus rift so you guys can
wake up in your dorm room or in your
apartment and you don't have to you know
change your clothes and you just put
that on I can do the same thing from my
own butt that I was like let's do a
lecture right so maybe we should be
moving more in that direction because I
think it's also more interesting than
the way we do online education now where
it's just basically using blackboard or
other learning management systems and I
think having more of an immersive
environment to be in might create better
learning opportunities for students so
in conclusion we need security by design
we need Atlanta this is a landscape for
novel attacks that we need to
continuously explore it might be the
perfect way to control humans in the
future
and when I say xr-- by the way so so I
don't know if anyone's heard the term XR
XR means like V like VR it means
augmented reality it means all of these
things lump together is X right so X is
the unknown we don't know what's gonna
happen next right so what are the next
steps right what are the next steps and
this is why I co-founded an organization
Kavya Perlman is actually the founder
it's called the XR safety initiative if
you go to XR x RS org in order for us to
really start getting people to think
about this problem and they released an
XR data classification framework not too
long ago again I'm just I'm the
co-founder but she's the head honcho on
this initiative and we hope that we can
get more people to think about the
problem and realize that it's something
that we need to start looking at more
closely as we do a lot more research
into security and forensics affects our
systems as any good academic would say
this is my this is my reference list and
thank you very much and I hope you
enjoyed the talk
I have a question basically through your
opening the gates of Hell be cut the
communication with the environment for
everybody is just mostly by the senses
that you have you look you see you're
here you touch and you taste another
stuff but this one sometimes it's
getting some people in the deeper state
that's basically cutting off from the
reality so I don't know in real getting
really involved in this kind of thing
you're gonna get to the level of
hypnotism so we can program people their
mind and then you decide around and then
basically you had them before we had the
drug we should control the mind now in
combination with this kind of a system
this is gonna be very dangerous and you
can add to that the subliminal
communication that you can have with
this kind of system so basically this is
gonna produce some kind of people even
though a lot of people this looks like
some kind of a game or entertainment
it's gonna make it really dangerous so
as I said what just listening I was kind
of confused that if you have some kind
of you should have some kind of a
commission maybe genies out of the
bottle but they have to have some kind
of a commission to see for the sale of
these products and basically development
of this kind of system because it's
playing with the mind of the people and
that's I say very dangerous I don't know
what you think about it so it's funny
that you said that because there is a
company and I forgot what they're called
it's like called it's called VR drugs of
are drugs so so the idea of are drugs or
VR drugs or I forget what the company is
called like their whole mission is can
we create alternatives to drugs in
virtual reality right can we stimulate
and have the mind operate in a different
way by placing people immersively in a
different environment so there's already
companies that are coming out and saying
we want to use virtual reality as a new
type of drug solution for people and I
think that's it you know again it's
interesting that you bring that up I
think the thing that worries me is like
any other technology there's positives
and negatives and what we have to be
aware of is
applications of the deep privacy
violations that can happen with VR
because it's no longer just a cellphone
that you're carrying so with a cell
phone you can approximate the person's
GPS location right but with a VR system
you're in their house
right I know that this is a wall like
the VR system knows that there's a wall
there the VR system can approximate
where the floor is so we're getting to
the point where our devices can see
inside of our house and we're getting to
the point where again the screen is
getting closer and closer to our eyes
right because right now it's a cell
phone you can pull it out and look at it
and we all do that right but in the
future you're just gonna wear some
augmented reality system that you're
gonna augment the world around you with
other things so to speak right so the
solution I think is we do need some sort
of a regulatory process for some of
these things as they're happening and I
think that the technology has moved
really quickly to the point where it's
become mobile and it's just gonna keep
getting smaller and better in my opinion
as we move forward and with the
advancement in machine learning
especially a lot of a lot of the systems
don't need to have the same
computational power to potentially
produce the same results as like a very
expensive system would so machine
learning is being used heavily in VR
systems these days in order to make
things just appear better for the user
and I think that that that there's gonna
be more things that we're gonna see but
then that brings up safety initiatives
for a machine learning and AI which is
another discussion obviously that we can
have I mean
basically if you continue you're gonna
have you're playing with somebody's
psyche right it's gonna be tough to see
what its gonna be the fingerprints and
stuff particularly if something happens
and basically it's gonna destroy your
mind and that's key that's a very
dangerous thing because you don't know
what the people are being controlled or
not or what's gonna happen next so
that's what point yes I think like I
said I think we need a better regulatory
process for some of these things as
they're starting to emerge that's that's
kind of the best way to do it yes if
there was like
a safer version of the video game
technology where someone could like sit
down physically in a chair and interact
with like a physical system like a
monitor so are you saying that I was
making a joke I was saying only
physically sitting down at a computer
would be a lot so I mean you're singing
a joke but I'm not actually I'm not
lying because my mind took me to to the
new sort of hololens
and in some of the VR systems that are
being used basically they're saying
that's what's gonna happen in the future
you're gonna have a lame desk that when
you look at it's not gonna be lame in VR
right because you can touch the physical
desk and then you could augment whatever
you want on top of it right because the
new VR so so I mean I you know how my
mind took me to like where we really are
going right so it's funny but it's also
like realistic right I mean I think I
think and it's actually as soon as I
started playing with VR I'm like this
would be a perfect way for me to change
what my room looks like every other day
because I don't want to get bored
looking at the same thing right
if you have I don't know your augment
things like if I have a student that
really bothers me in the classroom I
just like change them into another
student I'm not saying I'm gonna do that
just saying like maybe you'd want to go
down that route maybe right now you're
really annoyed by eight because he kept
on bothering you cuz you were on your
lap I was like just shut a bar I don't
want to see him right so I think I
honestly think that there's going to be
tremendous opportunities in VR and AR in
the future but I think that we need to
thread lightly because it's gonna open a
whole new avenue of security work I mean
it's great for us right security people
like we're oh this is great like it'll
study the security of this with the same
token I feel the same way about AI in
machine learning
there was like let's machine learning
this let's do this let's do that it was
like oh now it's like we have all these
other layers of security that we have to
worry about security and forensics that
we have to worry about so it's just one
of those items that new technology
school but we'd have to step back and
understand what we're really doing yes
they were asking your attorney I'm sorry
so I wonder Li how hard it is to get a
memory dumps from these VR devices is
there a unified interface or protocol
for you to do this so the ones we worked
on we're running on Windows so we were
just dumping memory on the Windows
system so that was easy
okay but the newer ones are Android
based so as long as you figure out a way
to dump memory from an Android phone or
Android device
there might be a way of doing that right
okay so there I think I think the oculus
quest uses a Snapdragon and probably has
an Android and Android operating system
running on it so I assume me to require
some rude permission to do this like so
I yes it's not impossible as we all know
right okay sometimes it is harder and
sometimes it takes a couple of years for
an exploit to come out yeah but
ultimately you know like especially with
the iPhones right now I mean you saw the
I'm sure you've heard about what does it
call check ro yeah yeah it's like
everyone like all the forensic companies
integrated check route like one week
after it came out you're gonna take an
iPhone dump its data and you're ready to
go there hasn't been enough work I would
say in the memory forensics domain of
mobile devices a lot of the stuff has
been more on like Linux UNIX and Windows
there's not enough memory forensics work
on mobile devices so I see thank you
well the ARM architecture is not very
well studied in that regard to missing
any other questions anyone enjoyed the
talk also good all right thank you
[Applause]
you