good afternoon it's my pleasure to
introduce dr. Barrera Akuma dr. Kumar is
a postdoctoral research associate in the
Department of Computer Science at Purdue
University vajra earned his Bachelor
degree in electrical engineering at
Indian Institute of Technology Delhi in
2009 and he speech the degree in
Computer Engineering at Virginia Tech
into in 2016 he was the recipient of the
outstanding PhD student award by the
Center for embedded systems for critical
applications at Virginia Tech he also
had a short stint as a project assistant
in the department of electrical
communication engineering at Indian
Institute of Science in 2010 his
research interests include discovering
and mitigating security vulnerabilities
in the communication protocols employed
in cyber-physical systems including
smart home smart transportation and a
smart city brushless research has
featured in top-tier secured venues
including ACM conferences on computer
and communication security CCS and I
Tripoli transactions on information
forensics and security tips he also
served on the tpc a flagship conferences
including I Triple E conferences on
communications and network security CNS
and I Triple E international symposium
on dynamic spectrum access network dai
span so we'd further without further a
do let's welcome dr. Coleman
yeah thank you for the very nice and
very long introduction yeah yeah so I am
very glad to be here and let's look into
some of the security issues that we
encounter in current vehicles and that
we are going to encounter in
next-generation vehicles as well so what
is I guess so let me first start with a
question so what is the first thing that
comes to your mind when you think of an
autonomous vehicle so can somebody just
tell me what is the first thing and
please feel free to stop me in between
and then ask questions safety okay
that's very nice yeah that is very nice
as well yeah so yes so those are the
things that come to your mind
when you first hear about an autonomous
vehicle so the few of the things that I
would like to firmly put some of the
advantages of these connected autonomous
vehicles are driverless travel traffic
management and minimizing accidents so
these are the numbers from India so into
four cities in India if you go outside
with your car you will spend around
forty five minutes driving from your
home to your office location and also
you will spend another thirty minutes in
traffic jams but the most important
number here is the number of accidents
and the number of deaths that happen so
in India more than 100,000 deaths occur
every year which translates to 275
deaths per day so it is very important
that we develop a smart transportation
system which takes care of the faults
that drivers make on the road okay so
the idea of connected and autonomous
vehicles has two components so the first
component is the autonomous component so
the autonomous component means that the
onboard sensors on a vehicle for
instance the cameras the leaders they
make
decisions by sensing their environment
so the autonomous component is just an
in vehicle error component where you
have these nodes which are called
electronic control units which control
each of the components of your vehicle
so one electronic component controls the
brake when another electronic component
controls your steering and similarly
there are around hundreds of electronic
control units in your car these days but
all these electronic control units
communicate over this network which is
called controller area network can so by
communicating over these they make
intelligent decisions for instance when
you are actually using cruise control
the your engine control unit your
steering your brake your accelerator all
of them are talking to each other and
making intelligent decisions so that is
the part of the autonomous component of
our architecture now let us move to the
second component which is the connected
component now you in order to make in
order to enable a smart transportation
you need to make sure that the vehicles
are talking to each other and the
vehicles are also talking to
infrastructure which it may include
traffic lights or other types of
infrastructure so when these vehicles
talk to each other they could make
intelligent decisions in such a way so
for instance when you are using just a
camera the camera will have to detect
that the vehicle in front of you has is
slowing down and then the camera could
instruct the vehicle to make to enable
braking and then the the vehicle which
is behind the actually braking vehicle
will be able to stop itself but when you
have this vehicle to vehicle
communication the first vehicle even
before going even before it is going to
brake it can tell this the vehicle which
is behind it that it is going to brake
and then the second vehicle could also
start braking so it is it will be a very
nice our way to have this connected
vehicle idea as well so now the nodes in
this connected vehicles idea
called onboard telematics units OB user
and the protocol that they utilize to
communicate among themselves is called
vehicle to everything v2x
communication protocol okay so when we
look into the whole model of a connected
autonomous vehicle you can think of it
as an OB u which has these two modems
one is called a v2x modem which is
required for connection over a wireless
network and the different vehicles
talk to each other through this v2x
modem and then the OB U is also
connected to the inn via cooler network
through this kin modem which is the
controller area network modem and then
this can bus is actually a via dub it is
a wired protocol these issues are
following this wired protocol to
communicate among themselves and as I
said there could be a large number of
issues which include body see you or
which controls the doors and other stuff
and you could also have brake or engine
now once we have this vehicle model now
what could go wrong here so it is very
nice to think about the security threats
that we could have in any system but it
is particularly important to think about
these kind of things for us very safety
critical system like a vehicle now most
of researchers here who are looking for
the look look into these are standard
protocols which could be a cellular
protocol or which could be a Bluetooth
protocol and then we also have to look
into this new generation v2x protocol
which will be which will enable this
vehicle to vehicle communication now
when these vehicles were designed they
were never designed to be connected to
the outside world through these
communication protocols because the
controller area network or the idea of
having electronic control units to
control each individual unit in a
vehicle it came around 1990s when there
was no concept that you could you should
be able to use your mobile phone to open
or to lock or unlock your door or
start your engine these concepts were
not there and therefore in the design
phase of these vehicles the the security
was never considered and then also they
there are these resource constraints
which come come because of these price
issues so these because each vehicle
contains hundreds of units the price of
it is very important for the vehicle
manufacturers to keep the price of each
unit very low and therefore the units
which are actually employed there have
resource constraints in terms of energy
and in terms of the bandwidth that they
utilize to communicate with other is
useful ok but now we know that it is
possible to have bugs in these
communication protocols and once an
attacker finds a bug in these
communication protocols it can find a
foothold inside the vehicle or network
and once it finds the foothold inside
the vehicle Network it can take complete
control of the vehicle because as I said
there is no security that is built in
inside the vehicle the messages that are
being communicated they are communicated
in plaintext and therefore when the
attacker takes just that foothold it
will it will be able to control your
brakes it will be able to control your
steering wheel and it can do many other
things very very interesting things to
your vehicle now it is not that there is
only one particular manufacturer which
could be affected by these bugs so
researchers have found a large variety
of bugs in all different top
manufacturers of vehicles which include
Tesla as well and so in order to just
illustrate what can happen when somebody
gets into your vehicle I would like to
show this quick video in which the
attackers are able to do very
interesting things so here you see the
attacker controlling the steering wheel
of a vehicle the door lock and
or feature the rpm meters the brakes
yeah so it can actually do many
interesting things and what the way they
do did it was the that they found a bug
in the entertainment system that was
installed on the vehicle that
entertainment system utilized a cellular
connection and therefore the attackers
were able to get into the vehicle
wirelessly so they exploited the bug in
the entertainment system to ensure that
they have full control of the vehicle
now because of this vulnerability in
2003 which was shown in 2015 Jeep had to
recall 1.4 million cars and do this
security patch for their entertainment
system so that these this security
vulnerability could be mitigated now
some of the researchers in IBM they
actually went ahead and analyzed what
could be an impact of these kind of
security bugs so they found that if if
these type of bugs were not mitigated
during the design phase and they and the
manufacturer would have to recall all
these vehicles and then mitigate them it
costs the vehicle manufacturer a
thousand takes more to do that and
therefore it is very important that we
develop these security mechanisms which
prevent all these different types of
attacks during the design phase of the
vehicle ok so now let me talk let me go
into the technical detail of my talk so
I will go into two so we just looked
into the two components of this
connected and autonomous vehicle idea so
I will go into these two different
aspects and talk about the different
attacks and possible defenses in those
components so looking into the first
component which is the autonomous
component we will look into an
impersonation attack and in this
impersonation attack we assume that the
attacker has already gotten foothold
into the vehicular network which means
that perhaps the OBU is already
compromised
and now we will see what this OBU the
compromised puke can actually achieve
okay so as we already said that this in
regular Network does not employ any kind
of security which means that it does not
employ any encryption or authentication
mechanism now so what would be the
solution so the researchers have
proposed that how about we install an
intrusion detection system on the bus
which detects these different types of
anomalies which can occur because an
attacker has started launches launching
some attack on the vehicle so the ideas
will try to detect these anomalies and
raise an alarm okay
but yeah so you might realize that these
ideas are never perfect
so you have you always have this
cat-and-mouse game so the first attacks
that were proposed where message
impersonation attacks on the canvas and
then people came up with these anomalies
that can occur in messages and detect
those anomalies to come up with an alarm
system then this race continued and
currently we are at this stage where the
state of the art intrusion detection
system utilizes this voltage based
fingerprinting technique now let's see
what are these voltage fingerprinting
based the integer notation system so in
if you see an ECU the architecture of an
ECU you will see that when the ECU wants
to send something on the bus there is a
very simple mechanism to do it so when
the issue wants to send a bit one on the
bus it sends a volt zero on the bus and
when it wants to send a bit zero on the
bus it will send a value of voltage to
be 2 volts
now since this mechanism is implemented
in hardware and hardware is actually a
set of transistors and resistors these
things are never perfect so
in inducing such voltages that never
perfect so on the bus you will see these
different fluctuations in the real value
of the voltages so what the researchers
did was they actually found that these
voltages have a distribution and if we
extract significant number of features
from these distributions it is possible
to differentiate between the senders so
if an engine control unit is sending a
message it will have a particular
distribution of voltage values if the
brake control unit is sending a message
it will have a different distribution
and therefore the proposed mechanism was
to train a machine learning algorithm
with these features and then at the when
it in the operation phase when somebody
sends a message you match the
fingerprint of that message to the
learned fingerprint and if they do not
match you raise an alarm but there is an
issue here so these voltage fingerprint
based
IDs they require regular training
because the voltage fingerprint can
change with temperature because when you
have these resistors and these
transistors working they actually change
their behavior at different temperatures
and then that behavior also changes over
time so when they get old their behavior
changes therefore this irregular
retraining is required in these widths
okay so now let's see how these widsom
these defense were evaluated in the
priority so in the prior art what they
were doing when they were proposing
these with defense mechanisms that they
considered a victim so let us say the
engine control unit is a victim here and
then they said that okay we will have a
whit's defense there and then they
considered one attacker so in this case
let us say the telematics control unit
is an attacker and now the what the
attacker could do was there are
I could only heat itself or cool itself
to change its voltage characteristics
because the voltage characteristics are
generated by the hardware of the vehicle
so even if you are have compromised an
attacker you cannot compromise its
hardware and therefore the voltage
fingerprint cannot be changed but the
attacker could just only try to heat or
cool itself to change the voltage
behavior but you see that the defense is
actually using a machine learning
algorithm and there is an asymmetry here
so the defense is using the machine
learning algorithm but the attacker is
very naive here so therefore we saw an
opportunity to ensure that we can come
up with a better attack that has been
proposed in the prior literature so
therefore we came up with this attack
which we call do it
so this attack requires two compromised
ECU's so we have hundreds of ECU's in a
vehicle so we considered that let's have
to compromise this use so one could be
the telematics control unit which has
this cellular connection to the outside
world and the other could be the VC I am
the vehicle communication interface
module through which you use your mobile
and you connect using the Bluetooth so
the Bluetooth is actually controlled by
this VC I M so let's have these two
compromised ECU's in our attack model
and then these two compromised ECU's
they would employ an adversarial machine
learning technique to actually counter
the machine learning based intrusion
detection system so the specific machine
the adversarial machine learning
technique that we utilized is called a
training set poisoning and let's see how
that works
so this is again revisiting the same
concept that different ECU's will have
different voltage characteristics and
they will have different voltage
distributions so here I have enumerated
them the three is used as victim
attacker and accomplice so now in this
case if the attacker wants to
impersonate the victim
because their distributions are
different the widths will detect that
impersonation attempt but now what we
will do is we will try to bypass the
widths but here one important thing to
note here is that these all three of
them have this unimodal Gaussian
distribution which means that they have
some variance around just one knee the
voltage values have some variance around
that one mean okay so what we will do in
the training phase of the Wits is that
now the attacker will start transmitting
simultaneously with the victim and it
will corrupt some of the voltage samples
that are being transmitted by the victim
so when it actually corrupts some of the
samples that are being corrupted by that
are being transmitted by the victim it
will lead to a bimodal distribution
which means that now you there are two
means one is corresponding to the benign
samples and the other one is the
superimposed samples which are called
corrupted samples here so since the
superimposed samples will have a higher
voltage values because of the
superposition you will see a bimodal
distribution when you see the voltage
characteristics of the victim now in the
training phase the width is now learning
from this bimodal distribution okay so
what is the next step then so now in the
test phase which is the operation phase
of the width what we will do is now the
accomplice and the attacker did start
transmitting together so the message
that is being forged it now contains the
finger fingerprint or the voltage
samples corresponding to this attacker
plus accomplished now again you see that
because there are two issues
transmitting together and they are
superimposing their voltage samples you
will again see a bimodal distribution
which means that so in the training
phase we have tricked the Wits to
consider any bimodal distribution as the
victim and therefore in the test phase
if it the witzy
a bimodal distribution it will classify
it as coming from the victim and
therefore the accomplice Plus which
attacker is classified as coming from
the victim and therefore we have
successfully bypassed the Wiis detection
mechanism now you will notice that in
order to do this in order to do this
simultaneous transmission there are some
challenges so the first challenge is to
do time synchronization which means that
you the attacker should be able to
transmit at the same time as the victim
and in order to do that what we do is we
track the victims periodic transmission
so the victim the all the ECU's on the
canvas including the victim they
transmit messages periodically on the
bus and therefore if we could carefully
track these messages we will be able to
ensure that the attacker could transmit
simultaneously with the victim and then
the second challenge was to superimpose
some of the voltage samples and for that
you need to guess what would be the
payload in the victims message so here
that we call as payload synchronization
so we notice that on the canvas these
miss the messages on the canvas they
have some counters they have some
multivalued numbers which could be
easily guessed and they also have some
sensor data which do not change for a
very long time so for instance some many
of the things so the status saw of the
gear the status of the door they do not
change for a very long time unless you
make and unless the user or the driver
makes some action on the on those things
so therefore we found that it is able to
predict the payload of the next message
by seeing that current message of the
victim and therefore we were able to do
this payload synchronization as well so
in order to do this payload
synchronization we came up with this
idea of predicting these payloads and we
found that we could do this prediction
with very
high accuracy so in this curve what I am
showing is that so let me just get into
the specific example so this curve shows
the cumulative number of messages in
which you could predict certain number
of whites of from the victims message so
here you could on the y-axis we have the
number of messages and on the x-axis you
have the number of bytes so you could
see that when the total so the byte 0
means the total number of messages that
an ECU transmits so on the so for the
red curve you see that the out of 50
messages which you could see on a
particular vehicle there were 45
messages where we could easily predict
at least first 2 bytes of the data and
therefore an attacker could easily
transmit simultaneously with those first
two bytes and corrupt the voltage
samples of the victim okay
okay so now this is the final result
that we have so we actually conducted
our attack do it on a test bed
consisting of these electronic units
which were emulated using Arduino boards
and then we also conducted attacks on to
real vehicles one was Impala and the
other one was gross and we achieved a
very high success rate which is on the
y-axis on this curve and on the x-axis
we have the length of the predictable
payload prefix so which means that if we
were able to corrupt more samples in the
victims message we were able to achieve
higher attack success rate so if we were
not able to corrupt anything in the
victims message that access rate attack
success was very very low so at max we
were able to achieve at more than 80
percent success rate even in vehicles
and an 80 percent success rate is good
enough for a very for a masker attack on
a cyber physical system ok so now I
would like to present an attack demo or
which we created by a
in a real vehicle so in this attack our
goal is to impersonate the RPM meter
while evading the width so the first
what we did was we did some reverse
engineering to find out what messages
correspond to the engine rpm so here you
see that the engine rpm is 700
evolutions per minute now
these widths algorithms they were
implemented in our laptop and we
collected the voltage samples through
the oscilloscope that you see here so in
the first stage which is the training
stage you see that nothing is changing
we are corrupting the voltage values of
the victim but the width is learning
from those corrupted values and nothing
is you do not see any change here but
now when the next attack phase starts
you see that the RPM raises to 7,000
revolutions per minute
you could never reach that value in
these cars if you are right if you are
driving a Formula One car profitably you
might reach that number but in a real
car you will never do that so what we
are doing is we are impersonating the
engine and sending these fake messages
force messages to the this RPM meter and
the RPM meter is accepting those values
and then we notice that tab the width
does not raise any alarm because we were
able to do this successfully able to do
this adversarial machine learning
approach of training set poisoning okay
so that is the end of this first part I
would be happy to take some questions
here yes
remote attack surface I saw that for the
wireless attack it involved targeting
the like the single chip modem like the
road link modems yes would there be a
way to try to mitigate a wireless attack
surface by making that protocol
authenticated
to try to reduce that yeah so definitely
if you enable authentication you should
be able to do you should be able to
reduce the attack surfaces but the
argument here is that you will always
have some bugs in Bluetooth you will
always have some bugs in cellular
protocol we always see researchers
coming up with these bugs and once you
have these bugs no matter what type of
authentication you have in these
vehicles an attacker could always find a
way to get into the vehicle testing
framework so what I want to ask you to
so basically this clear it's pirates so
in the vehicles so typically especially
your target odd vehicle how many issue
there are in so in a Tesla you might see
around 200 so each component of your
vehicle is these days now being
controlled by one electronic control
unit okay in an old vehicle you would
see a dozen electronic control unit so
the vehicle on which we are working it
has around a dozen electronic control
units in the 2011 Impala then probably I
just said so some of those and you see
some of the issue components may have a
some controller logic like a PID
controller whatever how many control
logics are there probably so these are
not very complex electronic units so
they have they have usually one MCU and
then that MCU has one electron the
architecture of that MCU is very very
simple so probably I would say so they
have so one MC you can have multiple
chips
and one of those chips could be a can
controller which enables that ends you
to communicate with this with other MC
used through this can bus so yes I guess
that is the overall architecture of an
electronic control unit that you see in
a vehicle know then just say my question
is uh how many CID contours are there
probably out of that although can was I
would not be able to tell you the exact
number but there should not be many PID
controllers innovator I have a question
so once we find there is a vulnerability
in the ECU so what's the possible
options to fix this or they are totally
cannot be fixed now you can always do a
firmware update so that is what Jeep did
it we call the vehicle so that means we
need to use some devices to connector
that the car and do the update for these
vehicles so now people are coming up
with this idea of over-the-air update so
they could actually update the funder of
an ECU over-the-air so there is not need
to actually recall all the vehicles and
then fix the 1rw
okay thanks okay okay so now that you
know that authentication is very
important before getting access to a
vehicle now let's see an adversarial
model adversity model in which the
attacker is actually trying to get into
the vehicle so the victim is now the
onboard unit and the attacker is trying
to get into this onboard unit so as we
just discussed earlier what we need is
an authentication protocol here which
prevent
this adversary to get into the vehicle
okay so now let us first talk about the
need for these connected vehicles so I
would like to highlight the need for
these connected vehicles through this
video which does not have yes we don't
have a way to hear this but yeah let me
just stop it so no it's fine I could
just tell them it is fine it is alright
yeah no that is fine so this so this in
this tesla vehicle it actually rammed
into a police car which was stopped in
the middle of a road so what happened
was the tesla vehicle did not going at
60 miles per hour
did not expect any vehicle to be stopped
in the middle of a road and when it
actually noticed a vehicle although it
tried to brake but it could not break
and it went directly into that vehicle
and causing an accident so now what what
what was wrong in this scenario the
issue was that these sensors that you
have on a vehicle they have limitations
so for instance the camera could only
see for a particular distance and in fog
probably the camera will not be able to
see anything so these onboard sensors
have limitations and therefore we need
the concept of these connected vehicles
so that these vehicles will talk to each
other over a wireless medium and tell
the status till their status to other
vehicles so for instance in this case
the police car would have broadcasted
its information that it is stopped in
the middle of a road and if this Tesla
vehicle would have received that
information
one kilometer when it was one kilometer
away from the vehicle it would have made
a better choice so now in order to
enable this idea of connected vehicles
the Society of Automotive Engineers ASCE
it has defined a set of basic safety
messages now these basic safety messages
include the broadcasting information
about location speed acceleration in
some cases you also we needed the
vehicle will be needed to broadcast this
forward collision warning intersection
movement Assist so now these so
particularly these location speed and
acceleration messages they are
transmitted periodically over there so
one of the standard value of that period
is 100 milliseconds ok so now let's see
what what properties we need for this
connected vehicles idea to be secure so
the first security property is that we
need to validate those safety messages
so if vehicle is receiving those safety
messages about the location about the
speed of another vehicle it should be
able to authenticate those messages and
therefore authenticity is the criteria
here now we also need to provide privacy
to the sender's
so these senders are actually
broadcasting their private information
about their location over there so it is
very important for any mechanism to
ensure that this private information
about the location cannot be exploited
by an adversary to track the movement of
that driver also the information about
speed and acceleration they could be
utilized to profile or fingerprint a
driver so the driver does it is very
important that we provide this privacy
to the driver and therefore the security
property that we want here is privacy
and then in a regular environment we
also need this
property of revocability because you may
have many vehicles malfunctioning
vehicles and there and you will need
them to not come on the road and
therefore you want to suspend the
license of those vehicles and therefore
we need this third property of revoke
ability but all these the three
components can be provided by this
mechanism called a privacy preserving or
anonymous authentication and one nice
way to do it is called group signatures
so here I would give you a very
high-level overview of group signatures
which was proposed by the researcher at
a Stanford named dr. Dan boney so he is
a cryptographer who has developed many
different types of signature schemes
among them is the group signature scheme
which actually provides privacy
preserving authentication so in this
environment there are three entities the
first is called the group manager and as
the name suggests it is responsible for
generating the group public key now what
is the need for generating this group
public key so that I as the name
suggests the group signatures the
anonymity here is in terms of the group
which means that every sender will
broadcast information saying that I am
part of a particular group and the
receivers will verify that whether this
signer is part of a particular group or
not but the signers will never embed
their own information or their own
identity in the signatures so therefore
the larger the group the signers privacy
will be higher so the very very fire
will not be able to know who is
transmitting it will only be able to
know that someone from the group is
transmitting the message okay so the
group manager task is to generate is to
set up the group by generating the group
public key and then it will also assign
secret keys to these signers then it is
also responsible for publishing a
revocation list which will contain the
information about those whose licenses
has been suspended
now the signers task is very simple it
has to just generate an anonymous
signature of the over the message that
it wants to broadcast and then the
verifiers has verifiers has to do two
things first is to ensure that the
signature is authentic so the message
that it is receiving is authentic is
determined based on the authenticity of
the signature and therefore the verifier
has to verify that and then the second
task that the verifier has to do is to
check the relocation status of the
signer which means that the signer is
not revoked okay now let's look at the
scale of the network that we are
actually considering here so we and the
and the functions that we are employing
in these group signatures so in this
group signature scheme one fundamental
function was called a bilinear map
operation and we ran that operation on
an Intel i7 processor based a computer
and found that it took two milliseconds
to run that by linear operation by
linear map operation this implies that
the the the verifier could only run 500
operations per second now the dilemma of
the verifier is that the verifier does
not know the identity of the signer and
the revocation list does not contain the
identity of the signers it actually
contains the secret keys that were
allotted to those signers and therefore
when the verifier receives a message it
has to look to each entry in the
revocation lists see if that secret key
which is in the revocation list has been
utilized to generate that signature or
not and then move to the next entry in
the revocation list which means that the
computation cost of the verifier is
actually linear in terms of the size of
the deviation list
okay so now you could see that a
verifier could only run these 500
operations so potentially the verifier
could only check a revocation list of
500 entries now let's consider let's see
the scale of this network so now we
consider a simple scenario where you
have a road with three lanes and tuve
highway and you consider one vehicle and
in each 50 meters so the distance
between two vehicles is 50 meters in
each lane and we consider this typical
communication range of 1 kilometer and
we again consider the typical
periodicity of 100 millisecond for the
location and the other information that
each signer is broadcasting so this
translates into 2400 vehicle to
everything communication messages per
second so v2x messages per second okay
and now let's see the number of revoked
vehicles so in u.s. there are around 11
million revoked licenses currently now
if we reduced that number to a vehicle
so and we sold the vehicles will be
malfunctioning
but that malfunctioning could come from
the malfunctioning of the components of
the vehicle or that malfunctioning could
also come from the malfunctioning of the
drivers and therefore we should consider
a conservative number so the
conservative number that I consider here
is a thousand revoked signers now this
means that you need to run that
operation of wiling your map 2400 into
thousand times now you cannot bridge
this gap between the capability and the
requirement by using simple techniques
which which you could employ to do
parallelization or hardware acceleration
and therefore it is imperative that we
develop a novel mechanism to address
this challenge ok so what we proposed
was that rather than verifying the
revocation status of
deterministically how about we verify
the relocation status probabilistically
so now you could think of the analogy
with the Milan rabban primality testing
algorithm where the Prime ality of a
very large number if you want to
determine it deterministically it is
very very computationally expensive but
if you want to just use the
probabilistic algorithm proposed by
Miller and Ravan it is very very
efficient although that efficient
algorithm will not give you 100%
accurate result but still almost all
systems in the current world they
utilize this probabilistic algorithm
called the mirror reliable primality
testing algorithm ok so our idea was to
have this group signatures with
probabilistically vocation so the first
contribution was that we come up with
this idea of alias tokens which these
signers could embed in their signatures
so these signers cannot reveal their
identity in the signatures but what we
wanted to ensure that these signers
reveal something in their signature and
that we call a Lea's token so now these
alias tokens are given to these signers
by the group manager and these signers
now reveal this alias token one aleus
token any signature okay now the second
contribution is the signal processing
part where we check this we will utilize
this alias token that has been embedded
as part of the signature and come up
with a probabilistic revocation check
mechanism so now when the group manager
revokes a signer
it actually revokes these alias tokens
and now the verifier actually checks the
revocation status of these alias tokens
in order to check the revocation status
of the signer okay now let's go into the
details of these contributions so for
this embedded alias token so wha
what we did was we utilized the same
fundamental operation which was called
the bilinear map operation I will not go
into the details of the function but you
could see that it is a very simple
operation so that valanor map operation
ii when conducted on two parameters you
raise to the power a and V raised to the
power B it it is equal to the operation
when it is implied on those two
parameters U V raise to the power a B so
this bilinear map operation is the
fundamental operation which provides
privacy to these signature algorithms
okay so what these three things three
entities in our signature scheme do so
the first step is to generate the group
secret key which is the same here now
the second step is to generate these
alias tokens so the group manager
generates these alias tokens and assigns
them to the signers but the most
important thing to do here is to
generate the signer secret key and now
you see that here in this third step of
the group manager the signer secret key
is generated using all the alias tokens
that has been assigned to the signer so
the finest secret key is now related to
the all of these alias token now what
the signer
does is seiner generates these other
parameters some parameter B and some
parameter C but the important point to
note here is that the parameter B is
generated by all the alias tokens that
it has and the parameter C is generated
by all earliest occurs except the alias
token which it wants to reveal into
signature now when it generates a
signature it sends the information or
the 0 so what we call is zero knowledge
proof of knowledge of these three
parameters ABC and it reveals this alias
token X I as well and this verifier now
checks whether the signer has a valid
secret key so it runs the same bilinear
operation which is called e or and it
checks if the
just a and we satisfy a particular
equality or not and then again this
Elias token is so that now the now the
verifier ensures that this Elias token
is actually cryptographically linked to
the signature or not so it again uses
the same bilinear map operation to check
for this linkage of the Elias token with
the signature scheme okay now the second
aspect how we utilize these Elias tokens
to actually do the revocation check
mechanism so in thing is so for this we
utilized the very popular technique
which is utilized in 3G communication so
it was in the in 3d communication what
happened was that the users were allowed
to transmit or at the same time and at
the same frequency but when these all
these different senders transmitted at
the same time at the same frequency it
is difficult for the receivers to decode
those signals so this concept of
spreading codes was developed where
these goods are utilized by these so
different codes are utilized by
different senders and they code their
signal using these different spreading
codes and when a particular receiver is
interested in a particular transmitter
it will use the same spreading code and
then it will be able to extract that
message from the overlapped signal and
it will be able to know what the sender
was transmitting over there
although the sender is actually sharing
the same spectrum and the same time with
other senders as well so if you use the
same spreading code if the sender uses
the same spreading code and the receiver
uses the same spreading code they could
have this communication of information
okay but if they use different spreading
codes they will not be able to know what
they have what the sender has sent and
they will also not be able to know
anything about that information so that
there is a privacy component there as
well ok so what we did here so what we
did was we actually took these alias
tokens and map did to stress
reading codes and then when the revoke
when the group manager has to revoke
these different signers by revoking
their alias tokens we revoke these
spreading codes corresponding to those
alias tokens and the way we revoke this
is to generate a revocation code so
rather than generating a revocation list
now we generate a revocation code which
is actually a sum of all these
revocation codes so now you see that the
analogy of sharing the same time and the
same frequency using their spreading
code comes here that now you have what
you have done is you have generated one
code which is called any vocation code
here by summing up all these spreading
codes which were revoked and now when
this when a verifier has to actually
check the revocation status of the
signer by looking at an alias token so
that what the verifier can do is the
verifier could map that and he has token
to a spreading code which is which we
call here as Elias code and then it
could compute a correlation with the
revocation code and this correlation
value will lie between 0 & 1 so the
basic thing here is that if the
correlation is above a threshold which
means that the Elias code was encoded in
the revocation code which implies that
the signer was revoked and if the value
is lower than that threshold implies
that the signer was not revoked so this
is so this mechanism ensures that you
are actually using a probabilistic
mechanism to decide on the revocation
status of a signer okay so using this
probabilistic mechanism we were able to
significantly reduce the computational
cost of the group signature mechanism so
here you see the blue curve which is the
curve for our group signatures with
probabilistically vocation and the red
and the green curves are from the prior
art and we
see that we were able to significantly
reduce this computational cost and make
our scheme implementable in a standard
vehicle to infrastructure communication
network so you on the x-axis we have the
number of revoked private keys and you
see that even if the number of revoked
private keys reaches some number like
10,000 on the y axis we have the
computational overhead in milliseconds
so you are still less than 100
millisecond so the verifier would take
even less than 100 milliseconds to
verify each of those messages and I will
remind you that 100 milliseconds is the
time when you receive a message so it is
very important that you should be able
to verify a message within hundred
millisecond okay so I would just
conclude there here I already talked
about the two components of this
connected autonomous vehicle in the
first part I talked about this attack do
it which evaded the state-of-the-art
fingerprinting technique that is
employed by the intrusion detection
system and the second part I you till
eyes the this idea of probabilistic
relieve occasion to come up with this
scalable privacy-preserving
authentication mechanism for the v2x
communication yes so the goal here is to
actually come up with an in to end
authentication mechanism and my even my
current research directions are in to
enable this smart and secure
transmission by transportation by
enabling this into end authentication
that is the end of my talk and I will be
happy to take more questions yes
yeah so how's the threshold is
determined where vacation
yeah so we ran some simulations of how
many number of how many number of
revoked signers if you have and you
generate a revocation code and you do
the same mechanism of setting up the
threshold and detecting the revocation
status of the vehicle so we found that
in order to achieve so these are all
mechanisms to ensure that you achieve a
particular false alarm rate and a
particular detection rate in that system
so we found that if you have if you
determine a particular false alarm rate
you could find the threshold and then
you could set that threshold in your
scheme so you will have two so we first
start with the particular false alarm
rate and from there we determine the
threshold value you mentioned that the
speaker updates their formula by using
the Obata air channel yeah so I'm
curious about the weather when they
conduct about for my update they
utilized any authentication one formula
signing message or not so I think they
do utilize it so so at least I know that
Tesla utilizes this over there update
mechanisms and they do utilize the
authentication while doing that
[Applause]
you