all right so let's get it started
it's my pleasure to introduce Douglas
Rapp CISM is a cybersecurity catalyst
throughout heath Korea you will find
he's squarely at the center of countless
firsts this includes writing the first
state-level cyber incident response plan
leading the critique e^x national
exercise establishing the region 5 cyber
protection team and establishing
Indiana's first cyber working group
which leader involved into both the
Indiana cybersecurity execute executed X
you executed Council and the cyber
leadership Alliance Dawg has served as
the adviser and authored Indiana's
cybersecurity economic development plan
he has started skilled and page
cybersecurity businesses and serve as a
consultant and intrapreneur in residence
for Purdue University his most recent
accomplishment accomplishment was
creating a statewide emergency security
workforce development program and raised
three million dollars in commitments to
student financial assistance dog is a
published author international speaker
and has testified before Congress on
cyber security workforce development it
decorated combat veteran his greatest
accomplishment is having raised two
amazing children and having been trusted
with America's sons and daughters with
further ado let's welcome Tom thanks
Dave well thanks so I appreciate all of
you coming out tonight because I it's
4:30 in the afternoon which means that
I'm probably standing between you and
food and/or beer so and you're very very
fortunate so you're very fortunate
because this is the first time giving
this presentation the next time this
presentation will be given will be in
Rwanda so here at the end next month so
you are the guinea pigs
so what you also have the
you also have the dubious honor of being
here for the unveiling of a new hallmark
term which I'll get into I'll point it
out and you'll be able to say I remember
when I heard that for the first time so
security ethics in the end of the world
as we know it it's a pretty ominous
title how many of you actually read the
little summary what we were going to
talk about tonight
so okay all right one that's great so we
live in a digital economy and that's
certainly no surprise to anybody that's
here and when we think about what a
digital economy really is we have to
look at how we interact economically
with other cultures with the rest of the
world many people have claimed the data
is currency and there is some truth to
that what the analogies that they use
are a little bit outdated we've heard
data as equivalent to black gold to oil
but the fact of the matter is is once
oil is used it's gone it is a finite
it's a finite substance land we've heard
it compared to land in the economic in
the economic sense however again once
land is built upon once that yet land is
utilized it can't be reutilized
until whatever is built on top of it is
torn down so when you look at data data
as currency data as something of value
has an exponential factor to it and that
is that data can be used multiple times
and it can be used in infinite numbers
of ways that provide value so as we
enter the digital economy and the
digital economy is really a global
digital ecosystem where data is gathered
organized and exchanged by network
vendors for the purpose of deriving
value from the accumulated information
when we
get it we look at look at the market
share in 2015 one hundred and twenty two
billion dollars in data analytics and
the exportation of buying and selling of
data the projected market share for 2022
is two hundred and seventy four billion
dollars around the world so you can see
some of the quotes they're the most
valuable valuable commodity of the
digital age the most valuable resource
in the world in an age where stock
traders are locating their offices as
close to the New York Stock Exchange as
possible so that they can have a
fragment of a second advantage in
transmitting data to make a trade
you can really start to understand the
value of data so data as currency when
we look at the new world as we
transition and understand the value of
data there are four factors that have
been described by Harvard as factors
that can define data wealth within
countries so we look at volume the
absolute amount of broadband consumed by
a country and in doing this research the
only the numbers that they were able to
analyze really had to do with broadband
consumption and utilization so it's it's
impossible to track the transition of
data back and forth around the world and
really quantify it so when you look at
how do you say a country is data rich or
has the potential to be data rich so you
look at volume you look at usage the
number of active users that are on the
internet you look at accessibility so
how how easy is it to get a hold of that
data and you look at complexity so what
level of complexity can you perform with
that digital activity
and if you look at this this slide put
together by Harvard you can see that
United States's is way out front so when
we look at companies like Indonesia or
China or Russia and we put them in the
context of these four criteria that
we've we've defined volume some of those
countries you can see have huge volumes
of data but they limit accessibility so
they limit accessibility and usage for
individuals so not being one that wants
to pick a fight with Harvard but I'm
going to you and that is that I argue we
cannot look at wealth in the context of
nations anymore in a digital economy
what we're seeing rise out of a digital
economy is not what's what's important
is not necessarily and completely the
wealth of nations but what we're seeing
is a rise of what I call data barons
just like the old robber barons of the
Industrial Revolution who accumulated
massive quantities of wealth and drove
innovation and drove progress what's
arising right now what I argue is what's
arising right now is really about seven
companies around the world that have in
essence these four criteria and I'll
explain a little bit that these four
criteria which make them and will make
them more powerful than the government's
and the confines of our national
boundaries so when you look at these
data Baron's
you look at these companies that exist
out there and they accumulate the wealth
and access to the data who's collecting
our data out there alright so who is
actually looking who has the means to go
out and collect all that data that
exists out there so in 2015 the majority
of the data that was collected in the
world had been collected in the last two
years that's grown exponentially since
2015 so as we look at the seven major
players in the ecosystem you really come
up with two two major countries where
those companies exist but again I make
the argument that we are transitioning
from the power of nations to the power
of these companies as these companies
continue to grow their capability to not
only collect data but also to take that
data and the algorithmics and invest in
things like m LDL and AI and are using
that data to generate wealth for their
own individual companies or their own
self-interests yes deep learning and
artificial intelligence so when we look
at these if you look at government's
particularly our form of government our
government is not in the business of
selling data it's in the business of
data that is freely accessible to
everyone we live in a democracy so when
we look at other forms of government
look at China which is a fundamental
difference all right in the United
States we Revere innovation Silicon
Valley is all about what's the next
great thing what's the next great
invention that's coming out there and
god forbid you take somebody else's
concept and improve upon it you're
asking for a lawsuit in an amazingly
litigious society but the fundamental
difference with the entrepreneurship
culture in places like China is the fact
that anything that is if you can take
something to make it better if you can
take your adversaries product and make
it better that's acceptable that's
acceptable and the difference as we look
at the two major players in in data
particularly in use what's with AI which
is the evolution of how we utilize data
is that while we are concentrating on
the next great innovation nations like
China Indonesia Russia and others are
taking that data and creating massive
quantities of practitioners in the
application of those technologies and
algorithms so let's take a just there's
two basic ways to really quantify
artificial intelligence I'm gonna use
the example that closely really mimics
comparison to the human brain to humans
so these types of AI you know reactive
AI has been around for a while
it's basically reacting to two input
limited memory which is capable of
capable of learning from repeated
processes of historical data and using
historical data to make decisions those
two exist
and the good news is is only those two
really exist right now the theory of
mind where AI is used to better
understand entities by being able to
determine what their needs are their
emotions their beliefs and thought
processes that's being worked on right
now emotional AI is
it's in the works people are doing it
what exists only in theory right now is
self-awareness so and I don't think I
have to explain to you what you know
what self-awareness is so keeping that
in mind if you read the synopsis of what
I was going to talk about or what I'm
talking about tonight I talked about
rogue ai's so mmm and this all what I've
been talking about it's really kind of a
prelude to what we're going to get into
right now so a couple years ago
Amazon decided that they were going to
take an AI tool which they built and
they were going to put it in Ravello
revolutionize their human resources what
ended up happening is you can see by the
headline is the algorithm that AI came
back and said don't hire females so now
why is that so what does it take to have
a really good AI anybody know what do
you have to have in order to develop
artificial intelligence training data
lots of data massive quantities of data
massive quantities of data so now
remember we're talking about data as
currency all of these things if we can
if we gain a competitive advantage
whether in business or in medical
processes or in banking by the
implementation of AI then in order to
lead in that field you have to have
massive quantities of data so which
brings up some really interesting
questions considering data and privacy
right now is is a huge issue and
particularly in the West not so much in
the East so Amazon decided we're going
to take AI and we're gonna we're going
to use it to hire the absolute best
candidates for our company so why do you
think that the AI came back and said
don't hire women the reason was as the
data set was flawed it wasn't actually
it wasn't flawed the data set was an
accurate representation a
historically what had been done so the
technology sector historically has been
dominated by men so the data set that
was used to program the AI reflected
that so that brings up a very
interesting ethical question as we look
towards the development of AI and as we
gather and process data for applications
if our datasets are skewed like that
should we be altering those datasets to
reflect the values that we aspire to
versus what has historically happened so
if you answer yes to that question then
the next question is who gets to do that
is it Amazon it's at Facebook is it
Alibaba
so Huawei so very very complex and very
interesting ethical questions so we move
further down this path of ethics and
data and security and I ask you to look
at three different definitions that I've
put up here so notice the similarities
in what they are some could argue that
they are a gradation of the same scale
so advertising is about making people
aware of something brainwashing if you
look at bullet point two is persuasion
by propaganda or salesmanship all right
and the big buzzword of one of the big
buzz words of the day social engineering
is the use of centralized planning in an
attempt to manage
change and regulate the future
development and behavior of a society so
I ask you to consider the techniques at
which those three things are employed in
modern society and where we're headed
with those so as anybody's seen the
great hack on Netflix
okay little dramatized but definitely
drives a point home
Cambridge analytical has anybody really
thought about what Cambridge analytic
could did and really you heard a little
bit about it during the elections and
things like that but when you take a
look at what Cambridge analytic actually
did they collected over 5,000 data
points on every undecided voter in the
United States of America and created
individual advertising plans for those
folks for those people so now I ask you
reflect back on that last slide on those
three definitions was that advertising
was it brainwashing was it social
engineering where do those definitions
begin and end
so again other very important questions
that influence ethics in a digital world
that's being transformed so social
engineering by another definition is the
application of social science to to
individuals to populations so the more
we learn about what influences society
and what people react to whether it's at
the basic level you know maslov's
hierarchy of needs to the way that
individuals interact to the way that
groups interact the way that nations
interact the application and
understanding of how people predictably
will behave when in
reduced with information companies like
Cambridge analytical in others Bell
pottinger there's another organization
practice the theories of social
engineering on whole nations all right
they did it in Africa to a massive scale
and to some extent it's still going on
today
Cambridge analytical used elections in
Africa as the test case for what
happened in the EU with brexit if you
didn't know that and with the last
presidential elections in the United
States they were confident in their
ability to accomplish what our last
president wanted during his campaign
because they had already done it using
Africa as a test case now they're not
the only ones
so they got caught and they were really
good at it as we speak
now countries like Ethiopia Nigeria are
using spyware to influence dissidents in
our own countries to also influence
people within their own boundaries on
how they should vote Bell Pottinger
actually had to formally a pileup
pologize
because they stirred up so much racial
hostility on the grounds of fabricated
in justices and inequalities they
actually had to come out and publicly
apologize in South Africa for what they
had done so the African National
Congress hired hacking teams RCS to do
the same thing
and while doing research for this speak
a company that I routinely do business
with sold spyware to Ethiopia or that
was used for some of the same dubious
efforts so we have to begin to ask these
questions is it the responsibility of
the company or individual that creates
the product is it their responsibilities
should they be held liable what is their
ethical responsibility or is it how that
tool is used so if you look at business
ethics it is the responsibility of a
business leader to maximize the profits
for their shareholders by that
justification there's no there's there's
there's not a standard for fairness
there's no decent standard for fairness
out there I mean the last administration
had to create a consumer fairness
division you know because of the way
that companies were interacting with
with the public so you have to ask
yourself ethically who's responsible for
that is it the person or people or
organization utilizing the spyware or is
it the company that makes it so very
interesting yes it's gonna bring up that
you know we did have an answer to that
years ago in South Africa and it was
called divestiture that it was the
responsibility of the company owners to
say we're not going to own a company
that does these things and guess what
that affects the return to the
shareholders and then the CEOs in their
duty to the shareholders have to respond
sure so you know I would say that there
is probably a bit of a there's a
difference between a Cambridge
analytical and in the company that made
the spyware in the
fact that Cambridge analytic was all
about the application and the intent the
for the use of the products and
analytics that it was doing whereas you
could you know ethically you can argue
you know you it's not the gun owner you
know or it's not the gun it's the gun
owner it's the intent of the gun owner
and even to a certain extent our
judicial system is as consideration for
great consideration for intent so so
that brings I mean it's a very I mean
this is exactly I'm talking about it's a
very interesting complex organ achill
question so for sure but you know
Cambridge analytical Bell Pottinger both
went out of business when it was
discovered what they were doing so
however had they not gotten caught my
question I mean look what they already
did before they they got caught so did
they really even get caught were they
doing something that was illegal were
they doing something that was immoral or
unethical you know those are the
questions we have to ask you know so but
that's a that's a great court a great
point so in my in my in my little
write-up for this I talked about also
about you know a fantasy world where
millions of cameras track track eeeh and
using predictive analytics they
determine whether or not you're going to
say something bad against the government
and the facial recognition software
picks you out of a crowd the storm
troopers reach down into the grout crowd
and grab you and then they take you away
to a reprogramming camp so sounds pretty
fantastic doesn't it so welcome to China
so as we speak the Muslim minority in
the north part of China the Chinese
government is using facial recognition
and predictive analysis and some of the
criteria that was recently linked on how
they're determining whether or not
somebody is a dissident is as vague as
they had a beard or once had a beard I
mean this are real documents that are
that are you can go and look at the
criteria that they're using to select
people so they're doing at some level
predictive analysis on who might cause
social unrest now understand that while
we see this as potentially a crime
against humanity against free will and
democracy you have to understand the
cultural mindset you know not everybody
thinks like we do I know it's a crazy
concept all right you know but not
everybody thinks like the West
particularly like the United States the
United States was a country that was
founded the city on the hill right we're
supposed to be the great utopia for all
the religious organizations that got
kicked out every decent country in
Europe so they were gonna come here and
build this shining city on a hill all
right but in some cultures and it's not
right wrong or indifferent necessarily
but in some cultures social stability is
more important than individual rights so
right now as I said the Muslim minority
in northern China is being picked up
they're being there's a huge massive
intelligence collection data collection
effort both a physical one with agents
operating within the populations and the
utilization of AI m and M L and D L in
determining who the people are who are
likely to become dissidents as I said
facial recognition software millions and
millions and millions of cameras
all connected being able to identify
those people and they're taken away to
camps to be reprogrammed and this is an
actual satellite photo of one of those
camps so they exist
the official message on this from the
Chinese government and I feel like I'm
don't feel like I'm picking on the
Chinese so much but right now they're
you know they are the the other AI world
power so but the official the official
line from the Chinese government is that
they are you know teaching them how to
better integrate was to integrate with
society but the fact of the matter is is
you have to ask yourself how does this
different from other regimes that we've
seen try and accomplish this with more
brutal or less sophisticated methods
like we saw in Cambodia and Vietnam and
in other places even in Russia so so
this fantastical environment you know
where where you've got Tom Cruise
running around trying to prevent crimes
before they happen to some extent it's
it's here it's here it's level to AI but
it's here so the good news is if you go
back to that that that classification
for AI is we're still only at level 2
which means right now is the time that
we need to ask ourselves these
incredibly hard questions about ethics
and how we want our data to be utilized
and how we want our algorithms to
represent whatever values we choose so
if this scares you and you think well
hey you know at least we're not doing
that in the US all right anybody ever
heard of be linked
okay
so be link is the city of Indianapolis
that's partnered with businesses and
residents all through Marion County who
can voluntarily connect to the police
connect their security cameras to the
police intelligence center so not quite
a nation sponsored effort to subjugate a
whole culture or society or religion but
what I'm telling you is is that if we if
we don't address the human ethical
aspect of this it's not a leap too far
that this technology that we're using on
our own is utilized for a nefarious
purpose right now this system is being
used to solve crime you know and it's
within the police department in
Indianapolis they do predictive analysis
on crime they absolutely do but my point
to this is is it's not just China it's
here - it's here - and we have not only
a responsibility but an obligation to
inform the people that control this
technology of what values that we want
for them to represent as a society we
have to determine that so that brings up
a really interesting question I've
talked a lot about technology and the
use of data and how people are using it
and and it's a tool good or is it bad is
that the way it's used is it not the way
it's used and we've been talking about
ethics for a long long time as as a race
as a human race so you can see Immanuel
Kant deciding whether or not one's
actions are moral it should be
considered what the universal benefit is
so by Kant's theory if I were to steal I
have to ask myself if I want to
determine whether or not it's more
or ethical I have to ask myself if
everybody's told would that be a good
thing or a bad thing
and that's how Khan said we should
determine what our ethics are so Karl
Marx and Friedrich Engels they believe
that you can't have a universal code of
ethics and and again that's another
question as nations nations use to
decide what their ethics and values are
but as we look in a digital economy and
we look in a digital world those
boundaries mean less and less they mean
less you know you can experience the the
life of somebody in Syria through
Twitter to a great extent things that we
could never access before that
one-to-one human connection and and
transmitting of experience and sharing
of experience now doesn't recognize any
borders nobody can control that anymore
so we look at things we have to start
looking at things from what what is
Universal what are the universal values
that we all have to subscribe to because
as as all this data comes together and
all these algorithms come together and
right now AI level 2 is being used
primarily in business and medical and
finance and a few verticals all right
and believe me we're we're a long way
from self-actualization we're a long way
from that long long long way but it's
coming it's coming
so so again the point is we need to
start looking at universal values but
Karl Marx and Frederick Engels they said
there can't be any universal values
because ethics and values are dependent
upon the economic situation of the
nation that it's in there's a certain
amount of relativity that goes along
with that what is now flawed in that
theory again as we look at what is the
importance of nations and borders so we
are experiencing cultural one-to-one
human contact on a massive scale through
the revolution of data and
technology right now so I challenged
this theory in that it may have been
accurate to some extent at one time but
it's less and less accurate now so as we
work towards convergence we are less and
I may get I was an army for a long long
time so this is this is not a betrayal
of our nation but it's less and less
important on an individual level whether
or not we're Americans or Saudis or
Chinese or Panamanian it's less and less
important so Max Steiner the next
evolution you know the common good is
only an illusion because the only ethics
that are benefits are the ones that
benefit the self so if you go to the
fact that we are all born naked alone
and we all die alone his argument is is
that you know ethics we can justify
anything that becomes self-serving so
and then Frederick Nietzsche everybody's
phrase the favorite crazy person thought
that everything that the powerful do is
is moral so I don't know where you got
that but I don't know where you got a
lot of us is theories I'm sure there's
something to it I just find it to be
ridiculous so we look at the data
revolution we look at the security of
ourselves or personal information the
way that we live democracy freedom think
about think about democracy and social
engineering there's something if you
want to chew on it for a while you know
are the choices you make really your
choices anymore when we're applying
social science theory to marketing so
one could argue that those X amount of
votes
in the last election you know did they
really vote the way that they wanted to
or did we cross that social engineering
brainwashing advertising boundary so
there's another theory of moral
development and I ask you to give some
consideration to this as we evolve as a
as humankind as as a race as the human
race I ask you to keep this in mind can
we evolve to a level of individual
ethical standards that in an age where
individuals can access power and
knowledge at massive scales
all right you no longer have to come to
Purdue University to be the world's best
hacker all right now I'm not I'm not
saying don't go to Purdue University but
my point is is that in the 80s we had a
saying information wants to be free
we are very idealistic and when the
universities and the government owned
the internet we would break into the
Internet in order to gain access to
knowledge and what we thought was that
access to knowledge will allow people to
raise themselves up out of their
condition just like the printing press
and the Gutenberg Bible you know we
believe that the one thing we didn't
take into account was that very very
very basic ethical question and that is
it's not knowledged it's inherently good
or evil it's how you use it it's the
application of that knowledge that's
inherently good or evil so with
individual access to massive quantities
of data and with the convergence of all
of this data and the refinement of
algorithmics and the development of AI
and all these things you know we have to
ask ourselves do we need to evolve
ethically as humans when we have the
responsibility of having so much
knowledge and power at our fingertips so
it's a huge question and it's it's a
very complex area and to be honest I
haven't seen a lot of people looking at
it
there is a lot of questions about ethics
within certain verticals and certain
subjects in certain areas but you know I
put up here this example of X answers
universal principles of data ethics you
know it is one of the very few stabs
I've seen at someone or some industry or
somebody in industry starting to say
where does the responsibility lie does
it lie with the with the coder does it
lie with the you know doesn't lie with
the company does it lie with the person
who utilizes the tool and I just don't
see a lot of work getting done in 48 the
UN came up with the Universal
Declaration of Human Rights
how is that gone you know we still can't
enforce Human Rights around the world
you know so when we look at universal
ethics or universal code of conduct and
we do it through the cultural lens of
different countries and different
societies it becomes an incredibly
complex ethical question so what makes
one value system better than the other
but what I can tell you is is with the
interconnectivity of individuals this
this question is going to become more
and more important what are the
universal values we can wait for it to
evolve but can we wait for those
universal values to evolve while we rush
into technology like quantum computing
and AI in other areas so I've seen some
things out there global bioethics
anybody anybody's seen anything on
biohacking so CRISPR technology that you
can buy kits on the internet now do it
in your garage so we're now starting
just now starting to convene global
organizations to talk about these things
and to help define what those ethical
responsibilities are you know is
withholding a cure because you don't
know or a solution potential solution
because you don't know the effects the
long-term effects of it you know is that
ethical versus unleashing unproven or
untested technology out there so I've
talked about kind of a lot of things at
a really high level here and I hope that
I'm giving you something to really chew
on it's not what I'll be able to effect
in the remainder of my time here on
earth in this area will be will be
pretty small but those of you that are
still have many more footsteps on this
earth these are the decisions that
you're going to have to make these are
the things that you will confront these
are you will become the leaders and the
researchers and the scientists and the
coders and you will have to make those
moral ethical decisions at some point on
how your technology or how the
technology in your life influences you
and this decisions that you make your
quality of life how it impacts other
people so I would just ask you to the
more complicated things get is to go
back to the most simple things and that
is how do we wish to consult ourselves
as a human race how do we wish to treat
each other
how do we want the future to look and
you know work on those work on those
hard questions they're yours so that's
all I have for tonight I appreciate all
of you coming out I'll be happy to
answer any questions that you might have
I know that's a lot of really deep heavy
stuff so Frank how do you think like the
state and the federal government are
kind of addressing some of these key
issues they're not they're not right now
the industry the industry is smart
enough so it's been pretty interesting
so specifically to AI we've heard
several tech leaders prominent tech
leaders come out and say actually say to
the government we need to regulate this
so what I would what I would say is
there's a lot there's a lot of great
people in Washington DC I mean I believe
that there's a lot of people there that
are trying to do the right thing but I
don't know if there's a level of
understanding about the effects of what
technology and data and convergence
singularity what that's bringing for the
future and I'm not sure that the
industry right now particularly in the
United States is very interested in
influencing privacy and how how I could
segue to that is is the fact that with
privacy that limits the data that can be
collected then how it can be utilized to
some extent in China they don't have
those restrictions the the population
freely gives up their data in order for
convenience so and to some extent we do
we give it up in Facebook and we give it
up in in Amazon and their web browsers
and all those things and those 15 page
legal disclaimers that nobody ever reads
but we all check off on so right now to
my knowledge there are no international
work groups or think tanks that are
specifically looking at ethics and data
in
in the application II I'm sure there are
some out there but I'm telling you
there's it's just not it's our
governments aren't looking at it oh is
there anything in Israel they're doing
that's unique or any best practices over
there that we should be duplicating so
again Israel is my experience with
Israel is that they are an incredibly
innovative society and I believe that
innovation is born of three different
things
innovation is born out of research
innovation is born out of businesses
that do business daily that have to
invent processes or niche naturally come
up with processes that make their lives
easier and then necessity I mean
necessity is the mother of invention
so specifically within Israel they're
constantly at war particularly in
cyberspace so they are very good at at
technology - they're the second largest
exporter of goods and services for cyber
security in the world which is about 30
times their weight per capita so I would
say innovation is is what their their
hallmark is and they've also figured out
how to commercialize that innovation
mostly through support through the State
of Israel through the country so they've
got a great great way of doing that but
particularly geez I mean they've got all
kinds of cool technologies a lot of
water a lot of water technologies and
because their needs over there and
definitely a lot of security
applications social media applications
they love our cellphones so if you ever
go to Israel you don't want anything on
your cell phone to be owned by somebody
else take a burner so it's just a fact
of life so yeah so and you know again I
talked a lot about about China and the
cultural differences in the way they
view things there but you know our
allies are you know
I won't say there are allies do similar
things and we all spy on each other so
you know the largest spy ring ever
busted in the United States was Israel
so anyway any other questions come on
it's me yes I think they 60
it depends what your reference frame
when you're talking about say data or
ovoid or whatever nowadays it's
basically the say the dollars and the
markers and it used to be some people
they worship in the Golden Calf now they
are worshiping worshiping the bull
market now what's going on right now
some people they somebody wrote a book
about the Black Swan and right now it
seems there's a flock of Black Swan
which are coming in and basically you
don't in the regular media they don't
talk about it even though the whole
bunch of thing going on particular in
China and those people that are on China
know it's gonna affect everybody all
around the world that the parts that
were made in China now they're closing
factors in South Korea because there is
a mess there is no tourists from China
try not to go over there so they have to
put money into that hotels and
restaurants and everything so everybody
is just printing money and it seems
that's the only solution that most of
the people that they have it just basic
printing money more money more money
more money which is gonna be sacrificing
many for just a few very few no as I
said you're talking about the oil oil is
some necessity you have to use it it
doesn't matter who you are where your
money nowadays and the data that you are
talking basically those people were
paying for it those who were in the
market and that's the first narrative
what basically that's what the fake news
is just projecting for everyone this is
the only thing that you have to have and
now we are getting to a point that is
gonna be some kind of a problem big
problem for the whole world
now nobody discusses it because
or if you say this something's gonna
happen it's gonna be bad and whatever so
I don't know what's gonna be your
perspective on that one that in this
particular segment of time this is what
people think is important but it is not
and they used to be a golden rule that
they say don't do to others what that
you don't want to them to do to you or
do to others what they want them to do
to you now they have changed it to
golden rule is whoever has the gold is
gonna settle so I don't know what you
think about that now that's a great
point so you know Gandhi had I think
seven rules of seven rules that he
talked about and about rights and human
rights and things like that but he made
the argument that if you know if you
have the right the individual has the
right to to exist to life then you also
have the obligation to to not take
somebody else's life so he was talking
about the rights and obligations so
within the world today we talk a lot
about what our rights are but we don't
talk a lot about what our obligations
are so you know the greatest point of
prosperity in the United States and you
can actually fact check this was a time
when when we taxed the largest companies
the most so you know countries are
experimenting with things like a living
wage you know as we displace workers in
the workforce which is coming with
autonomy it's it's happening now with
robotics as we do those things we're
going to have increasingly amount of
people that are displaced and our
standard of living will continue to rise
for those that can afford it so you know
so again this takes me back full circle
to you know how do we how do how do we
wish to define ourselves as we move
forward forward now I'm not going to
talk politics and and and candidates and
stuff out there but you know in the
richest country in the world right now
we don't have a healthcare system that
takes care of the most disenfranchised
people in in our our country so what are
we going to do even more when people
don't have jobs you know when they're
replaced by economies or by autonomy and
things like that and then you look at
the gathering of wealth up there you
know businesses and people are
collecting wealth right now they're not
reinvesting it they're holding on to it
so if you look at the richest people in
in the world today they're not
redistributing that wealth they're
holding on to it and that's a phenomenon
that's that's unique to to some extent
to this time period so you know getting
back to what you're saying you know you
know the Krays first of all i'll be the
first admit i'm not a huge fan of
Silicon Valley because the craze out
there is you know these companies with a
mission that feel good and what's
happening is when they capitalize when
they take in all that money they get to
decide who the money goes to they get to
decide what charities they're they're
supporting you know individual giving is
dropping off but yet we as workers
expect our companies to contribute and
expect our companies to have a social
social mandate yet the people you know
to a great extent it's like you said the
people who control the gold make the
rules so and it goes back to Nietzsche
right who said that the rich and the
powerful anything they do is moral so
again very very complex questions but
absolutely the only I am a bit of an
optimist in the fact that with the this
human connection without the boundaries
and the vestiges of bureaucracies of
governments and I'm not an anarchist but
with the ability to connect one-on-one
with people and experience that you used
to only get through traveling to a
different country that we can achieve a
a higher level of understanding in human
needs I was a soldier for a long time
and what I can tell you is I've been to
some of the worst places in the entire
world and when I know to be true is that
when I sat with a Bedouin the Bedouin
wanted the same things that I wanted at
a very very basic level they wanted they
wanted safety they wanted they wanted
the ability to have some opportunity to
feed their family
you know those basic Maslow being I
don't know if that's a word but I'm
pointing it now but those basic needs
human needs they wanted those awesome
now all the trappings that came on top
of it you know come with societal
controls you know like what tribe do you
belong to what country are you you know
what's your religion say or whatever so
so a bit of an optimist in that that
one-to-one human connection that that
this next generation will be much more
evolved in that awareness than than we
were and then we can shake off some of
the trappings of you know I can't talk
to you because you're a communist you
know so I mean that's just stupid
so yeah sure they said some people they
believe that basically because of all
these gathering there might be some kind
of a and trash or something that maybe
the dog was below ten thousand or
whatever but then it's gonna recover and
then it's gonna go up to maybe fifty
sixty thousand and they say by that time
because of the way that they're behaving
and creating money probably it might be
sixty seventy thousand but the loaf of
bread is gonna be basically two thousand
dollars so what do you think about that
what they are saying about this
I think our economies are too hopelessly
entwined to allow that to happen anymore
I mean we bail out our system now
instead of allowing it to fail so as we
Teeter towards these things we'll take
the most extreme measures that we can to
keep our economies and in line but so I
don't I don't see a I don't see an
apocalyptic crash coming or with the
with the economy with any
mmm with with any of this I mean that
term too big to fail the whole world is
that way now I mean we can't go to war
with China we can't go to war with
Russia because our economies are too
hopelessly intertwined so and and I
think that's a good thing
so because that's basically what you are
saying the bible's and the blessed are
the peacemakers but what they are saying
over here are blessed by their war
mongers because you know all of these
industries if involving war they're just
going on and everybody believes in them
rather than believing in peacemaking so
as I said you might be an optimist I'm
also an optimist in general but the way
I look at these what's going on around
me
I just don't listen to the regular
numerous brainwashing you go a little
bit behind the news because when you
look at China they say 500 people 1,000
PPR 2,000 people have died and there may
be 75,000 or infected general you look
at it you don't close the industrial hub
of the world for maybe 2,000 people
75,000 is something like that so
something doesn't add up so that's what
I'm saying what I agree with you there
are a lot of things that you talked
about and they are basically major point
that everybody has to discuss with their
people around them and then decide what
they want to do yeah I'm kind of
encouraged I mean this this whole I
forget what the name of the virus is
that's that a corona virus so yeah well
somebody I heard somebody refer to it is
the kind of flu the other day I thought
it was rather interesting but I'm
actually kind of encouraged by it
because you know seeing the world
respond as something that's poached
potentially a pandemic you know and
respond in a coordinated fashion I think
is is encouraging and again as we become
more intertwined I think that we're
gonna we will see more of that when we
do see more of it now so we see world
reactions to two things that affect us
all so we can't afford not to so
did you have a question earlier so my
question is that so I completely agree
with the way we you you spoke about how
the corporates especially need to have
certain rules and ethics on how they
utilize our data which is available
publicly and I believe the acts like the
GDP are and the CCPA or maybe one of the
the forefront acts in allowing us to
properly set rules and guidelines on how
data has been utilized but I also
believe in the the sovereignty and the
freedom of data in the Internet and so
people always have a choice like you
said you spoke about we always we never
read the Terms and agreements where you
just checkoff on it and so what I'm
trying say is like shouldn't we try to
in this digital age shouldn't we try to
incorporate knowledge and how we should
use data and how we should be careful
with social media with with the Internet
as a whole into our education system and
tell people make sure people understand
the implications of things which go
wrong you're preaching you're preaching
brother I mean I I love that and you
know I always use the analogy back in
the back in the old days on on after
school and on Saturday mornings you know
we had a little public service
announcement announcement PSAs and they
still had some out there now but they
had a guy named Freddie kilowatt who was
like a little lightning bolt and I
learned from that cartoon not to stick
my finger in a light socket
you know why we don't do that with the
world that we live in now and where the
dangers really exist which is on the
internet you know why we don't have
those same type that same type of
education why digital citizenship is not
required in K through 12 is beyond me I
mean I fight that fight every day here
at the state of Indiana to try and
convince you know DoD and our DOA and
DWD and those guys to
to consider things like that so
absolutely I mean digital citizenship
there's there's countries doing great
things like Estonia is killing it right
now just in digital citizenship you know
where they're starting to really
understand what the responsibilities
aren't for that so but yeah so I'm with
you so any other questions all right
[Applause]
you