okay
uh hello everyone welcome to the
presentation epp edr unhooking the
protections my name is daniel and i work
as an ethical hacker at the company
strong i.t
in innsbruck here in austria and we are
a small but very fine team
with about four team members with
different focuses on blue and red
teaming
and our company was founded about 10
years ago
by david winkler which is one of the
pioneers here in austria
in the area of cyber security so
i want to say many thanks to david and
also to my colleague robert
for supporting me because without
their support it wouldn't be possible to
speak here right now
my currently focus is on learning about
red teaming under the windows
environment
so for that i do a lot of studying
in the last few months the windows
internals
in my opinion the windows internals are
a great resource
no matter if you are a blue or a red
teamer and
also that knowledge from the internals
helped me a lot about to
understand which mechanisms
could edr systems use under the windows
west system and that is also
the main topic we will speak about today
so we take a look at two different spec
mechanisms which can be used from edrs
under windows
the first one is user mode api hooking
and the second one
are kernel callback functions
but before we can speak about that we
have to
clarify some basics so we speak shortly
about what the
main difference between a epp and an edr
system
and what do we understand uh
under the bus world behavior-based
detection
and also we need a little bit to know
about the windows architecture
to better understand uh what is user
mode api hooking
so from the red team perspective for
that presentation we have the goal to
understand
api hooking and kernel callbacks because
when we understand it
we can try to bypass it and
in that presentation we want to bypass
api hooking and callbacks because we
want to dump uh
credentials from the elsa's process
without
creating any alert in the edr system
and we will see that also very tough edr
systems
have to play with the rule on the
windows and so they also
they have certain limits um in the
windows environment
and at the end of the presentation we
will have a short look
from the blue team perspective uh what
can we do about idyapai
passing in the context of credential
dumping
the elsa's memory
so what's the main difference between
ebp and edr
very simple app has the main task to
prevent the execution of malicious files
before they can
get executed by a user for that atp
use different mechanisms like static
dynamic or in-memory analysis
but the problem with that is that sooner
or later an
attacker will find a way to bypass an
epp
so our test cases and practices show
that there's currently no epp which
couldn't be bypassed
by for example by a trojan to get the
command and control channel
and after the first compromise
with an epp alone you have
very pervisibility on the endpoint so it
it's very hard to find out
what maybe had the hacker also done
after
compromising the first endpoint so
not really a good visibility
compared to that the edr a pure edr
has the task to detect malware not to
prevent
so for example the edr also tries not to
only detect malicious signatures
ddr also tries for example by api
hooking
to get your response about malicious
behavior on an endpoint
and also you have the possibility uh
with an edr
by the collector telemetry on the
endpoint to
front half to fret hunt for malicious
behavior also when there was no previous
alert
uh because you have centralized lock and
so it's possible also when you just have
when the fret hunter just have the
theory about
a possible compromise on endpoint uh he
can search for that
because idios compared to epp
have a very high process or high
end point visibility in practices for
sure you will see
always combination between epp and edr
because you
need the prevention but more it's
you also need the visibility on the
endpoint
by an edr system and
also when i speak in that presentation
about edrs i always refer me to
the combination of an epp and then edr
so while learning about edrs we see in
our pants that
more and more customers are using edr
systems
that is a good thing from the blue team
perspective because
uh for sure we will reach that our
customers get better in i.t security
but also from the red team perspective
we have to critically ask
ourselves our edrs
really do behavior based detection or
there are
also still a lot of cases uh where they
just use signatures to
to detect malicious files or malicious
behavior but
it just definitely raised the bar we saw
it in pentest about five months ago
that we have to deal with a very
interesting edr system
so it was very simple to to get a
foothold on the system
but compared to that the post
exploitation was really hard because
we have to get rid of that foothold
process and inject
into a more legitimate process but
uh no matter if we try to inject into
another process
or later on to dump the
memory address space from the alphas
process we always get detected by ddr
system and so
it was very hard and we have to deal and
dig deeper into
why edrs why does ddr detect
us and so we have to deal
for example with user mode api hooking
so user mode api hooking is a technique
where we which we will see later on what
it does exactly but
for example by api hooking the edr has
the policy possibility
to check process accesses so
edrs are not just signature pay do
just signal to base detection but
in the case when we have uh
behavior-based detection like
in for example when we try to dump the
elsa's memory
we also want to know what can we do
about it and so we are forced to
uh deal with api hooking and later on
also with
callbacks so our motivation was to see
how long would it be possible to stay
under the radar
when we bypassed that techniques and
also we created an
own technical evaluation process based
on the mitra tech framework
for our customers when they are choosing
an edr system
or evaluating an adr system
so what's all about that buzzword
behavior-based detection in context of
edrs
behavior-based detection for example
could be when the edr detects that an
unauthorized process
injects code into another process so
in that example we see that we clearly
get blocked by the edr system
ddr detects malicious behavior on the
endpoint because we
try to break demonseration by process
injection
so we ask ourselves is it really the
idea does it really
detect malicious behavior or do we have
chance to get rid of the signatures
in our payload
so uh we used a very uh nice tool from
daniel buhaynon
which is called invoke obfuscation and
obfuscate our power shell payload very
heavily
and that was very interesting because
after
after that we executed our payload again
and we there was no further detection by
the edr system
so um detect the
detection before wasn't really behavior
based
uh because we have just to get rid of
the signatures
and we're still able to do our process
injection
also in that case we try to get
persistent by a scheduled desktop
uh in the first run we go to access the
knight from the edr system
and again in the lower picture you see
that there is a little bit different
obfuscation and
after that we were able to successfully
create our
schedule desktop so again
we have just to get rid of the
signatures in our
command
also very interesting we
intentionally used the pre-compiled
version from rubios
and started the cabarrus attack and
we see that we got detected by the edr
and very simple i just renamed the
file from rubios to pari.dxe
and we were not longer detected by the
edr system
and can successfully
create our kerberos attack
so we saw some cases where the edr
maybe tells us it detects malicious
behavior but
we saw there was
there was just signatures we have to get
rid of in our
commands or payloads but
depending on the dr system for example
in the case of credential dumping the
elsos process
it could be a little bit harder because
they're not just
going on signatures for example in mimi
cuts or in other credential dumping
tools
they also check for example which
process tries to access
the address space of the ss process
and so um we currently
uh had no had no way to
to to dump the elsa's process without
creating an alert in the adr system
so we ask ourselves what could be the
reason for that
one reason can be that the api
at the adr system use api hooking
so by api hooking it can check the
process accesses and also can check
for example which process tries to
inject code into the
address space of the esos process and
that's also that the process visibility
which i had speak before about
so just getting rid of the signatures in
our tools
isn't enough so we also have
to think about what can we do uh
when we get rid of the signatures but
also get
but still get detected by malicious
behavior
so we have to deal with user mode api
hooking
and before we clarify some basics in the
windows os
architecture to better understand one is
api hooking
so since windows nt 3.1 windows is
separated into user mode into
kernel mode very easy
or easy said in the user mode they are
running our all
user applications like word excel chrome
etc what else
and in the kernel mode are all critical
system applications like
the file system or the device drivers
and by default there is no way to
directly execute code from
the user mode into the kernel mode
because of that address
because of that memory separation on
processor level
very important to understand before we
go on
is that the ntdl in user mode builds the
lowest common
common denominator in user mode before
there is a way to access the kernel
but still of that separation there has
to be a way to get a transition from
user mode to kernel mode
and this is done by the play together
from windows apis native apis
and system calls in user mode so when
application
tries to access the kernel
it can use the windows apis to call the
associated native api and the native api
includes a system call which initiate
that transition from user mode to kernel
mode
have a look on an example where for
example when you write some code in
notepad
and you to will save your your document
notepad needs needs for the saving
process access to the file system
and to the device drivers and as we
learned before
both of that are running in kernel
length in kernel mode
so what happens when we click on the
save button in notepad
notepad calls windows api which is
called
create file w from the kernel 32 dll
and by that dll it calls the associated
native api
anti-create file in the anti-dll as we
learned before
the entity dll builds the lowest common
in dominator
in user mode before access is accessing
kernel land
and in the native api there is a system
call with a specific number
and but i just by that system call we
get the transition
from user mode ring three to kernel mode
ring zero
but still the kernel needs to know which
native api should be executed so
the kernel can use the system service
this page table and the syscall number
to check
which native api should be executed
by the kernel therefore you see
in that case it calls the anti-create
file from the ntos kernel.xc
also often you see
instead of nt you see the kernel version
nativifi
api which is called set w
so what's now about eds and api hooking
ebr api hooking you can imagine like
a proxy on process lab which means that
the edrs
use api hooking in different ways for
example
with inline api hooking to set a jump
instruction
in the anti-dll in the native api of
in the ntdl and redirect the code to the
edr
so by that redirection from the executed
code in a
context of a specific native api
the edr can analyze
the process or the code which get
executed in the context of that native
api
and in our test cases with different edr
products we
saw that edrs
uh always use or in that product product
use inline api hooking and inlet api
hooking is
as i said realized by a jump instruction
in specific native apis in the entity l
why in the ntdl because the ntdl
built is the last last executed code
before accessing kernel land
so what are indicators for api hooking
when you have an endpoint with installed
edr
you simply can use the process explorer
and
check the loaded dlls by a process in
that case by the command gel
and maybe you will find injected dll by
the edr system
you can check it a little bit more in
detail
when you install for example windy gb on
your
endpoint with install edr and use the
command x to examine
uh a specific idea specific native api
for example anti-map view of section
then you get the address of
that native api in the
in that process in the address space of
that process
and you can disassemble the address to
get the assembly instructions from the
native api
and we see with installed edr we have
clearly a jump instruction in the second
line which could be an indicator
that the code gets redirected to the edr
system
compared to an endpoint without ddr we
see
uh in the second line in the same native
api
that there is no jump instruction
instead of that we have a move
instruction
and that move instruction moves the
syscall
that we see the cisco number to a hex
into the ea x register and the the
syscall can be directly executed
compared to the upper picture before the
cisco can be executed
it gets redirected maybe to the edr
so a jump instruction isn't really
a clear sign that have to be api hooking
but we can for example use the x64
debugger
to follow the jump instruction in
the address space and we finally
will see that we start in the ntdl
and it ends in the the jump instruction
when we follow the jump instruction
it ends in the adder space of
the edr dll and that is a clear
indicator for the that ddr
redirects the code by using a jump
instruction for analyzing
the executed code
so one question why speak be always
about user mode hooking and not kernel
mode working
that's very simple micro do microsoft
implemented in the kernel with windows
xp
service pack free for windows x64
systems
bit systems a mechanism which is called
patchguard
and patchguard prevents edrs and epps to
set
officially their api hooking in
kernel length so the edrs are officially
forced to set the api hooks in
user mode in the anti-dll and because of
that
because of the windows architecture we
know that they are the same rules for
everyone in user mode and best
lead us to some ways to bypass
user mode api hooking from the red team
perspective
so there are several ways to bypass user
mode api hooking
in that presentation we will have a look
at direct system calls
which was uh released or introduced uh
two years ago by a very great blog post
from outflank from the guy
from the guys from from the netherlands
so i just can recommend to have a look
on their blog post
you can really learn a lot about red
teaming
and yeah api hooking they have a very
very great block which you can read
about
so still we have the goal to get
credentials from the elsa's process
without creating the alert
any alert and so we have to to
bypass in the first step user mode api
hooking
and we use a tool by outflank which is
called
uh dumpart and dumpert uses direct
system calls
to dump the address space of the essos
process
uh by direct system console so without
without touching the entity level so
first we compare short in theory
the difference when we dump credentials
with mimi cuts and when we dump
credentials with dumpert so mimikatz for
example
uses a native api which is called
anti-read with your memory
to read the virtual memory of the elsa's
process
but often edrs set in that native api
a jump instruction to redirect the code
for analyzing the executed code
in the context of that api and so you
often have the problem that you are not
able to dump
credentials with maybe cuts on currently
edrs or epps
instead of that dumbart also needs
the native api anti-virtual memory to
read the address space
uh from from the lfos process
but instead of calling it by the ntdll
dumper uses a combination of api hooking
and direct system calls and implement
the associated native api and the
assembly instructions directly in the
binary
itself and so it is necessary to
call that native api by the anti-dll
and so also the code executed code
cannot be redirected to the edl
edr and ddr has no visibility
into the cult native api
okay so in our first demo we will try to
bypass
api hooking in user mode by using
the tool dumper which uses direct system
calls and we try to
dump the asus process without creating
an alert
in the edr system and we will check
if it in that case isn't is enough to
just bypass
user mode api okay so we switch to our
demo system
okay there we have our endpoint we see
installed in yeah
to keep everything anonym we have
disabled
uh every notification from the edr
system
so at first for short comparison
we can try to execute mimi cuts first i
i
create a copy because we need it later
on
so we will see when we execute mimi cuts
we get detected by edr and also mimi
cuts gets deleted
so no way to dump credentials with
memory cards in that case
on that endpoint
okay so we will try it with the nice
tool from outflank
with dumpert
to create a dump file from the elsa's
process by using direct system calls
to bypass user mode api hooking
okay here we see a little bit what
dumper is doing
so we see it uses the native api anti
read virtual memory
and reads the address space of the ss
process
and creates a dump file to that
directory
but there is one problem the byte has
zero kilobytes so i asked myself what
could be the problem for that
and checked checked in the binary in the
source code the native apis
so maybe i use a wrong version or i have
to
to check the native apis in the binary
because they can change from
one one version from windows to another
version
but the real problem is that in that
case with that edr system
just bypassing user mode api looking to
get credit
credentials without an alert isn't
enough so
we have also to deal deal with another
uh mechanism which is used by that edr
and that are the kernel callback
functions so we go back to our
presentation
have a short look about on what is
what are curly callbacks and how can we
deal with that
from the red team perspective and then
we come back to our demo system
because still we want credentials from
the elsa's process
okay as i said at the first try it
wasn't enough to guys
just bypass user mode api hooking um
when we have the possibility to look
into the web console which isn't
currently possible because then you will
see which edr we are using
you will see that we still create a
critical alert because
the edr checks that we try to
access the address space of the essa's
process
from unauthorized or from an unusual
so we also have to deal with kernel
callbacks
as i said before patchcar prevents the
edr to set the api
hooks in kernel end but this by
patchcard there is still a possibility
to get feedback from the kernels for the
edrs
so what they can do they can load a
device driver into the kernel
and register some specific callbacks
like the pset create process notify
callback and by that callback the edr
always gets informed about when a new
process
is started on the endpoint
and how can we deal with that how can we
maybe remove that callbacks because
the callbacks are in that case
uh still the reason why
we are we are not able to create a dump
file with dumper
with the credentials or with with the
credentials from the ls process
and we still create an alert so how can
we deal with with the callbacks
for that we have to move into kernel
land because
as i said before it isn't possible to
execute
code from user mode in kernel land
so what we can do when an attacker or
how can we
achieve it to get into the kernel
when an attacker access or reaches
full administrator privileges it can use
that
privileges to load a vulnerable driver
like the mse
afterburner driver into the kernel
and by the vulnerability of the driver
we get
directly read and write access to the
kernel from
userland and that is a very interesting
changing point because in my opinion
when the attacker
has reached administrative privileges
and has upon its possibility to
compromise a kernel
by loading a wool level device driver it
is a whole game
changer because uh yeah when the kernel
is compromised
also in my opinion the endpoint is
lost completely his integrity so by
moving into the kernel we have the
possibility
to remove the callbacks
why isn't that uh device driver loading
from vulnerable device wherever not
prevented
this depends strongly on the certificate
date of the vulnerable device driver for
example the amazing afterburner driver
is uh released before end of july 2015
and so still when the when microsoft
knows about their vulnerability
the driver can still be used to to
uh to load into to get access to the
kernel
after july 2015 it is a little bit
harder because
instead of the one certificate you need
a extended validation
uh hard reset certificate but also in
that case you will still
find uh drivers with vulnerabilities
which can be loaded into the kernel and
give you access
to kernel land
okay now we know a little bit about
kernel callbacks so we go back to our
demo system because we still want
credentials from the elsa's process
without creating any alert in the edr so
what we do
we use a very nice poc which is called
jackie blinder
from that guy and
by that plc we load a reliable device
driver into the kernel
remove the callback and see if we can
finally
get our credentials or dump the elfs
process
without creating an alert so we go back
to the demo system
and in the folder you can see
the poc which we are using and also the
vulnerable device driver which we
load into the kernel to get access
from userland to kernel land
so first we can check the options from
the poc
and we can install
the driver with the vulnerability
so now the driver is registered in
kernel land
and we can uh list
all regis registered callbacks uh on
that
machine and uh these are not all
callbacks from the edr system so you
have to
because when you remove the once you
remove the callback you have to find out
which callback is from the edr in that
case i
do it very often i tried it before a lot
of times
so i know it and we can very simple
remove it
so we can check the registered callbacks
again
and we will see that currently the
we we are we are able to remove the
callback
so what did we know or what have we done
by removing the callback now the edr
has not longer the possibility to get
informed about
when a new process is started on the
endpoint so
no matter if we are now executing
dumpers or mimi cuts
or just for simple post exploitation id
config
which needs ipconfig.exe in the
background or who am i which needs
uemi.exe
the edr system has not logged the
possibility to collect that telemetry
on the endpoint so now we can
execute dumper again and see if we now
can successfully dump the
ss process
and we see it changed from 0 to 50
kilobyte
and now that file can be used to
take it to a local machine uh load it
into memory cards
and read out the created clear tech
credentials or hashes
from that end point but very interesting
when you have removed in that case the
callbacks from vdr as i said the idea
gets no longer informed about
which process is started on the endpoint
and so also
uh the combination from api hooking
and kernel callbacks is no longer
working efficiently so we are
also able
to directly execute mimikats now
which wasn't possible before
and we cannot just start mini cuts
also
it is not possible
to dump credentials with memory cards
directly
so that is not longer it it's not no
longer necessary to
use uh direct system calls to bypass
user mode api hooking
when you were able to
load a vulnerable device driver and
knock out the edr
by removing the callback so from that
point it's a it's a game changer
because the attacker has in my opinion
for 100 percent compromised the endpoint
and the endpoint definitely
lost his integrity
so we see that in that case it wasn't
enough to just bypass apioking to get
credentials from the else's process
without creating an alert
but this depends strangle strongly on
the edr the also edr's weight is
just enough to bypass user mode api okay
also it depends on
what the attacker is doing for example
for process extraction it could be
enough to just bypass user mode api
hooking
but in case of credential dumping the
else process maybe you also have to deal
with kernel callbacks
so you can think about your strategy
but it is possible depending on the
sensitivity of a system
maybe you can try to load that driver
and use the short poc
to remove the callback lock out the edr
and try to
dump credentials from the asus process
very important when you are finished
with your work in your lab or
also in your penetration test when you
use it
do not forget to unload the device
travel it's very important because
for example in that case of the msc
afterburner driver when the driver is
still loaded
um an attacker has the possibility to
get system privileges directly get
system privileges from the
standard user account
okay so we are finished now from
directing perspective
but as i said before what can we do
about from the bluetooth
perspective to protect us against
credential dumping
when the edr system is bypassed
i have to say that it doesn't matter
which edr project you are dealing for so
it can be harder with one product
compared to another product but
uh every edr system have to play with
the same rules under windows
but um er systems
do still increase the activity security
so
it is definitely a good thing to
additionally use the edr product to a
classic
epp protector but still
independent of using products you have
to harden your windows environment
because when an attacker was able to
bypass tdr system
and gains admin privileges he can
dump credentials from the elsa's process
but when you before hardened you
previously when you harden your windows
environment and the
attacker isn't able to get credentials
uh
admin credentials it doesn't matter
which tool
he uses because for every tool we use to
try the credentials from their
process we need admin privileges
in more detail when we try to dump
the access process from a user session
we need in our admin
token the debug as a debug privilege so
for example
when you harden your administrative
token and remove that privilege
the attacker cannot dump the ss process
from a user session for sure it can
again
get can gain uh when he already has
admin villages he can
get system privileges and then he has he
can
he's also in the uh works from the user
session so
the icd privilege is no longer necessary
but for that the attacker has to do one
step more
so another way to protect the asus
process is to use the lsr protection
which uses a technique from microsoft
which is called process protection lite
so when the ss protection is enabled
an attacker cannot dump the address
space of the ss process
also not when he has admin or system
privileges
but there's still a way by mimi cuts to
remove the
ppl of the ls from when elsa is
protected by
ppl so you can use mini cuts to load a
vulnerable device driver
into the kernel as we learned before you
from the kernel then you have many
options
for example you can remove the callbacks
but you also are able to
remove the ppl from a process and so you
can
use the ring zero options by mimi cards
to remove the ppl
of the ss process and you were
again able to dump credentials from the
process
but additionally to elsa's protection
when you have the requirements fulfilled
on the endpoint you can use credential
guard
and credential guard works a little bit
different because it uses
the hyper hypervisor based protection
for creating virtual trust levels so
when you enable credential guard
you create um two different
uh virtual trust levels so in the normal
mode which we are working on
in the normal user mode in the normal
kernel mode is default l0
uh credential when you activate
credential guard you create
a virtual trust level which is called
faulty l1
and by activating credential guard
the domain admin credentials are no
longer stored in the elsa
process in the normal mode
so uh they get from now on they get
stored in the lsr iso process
lsr iso is named for
lsr isolation and currently there is no
way to get access
from file to l0 to file tl1 so
also when an attacker has gained access
admin privileges in the kernel mode in
in
faulty l0 he has no currently no way to
get access to the address space of the
lsi so process
in fact that is one because of that
separation
based on the hypervisor
okay so uh thanks a lot for your
attention
i hope it was a little bit exciting to
learn about
using what api looking kernel callbacks
and so on what we can do about it as a
red teamer
feel free to ask any questions also you
can write us later on email
and yeah have a nice day and
we will see you