just in case my battery lasts for about
six hours but just in case I plugged it
in because of jet lag and white my last
rehearsal lesson over two hours so it's
good that we have an open mic up for my
presentation
yeah thanks everyone for staying late
for why yeah why my talk it's not really
my it's it's it's my end Alex's talk and
they they they work behind it you might
have you might have seen some of our
research presentations we did a lot of a
lot of security research and the firmer
space specifically UEFI space or or Mac
EFI or related it's recently a more
recent decor but we've we've done that
back at Intel and now we we have you
probably haven't heard about this
company it's very new we started the
company a few months ago it's called
Eclipse ale
and so the presentation today is
discovering you v ulnar abilities at
scale or vulnerable you fight systems at
scale and so what motivated us to to do
that research and it's slightly
different it's more of a data analysis
than looking for some new
vulnerabilities and new systems but the
motivation is that we tend to focus and
we meaning research community and also
also in particular we tend to focus on
trying to find new classes of
vulnerabilities preferably new systems
you know the more complex the
the problem is even the newest systems
today a lot of them the lack just basic
perma hygiene they lack basic
protections over there the unify firma
that they have moreover there are still
lots of old systems and use especially
in the public sector there are still
systems that are telling here 10 year
old even running legacy bias let alone a
ufi or worry of Isis terms but
definitely not the the the most recent
seventh or whatever generation of
install processors you know the most
expensive Dell or HP servers public
sector runs very old equipment and so
there are tools currently available to
test those systems or basic primer
protections like there's a there's chips
AG that we've we've off authored they
can test if the firmware on a particular
system is vulnerable the problem is that
the problem with that is is that in
order to do that we literally need to
have all of that equipment to test it on
and that's not always possible and also
it doesn't really not provide provide us
with the full picture of where the
industry is in terms of basic basic
firmer hygiene so how do we how do we
understand the state of an entire
population of all the systems that's
what that's what motivated us to do this
research but prior to doing that I'll
I'll just explain some basics in terms
of how modern systems protect the
beautify firmer in the system flash
because will will need that information
so system flash is something that stores
your main firmer in in the recent in
modern systems you fire firmer but also
other types of firmer like manageability
engine firmer like the embedded
controller firmer often like the
persistent settings for a network
interface card and other things so there
are two types of access that software
uses to get to that perma on this buy
flash first is the direct access to
memory mapped memory through the memory
addressable space basically any any
address of a below certain size
underneath the the poor gigabytes is
magically translated into this buy read
cycles on the on the spi bus and and and
and and get to to the contents of the
SPI flash but there's there's a this is
all the this is only used for reads it
it's it's used to bootstrap the the or
actually the fetch the the reset vector
out of Flash one they CPU comes out of
reset
but there's another access programmable
register access that the software is
using in order to read or write to the
system flash and that's usually done
through the memory mapped i/o registers
so player of the chips out of a SPI
controller in the chipset so with that
software programs the flashlight near
address is explicitly into the registers
indicating to the controller which which
or where exactly it needs to write to or
read from and so system flash can be
partitioned into multiple regions one
region is the the bias region u5m region
another is manageability engine embedded
controller region
GB
and so on but there is also this
partition table called flashlights
scraper which is also a region by itself
it's the first region that actually
describes the how the flash chip is is
partitioned so that descriptor is is the
first four kilobyte of of spy device by
chip device located at the fillet zero
it the way hardware or the way chips
determines that the flash is operating
in the descriptor mode is it reads
certain signature and if it sees the
signature then it considers that a ten
hex offset then it considers that their
flashes and is valid and their
descriptor is valid and the flash is
operating and they and they just kept
remote but in so that that that
descriptor
it's a literally a partition table so
what it would what it has it describes
all other regions where those are
located what's the size of those regions
but it also describes who can access
which regions so that there are there
could be multiple masters in the
platform that can access the same flash
and some masters should be able to
access some regions while others should
be able to access other regions and so
that particular so that access control
table within the descriptor region
defines which master who can access
which region in
in the flesh and which type of access
read or write access so how how the how
that affects the security of the system
firma in that system flash well first is
or what are the what are the what are
the basic mechanisms to that systems use
to protect the firma
the first is the is pretty obvious one
the this every every system in order to
maintain some basic level of protection
so the firmer it has to have has to
support sign updates and in the unified
keys those are typically signed updates
are typically used as the so-called
capsules that sign capsules which are
submitted by the software to the firmer
on well through memory or through a file
system to be flashed on reboot or upon
resume from sleep state from s3 and so
the those capsules contain multiple
volumes as a payload those volumes could
be the the actual firmer volume that is
being written to the flash but also from
volume that includes executables that
will be there for maybe update so there
it's a rather flexible mechanism the
capsules might also include how they're
firmer blobs so not not just the UEFI
but embedded controller and so on so
they when that capsule is submitted
through memory if it's a upon a3 resume
or through file system if it's upon a
reboot then the one one system comes up
from reboot or sleep it checks the
signature of that capsule authenticate
said it also authenticates the the the
actual executable that will be
performing the update typically through
a secure boot mechanism and and then
writes the updates the
the contents of the firmware the
contents of that capsule so that that's
the first basic mechanism the second
basic mechanism obviously is the that
the the the actual flash memory has to
be right protected at one time because
if it's not then the the fact that your
system implemented sign update doesn't
mean anything because if the exploit can
just directly modify the the perma on
the flash then they will be able to uh
it will it would be able to modify the
code that is performing the signature
check so that's the the other basic
mechanism that has to be present on
every system and on on x86 systems there
are a number number of ways to achieve
that one as the as which Chromebooks are
using they basically just have a screw
that asserts the write-protect pin on
this pi devices but most of the non
chromebook devices they use chipset
based mechanisms one of them is the
so-called protected range registers the
other one is some members based write
protect mechanisms so basically that
allows software to update the flash at
runtime
only when that software execute sin that
special mode called SMM and obviously
after checking the second trough what
what is being written to the flash so
that's the second mechanism so obviously
the firmer has to be write protected and
the third protection is the descriptor
itself has to be write protected as well
and the way it's achieved is the the the
Saxa control table within the descriptor
is is program to the manufacturing to
prevent writes to that region 0
descriptor region so it's a self
protecting and that happens only once
when descriptor is flushed into the
flash chip then software is not able to
update that description
anymore so that that's how those
protections are supposed to work because
otherwise if exploit is able
modified the descriptor then it is able
to modify that the partition table or
access control table or other things for
just even break system so those are
three basic mechanisms that have to be
present on every system and I'm not
talking about any like complex
vulnerabilities in the unify or in SM
those are basic things that have to be
everywhere and so the usual way to check
for those basic things is let's say run
chip sack there are modules and chips
like that just test for each of those
and so sure enough a lot of platforms
even the newest used ones they fail
those tests for example you just did we
did the tests on there it's kind of like
based MSI systems they they failed Alex
Madras have recently did the analysis of
gigabyte systems bricks and and those
failed we also did some Corbett analysis
on systems that are that have corbett's
not Chromebooks but just random systems
and those failed as well but again the
downside of this approach is that it
requires a actual running an actual
equipment so that that's that's not
scalable we want to scale to understand
the whole the whole picture without
playing this whack-a-mole game of
testing on every single system and
finding the same things again and again
so that's what that's that's why we
started that analysis so first is how we
can achieve that we have tons of efi
images available to us through the
websites of manufacturers can can we
actually use them to test for those
basic protections can we find out which
systems lack those protections just
based on the analysis of the update
images so we were not the first who did
this type of research
read in the past three years ago it did
an awesome research where he where he
essentially applied a lot of analysis to
tons of update images that downloaded
and as part of that research he released
a number of tools including sub-zero
including the prizefighter a lot of the
lot of the ways that you fry spider gets
damages don't work today because vendors
changed either way they publish update
images so we had to fix that a lot a lot
of that but we have used ufi spider
among other things to actually grab all
the scrape all the websites from all the
vendors and and get all the updates
there are also tools that can parse the
images because in order to do some
analysis or any analysis you need to
parse you need to extract firmer volumes
and so on so the teddy has a ufi firmer
parser nickel Ashley has a ufi tool or
unified um specifically utility that can
do that chip cycle so does that so we
you can use either either of those tools
so but let's let's continue so this is a
this is essentially this is essentially
what we based our research on and we're
trying to remotely screen all of the
firmer update images for certain
problems in order to find
vulnerabilities screening right so or
even shorter telescreen some of you
folks might appreciate this
especially here so the the idea behind
that analysis is what if what if we find
firmer update packages that contain
images firm Ramage's that are not
capsules but images that include full
valid spy descriptor what does that mean
that means that those images are most
likely after filtering of course false
positives most likely those images are
full spi flash images and so those are
primary suspects for us because that
means that the update for the firmware
update is distributing the entire spy
flash ROM image which may be an
indication that there is no signature on
the system that this update is intended
for and there's no write protections of
the assistant flash that someday goes to
so that's easily automatable but the
problem is a lot of updates include
those images for different reasons so we
actually need to hear in this to
understand once we have this set of
suspects we need to understand if the
update is actually using that image for
the update or if that image is for
whatever other reason so that's is not
that that's that's a little bit more
complex it's less easily automatable
but once we find those candidates what
that tells us is that the update
mechanism is using entire ROM image
which means that they are not signed and
if they are not signed that means that
most likely means that the system flash
is not protected because if you don't
implement signed updates why would you
protect the assistant flash at all and
in in in a lot of cases now explain why
a lot of cases that also means that the
descriptor is right at rewritable so we
essentially if we find those candidates
then we find systems that have those
three basic vulnerabilities there so the
whole process looks like that we just
download a lot a lot of firmer updates
from vendor websites then we extract all
sorts of binaries from those updates
update packages which look like firmer
images then of course the we get a lot
of candidates for images but not all of
them are really firm Ramage's some of
them are just too weird whiners so we
need to filter out the the binaries that
are really firm Ramage's and after that
we need to understand if those are unify
images or full spy images or bias images
and so on so we need to parson analyze
those that's uh that looks rather simple
so this is what essentially we did we
we've downloaded approximately 33,000
firmware update packages from nine
vendors some of them better coverage had
better coverage than others but it's
been a pretty significant amount of big
packages that we got we've extracted
44,000 different candidate images by
filtering them through known known
binaries used in the in the updates like
ROM Ben I am a cap and so on basically
the typical typical extensions used by
the vendors for the firm Ramage's but we
also applied some other things because
sometimes extensions are not enough so
we applied some some basic heuristics
look for no magic valise and looked
whether whether the image looks like a
unify for example it has some FB age
from Reb Oleum signatures and so on and
then after that filtering we've we've
got 21 thousand unique ufy former images
in
there there there there were duplicates
so so that's why you know the number is
lower so 21 thousands unique ufi images
we've parsed them analyze them the rest
of the images were we're all so laggy
see biases so one thing in this process
is that it it supposed to be work it it
it should have been generic it should
have been simple to extract those images
but the reality is there the update
packages there they're not equal to the
actual actual firmware images that Union
to analyze so there is no standard
formats so for examples that we've seen
that that we've seen that update
packages include all sorts of utilities
for different OSS like das GFI shell and
Windows and Linux and so on for update
then the the firmware images in a lot of
updates were encrypted or in some
updates were encrypted so we actually
had to understand how they decrypt those
how does the update package decrypt
those then there were multiple types of
firm Ramage's for the same update but
it's used in different cases in
different in different ways they updated
apply and also in a lot of cases we've
seen that they images were just plainly
embedded into the executables so all of
those had to be had to be somehow
understood comprehended and and in order
to just even extract their suspects at
images and yeah so the the algorithm was
rather straightforward so we try to
apply common we'll try to understand if
it's a it's if it's a just
sort of a known archive and we
decompress it if it doesn't work use bin
walk sometimes use them there's specific
utilities sometimes the vendor updates
had a special command-line arguments in
order to extract images out of the
update that we found it and we could use
and also other things like for example
just monitoring the file system how the
update changes file system and where it
drops the the contents of the date
package so after all of that is done we
need to search forest by descriptors in
the images because we we need to find
those fools by raw images so in order to
do that we've excluded capsule known
capsules cap FL type of images from the
updates we only included images with the
exact size of a spy flash chip because
we're interested in the fools by image
we only included images which contain
valid spy flash descriptor and also
rewritable descriptor so the valid flash
descriptor it has a couple of conditions
first it has to have signature at the
offset ton hax then it's not really
sufficient to look for just a signature
because there are spurious signatures
all over and so we've we've looked for
the reserved reserved bytes in the
description so basically basic sanity
checking rewrite access to the spy flash
descriptor is basically defined by that
access table that I mentioned and
previously so we've looked for the
images that contain descriptor which is
read writable basically this first our
RW value of CP you can read right to the
spine descriptor as a result of that
we've got out of 21,000 unique efi
images we get approximately 3 3,500 full
spy images and those are primary
suspects so that's approximately 17% of
all
the images we actually have analyzed but
what stands out is that there is a disk
disproportionate well there's a
difference from vendor to vendor some
vendors did not have spiteful images at
all like in Seoul for example or Acer
had very very few old older images some
vendors had more but still kind of a
lower number of full spy images like
Dell HP Lenovo but but there were a few
vendors like gigabyte Imus I an asus to
a lesser extent that had a huge amount
of spy images within the update packages
so so obviously all of all of those
don't necessarily mean vulnerable
systems automatically there are false
positives
not all update packages which have fools
buy images are indicating that those
systems are vulnerable because there
could be some updates had both capsule
and a full spy image and when when the
update is happening from the wrong time
then the update is using capsule but
then this whole spy image is included
for some other purposes like essentially
you know I used it manufacturing but not
during the update so that that that
could be a false positive or in some of
some of the updates included full spy
image but only used with the user
interaction basically when you reboot
the system you enter the bias settings
and then you update the flash from that
image but it requires user interaction
physical present user so that those are
false positives also there are false
negatives there are things that we've
missed for sure for example the fact
that this signed capsule is in the
update package and we consider it as a
non vulnerable update package it doesn't
really mean that this isn't the system
isn't vulnerable because what we've seen
in the past with ASUS for example is
that they implemented capsule updates on
capsule updates but they have not
implemented write protection software
over the system system flash and Ivy
Bridge based systems in the past so we
would miss that through that analysis
there also there were also updates with
the images that we just couldn't extract
and also we've excluded read-only flash
descriptors but those may indicate
vulnerable systems too in case if update
ignores descriptor so those would be
those would be false negative as well
and capsules don't necessarily have to
be signs so capsules there there may be
older systems that use capsules without
signatures but ultimately doing an
additional analysis over all of those
suspects yield yield it certainly the
results you can see here
so we've we found ultimately over 500
modal's through that analysis that lack
basic protections of the efi AFI firmer
some of those are older for example a
Sturrock our asrock they they had 73
images that are potentially vulnerable
which correspond to 53 medals but all of
those are older than skylake although
those are older than 2015 asus had 600
ish potentially vulnerable images which
corresponds you 61 modal's all of those
were older than Ivy Bridge so basically
a sand abrasion and so 20 2012 a few
vendors had a smaller amount of
modal's that are appeared to be
vulnerable which indicate that they
might have just forgotten to implement
you know those protections on those
systems but you can see that there are
some of the some of the vendors like
like gigabyte had over a thousand
potentially vulnerable images including
345 skylake and above that's 2015 and
above corresponding to 247 modal's that
lack basic protection so that's pretty
much almost every system that they have
Emma sighs same thing 1461 potentially
vulnerable images corresponding to 98
modal's 495 modal images are skylake and
above so those are those are vulnerable
the novel had potentially up to 26
modal's that we found potentially
vulnerable and those are a primarily
ThinkCentre idea Center and think
servers they they used it was full spy
image for for the update or they appear
to use pools by image for the update so
a few examples Emma saw is what standout
as I mentioned almost 500 skylake and
above images vulnerable total almost
1500 and corresponding to approximately
100 modal's we confirmed them on some of
the systems because there was a big huge
number so we actually went and confirmed
on some of the MSI's systems and sure
enough they don't have any protections
so one thing was was interesting is that
they they they provide a live update
utility through the software that can
update their unify framer and you can
see that it what it does it's a online
update of BIOS and former auto detects
and suggests the latest bias from
exactly what we need a live update over
the network of a on science bias firmer
on those systems and in addition to that
you can see that antivirus software is
actually conflicting with that tool so
it has to be disabled as well so that's
that's a very good live update of Troy
and iced Verma so del we we had 78
suspect suspects corresponding to 24
medals but 13 updates corresponding to
four models appear to be false positives
because they had capsule and ROM image
ROM image together so the ROM image is
probably used it manufacturing it
capsule is used in the actual update so
right now we suspect up to 51 update
packages and 11 models that seem to be
vulnerable most of them are inspiring
boss through older models older than
but with updates up to 2016 we're still
in this investigating some of the others
Lenovo as I mentioned mostly things
server and things central idea center
modal's all say older ones although
things think server had rather recent
2016 updates so you might you might look
at this at this utility that Lenovo
provides for firmer updates and what's
interesting is that this is probably the
the longest support period of the
utility of a software tool I ever ever
saw 1984 through 2016 that's how long
they support that flash update utility
the interesting thing is that they
started in 1984 as well so with that
analysis we we seem to be able to at
least come up with the
vulnerable modal's will or modal's of
systems that lack basic protections
which is important but we also through
that through that dump of update images
we can do other things we can we can
build start building a list of known
executables in the ufi space and we can
apply to you know to monitor changes in
the in the former so for example we we
cannot if we want to monitor a certain
change in the in the in the ufi
framework we cannot just compare hash of
the entire from ramage because there are
so many modifiable data there the NVRAM
and by tables and certificates and a
whole bunch of other things that would
be pretty useless so basically we need
to extract all the executables out of
the every year for image and we we need
to compare the those executables against
the known list so what we found is by by
extracting executables out of those 21
thousand unique efi images we've been
able to build this global whitelist for
those nine vendors and the tenth vendor
is is kind of a work in progress by the
community at the moment so we also can
have get some interesting numbers for
example there are 45 to 90 unique
executables per update but at the same
time there are about hundred to 300
unique executables on in your firmer so
which means that the updates are
typically much smaller than the actual
entire image which is understandable
because the update is and updates are
typically capsules and donate
with everything so now based on that
data we can build we can build this wide
list or a list of now and executables so
how do we actually do that what what
would what hashes we were going to use
the plain hash over the entire PU cough
image or the authentic code compliant
hash or something else so for example
most of the platforms in the UI they
support authenticated hashes for most of
the functionality like secure boot like
TPM CPMs basically except will not
accept that UEFI firmware submits
authentic code compliant hashes to the
TPM so we can we can build the the
whitelist through all of those type of
type of hashes so for and and that's
what we did
we we built approximately 2 million
global whitelist based in plane hashes
but also authentic code compatible
houses and we've build another wide list
that contains approximately million
executables unique executables without
authentic code hashes but in addition
with the time/date stamp filled in the p
had a masked off so the authentic code I
probably will just you know just skim
through the authentic code hashes is the
way Microsoft specified how to calculate
the hash of the Peikoff executable there
are certain fields that are masked off
and not included into the hash like
checksum or a certificate table entry
and so on so that basically provides a
way to uniquely identify Peikoff
executable regardless of the checksum
exclude some of the some of the some of
the data which is not really
so in addition to that it in addition to
that you can you can mask off the time
the date stamp so that that would
essentially eliminate duplicate
executables which were just you know
build at different time but haven't
really changed so that's why there are
fewer executables with within the
whitelist with the authenticator plus
the time date stamp cleared so that's
the some statistics over the the unique
if I hash is that we gather through that
analysis you can see that a million nine
hundred thousands plain hashes million
eight hundred thousand oh thank gosh
it's approximately the same same number
and lower twice as low of authenticate
hashes with timestamp clear so now with
that whitelist and there the the part of
the whitelist is open source right now
on a github other parts will probably be
publishing those soon but now you can
what you can do is you can actually
check your a firmer against that known
list of executables and finds if anyone
and you know added any extra executable
that shouldn't be there it's not it's
not a you know fully perfect because
there are false positives and Alex for
example he ran that global whitelist
against his Lenovo
4:58 into 430 and found one single
executable that wasn't indium in the
white list so he freaked out and but
after about four hours of reverse
engineering of that executable he
figured that this was a false positive
level there was a Lenovo m/sec be a
legitimate image with a small change
only on that particular system and none
of the hashes detected it
none of the ashes not the authentic cute
not the plain house have that hash of
that executable in the white list
so obviously it's it's not foolproof so
you can give false positive as well but
in addition to building the white lists
and checking the firmer against the
against that white list we can also
start gathering statistics on
interesting components and features and
statistics on which systems support
support or enable those components or
features so for example you might
remember absolute compute race which is
kind of a firmer based anti-theft
technology but can be of dual use and
there was some controversy about that
some this technology what it does it
actually embeds a lot of executables
into the into your firmer but in
addition to the OS so what we did is we
decided to apply very complex heuristic
to find systems that support compute
race we decided to search for word
compute race and the name of the
executable and so we found 13 39
different Dixie MPI modules used by
computer ace on on the fly based systems
some of them specific to your specific
vendors like Lenovo others are more
generic presence in several vendors and
we yeah we can we can we can now start
gathering statistics for those type of
components or features across all of the
entire population of the system so in
the computer ace case we we found
seventeen thousand seventeen and a half
thousand computer ace modules across the
vendors which which were corresponding
to approximately 7,000 unique if I efi
images which means that two
two-and-a-half components on average in
each efi image corresponding to two the
company trees so those were rather
simple heuristics that we've applied in
in in all cases both in in detecting
those basic protections missing basic
protections as well as building the
whitelist as well as searching for
specific components so we can improve
that we can improve we can detect we can
detect better detect capsules we can
explicitly detect that the capsules are
present not just you know by simple
heuristic versus the full spy image but
more more precise things like for
example detecting the firm update the
driver detecting the system from a
discreet API module or detecting the
image authentication structure in the
capsule which which contains the actual
pkcs7 signature for the capsule we can
also start detecting within the images
that they support sign capsule updates
and stay support secure flash update
because there are certain Dixie and P I
components that are responsible in
aiding in EFI based systems for
implementing those capsules and secure
update and those are like the FMP
authentication lab as part of capsule
update capsule package also PCH bias
right protects those are modules can
responsible for protecting this by flash
so we can start detecting those and
those would be more precise so as a
conclusion as a conclusions
even simple analysis of a huge chunk of
update packages can yield certain
results can find systems that are that
lack basic protections of the firmer
without without the need to actually
purchase those systems and run tools on
them through just the analysis of the
updates and what we've learned is that
some vendors have had those basic
protections for a while like Dell like
so like HP some vendors started recently
like aces or a throg and others haven't
even started yet it's like MSI gigabytes
so this this is kind of a type of
analysis is not perfect there are false
positives there are false negatives
there room for improvement and it also
can be applicable to finding other
vulnerabilities more complex things not
basic - not just basic protections but
more complex things like s3 bit scrape
former ability system is use and all of
those without the need to get the
system's physical systems so with that I
think that's that's pretty much
[Applause]
[Music]