hello there I'm Carol Drake I'm gonna be
talking about high tech to RFID which is
low frequency RFID cards with crypto
handshakes and authentication and
encryption I was going to start by
showing my lovely video 44 con happiness
but I've wasted so much time setting up
that you'll have to go in it for that on
YouTube so she searched YouTube for 44
Korn happiness and you'll find a silly
video I made a couple years ago that I
think is awesome so normal slide this is
a bit about me is the normal stuff you'd
expect I do work in cyber clearly so the
first question of course is why copy 125
kilohertz RFID tags and the answer is
because they're used to secure things
there are quite high asset high value
assets so you find them in cars
protecting the immobilizers on a number
of cars you find the same crypto in use
on the 4 33 megahertz Clippers that open
the doors you find them in building
access control now I've not looked at
cars but the same technology and the
same stuff would work in cars apparently
you might need different antennas I
haven't even looked at keys so if this
doesn't work for you with your cars then
you might have to do a bit of hardware
to make them work but basically I people
use them to secure things because they
think they're secure and obviously
they're not so I'll start quickly by
talking about a simple RFID tag 125
kilohertz these are the ones you
normally find when you're doing a normal
building access control job so am 4102 S
or Q 5 or unique kind of the names that
go under and they're basically a unique
identifier that is preceded by a
synchronization pattern if a
synchronization patterns usually a part
of the unique identifier a technical
level not that really matters when the
tags energized it repeatedly display
it's repeatedly sort of talks the unique
identifier over and over and over again
and the reader that's energized the tag
spots the synchronization pattern within
that stream and then just read whatever
comes after the synchronization pattern
and that's the number it then uses to
make access control decisions so of
course they're really easy to copy if
you want to copy those go on Amazon by a
RFID copier
and it's six quid or nine quid or
something and it slipped a push button
and you can copy those there's other
types of tags like T 5 5 5 7 s T 4 5 6 7
2 4 5 7 7 s all kind of same technology
and again you can buy a copy of some
Amazon little bit more expensive but you
can do so equally you could use an hour
fiddler which I'll be talking about in a
minute or a fox mark for the similar
kind of jobs but they're very
straightforward
they're basically broadcast their data
in public and so if you can read that
data then you can write that to a new
tag and then you've got a copy of the
tag so no one should be using those who
build an access control everyone does so
avoid so quickly at the electronic level
or the RF level how a 125 kilohertz tag
works the they have no batteries in them
I mean I'm imagining everyone in the
room has some idea what RFID is but this
is just the background the reader
emanates a field at 125 kilohertz the
tag itself energizes from the field
power and that's what acts as its power
source essentially and then the tag
modulates that field by dampen its coil
or not you know you kind of binary
pattern which the reader can then pick
up equally if the reader wants to talk
to the tag let's say you want to program
the tag with an e new data then the
reader can modulate the field itself
from the tag and pick up those
modulations so there'll be a little
capacitor within it to cope with the
field going on and off and stay powered
up so data modulation and encoding I'm
not going to talk about this in any
depth whatsoever but there's different
types of modulation and there's
different types of encoding and if you
start playing with RFID you'll become
very aware these very quickly some are
easy to use some are not so easy to use
but you'll get used to this if you get
anywhere in the world of proxmark or al
fadela they've both got support forums
everyone's talking about modulation and
encoding so what would we want from a
secure 125 kilohertz tag
well we'd want to weight communications
so that it set up some kind of encrypted
channel with some kind of or randomized
authentication randomize because we
wouldn't want it to be replayable
we'd want authentication and encryption
because we want it to be copyable so the
idea being that if you can get if you
got hold of someone's tag you wouldn't
be able to read it you wouldn't be able
to copy it and if you could eavesdrop on
that tag talking to a reader to open a
door then what you could eavesdrop
wouldn't be enough in order to copy the
tag that's kind of what we what we'd
expect so today I'm going to talk about
hi tag - in password mode very very
briefly because it's awful and hi tag
doing crypto mode which is the
interesting one and that's where the
attacks coming from there's lots of
things I won't be talking about and I'm
not going to go through me in any
details but if any of this is
interesting to you there's a workshop
tomorrow at half past 9:00 in the
morning
Steve Lord did laugh a lot when he told
me it was a half past 9:00 in the
morning and where I'll be doing two
hours
I say workshop it's a two-hour lecture
with interactive questions okay there's
no like sit and do type stuff and do
stuff it's just like watch and listen
and ask questions where it doesn't make
sense but if any of this is interesting
then you can ask questions at the
workshop rather than here if you've got
questions about this bit this kind of
talk obviously ask at the end it's
probably better so there was an academic
paper called gone in three hundred sixty
Seconds hijacking with hi tag to buy
adult Garcia and bash no this is from
2012 and this is a seminal paper if you
look at the proxmark forums or the are
fiddler forms there's a lot of people
asking for implementations of these
attacks because they let you start cars
essentially I will say that the sort of
the authors went on and last year
produced a new paper called lock it and
still lose it where they could do
everything much faster and that's the
one they got sued by Volkswagen over and
they actually wrote in their paper we
can do we can open the doors and start
up every Volkswagen from 1990 to 2016
which also means every see at every
Skoda and every whatever the other cars
in Aldi they said we don't know about
Lamborghinis and Bugattis because no one
will let us have one to try but they
theorized it would be possible so yes if
Volkswagen took a great interest in
their paper last year and certain
details didn't appear in the paper
but I'm focusing on the one four five
years ago so high tech to high tech to
is an RFID tag I have one here I mean
this is like in the ISO card format but
equally you can have little round tags
they all have eight pages and each page
is 32 bits long the first page is the
user as the unique identifier for the
tag which is factory programmed and
read-only so when you buy yourself a
high tag to tag it will have a UID in
page zero and you can't change it there
are rumors of Chinese ones where you can
change it but I've never seen one
personally that UID is only used in the
crypto handshake type stuff for all the
the handshaking it's not used for access
control decisions and that's important
because it's public data that's why it's
green you'll see a color scheme
appearing but that's why it's green the
red pages contain the keys and passwords
for the tag that provides the security
mechanisms and then the pages four to
seven contain user data which is 128
bits of information which essentially
makes up your person information so when
you go and turn up a building and wipe
you know flash your card at it that's
the information it's gonna make access
control decisions based on if we want to
copy these we need all of that and
obviously that's where the fun bit comes
in in both password and crypto mode they
have pre shared secrets they have to
because there's there might be lots and
lots of readers and an estate because
there might be lots of doors and it
might be lots and lots of tags in an
estate because there's lots of people
well the only way they can secure
communicate securely is if they both
know something that the other one knows
so it's shared secrets and mutual
authentication throughout so password
mode I said I'll talk about this very
briefly this is the protocol for how to
password mode as you can see
everything's in clear that means if you
can eavesdrop on the communications
which if it's your tag because you're
active insider or because you've stolen
a tag or found a tag then you can
eavesdrop the information and once
you've got those passwords you can then
interrogate the tag directly yourself so
we're not going to talk about password
mode again but proxmark and our
Fiddler's can both eavesdrop on these
things
crypto mode on the other hand and pop
from the the UID that sent at the begin
unclear because that kind of bootstraps
the process everything is encrypted
after it's it sends that the reader
sends it any nonce which is encrypted it
sends it a challenge response value the
challenge being ffff ffff
which gets encrypted and sent over the
tag can then decruz the nonce to see it
it's RNG decrypt the challenge response
value make sure it is ffff ffff
and then it can send back its page three
take a page which has got the conflict
byte and the tag password so the reader
can confirm it's the right kind of tag
from the right system at which point the
readers and then same commands and the
token them respond and all of that is
encrypted so in a nutshell this is how
it works from a very high level the
reader has the key the tag has the key
the reader seeds the it's PRNG with the
key and the nonce and the UID from the
tag it then encrypts the nuts or sends
it to the tag the tag seeds its RNG with
the key its UID and the encrypted nonce
it's just received and from that point
on which the two PRN GS on the reader
and the tag of both in step they're both
they're both seed to the same starting
point and as you extract extract bits
from each of them you'll get the same
bits out of each end so you can then use
it as a stream cipher or as the as the
pad for a stream cipher so stream
ciphers you'll know about stream ciphers
it's that famous XOR thing you basically
take get if you've got a 32-bit message
to send you ask for 32 bits from your
PRNG
you XOR that with your data and that
gives you encrypted data and then at the
other end the other end gets 32 bits out
of its pure energy which will be the
same 32 bits it with the same key stream
they XOR that with the encrypted data
and that gives them back the plaintext
and then the PRN Jews are back in step
again and and so it's quite
straightforward how they couldn't
communicate it's half duplex you know
it's like one talks and then the other
one talks so let's have a look at the
PRNG pseudo-random number generator for
those that are catching up it's a linear
feedback shift register now if you're
like me you'll have no idea what this is
before you come across it but a linear
feedback shift register is a very common
way of implementing
PRN G's
it's used all over the place in fact
NASA used lfsr's for various things
there's lots of different constructions
but this one's pretty straightforward so
it's 48 bits wide and it's initially
seeded with the UID and the lower 16
bits of the key this would be on the
reader and the tag let's start this sort
of handshake at this point the reader
generates a new nonce set it to bits
wide it X's that with the upper 32 bits
of the key and then it shifts that in to
the lfsr and as it shifts it in the bits
on the right fall out and disappear and
as it does it for every bit it shifts in
it generates a bit of pure energy output
which will be a pseudo-random bit stream
essentially so you're pushing in 32 bits
there were 32 bits of output coming out
it uses that 32 bits of output that's
come out to XOR that with the nonce
which essentially is encrypting it in
this stream cipher that we just talked
about and that gives you the encrypted
nonce which then becomes public data
because that's then transmitted to the
tag as an encrypted value the tag and
this bits quite clever or quite like
this it's sets itself up in the same
situation it can get a bit out of the
PRNG because you get the bit before you
shift the next one in again it's got the
upper 32 bits of the key and it's got
the encrypted nonce it's just received
well it does it basically excells the
first bit of that encrypted nonce with
the first bit of the pure energy output
and the lower of the last 32 bits of the
key and shifts that bit into the lfsr
which moves the whole thing along which
generates another bit of pure energy
output which we can then use to do the
second bit and then that whatever the
output is that goes back in it can do
the third bit you know the clever thing
is when it's done that both the tag and
the reader end up in exactly the same
situation because of the magic pixel so
this is now a fully seeded pseudo-random
number generator lfsr and as you can see
it's all red because these are values
that we do not know as an outsider yeah
we don't know where the key is and we
don't know what the nonce is all we know
is what the encrypted nonce is at this
point which as you can see is kind of
lost in the in the world at this point
at this point the feedback function is
enabled
and so from now war and we've seeded the
lfsr every time we generate a bit of
output and shift the lfsr we're not
shifting in seeding information we're
shifting in a new bit and that bit comes
from the feedback function so it now
becomes autonomous like any
pseudo-random number generator you seed
it at the beginning and then it just
keeps on generating well this is how it
generates so if we're encrypting data as
you see this is the stream cipher you
basically get as many bits out of it as
you want XOR that with your data and
that'll give you an encrypted data and
on the other end you take you encrypted
data XOR that with a PNG output and that
gives you back the original data so we
look quick look at the feedback function
is simply the XOR of 16 bits from the
lfsr I would say randomly chosen but
clearly not clearly like you know
someone decided this and designed this
thing but a 16 of those bits and if we
don't know the internal state of the
lfsr it'd be very hard to predict what
those sixteen bits are when they were
all XOR together you get one bit so
either one or one you know your chances
of guessing that without any information
is 50/50 as it should be now the output
from the PRNG
it's not simply the bits that fall off
the end when you push a new bit in it's
actually generated by a filter function
f and that filter function is made up in
a hierarchy of functions a B and C and
each of those functions take four bits
from the lfsr so you've got 48 bit state
we're going to pull 20 bits from that in
chunks of four and they feed into these
functions each of those produces one bit
of output which is 50-50 biased and
those five bits feed into function C
which produces one bit of output again
5050 biased and that output bit becomes
the output of the PRNG
so as you can see it's kind of hard for
us to predict what this pure energy is
going to output essentially you know
when you when you sort of start you're
sort of think oh you know there's bound
to be something really bad in the crip
side and there is which should all be
amazed by when we get to but so far this
is looking pretty solid I think you know
so right we'll go back to the protocol
so it's sent the encrypted nonce it's
then sent the challenge/response value
encrypted the tags confirmed that it's
replied with its page three value which
is the config in the password encrypted
again and then the reader gets to send
commands and the tag gets to respond to
him so let's talk about commands there
are four commands in hi tag - the vol 5
bits long so the first two bits
determine which command it is so you can
read the page you can read a page with
all the bits inverted you can write a
page and which will obviously require
following data you know what you want to
write and then there's a whole command
to turn a tag off which is useful in
collision environments where you've got
multiple tags you talk to the one that's
the loudest and then you hold here the
end and then you talk to the next one
that's loudest apparently not had it
confirmed but apparently they use this
in Las Vegas to track chips in the
gambling halls in the hotels and so they
can talk to hundreds of chips at once
using this kind of protocol so if you
happen to know their high tag - who
knows just saying but I'm not sure all
Vegas is the right place to get arrested
though so if you imagine that a command
is five bits long you don't just send
the five bit command you actually send a
10 bit command which is the 5 bit
command followed by the inverted version
of that 5 bit command for integrity
purposes you know you don't ask it to
read a page and accidentally what gets
received is read page inverted and give
you back the inverted version of the
page because that's not what you're
expecting equally you don't say read
page it sends your back right page you
know if so they've got integrity built
into the into the protocol and that's
basically just invert the five bits you
know so 1 to 0 0 to 1 except like not it
ok but you don't you don't only have to
do it twice you can do it as many times
as you want so as long as each block of
5 goes normal and then invert it than
normal than inverted than normal than
inverted you can do this as many times
as you like
literally for thousands of bits if you
want it to and to read the tag that
receives this will check after it's
decrypted it will check that each block
is the inverse of the next block all the
way along what it's just received to
confirm that there's been no errors in
transmission it's a very strong
integrity
thing something that we're gonna abuse
really badly in a second so let's go on
to some abuse so the paper that I
mentioned earlier gone in 360 seconds by
Vidal Garcia and Bosch three attacks in
that paper and I'm going to talk about
the first attack in this talk and in the
workshop tomorrow I'm going to talk
about tax two and three I would have
loved to have talked about all three in
an hour and as you'll see if you come to
the workshop tomorrow it just wasn't
really feasible not in any kind of debt
not in the kind of depth that you'd like
to see anyway so we'll talk about the
first one which is the nonce replay and
length extension for keystream recovery
attack I'm sure there's a pedophile
Drake in there but I can't quite think
what it is Offutt on my head right so
obviously you'll have noticed from that
protocol that we talked about earlier
that the the only entropy give given a
particular tag so if I've got a tag and
it's got a particular UID on it then as
long as we're only talking to this one
tag the UID doesn't change the key
doesn't change because it's the same key
on the entire system so the only entropy
in the system comes from the nonce
that's generated by the reader the tag
itself generates no entropy so that
means if we capture the encrypted nonce
and the encrypted challenge-response
value that's been sent from the reader
to the tag at some point then we can
pretend to be the reader and replay that
to the tag and there'll be valid values
you know there'll be nothing wrong with
those values and the tag will quite
happily respond to them that will cede
the PRNG on the tag to a particular
point which we don't know and we don't
know what that key stream is going to be
that comes out of it but what we can
guarantee is that every time we
initialize the tag with that
particularly encrypted nonce and
challenge-response value the PRNG will
go to the same place and start from the
same point and therefore have the same
key stream coming out of it every time
so we're going to use that this is the
non tree place side of it what we going
to do is every time we try and do
anything with the tag we're going to
start by initializing the tag with it
with the same encrypted nonce and that
means we'll have the keys the same key
stream in every session and all see
anyone who knows anything about
excellent crypto means that you know you
now got something you can attack so this
is just sort of set you remember after
the nonce was sent and after not so just
received by the tag that was the state
of the lfsr as you can see the only
entropy is the nonce the NR value this
is how we're going to emulate it
basically we're going to use so I'll
hold it up so you can see this is an R
fiddler I guess I guess everyone's seen
one it's like a proxmark but better for
low frequency so if you want to do top
tip if you want to do 125 kilohertz RFID
used in our Fiddler's they're only about
hundred pounds from aperture labs and
they're really good if you want to do
high frequent say use of proxmark 3
because there Adam who Adam Laurie who
wrote the code for this wrote the code
for the a lot of the high frequency code
for proxmark and that works but the low
frequency code for proxmark no idea who
wrote that but it crashes all the time
especially in the high tech world so
we're going to use that as an emulated
reader and that's going to replay the
same nonce every time we seed it so as
an example if we gave it the encrypted
nonce for a 85b to D F and then it would
see the PRNG
and it might produce the key string
naught 1 1 1 1 naught naught 1 1 1
naught 1 naught blah blah blah right and
every time we see the tag with that
nonce we're going to get that same key
stream hence the thing we're going to
that's what we're going to attack so the
way we're going to do this is we're
going to find the encrypted read page 0
command so we don't know the key stream
but we know there's a command out there
which will be the encryption of read
page 0 we're going to find that and
we're going to play that command and
it's going to give us the contents of
page 0 the reason we'll go for page
zeros because we already know the
plaintext of page 0 because that's the
UID which is presented at the beginning
of the session ok so we know the
plaintext for the command we were
looking for read page 0 and we know the
answer plaintext and so if we can find
the encrypted version of the command and
we can get the encrypted response we've
then got the encrypted versions of those
we can explore them together that'll
give us the key stream and then we've
kind of one okay so
encrypted commands a 10 bits long which
means there's a thousand 25
or potentials within there there's 16
valid read commands 8 4 read normal
nectar of inverted pages and when you
send a valid encrypted read command you
get back a 32-bit response but if you
send an invalid command you get back the
unencrypted error response and the
reason it's unencrypted is because
clearly your crypto has failed you know
if you ignore all hackers and just think
about the normal run of stuff there's
something's gone wrong in the process
well it can't reply with an encrypted
value because there's no guarantee of
the crypto set up correctly and that it
can decrypt what you've sent so the
error is always unencrypted it's always
that value there at 4:02 8 8 9 see so
we've now got an area that we can
compare against so the approach we're
gonna take is going to find one valid
encrypted read command not know which
one it is but fine one we're going to
bit flip that to find the other 15 and
then we're going to test each one until
we find the one that actually is read
page zero and then we're going to use
that to recover the key stream and from
there we're going to attack the card I'm
going to go through all those in detail
so here would be the simple brute-force
approach to finding a valid command
you've got a thousand twenty four of
them just try every one one after
another make sure you see the card
before you send a command and eventually
you'll hit a valid one that's quite lame
not very optimized so a different way of
doing it if you imagine that we've got
this encrypted command which is going to
be e f g h i j k l m n each of those is
a single bit we know that f will decrypt
to 1 and k will decrypt to 0 because CM
0 has to be a 1 for a read command and
the second half is the inverse of the
first half right so we also know that so
effing k must decrypt to 1 and 0 we know
that e G H and I must decrypt the
inverse of what jl m and n decrypt to
well if we don't care which we command
we're looking for we can hold jl m and n
2 zeros and that will decrypt to
something and then we can brute
EG h and i to find the inverse of those
when it gets decrypted so we actually
only need to brute-force six bits F and
K and
eghh and i so that gives us six bits 64
possibilities of which we're likely to
get hit after 32 so we've just kind of
reduced our program from a you know some
16 over a thousand or 24 down to 32 both
of those but yeah it's it's better so we
would cycle through those until we found
one encrypted read command that gives us
back any value other than the error
right and we'll call that efg hijk LMNOP
so what we're going to do now is we're
going to find all the other valid read
commands and we're going to use a bit of
magic so if you remember FD Crips - 1
and K 2 Crips to 0 and you know eg H and
I decrypt to the inverse of what J LM n
and decrypt e then we can flip some bits
because it's a stream cipher if you flip
a bit in the encrypted version it flips
a bit the same bit in the plain text
version
alright that's crypto 101 so if we if we
had an encrypted command that happened
to decrypt a read page for inverted for
example right and it happened to be this
key stream and it happened to be you
know this encrypted command that we had
if we flip the first bit which flips it
from a read inverted to a read command
you can see that we don't have to know
anything about the key stream or which
command we've got we just know that
flipping the first bit will flip that
come on but when we flip that first but
we also have to flip the sixth bit
because whatever the first one is going
to change to the other one's got to
change to the inverse of that so if we
flip a bit on the left side we also have
to flip the same but on the right side
but we don't care that it's encrypted it
just it flips the plaintext bits as well
so we can flip the inverted bit quite
happily equally if you've got the page
bits which are the second third and
fourth the third fourth or fifth bits on
the left-hand side and the third fourth
and fifth bits on the right-hand side if
it was reading verted page four we could
flip the fifth bit and it changed it to
page five and equally we have to flip
the same bit in the right-hand side of
the command
well so it's the same thing we're
flipping bits in the encrypted content
and it's flipping the bits in the
plaintext for us it's like a known
ciphertext attack it's that kind of that
kind of world
so using that we can build up a massive
table there's any four bits to flip and
the same four bits on the right-hand
side and which is 16 possibilities which
is the right number a we ate normal and
eight in varied so we just build a big
table that flips all of those we don't
have send anything else to the tag we
can just from getting one encrypted read
pile we can then get the other 15
instantly but instantly it's a couple of
hours of C but you know so now you've
got a table of all sixteen read commands
one of those will be read page zero not
inverted which is the one we're looking
for because we already know the answer
to page 0 which is the OID so what we're
going to do is we're going to
essentially test each one yes really
straightforward and every time we test
one we will initialize the tag so that
we get the same key stream otherwise
none of this works all bets are off but
want the same key stream every time so
we're gonna use our you know emulated
video remember we're sending the same
month each time so you get the case same
key stream every time so what we're
going to do is we know it would take our
first guess we're going to assume it's
correct right
so we're going to assume our 10 bit
guess I our first 10 bit encrypted
command is read page 0 and we're going
to assume the response we get back is
the UID so we can XOR the encrypted
command that we send and the encrypted
response we get back with the plaintext
command for V page 0 and the plaintext
response of what it should be which is
the ID page 0 and that'll give us the
first 42 bits of key stream if we're
right how do we know if we're right well
if you remember the extended command bit
we've had earlier you can make your
commands as long as you like well we can
make a 40-bit read page 0 command but
basically just repeating the blocks so
there's eight blocks in here you can see
you've got a normal block and an
inverted block repeat it four times
which makes 40 bits so that would be a
you know a really really high integrity
we paid zero command right well we can
reset the tag by reinitializing the PRNG
again by doing the
hello in his I replayed nonce so we're
back to the same key stream we were
using before and then we can take our 40
bit read page zero command XOR that with
the first 40 bits of the key stream that
we think we've recovered if we were
right and that will give us an encrypted
repo zero card we then play that to the
tag having you know initialize the tag
and we are either get back the error
response which means that it didn't
decrypt properly as in the integrity
failed and know that that isn't read
page zero that we've found and move on
to our next possible guess or we get
back a 32-bit response which isn't the
error and if we get that we know that
that is the tag replying to read page
zero so that is the encrypted version of
page zero which we know so we can XOR
those together and get the next 32 bits
a key stream no it's a really neat
attack I'm yeah it may I say it made me
think about crypto differently the way
these academics go about this so at this
point we've got a replayable nonce
challenge response pair where we can
integrate the tag and we've got 70 to 72
bits of key stream which is more than
enough for what we want to try so what
we want to do is read all eight pages so
basically in a loop from naught to seven
we basically initialize the tag with
that we played nonce so we set the key
stream to what we now know the key
stream is we make a command read page n
or I in this case increment and then we
encrypt it so we XOR that with the first
ten bits of the key stream send it to
the tag the tag will quite happily say
yes that's a valid command that is this
thing and reply with an encrypted
response well we can XOR that with the
next 32 bits of key stream that we've
got and that will give us back the clear
text version of that page so we're now
communicating with the tag as if we knew
the key but we still don't know the key
all we've got is the key stream that
tanks using because we've used the nonce
FreePlay
and the integrity protection to ensure
that so it's quite a neat little trick
and because you do the whole thing in a
loop you only need the first 42 bits of
key stream because each time and you
reinitialize and use the same bit of key
stream again so that should give us back
all eight pages of the tag and you
notice that the key is convenient ages
one and two and the tag password is
convenien page three so once you've got
back your 8p
you can then write down the key and from
this point onwards you can just off to
the tag by setting your own reader to
use that key and then you don't have to
do any of this monkeying around
so you crack one tag in a system you can
then make a reader that can read
anyone's tag you know you know if you
only have to crack crack it won't you'll
have to crack it every time so of course
if you like me you go to the art fiddler
page and you download the source code
and then you download the build
environment which is mplab IDF of pics
80 which takes about five hours to
install on Arch Linux you know there's
the longest five hours of my life and
you find it's all in C and if you can
see that that's that's some of my
horrendous code but it's all C and you
can find all the codes you need within
our fiddler so in there I've written
like a transmit and receive function but
I basically just went mining like the
our fiddler code and found commands that
I liked and then tweak them in and hack
them until they worked so all of this
code is well it's all it's all on a
github whether Adams pushed the button
and brought it into the main master I
don't know but he's supposed to do it
today so today tomorrow next week
sometime
I've seen him next week actually a
hardware to IO so if it's not by next
week I'll make sure it is next week
sorry yes yeah yeah we've had
disagreements over style as you'd
imagine
mainly I have no coding style and Adam
yes so here's the commands that I've
added to our fiddler six high tech two
commands basically the crack function
which is the attack I've just talked
about key stream function which
retrieves key stream which we need for
attack to I'm talking about tomorrow a
high tack to reader which actually will
just given a key will just read tags
quite happily and if you give it s it
will store them in NVRAM so you can
power the off vigil off a battery so you
don't eat your laptop then you can just
like sort rip off people's tags it just
took someone into everywhere and when
you took it back into your computer you
can then list the account how many there
are and then
and I've modified the sniff pwm function
so to actually read the nonce encrypted
not encrypted challenge-response values
that the reader presents to the tag so
again you can power that goes all goes
to NVRAM so you can power your are
fiddler and stick it on the reader and
present a tag and it will capture those
values for you so you've got some values
to use in the attacks so the way this
attack would work very quickly is you
set it too high tag to mode you'd clear
the PWM non storage tell it to sniff as
in whatever in command which means you
can pair it from a battery stick on the
antenna load value stick plug into your
computer list the values you've got and
then use one of them in the attack
against the same tag that you've just
got a nonce for would you like to see a
demo so this is the live demo there is
no recording if you see it's easier up
here right so this is our fiddler it's
so all in mini-com so there's all my my
new functions shiny so make it high-tech
to write I've got so I've got to our
features appear got another one acting
like a reader I will say like getting a
high tag to readers really hard I've got
one for a building access system but
it's not a normal one it does the stuff
that is far too complicated to talk
about these talks but it's slightly more
involved protocol but getting an actual
high tag to video so first make them and
there's other people who make them
technology box up one form a company
called frequent and Technology horrible
to deal with like just just to say I
think I've tried to deal with them not
very nice people and the first one I
can't make any of them work about three
my hands and none of them work so I'm
using another our fiddler as a reader
abusing my high tech to read oh c'mon
so so we're sniffing the pwm traffic and
you can see they're just our earth come
on because the reed is costly start
walking and I'll put a tag on put a tag
on be right they go so you can sort of
see interacting and you can see the
nonce keeps changing the PRN yep so that
would be how we'd capture the oh it goes
off the side of the screen that's a
shame did it the joys of live demos a
right oops I don't think I was on the
mic was it good so use high tech and
then put a come on get the tags around
yeah right so yeah so you can see the
PRN is the encrypted nonce and the
secret is the encrypted
challenge/response value if we were just
then go like list the ones that we've
got I've got nodes that we've just
captured doing that so you could take
this and put it on the reader and you
could capture a challenge response
encrypt or not so challenge response
value you probably want to capture a few
because if any of these bits have been
flipped in the RF world then they become
useless to you so get more than one
because you probably need them now
if so take my tag we can take the last
one I actually doing it live and right
even using like and values we take the
last one I've got a tag I've got a tag
on there at the moment
sorry no yep there all right so we hit
crack and we give it the encrypted nonce
encryption challenge response value
yeah okay I need to move my laptop
around a little bit it's the fields over
um right oh it worked okay let's let's
just run that again and see if it works
like properly now I've moved all the
stuff out of the way yeah this looks
look yeah
oh yeah that's because it would have hit
a non read command at that point yeah so
that's how the attack should look okay
so there you go that is a TAC one
working and then we could that's one
eight pages yeah so can you see can
everyone see I can't even for my mouse
as well can you everyone see this so
that's the UID there which is public
that is the lower the upper 32 bits of
the key that is the lower 32 lower 16
bits of the key that's the conflict bite
and the tag password and these this is
all day to user data that's my office
phone number if anyone cares because you
have to put some it in their head you
know right so we could then go hi to
reader so we could paste this in so 6
and we these are like test cards I've
made myself as you can tell then they're
not from any real system so you know
don't go right in that key down I think
it's going to get you in anywhere but so
so that's reading tags now if I grab the
other tags you can see as a second
there's a second tag beef face and third
tag feed face so you know I said the
Vedic wise but free straightforward
that's right
I don't know how badly I'm doing for
time it's a quarter past three you're
not finished at half past is that right
oh wow
it's almost like I practiced this right
so once you've got the eight pages of
data it's really easy to clone a tag
okay because we can either use hi tag to
reader which I just demonstrated there
or you can take the eight pages that you
got from the crack command and write
them into the V tag so a V tag on hi on
our fiddler is a virtual tag so you tell
it what what type the virtual tag is so
set V tag Kai Tak tun it'll create all
the white space and structures for pi
tag to eight pages and then you can just
rewrite zero for bank zero and then the
bank zero contents v right one for Bank
one or if you want you can go V write
zero and then all eight banks and it
will just check the whole lot in and
once that's in the V tag you can put a
blank high tag to on the antenna and go
clone and then tell it the password or
key of the blank which is in the
specification sheet for high tag two
tags I've got it in text files
everywhere because I always forget it's
like 4 9 4 d something like that but it
is it's mi kar in capitals in ASCII
essentially but but you can find it in
the specification sheet and what so you
need that in order to off to a blank tag
because a blank tag already has a
password on it and it was already in
password mode but once you know it it's
dead easy UID 0 the you can't change
page 0 but the page 0 UID value is only
used to set up the crypto it's not used
for access control decisions typically
because it's public why would you and I
say it can be done at distance with the
right equipment I would argue that
technology using a friend Qin African HT
RM 801 it's not the right equipment
because the read range was only about 18
centimeters and the whole thing died and
we don't quite know why yet we have done
a full post-mortem but that's probably
not the right equipment we have
alternative ideas I'm going to talk
about those in the workshop if anyone is
interested in long range high tech to
reading so if you cared and you want it
to like copy Tom's car keys or you want
it to get access to a building that is
using high tech 2 then you put one along
the edge reader as part of your like
been around stealing things up people
realizing you you will have the same
problem that we've had and you've got to
build something right so it's not
trivial but if with the right equipment
or with a really good RF electrical
engineer you might be able to build the
right thing we're not really good our
electrical engine hits as you can
probably tell so closing remarks
this attack needs access to a tag you do
need a valid tag to do this attack right
so you have to either be an insider and
have one or steal one or borrow one or
be a contractor or find one on the
street or something right you do need a
tag and you need one valid encrypted
nonce and Christian response value but
that's easy when it's got the tag you
just go to any reader stick the our
fiddler on it wipe your pass and you'll
get the nonces as you saw it takes
literally seconds to crack a card which
i think is awesome now you can but your
is recommended in the tag specification
to read protect pages one two and three
right which contains the key and the tag
password and if and that's basically a
conflict by setting and if you do that
then even with the key or the key stream
you can't read pages one two and three
so you can get the user data but you
won't be able to copy the tag because
you won't know what those keys are well
attacks two and three which I'm talking
about tomorrow at half past 9:00 in the
morning honestly crypto in the morning
two hours a crypto you know it makes
sense right
I don't know what state you're being but
I will not be in a fit state to be
talking maths but that that will recover
the key using different techniques and
they're both awesome like they both
build and they're build on this and
they're different to this but if if you
like novel kind of crypto attacks they
are I think they're pretty amazing so
that is it does anyone have any
questions
[Music]