all right welcome everybody thanks for
coming in sitting in on my talk about
remotely exploiting connected vehicle
API is in applications so first my name
is Aaron Guzman Twitter handles up there
as a scripting xs/s first things first I
love pizza this already this trip I've
been here since Tuesday at Pizza three
times already
each different places of course but
everywhere I go everywhere I travel
Pizza is definitely on the list I'm from
Los Angeles I'm a co-organizer of apps
at California which is an awesome
conference in Los Angeles and Santa
Monica on the beach last week of January
any of you guys you don't want to get
away from the cold and rainy cloudy
weather I manage the volunteers and get
you in for free i hack all the things
literally I used to work at balcony and
Linksys so that's kind of how I got
wrapped up and embedded in IOT ace elite
security for the networking aspects so
that's like the routers and the cameras
as well the technical editor for
practical and Internet of Things book
that came out last year and the second
revision just came out actually I'm
actually currently writing a book for
pentesting I wrote a cookbook for packet
publishing as well finishing the last
chapter so that should be out maybe in
the next month or so I'm a board member
for OAuth Los Angeles as well as cloud
security alliance out of California I
contribute to a lot of white papers my
current employer is GDS Gotham digital
science so today's topic what you guys
are all here we'll be talking about
Subaru StarLink remote services and
specifically that is the in vehicle
technology and the capabilities that
Subaru has introduced into their cars
from some 2016 models and all 2017
moving forward and what you can do is
you can unlock lock your vehicle you can
honk the horn you can locate you can
have a vehicle Health Report you could
schedule any services you can see
personal information VIN number
addresses and then we'll go into the
details afterwards as far as you know
the the exact
a data that is captured with a Subaru
StarLink what it doesn't have though is
a remote start feature so it's purely
just unlock lock honk the horn but I
mean someone could really just purchase
an add-on it's only 300 and something us
to install a remote engine start and I'm
pretty sure there's a capability to
remotely use that in the application so
and I'm sure it might be introduced in
the future but just to kind of set the
stage it is only unlock lock locate the
vehicle as well as the owner so again I
mentioned only a certain number of
vehicles are supported for StarLink
anybody have a Subaru by chance show
hands oh wow that's good I guess all
right so uh so like I said there's
mostly 2017 and 18 moving forward but
there's also some 2016 models and
because I mean for that exact reason I
asked you guys how many you know how
much how many of you guys have a Subaru
no hands so literally I purchased a
vehicle to you know perform research on
it and I had a 2016 version thinking
that it was gonna be connected but I
didn't have telematics so literally I
waited till you know my lease you know
six months got to till 2017 and we'll go
through the timeline afterwards but you
know it's it's fun story but along with
the motivations was that dmca for the
u.s. you know they're exempt for
anything
IOT or consumer products so you can now
test security research as long as it's
lawfully acquired as long as you have
good faith it's an instant controlled
environment so it's totally fair game
now which is cool and definitely I have
a Impreza STI so it's a fun car for sure
but I didn't want you know a leaf or you
know a Prius not only that I mean
research has been done on that by you
know you guys already know from from
years already and again we're gonna have
my 2016 version it did have capabilities
to log in and manage my car just the
services like you know just schedule
schedule service with like a sales sales
branch office of Subaru
but not nothing crazy so I'm gonna jump
right in and show you guys exactly what
I found then I'll go through the
methodology which I found it kind of go
the opposite way typically so here we go
I figured you know might as well be
cliche from Los Angeles might as well
you know throw me that Santa Monica
hello everyone today we will be
demonstrating exploitation remote
exploitation of super-move Starling
conducts services to unlock lock the
vehicle add two users to the account
which has full control over a Subaru
account also you used to deport but what
other demonstrate today is just adding
two users unlocking the vehicle honking
the horn and flashing the lights
so first what will get started is making
sure the vehicle is locked by pressing
the lock button twice here this is the
exact video I said to Subaru so there's
also the videos following up just so you
know it's the exact video and then we'll
place the keys here on top and first
show you that there are no authorized
authorized users to a Subaru account
here and screen crash
[Applause]
refuseniks so let's go ahead and script
here
it's appear to have a previous one let's
go
you'll run it again just to show or
bypass Equalization the vehicles going
to unlock then foreigners going to mount
keep an eye on the keys on top of the
roof car is now a lot
and the horn will hug the lights went
out flash
so now that we know cars unlocked horn
horns honking let's make sure the car is
unlocked let's check out cars unlocked
full access and then let's check the
users that have been added to be my
super account then again keys are up
here and remember we did block the car
so refreshing the screen over here for
my super account you can now see two
users have been added again these two
users have full access to my super
account to view everything as if you
were the owner and not a subset so it's
also something to keep in mind
so again works of in two percent of the
time remotely unlocking the vehicle I
saw the keys were on the roof here and
we unlocked the car honk the horn and
flashlights again this is a Subaru WRX
STI 2017
so here's how it looks and you're adding
the users authorized users
well again authorized users have the
full same access as if you were the
owner so I'll discuss the steps in which
you know how the script is created and
and the vulnerabilities and such my
script here so the infrastructure in
which Subaru runs it runs like I said
for 4G 18 t but then he also goes
through Amazon AWS so take some time
loose back around
I even tried this I found it right
before RSA in San Francisco
I even tried it on the airplane and it
worked I want to make sure like it
worked all the time
so these are the two emails car hacking
car honking email at gmail car honking
email one at gmail so I should flip back
over to the Subaru page refresh now we
have two users and they don't even have
to have a Subaru or my Subaru account it
just sends an email and they create an
account so you can literally just kind
of make up email addresses and and again
I'll go through some of the other
vulnerabilities that were observed
so there we have it now let's swap back
over here so it's pretty simple actually
it's nothing groundbreaking you'll see
why you know this is what one of my
buddies coined old remote executable WRX
STI there was no articles written about
this when I released it back in June and
it kind of influenced the new
applications being built for Subaru so
now they totally rebuilt it but here's
like the timeline in which I purchased a
vehicle late January actually got
delivered to my house a couple days
later I paying my buddy Samy Kamkar you
guys know Sammy he's hilarious so he
looks kind of close by and I was like
hey dude I got this new connected
vehicle you know they start hacking he
goes yeah man do you have any peak apps
you have any uh any burp state files
anything or anything and literally you
know within you know an hour you can see
726 856 I wrote him back like actually
dude it's pretty simple to do from the
mobile on web app found an off bypass
testing session fixation XSS and a way
to add a user from a user to my account
who can also unlock my car going to
script it up he was like awesome man so
then I created a video on the 2nd of
February but I felt it was it wasn't a
good quality was like in a park and I
needed to be again cliche go to Santa
Monica because I live in Los Angeles so
recorded that video we just saw I just
closed the Subaru the findings super
acknowledged the findings after you know
heckling around finding the correct
person to speak to I got an update from
Subaru a month later that they fixed the
critical vulnerabilities that I
discovered like off bypass one of them
section fixation and then they deployed
new my Subaru apps for iOS and Android
and again not the web app yet so then I
was in touch with the journalists over
in Australia I was doing a separate
embedded talk and that's you know kind
of hobby the articles got written but he
had gone in
with their communications you know in
legal counsel and kind of sparked a fire
and some drama stir things up so it
turns out you know when it was published
the new web application also was
revamped and deployed which is totally
different and again same thing with the
in my super app for Android and iOS and
now again I'll talk about you know what
these apps are you know what they
consist of and as far as you know
libraries and the steps I took to kind
of disassemble the applications but they
were pretty easy to work with they gave
me some credit you know give them
details on how to fix things they were
too bad they're you know open to open to
research and open to you know finding
you know to the community basically so
again how I got started the first thing
I always do I'll perform a threat model
whether it's in my head whether I'm
writing it down and I already knew
there's you know connected vehicles
there's you know Bluetooth maybe we can
afford GE LTE the RF from the key fobs
there's you know SD cards that get
plugged into the infotainment system
there's there's tuning tuning
applications and and accessories like
Cobb there you know the ECU there's also
you know obd2 and canvas but again I
knew there was Android app iOS app and a
web app and again Finnick the vehicles
are the same thing as IOT very very
simple you find the weakest link in the
chain but you know so for me I'm apps
tech pentester so I'm gonna go you know
the easiest route which is app sec and
mobile apps and especially mobile apps
the first thing you're gonna start you
know it's probably Android iOS but you
know again IOT so easy take the vehicles
it's the same thing there's so many
again attack surfaces and you know hard
work sucks all right why go for
something difficult
have to be physically there when I can
you know do it in my office and not have
to be next to my car sitting down there
sweating so again first thing Android of
course because and ER is easiest to kind
of disassemble and the apps and there's
so many tools literally can do it in a
matter of seconds can disassemble the
apk and analyze the classes the methods
monitor activities services and intent
so my goal was to almost statically
analyze their code and find
vulnerabilities in their logic and
anyone any wonder about libraries and
dependencies that they were using I mind
you I did like I said last year I had
researched their apps before I had any
like telemetry in my car or telematics
system in my car so I had an idea
already
you know what the app consists of but
they did change some things however I
did look at the findings that that I
sent last year which was a hard-coded
client ID and secret for oauth2 which is
not not good you can basic identity
without putting using or a password
similar to what I found but we'll get to
that in a bit so I find it's a hybrid
app the hybrid app meaning its most
basically a web application in a mobile
app you know so it's not a native
application and then what I did you know
perform recon and just you know all the
application functions I did you know how
the login logout unlock lock hunk the
horn flashlights locate the vehicle
owner of the view health reports and
this is all through I did it through
burp and zap as well anybody anybody use
that no one ever uses app okay we got
one loyal easier yeah so yeah so I
basically had a baseline you know I
highlighted things commented to you know
just get an idea what I can attack first
so next step was to set up the iOS
infrastructure and and proxying as well
and at first again I start statically
right I get the application decrypt it I
drop it in hopper so I can look at the
code statically analyze the code so it's
a little little tiny bit more work than
Android but again it's the same steps
you're gonna dump the classes and the
methods you Freight look for anything
that's hard-coded anything that may be
vulnerable I look at the runtime
behavior you know when the app is
running and then I also have some
findings from last year which is they
had a handoff token that was in the URL
not resolved and we'll get to that in a
bit
they also cashed all requests and
responses and put it in a cash database
on the iOS device so like literally
everything like your PII data your
passwords your tokens everything is
cached so they kind of fixed it though
they picked and choose what what they
were going to to cache but it still had
sensitive data so again I'm gonna add a
lot analyze the storage on disk
whether that be P list file secret light
databases local storage files and ROM
databases and then I went to the same
approach proxy to all API calls from the
mobile app login logout lock unlock honk
the horn flashlights locate the vehicle
end owner and then view the help report
in the help report just says you know
all systems are good tells you the
mileage it tells you if there's any
issues it gives you literally the usage
report of how many times you've unlocked
a car locked it how many times you used
a locate so it gives you you know pretty
pretty granular details I mean usage
data which could be used you know
privacy wise they can also edit vehicle
details so you could have a nickname for
the car you can also add license plate
things you can add I mean you can change
a number of different things there's
only a few actually so let me show you
what I found last year so you have some
sort of context and you'll see it's it's
not it's not hard at all again this is
the same exact video that was sent over
to Subaru as well last year it's only a
minute so so here's the handoff token
here was a big arrow it's a handoff
token it's just uh like a Olaf token and
this is in the cache database here so
what I did is I pulled this cache
database from an iOS device and now I'm
using a sequel Lite browser to view the
contents of the sequel Lite database and
everything says blob but usually
whenever I see sicklied databases and it
has a blob I just kind of click in the
middle see what I find and it's uh you
know it's binary data but not really
uh-huh
you just send it to you know make
when you get a text file you can see
these are all the requests and responses
that are cast so literally copy and
paste I hand off token there boom logged
in but wait it gets better
and we log out and we log out and then
try it again sweet and even if you log
out of the obviously you log out of the
phone as well or anything it sits there
all it's always live and it creates new
tokens as well so it's like you know
nested tokens and they never expire so I
could imagine like they're you know the
database you know their session states
so what I did well we'll see
so that was installer that's the bug
that basically got me it was fixed last
year I talked about that a little bit at
Iowa village last year and it was fixed
before I gave the talk
somehow they reemerge their code and
reintroduced it you know cuz you know
that happens I guess okay so next step
you know I went through the web
application again same methodology wise
proxied everything except there's more
options in the web application you can
change specific settings you can get
into more detail changing a pin because
they're certain you know there's there's
a pin code that you are supposed to use
to make these remote service calls every
time you know you go through the app or
through the web application supposed to
put a four-digit pin which could be 1 1
1 1 or 0 0 0 0 by the way you can change
the password security questions as well
and again there's two personal data and
similar
everything's on verb and the app as well
so from there I had a good baseline for
the app set point of view again not from
like the firmware aspect yet although I
did pull the firmware this week from my
car so stay tuned with that so there's
some roadblocks what I saw and some
differences between the apps I saw for
anytime I was gonna lock the car or any
remote service there was a unique
session ID in the post parameter almost
like a CSRF token but I couldn't find
where it was exactly coming from it
wasn't hard-coded in the mobile app I
wasn't coming from the sir
because I was looking at I was proxying
it so I moved on just noted that as
something that was an of an issue and
again I was in fear of session
expiration and randomization but as we
saw in the last video you know they may
not be an issue and there's security
questions in a pin like I just mentioned
they must be sent to make remote service
calls on all the apps and the remote
service calls send emails to the owner
if they have it set up but by default
they do but it's most not all of the
remote service calls and same thing with
the security questions and pin so here
we go again we talked about the
authorized users who have full control
so here's you know again what's what's
observed here the owner does not get
notified if users get added and you can
add as many users you don't have a limit
so I mean users you can add which is
strange found a cross-site scripting in
the vehicle name so they're you know
that's huge
again no anti CSS or have tokens for
state changing configurations like pin
security questions names and so forth
your URL rewrite everywhere so same
thing as the last video everything's in
the URL that things you know not not
everything is being sent as a post body
request the mobile apps work and we'll
get to the web application as well
making the token never expires ever we
talked about that even if you log out or
change your password which is funny then
we talked about you know there's no I
mean there's new tokens that get issued
if when you have a new device as well
and installed so if I have if I have two
accounts and I have three devices you'll
have you know three tokens for one
account three tokens for another account
that's that's three devices here each
each device has a token it's all tied to
the same account so I have in red up
here car hacking email car hacking email
one at the bottom so in the red you can
see there's two different devices I had
a Android device and two iOS devices
then those are
you tokens that were issued you can do
again more you go through emulators you
can do whatever you want really anything
grab a token for that user let me take a
step back to this I can show you guys
this was the cross-site scripting
vulnerability in the vehicle it's a
vanilla cross-site scripting like
literally no output encoding whatsoever
and I use that obviously as a foothold
to get one of these tokens because that
you know we have to have a valid session
in order to make these calls to the user
account that my super user account so
again you can keep making these these
tokens here they can go on forever you
can have ten tokens for one user same
thing with ten users and even not you
only have to get the the owner's token
you can also get an authorized users
token and have the same access so say I
delegate you know I sign I don't know my
little sister an account and that her
token gets compromised and the chicken
someone who has access to that token can
also perform the same calls as me as the
owner well here's some more
vulnerabilities of course the web
application sends everything as get
requests even the remote service calls
without a session ID the unique session
ID I was talking about that I had an
issue with for the mobile applications
so I checked that one off was that cool
don't worry about that anymore and the
web application also didn't require a
pin or security questions to send these
remote service calls so again
weak weak link obviously the web
application and as you can see over here
to the bottom right you don't have to
verify your PIN you can just create a
pin and confirm it same thing with your
security questions so no validation and
definitely vulnerable to replay attacks
and there was no certificate painting or
cert validation for no sir cleaning for
iOS but for Android there was oddly
enough but you can still proxy the
traffic because there wasn't any
certificate validation and no
rate-limiting so you can keep sending
these calls as long
the car is going to accept the calls
there is a tiny delay like five seconds
but that's because it's going through
AWS coming back down it's already making
the call I'm processing it so nothing
crazy so at this point I'm like yes I
have everything I need I already have
you know I have an exercise I have a way
to obtain a handoff token and CSRF and I
can just you know a craft a malicious
page with the cross side scripting
payload to gain a valid session with the
token then then right there add a user
and make remote service calls via CSRF
very very simple it sounds simple you
guys know what CSRF is it's forging
basically forging values from from the
my super account so in this case it's
the remote service calls so unlock you
just send literally it's over you know
it's a get request you just send with
you know a timing and it's like either
zero delay or now all you have to do is
plug in the handoff token and it and
your game it's good so you obviously you
can automate that you can just send you
know HTML page if someone's logged in
and then from there you know use the
same methods you know the cross site
scripting obtain the token or you can do
it manually to add the users all you
really need is that token to be honest
and again you can track the track the
owner and track where the car is that as
well so for example right now my car is
in Los Angeles and I am over here and if
you press even this little map so it
gives you directions right to the car
like literally where the car is at like
I went I went earlier today and I was
like wow it's back Lee my address so
it's pretty pretty course so here are
some attack scenarios you know we talked
about utilizing the cross-site scripting
you can have the victim login on the
attackers device hey can you show me
real quick can you unlock your car very
very simple you can have the victim you
know you want you want to charge your
phone you know and then from there trust
it back back up the the contents for
Android and iOS you know depending on
what device they have because on their
Android application you can backup the
applique
data as well so nothing again all you
need is the hand off token so once you
have that you know it's fair game so you
can also just man in the middle again
they're very very very targeted anything
with in IOT connected vehicles anything
like that is very targeted tax I mean
even if you're on the corporate network
and you're logging in with your super
account you can look at the audit logs
you know they're all get requests if
they're all proxy they're not doing any
cert validation you know some admin can
use that as well
it's pretty sad and against social
engineering again to obtain a token you
can install a malicious application I
forgot to mention they did log
everything to console and to log cat so
in console iOS and log cat for Android
so you can easily grab that data and
you'll even have to again authenticate
for the iOS device you can plug it in
and have a console running to grab just
the token so it's very very simple if
somebody knows someone who has a Mike
Subaru connected vehicle to get that
token aside from you know cross-site
scripting more technical approach so
here's the auto log-in this is the new
application actually literally it just
have my credentials just paste it in
there every time I open up the app you
just press login
so if someone logs in one time you know
from the on the attackers phone you can
have it forever so you know once you
have access what can you do pretty
obvious the first one you can still the
car contents sabotage the vehicle the
vehicles engine could be expensive
though for my car could be expensive iq
retain persistence tune in the car the
cars account get implanted out of bound
tracker if you wanted to Wi-Fi pineapple
with GSM you know those things are fun
as well some post post post exploitation
stuff you can also like I said there's
no rate limiting you can loop the car
locking API calls and maybe haven't
Forenza I don't know I could drain the
battery definitely that's that's
something that you can you can do if
you're making these calls all day and
night you know your battery's gonna
drain at some point you pump there's not
a way they're gonna be able to stop
unless they call Subaru and even at that
we'll talk about maybe some steps
afterwards what someone will do but I
guess the biggest issue here is it puts
personal safety at risk people at risk
of you know their content not only their
contents but you know something should
happen to them their safety as far as
their privacy their location those are
definitely things to keep in mind here
and I mean obviously the list goes on as
far as post exploitation scenarios once
you have access to a vehicle and their
account so talk about the likelihood and
impact again we talked about how many
vehicles have Mike Subaru you know
connected remote services but you have
to purchase the plan you get I think a
few months free then you have to pay
ninety nine us a year after that and
again you know it's it's very targeted
attack and it could be were mobile via
the authorized users like I said the
tokens all you need is one token from
one user you're authorized and it could
be a stranger's account really so
likelihood right now it's probably low
but the impacts pretty high although I
did read this article last week and it
was in a basically states that there
have been no reports of you know any
hackers or any criminals targeting
self-driving vehicles or just vehicles
and general connected vehicles so it got
me thinking like well are there any
indicators of compromise how is a user
going to know how is a manufacturer
going to know how are they going to let
the service centers the technicians now
are there going to be qualified enough
to make those decisions I'm sure they're
gonna say it's an electrical problem if
their cars unlocking they're probably
going to replace the telematics system
and then you know what's the next
escalation path as far as law
enforcement and sharing that data with
other car manufacturers and you know as
far as their teams you know how many how
many of them have incident response
teams that can go to you know whatever
an incident happened with the car being
compromised and how long would that take
and even us as professionals how would
we know I mean I don't know if I even
know I there's only certain things that
obd2 logs and they have a number of
modes here
it's ten modes and there have they have
other details metadata basically rpm
speed temperature I guess pretty
detailed but how are you gonna log
something you don't know what to look
for and especially in the talam attics
area so you know that's it's it's a
question and a Food for Thought to think
you know in the future how this is going
to be handled and shared with other
manufacturers as well so I'm sure right
now it's just in its infancy as far as
connected vehicles and and cars and you
know there's more to come so it's kind
of switch gears and talk about some
manufacturer lessons and and usually
when I do submit bugs to vendors and to
a couple car manufacturers uber being
one of them I always send them some
extra references and some some things
they should try and implement like a
disclosure policy you know it's pretty
difficult to get a hold of them but once
I did it was fairly simple I pointed
them to some best practices with Nitzer
ness that's in the States as well as
well as Auto Isacc which is basically
where the auto manufacturers share data
amongst each others if they're a part of
the group or a member of the group and
there's also some guidance documents
observations recommendations on
connected vehicle security with cloud
security alliance and there's a five
star automotive safety program from I am
the Calvary which has you know some
things like the disclosure policy as one
of the steps and incident response plans
things like that anybody heard of I'm
the Calvary okay and from I guess the
coding standpoint there's plenty of
guidance documents cheat sheets
especially from wasps you have you know
if you're building a new application or
applications already existed you can use
the application security verification
standard from wasp so it's basically a
set of requirements and and basic and
checks
an application should perform and they
have one for mobile as well and then
there's also the embedded application
security project which I lead shameless
plug but I mean there's best practices
that they can all follow from all
aspects of the connected vehicle but
definitely threat modeling is something
that should happen like please threat
model and here's the basic you know a
basic threat model methodology and it's
kind of you know how you would do it as
an attacker or internal enterprise
identify all the assets create a you
know architecture diagram decompose it
identify the threats document the
threats and rate the threats and this
goes for again every piece of software
and continuous testing internal external
even use you know third party platforms
to get more eyes basically on the code
bases and definitely observe and learn
from other manufacturers downfalls so
it's not all doom and gloom they've
actually improved as far as Subaru they
had some new know some little some
little features that were added one of
them is your last sign-on okay that's
cool at least I'll know you know when
someone's signed on by the way there's
no concurrent login limit or no I mean
not even an alert and I think within the
context of a car or vehicle that's
something that you might want to have
just to be aware of that someone else
has logged into your vehicles account
but they actually implemented output
encoding let's show you guys right here
so obviously that's gonna be my name
everything's always script tag stuff for
me see if anything executes they now
have rate limiting in place they don't
send raw credentials over the wire
everything's over posts now and your
account gets locked out and now you have
an option to do eyes devices and you can
see how many devices are logged into
your account and so again it's it it was
a matter of two months and they put all
these security controls in place that's
pretty cool from from a manufacturer to
do that from basically almost nothing
and now you know some some basic things
controls and probably some logging on
their side as well that can help you
know improve their security posture as a
whole
so guys any any questions
[Music]