hello
my name is paolo gonzalez and this is my
colleagues from ramirez
we are proud to introduce the atv pound
adversarial emulation and offensive
technics collaborative project
we are proud to be at activities this
year
besides we like very much the fmc part
and that's why we bring a tool call it
80-pound which helps to perform the
emulation of aversaries
also we want to tell you about the
collaborative side of
drawing first of all let's introduce
ourselves i am paulo phaleth i work at
telefonica in spain in april innovation
department
where we are very lucky to play with
cyber security and artificial
intelligence
we will develop several open source
tools
a year and try to contribute with crazy
ideas
i am mvp of microsoft
science since 2017
i have written some books in spanish
about cyber security
and i am a teacher at several
universities in
spain well my partner
fran ramirez works with me at telefonica
in the same
industrial department focusing on social
security and machine learning projects
he has worked several years in the usa
as a senior assistant administrator has
writing
some books about docker and machine
learning
before we discuss the tool and shows the
use cases first card
let's have a look at mitre 80 and ziki
the emulation of adversaries has become
extremely important directing work
it's an exercise that provides a glimpse
into the potential for a real threat
like many others that both business and
society have experienced
to affect an organization the goal is to
be capable capable
of verifying if the organization control
are efficient and effective
by detecting the threats or displaying
what new weakness
in response to them the purpose of a red
team exercise are the following
demonstration of the exposure run risk
level
demonstration of the business impact
demonstration of the prevention
capabilities demonstration of the
detection capabilities
demonstration of the capabilities of
reacting or
addressing incidents now we are going to
speak about
hdmc mitre identity is a database
containing the most common
techniques tactics and methods being
used
by attackers tactics are the high level
vectors of
attack and the techniques represent
implementation of methods of attack
the organizations can perform an
adversarial emulation and keep
mapping the security controls that are
applied to techniques
organizations can also have several
security controls related
to a giving technique the goal is to
verify the performance and efficiency
as regards the security control by
technics implemented
and the metered tnc key framework
that i takes on the security bridge to
so the starting point is the original
intrusion tactic
any activity that has been previously
carried out
will be covered by a framework called
pre
pre detensive
now let's find out more about the
rebound
edit the bound is a computer security
tool designed to emulate
other sites the tool aims to bring
emulation of a real threat into closer
contact with implementation based on
the techniques and tactics from the
meteorite in cqe framework
the goal is to simulate how a threat
works
in an intrusion scenario where the
threat
has been successfully deployed
its focus on microsoft windows systems
through the use of the powershell
command line
this enables the different techniques
based on meter ethnicity to be applied
httpound is designed to allow the
evolution of our service as for our
retina society fund to verify the
effective effectiveness and efficiency
of the organization contract
in the face of a real threat what is the
atd bank
core power cell okay a power cell is
released along with microsoft microsoft
windows vista
it's not natively embedded in the
operating system which
makes it very interesting for both its
itn administration military and
pentester
its new version includes a large
number of the of new features and models
that will help
to integrate interest in with the
operating system
and its many tools and
first version was released in
26. the first stable version okay
two version appeared in 29
with the release of windows 7
version 3 appeared in 2012
with release of windows 8 and
later and the last version
version 7 appeared in the year
year of 2020
the idea underlying entity bound to link
the meteorite lcd framework
along with the techniques that are
implemented via the microsoft windows
powershell command line
the many techniques implemented to using
powershell
support a high percentage of techniques
laced
in the editing schematics that can be
replaced
replicated the project is also provative
it means that the user can have
his initial knowledge base based
on 80 tnc key but can import new
implementations of the techniques using
powershell and relaunch them using the
techniques and tactics in the file
we have used json format files to export
this new call knowledge
and import it in other environments
where hd pawn has been deployed in this
way
the cooperative knowledge has become
very significant
this facilities multiple users to
serve knowledge between several
environments
the technical dynamic elements that are
emerging
through the evolution of offensive
security
now my colleagues from ramirez is going
to give
you little insight into attp
hello everyone first of all i want to
say that
it is an honor for us to be again at the
awesome activity
for one more year okay so now
let's see what the architecture of att
pound looks like
http has three main different components
the first one is the console that is the
power cell code
that will be running on the windows
machines emulating the treat
after this code is executed on windows
machines
it connects towards a command and
control and
it waits for the adversary's commands to
be emulated
the second one are the functions
these are the technical implementations
that are
mapped in mitre att and ck
this is interesting since any user can
create
their functions written in powershell
this makes http collaborative and a
project where any user
can contribute with their knowledge in
the form of technical
implementations all the functions will
be carried out
by the console when it is executed
through windows machines
and the last one is the command and
control mvc or
c2 this is the att bound control panel
from this panel you can set up the treat
or adversary to be emulated
you can use already preset up treats or
you can build you
treat or test
the tool's knowledge can be imported and
exported
from this panel since the user can
create his content
in the form of an implementation of a
technique in powershell
in other words a basic architecture
scheme
has two main elements from the
networking
point of view the first
is the agent or warrior is
the adversarial emulation and its code
is in powershell
the second one is the root node or
command control
from this web application it is possible
to manage
the application of the cheat to be
simulated by the different deployed
warriors also you can manage
the results of the emulation and make
decisions
about the controls
everything is fully connected with the
identifiers of the entity
and ck metrics
again from the networking point of view
the deployment of warriors over the
network will be accomplished
through different options remote
invocation through the network privilege
invocation of remote machine without
privilege local invocation
etc
it is recommendable not to include more
than 10 or 15 computers in this process
as indicated by the att and ck
these exercises are simulation but you
must
have a real as possible environment for
better results
okay and now let's talk about the
operational flows
these are the different flows between
the console or agent
and the entitybound command and control
the first flow is the connection flow
when a console is running on a windows
machine it
sends a high command
when the console is running it gathers
information from the machine
and then pass it on the control panel
through this packet
during the wire generation the ip
address to be connected
must be specified
but this is discussed further below
when the warrior needs to register as a
compromised
computer it sends a request
through the http pos method
of the root node stating the wire id
and they collect the information from
the computer
when this information is received by the
root node
the data will be stored into the
database
and will be made available for the user
that is in order to assign the plan set
in a treat
and perform its execution
when all this information reach the
command and control
it saves the information into a database
and sends
an ok signal
the second flow refers to the
adversarial planning
and execution process
the console or agent will ask for
information
about the treat plan to be performed
if the user has not created acid plan
for that console
the answer will be no treat plan
when there is already a treat plan
created for that console
an ok signal will be sent
later the console will start asking for
the functions that
are part of the trig plan
for its function downloaded and executed
the results will be reported to the
command
and control
in other words when the warrior connects
to etpound
it requests a new treat plan through the
get plan function
if the user has assigned already any
plan
to the warrior it answer okay and the
threat plan will be delivered
this plan is generated in a json
format more details about this file will
be
provided later once statute plan
is available for the warrior it will
perform
the request of its function or task to
be accomplished
this is made through the get task
function
a get task function will be run for its
technique
implementation that the warrior requires
to be performed
in order to fulfill the trade plan
for x prior run two values will be
returned
through the put result function
the first one whether or not the adtck
technique has been executed successfully
in the second case we get the output
from the function
that implements the return technique
ready for a technical review that can
check the results
okay and now the third flow is the sign
out flow
after all the techniques have been
performed the communication close and
the threat emulation is finished
so the console will send the by command
therefore the root note will also
assume the warrior as dead if it does
not report
any activity for a long period of time
in the other side the warrior will show
activity if
before a treat plan is associated the
warrior is requesting a plan
now let's talk about some key elements
in the http
to go a little deeper console the
console
will be created from the web cli
application specifying
the ip address from where the console
file
will be downloaded there there is a
file called cultural template that
houses
the instructions that will manage
the connection the threat plan and the
connection clause will mention it
in the previous section uh when the
instruction provided
is being executed on a windows machine
the power cell code necessary to carry
out the of the
warrior instantiation will be
launched the control has two parts
with a large if in the middle
the first part of the basic starting
part is the beginning
of the thread as seen
in the previous section connection
requests all
be made first a new unique id
is generated for the systems instance of
the
today to be identified in the root node
also the information of the on the
operating system where it's
running is gathered the second part
is driving by a case that
can happen in many threat emulations
the process will approve the circulation
or lateral movement
to another machine produce a new
privilege process
or one that can be executed in another
environment has been called splitting
in this case the console will be invoked
with an id that is it will not
have to generate the warrior id that
individual difficult individual
the warrior to the root node in other
words
if there is a plan with the
three tasks and the second task is a
privilege
escalation and this one is successful
then the third task will be executed and
in another
process at an operating system level
but from the att bound logical point of
view
it's the same word that is it
inhibits the same word ready
how do we find a thread simple through
a json file the thread plan is generated
in the root node according to the user's
needs
the user can use real threads already
created or reveal
their threats and see the output of
their monitoring techniques
the document format delivered with the
plan is json
let's talk about how create your http
functions using the skeleton function
any user can create or add features to
implement
techniques from the mitre 80d and ck
x implemented function is linked to a
technique
and one or more tactics in the framework
the main components from the skeleton
functions
are
the technique to be launched or the
function and
the main program this main program will
be in charge of managing the flow
of the technique to be performed
and this main program is in charge of
another three tasks
the first one is request the necessary
data
to the root node for the technique to be
executed
this is an execution prerequisite
the second one is check if the execution
of the technique
has been successful or not
the output will be stored in a true
first
variable
and the last one is there is some data
collected
saxa credentials dump ap addresses
or user enumeration that can be used
by another technique because all this
information will be
jumped to a data store that has the root
node
this scheme can be visualized in any of
the functions that can be found
in hdt pounds
ettipone is a collaborative project
where the goal
is to share knowledge through treat
plans
for the reason the tool allows sporting
user generated treats
and importing them into other 80-pound
instance
during the treat plan generation or
query the export plan
option can be used as shown in the image
once the file is stored in json format
it can be shared with the community
the json file contains all the
information needed
to recreate the drip plan with all the
tasks
and implementation of techniques
involved
even if these are not available in the
new
scenario now
let's look at some use cases in 80
pounds you can execute the fall or noun
threats and the threads or adversaries
that we create with our custom
threads we can make our own
version of a noun thread with http
technique set
selected by us create
our own version of an attack with http
techniques
and perform an execution of a threat
noun or created by us that implements
our own functions through the skeleton
function
in this section we will perform
different dictionaries
and explain them
okay in this first demo let's see what a
warrior is
to do this we will create the warrior in
this option
and copy the code that ettie pound
delivers to us
then we go to the computer where we will
make
the adversary or treat test paste the
code
it will be executed in a new powershell
and finally it
connects with http downloading a console
if we go to home section we will be able
to see
the computer where the warrior is
running
here we have the architecture data the
process dust is running
the ap address to which it belongs and
the warriors identified
in the plan section we have some
predeterminate
treats as we can see here
like wannacry not petty a flame dark
comet
or dooku let's select
for example wannacry and here we can see
the
techniques and the tt and ck tactic
identifier that forms this version of
wannacry
we could use it against a warrior
launch the warrior plan and finally
execute it
step by step all those techniques that
correspond
to wannacry in this case
in this second demo we are going to
gather
information to verify that there are
different
techniques within att and ck and
att bomb to be able to collect that
information to recreate the malware
treat
next we are going to do a privilege
escalation technique
that will split the 80-pound console
process into
one without privilege and the new one
with privilege
the first step will be to create the
warrior
copy the code
go to the powershell
run the code
and finally obtain the warrior executed
okay now let's go to the plan option
create a new one
select the gutter intacted where we can
see
here besides the implemented techniques
we also have the discovery tactic where
we can see some entity and ck techniques
generated
in this case we are simply going to make
a selection of the processes
that the machine has we will add this
technique
then we'll go to the escalation of
privilege
where we are going to use a bypass of
usc technique
named 1088
we add it we put a name to the tweet
and finally we will create the plan
once we have the plan created we can
select it here
we see the elements of our plan with
which metric tactics the mapping is
performed
and we can identify the wire over the
wire we want to launch it
and finally we launch the plan
at this moment the hdt pound console
will start
working and it will read the plan
and here we have the bending task
if we go to the result option we will
see how the first technique has already
been executed
in bulk process which is just a
collection of processes
we can see success
if we refresh it or we wait for a little
while
we will find that usc bypass has
also been successful
and we really get a double process
the one of the left is without privilege
but the one on the right is a process in
which instructions
with privilege are being executed but we
had no more technique
after the privileged elevation of
execution
in the 80-pound technical part we can
see the techniques
output
we can check the processes that the
computer has
and here we can also see the uac
bypass result
and here's the second demo
in this third demo we are going to
perform
an escalation of privilege but also a
credential stamp
to do this let's create a warrior
pointing to the http panel
copy the code and run it on the
powershell console
as we see before
here we can see the information about
the new warrior connected to the panel
and now we are going to create a plan
the drip plan will have a privilege
escalation
we will use again one zero eight eight
that is the usc bypass
we will execute a credential access
tactic
using a power dump but we could also use
mimikatz to perform
the credential damp
the interesting part is that once we get
the privilege escalation working
we will get a new process with privilege
and this process will be able to perform
the credential damp
okay so let's create the plan deploy the
treats select the treat
select the warrior and finally launch
the plan
okay and now let's go to the edit output
section
and here we'll be able to see the
techniques
or task pending execution
like the 1088
if we give it a little time
we will see that heath has been
successful
this new process with privilege has not
been created yet
we will see in the next afresh
here we can see the console without
privilege
and the second panel we will find the
credentials
damn still running
and now we can see that the power drum
technique
is finished but
where can we see the results like in the
previous demo
here we can see the output that this
technique has
in this case the uac bypass
while the second technique executed in
this process the credential damping
has returned us all this information
this information is very important as we
see here
we have users user id has lm
hash ntlm as i said this information is
very
important because we will be able to use
it through a data store
the data store can be used by techniques
that are performed afterward for example
a lateral movement technique can be used
these hashes and these users because of
this data store
this is a very very important element
within
edtpan
in this fourth demo we will perform the
following scenario
first an escalation of relays
second ready and dump orchestra lamping
and finally we will make a lateral
movement from computer with windows 7
to the computer with windows 10.
first we are going to play a warrior on
the windows 7 machine
okay as we have done in previous demos
we type in the 80-pound ip address and
finally create
the code we copy the code
from powershell and run it on windows
cell
okay we copy the code
from at this point
and run it on windows 7 on powershell
ok once executed
we hope we go to home obtainers before
they need the new warrior running
windows 7
ok well
now let's generate a plan where the
first step is to
execute this technique for example
by the counts t1078
okay the second
technique is an excretion of privilege
and third person technique is
the credential damping and the fourth
step
or fourth technique will be a lateral
movement
okay now
insert plan and
select a plan new plan
or new thread and
we assign a water id
or id warrior to
to your plan okay
and look at results
view and we have
a data data store okay
these these are these are
uh techniques several techniques
about the new plan and data store
we are we add an ip address to the
desktop
ok
okay well refresh the web page
several times until the lateral movement
is complete
and the technique of flattering
movement is complete
now led pawn is still
executing execute
all process
and
now refresh the web page several times
until the lateral movement is complete
okay
observe that we have an hd pound
console running on windows 10.
yeah then now we can conclude
this demo form
okay now we are going to
speech about demo 5.
well in this five fifth
demo we will work on
in all in one thread concept
where we will automate the service
discovery
and the discovery of machines within
within
a network as a threat or an anniversary
could do
the data discovered will be stored on
the data store
by a technique being used then we will
perform
appropriate escalation obtain a new
privilege
process on the windows 7 machine
then we will make a credential dump
thanks thanks to that privilege
speculation
where we will acquire houses and users
then we will make a lateral move where
we will use
the houses users and the ip addresses
for
from the computers within the network to
try to make
to make that lateral move through the
meter hd
technique in this way the whole process
is fully
dramatic so we can we can test the
effectiveness or efficiency of security
controls within
the organization we will start as always
by generating a warrior in this case we
check
the ip address again copy the gold and
go to
powershell to paste the code okay
okay in the home section
uh we'll we will see the control
connected soon
here we see the data now we go to the
plan
section
okay waiting for the warrior
and we go to the plan section we create
we create a new plan begin with
a discovery tactic tactic using the
t1046 technique
where this port's scanning will allow
us to discover computers okay
we add the technique to the plan
indicating an
escalation of privilege and then
credential damp
with power dump or mimics and finally
the large technique again
a lateral movement okay
and thread name defcon demo
5 and
an all-in-one and thread
description blah blah
okay we put the name only one create a
plan and link it
with the warrior we go now
to the results okay well
first allocate plan and now
we go now to the results
we see the control begins to work
and now
we can see here the task to be done
and the scan begins
one moment here
the scan is a technique that in duality
can take
quite a long time can be seconds or
meals
so we will speed up the demo a little
bit
so that this part goes as fast as
possible
okay once the scan has finished
we will be able to check that it has
been successful
and if we go to the data store
okay now we go to the data store
we will be able to see the computer ap
addresses that
are currently alive on the network
um right now the second technique
that is the escalation of village has
also also
been successful so the process has
has been unfolded and right now the
process dumped
credentials
okay if we refresh the page we
will see the credentials dumping has
been successful too
and if we go to the thread datastore
we see that we have ip addresses
users and hashes
the discussions can be identified
from here directly like any data
from the data store and the changes will
be saved by clicking on the after record
okay for the thread to finish
we will have to check if the result is
covered or not
in the lateral movement we must
consider that these techniques are used
to test
to test the efficiency and effect and
fitness
of the security counters within the
organization
therefore certain implementations may be
updated and avoid the execution of
some codes
okay now a new process on windows 10 has
been implemented
there are no tasks and we have performed
the lateral movement
in other words the thread has moved from
windows 7 to windows 10
from one machine machine to another over
the network
and we have also done the
whole process of a threat that is real
for us detecting computers in the
network trying to escalate privileged
dumping and
accessing information such as houses
and finally a lateral move with one of
the techniques
that can be implemented within the
lateral movement
most tactics
in this sixth and final demo we are
going to export
the thread plan and then import it into
http to make a simple example
we can choose notepadia
select the thread get the techniques to
use
and proceed with the playing sport
in this button we we export
this knowledge we if if
we want to share knowledge with other
users uh
our threat knowledge that we already
have have created or even even
techniques that we have implemented in
power cell and
add it to a http we call create any plan
set a name create a plan
choose it and proceed to export it
if we want to share this plan with
another user we will send him
the json file which we are going to open
to see
the content
okay json opening json file
in firefox okay
okay as you can see even
the function definition writing power
cell
exactly as we have created it is
transferred
so if we want to share this information
with another
user we can export those plans
containing the functions that
we have created in powershell and i did
to edit the pound and send this json
okay it's very simple and collaborative
way to provide
the knowledge to other users with
offensive techniques
within the httc key mapping
well this is the last demo and i will
pass the war
on to my partner front
okay so that's all feel free to visit
the att pound github
and download the software this is a new
tool
we are currently working on and we are
adding new techniques
also the project is collaborative and
everyone can help the project grow
and now we are ready to answer any
questions you may have about
edtpawn thanks a lot