hello guys i'm so glad to be here
and today we're gonna talk about the
second and comparing
binaries to analysis when do we
talking about the modernizes right my
name is felipe pierce and this is my
contact in the twitter
github and a medium i use a lot the
linkaging profile
not profile actually in social medias if
you have
any doubts or any questions please
this is my contact and i am available to
talk to you right
so uh some information about me i have
been working in a hacker security
as a global research manager right this
is the
brazilian company i am a founder this
course is about
amar analysis fundamentals and
now not actually not now i started to
work in
in this company zoop innovation i am
responsible to
zap zup security labs i am a
research and security manager as well uh
i'm responsible to provide many research
in antivirals and many different sensors
of security products right and this is a
brazilian company
as well and this is a
like a software house responsible to
create a software's apps and
applications
and as you can imagine the
kind of softwares and apps right so
here's some uh
papers or not papers in this case it's
article that i was
uh wrote yeah i put publish it
in a fantasy magazine a forensic
magazine and
the cyber security hub as well this is
not um you know my idea here is not
to hack the nscr nsa or fbi
or you know microsoft uh my idea when i
and i publish it this kind of articles
is to provide some basis
you know so my idea is to talk about the
basis what the fundamentals
uh is important when you talk about the
security products or
or more analysis or maybe trading
hunting or maybe
up and testing so we need to know about
the buses
during this our conversation now i will
explain more about this
right so here are not uh another papers
that i was
uh wrote right and you can read
uh in my social medias or this uh
magazine as well
right so the first step that we need to
do when you talk about the mara analysis
to identify
right uh this is that is called
identification right because we have the
artifact we don't know
if the artifact is malicious not or not
we need to understand if
if this if this malicious or this
artifact
actually is malware software malicious
or maldoc document malicious right
this is the first and very important
uh part right after that you can chose
what the
kind of analysis would you chose if you
use static analysis or dynamical as
analysis right after that have to
realize or you
executed it you can prepare a report
right
actually this kind of step it's very
important because you need to present it
to the
your manager your tech lead your
coordinator maybe
and you can prepare prepare many of
these
informations that you analyze it before
right
after that you can improve your security
defenses
mechanism right this is the main point
here because for example if you
try to explore any antivirus in your
environment right
you maybe you can try explore
explore many you know daily daily
injections you can try using
another different mower or try or maybe
using some exploits to try
explore your antivirus solutions
this is a very interesting point you can
present this to the
our or not our your manager or
your tech lead and when you find
any uh for example vulnerability maybe
bags maybe maybe uh i don't know
filers in your softwares in your
security software for example you can
improve you can
uh adjust many settings
inside your platform right and after
that you can prepare the beautiful world
has no like a cyber threat intelligence
or
cti right you can build it you can
build this kind of intelligence in your
company i know
maybe you don't have a big company you
have a small company
but you can work uh with for example
iocs uh indicator of compromise or maybe
you can works with uh
maybe uh eor or eoa it's like a
indicator of attack and you can build it
right this is the main point when the
we talk about the moronitis because you
know when you mention
our analysis maybe the people
that was watching me now maybe are
thinking for example
okay if i have this kind of
knowledgement
maybe i can work as in a sock or maybe
on a support
but you can receive this kind of
acknowledgement and you can improve it
it
you can work for example athletic
hunting or for the hunter or the person
that
realizes or is equal to this kind of
work right or you can maybe
uh do this research has has me for
example
because i am creating this in my uh
my company now and in hakasaki and
uh zoop innovation as well and my idea
to put
this kind of uh professional guy this is
the mower hunter in a top of the tower
right
the idea is to put in the research guy
in the top of the tower
this is my idea you know because when
you talk
uh for example with many companies in
the world for example
uh the the this kind of person or this
this you know this is a skill is it's
not clear
if this guy's working with a sock with a
sazad uh
in a you know for example in in cesare
or maybe in a support team
or maybe in a red team or or blue team
you know it's it's maybe a confusion
it's many companies so this is my idea
to put in the top of tower because this
guy
have a defensive you know essentially
but
they think the mind it's totally
offensive that's my idea right
and after that you can create the uh uh
the strengthening yes that your cyber
resilience because the threats
are changing all the time right this is
maybe a not a life cycle of the
morales but it's a suggestion
right it's one idea you know that's my
suggestion for you right so the first
step is static analysis it's very
simple usually this is the first step
use it by
uh mar analysts yes because this is
usually
it's described of the process of the the
the
some programs maybe the structure or
maybe what the
function function it is called by
any dll or maybe call it by any
a library for example if you are
analysing
for example a unix platform right
and usually this program itself it
doesn't
run at this time right because of course
it's the painting of the program
that you can for example using your
analysis but
usually it's more safe right because
it's not
100 safe but usually it's more safe
because
you not put in in real time right the
analysis it's not in real time that's a
a simple point here
when you talk about the statistic
analysis right the second step
is dynamic analysis just to explain for
everyone that was watching now
right the dynamic the dynamic analysis
it's based
as just in in behavior right uh
basically the interactions that the
mower
uh has with them the
the files inside the the the systems
operation
or maybe what the um the document maybe
uh this file can call it
but usually you put in the sample inside
of the virtual
machine one environment controller right
you run this sample inside this
environment and you can analyze this
behavior right so usually you can auto
you can automatizate that many this
kind of uh analysis right because you
can
today you have a many websites with uh
antivirus
engine engines to try execute your
suspicious files right and you or you
can create you can use it as well
the another concept called sandbox this
is the
basically it's a controlled environment
that you can put your your sample inside
this product for example you can run and
you can look in the
all uh dlls and many informations
are called but the big point the very
important thing here
is okay i put my sample inside this
sandbox
but what the response what the answer
are receiving report i can't
i can't understand what the the dll are
called because i understand very well
in low level in the kernel level or the
user level
uh you know i can understand this
because you know i have the
automatization tool but
i need to interpreter i need to turn
like a translate not translate but you
need to understand what this
report is talking you know that's very
important
thing because of this that's my mission
now here
to try explain some basis for you right
so okay so here i have a demo are you
showing my machine by the way
okay so i will try put here i will call
i will pray
to the you know to the the the lords of
demo to try let me check here i have
here
some samples right i have by the way
here file linux
32 yes this is that a simple
uh executable file right so if i check
here another in a wheel machine machine
let me check here what i have here a
simple file okay let me check here
if i use file command i can find here
the the in this case it's a portable
executable
from uh windows from microsoft right so
you have different
files here's to understand if it's
malicious or not let me check
here i have another different here um
let me check
here i have a view let me check here
bill
bill file build
this is a pdf file right it's a pdf file
okay
so but here i would like to try uh
explain about the basis
right because we're gonna talk about
file command right i don't know if you
uh
read something about this but what means
what that's what means fire in this case
fire determine fire type yeah i know
philip but how this
kind of tools or this tool in that case
in this case
works that's a a simple and very
important point right
because when you when you put this
command inside your machine
this a file or this tool actually
you run or are running your environment
and you show
some answered right in that you know in
the in the screen
but how this tools works that's
that's important because if you read
here if you read
here you can can read here the message
tests are used to check
for files each data in particular fixed
format
maybe you can maybe you are thinking now
and and maybe uh i don't know i know
philippis show me about the men of files
but here you can understand something
because here you can understand
those format is defined in elf doc h
so maybe here we have interesting
information if you
let me for example if you check here
for example if i put here for example
no no
you know let me
oh yes i will open okay so here you can
if you see here this information right
that i was
receiving here in demo from file
you can read here this file defines the
standard
elf types structure in macros
right and here below you can
read another informations about the
structure because
here in the beginning you can read here
the elf files header
this appears at the start of every elf
file right you have here 16 bytes
the first array of the name e identity
and you have the magic number and
others information so we have here
for example the magic number so what are
what means this in this case uh magic
number here
you have the key right so these files
have
a magic number is stored in particular
place near
the beginning of the file that tells the
unix
operation systems right so what's
what this means in this case it's very
simple
the file command has a database
responsible to provide
all this information to find all these
all those magic number in the beginning
of the fire right
so here if you i will show you now here
for example
i have here the i i downloaded this
this uh this file this
file a code to to look inside this to
show you
this information right so here we can
read you can read many informations
here's
of many information of this kind of
database for example
if you for example read the information
of
javascript in this case here okay so
javascript let me show you for you here
javascript we have here many
informations in the beginning of the
file
in this case is the magic number of the
fire having
many rules here that you could use
you that basically this file command
used to identify the fi they are defined
in this case
if is executable or not right
so let me show you some example now here
you create this file the name our doctex
that's just a text right
is it malicious
[Music]
let me right here okay this is a simple
question
have you read this information in this
case
perfect let me use file command here
it's really really text file right
perfect
so for example if i manipulate the
magic number information here let me
manipulate here i will put some string
here
that i know what this information means
i will change here and i use the file
again
context dot text and let me check here
and here
looking this incredible information now
we have a python script in this case is
as it
is a creatable file right so if is
executable i can
call it i can call me python
after you think about it so i can call
on not python python text
in this case
text because it's python right
show you let me read again this file
yes but we have a problem maybe you can
think about it some but the station here
is different right let's let me
uh because i have another python here in
the other representations i will
okay so i have a key i have here
yes okay so let me change now here mower
let me move from our text to the malware
dot pi right so here
we gonna buy so in this case we can run
now
just buy maybe you need to have you need
to have
the authorization that the privilege to
to execute this kind of information
maybe
let me change here okay so now let's
python again and let's check is the same
error why did this happen because it's
not a script python right
if you for example you can manipulate
again uh this information here
it's very interesting point another
again
let me move again and pour send pdf
truss maybe slash oh oh dash
actually 1.9
and i will save here and i you clean
and let me check here mower pointer pi
dock by it's a pdf document take a look
at the very interesting you know
that's a big point here uh maybe you can
ask
so philip now the file commander is not
confident
it's not uh you know it's not a
confidence con
comment i can use this kind of comment
no you need to use
right but you need to understand all
those days
right this is the very important thing
you never need you never
can believe in the extension uh because
of course you it's the same case when
you talk about the strings for example
if you see here the strings demand of
the strings for example here
the strings comment right so let me
check
here is strings
command string printed the sequence of
printable characters in
file right so here's the the simple key
the many many people never think
maybe because in the beginning of the
description uh
says for example for each file given you
know
strings print the printable character
sequence that
are at least four characteristics
long because of this you when do you as
i could for example here
um a string in strings
that they may be you is it for example
in the beginning of this the many
comments for example you
you don't you you don't find for example
the elf information or mz information on
the pe
information right for example here if
you
read here the x damp any let me check
here any 32
um the linux 32
but less okay in the beginning you can
you can read here the elf
right so but here you have a just three
la
three characters not four in this case
right
so if you try here for example
let me change here if you train if you
change it should
if you try for example run the strings
uh dash a putting in the
linux let me put pipe here
but like last sec here
and you put pipelines here and you if
you try
oops maybe s3's receive some red horse
here
oh of course i need to put the
fire correct yes so here if you put here
in the beginning take a look here you
you don't find here the beginning the
elf information because alfie just said
three characters not
four characters that is important thing
right this is all those bases right
that's very important when you mention
here right
so we explain more than uh elf
now so basically when you talk about the
structure
about the elf or maybe pe portable is
equitable
you can see in the pictures it's the
similar
form not exactly the same but very very
because you have the same header you
have the sessions here
in the txt or uh and
doc or dot dot dot
oh my goodness you have the text you
have
uh a or data you have the data in you
and you have uh many sessions heather in
the pa
portable we have for example the the two
uh parts first right the header in the
sessions
of course it's dividing you on other
parts
and you have for example in in inside
the header you have
the dos header when you can see the mz
information the signature mz
right when basically it's responsible to
the creator of this
kind of binary and you have here
the pe header when you can find
the pe signature this information
and below you can see the sessions here
is the informations where they usually
the attacker can put your malicious code
usually inside this session docs text
right and when you
try to analyze any artifacts for example
you can find the upx compressed or maybe
a packer
tools this is a technique maybe many
times the attackers can be using
us many different attackers usually
the packer can he absolute all those in
the sessions inside
in one of those uh packer basic
basically and you can
when you use some tools to try and
find some information you will find
for example the packer information right
do you you don't you can't see
this information in the session right so
okay
so we talk about the pe and alpha
structure of course it's very
very simple uh we i can't uh i don't
have a time actually to explain all this
uh binaries because you know uh if you
talk about the for example just a pe
portable executable from microsoft man
we have a many
many hours to try explaining and to try
uh goes to inside this all this
information right so i will try to
explain more
than pdf structure because basically
it's
it's in four main parts the header it's
made
baby it's basic basically it's the same
when you talk about another binaries we
have
always you have the header right you
have the boring
you have the cross reference table and
you have the trailer right
so here we have the all those structure
in the beginning of the file you have
the version
number it's the same information
collected by
file command do you remember when you
execute the file command you can read
you can read actually the magical number
of this information you can find this
information
you have the body and inside this kind
of body
you know you have many reference inside
of this
body you have the cross reference table
here and you can read here it's locate
location of object ethernet the file
or a random access what else
what as what this the things means
in this case is basically one structure
referring another instructor or another
object inside this bar in this case
right
in the trailer it's the same thing
you have here uh location of the certain
objects
inside the body that is
you have many connections of this parts
of this structure right so here
i will show you one of mine's
my analysis in a pdf file right to try
and understand
how you use basically here i used the
pdf id
it's very tools it's very known tools uh
provided by dda stevens right this is
basically i think it's in being
installed in many unix platform
but you can download this information in
the blog website from
dj stevens as you can use this in
windows in windows machines
sorry we have problem here with my demo
let me
try here okay i will pause actually this
this demo
because here we have all those
informations you have the header
you have 15 objects here and you have
this
two extreme you have the one trailer one
cross reference table here
and you have one trailer right
so below this tool we
we can find this uh
informations this is lash writing this
information
all those information all those these
lashes are
inside of this object that's a very
interesting point
because if you uh see in the manner of
the pdf id
you can note you can see this
information that's basically it's
uh is it's too is responsible to print
many strings inside of the pdf right
so here we have another interesting
point we have the encryption file
and you have here five java
script inside this pdf you know so you
can
think about it what do you think you
have a
javascript inside of the pdf file maybe
it's uh
it's a safer or malicious you know i
don't talk about the reverse engineer
here
just to try to interpret or to
try understand of this file right and
here you can
see another information open action it's
one what's this means in this case open
actions
refer basically when the user received
the file
and user click in a file in this case is
pdf file
and after that and after that
the file can execute something
in this case we can see here we have
five javascript
we just need to understand what this uh
or what this command
represent in this case right so i will
put
uh mars let me check here okay so here i
will use another
uh platform in this case it's a
pdf run right did some another platform
created by dj steven
pdf parser right oh my goodness we
haven't
i do have many problems here with my
in this case my finger you know because
i am clicking in a mouse
but no but but now i have you try to
show
you the the all those information in
this case
right because i will pause the video to
to explain
as you can see here this information in
the beginning we can
see the header right and here you can
reach the object
one if you remember when i explain about
the body
about the cross reference table all
those in for all those
these parts of this pdf are connected
one both another right right
so here for example you have the object
one
referring object to object three four
five six and seven but you know
and i know that we have fifteens object
inside this file right so let's continue
to
try understand here we can see the
my goodness here we can see
the javascript but here we we can
we can't understand what this
information means right
so we need to try understand more here
as you can see we have the option open
action
as you explained before to you right the
open action
when the user click in this file this
file
uh will run
someone or or or any javascript but
we don't know right uh what
this javascript maybe
call it or maybe can call it right so
let's continue to understand
we have object one and here
i will put okay
above here object four we have another
reference here
we have a reference eight and reference
nine and we have a two more referencing
right so uh you can
see here more connectivity in the many
objects inside the pdf
right so here another interesting thing
we have the
object 7 connected or referencing by
object 10 you know we are
growing up of this pdf file right
in here the object nine we have the same
case
we have the referencing the four because
the four connected
to the nine nt8 and the eleven
right so we can see
many connections of the object inside
this
name of body right so here we have the
the object 10 connected to
12 and here we have one
first interesting uh information
object 11 we have the contain
extreme in this case uh when this
object has some strings maybe you have a
javascript inside
this or maybe you can have some exploit
inside
this and you have this information
flakes decoded
it means uh these are streaming are
obfuscated i are closed inside
this uh flash decode you need to decode
this information
uh by the way so here another
information is you have object 12
it's connected to 13 and if you compare
here this is streaming it's much
uh bigger than
uh than than another that we see that we
saw uh later right if you compare this
stream it's very very high
the the size it's very high right when
you compare here
so maybe the idea is to try to looking
all those informations inside this
object right we have here the object
14 and here the 15 and finish
the file right so the next step
is to try to look inside the
object 13 right so in this case i will
use another two pdf tica
in this case these two it's not from dda
steven
by the way so i will run
the dump of this information and this uh
a key information
uncompressed because of you uncompress
all those information inside these pdfs
right because you remember i run the pdf
person
and i i can read all those
run information and here we i can
uncompress because i know
inside of this streaming we have a flat
the code information so now i am
seeing here the javascript obfuscated
in this case the attacker used the first
technique the
obfuscation technique right because i
can
see the evil parameters
and i can try to find
any information inside this obfuscated
code
right so here i will use uh the nano you
know i could
i can use vi maybe or another tools to
edit
all those informations and i will just
change any information here you can see
many informations in javascript
so here we can find or you can
try to read any information because you
can if you imagine for example
we're gonna talk about the javascript
javascript javascript to use
usually uh that you know the following
it's uh application your web application
page maybe
so because of this i will try to uh
there's a fuscate this kind of
code so because i have the here the
parameter
i use in the script html
i will using the document right to try
read
any information inside of this
code right so i generate the
payload.html
and i will try to read if i find for
example
uh any information inside of this java
script obfuscated
right so basically i will run now
this code in a html page and
i'll take a look all the what's the if
the in the interesting information that
we find here
the variable payload do you know what
this means it's basically the packer
or not the packer the package
responsible
to download uh in the vitmen machine
and this package is responsible to
response this information to the
attacker server right the it's known
uh the name it's a cac or command and
controller right
so take a look in the first step we find
that the pdf file
and this pdf file we have a five
javascript
but we have a one of this java it's the
bigger javascript
in this javascript have received
the obfuscated technique right
and after after that i will i i needed
to change all those information i need
to do sophisticated of this code
and when i execute the information in a
html page
i can find the payload responsible to
download
in the vitamin machine so if you
remember in the beginning of this
analysis when
the user maybe the vitamin this case
click
in the file do you remember the open
action the next action of this file is
to
execute this javascript in this case
it's you know it's obfuscated
so when the the user or the vitamin
clicking this file
this is scripted the javascript uh will
run
in the victim and will download this
payload that you can see in the
in the screen inside the whitman machine
right
so in this case i i was i was thinking
when i was
uh doing this analysis so if i have the
payload maybe i can try to find the cac
from the attacker
right so i will continue to do my
analysis in this case
so i have here some informations inside
this
payload right so here are you use again
my big friend
nano maybe many people don't like this
friend but
you know it's in my case it's simple oh
i could use again
vino vi or another uh edit test so if
if you see here we have a very percent
inside of this
information here when when i look at
when i look at
all those percent all those information
i can notes
i can see here no notes i can see here
the interesting information in this case
here
we have a you see two based on a unique
code
you know uh information it's it's almost
different when you talk about the ascii
or ascii as key it means a two by
one bytes when you talk about the
unicode you used in two bytes right
so here i have the the the the pure
not pure but the the run data of this
unicode right so now i need to translate
all this information
so i had the payload package
but when i see i i see another technique
the encode technique right so this the
this payload
is used with uh unique um
sorry it's used a unicode
encoding right i know it's very it may
be confusing but
take a look at this i have a payload
package
i have an information all those
information receive
a encode technique this encode technique
is
pasted in unicode right so basically
as you can see here i just using the
unix platform
but maybe you can ask uh or you can
asking felipe but i use just windows but
not a problem you don't
you however you you don't need to have a
consonant in this case right
so here i use another platform in
mozilla by bobby it's
it's a similar platform i have here the
same code
i need to cut you remember i need to cut
this percent
because i need to have the run unicode
information right the unicode code
right so here i have the unicode
information
and i can generate here the exa file
binary
this these two it's responsible to
generate this kind of information
after that i use it another information
uh another tools created by dda steven
sure
search executable to try and find any
http information because remember if i
have the payload package
probably this um
package went after two downloaded in the
vitamin machine
probably this package will make
some requests into the commanding
controller from attacker right
so that's my idea when i to continue to
do this
investigation so when you as you can see
here i found
the ip from the attacker in this case
the ip
is based in estonia europe
writes all this information from the cac
the attacker i i don't use it basically
here
the reverse engineer but we find the
javascript
obfuscated we find the encode
technique based in in
in unicode right
we've we can learn about the for example
open action inside the pdf files
so we can learn about many informations
right so if you have any question i
i am available to you this is my contact
again
and one more time thank you thank you
for this opportunity
if you have any question please let me
know