good morning and thank you for joining
this presentation
about hacking the activity 2019 badge
or how to break the device and resurrect
it
with another sound i am valerio di
giampietro i am passionate about
electronics since when i was a child
and for this reason i studied electronic
engineering at
the university on my daily job i am an
i.t
infrastructure manager managing service
but on premise and on the cloud
managing storage networking databases
and so on
i am also a linux enthusiast almost
since the beginning i installed linux
for the first time on my own pc
in 1993. my
personal website is valerio written
esva.ler.io
you will find a copy of this
presentation
and more important links to everything i
will talk about today
my email address is valerio written as
v8ler dot io
and my twitter handle is valerio being a
nerd i am
quite proud of these addresses
i have also a youtube channel called
makemiak
about hard working i started this
youtube channel during the lockdown
period when i had much more time to
dedicate to
this what we will talk about today
basic basically we'll talk about my
journey in hacking
the last year activity badge this is a
lot has a lot to do with
hacking maybe a bit less to do with the
security also if the two
items are very strictly related
i will introduce the activity 2019 badge
i explain how i bricket the page how
i reverse engineered the pcb to
reconstruct
the most important part of the
schematics
then how i used the arduino ide to
reprogram the main processor the s32
processor and how i refreshed the
coprocessor that it is the a number
based summon d21
the activity 2019 page was a nice school
gadget that was distributed
to the attendance at the last year
physical
conference in uh in budapest
it is a it has a lot of interesting
features because
it runs micro python it has connectivity
but
usb wi-fi and infrared connectivity
it is an app store where you can
download applications
written micro python and upload your own
applications
is six nice touch buttons a small
monochrome but nice lcd screen of 128
for 64 bits as six
rgb leds an infrared transmitter and
receiver
is also a buzzer and can be powered by
usb
or by battery it is being designed to be
hacked but
there are no detailed information on
hardware and
firmware about this device
it is a pretty powerful device at its
core there is an s
32 room 32 module that is a
that has a 32-bit dual core extensor cpu
is a 4 megabyte of flash memory
520 kilobyte of static ram
as wi-fi and bluetooth connectivity is a
lot of digital analog
and possibility modulated io pins
support touch sensors can have multiple
serial interface
implementing multiple protocols like
word spi i2c and so on
is also a an ultra-low power mode
the co-processor is also quite powerful
the core accessories needed the mains
the main purpose of the co-processor is
to talk the usb
uh interface because the esp32 doesn't
support the usb
interface the coprocessor is an atmel
atsmd21g16b
that has a powerful arm cortex
m0 cpu as a small amount of flesh memory
only 64 kilobytes
and a small amount of static ram only 8
kilobyte
as the serial wire debug interface that
interfaces similar to the jtag interface
that allows
to reprogram this chip and to also do
in-circuited debugging
being able to execute step-by-step a
program
directly on the hardware supports the
usb interface as multiple serial
interface implementing various protocols
as digital analog and possibility
modulated input output
pins support touch sensors
how i bricket the device after playing a
bit with the micropython
on this on this board i tried to use the
arduino ide
wrongly assuming that this board was
similar to some
some board for use for arduino so i
connected my board to my arduino pc
the badge was recognized as another
adafruit
playground express board i
suppose that this was correct so i
loaded the simple
blink sketch that will blink a led
the load was successful but then the
device was bricked bricked means the
device was dead
and the usb was no more recognized by
the pc
plugging or unplugging or the usb
needing to do any effect
on the pc so after this
i asked myself why
this has been wrongly identified as
other fruity playground
express because this board is the one
that you see on
on the slide is a processor this is
almost identical to our processor is an
optimal
uh some d21 g18a
our instead is 16a it is basically
identical to our processor the only
difference is that
it the underground the playground
express is four times more flash
and four times more studying ram
probably
our device our page has been
implemented in some way copying the
the other fruit playground express and
so it was
wrongly recognized but because the flesh
and static ram are different the sketch
that was loaded
probably uh simply breakage the device
and device became
unuseful so the first step
was okay i have to understand what's
going on on the board
how the chips are connected and what
uh signals are available on the
interface so the first step
was to solder pin adders on
the board that ships without pin headers
then try to find the pin adders
connections some connections
were quite easy to find because the
board is is a two layers board and you
are able
to see the traces on the board so
many of them are very quite easy to
follow
obviously you can always confirm the
connection using a multimeter
i also searched on the internet and i
was able to find easy to images that
are images of the top and the bottom of
the printed circuit
also without components so it's quite
easy to follow pcb traces
i also search it on the internet and
found i wasn't able to find the
schematic
of this badge but found i found the
of a different badge the disobey 2018
badge
that was designed by the same team so
probably
this schematic can be similar to our
schematic
i use the that is the open source i
would say
something similar to photoshop but open
source to follow
the the the image with the pcb
layout but during this activity i
discovered that what i found on internet
the image of the top
bottom of the pcb was not identical
to our finished product for example if
you see on the image i downloaded
from internet i have a connector with
four pins
on the same position in the real board i
have a connector with
17 pins so probably these
images available on internet are related
to some prototype
of our board and then our board was
later modified so what i found
on these two images must be checked
with a multimeter so i followed the
traces
using putting each image
on a separate layer and then alternating
the visibility
of the two layers so it was quite easy
to follow each pcb trace
and reconstruct the schematic but
i also used the similar project as a
hint what they found
relating to the disobey 2018 page the
schematic
i said okay so probably connections are
the same
and also i used as i hint
the data sheet because if you have
another sheet for example a reset pin
probably that reset pin goes to a push
button
to reset the board or if you found
pins that are used to connect the usb
interface probably these two pins will
go
to the usb interface so
uh taking this information that are not
strictly related to our
board but or but from similar boards of
the sheet and so on i confirmed the
connection with the multimeter anyway
this information were useful to speed up
the reconstruct reconstructing of the
schematic
so i was able to identify each connector
was
which signals we have on each connector
and i found interesting things for
example the connector j9
is the i2c bus i2c bus is a serial bus
often used in electronic
circuits it allows a master to talk
to multiple slaves it chooses life as an
address in this way
we can see what's going on on the board
monitoring
these um i2c pins the j-10 connector
exposes a lot of pins of the s-32 main
processor it is can be used
to attach sensors switches
additional peripherals to our badge
the j11 connector is a very interesting
connector because it
exposes the serial wired debug interface
of the same d21 co-processor that is an
armor-based compressor
the serial wire debug interface is very
similar
to the jtag interface because it allows
to reprogram
the device and to use this interface as
a debugging support to do in-circuit
debugging
here we have the two pins so this is
these interface
that are the data input output at the
clock
plus ground vcc and the reset pin
of the co the coprocessor the pin
adder j12 exposes other pins
of the s-32 main processor one of these
pins is uh
quite interesting for our purpose
because it's the so-called bootloader
pin
this means that if we reset the sp32
and keep low this pin during the reset
the sp32 will enter the bootloader mode
and will allow to load a firmware
through the serial interface
the j13 connector is the
circle interface of the s32 we have the
tx
rx and ground connection
on the bottom of the board we have two
switches
we don't have the actual switches only
the pathway the switches we can
put by ourselves but anyway we have two
switches one is
to reset the co-processor the summer d21
arm co processor
and the other one is to put in a
bootloader mode
the summer d21 co processor obviously to
put input to loader mode
you have to reset the the coprocessor
keeping low this pin
but to put in bootloader mode you have
a bootloader functioning of the
co-processor i break the device so this
this
was no more functioning because i
destroyed
also the bootloader
and i also found the main connections
between
main processor co-processor and display
the most important connection
is that the the co-processor used this
uart serial interface to talk to the
sp32
and act as a bridge between the usb
interface
and the s-32 then we have the i2c
interface the serial interface that
connect the
main processor the sp32 that is the
master
in this network the some d21 coprocessor
is one slave and the display is the
other slave
and then the somebody 21 co-processor is
the possibility
to reset the main processor driving the
n
the en pin and pin is enabled is the
reset pin
and also being able to drive the
bootloader pin so the co-processor can
reset the main processor and can also
put the main processor
in a bootloader mode to load the
firmware
inside this 32
the sum d21 co processor not only
drives the usb interface but also all
the touch buttons that are available on
the board
and all the rgb leds available on the
bolt
are attached to the coprocessor so this
means that the processor will
read the touch buttons and will switch
on and switch off the led
and the main processor will ask to the
co-processor
to do these operations on his behalf
using the i2c serial bus
so i my idea was to use to be able to
use the
s32 using the arduino ide so first step
was okay let me check if i can use the
sp32
directly with the arduinoid interface
and because
we have exposed the serial interface on
the board
i could attach a ttl serial adapter
to connect to this area interface into a
pc
running arduino then i can use
a jumper to put load bootloader mode
during reset to have a desperate to
enter
the bootloader mode to load the firmware
then i can reset the board unplugging
and replacing the power that is the usb
connector and
in this way the sp3 will enter
bootloader mode
and i will be able to the arduino ide to
load
a simple sketch then i can
remove the jumper reset again the board
i'm plugging
replacing the power the usb interface
and it is way
my sketch will run
now a simple demo of this approach
so yeah we have our activity page
here there is the cellular connection
with
a ttl serial adapter
here there is the put rotor switch with
the jumper
that activate the boot rollers which
because one is ground
and the other pin is the bootloader
switch and here
i connected a led connected to
the gpio21 it is the red
cable and to ground it is the
green cable now
powering up the device the s32
should enter the bootloader mode
after you power up the device we also
attach
the usb dtl serial adapter
to our pc
we can check using a
put tty terminal emulator we can check
that it
has really entered the bootloader mode
to be sure we power down
and power up again and we can see
that on the serial console we receive
the message
waiting for download this means that s32
is ready to download
a new sketch
so we close the youtube ui
and download this simple
sketch this sketch you can see basically
print
a let down message on the serial console
light the lent delay alpha second
another message to send a console with
led off
and then switch the led off
wait half a second again in the cycle
repeat
you can see that now it is
low the arduino ide is loading the
sketch
at the end it says are the setting via
ritspin but the rf the rts pin is not
connected
so this means that arduino e id is not
able to reset
the s32 so we have to reset manually
first of all we disconnect the jumper to
select the bootloader so
next time it will boot normally
we disconnect also the usb cable
because otherwise there is some
possibility that the power
goes through the usb cable to the board
and
it will not reset correctly we power
down
power up again and we can see
that this sketch has been successfully
loaded because
the lead is blinking half a second on
half a second
off we can also see
that something is printed on the serial
console
as per our sketch we execute again
the terminal emulator select
the comp 9 interface
open and we can see that it is printing
led on led off as in the
per hour sketch so basically we have
successfully
loaded this sketch on and the esp
tutu using the arduino ide
one important thing to note is that my
the co-processor
was bricked brigade means that basically
nothing was running or casual
instructions
were running and by default when the
co-processor of this armor chip
powered on by default every i o pin are
automatically
configured as input pin so this co
processor was
not driving the tx pin for this reason i
was
able to program the sp32 through the
through the interface the j13 connector
because otherwise the some d21 would
drive the tx pin it it will win because
we'll go directly
to the sp32 pin instead on the interface
we have
a serial resistor if you have
a functioning badge this example will
not function to have it function you
have auto brick
the device or you have to put
the somebody 21 co processor in
bootloader mode because in bootloader
mode
all out input output pins are
automatically configured as
input pins
once uh i i was successfully to use the
arduino ide
i wanted also to reflection some d21 arm
coprocessor y
the first reason is that i want to use
the av label
usb interface on the board to program
this 32 with arduino ide without
using additional circuitry like a ttl
serial adapter to do solder some d21
core processor i have to read
from the usb cell interface and they
have to write
to the sp32 serial interface and vice
versa
making a serial bridge i also want to
use which one is which of the leds that
are
attached to the to the sub d21
and i also want to use the touch buttons
that are attached to the summon d21 so
for this reason i
i want to re rewrite a simple firmware
on this co-processor uh
and interface it with the s32
to do so to to reflect at least i need a
hardware to refresh
as some probe to reflect on the page we
have
the serial wire debug interface that can
be used to refresh
the device and we can use but
we have to use a simple interface we can
use a probe
one of the problem the problem that i
used that i strongly recommend to use is
the segger
j-link a domini it is a very small
problem but very good
prop that is very well supported by open
source
tools and also by proprietary tools like
atmel studio
it is quite cheap it is the ed versions
and version means that you can use for
ob
or for educational purposes but you can
cannot
use it for professional use to make
money which is to make
to use for professional use you have to
use a normal
jailing probe that will cost a few
hundreds dollars but
has more or less the same capabilities
over this probe
there are also some other alternatives
alternatives one very popular
alternative is a breakout
board based on the ft-22 2232 chip that
is a chip
that is on one side the usb interface
and on the other side
it has two serial interface where you
can program multiple protocols
including jtag swd and so on
but is a interface you have to use with
an open source software like
open ocd and it's not integrated in
make commercial software like utml
studio a bit more complicated to use but
a good alternatives some other
alternatives
were popular in the past but today are
not more so used
like bass blaster based on the same chip
but more expensive
or bus pyrate that is very versatile but
is also slower and anyway it also more
expensive
once we have we know how to refresh the
firmware we have developed
we have to develop the simple firmware
that does
what we want uh to develop the firmware
the natural choice is to use
utml studio that is the the suite
of tools com the integrated the id
uh integrated tools to develop firmware
for the
uh for atmel chips it is freely
available so you can download
and install but it has some other box
first of all is windows only
usually i am forced to use windows
during my daily job but outside of my
daily job i
try to never use windows so it is was
not
the best option for me but it was only
options
it is overblocked because it took about
half an hour to install to install
my old windows pc the atmosphere itself
is more than four
gigabytes in size more you have my
microsoft visual studio this is another
one 1.5 5 gigabytes and
a lot it installed a lot of additional
software like dotnet frameworks and so
on
it is a totally graphical user interface
based
also to do simple things like assigning
a label to a pin
you have to use the graphical user
interface
it is a really overbloaded optimal
software framework so if you do a simple
project
like blinking led you use the go
interface to generate the template
for your project and the template for a
simple project like blink led
is literally hundreds of files so really
really uh bloated environment
the graphical user interface is very
easy to use but allows you to create
legal configuration so you create some
configuration compile everything
put the firmware on your chip but the
the firmware will not run will not do
anything because maybe you have
wrongly configured a clock signal
and the clock configuration is quite
complex because you try to use the gui
without reading the data sheet
and it's very easy to to make some
illegal configurations because it's not
easy to understand what you can do and
what you cannot do
but in any way atmel studio is uh is
also as
also some nice features for example
visual studio is a good implicit
graphical user interface
it is very well integrated with the
jailing probe so it's very easy
to flash the device from inside the id
you click a menu and are able to program
a device
with the firmware you have just
completed and it is
also very easy to debug your program
executing
it with a debugger securing
it step by step on the real hardware
so i wrote a simple hello world program
in the
in the hardware embedded space and
lowered means
lighting some leds in this case i wrote
a simple
hello world program that basically
alternates
the colors read the green and blue on
the leds and then
toggle each one of the six leds on the
board
i programmed his with atmel studio and i
wrote his firmware on the some d21
co-processor maybe because we likes a
lot of leds maybe is
not any lower the program and merry
christmas with some
some in advance but anyway this is a
small demo of this program
so here we have our activity
badge 2019 this
is the segger j-link mini
edu probe this is the
simple breakout board to convert this
this
small cable to these bigger
cables and these cables are attached to
the swd interface of the same d21
arm processor we can now
program this processor
using atmel studio here it is a very
simple program
that basically set the colors
to blue the first time to green the
second time
into red at the time and then it re
repeat again this cycle and
switch on and off each
one of the leds toggle the level of each
one
of the six leds
so we can build this program
with build solution the program has been
built
and then thanks to the integration
between the atmel
ide and jlink
edu mini we can go directly to the
device programming menu
we have selected the correct device
we click to apply we can
read from the device and then we can go
to memories
to program the device a weekly we click
program and then the the probe
will program the device reset the device
and as you can see we have
blinking leds
the collar or the leads switch between
green red and blue and
each single lead toggle is the status
status in each cycle
so we have built our hello world or if
you prefer our
merry christmas program in harvard
but after spending few weeks with atmel
studio i tried to write a simple
program to read from the usb serial
interface
and write to the expedite issue serial
interface making and usb bridged
but i found very difficult to find some
examples on the internet
and to mix and merge these examples so
at
the end i understood that i should write
by
myself and from scratch it is a simple
program
to read from usb interface and write a
desktorial interface
but i found that i didn't succeed in
writing this simple program
it seemed impossible to write as a
program without reading the 1000 plus
data sheet pages of some d21 or without
reading the 500 pages plus
of the atmel studio manual so basically
the optimal studio way was the opposite
of the arduino way and so i
started searching on the internet on how
to bring
the someday our summer d21 chip inside
the arduino
ide knowing that similar chips
like the other fruity playground express
that is a similar chip
but with more flesh and more are
already bringing inside the arduino ide
because arduino d is much easier
because the philosophy of arduino ide
as was written by massimo banziman of
the coauthor
of the arduino is that the there is the
concept
that rewriting
from learning how to write things
from scratch is a waste of energy what
you want to do is to
reuse what other people have already
done
and being able to very fast
make some prototypes and then if you
needed you investigate more
and i love the arduino way because it
allow the nobis
to very very fast start playing with
hardware
and the later investigate more if needed
i was quite lucky because not only i
found that someone
on the internet has already ported this
our
co-processor inside the arduino ide
and i should found this before trying to
do
things with the atmel studio but this
was bring it
inside the arduino ide by the same folk
the same people
that designed uh our
our page and what i found on the
internet was
a project for another badge the disobey
2018 page that is very similar to our
pageant was designed by the same
the same people
and i also found a similar repository
where we
i founded escape the schematics of the
disobey 2018 budget
helped me to reconstruct the
schematic of our patch
and in the what i tried to do without
success with atmel studio spending
weeks of time in the
inside the arduino ide is very very very
easy
so in the arduino ide usb serial to
esp32 serial bridge
is done with only 10 lines of code you
read from one serial interface with
a simple call and write to the other
serial interface with another call and
vice versa
so i rewrote the bootloader on my
some d21 co-processor the bootloader was
available
on this repository and
i compiled with the arduino id
the the firmware available this
repository
loaded inside some t21 using the
procedure that is available on this
repository using
the futil and so i uh
i add i should have everything really
to use for the to use with arduino ide
so i tried to load a sketch into the
esp32
using the arduino ide but with my
surprise
i found i cannot do i found an error
during the loading of the sketch
basically the problem was that the
serial bridge
was not fast enough the serial bridge
was dropping bytes during the
programming phase
the problem is that arduino ide is
fantastic it's very easy to use very
simple
but it hides complexity and sometimes
can generate code that is quite
inefficient
so it is the case it wasn't able to
read and write on two different server
interface
without dropping bytes
message to solve the issue what i did
was to increase
the tx and rx serial buffer
from the 64 bytes to 512 bytes
this value probably was so low because
our co-processor has
very small amount of static ram so
saving
each bite was important in this way
i add more room to prevent dropping of
and another modification was that i
rewrote
the the serial bridge
to be non-blocking this means
being sure to have already
byte available in rx buffer before
reading from the serial interface and
being sure
to have free bytes available on
tx buffer before writing
a byte on the seller interface in this
way
each call will return immediately
without
waiting for the actual byte to be
received
or to be sent
after these new modifications our serial
interface was working
as it is simple demo now i will show you
that we are
able to upload our sketch for the s32
processor and that our sketch will be
able to talk
to the some d21 co-processor and will be
able
to switch on and off few leds
and also to read the status of the touch
buttons that are attached to the
co-processor
we can see that we have selected as our
board
the the esp32 development module
basically we will try our esp32 directly
and as part we have content that it is
our disobey page
2019 port so we
can now press this button this will
compile our our sketch
and we'll upload this sketch
you can see that it is driving the
comma port and that it is uploading
our sketch now uploading is finished
and it started to
to power on some leds but there is too
light so you can see i will
lower the light just one second now
it's easier to see the leds lighting and
we can also see that
we can read the touch buttons if i press
the
upper button the backlight of the
display goes on so i can press
if i press the down button i select the
led the red color for leds deselect the
blue color and this one select the green
color
this left button will keep on
all the leds i can combine multiple
buttons so we have
all leds on and red or blue
and so on i can also drive the buzzer
clicking the right right button
as you can see we have successfully
loaded the sketch on our
board and everything is going well
this is a very nice arduino now it is
very nice arduino development board
we have removed the micro python and
a quite powerful arduino development
board with a nice display
leds on the board the touch buttons
and also infrared and a lot of available
pins
in conclusion i was successful in
bringing the arduino
ide in using arduino id to program the
esp32
on the batch and basically this way the
activity 2018 page
is a nice arduino id based
development port very nice development
board with the touch buttons
leds a nice display
infrared and so on a very very nice
development board
there is some something still to do it
that i am doing and that i will publish
on my website when done
to modify an existing library to drive
to display the because the existing
library
is able to drive the display but only
using the spi interface and
not the i2c interface interface
and i as in every project i learned
something or better i reinforced
what i already knew one of the first
principle is that
never to get stuck if you find a
stumbling block
during on your road you have to find a
sideway
you don't have to insist to
go to go forward in the in the road that
is blocked
in this way i should have spent less
time with
optimal studio in trying uh trying
to bring this co-processor inside the
arduino ide
before insisting with utml studio
and another very important information
that is always useful
in any in every reverse engineering
project
is to use also partial information like
information from a similar product
they made by the same company because
very often
information from similar products can be
very useful to speed up your reverse
engineering process
you have to check and verify that
everything you find on a similar
product will apply to your device but
anyway will help a lot in speeding
the reverse engineering process thank
you for
your time i am now available on zoom for
your question