hi everyone
welcome to the machine learning security
invasion competition 2020.
my name is zoetambaraj and i'm the head
of vulnerability research lab at cujo ai
i had some offensive research in the
past for example you might have heard
about the zombie browser toolkit
the hardware firewall bypass tool the
mother analysis
sandbox tester tool or you might have
heard
that i played with some crappy iot
devices
where i invented the idea of encrypted
exploit delivery via diffie-hellman key
exchanges
besides these offensive researches i am
the co-organizer
of the accessory meetup here in hungary
and i'm the program committee member of
the activity conference
this is a joint research together with
dr hiram anderson
he's an architect at the azure
trustworthy machine learning at
microsoft and he is the co-founder and
co-chair
at canvas organization his background is
from signal processing and machine
learning
but he's also very good when it comes to
information security
his main relevant research is that
he created some code regarding
reinforcement
learning with av evasion and he's also
the co-creator of the amber
data sets machine learning
is used in an awful lot of different
ways
in our life for example researchers can
use machine learning to classify objects
and for example when the machine
learning model
looks at the photo it can decide whether
there's a boss or an
animal on this object there was some
interesting research
done in the past by to trick these
machine learning
classifiers on the left side
you can see a normal boss and on the
right side
for the human eye you can see the same
bus but because there was an added layer
to this photo if you try to
reclassify the photo on the right it
will classify this
as an ostrich but we are in
information security right now so we are
interested in malicious software
detection there were multiple
research in the past how you can bypass
machine learning based
mother detection for example last year
some researchers found that if you
extract strings
from a game file and just dumbly
append these strings to a known
malicious executable
you can bypass the machine learning
detection i also did
some research in the past and four years
ago
you could even bypass some
machine learning models just by packing
the file
with a known packer like upx
luckily this has changed
recently so you cannot use this trick
anymore
me and hyrum thought that there's a nice
potential here
to create a competition
so we created the website
evademoverml.io
and what you have to do is basically
download
50 working mother samples and
download free machine learning models
with its weights
modify the mother samples to evade
the detection by these machine learning
models submit those to our website
and if you achieve the highest scores
you could win
this nice nvidia gpu
the outcome of this competition was
pretty interesting
around 70 people registered for the
competition
and at least 11 were able to bypass at
least
one machine learning model at the end of
august
william flashman submitted his
latest samples and scored the
maximum score you can have in the
competition
i highly recommend everyone to go and
check out
his excellent blog post about how he was
able to do this
you can also find other interesting
write-ups
for example you can check out jacob
devski's or fabregio
chess cleans research
and how they were able to bypass
the machine learning models
for example it might be
[Music]
interesting to see whether you can
bypass
detection by using a packer packers were
mostly used in the past
to bypass av-based av signature
detection
but turned out that because in this
competition we are using binaries
and some of these samples are already
packed adding another layer of packer
on top of it might break the
functionality of the sample itself
another interesting solution was to
add new sections to the pe executable
and for example you can extract
resources
from known files like microsoft files
and add these resources
to the malicious sample turned out
again this can be very effective to
evade the models in our competition
but unfortunately it broke some mother
because some other samples had
packers or self checks and
just by adding a new section to the
sample
broke the functionality
fun fact just by adding
a simple empty section
to a sample
you can even bypass some antivirus
engines
i believe this is because of performance
reasons
because the ev engine can quickly
check how many sections are in the
marvel
and only use
those signatures on the sample which
check the section size so this can be
a nice trick for your heavy evasion
last but not least the winning strategy
was to append some extra data to the
executable
with this technique is also called an
overlay
and even though this is very dumb and
plain turned out this was the winning
strategy after all
and williams
solution was to brute force the ml
models and found the pattern which
evades
all machine learning models
and again fun fact by significantly
changing
the size of a sample for example just by
adding a lot of overlay to it
you might be able to bypass some av
engines
again i believe this is because of
performance
reasons for example
here you can see one mother sample we
are using in the competition
and if you are adding some overlaid text
to the end of the sample you can see
how the visual representation of the
file
changes some key takeaways
from last year's competition turned out
that the markov and non-neck mark of
machine learning models are a bit too
academic and they are not very effective
when it comes to
practical mother detection
the life project which you can use to
modify
binaries is awesome and
it's not that shocking but dealing with
malware is tricky
because the iocs they can produce
can change over time which
makes it hard for us to detect whether
this is the same sample or not
and there was also this epic challenge
that some pack and protected samples are
hard
to deal with i also checked uh
some of these samples with the ssd
patch and turned out that those samples
which had
either these repeating
sections or some repeating
overlaid data they create
repeating patterns in the ssd patch
itself
and uh one interesting fact is that
uh from now on you can basically check
the ssd hash of a sample and if you see
repeating patterns in it it might
be suspicious because uh
in an average benign
binary sample there are no repeating
patterns there is
no reason to do this so this could be
some way
suspicious that for example someone
tries to evade a machine learning model
with this technique this year
we created a new defender challenge on
the top of the attacker challenge
where you had to create your own machine
learning model and submit it to the
competition
via docker format and in the edit care
challenge
you have to evade these previously
submitted
machine learning models but now
this was a black box attack
compared to last year where the
challengers at the
white box access to these machine
learning models
this year our sponsors and partners are
microsoft kujo ai
vm ray and mrg avitas but the main
organizer people remained
the same in the competition
and one reason why
it makes sense to participate in our
competition is that you can
win azure credits for your machine
learning
research plans in the defensive track
we received two submissions which passed
the minimum requirements and
you can see when you submit uh your
samples that there are three models
right now
the ember model the need for speed model
and random string model dom
these are the mother families we have
used in the attacker offensive
track which ends on at the 18th
of september at the time of this
recording
this competition has not finished yet so
we don't know the results
the flowchart of the attacker challenge
is that you go to the
msr.io website register there
review the terms and services and accept
it
download the 50 provided mother
samples you somehow modify your
samples you know and hope that it will
evade all three
machine learning models we also
hope that you check your mother
functionality in a windows 10
sandbox and new this year
we have an api to submit
your samples or query the results if you
don't
like the web-based ui
and you can use this api now
and whenever you are satisfied with your
samples
just create a zip file and upload it
to our website you can get
up to three points for each sample based
on how many
machine learning models you invaded and
the highest score wins but
with this year we are also counting the
number of total api queries
which is counted whenever you check a
sample
with a machine learning model and
in order to claim your price your
solution must be
published on a blog post
as it was the case last year please
check that your file names remain the
same
in the zip file otherwise we have no way
to
identify which sample is which
and besides the tricks last year
we have also some additional tips and
tricks you can use to manipulate the
binaries
for example you can add or remove
signatures
change the section names or properties
modify the
import or export tables create a tls
callback
change the header maybe fix or change
check sum add modify or remove
the version information create a new
entry point
or change some code or data which
doesn't affect
the behavior of the sample
still it's not allowed to use droppers
or self-extracting air highs
and multiple registration is against the
rules and will result in immediate
disqualification
feel free to join our slack channel
and last year and this year
if you are interested how we have
created this challenge
it's all based on python flask admin and
we are using
cloudflare enginex ng unicorn for
scalability and performance reasons
and we are running python backend
scripts
and we are using the vmree memory
sandbox
to check whether the mother sample
behaves
the same as it was originally
as mentioned we have an api this year
for example if you want to submit your
sample to all
machine learning models and get an
immediate feedback
feedback on it you can see the api
endpoint on the point one or if you just
want to submit your sample
to one specific emma model you can do
that as well
uh on the point three you can see the
api
endpoint to get the results
or if you already are satisfied with the
results and want to upload your
zip file with all the samples you can do
this
with the api as well or
you can query the specific zip status or
query all samples or specific samples
based on these api endpoints
but let me show you how this really
looks like in practice
so you visit our website mnsec dot io
you definitely should check out the
rules because you have to be familiar
with
everything that's written here we also
recommend you
to check out our github page for example
for the attackers section
hirom already uploaded
some interesting files which you will be
able to see
later now if i go and
login to the website
here as you can see you can download
the mother samples for this competition
and if i check what's inside
uh this
compressed zip file you can see it's 50
samples
with sequential names and now your task
is to
change these files in a way that
hopefully it will bypass
the machine learning detection but still
the sample will remain functional
now let's go and
upload our file
and
let me show it this to you it's
important
that in the zip files the file names
remain the same and you don't
use any directories for example
so let's download this new
zip file and
let's see what will happen
i paused the recording for a little bit
but now as you can see the samples
has been started to in the analyze
process
and here you can see all the different
information
uh from my test upload as you can see
even though these executables were valid
new executables for the competition i
was not able to bypass
any of these machine learning algorithms
mainly because i did not intend to do so
but as you can see
now the whole sample processing started
it's uh also interesting to check out
your user management site and
change your nickname to something better
because by default it's randomly
generated
and it's also important to have a look
at
the total api queries because
this counts into the your
total ranking and
every time a sample of yours is
submitted to
a single machine learning model this
counter is
incremented by one
and now if i check out
the scores section you can see that
someone already has the
best scores when it comes to
bypassing the machine learning models
because we have the free machine
learning model and 50 samples so that's
a total
of 150 scores
but this contestant used
741 total api queries for his solution
so maybe we will we don't know
maybe someone else will be able to
achieve the same score
with less number of total api queries
basically that is all what i wanted
to share with you you can also remove
some of your samples if it's
it was not able to bypass anything
you can also filter these
columns if you are interested or
you can also export all of your
all of data from this table to a csv
file if you want to process it for
yourself
so that's all thank you
this is all i wanted to share with you
guys today but
please stay because here comes hyrum
anderson
who will show you an example solution
which could have been used
to win the competition
my name is hyrum anderson and i'm
delighted to present virtually at
activity i'm going to be
presenting the machine learning evasion
code walkthrough
this tool was included in the sample
solution to the attacker challenge
in the machine learning security evasion
competition
you can download and play with this code
by visiting mlsec.io
and navigating to the attacker challenge
github repo
our example solution was designed with
the following things in mind
number one the models to be attacked
were submitted by contestants
in the defender challenge that concluded
previously
two models from the previous round
qualified to be included in the attacker
challenge
in addition we have hosted our own model
to be attacked that is based on the
ember data set
the models to be attacked report hard
labels
for submissions provided to them that is
they do not provide a score between 0
and 1
but just a 0 for benign and one for
malicious
finally we considered the leaderboard
criteria
while designing our solution the first
criterion
considers the number of model evasions
with three models and 50 malware samples
the maximum score is 150 points
a tiebreaker would be decided by the
efficiency
in which the models were evaded so we
count the number of model queries
thus contestants are incentivized not
only to be evasive
but also to do it efficiently
contestants were able to choose any
strategy that they like
to demonstrate one strategy we released
this example code
on our competitions github site
the code uses discrete optimization
over functionality preserving file
modifications
using a package called hyperopt which
ironically
is often used for tuning
machine learning models you can learn
more about
the details from the code
and documentation on the website
however the broader strategy may be of
general interest
it consists of employing an algorithm in
part a
to get the bulk of the malware to be
evasive
while remaining functional followed by
any
additional manual steps in part b to
fix any few remaining samples
we use the example code in our strategy
in part a
in which we break our algorithmic attack
into two phases an offline attack
against
a known defender model for which we have
code and weights
and an online attack the hope is that
many of the samples
that were discovered in the offline
attack will cross evade
the hosted online models without having
used any additional queries against the
api
you may visit mlsectao to download this
code
however please be warned that when you
run this demo code
you will write functional malware to
disk so please do so only using a linux
vm
to begin we initialize the attack by
analyzing a collection of benign files
the init sub-command extracts elements
of the benign files that will be
injected
later into the malware to launch our
offline attack
we first run a local copy of the ember
model
in the top window then in the bottom
window
we'll use the run subcommand of our
attack script
passing in malware samples
that were downloaded by contestants
the tool will write successful evasion
attempts to
pass one success and failed attempts to
pass one
slash failure also included in each
directory
are history files that would allow us to
resume our optimization of failed
attempts
in a second pass we begin with only the
past
one failures and iterate on the
optimization
again storing successes and failures to
a folder of our choice
having now collected candidates that
evade the ember model
we use those candidates as seeds for an
online attack
which now counts against our api query
usage
the online attack is enabled with a
simple dash dash
online flag
after several iterations we can now
gather the successfully evasive variants
and create a zip file to be uploaded to
the website
since there is a chance that the file
modifications have broken
some of the files contestants
have been encouraged to run the samples
in a windows 10 sandbox
to validate functionality before
uploading to the competition website
as a final note since the host of models
may
learn from the queries issued by
contestants
there is a possibility that an evasive
variant discovered by a contestant at
the beginning of the competition
may no longer be evasive to a model
by the end of the competition because
the model has changed its state
we're recording these talks prior to
knowing the winners
of the attacker challenge i would like
to preemptively congratulate
those who have won our grand and first
prizes respectively
in order to receive those prizes the
contestants
must publish or blog about their
solutions
i look forward to learning about the
winning competition strategies
i would like to thank our sponsors and
partners for making this competition
a reality