[Music]
hello everybody
my name is matthias digg welcome to my
talk
there is always one more bug or more
revisiting a wireless alarm system
at activity 2020 online edition
as the title of this talk suggests there
is still one more bug to be found
or at least this is often humorously
attributed to various it products
no matter whether they are soft firm or
hardware
by people dealing with them within the
next couple of minutes
i want to show that this assumption is
sometimes very true
using the example of a wireless alarm
system and some of its accessories
in which yet another security
vulnerability could be found over the
past few years
more than once but before we get to
interesting things
let me briefly introduce myself as
mentioned before
my name is matthias dieg and i've been
working as an i.t security consultant
for the german ide security company sus
since 2007. i'm also head of research
and development
and in charge of our responsible
disclosure program
regarding security vulnerabilities i've
been interested in information
technology
since my early days and very curious in
general
whether security assumptions in soft
firm or hardware hold through when
taking a closer look
the agenda for this talk is as follows
first i'm going to give a very short
introduction to the used technology
of the tested target device an arbor
sequest wireless alarm system
and some of its accessories then i want
to give an overview of our research
the use test methodology and the
involved people
in the last few years there has also
been published research on wireless
alarm systems by
other researchers that i want to mention
next i'm going to talk about the attack
surface and attack scenarios
which are relevant for a wireless alarm
system
then i want to present the actual
security vulnerabilities
of our research that we have found and
reported
and for most of them i have also
prepared short demos
finally i'm going to draw some
conclusions and want to give some
recommendations concerning wireless
alarm systems
and at the end of my talk we have some
time for q and a
here you can see the main target device
of this presentation
an arbor stack quest wireless alarm
system and some of its accessories
a wireless motion detector a wireless
remote control
and a proximity chip key later on
you will also see two more components
for the abu sequest wireless alarm
system not shown here
namely a wireless control device and a
hybrid module
as the word wireless in wireless alarm
system implies
the different components are using radio
technology
for communication purposes all
accessories besides the proximity chip
key
use radio communication in the 863
to 870 megahertz frequency band
on 868.6625 megahertz
the rfid communication of the proximity
key
is in the 13.56 megahertz frequency
range
on this slide you can see a top view of
the abu sequest main panel's pcb
with an arm-based sd electronics
microcontroller and a flash memory chip
for conducting security analysis of the
wireless alarm system and performing
actual attacks
the software defined radio hacker f1 and
the radio dongle
yardstick one both by greatscot gadgets
were used
in my experience these two radio hacking
tools work reliably
and are good enough at least for my
needs the hacker f1 is supported by most
sdr software tools for instance
new radio companion or universal radio
hacker
the yardstick 1 makes use of the quite
popular sub 1 gigahertz transceiver
cc 1111 by texas instruments
and comes with the rfcad firmware
installed
another tool used during this research
project is the erika neighbor developed
by thomas dietert
for the greatpat1 this device provides
four
texas instruments cc1101 transceivers
that can be tuned for different
frequency bands namely 315
433 868
or 915 megahertz the proper
configuration of two transceivers per
frequency band
allows for short reaction times required
in specific test cases
for instance concerning reactive jamming
attacks as you will see
later besides the presenter test
equipment
some experiments and proof of concept
attacks were also implemented
on a teensy development board with a
corresponding cc1101 module
or on another device with a cool form
factor that you will see
in one of the demos two important
technical facts about the wireless
communication
of the arbor sequest wireless alarm
system and its components are
that differential manchester encoding is
used and
that the integrity of radio packets is
checked via a 16-bit
crc our research of wireless alarm
systems
actually started back in 2016 when my
colleague gerard klostermeier
and i decided to analyze different
mostly low-cost wireless alarm systems
for the simplest radio based attack the
replay attack
the discount store aldi on the opposite
side of the street
back then was selling a quite affordable
wireless alarm system set
named easyhome which started this
research project
in which we tested several wireless
alarm systems by different manufacturers
the abu sagres wireless alarm system
happened to be the most expensive of our
test devices
our main test result back then was that
all tested wireless alarm systems
were vulnerable to a simple replay
attack
and to be honest i was surprised by this
a little bit
because i had assumed that a security
product like an alarm system
offers better protection in autumn 2016
we published our findings on german
television in the tv show plus minos
and raised the security awareness for
this kind of security issue
the abu sequest wireless alarm system
that we had bought was still available
after this research project for further
tests
but at first was stowed away in our lab
some time later we got a tip by thomas
stated
that the security fix for our repotted
replay vulnerability
introduced new security vulnerabilities
in the arbor segwest wireless alarm
system
thus with external support first by
thomas stated
and later on also by mikhail rutgers we
had some further looks at the abu
sakhwest wireless alarm system
and found some more security
vulnerabilities within the last two
years
which we have reported to abuse in the
course of our responsible disclosure
program
when analyzing the wireless alarm
systems we actually did not follow our
usual three-part test methodology
for radio based devices including a
hardware analysis
a radio based analysis and firmware
analysis
but this time we only used the radio
based analysis
fortunately this was enough to find some
security vulnerabilities
as with almost every topic there is
previous research
on this slide i have listed several
other publications
regarding the security of wireless alarm
systems
which has been released within the last
couple of years and
that i'm aware of so hacking wireless
alarm systems
is anything but new but i hope that with
our latest research
i am presenting here i can add some
interesting material to this topic
concerning the attack surface of
wireless alarm systems and different
relevant attack scenarios
there is not that much to consider in my
opinion
attacks requiring direct physical
hardware access are less interesting
and attacks that can be performed via
radio signals from some safe distance
only requiring physical proximity to the
target device
are more interesting different kinds of
attacks
against radio based systems that come to
mind are replay attacks
brute force attacks denial of service
attacks jamming attacks
slithing attacks spoofing attacks and
cloning attacks
the last one referring to rfid
communication
here you can see an overview of the 8
security vulnerabilities we have found
regarding the arbor segwest wireless
alarm system
and some of its accessories
the first security issue i want to talk
about is
simple replay attacks for exploiting
this security vulnerability
an attacker just has to record an
interesting radio signal
for example a disarm signal for
deactivating the wireless alarm system
and to replay it later at the right
moment when proprietary radio protocols
are used in wireless devices
they are often missing a replay
protection or only have an insufficient
one
as mentioned earlier all wireless alarm
systems that we have tested back in 2016
were vulnerable to simple replay attacks
this kind of attack enables an attacker
to deactivate an affected wireless alarm
system
in an unauthorized manner in 2016
we exemplarily demonstrated such a
simple replay attack in the german tv
show plus minus
on this slide you can see the probably
most simple flow graph for new radio
companion
which we use for our replay attacks
the second type of attack i want to
present here is a rolling code attack
in order to fix the replay security
vulnerability we had reported
arbus implemented a rolling code in your
remote controls of the
arbor segwest wireless alarm system and
claim to use secure wireless
communication now
as you can see on the corresponding
product website
but as thomas data found out the chosen
rolling code implementation was
cryptographically weak it was actually
so
cryptographically weak that by observing
the unencrypted radio signals
it was possible to deduce the used
rolling code algorithm
and by knowing the rolling code
algorithm and its current state
an attacker can deactivate the wireless
alarm system
in an unauthorized way or perform 18
hour service attack
against the wireless remote control by
desynchronizing it
in the next demo i want to demonstrate a
successful rolling code attack
our test setup consists of three parts
and our sequest wireless alarm system
an abu sagres wireless motion detector
and an abu sequest wireless remote
control
let's see if our test setup is working
properly
sounds good
with the configured wireless remote
control the wireless alarm system
can be conveniently armed or disarmed
the activation was successful
the deactivation also worked as intended
now it's time for our proof of concept
attack
the attacker listens for an arm signal
to learn the current rolling code state
and later sends a disarm signal with a
correct rolling code
the predictable rolling codes enable an
attacker to successfully deactivate the
wireless alarm system
in an unauthorized manner
as a matter of fact now no alarm is
triggered
we have also developed a python proof of
concept tool using
a yardstick one
the unauthorized deactivation of the
wireless alarm system
worked as expected
another proof of concept tool using 18z
3.2 with a cc1101 module
was developed by thomas dietet who found
the security vulnerability
for demonstration purposes this proof of
concept implementation
auto magically deactivates the wireless
alarm system
after a couple of seconds
the third type of attack i want to show
you is a proximity key cloning attack
the other sequest wireless alarm system
supports so-called proximity chip keys
unfortunately the insecure rfid
technology myfair classic is used for
those proximity keys
thus an attacker with one time access
can easily read the information stored
on such a proximity key
in a very short time from distances up
to 1 meter
depending on the used rfid reader
this allows for simple cloning an arbor
sequence proximity chip key
and deactivating an affected wireless
alarm system in an
unauthorized manner in the next demo
a successful proximity key cloning
attack is demonstrated
our test setup consists of three parts
an abu sequest wireless alarm system
an abu sequest wireless motion detector
and an auvo sequest proximity key
let's see if our test setup is working
properly
sounds good
an alarm was triggered thus we have to
manually reset the wireless alarm system
activate
now it's time for our proximity key
cloning proof of concept attack
using a handy pocket computer also known
as smartphone
first we use the android app my fair
classic tool by gerhard klostermeier
to read the contents of the abu sagr's
proximity key
then we use a somewhat special blank my
fair classic card
and write the previously read contents
to it
we enable an advanced feature to also
write a manufacturer block
and write all sectors although in this
case it would be sufficient to only
write block 0 of sector 0
containing the device uid
now we should be good to deactivate the
wireless alarm system with our clone
proximity key
success we disarm the wireless alarm
system with a cloned rfid token
in an unauthorized way as a matter of
fact
no alarm is triggered now
for rfid and nfc security tests and
demonstration purposes
there are also other great tools
available
for example the chameleon mini which is
a versatile nfc device
with a cool form factor
programmed correctly
it can also serve as a proximity key for
the abu sagquest wireless alarm system
last but not least i want to demonstrate
a third way to perform a simple rfid
cloning attack
this time i want to use this blue myfair
classic rfid token
in order to deactivate our wireless
alarm system
now it doesn't work
but this very user-friendly device from
china can help us with that
first we read the content of the
original
second process
5 then we write it to our blue rfid
token
let's see if the cloned rfid token works
as good as the original one
success we disarm the wireless alarm
system with a cloned rfid token
in an unauthorized way once again
the fourth radio based attack i want to
talk about
is a so called reactive jamming attack
the abu sequest wireless alarm system
has an rf jamming detection
which can be configured to trigger an
alarm if there are
unusual interferences on the used radio
channel
however thomas diet found out that the
implemented rf jamming detection
is insufficient as short jamming signals
are not detected
and won't trigger an alarm therefore an
attacker is able to perform
a reactive jamming attack the idea of
radio jamming attacks in general
is to exploit the used shell medium of
wireless transmissions
the electromagnetic spectrum in order to
disrupt a targeted radio transmission
using a specific wavelength an attacker
simply transmits his own radio signal
interfering with the original one this
results
in the intended receiver of the radio
transmission not being able to correctly
receive the original signal anymore
reactive jamming means that an attacker
reacts to specific wireless
transmissions
and only tries to disrupt those for this
the start of an rf message of a wireless
alarm system component
for instance a motion detector has to be
detected
and quickly after this event a stronger
attacker controlled signal has to be
sent
by performing a successful reactive
jamming attack it is possible to
suppress
correctly received rf messages of the
wireless alarm system
in an unauthorized manner for instance
to prevent alarms
on this slide overlaying an original
signal with a stronger attacker signal
during a reactive jamming attack is
illustrated
in the following demo i will show a
successful reactive jamming attack
here you can see the used test setup
with an abu segwest wireless alarm
system
a wireless motion detector and the great
fat one with the erica neighbor
connected to the attacker system
first let's activate the wireless alarm
system
and see if an alarm is triggered via the
motion detector
as you can hear the test setup works
fine
we reset the wireless alarm system and
activate it
again
now we start the reactive jamming attack
using our developed software tool
reactive jammer
while the reactive jammer is running it
detects wireless transmissions
of all components of the abu segwest
wireless alarm system
for instance the wireless motion
detector and
overlays it with another stronger signal
thus the receiver in this case the alarm
panel
is not able to properly decode the
original transmitted message
and no alarm is triggered furthermore
our reactive jamming attack did not
trigger the jamming protection
of the arbor sequest wireless alarm
system
the fifth type of attack i want to
present is a sniffing attack
the targeted device in this attack is
another segways wireless control device
you can see here arbus claims on its
product website
that this device also uses secure
wireless communication
but michael ritkes and thomas data found
out
that the used wireless communication of
the wireless control device
is not so secure as it is missing
encryption
hence by simply observing the
corresponding radio signals
it is possible to see all transmitted
sensitive data as clear text
this enables an attacker to gain access
to sensitive data
like pin codes and proximity token ids
and to deactivate the wireless alarm
system
in an unauthorized way once again
in the next demo successful sniffing
attacks against the arbor stack quest
wireless control device are demonstrated
here you can see the use test setup with
an abu segwest wireless alarm system
a wireless motion detector the wireless
control device
and a yardstick one connected to the
attacker system
in order to eavesdrop on the wireless
communication of the alarm system
the attacker simply starts our developed
python tool
this pin sniffer proof of concept tool
listens for specific arbus data packets
on the correct 868 megahertz radio
frequency
used for the wireless communication
thus when the alarm system is armed via
the wireless control panel
the attacker can receive and decode the
corresponding data packet
in order to gain access to the use clear
text pin code
as a matter of fact the eavesdrop pin
code can be used to disable the wireless
alarm system
in an unauthorized way
the system is unset
besides using a pin code for arming and
disarming the abu sequest wireless alarm
system
it is also possible to use an rfid token
also called proximity or chip key
for eavesdropping on the wireless
communication the attacker simply starts
another developed python tool
and now when the rfid token is used with
the wireless control device
fube 5001 an attacker can receive
and decode the corresponding data packet
in order to gain access
to the use proximity key id by knowing
this id
it is possible to create a cloned rfid
token
here you can see the attacker's blue
proximity key
without having the correct programmed id
but this can be changed by using a very
user-friendly device from china
that enables us to write arbitrary
serial numbers
to this rfid chip please four
four four
five enter the correct card number is
three eight zero five nine
six four four four 5
write success
the system is unset success
the attacker could deactivate the
wireless alarm system
with a cloned rfid token using the
sniffed proximity key id
in an unauthorized way
on this slide you can see the output of
our develop proof of concept tool for
a successful pin code sniffing attack
the sixth and last kind of attack i want
to show you in this talk
is a spoofing attack the targeted device
in this attack is an arbor stack quest
hybrid module
which can be used to extend an arbor sag
quest wireless alarm system
with wired components and to integrate
the arbus w
applox access control system the issue
here is
that the used wireless communication of
this hybrid module is missing security
features
regarding confidentiality and integrity
this enables an attacker to deactivate
the wireless alarm system in an
unauthorized manner
or to perform an authentication bypass
attack regarding the w applox access
control system
in a corresponding system configuration
in the next and final demo a successful
spoofing attack
against an apostate quest wireless alarm
system with a hybrid module
is demonstrated
here you can see the used test setup
with an abu segwest wireless alarm
system
a wireless motion detector the hybrid
module fumo 50110
with a programmed switch key switch
configuration
and a yardstick one connected to the
attacker system
the
[Music]
the system is sending
in order to perform a spoofing attack
against the insecure wireless
communication
the attacker simply starts our developed
python tool
this software tool listens for specific
status packets
that are sent from the hybrid module to
the wireless alarm panel
at regular time intervals of about two
and a half minutes
when a packet containing a status
message from the hybrid module is
received
the attacker can launch a disarming
attack using a spoofed radio packet
the system is unset and successfully
disarm the wireless alarm system
in an unauthorized way
now it's time to draw some conclusions
in order to have a better picture
it is good to know the current patch
status for the 8 security
vulnerabilities i was talking about in
the last few minutes
to my knowledge up to now only the
missing protection
against replay attacks was fixed all
other described security vulnerabilities
can still be found and exploited
in the corresponding arbus sequence
products
with that i come to the conclusions that
security products like wireless alarm
systems
may be more vulnerable to different
types of radio based attacks
than you would probably first assume
that marketing claims regarding security
features
may just be that marketing claims that
product certificates
like vds home and en 5131
grade 2 may give a false sense of
security
that some security vulnerabilities are
hard or even impossible to fix in
hardware products
already in use for example when no
update functionality exists
or when there are compatibility issues
concerning other devices you have to
consider
and that so-called forever bucks may
affect the security of a product
until its end of life
based on our research and my experience
with wireless alarm systems
i therefore recommend to choose wireless
alarm systems wisely
to perform a thorough online research
before buying such a product
to reconsider your previous decision for
using a wireless alarm system
to not have too much faith in product
certificates and marketing claims
and finally to ask the manufacturer or
vendor for further security testing
beyond product certification and this is
very important
the scope of those tests if there were
any
on the next three slides i have put
together several references
to further information about different
things regarding wireless alarm systems
i have mentioned in this talk
so this is it i hope you've enjoyed my
talk
thank you very much for your attention
do you have any questions
you