hi
welcome to activity conf we're going to
talk about
service mess to service mesh a journey
around service meshes
and in particular looking at istio and
linker d we'll see a live demo of each
of those
let's dive in
so here's the part where i tell you i'm
definitely going to post my slides on my
site tonight
you're gonna go look on my site tonight
tomorrow
next week next month in about three
months you're gonna get tired of waiting
you're gonna email me
in about six months i'll reply and say
no i'm definitely gonna post them on my
site tonight
and i'll never post them at all i've
been in this spot and i hate it too
which is why you can go to robrich.org
right now
and you can pull up the slides let's go
to robrich.org we'll click on
presentations
and here is service mess to service mesh
you can see the slides
right here while we're here on
robrich.org let's click on about me and
we'll look at this page
i'm a microsoft mvp i'm a friend of red
gate
az gift camp is wonderful easy gift camp
brings volunteer developers together
with charities who otherwise couldn't
afford software services
we start building software for them
friday after work sunday afternoon
we deliver that completed software back
to the charities sleep is optional
caffeine provided
if you're in phoenix come join us for
the next a-z gift camp it is a lot of
fun
or if you'd like a gift camp in your
area hit me up by email or twitter
and let's get philanthropy installed in
your area as well
sql server source control basics that
was a lot of fun uh minus chapter eight
i was on the gulp core contributor team
in version two and version three
one of the things that i'm particularly
proud of is i replied to a.net rocks
podcast episode
they read my comment on the air and they
sent me a mug
so there's my claim to fame so let's dig
into service mess to service mesh
when we look at a service mesh we we
talked about this guy
when we look at a service mesh imagine
imagine when you were learning how to
drive do you remember the feeling of
that open road
the the feeling of getting to control a
machine
going fast not getting caught going fast
imagine the empty road in a country town
how much fun that would be to drive well
over time lots of people may come into
town
the town may grow up and we end up with
traffic well now i'm not really going as
fast as i want to
you know there aren't any uh signs or
control
stations it just gets to be a mess
i'm not getting to where i want to be as
efficiently as possible
so how do we solve this well in time
we'll probably get one of these the
officer is standing at the edge of town
he's going to go grab all of the people
who are speeding
and ultimately we're now able to move
consistently through town well
we're moving consistently but we're not
moving efficiently
we've rewarded conformity over
expedience what would be better
is if we could do something like this if
we had a mechanism where the cars could
communicate with each other
and prioritize traffic based on urgency
or
based on priority or just communicating
so that we could all get there as
quickly and as efficiently as we needed
to
now this doesn't say that one car going
faster or slower is better or worse but
rather
that the cars can communicate together
to make sure that everyone gets
as fast or as slow as they need to to
get to their destination efficiently
we'll use this metaphor as we look at
service meshes and
compare that to the mechanisms around
api gateways and other technology
is a service mesh let's look at what is
a service mesh
let's look at some of the
pardon me some of the features around
service meshes let's compare service
meshes to api gateways
let's look at common service meshes
we'll look at istio and linker d
today and then let's do a live demo of
both
istio and linker d that will be really
fun and then ultimately we'll talk about
best practices when should i use a
service mesh when
should i not use a service mesh come
join us
so what is a service mesh well a service
mesh
manages network traffic between services
in a great
graceful and scalable way
we could think of the service mesh as
the answer to
how do i observe control or secure
communication between microservices
we're inside of a kubernetes cluster or
another containerized cluster
we have all of our micro services and we
want to control
observe or secure that traffic between
those services
well how did we get here so
observe control and secure
we'll dig into that quite a bit as we go
observe
control and secure that's really what a
service mesh does
observe it can watch traffic as it moves
between microservices it can see
when one service calls another service
and
it can see when services shouldn't call
other services
control now that i've identified which
services
call which other services we can create
policies around that to make sure that
some services are able to call other
services and some services are blocked
from calling other services
we don't want a rogue service starting
up and just calling out to the
everything
observe control secure
we'll do mutual tls between our
microservices
now the cool thing about doing this
inside of a service mesh
is that our code doesn't need to change
to be able to communicate
securely across the service mesh we'll
have mechanisms in here for
mutual tls for trust chains
the service mesh can be a certificate
authority or we can lean on a
certificate authority from an outside
source
we'll communicate securely and
efficiently
observe control secure that's what a
service mesh is
so how did we get here on the left we
have a mechanism
of monolithic application on the right
we have microservices
on the left we had this monolithic
application because deployment was hard
it was difficult for us to be able to
push things to production
so we did it really infrequently we
would bundle
as much as we could into that one thing
and we would push it to production
and then we'd be done the hard part is
over
as we got better at deployment and in
particular at containers
we moved to microservices like the
service on the right
now each of these microservices
accomplishes a specific
task and we can upgrade each one when
it's necessary
or replace a microservice which with a
microservice that functions better here
we moved from monolithic applications to
microservices because deployment was no
longer hard
and now we have a whole lot more options
we can scale each service independently
we can communicate differently
but now each microservice is
kind of public maybe not completely
public but in a monolithic application
all of our private internal methods were
internal they weren't exposed outside of
our executable
in microservices each one of our private
private methods has
a web address it might be an internal
web address but it's a web address and
anything could call it
and that's the problem that we're
setting out to serve
with a service mesh it's starting to
observe
control and secure that communication
between
our internal services within our
application
as we talk about securing communication
we'll talk about
north south traffic and east-west
traffic
just to kind of level set here north
south traffic
is traffic into or out of our cup our
containerized cluster
east-west traffic represents traffic
going between our microservices
so for example in this diagram here on
the right
a user is on top our database is on the
bottom so north south traffic will go
into our cluster or out of our cluster
and east-west traffic will go between
our micro services
just some cool terminology what's really
cool is that a service mesh allows us to
control
both north-south traffic into and out of
our cluster
and also east-west traffic traffic
between services
so what came before well we got to this
point where
all of our private services had ip
addresses
and that was interesting but now what
we created this api gateway an api
gateway is this boundary
fence around our cluster for any traffic
coming into our cluster it has to check
in with the api gateway to make sure
that it's allowed to proceed
if it has the right credentials if it
has the right keys
if it's running on the right ports then
the traffic can come in
now it is just a boundary around our
cluster
so it's able to control north-south
traffic really easily
but it's not able to control east-west
traffic
now we see in this diagram that we have
microservices calling other
microservices that's perfect that's what
we want
but the microservices are also reaching
into somebody else's data source
we don't want that but the api gateway
being this boundary fence around
our cluster has no visibility into that
the api gateway
is merely the boundary around the
cluster that traffic cop on the edge of
town
he couldn't patrol the content within
town his task was only to filter the
traffic coming into town
the north-south traffic coming into our
cluster the east-west traffic traffic
between microservices
we can't manage that with an api gateway
and that's where we reach for a service
mesh
so how does a service mesh work at its
core principle a service mesh will
typically deploy a side car
within each pod so in this case
service a wants to call service b
service a
is a container deployed in this pod
together with a sidecar container an
envoy proxy
service b is also deployed with a
sidecar proxy so service a wants to
reach out to service b
without a service mesh service a would
just directly connect to service b
with a service mesh service a is going
to reach out to service a's envoy proxy
now the envoy proxy is going to go check
in with the control plane
for the service mesh is service a
allowed to connect to service b
if so then the control plane will give
service a the
details of how to connect to service b
and it'll open a
mutually tls encrypted connection
service a's proxy then communicates with
service b's proxy
and service b proxy again checks in with
the control plane
is service a allowed to call me in this
case the control plane is going to say
yes and service b is going to forward
the
or service b's proxy is going to forward
the traffic onto service b
service b will reply to the proxy the
traffic flows across that mutually
encrypted tunnel
back to service a's proxy and al back to
service a
the cool part is the pod boundary that
network boundary
is the only place where service a and
service a proxy communicate
everything outside the boundary is
secured with mutual tls
that's a service that's a service mesh
service a communicates with services
proxy services proxy checks in with the
service mesh
control plane communicates to service
b's proxy
serves b's proxy forwards it on to
service b
now we can switch out the implementation
details perhaps
service a is ingress into the cluster
or perhaps service b is outside of the
cluster
so in this case we'll have traffic
coming in to the cluster
it will still check in with that control
plane and if allowed it will communicate
securely with the microservice in our
cluster
or for traffic leaving the cluster
service a's
envoy proxy will check in with the
control plane
and only if allowed to communicate
outside the cluster
will it create that encrypted tunnel
outside the cluster to service b
this is kind of the principle around
service mesh and this is that
magical piece we're standing in between
the communication between all the
services
well because we're standing in between
the traffic here
we can do some really really interesting
things
we're going to start with observe secure
and control
but let's dig in deeper observe control
and secure
since we're proxying all the traffic we
can observe
all the communication between all of our
services now this is interesting
we don't just get what the developer
thought was happening
we get what's actually happening on the
wire
now we can create access policies we can
control that traffic
is servicea allowed to talk to service b
or is service a a rogue service that
just got spun up
we can create these access policies so
that only the traffic
that we want flows in the directions
that we want within our cluster
and then mutual tls security
we're creating this mutual tls with a
trust chain
without impacting the code in our
cluster we don't need to
change our application to be able to
speak securely
between our services that's really
powerful
observe control secure but let's not
stop there
because we're standing in between all of
the
communication in our service we can step
up a level as well
let's map out the network topology now
this isn't
what the developer thought would happen
in our cluster
this is what's actually happening in our
cluster
am i talking to the configuration
service if i'm not
maybe those hard-coded debug values
accidentally got checked in
we can check our network topology and
make sure it is what we expect
service health because we're standing in
between all of the services
is this service timing out is it
returning 500 errors
is it taking too long to do a request we
can con
we can collect all of these metrics
around
a particular service and understand if
it's healthy
is it behaving normally is it behaving
abnormally
let's take all of that content and set
it in the log that log will
allow us to collect all these metrics
and to be able to do really interesting
things with them
because we're standing between the
service we can do lots of cool things
around
the traffic in our cluster let's level
up again
so now let's start about let's start
talking about traffic shaping
as we're creating these control control
policies
we don't just want to block traffic but
what if we create an a b test what if we
take
a new version and direct i don't know
five percent of the traffic ten percent
of the traffic towards this new service
and see how it goes
or do an a b test between two different
versions and see if we can learn
more about how our customers behave and
optimize our site
to create really elegant experiences
or let's create a beta channel or a
canary release
and point those users who have opted in
to that particular service
circuit breakers are really powerful
imagine a service is struggling
well if the service is struggling
we need to give it a break um if the
service goes down the first thing all
the clients probably do is
um retry so now that struggling service
that was overloaded
that just went down now it's starting to
come back up and suddenly it's flooded
with requests
and so the first thing it does is well
go down again
and so we'll have this kind of spike up
and down and up and down where the
moment the service gets a little bit of
its feet under it again it falls over
again with all of that traffic
instead let's trip the circuit breaker
like circuit breakers in electricity
this circuit breaker is there to protect
the equipment behind it
rather than blowing a
the electronics in our device we'll blow
the fuse in our circuit breaker
so that we can protect those electronics
reset the circuit breaker and now we can
try again
similarly when the service is unhealthy
the circuit breaker trips
and now this the circuit breaker can
tell calling applications
this isn't going to work take another
path
perhaps it's a recommendation service
and we can still let the user check out
we just won't show them
related products we haven't given them a
poorer
inferior experience we've just hidden
some of the lesser
features in our site once that service
comes back up
and it's healthy the circuit breaker has
validated that the system is live
then we can flow traffic back to it and
that can happen automatically we don't
need to wait for a human to go
reset the circuit breaker in service
mesh the circuit breaker can reset
itself when it's ready
all of these features are available in
service mesh because we're standing
between all of the communication in all
our systems
ultimately we're logging all of this
content and we can start to visualize
that in some really elegant dashboards
on the left is a grafana dashboard where
we see metrics around
our service on the right is a network
topology diagram where we can see
how services call each other these kind
of dashboards can give us
great insight into our services and help
us understand how our services are doing
we talked about preventing unexpected
traffic patterns
let's dig in again because a service
mesh is standing between
all of the things we can see that in
this case
our microservices are calling each
other's data sources we don't want to
allow that let's create a traffic
policy that blocks them from
communicating with data sources that are
not their own
yeah we'll probably need to re-architect
our application to do that
but we're able to discover this we're
able to control this
and affect some real change see some
status of updates in our
cluster as we make these changes a
service mesh
empowers us to have this visibility and
this control
into our service architecture
so what's some example service meshes we
could look at
istio and linker d we could look at
console we could look at open service
mesh
each of these service meshes has
features and benefits and we can start
to talk about well which one's faster
which one has the most
features and they all leapfrog each
other so for the most part
if you wait a minute the other service
mesh will have that feature too
so rather than comparing their features
or their cost or their
complexity let's instead compare their
methodology
take a look at how these things are
built and what they value
at that point we can choose the
methodology that best
matches our needs and that'll lead us to
the correct service mesh
so for example linker d linker d focuses
on simplicity in particular simplicity
of getting started
it has the bare minimum features they
work really well together
and they're available out of the box
really quickly
but if you want more complexity than
that more features you'll pull in third
party packages that will do that
linker d is really good at crafting
their own little pieces
and they work really well they're
contributing a lot to the
rust networking stack because they're
building it out in
they're building out linker d and rust
that's really powerful
by comparison istio focuses on kind of
having that kitchen sink experience
they install all the things and you can
turn them on and turn them off with
flags
a profile flag
istio also bundles a lot of best in
breed
products into the service mesh so you'll
get
a grafana dashboard over the top of
prometheus syncs
all of this con other open source
software is bundled with istio as well
so you'll get the best of breed
big din but it is a bulkier install
you can turn features on and off as you
need to and that's really cool
so let's dig into a demo we'll start out
with a demo of linker d
we'll also look at a demo of istio
so i have here a linker d cluster
or rather i have here a kubernetes
cluster that is
for the most part empty
let's spin up linker d as we
get started with linker d linker d's
pass getting started page is really
elegant
you start out by installing the
ctl i've already the command line cli
rather
i've already done this you put it in
your path
i've done this as well and next up let's
validate our cluster
ah linker d check
dash pre this will go through our
cluster and validate that it's ready for
kubernetes
does it have are ready for link or d
does it have all of the things set up is
kubernetes functioning correctly
in this case yes linker
d install pipe it to cube ctl
apply dash f dash
and it'll pull in all of the resources
associated with
linker d this six this install
experiment experience
is really elegant it just pulls it all
in
and it just works
linker nope linker d
check we did dash dash pre before to say
let's go see if our cluster is ready now
without the pre
we're going to go validate the link or d
setup and in particular
it will wait for those things to spin up
as it needs to
and that's really cool
is it ready go go go
go it's still spinning up
i love watching these things spin up and
i love how it checks to see that
everything is running correctly
it does take it a minute to spin up
especially when my machine is doing lots
of other things
but uh there we go linker d is ready
cube ctl dash n linker d
get all link d
get all and we will see all of the
resources that linker d spun up
the deployments the services the pods
and there's other things there's a cron
job that's pretty cool
linker nope linker d
dashboard
now the linker d dashboard is really
cool let's dig into the linker d
namespace and we'll get to see all of
the
pods available in this namespace here's
all those pods
they're uptime and we can get at a
grafana dashboard for each one
let's take a look at i don't know this
one
here's that grafana dashboard explaining
the
service health for this particular
service now obviously it's been up for
you know a second so there isn't a whole
lot of
descriptive content but that was really
fast to spin up
that was really really cool
now i'd invite you to come to linker d
getting started
and there's a great way to walk through
the dashboard and walk through a demo
app
but for the sake of time let's show
istio
istio has a similar experience of
getting started
where you start by downloading the istio
cli and i've already done that
install istio set profile equals demo
and set the namespace default istio
injection enabled
we're tagging a particular namespace we
can do this in link or d as well
and by tagging that namespace the istio
control plane knows that any pods that
get scheduled into that namespace
should have that proxy
that envoy proxy installed as a sidecar
within it
and so now as we start to deploy our
application
we can just deploy it and all those side
cars will get pulled into place
i've already installed this book info
sample application and this works out
really well we have a product page
it will reach out to this service to get
the product details
and then we also have this review
service in version one we have no stars
in version two we have black stars and
in version three we have red stars
and those will actually call out to this
other service to get the rating
now we want to experiment between
version 1 version 2 and version 3
and so we'll see the stars either coming
or going depending on what version of
the application we're running
i've got the application spun up right
here and in this case we're on version
two
let's hit refresh and now we're on
version one
we don't have those stars anymore let's
take a look at
in istio how we would flip between them
here's that
istio virtual service and this virtual
service says
i would like to point all of the traffic
to version one
that's what we've got going right now
and all of our traffic is indeed moving
to version one let's come back to
the thing cube ctl config
use context istio demo
okay so now that we're in istio
uh let's go move the traffic
so it's all on version one right now
let's say we'd like i don't know let's
put eighty
eighty percent of our traffic on version
one and twenty percent of our traffic on
version two
cube ctl apply
dash f virtual service
reviews
80 20. okay
now that we've reconfigured that virtual
service if we come here
the majority of the time we won't get
reviews
but every so often we will get the
and we'll start to see those stars
that's really cool
we did that live traffic shaping okay so
we validated that version 2 works let's
flip completely over to version 2.
here in this one it's only going to
version 2.
cubectl apply reviews v2
and now we will only get version 2.
that's perfect well now we want to do
some testing
um for those people who dig into
the canary channel the beta channel
we want to be able to give them version
three
but for those people who don't we'll
give them version two
so i think that actually might be
backwards
so we're unauthenticated and we're
getting version two
let's sign in and we'll sign in with
username jason
now we're signed in as jason and now
we will get oh i expected that to be
version three
oh we haven't applied it yet let's apply
it
cube ctl apply dash f
virtual service reviews
jason okay now we've got it
so now that we're jason we see version
two
if we log out now we'll see version
three
that's really cool we are able to grab a
header and
route traffic to different places based
on that header
okay so maybe let's do an experiment
let's split half the traffic between
version two
and half the traffic between version
three
cube ctl apply reviews v2
v3 okay
half the time we've got version two half
the time we have version three
and now we're able to test these two
which one helps our users be most
effective
i think version two is working pretty or
version three is working pretty well
so let's flip everything to version
three
cube ctl apply v3
there we go now everything is moved to
version 3 and we will always get version
3.
we saw how easy it was to configure
istio
to be able to route traffic in
interesting ways we saw how
fast it was to get link or d spun up
console and open service mesh are also
great service meshes and being able to
do interesting things
so let's take a tour through what we saw
with service meshes we are able to
monitor
log and mon do monitoring
logging and service health observe
control
secure taking a step up
we can do a tell intelligent routing
where we can start to route traffic
based on
maybe a b tests or maybe circuit
breakers or maybe beta channels
taking a step up again we can now take a
look at the network topology the logging
the
details around our system in what's
actually happening not just what we
assume is happening
based on the way the developer has
explained it to us
if a service is misbehaving we can route
traffic around it that's perfect
zach butcher wrote the book on istio and
he says
if it doesn't have a control plane it
ain't a service mesh
i completely agree and to that end
there is an implementation cost with the
service mesh
we have a regular kubernetes cluster
here on the left and we're adding to it
all the pieces of the service mesh on
the right
in a kubernetes cluster we have the cube
proxy
we have etcd we have the controller
manager
with the service mesh we have the
service meshes control plane
the uh the piece that does
spinning up certificates the piece that
validates the
routing rules
with a server with a kubernetes cluster
we have the pods
the containers that are running our
particular workload
with the service mesh we have all those
sidecar proxy containers
in truth we'll probably end up with
about
double the number of containers by
choosing to include a service mesh
now maybe your workload that spins up a
java application or is
doing intensive gpu calculations
is bigger than the calculations involved
in creating self-sign
or creating trusted certificates or
connecting two different services but
we may expect maybe one and a half to
two times
the workload running in our cluster as
we implement a service mesh
now that can require us to create a
bigger
more expensive cluster to run a service
mesh now that's okay
but understand that there are costs
involved in building a service mesh we
don't just get this for free
if those costs are worth it for the
benefits that you need then a service
mesh can be ideal
but don't just pull it out just because
it's available
service mesh is not the check box
towards the benefits of service mesh if
i need that to observe
control and secure my cluster a service
mesh is perfect
if i want to do that traffic shaping
if i need to validate access policies or
if i need
security between my microservices then
a service mesh is perfect
some great rules of thumb here use a
service mesh if you're running
trusted workloads like pki or pci
a service mesh if you're running
untrusted workloads together with your
expected workloads you don't want the
untrusted workloads to be able to get
into your normal work
and you don't want your normal work to
spill into the trusted the
extremely sensitive information and so
you can create a service mesh boundary
between those
if you're running multi-tenant workloads
now generally we lean
on kupernete's namespaces for this but
kubernetes namespaces are an
organizational boundary not a security
boundary
and so by creating namespaces we're not
securing the tenants between themselves
a service mesh can enforce that boundary
in namespaces if we need security in
depth
then service mesh can be great or if we
need that advanced routing like a b
a b routing or a beta channel then a
service mesh can be great
if you have these needs then definitely
use a service mesh
if you don't have these needs the
additional cost of a service mesh may be
too burdensome
this was a lot of fun getting to speak
at
activity conf if you have questions i'll
be in the conferences
q a channel in a minute or reach out to
me on twitter at
rob underscore rich or grab these slides
right now at robrich.org
thanks