hello everyone
my name is job officer and welcome to my
talk about
xpc exploitation on mac os
a few words about myself i'm working
right now as a content developer at
offensive security that's the company
behind
kal linux and the oscp or osce
certifications i used to be a red
and blue teamer before that for about
eight years
and recently in the past two years i
started to
macos vulnerability research
i have a wife two kids i love to do
hiking
and also doing yoga
so what i will talk about today is again
xpc exploitation on mac os
first i will introduce
it then talk about uh what is xpc
uh then talk about the xpc ap apis
mac os is offering and then talk about
all the exploit scenarios
we can face uh and
trying to exploit xbc services
uh one of them is the apple assemble
code
and then we will look through the
vulnerable clients
uh incorrect client verification
bid process id reuse attacks and
at the very end i will also talk about
how we can prevent
these attacks and how we can actually
make a
secure xbc service
so just a few words about how this
entire research or topic started
with me at least so last year i read
an excellent article from phil stokes
who is a
marvel researcher at centennial
his article was about spoofing privilege
helpers to gain
root and
in the middle of the article he had a
sentence that
abuses of this trust mechanism between
parent process
and privilege helper tool are possible
and
for some reason this both my attention
and i got really interested in
these privileged hairpers what are these
and i was like yeah please time more
well unfortunately fears article was
about something else but
i started to dig up uh
lots of stuff about xpc and actually
xpc exploitation so that time
last year this was about a year ago
this is what really falls out on the
internet so
there was this article the story behind
cv
2019 13013 which was an excellent
little snitch then was
an excellent presentation from tyler
pohan at offensive corn last year
in february about accelerating xpc
services
uh then of course we had apples even
better authorization
sample code for how to make how to code
privilege hyper tools
um then a few talks
at the upper developer conference about
xbc
but that's mostly about how to develop
these services um
and then and actually there are more
resources but
these were the ones i found that time
and started my journey on exploitation
and then
uh profit like honestly these bugs
are little everywhere like
it's it's all around and
you will find these xpc box on
almost everywhere really like i think
like
80 90 percent of all the third party
tools i audited
were vulnerable uh including like
vmware microsoft uh adobe proxy man
f-secure and just many many more
retailers really box everywhere
and really this is why i wanted to
do this talk these bugs are all over
very few people actually exploit them
and actually even macos research is not
that widespread
there is no clear guidance from apple
how to make a secure xbc service
and even if the fos uh
unfortunately there is no secure public
api from ever
for really making a secure xbc service
uh we see that unfortunately to use to
make it really secure we have to use
private apis but if we use private apis
for example you cannot load any
to the mac app store um
so if that api is changes in the future
you need to support and maintain your
application so that's a problem
uh it's very easy to make an error
during
making uh of the service and
it's also very easy to exploit
so and i think
we are in the golden ages of surfboard x
please xpc exploits i think
it will take a while by this message
gets to
developers since last year there were a
couple of other talks about
exploiting xpc and more and more people
try to spread the word how to make a
secure xpc service
but it will take time so if you want to
do this
go out and you will find plenty of
vulnerable applications
so but what is xpc i keep talking about
xpc
here um it's an inter process
communication
so mac os based ipc is based on mac
messages
at the core layer everything is going
through mac messages
including the kernel itself now xpc is
ipc built on top of mac messages
to make it much more simpler and it was
introduced in 2011
and it has a really simple easy to use
api
um compared to mac if you ever had to
deal with mac
or rivers and germac api it's
really clean and nice and uh and easy
and now what is xpc what it stands for
really no one really knows
uh the best of my knowledge ever never
really
uh to audit so it could be like a
xenomorph pet symmetry or
extended process communication probably
the second is more likely or it could be
cross process communication or yeah
anything you can
come up with
so the core idea behind uh xpc
uh why ever made it uh the the main idea
was to
have an application and divide it into
separate components
and each of these co components are
running as
uh as its own process
which gives you better security and
better reliability
and all the app components talk of or
talk over xbc
in between them so and each of the
components we have the least privileged
it requires so for example safari the
web browser
we have a component which is the
rendering service
and it will not have any network access
because it doesn't need it just need to
transform the html page
into a visible website
and basically what software you can do
the main application can
send over all of the the website content
the renderer will process it and send
and display it
it doesn't need to have network access
uh network access so if you for example
find an exploit in
uh in that service uh
the only you you are contained in inside
the renderer
process space which is really restricted
and if you want to go further you need
to break out of the sandbox
so it's another step or if it's crashing
for any reason
then the application can still run it's
enough to restart the the actual xpc
component
uh so crashing in one of those doesn't
affect the the whole application
and the same for any vulnerability
and the components
itself they don't have to be on
different privilege level
so the original idea was that
same application uh same
user level same privileges
run at the same level but then we have
this concept of
privileged helper tools which was before
xbc was introduced so
let's say you have an application that
some of its component requires root
access to the device like installation
updates
accessing a location where
only root has access or whatever really
or changing
system settings that only root is
allowed to do
you need the the idea is to have a
privilege helper tool that's the name uh
of these that we run as root and your
main application can talk to this
privilege helper tool
now it can happen over x pc or over
anything else like
it can happen over mac messages or
distributed objects or
whatever really you want uh
these days xpc xpc is the most common
uh ipc for everything
really at the top so i think
like ninety percent of the cases if you
have a privilege have a tool
that we use xpc and these tools
by design run as root
and they advertise the actual service
to max service names now
the problem is that by default any known
sandbox application can talk to these
privilege helpers so mac os doesn't
restrict the client
to the same developer id
or the same code signature by default so
anyone can talk to them
now actually apple or mac os does
restrict
if you so if if
you are using uh application components
which is inside the application bundle
but those are not
mac services uh advertised globally on
the system
so by default we can talk to this helper
tools
so and if we can talk to them we can run
privileged actions
and a full privilege escalation is
really depending
on the function offered by the privilege
helper tool
so because everyone can talk to these
tools it's up to the helper to
to actually verify who is connecting to
it
and who is performing the action and
this is where all the box
are so
let's cover quickly the xpc apis
that are out there and the first one
when xpc was introduced was the c api
this is a very short sample code on the
screen
from a client
so initially we create a connection
an xbc connection t
variable then an xpc object d
type variable msg which will be the
message
now the message in xbc is a dictionary
it's always a dictionary
and actually it's an ns dictionary
so we create an empty uh dictionary
and then we add keys and values uh
to it in this case we add strings
like where you and where you do but we
can add other
ones as well like arrays
or integers
strings dictionaries
it's very uh restrictive what we can add
and we cannot just do every type there
are about 10 types of different
[Music]
objects that we can pass
the next one is to look up the service
with xpc connection create mac service
uh we give it the com some helper that's
the name of the mac service
we are looking for and we are trying to
connect to it
this is where the connection is
established so if
the xbc service will not accept
us as a client we will fail here
if this goes through then everything is
good at least
on on the first step then we set a
connection event handler that is
required as per effort and then we
resume the connection
and basically the last step remaining is
sending a message
over xbc so it's really clean
and simple and and
the api is very very similar on the
service side so there is like xpc
dictionary guest string
and uh and so on so it's really easy to
reverse and and see the code
now there is the nsx pc api which is
part of the coco framework
and it
does it we use dc api underneath
uh but it allows more another
layer of abstraction so we can define
a protocol which is an objective c
concept basically it's uh
it's not a class but it's a group of
function that the class will
can implement and the function
uh this will have a definition
what's the return value and what
argument
it expects uh in case of xbc
the methods cannot return anything
but they can return a reply but they
don't have a classic
return value
so we define a protocol on both sides
both the client and the
service side the service will have a
class which will implement the protocol
and that class we serve the xbc
connection on the clear
client side we just define the protocol
then again
we define the service name
then we do an nsx pc connection init
with mock service name
we connect to the service then we set
the remote object interface
and here we create an nsx pc interface
with the protocol definition we have
in this example it's the helper protocol
and then we resume again
and then we set we create a remote
object proxy and
and basically that's it and then we can
call these
uh functions over xbc so we get back
we got back an object
as a return value and we can basically
simply call
the run app method in this case
on the object passing any arguments
we can see we are still restricted to
the same types
uh what xpc can use
but this allows
another layer of abstraction so we can
basically call functions
and it's more flexible than the c api
and it's also very easy and clean
to reverse now what are the common
issues
uh with xpc again all of the issues
are around who can talk to the actual
service
and who cannot so let's start with the
even better authorization which is
apple's
sample code for privileged hyper tools
it's really odd like really really old
and it's not better it's actually the
worse
[Music]
why the xbc service in this sample code
will accept everyone
so by default you can connect to the
server to the privileged service
now then the service itself try to limit
function based on authorization
now when you do authorization on the xpc
service
you need to pass an authorization
reference from the client
but the client at first hand it will
only
set up an empty authorization which
anyone can do
so you pass that empty authorization and
then the previous helper tools will try
to obtain the rights
for the client now
depending how the authorization right is
set up
uh you might be granted uh
authorization or not there are two main
cases
one is the rule class hello which means
yeah granted so it's
it's like it's not there it will be
granted
and then there is another one
authenticators admin
which what will happen the user will get
a prompt
that the application that is trying to
talk to the xbc service
is trying to do system modification now
if you
make a nice econ icon or
name your application
look like an other one no one can tell
that
who is making this uh request like i
think
mac os users are so used to this prompts
that
they will happily authenticate so in my
point of view
this is not really a restriction like
yes some users will stay alert and they
will not
type their password but i think many
will
so i don't really consider this as a as
a security protection here
and yeah these are the problems that
what we just
discussed now the example
uh for this i have is proxyman
and that's a small application
[Music]
monitoring network traffic
it has a privilege helper tool to change
the proxy settings it cannot do anything
else so it's
it didn't have like a full privilege
escalation vulnerability
it just gave you access uh to some
system configuration and they
the developer used for sample code for
this
and the authorization right was set to
hello
so basically you were just granted
access uh
now really kudos to the dev the the
developer because when i reported it
uh he fixed it in a few days and i think
that was between like
christmas and new year's eve or that
time period so
it was really quick responsive and
really fix it
really quickly so let's see a demo
of this
so here i have the application installed
uh
this is my network connection
and the proxies ah this is set so let's
go back and
remove the proxy configuration
let's flight let's just see that it was
removed yeah it's not set
and let's lock it so if i go back now i
cannot
change the proxy
now i can just run my exploit
and let's see it's not there is some
race condition
in this exploit so let me run it
a few times
but yeah now it's set so we have proxy
enabled
for localhost 333
and again just to show we did run it as
a regular user and not
as root
so this was proximate again using for
sample code and there are many
applications
using apple's simple code and again
i think this is a problem originating
from upper side because they are
clearly providing a really bad example
and if i were a developer i would
go and trust what is provided on apple's
website
which is actually not good
so moving on
vulnerable client so let's say
the xpc service properly validates the
client
uh which is many times not the case as
vbsc but let's say it does it
if our client is vulnerable then it
doesn't
to code injection uh then it's worthless
so basically when
can we do code injection on a on a
client
or on an application so there is no hard
and run time set
there is no library validation set if
these
two are not set you can just inject any
dialep
to the application and drawn inside the
context of the application
and if the xpc service is restricting
access to
its own client as we could inject code
it's not important but if it's time with
hardened runtime
which actually these days is a
requirement because
notarization service requires hardened
runtime
and if you don't authorize an
application these days
then gatekeeper will not like you
but if you have hardened runtime but
have the disabled library validation or
have the get task allowed exception
entitlement
entitlements this means that
these basically lift up some of the
restrictions and you can again inject
code
into the application either through a
die lib or
through task force so
when we set up an xpc service
we need to ensure that our client
who we are expecting to work with
is harder than again code injections
again if it's not done then the client
verification is completely pointless
and again anyone can talk to the service
now probably one of the
other most common issues is the
incorrect client verifications
uh this is that's the step
which even if you try to get it right
it's very easy to miss
some small pieces so
let's say the xbc service properly
verifies the signature of the connecting
client but it doesn't verify if the
client
is secure or hardened against injections
and that's a problem
why
we see why so what should be done to
make it properly so when
client verification happens uh the
service should verify
if uh the client is signed with a valid
code signing set
which in which is an apple sign
developer certification
if it matches the expected team id
because
uh if if the team id is not verified i
can just use any random application to
again talk to the uh to the xbc service
and then either three or four so either
verify
that the client is protected against
injection
by checking the bundle id and
checking the minimum version of the
client
which the developer knows that is not
vulnerable for
injection or just take the entire code
signing blob of the client and check
all the code signing flex and all the
entitlements that it's properly hardened
if we do all of this then it's
almost good but
so why is it a problem if we miss
to verify if the client is hardened
if we know that our client is hardened
because if we
take an order client typically from
the mojave times which wasn't
a long time ago like a year ago
that time hardened run time really
wasn't the thing
uh it falls in to use the mojave so we
can easily find an older version of the
client
uh which is vulnerable for injection so
we can take the old client
inject into the old client which will
satisfy the code signing requirements
and again we can talk to the helper tool
so an example for this is microsoft auto
update
uh they had a helper tool to perform
some of the update activities
and they really verified everything
properly they
checked if it's an apple signed
certificate they verify the team id the
bundle id
except they didn't verify the client
version
which basically meant that i could find
an earlier version
of microsoft auto update
inject my code into that and
make a copy with the application so
this service the xpc service offered
a function called create clone from app
which basically allowed me to copy a
file from one place
to another with root privileges so what
i did
i basically took a plist file
and moved it moved it to the launch
demons
directory where if i reboot
the mac that plist or the code
inside the p list will be executed as
root so
this is like a full privilege escalation
again how it looks
so again we have microsoft auto update
installed and i have
here an old version of the client
application as well downloaded so if i
check the
code signing
properties of this app we can see that
it's not
hardened so i can just
freely inject to this application
so i will inject a
dye lip through the the viadi insert
libraries
environment variables and this daily is
basically
we do what i said before if we copy
a p list into the language demons
directory but let me show you what's in
there right now so we can see that
uh we have the proxima vmware and
microsoft
helpers in launch demons and if
i execute the
the app the injected code
auto update pops up yeah i don't want
auto update
and if i check now what's in there
we can see that i moved a p list right
there
and if i print this out
so basically it will execute this
command upon reboot
let's move on and
the last typical issue
with client verification is the use of
process id for verifying the client
so if we use process id that's bad
uh why there are two problems
the the range is really small for
process ids so it can be easily reused
and the other one is that
you can spawn a new process inheriting
and the process id of the parent
the solution is is to use audi tokens
for verifying the client
but unfortunately that's private api so
you either do
uh an application with public apis
or potentially running to
box or issues
with a later mac os updates where
april decided decides to change the
private apis for
audit token
audit token is secure to identify the
client
and it's not vulnerable to reuse attacks
well since
2017 when young beer found out that it's
not better than
a process id you can read up the
the details on google's websites it's
really nice
again private api it's a problem
now how the generic exploitation looks
like
uh in this case we send so
v2 make a client any client
and we start with sending a message to
the xbc service
then we spawn a new process
with these flags
and we start the real client
with the spawning which we get the
process id of the parent
so uh when the xbc service gets the
message
and check the signature of the spawn
process
that time the real client will run
and the signature will be just fine
based on the process id and
although it's a race condition because
you need to spawn a new
process faster than the xpc service to
process
the xpc message
but it can be easily been
mostly because the xbc services are
not running by default so when you send
a message
mac os will start it up and then keep it
live for a
time period but when we first talk to it
it needs to set it up and
that takes slightly longer time than
spawning a new process so again
it's a it's an easy to win uh race
condition
an example for this uh vmware fusion
had a p3 with vulnerability so you can't
go to helper tool
tools because all of them were affected
uh
with this kind of attack and you could
do privilege extra execution
or someone actually found the full blown
privilege escalation
uh using this vulnerability
but how to do it securely
[Music]
hopefully i covered all the details uh
of this
during the talk but let's try to
summarize it so first the client
it has to be signed by with hardened
runtime
or library validation
and it
mustn't have any of these entitlements
the get task allow and disable library
validation
if any of these two present it's game
over
and it also shouldn't have any script
files
um because
when we start an application on mac os
the code signature of script files
cannot be verified
upon every execution so you can easily
put your own code into these street
files so basically all electrons
electron apps are
bad from this point of view
and the xpc service side
so when we hit the should accept new
connection
on the xbc service which is basically
deciding if
the service accepts or not the
connection it should first verify
if if it's a valid certificate from
apple
if it's signed by your team id then
potentially verify the bundle id you
expect and either
verify the software version beat the
bundle id
or verify that the client is hardened
against injection attacks so it has the
hard end run time
or the library validation flag set and
doesn't have those entitlements
and to do all of this it has to use
audit token
so if all of these are met on both the
client
and on the service side then it's secure
and it should be fine now if any of
these are
missed it's vulnerable now
and this is why we have many many many
vulnerable
xpc services out there because it's
really easy to miss
one of these steps
conclusion uh there are still a lot of
bugs out there there are not many people
uh exploiting xbc services so
if you want to find all days
potentially participate in bug bounties
yeah go out
spread the word educate app developers
it's it's really everywhere
unfortunately
and questions will be answered later on
on the
chat and a few more resources if you are
interested uh in
then uh there were two talks
at objective by the c uh this year about
xbc then as mentioned tyler pohan
had an xbc exploitation last year and
then jan beer
had an ipc exploitation talk uh
back in 2015 and there are some numerous
blog posts
these days both from reggie or myself
on the web so you can go and
read them there are plenty of pocs and
exploit details out there
and if you know application mac app
developers then
uh point them to these slides and
educate them thank you for listening
you