welcome still con 16 2016 third year
first year 150 people second year 300
this year with max out at 450 go be more
about that in closing this opening is
just quick get through things so
obligatory fire there's no plans for
fire drills today but if the alarms do
go off just make way out kids if you in
the kids track stay with whoever your
instructor is at time they will take you
out don't use the lips there's really
like the badges I heard a couple of the
badges had a little accidents on the way
in so if you've got something special in
your bag sorry if you haven't got worry
about it I'm going to be careful don't
promise things in talks and then have to
deliver sourcing 450 with it is a hard
job next year we have got it planned
something completely different but again
it'll be something cool and it's in the
works going to say the obligatory thank
you to our sponsors some of them have
got boobs out there so I'm a living just
online please go talk to them it's them
that make the day happen without them we
couldn't do this as a lot of recruitment
going on and your next year to
recruiting under corporate recruiting
get your CDs to them raytheon are you
recruiting as well yes r if you're
recruiting and pence s recruiting
everybody's recruiting I have quick mage
to blackberry our main sponsor next to
Dan TSL put up all the money for the
party tonight for the food for baking
booties for lunch the other came all the
ice cream you're going to be getting
your big thanks to them and reef you in
sponsoring the bad geez the lanyards the
Arduino small that kind of stuff and
huge thanks to Matt Bob if you've seen
your little combination locks they put a
lot of effort into those we will be
putting the video online soon about how
to build the things so don't worry if
you sort of can't quite work
out there will be a tutorial going up on
the website and for those who don't
realize the Bertie Bassett suites that
are in the bag there may just up the
road at Hillsborough which is why we've
stuck with those plums bday talks down
to tell when I finished lunch but
everybody is once or 20 kids as I finish
Sam if he's in here no Sam will take you
off to the kids track which is just next
door every else this is track one track
to up to the top of the stairs through
where the lifts are double back on
yourself and it's in PGH theater but we
somebody up there to guide you if you
need it a closing tour last talks at
five o'clock five o'clock we're going to
open sales for any space stuff it was in
the bags say sales we're going to put a
book it out took money for charity but
you've got a lot of value in these bags
so if you want to take on home for your
friends family whatever just took a few
quid in the book it and you can take a
spare bike and the party tonight starts
back half six runs fruits or two I go
through this quick because we've got
extra bits to do we're going to have a
book and hardware store it's going to be
so around registration desk we could be
loads of stuff on it still fighting
during day again take what you want off
meet the donations in the charity
buckets that would be on registration
desk and always going to be quite a lot
of cool stuff added there today and
we're also doing a raffle Virg that's
going to Moreland hospital books lots of
other prizes that will announce closing
we have actually just had to roll off to
get raffle tickets cuz we realize
meetings have them so they'll be on sale
as soon as we've got the raffle tickets
back here again the registration desk
this will be a bit floating gnomes
harassing you for money for it so this
is the fun bit to the opening bet you
wish you hadn't said that so this all
started I can see a cringing yes Julie
come on down god yes
so Carrie what exactly started this but
Jess came up with this this comment I
was really hoping you were wearing a
low-cut top today but I'm sure you can
find some way it does I'm she buy some
way to be yet wearing that to you in the
day next Emma are you in here where is
she Emma come on down it's Emma's
birthday today she's not real hacker
rather than going out to eat something
fun on her birthday she wanted to do
she's like boyfriend to drag her down
here today as she made this comment so
come on over you wanted hello kitty I
figured what goes better with Hello
Kitty Lambrini so strawberry and a kind
of sash thing that you wanted as well
there is a badge but I've lost it sorry
there you go happy birthday
next Chanin undie and an come on down is
Andy in here so these three are these
two as it seems to be like cardboard
boxes there's one there's two we've got
some arts and crafts stuff you get
glitter you don't yes we have some nice
safe scissors because I don't know
whether they could be trusted with them
and we have some for its thick by the
end of the day I want you to make
something bring it back closing there it
will be judged there will be very
special judge coming in for it so make
your best with it do whatever you want
bring in whoever you want make it a team
go for it so yours he's got all the
kitchen there to share them and he
finally just turn up there is another
box for him right and okay that's that's
the end of that little bit of it we're
going to be doing laser quest tomorrow
if you've been last couple years Sunday
morning is laser quest starting at
eleven o'clock at some ways are in town
it's about ten minute walk from here
about 28 people per game there's going
to be a sign-up sheet on the
registration desk just put your name on
it so it's more morning finishing a boat
twelve o'clock 1230 they'll nip round
the corner to Pizza Hut so I'll pay the
most West's paid from peets huts on you
but it's usually really good fun really
rarely getting to shoot people approach
is more in here the pro tip for mo
bright white shirts in a UV laser quest
not a good idea and lastly address it'll
be on legislation form things as well
party tonight next to sponsoring that as
I said doors open about six-thirty food
for me like seven you will need your
dogs to get in so turn up with the dogs
kids are allowed the more than wealth
Kim obviously keep control of them
please parents drunk includes one and
street in Sheffield is yeah it happens
but ideally not with us and there is
also going to be if I don't the slide
yet quit is forget the Pope or karaoke
but a quiz and scavenger hunts thanks to
jess and FC there will be kicking off
scavenger hunt in the closing ceremony
so they'll tell you what to go and that
bind please keep it legal this year not
good name drop but just know acquiring
things that you're not supposed to I'm
no cruelty to animals party that's where
it's going to be it's at the hubs which
is a couple minutes walk just down the
road so it's literally out of the end or
turn left to right look for the big
funnel-shaped building if you get stuck
just follow the trail of hackers heading
over there um yeah that's the sort of
lunch already mentioned and popping that
have fun if you get stuck with anything
crew or only two never t-shirts with the
steel condom first me Mike and Neil
we've got gaffer on the back if you feel
you need to go up to it just find one of
those Cooper and cowl are doing all the
AV do you still want to do a quick talk
through it all at lunchtime if there's
interest let's say half one find Tom and
Cooper is there he's put a lot of effort
in setting this kit up there is amazing
amount of stuffy and wires and software
and all sorts if you're interested in AV
go see him about half one will give you
a talk through what it is I think that's
about it and we've any questions nope
right this have fun I'm going to clear
up now and let track one speaker gets
dirty with your Chris track 2 is set up
to the top of stairs double buckle
yourself through the left and its kind
of their level is pink go for it
you