[Music]
startup in New York going to Tok of today
today we are going toque about original
concept
block and arcticle into chet
intelligence inz intro natural language
understanding and association rule
minings
of potential to help trade hunters
[Music]
sous Basile
[  Music]
[Music]
additionaliers when you are
we camside Insee
[Music]
intelligence wenzo attacker entering to
the
network switch try met Tryo lot of
things
resoul the fight again the life attacker
and the person responsible
isat incidents
abductive
process meaning that you have to take
base  subset of all the action
understand everything that drive
attack Daz and maybe
[Music] [
Music] [Music] [Music
] [
Music]
sound Foster ball yes madeleast
of02
content of the hortical
html
inch of the website
specific by surf en 10 hlml because
where once to of any Falls positive on we
don't want to Getz de foot et d'or ENI
Hauser data that will be only noise in
Howard
specific by surf hitch of the on 6
dance
it in the
[Music]
basic quality
lacks  de malware actors Darry the
lots of commonwords to define
carbon en lazy en silent aluminum
it's we don't want any Falls positive
so we want it to identify dos world to
taddem has ambiguous
innawa methodology les top arts we just
exclude d'osworld from the  skate machine
either gently we used by Gutenberg
project to identify
experience expertise
DNA synonym
[Music] [
Music]
positive
sakan lead of matching skate benefits
[Music]
availability [
Music]
[Music]
looks like 10 out of 10 titled
empty for givenline
now we want to beauty
technique Ford
given attacker groups
we Willi use
analgorithm
association rule algorithm satisfa old a
priori un avis
equation en mathematical things to the
grossistor SO basiclip
[Music] [Music] [Music] [Music
] [
Music]
[Music]
the problem
soforex bulbs that in hitch trans
actions
[Music]
statistico like counter things
ok in friends you drink wine and you eat
Pride OK [
Music] [
Music]
[Music]
engineer what we are not a priori but
very long because  you have to mind
over all the datase iteratively but as
you see yvani whip of blog article
upstream of data
intelligence is not thatma full process
6 minutes
combos the most
the most let's C over rated
Modus operandy is to use command line
interface to do network connection
discovery and wevelot of rule Liza
François
[Music]
[Music] [
Music] [Music] [Music
] [Music
]
[Music]
custom cryptography protocol
data explanations
if all evil web at 10 of persistent is
main true from Logan street  dance
or Excel
de saken one is the resistry runky and
the modify
[Music]
Windows 10
going to load de second stage of de sito
ifyou
if you wonder how to use
binary for Windows Inno dot or to love
your
pelota to YouTube
[Music]
binary in Windows from prating system
iNote or district of Norman execution
malicious activity
Windows management insumation with
software packing looks like to me like
pelota delivery
administrative door in Windows and
packing of cost or bypass antivirus
idiot
from edge discovery process
Discovery  looks like to me when you
perform your primo intrusion always
going to look into the
opating system i also live install
idiot [
music] [
music]
to hack website that is come
only visit target and dance
pelo in
Brother exploitation iNote or to hack
you tanguet we are the input capture and
the remote access tools
of Data outside
[Music] [Music
] [
Music]
[Music]
Discovery true remote  management access
once again of Redemption ok of running
true of modules load on 10 is the very
comment technical
running process
of content of the running process with
your hand pilots
like aurori ingruel finally engineering
kind of
attackhion
Star Wars stars just or open smell
[Music  ]
similarity analysis between association
rule and the
findings that we are first contribution
here
[Music]
anyone giving training to give evidence of
to supports argument that you can do let
the attribution with Modus
[Music]
collection process and the Willy nowing
what  we want it to do and to church and
out to do it we have good reesult and
final
in the Academy little Watchers more and
more publication [
Music]
yes 12 thinks that the mind is you here
is what we call Ding linguistic
diachrone
hills of text  and we have look at it
from one point in time the pointing time
of strafing attack six points to you
problem because we are notable to see
shift or gaps in the
attacking a modus operrandy there Worlds
that sweet exists now that Didden taxi
[Music]
[  Music]
[Applause]
[Music]
[Music] [
Music]
statistics that's
your can do at fredation
[Music] [
Music]
technique
ndiay is to look into a Walter
you have itypersens of the time when
this technique is present you have this
technique  care
exploratory search and investigation the
can do
Olso confirmatory
Queen tout tout look for the most
ofvious association so for us it's more
incident
purpose Razer than attribution anyway
with the capacity tout benchmark and see
the quality of the result
[Music]
[Applause]