well my name is David or David and I
work at a vast gen as Margaret analyst
and I'm currently focusing in iot and
Lino streets
let's talk about assist local rootkit
version 2 and about that it hides
seasonal K is divided in two components
the kernel rootkit and the user mode
board the corner rootkit has the
following features it hides the the
kernel module and updates a flag
accordingly with true or false depending
if it is hidden or not but in this case
it's hiding and it has directories
processes about process but also
malicious processes
it has it has the network traffic and it
also implements a magic packets that are
relatively complex those magic packets
uses different keys and different
encryption algorithms per sample and it
can execute about in different modes and
it also implements its all its own
payload by executing arbitrary comments
in user mode space from kernel space and
on the other hand the user mode both
that is hidden by the rootkit implements
a different protocols or different
Services per sample allowing the
attacker to connect to it and it can run
in different modes as we already
mentioned it it can run in normal mode I
mean it simply handles a comment from
the attacker
it can run in callback mode I mean it
gets subscribed with a callback to the
socket and in case the socket changes is
a state it gets the the command and
executes the command in a loop so so in
callback mode it's executed multiple
commands and it also allows to be
executed in proxy mode I mean it it can
send the a the bot can send also magic
packets to to other computers acting as
a process between the attacker and the
other computer and the magic package
fakes a normal traffic or legitimate
traffic like Mozilla Firefox traffic and
Apache 2 traffic and the user mode of of
course implements a two payloads one is
to spawn a reversal for the attacker and
the other kill kill its own execution
let's talk about the kernel rootkit
they're going to look at we found it in
in virus total so uh if we take a look
at the model info section we can see
that it was compiled in a Redcat 7.6
environment and if we take a look at the
magic of the of the of the version of
the governor we can see that it can be
also loaded in a Centos 7.9 distro that
has a very little different kernel so it
is possible to load it in this
distribution with the advantage that
this is a free distribution
are the following it allows to hide
Itself by removing itself from the list
of models in the in the system
and it has the user mode bot that is not
continuously running it is Magic packet
sense but yeah by the attacker
so a the user mode bought a hooks the
reader read the the function I I mean it
it replaces the pointer in the in the
virtual file system for uh the Red Deer
operation such that if if you take a
look at the at the either a disassembly
you can see the string the substring
that in case it matches with the
directory the directory is hiding there
is also um it also hides the TCP for
um events from the from the host uh in
case in case the the sequential file for
tcp4 events matches the the port of the
of the bot those uh those lines are
filtered and finally it also implements
a hook in the product filter function
such that if the if it if it
if the if in the proc directory of Linux
appears a file with the with the
processes in the in the list of bits bit
IDs or or some malicious processes those
are also High then
the way that uh Cislo K hooks the the
functions are using this dependency and
x86 and X 8664 dependency this is
important because this rookie will not
work in other architectures because of
this dependency
and you you can see that it performs in
line hooking with this disassembly
dependency it disassembles the first
instruction of the binary in case the
first instruction indicates that the
function is not a built-in function I
mean it is already hooked it escapes the
the function and don'ts performs hook on
it but otherwise it copies the original
byte
and then places the hooks based in a HKS
structure
which contains entries with pairs of the
original function plus the hook
and of course it implements magic
packets
the magic package Works in this way the
attacker sends a magic packet to the
computer and in the computer since
locate places three
um three hooks three Net filter hooks
that are anything and if out at an nfm
Pro
anything is the purpose of any of the
anything Hook is to get the the port of
the boat in in order to hide it
the the purpose of the NFL Hook is for
the outgoing traffic for a placing the
values that are able to to load the
attacker with other computers using the
proxy mode this is for proxy mode and
anything Pro is the is the net filter
hook that parses the bucket and in case
the packet fits the requirements execute
the commands in the in the system
so in the in the bottom of the screen
you can see the um at this at this
assembly in either that that shows you
how uh it uh how this is located
registers the hooks for anything nfm Pro
and NFL and on the top of it you can see
a table that indicates all the structure
of those hooks
um
if you take a look at the at the column
priority you can see that nfm Pro
contains is has the int Max priority I
mean it will be executed at last
but on the other hand any Fout and
anything has a the has
mean priority meaning that it will be
those will be executed at first
the hook number indicates something that
is evident on the on the name of the
hooks that is that anything Pro and
anything applies to incoming traffic and
NF out applies to outgoing traffic and I
think that is important for us is that
those hooks applies to a IP version 4
according to the PF number which is two
well if we take a look at the
disassembly of the nfm pro a hook on a
signal filter hook we can see that it
passes the magic packets and in case the
magic packet fits some requirements will
execute the statistic function that you
can see at the right margin of the
screen
and
[Music]
um
what this function does is to it
receives in in the AC register of the
processor the command ID to of the of
the command to be executed in the system
and and it executes the this command in
in user mode space if you take a look at
the table we you can see that there are
three commands that executes the bot
command 0 command 1 and command two
and finally there is an additional
command that is the command 99 it what
it does is to execute arbitrary commands
in user mode space so it can start the
bot but also has its own payload
executing commands in user mode space
command 0 executes the the vote in
callback mode uh command one executes
the board in normal mode I mean without
parameters and command two executes the
bot in
proxy mode
of course a one command one and two
updates some internal variables comma 0
is not fully implemented and it contains
bugs so the common common one and common
two updates for instance the login
information this uh this uh these values
that appear in in the login info are for
a login the attacker when the attacker
starts about some values are stored in
in this structure and will use a later
for a allowing or denying other magic
packets I mean those are for for logging
the attacker with the rootkit and there
is also a field for the port for the
poor boat or the variable for the port
vote
that is filled by the nfm pro net filter
hook and it allows the rootkit for to
hide the the level the port of the boat
there is also a passing State variable I
mean it checks a if the if the magic
packets are are going well or or those
don't fit their requirements and finally
there is a state that indicates is the
what if the bot is running is is not
running if it is zero if it is running
in normal mode if it is one and if it is
loaded in proxy mode in case the value
is two
according to the to the commands that
allows to start the vote we were able to
find the the boat in in virus total also
and if we take a look at the at the vote
obviously it implements the same in the
same
um comments as we already saw starting
about without parameters with callback
mode or proxy mode but it allows also to
add a port a com a port argument that
that allows to fix the boat to abort to
at least an import instead of running it
in a random port
and they both also implements the
Payless Spanish reversion and also
killing the boat you can see the the
variable PID initialized to minus one
which is
um
which allows to kill later the the what
well let's see let's see how the the
magic packets how the proxy mode works
the attacker sends the the magic packet
to the infected computer and since in
this case it the attacker is using the
step one
it starts the proxy in the proxy mode
Step One is how it appears in the code
and how it appears also uh encrypted and
also encoded in the in the magic packet
and of course the attacker gets login
with the rootkit
then the attacker can send a comment to
the bot which is already started in
proxy mode and this is called a step two
so they both sends a magic packet to the
to the computer that is indicated in the
command and the command gets executed in
the remote computer and attack it in the
attacker gets logged in in both
computers
there is also other possibility which
consists in that the attacker sends um
sends a magic packet to the to the proxy
computer
and this is called as the step three so
the attacker can update the login the
login information using step three but
if there is other computer in proxy mode
it is possible for the attacker to send
a comment and that the boat sends also
step 3 for updating the login
information in other computer
let's take a look on how to analyze
magic packets or or how I analyze it
because there are more possible
solutions so uh if we take a look at the
at the at the rectangle we have there a
python code that uh that that contains
the the IP here and the TCP header of
the of the packet so if you take a look
at the TCP here at the first byte it is
45 and it means 40 because this is IP
version 4. as you already saw in the
table of the net filter hooks that have
the PF number set to two that indicates
that it is a hooks for IP version 4. and
you can see also the the the
the the the five number that indicates
the size of the IP header in the words
and on the top of the of the screen you
can see a disassembly neither
and you can you can attach that are
12 is is pointing to the IP either plus
nine offset is pointing to the protocol
and you can see the comparison against
six and if you take the look at the for
instance the source code of Linux you
can see that 6 means TCP protocol so we
can understand the the template for our
our magic packet to TCP
it is recommended it is recommended to
to to patch the boat for for not hiding
itself so what I do for instance is to
put a return return instruction uh after
the call that that the
um that the compiler does for profiling
so in in the in the height model such
that it does nothing
and well this way we can list the the
the modules because this model is not
hiding anymore and we can see that in
this case it's not syslok K they change
the name to disk SC
and then we can also print the Base
address of the of the module
So based on that on the Base address we
we can place uh breakpoints on it and
also we can trace symbols I'm doing K
probes for this a facility of Linux for
for tracing
and in this in this part you can see an
implementation of uh of uh K probe that
I was using that simply gets the their
the registers that are available when
when the breakpoint hits and it prints
the the value for the protocol and
comparison to six to check that it fits
the requirements and with the research
received a byte of the TCP alert us to
see that it fits the requirements and so
on
so let's take a look on how to analyze
the common 99 I mean the the the magic
packet that allows to execute arbitrary
commands in user mode space
we start with the 45 because of the IP
version 4 plus the five day words in
length of the IP here there we add the
the value for the protocol in which in
this case is TCP which is
and and then we start with the TCP with
the comparisons in the TCP here that you
can see that our 13 is pointing to the
TCP theater plus d in offset starting
account by zero we can see that it
points to the flags which are compared
by the constant two
so we put a two in our template
and then you can see that it gets the
higher level of of with of a byte that
is five but what it does is the
following r13 is pointing to the TCP
here plus C it points to the to the byte
at the C offset but in with the sh ER
are
[Music]
um
assembly instruction it if it shifts 4
bit this byte to the right such that it
gets five
since 5 multiplied by 4 is 20 this is
exactly the size of the TCP here that
you can see this in the layer or layer
instruction
in Assembly Language which is a moving
the address the address of the data of
the packet to the RDI register of the
processor
well we are done with the IP header and
the DCP header if it's the requirement
so now let's focus in the data
we can see the value one one two two
three three four four and since we will
send it to the network we need to place
it in reverse order
and you can see that the next that the
next instruction is a call to a function
that I rename to Magic check flip last
bit and what it does is to take take the
wall data and flip
it the last bit for each byte
and then compare this this magic value
that needs too much
you can see here the comparison that
that checks the length of the data
so it needs to be at least 292 I will
use the value 293 and subtract the
length of the magic value to be presses
and and put 293 bytes of data
you can see also the RBI RBX register of
the processor pointing to the data plus
the offset four it escapes the magic
value so it is pointing to to a data
which is expected to be an unterminated
key you can see that I add this key with
the with the null value and also adjust
the padding for this
and finally you can see the arbitrary
command we reached the basic block that
that we was looking for
RBX is pointing to the data plus 24
um
bytes in in hexadecimal we need to place
there the arbitrary command and then
adjust the padding
this is how a k probes looks like when
when when we execute this this python
code we have in the left screen in the
left part of the screen you have the
shell that is executing the sending a
magic packet and on the other hand you
can see a terminal that is printing the
the the output of of our Tracer using K
probes and you can see that it executes
our arbitrary command
well I will not go with all the details
and all the comparisons with all the
magic packets but I will tell you all
the relevant information for the rest of
the magic packets command 1 executes the
bot without parameters I mean in normal
mode and uh got it what it does is to
check
um the the valid ER that the the packet
contains the the
one identity identification of of the
lead of of the list of valid IDs and one
value of of a valid six that that are
the sequence number for the DCP here
there
well what when when the what sends it in
in proxy mode it it chooses one value at
random and well there is an additional
version of command one that allows to
kill previous instances before executing
the vote and what it does is to use the
magic value zero zero zero zero zero
zero two c
this means killing before executing
and the the there is also the
possibility of executing the bottom
proxy mode what what what we need to do
for the Imagine value for the for the
magic packet is to place the string step
one encrypted with as AES encounter mode
using the appropriate key plus and
prepending the the length to it of the
of these encrypted data using numeric
characters and finally all of this data
encoded in basis using basis default
encoding
foreign
this is not the only the only place
where encryption is is used you can see
that it uses AES encryption and this is
the implementation this GitHub
repository
you can see that it uses an one xor key
that is an alternative solution to the
magic value that we was using one one
two two three three four four and there
are also more keys that are not being
used by this sample with other functions
that are not being used by this sample
but those can be used in other samples
in other samples and you can see that it
also contains code with our
rc4
encryption with with the keys and the
IBS and all the parameters with other
functions that are also not used in the
sample but maybe in other samples those
are used
and there is also a variant on command
id2 that again allows to run the proxy
mode but killing previous instances and
it again consists into sending a magic
value zero zero zero zero zero zero to C
well and of course it is possible to
update the login information when the
attacker gets logged in in with the with
the rootkit it is also possible to
update those values using these these
other comment that is step three and it
is encrypted with AES in Contour mode
prepending the length and finally
encoding it with base64 and you can see
that it must be it checks that the state
is two I mean running in proxy mode and
this is just after running the proxy
mode because of the variable three that
can that indicates that that the the
proxy mode was executed successfully
you can see that the Callback mode is
not enabled in the rootkit because it
doesn't work you can see that our cross
references to the statistic function but
only with the other common IDs
hard-coded as a constant in the SC
register of the processor
if you run the if you run the the if if
you run the Callback mode in in the bot
manually it it consumes a lot of
resources and it is not working but the
logic can be understood
we can see that it reduces the the code
from another NG for the for the hooks it
hooks the virtual file system and in
this way it is able to hide the
direction the directory with the
malicious stuff
and we can see that it performs inline
hooking using the you you this 86
disassembly dependency
with the
proc filter for hiding processes that
matches a list of piece but also the the
those strings the the bus process sh
process and also the about processes
which has this name as M1 and so on
it also hides the malicious traffic of
the boat and what it does is to store
the the part of the boat in an internal
variable and then filter the events for
the sequence file the the that stores
the events for IP version 4.
well let's let's take a look at the at
the boat itself
sorry
it the bot exposes different services or
protocols to the attacker for connecting
to it
for instance an example is is the SMTP
fake protocol and you can see that it is
that it is hard-coded the the value for
so depending on on which values are
coded in the in the sample it will
expose one service or another
again the the comparison against F4 with
the fake SMTP server and if we take a
look at the code of the SMTP server we
cannotize a typo on it that allows us to
go to the to the source code on Internet
that is for a 2017.
uh well this is the code that they they
use for implementing the SMTP server
we can see that depending on the on the
protocol they have a
function that handles both TTP TCP or
SSL and depending on the protocol that
is being implemented
so we transported from the developer's
perspective
and in case it uses SSL it will rely in
this certificate that way they was using
also in seasonal K version one which is
interesting for hunting new samples
and the magic packages that the both
sense are not evident I mean those fakes
Apache to
a legitimate Apache to a service and
Mozilla Firefox application
you can see in the right margin of this
table how it
structures the the code of the of this
fake applications
and of course the steps and also other
values that that are that can be
encrypted and then and then encoded are
performed in this function in the in the
in the bot
and those values the step the step two
and the step three goes in the cookie ID
this is the reason why they use base64
they want to make it
more realistic
and you can see the dependencies that
they use for uh for um performing the
the con the connections what they rely
they realize in this
dependency which is part of a course
from here from France the cool Cruiser
at communication
and it is a network toolkit
we can see also a more specific
dependency which allows to implement a
magic packets the the craft the magic
packets in user mode space this they
used this this called as an iPad for
setting the IP address sorry the the IP
the IP here the values and the TCP here
their values
and well that's all as conclusion we can
see that linear streets are getting more
and more complex that a net filter can
be abused in different ways for instance
it can implement multi-pockets but it
can also escape the firewall in case in
case because iptable relies in in net
filter
and the combination of traditional root
kit techniques that we can see in in
GitHub and so on and fake services and
Magic packets makers of cislope K
version 2 and an interesting and
Powerful rootkit that can Inspire others
to to implement botnets
that's all from my site
[Applause]
what questions
you have a chat open
up okay
yeah okay I go over there first
thank you
thank you for the presentation
um did you check on Showdown or
equivalent tools if some fake services
are Exposed on the internet maybe
through the SL
public certificate
well uh no I I didn't check it in in in
in Shoreland we was looking in in our
telemetry but
um it seems that that these malware is
under the under development as you can
see the Callback mode for instance is
not uh is not fully implemented and it
seems that they are
implementing the the rootkit and from
time to time submitting samples from
from virus total I want to be
transparent we found it in varus total
thank you thanks
hi I was wondering how you actually
found the sample that you started
investigating in the first place how did
you find it and how did you figure it
was going to be interesting enough to
start investigating it
sorry can you can you repeat the
question why did you actually come
across the sample in the first place how
do you how did you find it and then how
did you decide it was going to be
interesting enough to start looking into
well uh I'm I'm always hunting files in
different
um
services and one of them is is virus
total and and well by writing their
rules and so on we was able to find it
yes
thank you
thank you very much very for research
and my question is did you find like any
life infections in your Telemetry in
your data and also how far back this
rootkit goes is it very recent and and
also you didn't know mention any
obfuscation so there was no obscation in
the root kit so three questions well
um there is no obfuscation in the in the
in the sample it's not it's not
obfuscated and and well we don't find
data on it and we also don't so
others publishing anything about it
but what we are doing is looking for
this we first look for for theaters that
we know that root Keys tend to use and
we count samples this way with different
sources and
um
and well it matches our our rules and we
was able to find it
thank you Nikita for the question
okay
um
did you try to different with net filter
business filter attack like managed to
build some Fireball rule that can block
this magic packet
sorry are you are you asking if if I
found other samples no no no no I'm
asking did you can you use some iptable
or inevitable rules that could block the
magic packets because basically they
seem clearly defined so we couldn't
could just block them on a firewall
before it reached the server well uh I
know I'm not probably not the
appropriate person for for asking for
asking this for replying this question
because I I simply find a malware that
is that is new but even if I create
detections and so on there are other
other groups other other
departments that are responsible of
creating the technology and so on and
maybe a day know more about it
thank you
hello uh thanks for the talk uh I wonder
if you have any ideas on detection
sorry I wonder if you have any ideas on
the detection like here on the execution
stage or later when it's already running
well uh there are there are a lot of
points when when you where you can see
you can see the files that it creates
you can see the the net filter hooks
that it that it places and well you can
see that it also hides itself that it
reduces code from other NG so there are
a lot of places when where you can
create detections for it
yes thank you
okay thank you very much thank you
[Applause]