um it's a good day everyone thank you
Boko for having me I'm really excited to
share my research on tracking bumblebees
development
so my name is Sue and I'm a security
researcher at crowdstrike
so talk today will be quite technical in
nature we're going to look at timelines
on the development of different
bumblebee components
and what we'll notice is that the
developers they like to focus on a lot
of EDR evasion techniques some of which
are worth mentioning so we'll look at
them as well
and then finally we'll conclude drawing
a conclusion based on observing these
timelines what can we learn about
Bumblebee's developers what does that
tell us
I also want to note that crowdstrike's
name for the malware in the used in
reporting is actually shindig but I will
continue to use bumblebee throughout
this presentation
so before we look at development
timelines you might as well look at a
really short history timeline on
bumblebee it'll also help us to follow
the presentation better I believe
so bumblebee started was actually first
reported in March 2022 as you see here
it was reported by Google tag the
researchers they observed this new
loader being used by Affiliates who were
previously associated with conti and
that is also how they gave it its name
the Bumblebee string was used in the
user agent header when it made requests
to the server
now the same Affiliates used a similar
loader when they were targeting a cve in
a campaign back in August 2021 Microsoft
reported that incident in September of
that year but that loader was mainly
used for Distributing Cobalt strike it
didn't have the bot like capabilities
that we see Bumblebee having right now
so when we're looking at the timelines
we are going to focus on bumblebee when
it started off as a bot and we believe
that day to be 31st of Jan 2022.
so shortly after the first report there
was an uptick in activity there was
started spreading more and more in fact
it started off with three major
Affiliates using the malware and they
were more Affiliates over this craft
just shows the major ones and
subsequently down the line more and more
Affiliates joined the program the
developers as well went on two different
hiatuses and they're seen distributed by
the likes of smokebot and bath loader to
name a few
um
so what is the malware like when it
infects the system I thought I might as
well give a high level overview because
then it will and you'll like more or
less follow the timeline better from
this as with most e-crime malware it
starts off with the loader that is
packed and encrypted it will unpack our
malware in Bumblebee's case it is always
a dll file so once unpacked bumblebee
communicates with the server to receive
commands they refer to them as tasks
they are abbreviated three letter
strings hopefully you can see that so as
you see here like taking for instance s
i j stands for Shell Code injection I
won't go through this list quite yet
because we are going to talk on tasks on
much later in the talk
also the unpacked file has a hook module
that's used in conjunction with two of
the tasks
bumblebee 2 is modular in nature it can
run plug-ins simultaneously and those
plugins as well can communicate with the
server
so from this image you might as well
mention the timelines we're going to
look at is the development of the loader
and the main dll a second timeline would
be changes made to the C2 comms and then
finally the tasks
so here's a first Gan timeline analysis
chart
quick show of hands cool here is aware
of what a Gantt timeline is
okay a few of you so I might as well
just give a quick description on it so
again timeline it is uh as you can tell
it is a timeline chart it's so from the
left to the right in Bumble in this case
it starts off at 31st of Jan and it'll
end until uh first of March this year
that's what the research is based on and
then from top to bottom you see the
techniques or the that the malware was
using so what they've initially used and
dropped and you can see the duration of
how long those techniques were being
used I didn't add every possible
technique here because it would not fit
a slide I added what I thought would be
more interesting for the talk
so in the very beginning when bumblebee
started
it didn't have a loader it was very
simple I I think it was a tactic by the
Developers for testing out the bot they
were not even Distributing it so the
loader actually started getting used
around the time that activity was
picking up for the malware
before we look at some of these
techniques I want to mention that
Bumblebee's Main dll and plugins
uses a lot of code from the function bar
from boost Library boost is an open
source C plus plus Library it is header
based that means any program that uses
boost ends up statically compiling a lot
of these functions within the binary and
this is why bumblebees files are quite
big in size
so despite in the beginning being new
and you know being tested it did have
what we believe to be an EDR evasion
technique this was where the malware
would hook the API RTL exit user process
it was only hooked if there was an AV
hook present on it that was to make sure
so the trampoline code will make sure
that bumblebee finished its execution
before it went the control went back to
the antivirus hook likely to prevent the
antivirus from analyzing the process any
further and flagging it as malicious
they did though drop this For Thread
execution hijacking by end of June I
believe which in my opinion is a much
better EDR Vision I'll talk on that on a
later slide
now when the loader was introduced it
wasn't only used for packing the malware
it too had an EDR evasion called remote
Library injection and we'll talk on that
too in a later slide
the developers as well played with a
different format of the loader they when
they came back from their first Hiatus
they started using power sploits
reflective dll injection so not only is
the loader now a Powershell file it also
has another EDR on top of the remote
Library injection right now we've seen
mostly in campaigns for SEO poisoning
and malvertising
finally I have to mention alcazer alcazo
came about it's actually a repository on
GitHub by the way it came about
mid-april also around the time a lot
more public reports were starting to
come out on bumblebee this repository
contains different anti-analysis checks
one can run on a machine so the malware
used exclusively all of these checks at
the beginning of execution it made sense
you know to prevent analysis like us to
you know study the malware any further
they did though interestingly drop it
before going on their second break it
wasn't really clear why I thought it was
interesting but they introduced it back
after coming
from the break and in a completely
different context so we'll see that more
when we talk on the C2 communication
so now let's look at the EDR evasion
first off we have is the remote Library
injection so this is the EDR evasion
used by the loader
now the purpose of this technique is to
masquerade mobile bumblebees main dll to
appear running as a legitimate dll in
this screenshot it's a process Explorer
you can see the active threads of
bumblebees process one of those threads
is pointing to this Library called dim's
room it's a Windows system Library so if
you were to analyze the malware you'd
think oh dimm's room is running but in
fact it's Bumblebee the One giveaway
here is you can see referencing the
export function set path that belongs to
the malware
now the way this technique can achieve
it is it hooks apis used by ntdll for
mapping and loading libraries in memory
generally that operation is performed on
a physical file on disk but by hooking
the API they can
use that same operation against an
unpacked file in memory now this proof
of concept is not new it was released in
but interestingly enough the only other
malware scene used in it is ramnet as
was pointed out by IBM in one of their
blogs and this is an even interesting
part one of ramnet's loaders matches
exactly that with bumblebees loader when
used in conjunction with power sploit
and it's quite interesting given after
the remnant talk by clarify
given that ramnet also was seen using
powersploit so so it's not to say that
developers necessarily avoid aware of
this technique or with the same group
but definitely a lot of board code here
next stuff we have is thread execution
hijacking the EDR Aviation used by the
main dll now this technique masquerades
Bumblebee's offset in memory to appear
under a decoy offset and that Decoy
offset belongs to this long named API
part of ntdll
again we have a screenshot of process
Explorer you can see the active thread
and it looks like the API is running but
as you can guess it is Bumblebee
now this technique can do this by first
it creates the API as in a suspended
thread mode so when the thread is
suspended it can modify the thread's
context structure within the structure
is a field which specifies the offset
the start offset it just swaps the api's
address with that of Bumblebee
generally this technique is used for
process injection there's a good entry
of that in miter attack I was trying to
find something similar like a POC or had
no luck the closest I could come to was
this blog that talks about Cozy Bear's
Dropbox loader using this very exact
same technique and funny enough the same
API name as a decoy so again you know
coincidence maybe or not but not new and
a lot of borrower code
so finally that brings us to the C2
communication
right now bumblebee uses a websocket
protocol it creates messages in Json
format the rc4 encrypted before sending
as a request or receiving as a response
the keys in the main dll file
this uh here as you can see as a
truncated version of what those messages
look like it would be it's not possible
to give the entire version since it
would be quite small on the slides uh
I've also labeled them as ping hits and
tasks just to explain the flow better
now these messages they get sent in a
loop bumblebee has a beaconing style
communication and that's you see that
quite common these days with e-crime and
especially if you read dfir reports
you've noticed that you know a lot of
them tend to Beacon and the payload gets
delivered after you know an undetermined
amount of time
so uh now let's talk about the messages
so the whole point for the pink message
is to send across the Bots ID in turn it
receives a session ID from the server
and the session ID is used in throughout
the other request messages and that's
likely for their backend to track what
the messages are and then finally it
ends up with the task response that will
relate the tasks or commands and
potential payloads for the malware
what about this hit
this is where alcazer comes into play so
like on the first timeline we saw alcaza
was used all those checks were used at
the beginning of execution bumblebee
dropped that and now it's only run when
it receives a command from the server
that command is in the Ping's response
there's a Boolean field in there called
Hit if that's set to as true then it
will run all these checks it is it puts
all those checks in a really long Json
file different Boolean field values and
sends it to the server the developers
then only settle with using alcazer
checks they use some of their own things
like what are the current active
processes running on the system and plus
this field here binary DB it is it
contains a base64 encoded SQL database
of browsing history from chrome and
Microsoft Edge so what are the better
way of telling if the system is indeed a
victim or not or a Sandbox and also to
get a bit more contact on who the victim
is
I also have to mention um in case the
malware receives tasks they do send a
task result type request which is just
relays any potential error or any
information that's exfiltrated as a
result of running the tasks
now looking through the development
there's been quite a fair bit of changes
over time it's harder to kind of
understand it and I found that by
grouping them on based on certain
properties it helps us understand the
flow better
so you know in the very beginning at the
start uh bumblebee used https protocol
of course there are Infamous user agent
string Bumblebee the only messages sent
across was the task we didn't see Pingo
hit and they didn't rc4 encrypt those
messages there was a client version
number there one that was used in the
task request and the URLs endpoint
string was called gate now by mid-april
you know around the time as I mentioned
when there was more public reporting
they decided to randomize the user agent
pattern I know trying to make it less
suspicious that it's bumblebee but that
was clearly short-lived and then they
changed it further and yeah they
randomized the usage and even more they
started using rc4 key to encrypt the
messages
uh the URL string change from gate to
gate S as maybe their way of saying
secure
and then okay a month after they came
back from their first Hiatus they
switched the protocol all together and
that's uh websocket the client version
number also reflected that too and then
point string from gate s to gate W as we
can guess what w means this is where
they introduce the Ping message too
and right now where we are at uh is you
know the Ping hitting task messages we
saw earlier and and this in the very
bottom of the screen is the user agent
string they're using now it's always the
same string and I think it's just their
way of trying to make traffic look a bit
more legitimate
now this brings us to our tasks on the
left hand side here you can see a
description of what those tasks mean and
on the right hand side a really high
level overview on how those tasks are
executed
so our first four oops sorry that's not
what I wanted okay our first four tasks
are what's responsible for running the
payloads the first three of which uh
inject the payloads in the process they
use apcq code injection because it is
also a EDR evasion type technique I will
talk on that technique on a later slide
so they are able to inject shell codes
they also can inject dlls two types
secondary payloads that in dll form or
their plugins which are also in the dll
form and if it's dlls it's injected
along with the hook module the hook
module also has an EDR evasion role and
I'll talk about two in a later slide
Bumblebee as well has an option for just
directly executing the payload through
Dex
gdt get data allows the malware to run
bash commands on the system now instead
of directly invoking it via command.xc
they pass those bash commands to
command.xc standard input output via
named pipes this is actually quite a
common Programming type technique so
it's not entirely malicious then there's
ins for install which creates
persistence the malware uses wmi and
finally sdl silent delete the malware
uses Powershell to delete itself
and a final Gantt chart for today so
let's start off with the ins task
this task before they use wmi that shift
was made early may they were using
regular win32 apis things like create
directory and stuff so you could see the
process actually creating these
artifacts the shift to wmi is actually
quite smart because any process that
gets created with wmi ends up showing as
a child process of the wmi parent so
there's a like an unintentional parent
PID spoofing you do not see the child
parent process creation so it's harder
to track what the malware is doing
so continuing with that same task the
way it's implemented deferred based on
what loader was being used
so as in the beginning I showed they
were using either power sploit or it
started off as a regular packed file so
if it is powersploit you know the file
is a Powershell file the malware in this
case would use Windows data protection
API this technique allows to encrypt the
file using system encryption that's
likely to prevent antivirus as they scan
the file from reading the contents and
likely flagging it as malicious and
accordingly the malware will create a
schedule task that executes a script
which uses DP API to decrypt the
contents back before running it
now if it came and packed dll form it
was already encrypted it was already
packed there was no need for using DP
API so they just used the living of the
land binary odbc conf to execute the dll
gdt so that was introduced early May
when they introduced it it had a very
simple implementation here's a funny
part it matches exactly that with msdn's
documentation on how one can pass
input to a process a child process
created by parent process I thought it
was quite clever because it creates
Anonymous name pipes which are harder to
track what those commands are but they
were clearly just testing the technique
it doesn't allow to asynchronously
execute as many commands as you'd like
so by I think two weeks later or so they
just switched to using the boosts
Library framework on it so boost.asio
which allows for asynchronously running
as many programs I mean commands
um so here is a screenshot of the pipe
names that get created as a result of
using this Library it is not necessarily
malicious because you know boost is open
source but it's a great way for hunting
and also at the end of the name or pipe
name is you can see a numeral value
that's the process PID so the resulting
process that created this name pipe
finally um I want to mention about plg
so plg is what allows which is the task
responsible for executing bumblebees
plugins that was introduced around the
time they switched to websocket uh
protocol and I guess they decided to
make the malware more modular in nature
so when they introduced it they needed a
way to communicate with the plugins and
so they use RPC they created an RPC
endpoint via named pipes and this allows
for inter-process communication again
not entirely malicious but a common
programming technique currently what so
when the plugin uses communicates to the
bot main bot via this pipe they can
access what is the active C2 server IP
address and the active Port that the bot
is communicating with and so once it
requires it can separately communicate
with the same server
so now we have the asynchronous
procedure called Q code injection that
was quite long
um so okay this technique is getting
very popular as injection uh as a
process injection technique there's a
miter attack entry on it where you can
see other malware using it so this one
to give a short description is malware
they take advantage of APC by forcing
another process thread to execute code
injected into a process that's been
added to that threads APC queue so every
thread has an apcq and when the thread
is in an alertable state it ends up
executing whatever has been added to
that queue so in Bumblebee's case
um what bumblebee does okay so they
create the process and they in suspended
mode they inject the payload and before
injecting it they also modify the entry
point of the process with they Place
different instructions in there and in
this case the instructions are it ends
up calling the API sleep X in a loop so
sleepex is what allows the thread to be
in an alertable state so when the pro
when the process is resumed sleepex gets
called and the resulting injected code
is run so in the Shell codes case just a
shell code for dll injection there's a
loader stub that gets run first that
will load the hook module the hook
module does its job and finally it'll
run the payload so it's uh this is quite
stealthy because APC injection is not
necessarily malicious it is quite common
in asynchronous programming this is more
that it makes it harder to monitor so
you need I guess different types of
detection logic which
miter attack does list something but it
is still quite hard
and on top of it bumblebee doesn't just
inject the payloads into any process it
injects it into processes created with
wmi as we know that creates a parent PID
spoof spoofing so bam we have two
stealth and one here
finally the hook module
hook module is quite simple it removes
any input any EDR hooks on apis it
actually comes with a hard-coded list of
different apis that it looks for so it
does this by first comparing the api's
instructions in memory to that of its
instructions in the physical file on
disk because a hook is only Pro present
when it's in memory rather than on the
disk it does the comparison using a
function called a length disassembler a
length disassembler essentially
disassembles the instructions and then
it also to get the exact length of
instruction and it also compares the
prefix now if either the length or the
prefix is different it's likely it's
been modified it's hooked in which case
it just copies the instructions from the
physical file to the instructor api's
instructions in memory
and then yeah finally it uses a remote
Library injection this was the EDR
evasion used by the loader uses the same
technique to load the payload dll to
appear running as a legitimate dll
I do want to expand though on that
length disassembler in Bumblebee's case
it that lead and disassembler matches
exactly that with this open source
Library called lib splice it's present
on GitHub it's also that same libraries
seen commonly used by ramnet trickbots
some of trickbot's modules have used it
botbots proxy modules a lot of game
cheats you see it referenced in a lot of
forums a lot of hackers out there tend
to reference it in you know in our I
guess in the industry we tend to call it
inline hooking this technique but in the
hacking Community they call it splicing
so it's not something entirely new in
fact this library is almost a decade old
but so it's interesting that they use it
um you know clearly all the other
malware use it so why you know use
anything different
when something out there Works already
for your case
now that brings us to a conclusion so
now from all these timelines what it
helps us is is it helps us to map
activity to what Bumblebee's software
development life cycle looks like
um
so clearly they seem to have an agile
methodology about how they develop the
malware so the very beginning when we
saw bumblebee being tested out you know
it was quite simple in agile terms you
would call that as MVP a minimal viable
product in fact in a lot of these forums
where malware authors try to promote
their loaders they tend to say beta
version or this is my MVP loader
um it's almost like it's a very startup
culture like it's a kind of like they're
getting funding for their project so
clearly they were testing out between
that period and then phase two started
off you know end of March the same time
the loader was introduced and also where
they included more EDR evasion EDR
evasion is definitely big for a lot of
the loaders a lot of these Affiliates
they're more worried they don't want
their payloads to get detected so they
just want a reliable loader that will
bypass EDR
so apart from this uh we also noticed
that the developers seem to focus on the
C2 infrastructure on during the Hiatus
period
and in our heads I guess when we think
of Hiatus we think the developers are on
a break but uh in this case they are not
they're more on a break from
distribution now this makes sense
because if you're going to change your
back end you want to be able to
distribute a malware that can
communicate with your backend
infrastructure so they're still quite
active uh you know and even though
they're on the highest period and it's
also a flag for us when the malware goes
quiet because then we are like oh they
are up to something
these developers too seem to step out of
the norm in how they've gone about
developing the malware we don't see them
using API hashing or string obfuscation
I I guess not yet it wasn't clear why so
I kind of gambled on why this could be
the case maybe it's a result on how they
are using these EDR Vision techniques so
as we saw with the loader and with the
main dll those techniques they make it
appear as if it's a system dll running
or if it's an api's address in memory
running so if an antivirus you know it's
less likely to scan something that it
doesn't believe to be part of the actual
process
you know address or the actual process
itself so in this case it you know Yara
rules would be quite useless in trying
to detect the malware in memory
uh finally the developers they seem to
have some mature Dev practices
especially the fact that they use boost
and you know it's used for communicating
with the C2 it's used in the gdt task
when it needs to run commands
asynchronously boost is not really
common not quite common among malware it
is there are some families out there
that do use it it makes it quite bulky
but the fact that they use it means um
you know they they do not need to bother
about what win32 apis they need to use
end of the day they can use a library
that works
and also the fact that they're using uh
really common library for splicing lip
splice you know they want to make sure
especially when you're modifying an API
instruction in memory you want to make
sure that you modify it properly
otherwise your payloads won't run
and yeah so hopefully you enjoyed the
talk you've learned something about what
goes behind developing malware what that
looks like and I look forward to any
questions
[Applause]
thank you
questions
okay
thanks for the presentation a great
research thank you and
I have a short comment about boost
actually the Boost library is used by
the developers like normal developers so
maybe they hired somebody experienced on
the team
and another one did you see how it's
being delivered like through fishing or
and anything else
um yeah so I didn't talk too much about
the campaign because
which focuses a lot on the distribution
techniques but it's usually spam and
they use you know ever since the
macros were disabled they started using
things like isos container files
vhds and now SEO poisoning is quite
common so they start off with MSI
installers
the MSI installers here usually has the
Powershell file I have seen them use the
executable file so there's dll side
loading
um
I think that's what comes to mind
there's probably some more out there
yeah but mostly spam you know if I made
one more so uh and did you detect many
of infections throughout your like
Telemetry of the company like searching
for the stuff
did I take what yeah detect any live
detections after you started researching
it and you know feed the feedback to the
systems did you did you see many
infections or
um
that's an interesting question I don't
know if I'm quite allowed to talk about
infections within the company but we can
talk about it later I just saw it on the
air of caution here
okay thank you
[Applause]