okay thank you
I I'm Alec I think maybe more of you
probably know my co-presenter here at
wukish and as you said we're from the
Android malware research team at Google
uh so yeah so we're here today to talk
to you about
OTAs uh which I'll explain a little bit
more what those are if you're not
familiar but basically they're the
system updators on Android devices so
over the past couple years Lucas and I
have been primarily kind of focusing on
pre-installed security threats on
Android devices
um so we're taking a look at like the
device firmware and all the system apps
and everything else that comes
pre-installed on a device out of the box
um
because unfortunately a lot of times
there still is malware
uh in this space
so we'll talk today about some examples
some case studies including you know why
is this actually a Target and what is
Google doing about it
so just to give a little bit of
background first on the whole space that
we're talking about here and where OTAs
fit in the supply chain for Android can
get kind of complicated part of this is
because there's just a lot of different
devices that might run Android you know
most people might think of it as a phone
operating system but it's also used for
cars for televisions tablets and a
million other different iot devices
so in the production of any one device
there's going to be a lot of different
companies involved
and the boundaries between these
companies that you might see here in
this chart get blurred a lot so for
example you might think of mediatek as a
you know chipset producer but for
Android devices a lot of times they
might even make things like you know
music or media players or messaging apps
um
Sometimes some devices are just a
re-licensing of a device that already
existed from another company
and depending on different use cases the
company might not have a lot of
expertise in that domain so they might
uh
contract out certain parts of the device
one of those things being OTAs
so OTA just stands for over the air it's
over-the-air updates so basically the
system update when a new version of the
operating system or when new versions
applications security patches things
like that you know probably that button
that you're always clicking ignore
because you don't want to restart your
device
I know I do it sometimes I'm guilty of
it
but on Android this process is actually
pretty straightforward for developers to
implement all it requires is just
downloading
the new system image that you want to
install on the device and then there is
a single API call
in the recovery system API that actually
verifies the signature installs it and
then you reboot the device
it's very straightforward
I
one reason they cannot be
straightforward though is as a device
manufacturer there might be a lot of
customization you want to do in this
space so if you have a pre-installed app
you might want to update it out of band
you know it doesn't make sense that
every time you want to update your
settings app you have to do a full
system update and reboot the device
right maybe you want to do just update
that one app or maybe you want to update
some system properties or you know
change the server that it connects to
just small changes
um
some other things that might cause
complications are you know you know
where you're actually going to host
these big files for download maybe it's
something that's too expensive for you
so that's uh
kind of why these end up being a target
for abuse is that they're frequently
contracted out to other companies other
companies will develop these whole tools
that allow you to manage you know which
devices are going to get updates when
they get updates depending on a variety
of factors like region mobile carrier
things like that
another reason that they're a main
target for abuse is that they're very
privileged apps on the device
so they automatically are expected to
have access to a lot of sensitive
permissions
and they run as a more privileged user
on the device usually so they actually
run with the shared user ID
which is basically like running as a
privileged Linux user that run that the
rest of the operating system runs as the
Android system user and it gets access
to a whole variety of extra permissions
that user space or user installed apps
don't usually have access to
and uh as well as a bunch of other apis
in addition this these are apps that you
would expect to be downloading other
applications so if you're looking at
your device and you see that this you
know system updater app is installing
other applications on your device that's
not immediately suspicious
so it's a great opportunity
for someone who wants to sell access to
your device download a bunch of malware
to just kind of slip things in
occasionally
so we end up seeing sometimes OTAs will
do just that they'll sell access to
devices create a botnet start
downloading you know add fraud modules
and just running them whenever they feel
like it
so the first instance we'll talk about
is digitime
so this is something that has been
discussed by others already externally I
think it first made headlines with a
Malwarebytes article that was
specifically talking about
some budget phones that were
being distributed by a program through
the US government
um
in with a company called Assurance
Wireless
um some more technical details were also
posted on this blog which there's a link
to here I'll talk about all that
information that's already public but in
addition today we're going to talk about
uh some other things that haven't really
been published yet like what were the
apps that they were actually downloading
and then other versions
after they realize that they've been
detected
so the initial version was being
distributed on a variety of android
devices I think it was ended up they had
like a few dozen customers in the
Android space oems and carriers and
things like that
where did you time was the
standard OTA or system update provider
the actual application looked pretty
basic uh it just did like the basic
system update you know it's a pretty
small application but there was like two
lines in the Java code that launched a
Lua interpreter
and the Lua interpreter I had a Java to
Lua interface
and so if you looked in the asset files
that were included in the application
there were these two files called
license one and license three that were
actually
compiled Lua code and they contained
this whole
uh command and control
module that would connect to a server
and do things like it could check in and
update itself I
it would also have the ability to
download other modules in Lua and
execute them
and it would just basically repeatedly
check in over and over again self update
and I all this Lua code was running with
the elevated permissions of this system
application
so when you take a look at how it was
communicating with the back end the
first thing it would do is just check in
you know identify itself as a new user
device and download and update to the
Lua code and so you can see all the URLs
that they would use here for their
backend servers
were all things that looked kind of like
they could be legitimate my favorite one
here is Android security team.club I
don't know who they thought they were
fooling there
uh and I also thought this was
interesting because it's not something I
normally see in Android malware where
they're trying to blend traffic in
um
normally
you would just see them using one URL
and when it gets burned they just throw
in another one but these applications
were actually uh
really frequently updating their command
and control servers Sometimes using
multiple at a time and so I just thought
that was something I'd normally seen you
know more with like Windows or Linux
malware not not very typical
um
one of the things that it would
initially update with once it was
convinced that you know you weren't an
emulator
was that it would run these modules that
allowed them to launch applications by
specifying the uh the actual component
name that I wanted to launch so it could
launch an activity in another Android
app or a service or send something to a
broadcast receiver
so the uh
the applications that they were
downloading were frequently
these applications that actually had no
user interface they were only able to be
launched
uh
automatically buy these OTA applications
so they would frequently contain code
from families that we've seen uh you
know on play store or
um
through other side loaded user space
applications
um some other some of the families we
noticed that we've talked about before
were things like snow fox and chamois
um
but in this case they would just take
those sdks put them in a custom
application that the user would never
even see didn't have anything user
facing
but they all had these
service or activity names
that were all formatted the same way so
you could you could tell these
applications were all being distributed
by the same person
and so when you take a look at the code
some of the things they would normally
be doing would be like clicking on
applications showing visible ads uh
also doing install referrer fraud
basically trying to take credit for when
an application was installed
even if they weren't the one who
actually downloaded it
another uh interesting thing that kind
of came along
as a side effect of this whole campaign
was that OEM started introducing new
framework code into the Android
operating system on their builds and so
they added a system service
that could be called by applications
that did all these
privileged API calls and normally these
are all things that would be guarded by
sensitive permissions and are only
accessible by pre-installed system
applications but in this case any app
could call them including the apps that
they were downloading without requesting
any of those custom permissions
so this include things like the ability
to install and uninstall other
applications you could automatically
Grant all the permissions that they were
requesting you could
enable individual components of an
application or disable applications
altogether
and do things like access all of the
system files that were written onto the
device
uh so we actually ended up reporting
this as a vulnerability and disclosing
this publicly so you can go to the link
here and find more details about it and
another thing that was interesting about
this was that we started seeing this
system service on applications that
weren't even using the digitime OTA
so some oems were introducing this
higher up in their source code and then
it just ended up being on all their
devices
so this system service ended up being on
you know like a few hundred uh different
device models
um probably about four or five times
more device models than we're actually
using the digitime OTA
once they noticed that we were actually
detecting them they updated
their whole framework to add a bunch of
anti-analysis a bunch of debugging and
unpacking
so whereas before they just had this Lua
framework that was packaged into the
class that was all moved out of the
application and elsewhere into the
operating system
so now the new applications would just
call to a custom uh
Android Java API that was in the
framework code
that would call over jni
to a native library that was stored
somewhere on the device usually they'd
piggyback on something that was already
existing so it'd be something like a
mediatek or a Qualcomm library and they
would add in some uh
jni methods in there
and then that would do probably the most
emulator detection I've ever seen in one
application or in one malware sample it
checked for basically everything that
you can find anywhere on GitHub or on
the Internet on any you know blog post
checking all the different possible
system properties checking the chipset
uh checking for things like Frida or
exposed
checking for virtualbox basically doing
anything they could possibly check to
see is this a real device or not
once they were satisfied
finally they would actually unpack some
encrypted Dex file
from uh from library and they would
actually save it to the cache the Dex
execute or the Java executable cache on
the device so something that's not even
normally accessible to apps
and then finally that from would decrypt
and execute the original Lua code that
we saw so they would generate this key
and then sorry generate this key and
then do xor decryption of uh the Lua
code and end up executing
the same package that we saw before
so this was interesting because we
actually reached out to digitime
originally for the first version and the
answer we got was oh this is actually a
module for our customers so any apps
that you're seeing are being downloaded
by the oems which obviously was not true
because all this apps were the same
across all devices and the oems had no
knowledge of this
but for some reason people kept
partnering with them and I
went on to keep using this next version
of this app but I think so far we have
not seen a version three so okay
I'll pass it over to Luke I should talk
about the second case study
thanks
um I'm slowly losing my voice so think
of it as a built-in talk ending point
when I lose my voice completely but
I will talk about the second OTA app
that is not connected to the first case
study at all it's just
it was built for the same purpose but uh
by a completely different company and
using completely different methods so
um this one for this one we only had one
external report that we are aware of
this was by Malwarebytes
um and uh it dealt with some mobile
phones in Germany specifically that had
the previous told Auto installer they
call it an auto installer but it's a
part of the OTA app so again same story
there's the OTA path that updates the
system image and that's fairly
straightforward in the year and it's
handled by the Android operating system
but there's additional functionality
that downloads apps both updates and
malware
uh and in this case the Malwarebytes
blog post uh presented just one case we
were able to find three different
versions so I will talk about three
different versions of the same uh of the
same malware so the first version uh it
had an ad framework and that dropper by
that I mean that the ad framework was
built into the OTA app it wasn't dropped
but it also had the ability to drop
other apps and uh instantly run even
more stuff so you can see that there is
a really weird file in assets called
input default 4.0 for 10. and this is
the default jar file that will have that
ad framework and also with the
functionality of a dropper so this was
loaded and then
it had methods to download more decks
code download jars install apps but also
display ads so it was fairly
self-contained
um apart from that it had the update
functionality so it could update itself
obviously to a newer version so fairly
basic and you can see that the method
names are um well
self-describing really I didn't change
the names uh so this is these are the
names that they've used when they
um compiled this next file the features
were kind of interesting so the first
feature was that they have a very
opportunistic use of SEO so they didn't
try to root the phone they didn't have
exploits they didn't install Su if Su
was there so if you had your phone
rooted and you had an Su binary they
would use it but they wouldn't try to do
it themselves so we can see there are
two paths on the right hand side one is
the regular path that installs an app so
it will trigger a regular install flow
and user would be aware of that so it
wasn't very fancy in that way
um but if if it found the Su by binary
there is a second path and you can see
it just invokes PM install so if the
phone is rooted and has the Su binary
user won't see the install happening
another interesting feature was a
complete lack of TLS validation so they
connected over https or TLS and they
didn't validate the the server
certificate in any way so you could just
connect to any other server and
intercept the traffic it didn't have to
be signed by a known CA or anything like
that
um which is fairly interesting but it's
also a fairly
common mistake that some developers do
that they don't bother to validate the
certificate when they connect over TLS
so then uh when we started detecting V1
same with digitime they noticed that we
were detecting them and they changed the
version the interesting thing about this
particular malware is that it had three
versions and all three versions are
completely different it's like that you
rewrote the thing from scratch or at
least I cannot find a like very common
patterns
um they use similar CNC so that part
stays the same but the code is like we
abandon all of it and we will write it
again from scratch which makes the
detection very difficult and it's also
something that you don't often see with
malware at least they try to you know
retain some of the code they already
wrote to have less work but this one was
just oh we will start again
um so this one had a bit more
obfuscation you can see the class names
using are using UTF characters so it's
not so easy to reference them
um the names are also obfuscated so it
wasn't as easy as the previous this
version whether you could basically
guess what the method is doing based on
the method name
and the app dropper functionality also
got updated so we can now install apps
using an intent and you can see there's
a package name version version code
download URL so we can pass everything
you want to that app and it will do the
install the download and installation
for you again because it's an OTA app
it's supposed to install apps because
it's supposed to install app updates
right this is what you expect from an
OTA app so it's using the existing
permission that it has for different
reasons to install apps
to install malware apps that users don't
want to not only system updates but also
also malware
they retain some of the features the the
most prominent one that you retained is
the complete lack of validation of the
TLs certificate so this kind of stays
the same alongside the versions they
might have actually copied the code here
so yeah it doesn't do anything
um the other thing they did is they
encoded the CNC URLs as base64
um and this screenshots all screenshot
always reminds me of a kind of useless
knowledge that I keep in my mind and I'm
pretty sure a lot of you keep in your
minds so when you see ahr uh you will
probably think of HTTP or https because
that's how the URLs URLs start and it's
just by 64 there isn't any fancy thing
so if you debase 60 for it you will find
the CNC address and there are several of
them
so that they can use backups
interestingly it also starts activities
so the problem with installing an app is
whenever you install a new app on
Android it won't start automatically
and it has the app itself has no way of
starting automatically at least then I'm
I'm aware of so first time you install
it you have to click on an icon usually
that's what users do to start the app
and then the app starts itself so in in
order to install the app successfully
Redstone uh OTA not only had to download
it and install it it also
was supposed to start it so it got the
activity name for the thing it has to
start
um and then when we started detecting V2
obviously they went
they rewrote the whole thing again and
we got the V3 V3 had a custom decks
obfuscated format or APK obfuscated
format and you can see that the class
names are still Unicode characters so
it's difficult to
um to reference them the thing that
really stands out and I forgot to
mention it with previous versions but it
stayed consistent along all the versions
is that you have this part of the code
that is that looks very clean right has
proper names and all that that's the top
part and this is the part responsible
for the OTA and for the system updates
and for everything that they were
supposed to do and then you have a
separate part that is obfuscated and is
doing the malware stuff so obfuscation
is good but also when you see an app
that has a clean part and the obfuscater
part your brain goes what's the
obfuscated part about right why isn't it
all clean code with proper function
names and and class names
but they kept this scheme of having
proper part legitimate part and having
the malicious part kind of separate
obviously there has to be some kind of
an overlap but it's mostly separate and
in this case the the format was kind was
also interesting so it started with the
Magic The Magic was cortex one or cortex
two just in ASCII and then you had the
file size
um and then you had the sort APK so the
obfuscation method was just starting
and as far as I can tell the difference
between cortex one and cortex 2 was the
sore key
um I'm not sure if there was any other
difference and when you unpacked it or
the obfuscated it
um then you get this code with classes
that decks and manifests so we got the
kind of an APK file and inside of it it
was there was classes the decks and you
can see that the method names here are
well they are non-descriptive
um you still have a class that's named a
but they don't use the same obfuscation
that the code that loaded the decks used
so they don't use Unicode they just use
a regular
names for that
um and this is what the CNC sends back
so one of the cnc's uh in one case we
were able to uh get the traffic that
came from the U.S from the CNC to the
device and you have the package name so
this is the app name that was installed
and you can see there is a bunch of apps
that were installed here then you have
an action action is when the app has to
be started so the OTA was responsible
for making the app persist on the device
or run persistently but also reinstall
it when the app was removed so in most
cases you have something like user
present or screen on which means that
the user is kind of engaging with the
phone and that's when you start the the
main activity it's similar to digit time
and similar to what Alex said the apps
are had less there's no
um
user interface to speak of users cannot
really interact with the app in any way
except for maybe when it displays the
ads but you wouldn't see an icon or
activity this was all done
programmatically
um so um yeah I just want to repeat
again there's a bunch of apps here so
it's it's really
um it's really a lot it's not it's not
just one and since we're talking about
the apps
the payload generally falls in the same
category as with digit times so it will
be some kind of an ad fraud whether it's
a click fraud so clicking on the ads
without user interaction
um ad spam which means that the users
will just see ads
um all the time or um or very very often
there are hidden ads these are meant to
come get impressions from users without
actually displaying the ad to the user
so it's meant to trick The Advertiser to
think that the ad was displayed to the
user and the ad isn't displayed to the
user so it's usually like a
unseen activity or transparent activity
and there's also disruptive advertising
this means that when the user is doing
something is trying to browse the
internet or whatever whenever you have
the user attention you're going to
display the ad which is a terrible
experience for users you're just trying
to to I don't know launch a web browser
and the first thing you see is an ad
and this is an example of a click fraud
app that was heavily using randomization
so if you have a click fraud that tries
to click on an ad without user
interaction you would usually have
some kind of randomization because
otherwise the server side can easily
detect that the app is clicking on on
the ad user will usually click in
different places on the ad the user
usually won't click on the center of the
ad every single time that's just not how
users click on ads
um so you have to use some kind of
randomization
don't tell that to anyone but the users
also don't randomly click on ads which
when you see that there are random
clicks you can you can actually do
something about that
um
so
um they had a really interesting tricks
um these are tricks from the payload so
most likely
um even though I don't know that for
sure but most likely the apps that were
downloaded were written by someone else
and they just paid for instance right so
it's not necessarily the same developer
and the payload apps the apps that did
some kind of an advert had really
interesting tricks in them so the thing
that you can see on their upper right
it's not only an icon this PNG file has
also embedded a jar file which is sort
using a key that's also in the PNG file
so it displays the wrench but if you try
to parse it you can get a DEX file out
of it as well
this is I guess a method to
make us not reverse engineer the app I
never understood this because the PNG
file list is huge for a range
um for an image of a range but um
yeah and there are counters that make
sure that the ads aren't displayed too
often
um
I would like to think it's for user
experience it's probably more that the
server will throttle you and detect that
you're doing out front if you display
ads too often right so not single device
shooting display in hundreds of ads per
minute right it's just not how ads work
so they make sure that they stay under
the radar and are not easily detected by
the other networks that they are trying
to abuse
but the most interesting thing to me was
the way that you were trying to get the
top activity
um in recent Android versions
um almost every
version that that's that was released
recently
um you cannot get the top activity
that's running you cannot get the top up
that user is interacting with if you're
not the top Hub itself
um so they will try to get it
to figure out what the user is doing so
that they can display ads right so if
the user is opening a browser they can
obviously display ads because the user
is trying to engage with the phone so
they know that and getting the top
activity is just the thing that for the
Upstream to are trying to do and the way
they were trying to circumvent that
there's no API call that allows you to
do that is they first
start the PS command then they dipped
the list from the previous PS command so
they had to do it twice so they were
looking for a new process that was
started then they removed all the
processes with names that are not
starting with com dot
um this is to get rid of system
processes although
Android packages don't always start with
com dot especially if you're not in the
US or English-speaking country
then they had hard-coded list of
processes that they didn't want to see
so they removed them of the list as well
and then they get get got the process
with the highest process ID because you
know the highest processor ID means it
was recently started
and as a homework to all of you you can
all figure out why this goes wrong so
many times in so many cases and you
cannot really get the top activity out
of that
um but yeah they were at least trying
um or copied it over from the internet I
don't know
um okay so uh last couple of minutes I
will tell you how we are dealing with
these OTA apps so Oda apps are usually
pre-installed and the thing with OTA
apps is that they have these two paths
right so users still want to get system
updates obviously they want to get
security updates and always updates but
they don't want to get malware with it
so
um we we scan all the devices that have
Google Apps before the device or an
update today to that device is released
they are scanned using
a bunch of tests which are done either
on device or on the system image it
depends on the test type
and the tests are not necessarily only
for security reasons some of them are
for compatibility reasons so they are
testing different things whether the API
is working correctly whether the
hardware is working correctly but the
one that's most interesting to us at
least is BTS which stands for build test
suite and that's the test Suite that
scans for malware
and we scan the system images not only
by scanning the apps but we also scan
the binaries and everything else is on
the system image and then when the test
or the scan is done then the device can
be launched so it has to pass all of
these tests including a test for malware
and this is how we detect OTA so if it
has the
OTA that we deem to be malicious that
device cannot be released and we need a
second system image with either a clean
version of the OTA or without that app
at all
and finally some stats for you for the
last calendar year so we protect over 3
billion devices uh Android devices that
have Google Play on them have a thing
called Google Play protect which scans
the apps and removes malware or asks you
to remove malware
in the last calendar year we scanned
over 4 million pre-installed apps that
were on I over 170 000 system images
when I say system image I mean both the
update and the and the first system
image so this is the these are the
numbers that we're dealing with when we
are trying to look for malware and
system images and in launch devices and
we have five minutes I believe for
questions so thank you
my voice made it to the end
[Applause]
hi really cool presentation I have a
question about the PS trick I know that
in the latest versions of Android you
can no longer get the full process tree
are they that dumb or I am missing
something
foreign
I think they were just targeting older
versions or they didn't didn't get the
memo that it doesn't work anymore
um yeah it never really worked anyway so
I didn't quite get hold of the gtime
application gets on the front of the
first page like is there like a legal
company selling this application and if
so how come you get a V2 I mean
yeah
yeah so for both of these cases
um yeah they're developed by
we'll say legit companies but basically
uh yeah companies that the OEM or some
other person in the distribution chain
partners with to contract out the OTA
part of the operating system
so yeah the company names were actually
digitime and Redstone uh it just kind of
seems that sometimes people
add these features on the side and say
you know we're going to be on all these
devices we're really privileged let's
make a little money on the side
um basically anytime I think we've
reached out it's you know a rogue
developer so
so building on the last question how
many times do they get to fool you
before You Yank their key or revoke
their signatures
so
do you mind yeah sure
um
the problem is that it's as Alex said
these are subcontractors they they are
not companies that make phones
themselves it's the companies that are
hired by the companies that make phones
right so it's kind of this chain of of
companies
um and they are usually signed by the
oems themselves the apps are signed by
the oems themselves the apps are inside
by the developer
um so it's um you know that the phone
making company I don't want to use the
word manufacturer because it's more
complicated than that but the company
that makes phones subcontract someone
else and asks them for some code right
in this case an OTA app and then they
include it in their system image
um as a kind of their code in a way so
it's signed so we really don't have
a way other than telling the OEM not to
work with that company and we don't have
any other method of doing that and to be
honest
the company can just change a name and
pretend to be someone else for the next
time right so
yeah so we we can ban a company from
contributing to the system image
but it's more complicated than that
because it's not as simple as we have a
relationship with that company and we
can just break the relationship it's not
our relationship to the company it's the
phone manufacturer's relationship to the
company
we can talk more about that later
a last question
sure yeah okay
cool presentation thank you out of the
stats you presented you did not speak
about the malware you actually find
before
and if you have any idea of the estimate
percent of malware that escaped this
validation Escape
so
no okay so we have two questions
actually first one is we didn't say how
much malware we find
and I don't have that off the top of my
head so I won't even guess
um I just didn't include that the second
question was how much malware we don't
find
um
yeah
I don't know how to measure that
how did you find it
um so it's well
I can say how we kind of discovered
Redstone it's it has the second part
that's obfuscated that's really
different from the first part so when we
started looking at the OTA apps it's
stood out to us but the way we usually
approach this kind of things is we try
to look at apps that are
particularly privileged privileged like
OTAs or other apps that have lots of
Privileges and we are trying to go
through them and find if they are having
any kind of obfuscated code or weird
code or additional code that's not in
ausp or that's not expected to be there
okay I think we're finished thank you
thank you very much thank you
[Applause]