next up we're gonna have a talk from
Nicola who's going to talk a bit about
the game 0ad which is a liberal realtime
strategy game and the slogan is history
is yours for the taking
right good luck the stage is yours hello
does this work yes I'm here
so welcome everybody to this
presentation thank you so much for
attending it so I'm Nicola over there
and I am the project leader of 0ad
which is a free open-source realtime
strategy game that you may have heard of
if you don't 0 it is a real-time
strategy game so you might compare it to
old commercial titles like edge of
vampires or Warcraft Starcraft this kind
of game basically you have a base a
military base that you have to build up
develop make it flourish economically
and then you can crush your opponents on
the battlefield but the important thing
is that your ad is not a clone of those
commercial games you might know it's
really a completely original game which
is made by us on our free time as a free
and open-source piece of software it's
more precisely it's a history call
strategy game set in ancient times hence
the name zero ad in the Gregorian
calendar zero it doesn't exist you go
straight from 1 BC to 180 0 ad is like a
time that never was in which you can
play big civilizations from 500 BC to 0
ad as at the peak of their influence and
prosperity in the mid in the
Mediterranean world and beyond so we
have 13 factions that you can play in
the game from from the ancient world you
have the Athenians in alphabetical order
the Britons the Carthaginians the goals
the GI variants the crew sheets the
Macedonians the mauryas the patient's
the Potala means this the Romans the
Seleucids and the Spartans so you have a
wall word of ancient civilization that
you can control make them
in achieve supremacy on the battlefield
and really history as you as you make it
yours as 4-0 ad itself in this
presentation about from the world map we
just showed this is only in game footage
the game really looks like this I will
try to show you a video a bit later in
the presentation so the game is
beautiful and also actually fully
playable we advertise it as in
development because we still want to add
features to it but basically you can
play alone or with friends and the game
is almost complete in terms of solo
games you can play against the computer
against the powerful AI which is rather
difficult to beat the first time so
maybe take a couple games before you
increase the difficulty of the AI but
it's really working well here you see a
game played by four different a is
playing against each other and in the
mute multiplayer aspect the game is also
a feature packed we have a multiplayer
mode which works locally if you want to
organize a local arena game we have a
multiplayer lobby with a very active
community so you can just come and have
a game and be crushed if you're still
starting with the game or you can play
with with a friend with direct IP
connection we have some features that
even commercial games don't have
especially in multiplayer we have a
feature in comes in case you have a bad
Network you can join during a game or
rejoin if you get disconnected because
of your network this is a feature that
you can't find easily even in games that
are not made just for fun we have a lot
of other features from multiplayer like
replays of seven modes the chat in game
obviously the ranking on the logic is
done with the same system as for chess
if some of you play this
you have a friend system and much much
more finally of course if I'm here at
first them to present the game is
because 0 ad is free open-source Libre
if you prefer and cross-platform you can
play it on Windows Linux BSD Mac
anything you use it works it's in most
package managers as sorry package
repositories and it's free under the
code is written the GPL and all the art
is licensed under Creative Commons so
this is really a game made by volunteers
for the users in all meanings of of the
world another thing that is made
possible by this openness of the
development of your ad is the mobility
of the game we have a lot of mods this
one is a bit dark sorry we have a lot of
mods and thriving modding environment
here some screenshots of tera magnum
which is a mod that adds civilisations
from the ancient world from outside
Mediterranean world here you have the
Chinese from the Han Dynasty the
Zapotecs from Central America and the
show me new nomads from Central Asia
those are added in each era Magnum mud
we have millennium ad which is obviously
a mod of the the medieval civilizations
in the AG a tribute to Age of Empires 2
and we also have this mod which is
entirely different but has a lot of
success which recreates the world of The
Legend of Zelda in the engine of the
race so really the modding capabilities
of our engine are a big selling point
for for the region for everything and
and for everything we do with that and
actually in the latest version of the
0ag which was real
mid the 2019 we partnered with dot IO
which is a new service provided by the
creators of in gdb and mud ZB I don't
know if you know this website but we
partnered with them to bring modes
downloader inside zero ad
so basically mud that IO provides us
with a website where mothers can upload
their mods and we use their IP their API
to download mods directly into the game
and this has been a huge success we have
a lot of mud some of them are official
made by ourselves and some of them are
made by the community in nine months of
existence since May of 2018 when I
created these slides we were at 42,000
downloads and we are slowly but steadily
going to the 50,000 downloads as you
could see in the few slides I presented
you the art of the rarity is a very
important thing for us we are very lucky
to have great artists who contribute
like voluntarily and create their art
and their content and their assets under
the Creative Commons license and it
allows us on top of the the graphics
capabilities of our online to provide a
game that is beautiful to see beautiful
to play and I will also give you an idea
of the beautiful music we have by
presenting you some excerpts from the
trailer of the latest version
so the entire soundtrack is composed for
0z by another composer played with real
instruments and if you want to come to
our booth in the K building we can give
you City South cities of the soundtrack
of the game so those are some major
features from the latest version and
actually in game footage
[Music]
this is the latest CV zation that was
added to the game which is the kingdom
of cush from ancient Egypt
[Music]
each civilization of 0ag comes with a
full set of models for buildings and
units there are not a lot of difference
in the gameplay between the factions but
it's an entirely different experience
visually
[Music]
we have a map editor which comes with
the game in which you can create maps
like placing elements on the map and you
also have a powerful API for scripting
RAM random maps random map generation so
I hope this gave you the the idea to
download the game and play it at home so
you probably wonder how we got here in
the first place
so it all began in around 2000 where the
original developers of the raid he
actually created a mod for Age of
Empires 2 which was a huge hit so they
decided to do something even bigger and
even more successful and they created
zero ad as a entirely different game
it was first the aim was to create a
game that was free as in free beer
because they came from the muder
environment but in the end they decided
in 2009 to go open source and libre buy
at the same time which allowed the game
to be developed very way further than
was anticipated and we're still going
strong and creating new content and new
features for the game which is actually
no almost finished and so we were global
team of people from all over the world
creating this game so if by any chance
you want to join us you're warmly
welcomed because we always can use more
contributors we can welcome contribution
in
big red referees of course the first
area where we will never have enough
contributors is programming so if you
want to contribute code you can go to
our wiki pages and there will be a lot
of information on how to start your
first tasks you can provide patches on a
platform which is fabricator we use SVN
as a central repository we host
ourselves but we have get mirrors on
github did lab the best way to get in
touch with us is to use the IRC channel
which is now bridged to metrics in this
court you can contribute art just by
going to our forums and chatting with
the community and proposing some new
assets you can contribute other kinds of
content like mods and maps as well on
the forums we have guides on the wiki
and I talked about map editor briefly
earlier and of course if you don't have
all these skills but you want to further
the cause of 0ag you can just talk about
the gameplay yet make every friend know
that you are playing zero ad and you can
also come to the forums and join the
community whenever you want thank for
your attention you can see us at our
booth building K stage 2 and I giving
you the website where you can download
and have more information thank you very
much
[Applause]
[Music]
thank you very much Nikola perfectly on
time yes has he explained if you would
like to talk more since there was no
time for questions you can go to the
booth in building K it was right exactly
very good