hello everyone
thanks for having me
taking time for my brief story about
friendship because it's my first time
here at Weston yeah shame on me give me
a few seconds to introduce myself my
name is Stefan Dooku and I was born in
the late 60s I started doing my first um
IT business in the mid 90s at this time
we built static HTML web sites with I
don't know if you know it BB edit or
Dreamweaver and tested it with Netscape
cold and such stuff from the early years
from the internet later on I found
software it's called content management
systems and at this time we are able to
build dynamic websites I tried several
from the CMS and after some experience I
had a place to stay and it's called true
power I don't know if you need if you
know it it's roopa CMS doing stuff with
CMS was a time I've realized that
contribution to open-source is not only
contribution in code it's more about
find your place to contribute Thank You
volunteers for pasta I I was the
organizer of the Drupal need help in
Berlin for several years I was the
organizer of Linux tag for booth from
for Drupal and later on in 2010 I have
maybe too much time I'm a candidate for
the member of the board for the German
trooper Association today I work for my
own company for development of it and
I'm the president of the CMS garden
that's enough for me
what does CMS garden we started as an
initiative marketing initiative for the
most active content management systems
and today we have more than 10 members
from different CMS in our CMS Garden
Association let me let me rewind to the
time a little bit that was in the mid of
the series as I told you before I was a
proud community member of Drupal and I
found a founder situation inside the old
how all of the CMS's we had an inner
circle and we had the other one we kind
of competitors and when this picture was
taken from Linux TAC I think in two
thousand seven or eight and we had
neighbors from type of three and they
had an orange a booth and we are in blue
and we had two blue balloons and because
the type of three community is we stayed
later on the fair and we decorated the
or orange booth with our blue balloons
and the next morning we had friends no
we kicked type of three as well feeling
of the time maybe you know it what I
mean
in 2012 a German hosting provider invite
us invites us and other different
communities to have a joint booth and to
spread the word to spread the word about
open source on his booth and if you
recognize we had wordpress between
drupal and typo3 but we leave with fair
as friends we shared our t-shirts at the
same time we had a great talk - what
kind of Frank
what kind Frank is the organizer of of
the open source Park exhibit and he's an
true supporter of the idea of open
source and he invites us to have an own
booth at cbut all with a shared chef
scene as John space and that was a great
idea because we want our own booth
without a sponsor logo up there but but
booth had a Sibbett it's more about
50,000 euros and the hunted management
associations won't spend so much money
so we had to collect money and our idea
were to print the book we called it
garden feeble or CMS gardener's guide
and cells sell ad space inside 10
minutes
at the end we got so much money that we
can pay for a booth and and branded 10
hostel rooms for takeover the costs for
the ambassador's we rent an chef at the
conference space so it's a little bit
dark but we had an 80 square metre booth
at save it every day after the fair
would come together and eat fresh may
needs making Ora our day work and it
happens that a Drupal guy looks over the
shoulder of a Joomla guy and said talk
about the concepts of the different CMS
after the C bit we had new friends more
than 50,000 euros eight different CMS 50
ambassador's 10,000 from this booklet
and one crazy competition which CMS
snores loudest
in 2013 we founded our CMS garden
Association and I decided to rule over
this one he is taken in 2014
bigger louder as about 120 square meters
up to 10,000 from his books 50 or 60
ambassadors and many talks to different
event organizers from other fairs and
conferences at the end of 2014 we had
more than 25 events which seemed as
gardeners on Sat what was on side
because of the car team there's less
than 15 active people we decided okay
public relations or marketing initiative
for the most active open source content
management systems check what else can
we do and we found new we found new
target groups in our at our fairs and
events and I have to look what is in
English federal office for information
security asked us to help writing the
second edition from the CMS security
study and we know the guys from
initiative s it's an project in in
Germany for making websites safer we we
are invited from word hosting days it's
a trade fair for the the biggest threat
for from the world for the hosting
industries and we talked to a target
group and we've heard that there is a
need for securing the CMS outside in the
world
so our next focus was to switch to what
can we do as CMS communities to make the
internet a safer place because of the
missing updates from lazy people who
won't update the CMS and we partnered
with echo echo it's I have to look echo
is the Association for the in the
Internet industry I think and we wrote
in and grant application for sawako's in
short it's in long it's secure websites
and content
element systems and we was accepted in
2016 from the federal ministry for
economic affairs and energy what is Sai
because or C because three parts one
part is the scanner from outside to look
after known known security bugs the
second one is a plugin for for a deeper
look from inside a content management
system and the third one is a project we
call it a hosted service you can imagine
three hosted service every time security
update for one of the CMS was released
they see because gives more security
firewall rules - the whole thing - the
whole thing partners to secure the lazy
and not updated CMS because it was
public money the public code feel are
interested and what we're doing with
maybe your money if you're from Germany
and go to github see because
what's next in 2019 at this time one of
our friends from the Joomla world is in
Chicago on the CMS security summit from
Google has a burnt from the formerly
from the WordPress community is leading
a cross CMS working group for GDP are we
partnered with cloud fest
and build up in hackathon if you never
ever be at cloud fest it's a great event
in March in a Whooper park hosts and you
can join us at the internet World Expo
and at the end of the year save the date
our fifth fifth fourth I have no idea
maybe the sixth edition of CMS gun and
conference in Essen for me it's
important that you understand nothing
from this could be happy if there's only
one community we had to join forces we
have to know and to recognize that we
are not competitor or competing each
other we are now friends and we have the
chance we had to chance and you took the
chance to be more together for me it's
important to talk to you here at first
and because in the last year's we only
we had our border in our German language
we want to share the idea of friendship
with other countries other communities
and in other languages so I hope
understand the idea in front next for me
all the the competitor next to you maybe
is your friend
[Applause]