any arrests so I
[Music]
and I actually even
both times it's mostly such as doesn't
matter who eventually who knows the
difference
and also ideally I would like to watch
their
person suffering from scratch entirety I
wrote them to I at least consider using
Shunta
what's reading dusty let's begin like I
truly am straight over for this festival
was become bad
and as
is nuts I don't
my
yeah so we're basically buy so much in
support of the pie symmetry is Xbox
like a hoodie and there is a base over
to France and she will say 20 porta
power and then you ask one of the
adjectives for all these centers and so
- likewise together constantly process
for Internet
[Music]
can you track if you let please
all right
okay so usually that means that you're
gonna want to build an in-depth Linux
and an inverted index is simply
something that associates to each term
list of sorted list of shot a list of
the pages and this simple data structure
is sufficient to actually compute any
kind of good enjoy
so I'm gonna explain a rapidly our
intersection walks so assuming that we
are trying to find all of the documents
that are matching zirconia and mag wait
we're gonna have like this - posting
list we take the first one the first
document of the first one is - and we
are going to seek into the second
posting list for the document - so by
seeking what I should mean is that we
are going to do exactly as if we are
advancing well going through the
scanning through the second posting list
and we are going to stop at the moment
where we find the document that is
greater or equal to the document if it's
equal then that means that two is in the
intersection if it's greater than it's
not so again it's not and we found the
document five and we are gonna like do
symmetrically we are going to add seek
for five in the first posting list there
we go
five was found so it's gonna be now we
can have done the first posting list and
now we're seeking for seven in the
second list and so on so forth until we
reach the end of one of the posting list
so don't only take away there is that if
you want fast intersection you need to
have a fast way to seek through the
posting list
for union its we could use the same
strategy like basically it's like the
mail i everybody has different name for
this algorithm that we could merge put
those two post English and and get the
Union but that's actually inefficient so
I'm using the same trick as Lucinda's
the idea that you prepare in advance
some kind of beat set here and so just
for the sake of this slide the bit
search is actually on offense AIDS but
in tone TV we're using 4096 bit so it's
much larger and what we do is that we
are going to take the first posting list
and we are gonna so so we are going to
append all of the talks that are between
two and two plus so this origin in this
case eight but in 24,000 and we append
those documents in this bit set so in
this bits at the first bit will mean to
the second it will mean 3 and so on
suppose we do that for the first
position is and we do that on a second
time on the zoo composting this is what
we get for bit set and now we can flush
it
so we transform the decreases bit set
into the document that it represented so
it can be done quite fast because your
CPU usually has an instruction to pop
the lowest significant bits out of 64
bit world so you just pop it and so on
of course all right so that's how
interested index is used to compute per
employee
now the question is how do we represent
that on disk so tone CD is relying on a
map for all of its i/o and when you
start on TV the only thing that it does
is basically I'm mapping all of the file
of the index it goes really fast it's
ready to go so we don't have to load any
data structure and put that in any
anonymous memory and
and like have some kind of harsh map in
an image memory everything is on a map
so so stuff that time is very very nice
but that means that we need to have data
on the disk that is usable as is for
travel people and animals memory is more
or less like a sheet
so the first other structure that we are
gonna have to you have in our index is
the term Nick shine so a term addiction
I will be after big dictionary will be
broken down into two step one step will
associate the terms of like the sequence
of writers that with the term to some
kind of term ID and then we're gonna
have another data structure that
Associates a term ID through some kind
of their meaningful strokes a timing but
basically like half point of two files
and like so the beginning of the first
English Winters I'm not gonna talk about
the second data structure because it's
going but let's talk about the first one
so how do we go from terms sequences
right to damn idea so if you are
actually trying to build your own search
engine you will have two broad kind of
family for this solution one could be
like harsh based engine are maybe you
will go fancy and I like the effect
harsh or anything like that it's a very
nice solution in the sense that we you
you would get like very fast hookups and
especially if you don't have much RAM
and everything is sitting on your hard
disk you will probably require very
little IO to do that your hash map will
be able to send you directly in the
right place on your list another
solution is using like a tree based
solution or like a trial so this will
require this we use slightly more CPU
and you will have a lot more random i/o
so that kind of depends on
the layout of your data but you tend to
jump from one node of your try to
another node of your choice it was my
dear root of 6 so there is a is on your
disk but it has a lot of benefits so one
benefit is you can iterate for a round
of keys you can so naturally you will
probably use them all the nodes so by
Domino's I mean if Arabica is your first
word in your dictionary then it would
get term IDC rule the first word
so when softened lexicographic came in
and then the second word might be
something starting by abs and it would
get gamma D no B term with 10 watt a
node 2 and sunspots
so tomodea nodes will Ted your term ID
will be soft at exactly the same whether
your terms
that's a very nice property but more
importantly you can do an intersection
of you try or you try like structure
with the gfs who are you guys familiar
with with a DFA is okay we we still
explain it a little I actually made a
mistake in the year but so that's one so
Jeff S stands for deterministic finite
automaton and that's one way to
implement regular expression so we can
transform any regularize question into
an automaton like this one and the way
it works is once you have it into this
shape then matching a string on this
automata means that you're going to
consume every chart in your stream you
start in the state over there I was
hoping I could point out stuff at
attention
so you started the wait sit over there
and let's say that you are trying to
match carousel your first char is see
you look at the outbound arrows that I
emitted by the state you are in our one
is labelled with the C so I think that
after consuming the see I'm in that
state so 0 1 and then cows are second
later is an a I'm gonna follow this
letter this arrow and I'm in the blue
state ah I end up in this state and we
sell until the say Tigers without the L
will be following the arrow with a star
over there and then also last L will
bring me to the end state so it's really
nice because I'm advancing one chart a
time and I just have to look at the
state of the the end state of my string
to say whether I matched or not
now I must state that match by a double
circle here so I'll try it looks like
this and it's it's actually possible to
much to this DFA about the try very
efficiently so I'm gonna show it's done
so here if we consume this here we end
up in the yellow state just like Raquel
said they consume the a I end up in the
blue states if I get to B then I
underpin this gray state which happened
to be a sink so the sink is a dead end
we will never match if you reach the
state we don't need to see what happens
with the following characters and that's
great because that means that all of
this sub-tree we don't care about
anymore
so for the purpose of fitting string
into the slides this way is very simple
but you can imagine that maybe is as a
gigantic tree that is a child of this
node and we just cut that so that's much
much faster and now we want to much
we don't have to recompute what is a
state required for air we can just look
at the state of a before so it's true
and we see that we are in the sink state
again
and and so on so forth so we are just
putting corrosive our try to guess which
which Terra mean our dictionary our
matching your deterministic finite
automaton that means that I can go
through all of the terms that match our
eager expression but also I can get very
rapidly all of the terms that are at
level strange distance or edit distance
of one of two that means that if you are
asking me please string me all of the
terms that are one type away from what I
tied I can do that very very efficiently
so tone TV is using a like tree based
solution it's actually using a finished
state from this machine those two and I
did not have to cut anything
the rustico system is nice enough that
somebody already coded a very nice
implementation of finished a transducer
I will not explain how it works because
I didn't call it but things that you
might want to know about it is it's
pretty much like a try exact except that
knots can share a few fixes so you you
try will never have an arrow that goes
like this right so because it can share
fixes you end up with something this
slightly more compact on a try and
that's always a very nice feature when
you're being space with your run now
let's talk a little bit about how we are
going to encode posting lists so posting
this a lot of integers it's going to
take a lot of the size of your index and
you're going to want to compress them
integer compression is a field that has
been well studied there is a lot of
solution to do integer compression i put
the chopped over there but basically my
point here is you have a trade-off
between something that is compressing a
lot so it's always like that right you
have to choose with something that
compress the rods and something that is
very fast another thing that I need to
point out is basically all of the guys
are over there and yeah all of these all
of the best algorithm they're all using
Cindy instructions to sync the
instructions are instruction on your CPU
that makes it possible for you to
process for 8 integer at a time so
that's something that actually don't CD
is using a lot so I TV is actually using
so it's a it's a compression scheme that
has been designed by Danielle linear I
recommend you to read this book it's
always very interesting if you're
interested in in things related with
search or data structures
I used to depend on his library actually
in C and I removed it because I I prefer
to be entirely interest and I we
implemented it entirely in rust the gist
of it is like mini of the scheme you're
posting lists are increasing so it
starts by doing something called Delta
encoding so instead of compressing your
integer directly what you do is that you
take the difference between two
consecutive integers and you get
something that is much smaller you take
a pack of those so in my case blocks are
128 integer wrong and out of those
rather than 28 deltas you look at the
one that is a larger so I think it's
example it should be this one at 16 and
you can you notice that you can be
represented using five bits so what you
do then is that you represent all of
show deltas over five bits and you just
concatenate depression so that's called
peat packing so I described what was the
solution for like the scalar version of
it packing what I do is actually I use
Cynthia instruction for that and I do
that with 22 times so Eddie could for
integer at the time and so algorithm
really looks like like this trick that
we were using at school to avoid like
writing lines when we are pinched by our
professor so it use exactly the same
algorithm at the scatter solution you
just choose Cindy instruction in place
of like the scalar instruction it's very
very simple and an interesting
improvements compared to the method that
existed before Daniel Amir's paper which
is so algorithm also take advantage of
the fact that as we are decoding the
integer we end up at one point where we
have one register with deltas that we
are decoding and we can decode the Delta
using Cindy instruction as well so this
is also a similar instruction and we do
that at the point where there are
already in the register so it goes
really really fast and we're talking
about when I say fast to give you an
idea I'm talking about four billion in G
Joseph M we are already very we were
flirting with the bond width of your RAM
delicate so I I told you that Russ was
nice and was able to compile like very
efficient code that it was very close to
C plus person so I wrote that in rust
and this is
some is generated I'm not gonna tell you
that I understand what's what's in there
but important point here is that all of
the like long looking instruction over
there every single one of those is
walking on four bytes at a time and you
will see scalar instruction maybe here
here here so the the assembly code that
is generated is really as good as
possible it's very very close to it
it's probably exactly the same as what
we had in propose so I think we talked
this morning you heard about the m25 and
tf--idf just three coils - so the those
are like the scoring the default scoring
function of regime don t v-- comes in
with being 25 or so this requires to
have access to the term frequency as we
search for when we match a document we
need to have access to the number of
time a term appears in the document and
it's nice to a good locality for that so
we actually interleave blocks of the
cages we don't block of ten frequencies
so that we are likely to have it in in
you know in a nice cash at the moment
where we are reading the as we are doing
so much as we are running the query so
we have one clock of the cages and then
one block of jump frequency and so on so
forth each book is representing 128
blocks
so unfortunately posting is not always
exactly a multiple of 128
work through the last one is using a
different compressing scheme which is
not interesting
and so we also need to have the
information of how many bits are used to
encode each block and we also would like
to have some way to avoid the
compressing this block if we are running
in intersection for instance maybe the
document is not in this broken in that
case we would like to entirely avoid the
compressing it so for that we have
another structure on top of that that
allows us to precisely skip and go to
and the compression is the block that
might be interesting we cannot talk
about something else now so I said in
the beginning of the talk that we wanted
to be able to index an arbitrary large
amount of data use about terabytes and
that's a big problem because if we have
a reduced amount of RAM how are we gonna
be able to build like this nice data
structure on disk we have another prime
which is people might like create an
index and they want to add new documents
we want something that is dynamic we
want to be able to add documents to an
existing index that's another prime it
happens that the solution is the same
for both of this problem so just we find
the idea of White Way it's difficult to
add new documents in an index so data
structure that I described to you on
disk is extremely compact right
everything is should be are compressed
everything is laid out on on disk one
after the other so it really if you toss
a bookshelf it looks like this and if
you are in front of a bookshelf like
that and somebody give you a book and
tells you to put that in the library
you're gonna throw you're gonna have to
move everything away it's an iPad what
you want is to have something that looks
like that if you want to update your
bookshelf or all the time
so Jenna is speaking
there's a trade-off between being
dynamic and and and being compact there
is a nice Creek that exists in many
database it is called the Lord look at
Mick method the idea will be we're gonna
have my compact book Shrek
like that but we are gonna have many of
them so the way it works is the user
will talk on CD will tell you seen hey
consider I will give you a budget of
let's say 300 megabytes and this 300
megabytes would be used for the dynamic
bookshelf here so there's gonna be a big
bookshelf and people will add books into
that until the bookshelf is is full once
the bookshelf is full we are gonna
transform it into a very compact would
sell so in I'm gonna stop with the media
but basically we we serialize our
dynamic data structure into the static
data structure that I described before
and this piece of like very compact
index is called a segment so that what
that you probably heard in English a
data segment and the Boston machine and
in 20 V there is a strong architectural
choice a segment is basically an
independent index so you could literally
like pick your segments and and copy it
into another index and it will run
through the same as long as the schema
of the same that's a very interesting
property actually so if we do that we
are going to end up with a lot of impact
segments and maybe that's not optional
if we have a one terabyte of data that
would be a lot of small segments and
when we do a search we are going to have
to do as many lookups in the dictionary
and that's very inefficient right so on
the backbone we also have a process that
may show segments to get
and you can actually control you you can
define on your own as a user which is a
like strategy used to merge this segment
but it comes with a default strategy
calls are not much policy and the
heuristic behind it is just we try to
merge by default it's gonna be eight
segments that have about the same size
yeah so this technique is also really
nice because that means that we can do
mr. shredded indexing very very easily
220v ask you how much data you give as a
budget and also I mean indexing thread
you want to use and then when you open
the document what you are doing is that
you are paying the document to document
queue and you in the background and you
don't control it but says you're given
number of indexing threads that are
consuming his document queue and that
are populating his dynamic - as I was
talking about
and once they reach their capacity then
they're gonna have say as a signal
segmented like step so the very compact
data structure that we use in the end
and some measuring thread will merge
those very transparently yes thank you
so there's a bunch of pros and cons to
this one plan that is very evident when
use 20v and assisted through for to some
extent is who with machine is that you
when you add the document it's not
sociable right away so it's quite
puzzling for people who are using sequel
database because we decided to have our
segments to be independent index they do
not share any dictionary and that's
sometimes that makes
like specific use a dose of self
difficult not to be able to to actually
match the result from the different
segments very easily yes
so it's not one dictionary I didn't talk
about deletes and updates but those are
a natural night nightmare it's very
complicated
yes that's pretty much all I have on
this flight and then the pros who will
be the next group which is actually the
excellence if you can batch stuff if you
don't have to commit all the time you
can we index a gigantic amount of data
so sync on my laptop I Index Wikipedia
in I thought fit IR s always fit two or
three minutes but that's the amount of
English Wikipedia but such a the speed
we are talking about that we keep AJ is
like a tiny benchmark in search it's not
a big data set
yes so segments are independent index so
you could decide to actually do your
indexing on Hadoop and just copy the
fire of the signals in the same place
and everything would work just the same
or you could decide to do a distributed
search by sending the segment and
dispatching them is we just copying
files it's very transparent and because
we write fires and then we never touch
them again we just write very large file
and and then they read only there is no
like problem of locks or anything widows
just like reads of file and nobody is
touching them so it simplifies a lot of
my work I have a bunch of light there
let's keep them so that you we have a
bit of time to to to ask questions to
you guys of question
so yeah so the question is a is rust and
building a search engine a good fit I
guess with it especially in contrast
with machinima and Java so I would say
yes
so the main benefits that I get from
rust I guess compared to Java is first I
can access seemed instruction so what I
have a lot of control of I know when I
write code whether I'm gonna get static
dispatch or dynamic dispatch
that's something that is extremely hard
in Java you never know what happens also
all of the things like and my M up being
a nightmare in Java it's something that
I I don't have any problem about I don't
know if you everyone knows what I'm
talking about but basically when you're
working with a thick memory in Java like
if you are I'm making a huge amount of
data and you have very little data that
is on your hip your data will be
unmapped only at the moment where the
object that is holding a map thing is
garbage collected and garbage collection
happens only if your hip is actually
like kind of full that's I think that's
a that's a big problem with Java source
of some JVM give you a non-official Java
API to a map stuff some people just like
decide to use Gina equal to do the a map
well I never have that kind of problem
with a with rust everything I'm I'm
working with C or C++ speak
and when I started this project I didn't
know rest at all and then he started
talking to me to actually lowest
which is a bit stupid and credit so I
already knew she prosperous and I had
done a lot of travel as well and after a
long two weeks you don't have to believe
me but I was more productive Universal
and and I felt safer right synced in
verse and I was in both Java and C++ is
an English word I often do that actually
I like treating English words that
nobody knew as a project names is
actually not bad at all for SEO and yeah
people know Manuel everybody's happy
right
so the continued means at full gallop
hands or horse and the a bruiser horse
myself see that one of the best
achievement
[Applause]