okay next up we're gonna have Michael
Johnson was gonna be talking about
tracing and containers with LT TNG so hi
can everyone hear me all right yeah okay
so I'm here to talk to you about delta T
and G n containers and I want to say LT
t & G stands for the Linux trace toolkit
next generation which is a name we don't
really like but it's it's been like that
since the beginning and it stuck with us
so protip choose your project name
wisely so my name is Mikkel John so I
work at officios which is the company
that those that does most of the
development work behind LT TNG I am my
background is not in development but
mostly in system administration so I do
mostly all the CI work the porting to
different architectures builds them and
so on and since last year I started
developing new features integrating
container support into the ltte and G
toolkit so just a quick overview of what
I'm gonna cover today so this is a
follow up to last year's talk if you
were here last year I apologize there's
gonna be a lot of the same material
covered because last year was I was
explaining a proof of concept but now
we're in the implementation phase so
yeah I'll cover why well first what ltte
energy for people that are aware of what
it is what do we mean by supporting
containers in the in alpha TNG and our
progress since last year talk and I'll
go over the feature we have now and the
features were planning to implement this
year so what LT TNG it's it's a suite of
tracing tools so we have two tracers
when Colonel base which is kernel
modules you insert in a in a Linux
kernel and the N one is a user space
tracer which is a set of libraries which
you link into your project and then add
a trace point in them
so how can you describe what is a tracer
for to start it could be described as a
fast non-blocking structured binary
logging framework
so basically logging but faster and more
flexible so the kernel tracer is used to
get low-level information about your
system so you could you can get sis
calls and their parameters scheduling
event a UI events so it gives you a
really in-depth view of what's happening
inside your kernel and then the user
space tracer will be used to well
applications have to be modified to use
the app the user space race or so trace
points have to be added to them but
afterwards if your application is
instrumented then the two tracers can be
used together to correlate information
with with the kernel formation so our
tools use a common trace format which is
called
a CDF so it's what's produced by both
tracers and then what's consumed by the
tooling and the analysis scripts and so
on the CTF format is also its aspect and
spec format that's also used by other
project like gdb for their trace tracing
functions to the tooling is called ltte
energy tools so it's a common tooling
that that's used that you use to control
both the kernel tracer and the user
space racer with the same kind of
commands and primitives and then we have
a command line trace reader which is
basically a command line tool that's
used to read the binary tracers the
trade binary traces and convert them to
human readable text format and also
could be used to convert between
different binary trace formats and so on
and we also have multiple graphical
trace readers which are you eyes that
gives you a graphical view of the
content of traces so there's one that's
called trace compass and then so and
there's also out
gingy scope so why would you want to use
LT TNG because it gives you a combined
view of colonel and user space and also
it's a very low overhead lugging
interesting solution so it can be used
on production system that have actual
production work clothes well without
having much of well there's always a
small impact but the impact is usually
low enough to be used on production
system so the difference of logging
framework where if you would set your
logging framework to be a verbal debug
output would usually have a very big
impact on on the running system it also
can be enabled disabled and reconfigured
at runtime so if you have a running
system and something happens instead of
having to reconfigure the daemon to
output more information and then we
start the service without the T and G
you can just start a tracing session in
the background attach it to your running
system and then get the information you
need to troubleshoot the problem without
having to restart or reconfigure the
system it also provides you flexible
storage of traces so traces can be just
basically this simply written to the
local disk but they can also be streamed
over the network or they can be stored
in memory ring buffers and only get the
disk on certain events when you really
need the data but otherwise just spin in
memory and have a very low impact on
your system and now in the context of LT
TNG what is the content well not only in
the context that what is a container and
how can we observe it with delta T
energy so the problem we faced was that
from a kernel perspective there is no
single concept of a container so you
cannot like read a data structure that
in the kernel that would list all the
existing care
no the articles the existing containers
in their names
and so on so we have to find other
solutions to get this information and
also there's multiple container runtimes
like lxd Rockette darker and many others
that all use the same kind of facilities
in the kernel but I'll do it kind of
their own way and if we want to be a
generic as possible and support all the
use cases of all your users we have to
support all those different container
runtimes
so what we came up with is that all
other containers are all based on the
same kernel subsystem so basically the
namespace cgroups
and also other isolation and security
subsystems depending on on on the
runtime so and now what does it mean to
support containers in a TT and G so we
can divide this path into main objective
the first one is that the traces will
produce the data you extract from your
system without et energy needs to be
needs could contain information that
related to containers so you can
basically like filter events based on
let's say I want to know all the SIS
calls that are all the rites of skulls
that are coming from this container
instead of having the list of all skulls
that are done by all the containers on
the system and the other main task would
be to adjust our tooling that which is
currently which currently assumes like a
monolithic system which it was designed
before containers existed so adjust our
tooling and our deployment strategies so
we can it get it's easier to use
LT TNG in container systems so the the
main task we tackled last year since the
the
my talk last year was the trace content
so the features are developed they're
not they haven't it there haven't been
released yet but they are huge for
version 2 12 LT TNG which should be
released around April a twin of this
year so the main features are so we
added to the kernel tracer a state dump
of the namespaces so that will help you
to get the state of the system at
tracing startup also we added context to
classify and filter events with
namespaces and we already add but we the
Cisco events that will be used to track
namespace changes so I'll go over more
details on each of those features and
also and the same kind of support was
also added to the user space tracer but
only the namespace context was added
because from user space there's the view
you have from our container is much more
limited than from the Locarno side and
what is still missing is having some
more events that come directly from the
container runtimes you get a view of the
lifecycle of the containers and some
more metadata from the containers so for
the specific features first was the
context so what is an entity jah-el
wealth is an LT TNG context it's
basically a metadata field field that
you add to a trace event so if you have
an event that says basically an event
from the kernel for example which is a
scale for example well you want you can
add information to this to this like
logging statement you would add metadata
for a week or in the current context we
currently have or like process ID
threads ID process name so you could
basically enable those context on your
tracing session and each of your event
would be tagged with the proper
information
it's useful for when you manually read
traces text traces but it's also very
useful for filtering so if you want for
example to only get the SIS calls that
come from a specific hit well you could
add a context and then add a filter that
would say only read the events that come
from the speed in the context of
containers so we added context for each
of the namespace type that are in the
kernel so and this enable enables us to
do filtering on the events per container
and on the user space side it all we can
have the same context so basically have
the same container ID to the user space
events and then it will allow you to
correlate events between a kernel trace
and a user space race that would and you
will be able to know they come from the
same container so here's an example of a
text representation of a Cisco event
they get time of this is called event
and you can see that the we added a
namespaces you can see a namespace sorry
the namespace for the the pit NS names
is context in green so basically it
gives you an ID for this patinas inside
the kernel there's no kind there's no
concept of containers as I said before
but there's only namespaces and
namespace don't have names or there they
can only be referred to by the inode
number of the link in the proc file
system which they are exposed to user
space so that's the only unique ID we
found that we could use to identify
namespaces and so you can see in this
example that the event is tagged with
the context paid NS so you know who from
which container it comes and we you can
also see that since this is a pit and s
then the PID would be different inside
the container
outside of it so you can see in the
field PID and VT ID the view in orange
from the host and the view inside the
container so in this example this is a
docker container running radius server
so the the the the init process is ready
server and you can see that it's bid is
1 inside the container but on the host
it's 11,000 something and so the same
thing we we did the same thing for the
user space tracer context so you can see
the same kind of values and the same
kind of filters and so if you wanted in
here is an example of the commands you
would have to run to enable a tracing
session of all the statistical events
are deaf are coming from a specific
docker container on your oath we also
have which we call the the tracker
feature which is basically a simpler
filtering system that's much faster and
we already have an implementation for
PID so basically to trace specific key
IDs on the system without having to use
the filtering rules and we're planning
to add the same the same feet we'll
adding namespace support to this tracker
feature so you can basically trace all
the events that come from a container on
the inside the kernel without with more
much more easily and the other feature
which we worked on is the state dump so
what is what's unintel what's a state
dump in LT TNG terminologies when you
start tracing there are certain events
that are emitted which gives you a view
of the current state of the system so
for example a list of all the pits a
list of all the open FD is a list of all
the block device and so on and so we
added to this information to the we
added to the process information in the
namespace context so now you can have
you can
have an initial state of your containers
when you start tracing and you can use
this too when you do analysis afterwards
to build an initial state of the system
and so we added this information to all
the same same namespaces and also the
PID in user name space are hierarchical
so they there's a year our key you can
add you can have containers and
containers and containers so this is the
information is also provided for
modeling and you can see the events that
are generated when you start tracing and
you can see that they now contain the ID
number of the for example the process
PID namespace and so this the second big
task we have would be to make our
tooling aware of containers currently
all the tooling in alta TNG expect a
single to be running on a single system
with with a single view of the mounts
the no ID mapping so a single view of
what our user IDs what P IDs are but
when you're in a containerized system
depending on where you're running or
were from where you're observing a
process it in have and I appeared that's
different from if you observe it in the
whole story and the containers so that
about things that we have to adjust in
art we have to adjust those assumption
in our tooling and also if we want to
give some easier solution for deploying
a LT change in container system we have
to review the security how we do
security because right now it's pretty
simple it's based on UNIX IDs and file
system permissions and so on on on UNIX
socket so if we don't if we do like bind
mounts to expose a UNIX socket from the
a daemon running into the in the host on
inside containers then we have a whole
problem of like what's what's a UID and
we can control tracing and so well
so currently the support the support
deployment is pretty simple is that you
have the kernel tracer inside the host
and you have your one instance of a user
space racer inside of each container but
what we're where we want to go is to
have a single instance of the tracer in
both user space and kernel inside dolls
and then I've access and then give
access to this resource through the
containers so you wouldn't have to do a
full installation of LT TNG inside of
each container and you could control the
whole system as a whole instead of
having seeing the containers as each
whole system and so that's the division
that the decouple the container were
tooling vision we have for the future
and we really want to know what what are
your needs and your use case so if you
use containers and you use tracing or if
you don't use tracing right now but is
something that you're interested in we
really want to know about what are you
use is what what's your current pain
points and how we can make things better
for you to you to use tracing so you can
contact us on our C Twitter and we also
have a development and user amazing
mailing list so does anyone have
questions that's going to make things
easy oh yeah that's not gonna make it to
the camera about things that we are
fitting right now for example will you
have like several containers with an
Orchestrator like where natus being able
to trace something running in a pod in a
node in a class that it's it's a hard
problem right now so I'm sorry I really
can't really real
thrashing in coordinator so you have
like a kubernetes cluster we serve all
instances of our application drowning as
well nodes having a tool to be able to
trace these obligations without like
going inside the port or the container
or going to the note and then tracing
from the node okay so if you have a
cluster yeah with containers and you
want to trace a specific application
inside us
perfect containers yes a bit container
well yeah we don't have a solution for
now in there in the line of problems
that we are facing the last idea soon so
you think that's one of the problems
right now
okay by pressing on on clusters of
containers not safe containers yeah I
know that well what a lot of people that
are using containers right now that are
talking to us that it's that there's a
yeah well there's a shift in before
systems were static and they were you
would configure manually each of them
but right now they're spawning
containers and we would need to have
some way of auto configuration
auto-configure in tracing into their
containers and having remote
administration but that's that's
something we're interesting into in
looking at but that's we don't add it
right now
all right out of time thank you Thanks
[Applause]