Stupak I become Robin from arm and he
was interesting talk about mv8
so the important me talks which is based
on ritalin rest to the arm 64 feet thank
you so uh this is my first positive I've
never been for one before and I must say
I'm really really impressed and I'm
gonna be a regular now so you know
alright thanks for coming
I'm overwhelmed with this response I
thought I'm just come bear with this
funky new language and there'll be two
people in the room will be interested
but it turns out a lot of you are okay
so the title louder than this it's going
to be really hard I will try I'm sorry
I'm very self spoken soft-spoken so a
microkernel written in rust is the title
some time back I'll explain the
background to this some time back a very
senior processor architect at harm
whispered in my ear about rust and in my
spare time I've been playing with rust
everything over here is basically a bit
of a experiment to scratch in which I
have okay so porting the unix-like redox
operating system to arm v 8.0 I want to
talk about redox this nice new
microkernel based stack and I want to
talk about how I got it going on arm I
should point out though as I was telling
Sebastian I think it was I'm absolutely
floored by the level of detail that the
G note guys put in their slides right
I've been watching their work for a
while now this is nowhere close okay
disclaimer all right so I have to talk
about redox um arm
but redox is written in rust which is a
fairly new language it's a fairly I
would say it's really controversial as
well and I might come to some of that
later but in order to explain an
operating system stack written in a new
language I should introduce the language
now that's hard because you can turn
that into a tutorial for the language
and I don't have
time for that so after Jerry picked only
those things which in my subjective
opinion were interesting things in rust
okay for doing micro curls
so I will discuss rust as well so the
goals are I primarily will talk about
rust very lightweight intro some of the
unique features I'll explain why a Tom
we think it's interesting right and I'll
try and speak a little bit about what
has been done in the rust language for
the ARM architecture and then I'll get
into redox but all along I want to keep
it a little informal because you know
microkernel language I want to talk
about some interesting anecdotes
paradoxes that I see in in in the space
that I work in I'll share that so I work
at Cambridge forearm in the open source
software division it's one of the
biggest divisions as it turns out I work
specifically in the system software
architecture team we are a bunch of four
people who basically are responsible to
try and chart out the right strategy in
different ways and I could explain that
but you'll have to buy me beer but you
look at for make a little middleware
platform all that kind of stuff but it's
all about software really it's kind of
an interface between the software realm
and the hardware guys my specific
responsibility is the so called safety
track where we want to promote the
uptake of our IP in safety critical
domains using open source software as a
medium this comes as a shock to many
people it came as a shock to me because
what the hell open source software in a
safety-critical automotive environment
are you mad
it turns out that it's there a lot of
open source software is used but it's
not used for product ization and
necessarily anybody in the business of
silicon design or system design in the
automotive space I'm going to use that
as a punching bag the automotive
ecosystem they're all using open source
software for silicon bring up research
and development and yada yada yada up
until the point they want somebody on
the hook for the product that's when
they remove the open source stuff and
they go to proprietary service vendors
it's a very well-established thing so
areas of interest all of this I like
this is my own personal list I like
systems programming languages being in
Cambridge having access to the game
University is a bonus I get to speak to
people over there on interesting topics
the university works with arm on ARM
architecture extensions I'm particularly
interested in ARM architecture
extensions that are for safety and
security system design how the
architecture is turned into
microarchitecture and stitched together
into a platform I I'm involved in those
things
so I standards for arm it took awhile
for arm to realize the value of doing
open-source when I joined arm there was
like two and a half people doing
open-source software now there are lots
of people doing open-source software the
reason is that we recognize the value of
trying to use open source as a as a
forcing function to standardize software
because arms biggest strength is also
its biggest weakness strength being
flexibility license the IP do what you
want for that right that's a nightmare
for software so having standards is
important and I interact with those guys
open-source communities my primary
charter is open-source there are lots of
people here whom I've met who are my
friends in this room actually with whom
I have I tried to find out whether
there's an opportunity for their
particular style or doing a microkernel
or some related technology is optimized
for arm or not how can we help do they
have a community you don't have a
community come and attend the lonardo
connect I run a safety track there we
can introduce you to people that kind of
stuff and some people have actually
benefited from that so all of this most
of us my primary focus area which is
safe data fusion and perception
everybody who's in the autonomous space
whether it's for automotives or anything
that requires perception is in the
business of trying to come up with
system hardware that is generic and
applicable for data fusion and
perception in different markets with
some parameterization on top and it is a
really hard problem to make safe right
this is a very very simplified overview
of the kind of systems that we reason
about at in arm you have sensor blocks
with lots of arrays of sensors you have
an i/o concentrator that tries to fuse
as much as it can together the data
format for all the sensor information is
standardized using algorithms I can go
into detail if you like but anyway all
of that is done so that you can build
sufficiently comprehensive environmental
model of the immediate vicinity of
whatever
is that you're trying to make capable of
perception you have general-purpose
computer clusters with processors with
insanely high frequency of operation and
very very sophisticated
microarchitecture implementation that's
fine I have that effect on people
I'm sorry yeah so you have an influence
block that is basically a fancy term for
a subsystem that has the ability to run
three trained noodle Network modules
which have been you know trained to
detect lanes and signs and pedestrians
and all of that stuff and you have an a
synergy between the general-purpose
computing and the influence block to try
and come up with a particular goal
expression that needs to be solved like
okay someone pressed the brake right you
have to decide what to do next right so
there's a goal solving aspect of this
and then all of this goes out to these
mechatronic interfaces and on to the
actuators now how do you make this safe
there are lots of weaknesses in these
links in terms of unpredictable
operation in terms of inability to meet
deadlines in terms of noodle networks
being generally very hard to put
constraints on in terms of a priori
execution times and things like that
right so that's all the stuffing and
micro kernels actually find use in the
general-purpose computer side and and
interestingly now in the infant inside
as well what's more detailed so the
processor architect said hey you should
check out rust right and when a
processor architected arm tails you
should check something out that usually
means I want you to actually do a
rigorous analysis of it so I kind of I
would say I did a rigorous enough
analysis but I said okay I look at this
a little more seriously in my spare time
I wanted something that allowed me to
explore microkernel based systems of
their composition because that is the
most prominent design pattern in the
safety space when it comes to operating
system architecture right all the
proprietary operating systems are
actually popular with vendors our
microkernel based ones I definitely want
to look at the ARM architecture aspect
of the system design anyway so we've
added new instruction sets we've added
new capability into the instruction set
architecture to support safe operation
there's memory tagging there's pointer
authentication lots of stuff going in
over there
I needed to reason about that
and of course I've always wanted to look
at a safety theme systems programming
language and here was my opportunity so
I said all right how do I blend all of
this together I started writing my own
microcon because I'm a huge fan of the
ACL for stuff I've been following it for
a long time I know good know personally
but a new language and it became a
little daunting right to try and mix all
of this together so I said okay has
anyone else tried to do a microkernel
and it turns out that somebody had and
that was redox and that's what I'll use
that as a bit of a scratching an itch
exercise right so before we get there
here is a paradox now this paradox is
not about rust or redox it's just a
general paradox about some of the stuff
that I look at right you often have
completely orthogonal requirements
placed on hardware and software a very
very quickly this is like a very
notional trained trained system of the
kind of compute in terms of non you know
nominal peak single-threaded compute
required and automotives over the years
right I'm not putting anything absolute
over here because people read too much
into any slide I put in an open audience
with material right so this is just a
notional stuff you had brake control
power train fuel injection these are
what I call the traditional things in
the car came about in the 80s
microcontroller class goes all
everything everything really well
understood in terms of worst case
execution yadda yadda yeah interesting
tricks like redundant execution used to
get additional confidence then you had
ivi where there was a big spurt in
compute requirement because people want
to do I don't know watch movies and play
games and all of that all that was great
for ARM Cortex a processors are kind of
dominating in that space and then in the
mid-2000s everyone went absolutely not
so this autonomous thing and basically
the compute requirement is just going
nuts ok if you haven't seen any trend
where it's converging it just seems to
be seems to be going higher and higher
and higher why am I telling you this
because it raises some interesting
paradoxes right so if you look at the
degree of criticality of these classes
of software of course brake control fuel
injection very high degree of
criticality we need the highest
Oren's give us your certificates of
assessment in vehicle infotainment nah
you can run Linux or something on
anytime cool with that right I don't
care so much about the response time
autonomous control
nobody says this explicitly but actually
thinking about it it has an
exceptionally high criticality
requirement as well fine
however there is a linear trend between
the sensitivity to deterministic
execution and the degree of criticality
this is again kind of an unwritten rule
if you have something that's very
critical it must have an a priori known
worst case execution time and you know
all of that should be analyzed to death
and you should give me proof that you
are working within those reaction time
right so as you're becoming more and
more performant your ability to react to
an asynchronous event in a bounded
fashion is becoming really hard to do
because to give you that performance
processors are becoming multi order out
of issue speculative characteristics
complex cache hierarchies translation
regimes it's becoming really hard to
come up with the upper bound right so
autonomous control has very high
requirements it has very high
criticality requirements and performance
requirements but high criticality
requires deterministic execution but if
you're increasing the professors the
professor the processors performance the
slower is its reaction time right this
is a paradox and people are going nuts
trying to solve it right they're making
progress there and you know about the
thin line between safety and security
this is just taken from CVE details I
think this is a trend line and a pie
chart showing that some of the most
common causes of security and I would
say safety related problems are to do
with overflows use after fees privilege
escalation all of that stuff right which
kind of fits very well with the theme of
the stock weight but I spend a lot of
time just screaming silently in a room
with padded walls because I'm
uncomfortable with more complexity when
the question is about a person's life
right but yeah someone something needs
to give autonomous functions started
becoming into the limelight because of
cars but now they're going into toys
drones robots industrial assembly lines
take your pick
hardware engineers are trying very hard
to make this sensibly safe
the software complexity is not going to
come down it's going higher than higher
right so anything we can do to make the
software safer is welcome what have we
done
mixed criticality hardware and software
design let's chop up the design into
bits that are very critical bits that
are less critical and come up with some
guarantees of those boundaries do
traditional quality management software
show me a specification show me a design
have you written the test where is a
test report
ar-ar-ar a-- or or you know what C's
ambiguous will give you a specification
called misra that kind of removes the
ambiguity now you have to recode
everything you wrote using this and show
me that it's all compiling correctly I
don't like it I hate it but it's there
in the industry and then this formal
verification of hardware and software
which in my opinion is the gold standard
rain machine
shakable proofs of implementation
correctness of the hardware and software
both I really like what the ACL four
guys are doing but as I've told them on
several occasions there this is the up
against the wall okay
formal verification unless it gets
commoditized to the extent that your
friend who wrote JavaScript to add this
funky spinner on his web page unless he
can use formal verification without
knowing what formal verification is
people are not going to adopt it right
so I'm a huge advocate of formal
verification and I'm there for the ACL
for guys as they know but I worry that
it's unless they solve the
commoditization problem it's gonna be
initial so then why don't we look at a
language right there's a new language
that's is disruptive but it's got safety
properties let's check it out
I don't want to see this my vision of
cute furry cats and safe cars you know
just very sweet turn into this right
what's up I'm not just a car I'm
actually a killing machine right and you
can program me remotely and influence my
neural network to actually pick out the
particular people I want to assassinate
right so let's try not not get there
finally trust this is the URL of the
Russ language website that's the logo
and that's hello world I have a couple
of quotes right it's a great way of
introducing something nice and
controversial and just cherry pick some
quotes
from the internet usually from reddit
and put them over here but some of them
actually interesting right so rust is
like doing part curve while suspended on
strings and wearing protective gear yes
sometimes it'll look really ridiculous
but you'll be able to do all sorts of
cool moves without hurting yourself
gold I need to send this guy a message
and say I do it that was awesome
the rust book introduction has a very
profound statement which I initially
took as marketing speak but in hindsight
I think it makes a lot of sense it
wasn't always so clear but the RUS
programming language is fundamentally
about empowerment no matter what kind of
code you are writing now rest trust
empowers you to reach farther to program
with confidence and a wider variety of
domains than you did before I stand by
this by the way ok so Russ is very
expressive I often use rust instead of
Python or Ruby and this is by a
gentleman called me that's me right so
apps it is expressive I'm using it to do
stuff that I would do with bash scripts
or Python or Ruby unite I just like the
syntax it's clean it's easy to read it's
quite in Tudor rust expressiveness is
great for making complex system software
concepts accessible this is again my
comment the snippet here is a page table
walk example from redox in the generic
part of the code just read this ok and
then try and look at similar code in
Linux or FreeBSD or anything else this
is beautiful it's prose right I want to
get a reference to a particular fourth
level page table if something's missing
there please create the table right
there at the index I care about and fill
in the hierarchy for my translation
table walk easy to read gets the idea
across immediately very subjective but I
think it's really really expressive
performance right so everyone's got a
bee in their bonnet about trust versus C
and C++ and GU I in my lab intend doing
a far more comprehensive benchmark for
the moment what I present before you is
the very controversial benchmarks game
which is a suite of synthetic toy
programs written by a large community
that tries and scores programs
programming languages
so what I do find is that the comment
made in the rust literature which is
like the performance of machine code
generated from idiomatic rust is
typically at par or better than machine
code generated from idiomatic C++ it's
often true okay
these are you can't read this clearly
but you'll get the slides the names of
the programs they have there's a
nucleotide folding kind of algorithms
and a bunch of others and then they've
scored all of these languages all I'm
trying to say here is there is a case to
be made for rusts performance you know
it can't be ignored now I'm not going to
necessarily name special specific
projects but being at arm I get to speak
to people across the ecosystem on the
topic of safety and on the topic
increasingly of of rust
I think everyone's using it some people
are using it as a way to locate hot
spots in their code in terms of
performance and then replace those hot
spots with the library they were written
in rust right so that's the safer path
they start getting performance and scale
all of that stuff without adopting rust
the language other people are saying
we're going to use rust straight off
Amazon is a great example of that so now
some random statements which I can back
up you can't forget to explicitly
initialize variables with rust the
compiler will prevent that it won't
allow that
you can't overflow an array the compiler
won't check that at compile time but at
a runtime you will get a panic
consistently as opposed to C or C++ but
you may or may not have something bad
happen right which is a feature I love C
my career was based on C and C++ but
facts are facts you can't forget to free
memory allocated on the heap no way if
shared data is protected by lock you
have to take that lock because that
locking scheme owns the data you can't
say I use a wrapper in a library which
had an API asking me to you know take
this lock and I forgot or something
right no it won't compile you can't have
a dangling pointer or double free is not
possible use after free is not possible
generally speaking there is no undefined
behavior and they put a lot of emphasis
on making sure it stays that way
excuse me
so what's the big deal the big deal is
it's all checked at compile time which
is huge so it's actually a combination
of two languages let's turn up the
controversy a little bit there's a frost
and there's unsafe frost the moment I
say this to somebody who's a bit of a
skeptic and by the way in the first time
I've had two or three instances of
heated debates from this one it's unsafe
that's it I'm not using it it's unsafe
don't talk to me now it's supposed to be
safe you it son saying I'm not talking
to you that's not the point the point is
with C and C++ the whole paradigm is
unsafe by design now I should be able to
create a buffer populated with random
numbers get a function pointer to the
start of that buffer and call that junk
as good right because I need that for a
whole class of problems and C's C and
C++ gives me that right you can't do
that in safe rust for very good reason
however if you do need to use that kind
of shenanigan you have an escape hatch
called unsafe rust the cool thing is
that you are forced to annotate all the
code where you want to do this so static
analyzers explicitly know where the
unsafe code is nine times out of ten and
I'm it's probably 10 out of 10 or I'm
just saying 9 out of 10 because I'm not
100% sure if code compiles with rust the
rust compiler it's correct it doesn't
have any of these problems if you're
writing an operating system like I
encountered this with the redox where I
was doing context switching and I've had
problems with some assumptions I made
with register frames or whatever yes
there was a bomb out I knew where to
look because the scope of the search
space had been reduced to just the bits
that were tagged with the unsafe code
I think that's superb I think that's
great that there are unsafe sections in
Indian rust right mmm yeah I think I
said all of this ok so it's not an
interpreted language a lot of people
don't know this it compiles to native
machine code there's no garbage
collector
there's no associated the runtime
non-determinism which becomes an issue
within our areas there's a
scoop based scheme where allocation and
de-allocation is checked at at compile
time so all the types of all variables
have to be known at compile time the
compiler will not allow you to progress
otherwise but the compiler can do type
inference which is handy if you're doing
a lot of code and you don't want to
repeat the types again and again so
that's a modern feature a lot of modern
languages have automatic type inference
as well right
so and here's the really cool one right
so as opposed to C C++ way if there's an
error in the return value of a function
you can do be a really diligent and
smart programmer and check and do
follow-on actions often enough like me
you will forget because you're a lazy
kid but if you're using rust you have to
acknowledge the fact that this function
can return multiple return values and
you have to acknowledge that you have
you you mean to perform a follow-up
action you can't ignore it that
automatically takes of a whole class of
problems when you don't have exception
handling in rest because you have this
separation of recoverable and non
recoverable errors and there is a very
nice trick involving generics and
enumerators that is used to encapsulate
potential problems like if there is a
result is it ochio it is or is it not
okay there's no null pointer check to
see whether the right thing happened you
have a clean pattern matching functional
language paradigm to actually look at
the return of some operation and check
whether the right thing happen or not
that's really cool and you have panic if
there's a problem and you get back
traces and follow the funky stuff
there's another one that people don't
realize the value of okay so every day
all data is immutable by design in rust
if you want to modify data you have to
declare the data to be mutable it's
immutable by design think about it right
this is the root of a lot of problems in
software written at scale that is being
run concurrently and being worked upon
by dozens of hundreds of programmers
right so if you have data that's
immutable by default you have to think
about when you want to modify that data
right that just suddenly makes the whole
LAN thing a little safer
there is no numerical type width
ambiguity I have been personally bitten
in C and C++ where I assume that the
integer size R was the word size on my
architecture which is great but the
architecture
32 bits for word size on one
implementation in 64 bits on the other
simple rate just encode the type weights
in the names of the types right this is
what we end up doing with stood in 10
what have you in C in C++ it's just a
part of the language specification I
think that makes it very clear you don't
have classes but you have composite
types like structure enumerators if you
want behavior for composite types like
you have in classes in in in C++ you
have the ability to implement that using
a concept of traits which are interfaces
so you kind of get like the kind of the
design pattern of C++ for doing for
composable software design but without
all of the arguably very tedious stuff
that C++ has right you have genetics a
systems programming language with
generics is quite unheard off in my
opinion I'm happy to be proven wrong
this makes the duplication of code a
real possibility right so yeah you have
Atomics so I can write a synchronization
primitive and I can see that it is
contingent upon one particular variable
that is of an atomic type and if I say
the specific kind of memory consistency
I want to associate with that atomic I
can do that in the language itself
rather than relying on inline assembly
and arcane instruction selection for a
particular processor and you have
everything you need to build
synchronization primitives of complex
types on top so this is the bit that is
really hard to explain without
whiteboarding and with lots of little
time but all of this is possible the
compile type checking of memory safety
is possible because of a set of rules
which are called ownership rules and and
the rust compiler enforces those rules
for you what it means is that if you
have some data and you hand the data
over to another scope you can't access
that data anymore because the ownership
has changed to the scope that you called
if you still want to pass data around
you have to be very clear about how many
people are there who can likely mutate
this data you can have references to
shared data but everyone must use an
immutable reference if there are
multiple people reading that data if
there is even one person who wants to
mutate it you can't have immutable
references and immutable with you
references together this is probably the
biggest hurdle in my opinion to actually
cross when you are taking rust on right
but it's not hard excellent support for
threads it's all built in
I love the functional patterns like
iterators closures generators those kind
of things in a systems language right I
mean this is not Python there's not you
know so it has a very rich standard
library you don't have to rely on the
standard type template libraries or
custom vendor libraries all of this
stuff is maintained by the community
it's rigorously tested and performance
analyzed you have iterator generators
closures you often do feel like you're
doing Ruby programming with this because
it's influenced by a lot of other
languages first-class support for
writing tests you have decorators for
methods they become tests automatically
the tools do it for you if you want to
do documentation generation you have
classy support you just type this one
command and it opens up a browser with a
rendered HTML page with sequences of
text taken from your code it's got a
really good foreign function interface
so you want to interrupt with see you
won't see to interrupt with the rust
very good support for that rust app is
like this one tool I think like with CC
plus taul any language right you'll have
a route to get similar functionality
where you want like the ruby gems or
pipe I like a simulation of creeks from
other people etcetera etcetera Russ just
makes this part of the language right
you have a tool which you can use to
compose lots of stuff etc etc how much
time I got I think I'm I need to rush
1700 lots of time chill out
so yeah installing Russ is painless you
have this Russ top tool you download it
using curl run it it will create a new
sister owed for you and install rust
everything is ready there's really good
support for switching your cross
compilation target that was really handy
for me if you are it's bound to LLVM and
si lang I should have mention that if
you're if LLVM supports a target backend
the insurances are that you can just you
cross compilers for that using just a
stop you just say rest up install this
target and then when you compile the
code you're compiling it'll generate
code for that particular target which is
really easy to do right if you want to
override what LLVM is default
assumptions are for a particular set of
compiler flags you can create a JSON
file and provide overrides and rust up
we'll just look at that instead there's
this thing called cargo which is the
package manager and this is what I meant
like things like ruby gems etc it's very
easy to use semantically versioned lists
of what are known as crates which are
like you know libraries modules that
kind of stuff and you can be guaranteed
that if you pass somebody a
specification file for cargo for a
particular bit of software you've
written they will be able to recreate
that right down to the exact versions of
all the crates involved without you
having to intervene at all Goldin
there's a central package repository
called crates dot IO and there's a lot
of work put in to try and reduce
compilation times there's lots more work
remaining over there this is the
sequence I chose to learn rust I'm just
mentioning it here in case it helps
others there is a really nice book the
community has written called the rust
book it's available in print form it's
also available on the internet I read
that first then I read it again because
the first time I kept interrupting
myself so the second time I had a cool
reading rust by example is really good
if you just want to go straight to have
a specific problem tell me how to solve
it the rust nomicon provides a lot of
detail some of the internals of how
unsafe works in reality and then there's
the rust reference interestingly there
isn't any rust language specification
yet but there's a working group being
created to attack that problem and I'll
revisit that if I have time so what was
generally useful for implementing a
microkernel I think I can say yes I
particularly like the benefit of unsafe
right it helped me localize the tricky
bits of code the expressiveness trying
to explain a complex bit of system
software was in my opinion easier
interrupted ASM code was a breeze GCC
used to have this naked attribute to
remove that the
it allows you to write functions without
epilogues and that's often very useful
and I appreciated the fact that I can
just use the naked decorator and it just
worked synchronization code was easy to
do because of the memory model
inconsistency specification and the
module subsystem was great basically the
kernel in redox is a library module
called kernel and you can write an
application that links against it and
all of that is hidden by the tooling for
you so what's next for rust and arm
before I finally get to redux thank you
I'm the rep for arm in the cortex a
embedded working group and we are trying
to do some bare metal crates over here
that allow people to do bare metal rust
programming for cortex eight designs so
if you want to write a boot loader or a
secure monitor or something like that
you can just use this great and it has
abstractions for all of the instruction
set architecture and the system control
bits there's a very nice very active
cortex-m embedded working group which
has been there for a while and they've
done something similar for cortex-m the
rust language specific specification
working group I want to try and explore
ways in which we can help the rust
community come up with I won't say ISO
like but a morph and I won't even say
formal specification because that means
something different but what I want is I
want to go to a compiler guy and there
are compiler guys in our my go-to and
when I tell them about rust they say
show me the language specification and
there isn't a language specification
there's a psychological ripple effect
that kind of situation has and then
there's the Rust Belt project that I
want to involve myself with if I can
that's a formal verification of an
intermediary language representation
that rust has called mere and if they
succeed in what they're doing you will
have enhanced confidence in the
correctness of rust finally okay redox I
hope you appreciate that I needed to
seed your mind with that literature
before I can come to this right so this
is redox it's not just a command-line
thing there's a complete suite of
applications including shells including
a POSIX compliant C library a windowing
toolkit frame buffer drivers yadda yadda
yadda this is what it is it's got a
simple browser that often doesn't work
but their work in there trying to fix
that editor is all of that stuff right
so it's got a shell call
that was written by the community for
Linux but it runs under the docs MIT
license rust microkernel reduced set of
UNIX system calls implements as much as
it can in rust there's a really nice C
library written in rust yet another one
it's called a real Ipsy sorry
yet another C library the first one I
believe written in rust called real MC
and about that I'll come to that later
why did they call it rust because
oxidation rust and oxidation involves
this chemical reaction called redox
that's why they call it redox and redox
kind of sounds like UNIX okay so that's
the theory if you try really hard so the
aims were to leverage rust use idiomatic
rust to make complex system concepts
easier for laypeople a programmers
improve the scope of people coming into
the project liberate the existence of
basically the idea here is just rebuild
your code against this other C library
and it should run here okay and then
cover a wide range of target domains the
the guy who wrote it I'll just come to
that his focus was desktop because I
started supporting this with a few
patches they want to go down the
embedded way and then the long-term goal
is target servers will they get there
time will tell so it's written by a guy
called Jeremy Saleh he's become a friend
he wanted to learn how computers work
but he wrote a lot of assembly code and
then basically started getting fed up of
the problems they're discovered rust and
kept writing incremental rust code and
in the end shared it with a friend who
put it on reddit and after that there
was no looking back because that's what
happens with reddit right and there's
been studied development ever since so
there's a efi OS loader x86 64 at
present there's a c library I mentioned
the library has B thread support they've
written a simple file system called
redox ifs there's a small but growing
driver library and there's a group
there's a pretty significantly growing
list of applications actually somebody
or the other somebody did a scummvm port
the other day and you know played old
games it was awesome so Google supported
them in 2017 and made redock self
hosting in 2018 they didn't but people
had started getting interested on
patreon and they gave Jeremy enough
for him to create a redock Summer of
Code instead so he said why not so a lot
of things happen over there that's
roughly when I got involved and I was
like okay give me a student and I'll try
and help them these are just screenshots
of some of the packages that are
available some of the drivers that exist
every week there's something new this is
the stack
it's a typical design where you have the
kernel doing very little and most of the
stuff in terms of resource management
being done in user space I mean I won't
go into details over here I suppose the
the unique thing is that they're
inspired by plan nine the plan lines
everything is a file philosophy but they
are doing everything as a URL which is
interesting
so you there are some cases where you
kind of have some interesting outcomes
right so you don't have a semantic
recursion whether you have a device note
on your file system at slash dev slash
SDA which represent another indirection
into the file system or you could
perhaps have slashed off with another
device know and DRA array or it just
keeps it clean whether you have a fully
qualified URL and you don't have these
oddities about special files and you
know is slash dev slash null is supposed
to indicate null but what is the size of
this file I mean we know what the answer
is but it's just cleaner so you have
URLs and this is wrong the USB one but
just assume it's correct for the moment
we basically you have these fully
qualified URLs to actually access
services and this is the protocol that's
used between elements of the file system
user space kernel different execution
context they call schemes very easy to
write actually written in rust you have
primitives for all of this stuff you
have an interesting containerization
scheme where basically you have this
null namespace and you can find it at a
fine-grained system called level socket
level restrict capabilities you want a
particular process for half so that's
that's their capability model there is
SMP support but the scheduling
algorithms are very simple right now and
that's probably a good thing you'll see
I want to do a line of code thing so
there's a utility called LOC is written
in rust you should check it out you
pointed at a code base it does some
inference and spits out some stats but
basically the upshot of this is that the
kernel is roughly in the region of 8,000
to 9,000 lines of
give or take right
virtualization and redox there is no
support of virtualization at present I
don't think there will be support but we
will see I think what the community
wants to orient around is the philosophy
that you should just rebuild your
software against real ipsy if you want
to run it and that's the virtualization
play rather than supporting running
unmodified software and a lot of people
are okay with that right going to the
overhead of working with a fully new
language you probably are okay with this
rebuilding software at least Oh pre
lipsi posix-compliant
uses this tool called Sieben gen for
foreign function interface in with C
code targets redox and Linux there's a
new project called 'rain that enables
running redox applications under linux
using some tricks with real ipsy its api
compatible with the linux system called
set and for a given architecture
obviously it's a bi compatible as well
and this is what makes it possible to
run most programs that have been known
to run under linux or the bsts without
too much pain on redux the RUS compiler
is is built for this particular triplet
and that's in associated with real ipsy
and that's how the tool chains start
supporting all of this stuff now I don't
know how I'm gonna do this super quick
so I I this is basically a list of
everything I did to get the port happen
right so I identified what I was after
in terms of which particular
architecture number and execution state
to target I wanted to keep things simple
I chose frame use virtual machine
emulation for 64 as the platform target
that's the configuration I wrote on a
scope and put it on the redox gate lab
and waited for people who tell me
something no one did so I just went
ahead anyways I started speaking with
the arm guys because I am like with most
silicon manufacturers you have to get
permissions to do this kind of stuff
started playing with rust the compiler
which is rust in LLVM and looked at what
was done to add support for one
particular triplet then said okay I'll
write something similar for a at 64
unknown redox rinse repeat until I got
what looked like arm assembly
ran into trouble with thread local
support because I don't think anyone
survives thread local support the first
time in any
operating system implementation it's a
pain in the in the nether regions
the you have separate instructions for
doing TLS accesses at two separate
exception levels and armed one for the
kernel one for the user space but LLVM
would only ever generate code for user
space even for TLS code that I was
compiling on the kernel side in because
it was making the using the wrong
instruction so I had to modify LLVM
which was not bad actually and then I
came up with our debug flow involving
gdb and gdb is super great stuff there's
a guy at arm who's our gdb mint take
back what I said there's a guy at almost
a cream.you maintainer and with his help
I figured out how to make gdb and claim
you give me some really good stats for
debugging and tracing I created a boot
flow with you boot because I wanted to
try and stay as close to the experience
people would have on an embedded target
with cream you and I use eater net and
this TFTP emulation and I use FTP to use
to transfer environmental information
from the boot environment to the kernel
replicated the x86 if your kernel code
structure stopped everything out got a
linker script done up got a link cable
kernel image that wouldn't run verify
that execution is reaching the kernel
started writing early init code did lots
of MMU song-and-dance in the end managed
to jump to rust code fleshed out
recursive paging implementation for a at
64 this was fun
it's a trick used by on typically on x86
64 to have the MMU help you when you
want to do page table updates rather
than you walking page table hierarchies
but it involves tricks with selection of
virtual addresses and the way in which
you programming amuse and nobody had
done it for arm v8 and I spoke to some
of my friends in the arm kernel team
they said it's probably possible
try it out I tried it it kind of works
but it's fragile I will probably replace
this with proper linear paging at some
point yeah so mapping so I packed in a
diagnostic UART and got hello world and
I was quite pleased with myself and then
just random selection of bare driver
support all the while I was kind of
making sure gdb is kind of
working with simple tests stack frame
unwinding no symbol support but at least
I have a stack trace and that's helpful
I did it at 64 support of ellipse e for
the system calls for all of the
interrupts with the rest of the kernel
context a ring stove and I got in it the
user space program to build try to run
it failed tried hard to figure out what
was going on issues with elf parsing
eventually it said hello which is good
then I've fleshed out supporting system
calls and got some optimizations there
lots more work required here got init
scripts going context switching code
rinse repeat everything's fantastic
interrupt controller timers shady lo
hooks FD T drivers changing all of the
raw drivers I had written to use ftt so
you can be a little more dynamic and
then started using like this f TT is the
flattened device tree it's a way of
abstracting away the kernel from
platform specific things like interrupts
number as always speak to me afterwards
and then I simplify the live disk
support so you basically have this
structure that's easy to build and run
and does not involve using a disk
controller just yet because I haven't
finished that and then login shellsworth
I got KT going and I on without too much
trouble and then everything just worked
I did some CPU identification stuff and
then I drank a lot of beer suppose I
like beer so current storage status
there's a clean room exercise underway
because I have broken it as of last
night code is continually being checked
into a are 64 branches of various
repositories which are in the redox
github get lab there's a documentation
rewrite we have some people working on
silicon it's taking time but it will
happen this is stuff that we want to do
in 2019 I won't go into the details read
it ask me if you have questions and then
sorry these are the generic redox things
and these are things I want to do for
arm if I have the time these are details
about the redox community they follow
the rust Code of Conduct and they stick
to it it's actually very a very pleasant
community to work with I should add
the guy who's done it boots it on
literally dozens of laptop families
because he works for system76 they make
Linux laptops man so he uses all of
those as his test target there's a guy
from my team called Caston Heights low
is he here it's not here so he told me
that the only way to check sorry and
this is not a at 64 okay and it might
crash but just hold on he said the only
way to check whether operating system is
truly complete
isn't it always doing it runs do
[Applause]
so this is a rebuild of freedom of PR
doom against real epsy and it's working
so I don't know where redox will go
frankly I'd love to see it go places
it's given me a foundation for some of
the architectural exploration I wanted
to do which i think is cool but I think
it's made a lot of progress in a very
short amount of time compared to a lot
of other microkernel stories there's
something do we learn from that okay
that's it
[Applause]