hello thank you okay
I presume you all have an idea of what
two-factor authentication might be on
cloud I also presume you know what on
cloud is it is a self-hosted file
sharing system to explain it in seven
words some words about me I started to
deal with two-factor authentication 2005
and 2014 I started the project privacy
idea and here's a bit contact
information so what are we looking at
today I brought a small setup I've I
have an uncle out 10 installation it is
connected to Active Directory I'm sorry
for this you could also use open ended
up you could use a sequel database but
the point is you have somewhere user
store where your users are located and
currently your setup is that the users
authenticate to this own cloud with a
password and well we have some news
lately about passwords it's finally it's
getting a bit boring I think and for
example this SAP line there says that
the right time to have a password or to
have a second pass but is now if you see
this will be different I think the time
to have two-factor authentication is now
so how will we do this
who of you knows own cloud ok great then
you probably know that there's also a
cool app with an own cloud a TOTP app
the user can enroll a second factor by
creating such nice QR code and then he
can secure his log in to his own cloud
with a second factor on his smartphone
this is a great thing the users in
control
do
use it that's fine but also be aware
that this is a TOTP algorithm totp means
that is only time dependent this means
the secret key is contained in this QR
code everyone who scans this QR code
will have a copy of your second factor
and the downside is the users in control
so if you have a an organization where
you want your users to for example force
to use a second factor this is not the
good solution and finally if you are
setting up a second factor for all your
applications this way you will end up
with lots of second factors okay so what
I actually the requirements for
two-factor authentication when we look
at enterprise environments first of all
users have to comply to policies user is
not allowed to decide if he wants to do
two-factor authentication or not he has
to do what the company or the
organization defines then it's nice to
have a lot of different token types to
choose from and most important you have
to have a central management where you
can manage the second factors where you
can connect different applications to
and where for example you also have
workflows for your helpdesk users and
this is where privacy idea comes in
privacy ideas such a central management
system it connects to existing user
stores it supports a lot of different
token types and has a lot of other cool
things like policies and event handlers
and finally if you set up a privacy
ideas system in your network you can
connect many different applications to
this authentication system okay so what
we will do now is we started with the
setup on cloud and Active Directory and
we will add a privacy idea system so
that on cloud is able to talk to this
privacy idea system the first factor of
the user provides will be authenticated
against active
rectory the second factor will go
against privacy idea for this we need
the privacy at your server and we need
to install a small plugin small app in
the old cloud system ok so unfortunately
I have spent five minutes to explain
this to you
so I'm bit in a hurry to actually do
this in 15 minutes and so I have to have
speed things up here you see on
Wednesday I started at 9 minutes after
9:00 a.m. to actually add a launchpad
repository I add the launchpad
repository I update the package index I
run an upgrade of my system and then
down there we probably cannot see it in
the launchpad repository is a meta
package privacy idea Apache - which
installs all necessary components on
this naked Ubuntu system in this case if
you like other distributions if you like
other databases if you like other web
servers of course you can do as you
please and you can simply install this
from the Python package index ok yes and
actually all batteries included you
unfortunately is also bad to see but at
10 minutes after 9:00 a.m. I am asked if
I want to install this these 250 new
packages with all dependencies I hit yes
I have to set my sequel password at 11
minutes past 9 and at 913 I'm actually
done everything which I need is
installed after 4 minutes and the only
thing that remains is I have to set the
password of an initial administrator so
this is also important we do not come
with a standard password because of
standard passwords Arabic
nasty so this was the server side and I
said we also need to install a plug-in
an own cloud we will do this now we go
to the marketplace in our own cloud
installation and then the most difficult
part is finding the app actually we
found it and now another difficult step
is to find the install button it's a bit
bit below down to the right and then you
can hit the install button and the
plug-in which connects own cloud with
privacy idea is installed ok to finally
make things even more exciting I thought
we do a small hands-on I will try to
show you how this is connected to Active
Directory we will enroll a few token
types for example now let's see how far
we come ok this is my privacy at the
installation here and you know wait a
second I can show you my connection to
the active directory so we actually have
a real running active directory here
with 18 users and the interesting thing
is you can you can Curie any LDAP server
quite flexible and here in the lock and
attribute you see we enter the same
account name and object geo ID so these
are actually the attributes which accept
which privacy idea accepts as username
in the locking request this is quite
interesting for ownCloud because the
default
identifier in ownCloud when you are
connecting to an LDAP system or to an
Active Directory is the object GUI D so
the authentication request arrives a
privacy idea with the object GID then we
have a lot of users which we fetched
from the LDAP let's take this one and
let's enroll a most evil smartphone app
ok I enrolled the smartphone app so you
may wonder so what's the difference if I
would use the TOTP app in on cloud the
thing is now my smartphone as
authentication device is centrally
centrally managed in privacy idea now we
go to the own cloud system nice I
already open the settings window this is
the setting configuration of the privacy
idea lock in
the interesting thing is I have I can
exclude user groups from the requirement
to do two-factor authentication this is
quite nice if you either do an enrolment
and only want to have friendly users in
a pilot to use two-factor authentication
or in my case too for example exclude
administrators so that you do not lock
you out quite at the start ok so the
thing is I now have to in the first step
authenticate with my Ella password and
own cloud then the plaque and says oh
please provide your second factor
because you are not in the group that
does not need a second factor I use the
second factor I just enrolled on my
smartphone
and login oh this is quite interesting
it's better to actually type the correct
number so but you see typing is a really
nasty thing so and for this privacy idea
also supports other tokens of course we
support these classical key fob tokens
but the interesting thing might be we
also provide support these nice you
bikies and the interesting thing about
you bikies is I do not have to type and
actually I can initialize the keys
directly myself so let's see nope well
initializing the Yubikey I have a
command-line tool I call the
command-line to privacy idea with the
parameter secrets this is simply a file
that contains some more parameters which
I do not want to type all the time I hit
enter provide my password my
administrator password for privacy ideal
the command-line tool
talks to privacy idea via the REST API
and starts to enroll you be keys so it
tells me please enter inside the Yubikey
I enroll a Yubikey I insert the next you
wiki and it finds the Yubikey and
enrolls the next you wiki so nice thing
I can buy 100 you bikies and roll out
the ub keys and 5 minutes and be sure
that these secrets are are only known by
me and now the interesting thing is now
I can go to privacy idea again I see I
have two new tokens these are the UB
keys I just enrolled and now I can
assign the ub keys
I assigned the yuba keys to the same
user and since I do not know
I cannot submit a key I cannot read the
serial number on the back of the Yuba
keys so I assign both you bikies I think
there's some time left to assign
actually both UB keys and as you can see
of course the system is also capable of
assigning several tokens to the same
user if needed so now my user has three
different tokens and he can decide which
one he wants to use to authenticate to
the system I take a Yubikey plugging in
the USB port touch the bat me and hope
come touch the button thanks I enrolled
to UB keys touch the Bucky Oh
would someone please touch the body
this is really interesting so I think
you all know how the Yuba Keys work so
they if you had working hands you would
insert the one-time password and you
would be authenticated thank you for
your time and your interest
[Applause]