so hello everyone my name is penny Xia
today I'm gonna give you enough
misty and I wrote not that kind of
update because if you've followed along
the what Silicon Valley companies do
when they write a blog post titled an
update on X that usually means that X is
cancelled or dead so my thesis net
beastie is not dead and I want to show
you something about it and I'm gonna go
reasonably quickly through the slides
because I only have 20 minutes so first
of all the last major release of net
beastie it seems an eternity ago but it
was actually last year so it's in scope
for this talk I suppose is a net 58 and
it was released in July has binaries for
55 ports available so ports are not
architectures it's with difficult port
is something like EVP arm evaluation
board with an ARM processor and then
there's multiple so to speak supports
for like 32 bits 64-bit ARM v6 army 7
how do I float software flow or
big-endian data anyway so there's lots
of those so at least e8 is quite a big
upgrade from net 57 for a number of
reasons the first one you'll probably
notice on the first boot is that you
have DRM for supported cards which means
you get a graphical console because the
kernel handles all the video mode
switching and all of that nonsense other
than that there is USB 3 support which
is which is really nice especially
because if you have a laptop or a
desktop with USB 3 it probably doesn't
support the older controller thingy so
either you have no USB in net 57 or USB
3 here nvme cards if you have those
they're quite a lot faster vio skocy i'm
going to talk about in a second it's
it's a storage layer for an emulated
hard drive that a bunch of cloud
providers use and also qmo
supports and and there's been quite a
bit of hardening for security that has
been done so there we now have a SLR
enabled by default in protect which is
which the open BC folks called W or X
position independent executables there
is a there's an option to build
everything reproducible which I'm not
sure I think it's not the default
there's an internal audio mixer which is
kind of minor but very cool so you can
play as many different audio sources as
you want that can all open dev audio and
and play stuff and it'll be mixed
together
no pulse audio or other crap needed and
so as I was saying it seems like an
eternity
the thing is net beastie a took a long
time to get released I dug out this
email here which was the announcement of
the branch and you notice it's from over
a year before the 6th of June 2017 and
it says here we don't have a strict
timeline for the 8 release but things
are looking pretty good at the moment we
expect this release to be happen in a
shorter amount of time
well that didn't happen they basically
what ended up happening was that DRM had
been imported and it was it's such a
headline feature we absolutely wanted to
ship with it but it wasn't quite working
and yeah I would have was the excuse for
seven what was the excuse for 8 anyway
so so these were both long releases and
yes and technically net beastie 7 is
still supported because the nepotistic
project supports the two last major
releases but at least on Intel and AMD
architectures I would really like to
encourage you to stop using at beastie 7
4 because of these two guys Spector and
meltdown net PC eight ships with full
mitigations for those the NPC 7 doesn't
and
have not been back for it so it's not a
good idea to be running at beastie 7 on
anything remotely sensitive now that's
all gone netbsd 9 so net beastie 9 is
not a thing yet it has not been branched
yet we keep saying that this release is
going to be the one that's better than
the previous releases and the net PC
foundation has actually done something
it has hired a person full-time as a
release engineer Martin who's a man so
we're cautiously optimistic that once we
decide to actually branch the thing
where I can release in a finite amount
of time in the meantime we're at a point
where net beastie current has become
really good compared to net 58 and
typically an open source that's a sign
that you should trust really is what you
have but it's not that easy so on a
bunch of hardware it's actually now the
best net beastie you can run this
current because it had major
improvements in drivers in performance
and in security so the security has the
introduction of colonel at a SLR if you
want that it's not on by default you
have to change your bootloader config I
think to do that it's it works by having
a little trampoline kernel so to speak
that pretends it's the kernel it loads
the image randomizes the addresses and
then puts it then there's the K leak the
kernel leak detector that there's going
to be a talk on this after Urmi then the
kernel address sanitizer the kernel
undefined behavior sanitizer all of
these have found quite a few bugs by the
way the sanitizers are also in user land
I believe that a number of usual n-box
have also been found and fixed due to
that there is an updated ZFS which is
now actually usable so you can actually
run your storage on ethnicity on ZFS
it's a bit fiddly to get it working
first because your kernel and your user
land must match exactly because the
interface is not quite stable I think
but yeah it's the ETFs is there we have
updated graphics drivers again that's a
big one if you're using any halfway
recent Intel board like I myself have
one with Intel iris graphics that was
not supported in eight but it's now
supported and there's also been AMD and
NVIDIA fixes I think it's all relatively
current so basically with all major
graphics hardware you should be able to
get graphical console accelerated X
accelerated video and even accelerated
3d which is nice and if you're running
on arm then there has been a tremendous
amount of work gone into net beastie on
arm and it is a lot better than at 58
and I want to show you a little bit
about arm because it's the new hotness
so to speak so first of all Jared McNeil
with an MVC developer have has made this
really nice page invisible dot see a
slash arm that gives you a bunch of
bootable images on for Annette PC that
you can just write on an SD card put the
SD card in boot the machine
I here I've expended a 32-bit menu you
see that we support the various PI's
there's the Raspberry Pi obviously the
orange Pi which is really nice
I have one of those at the banana PI the
nano PI the Oldroyd which is also really
nicely here and so on and then for
64-bit the list is a bit shorter but arm
64 is a completely new architecture and
epi ste current eight doesn't have it
yet so that's just that yes
yes good point it's also shorter because
there's a generic 64-bit image that
supports most of these so for example if
you have a Raspberry Pi 3 you can run it
in 64-bit mode the pine a 64 is
supported the the rock 64 Rock Pro and
the Nano PI a neo to an EO + to this
list by the way will get shorter over
time as first offset because of we have
better support for ftt flatten device
trees and better support for UEFI
booting which means that you no longer
need board specific kernels or bought
specific boot loaders or anything you
have one image and it's just going to
work on all of the things which is
really what you want and I see one here
in the audience this thing here is super
cool it's called the pine book there's a
14-inch version which are shown here
there's also a smaller one in 11 inch
there $99 it's pretty good they have an
ARM processor light and thin as it says
here and so that what happened is that
the net Vista Foundation bought a bunch
of those for developers I think about 30
and then gave them out to all of the
developers who wanted one basically and
as a result of course there was rapid
development in drivers and bug fixes and
whatnot to the point that I think on
these things
Anette beast is more or less the primary
OS now so that they should still ship
with Linux by default that map st is
relatively prominent on them so that's
really cool then I have one more thing
that I scraped off so Zechariah McGrew
did is doing a port of net piece tree to
risk 5 however it's not in the tree yet
it's it's a separate tree right now it
hasn't been merged into the main tree
and I think it's not quite
at the state where you can boot a full
system and go multi-user so compared to
FreeBSD what we heard just in the
previous talk we're a bit behind on that
but yeah they're basically in the
process of setting up Newport mailing
lists and and the structure for adding
new ports for risk five so that's also
gonna be a thing very soon I don't know
if it will be it will probably not be in
at 59 I suppose but it's coming will
risk the risk 5b the new arm that's a
good question I don't think so I think
arm will yeah arm will be the the main
thing in the future really like Armas at
the point of displacing I suppose Intel
the Intel architectures you see it in in
various cloud providers you see it in
the persistent rumor that Apple is gonna
have ARM processors for the next
generation of MacBook so it's gonna be
very interesting and from the point of
view and now I want to talk a little bit
about virtualization and cloud because
net beastie is a great cloud OS believe
it or not so if you want to virtualize
something on a net bsd desktop let's
start small you have you have a machine
running net beastie you want to
virtualize something else on it these
thing you can do is run qmo and have it
emulated in software that's kind of slow
it's kind of sucky and then up until
very recently you had as a second option
only sin and there's two new options
that I want to talk about so sin is
those that don't know it's a hypervisor
where you install a special kernel the
Zen kernel and then load your operating
system kernel as what's called the Dom
zero and then you can create new domains
in it it's it's a bit heavy weight it's
not super easy to set up and the net
based extend support this
used to be for really first class and
it's slightly bit rotting I think
because it doesn't for two of the four
virtualization modes that then offers
and those to happen to be the preferred
ones these days but we gain two new
virtualization frameworks funnily enough
one of them works better on AMD one of
them works better on Intel so nvm M is
written by a net bsd developer in us in
a weekend essentially it's a it's a
simple library and a little kernel it
has user done part in the kernel part
and it does primitives for vm management
if you will using hardware
virtualization on certain AMD cpus most
AMD CPUs and they and hexam is the Intel
hardware accelerated execution manager
it's a thing developed by Intel and used
for instance in by Google in the Android
studio builds it's the default emulation
framework to do the Android emulator and
Android emulation that has also imported
to the netbsd kernel it is in the kernel
in current and what these both of these
share is that the front-end to
manipulating them is qmo again so you
compile qmo with the backends for these
two and it'll select the one that works
as false um or you can give it a
command-line option to say I want to run
this VM or with hexam or with nvm em and
then you'll have basically the full
speed of your hardware you'll be using
hardware virtualization instructions
that are built in these CPUs you can run
multi-core VMs as many as you have
course you can even run more emulated
course and you have real course although
it gets bit slower and it's really nice
so you have
performant virtualization support using
these two things and then if you wanna
run net beasty off-premises I've put
here three options that are all three
really good I think the first one full
disclosure I work for Google about I
think Google cloud platform is great is
fully supported with net BST although
you have to build your own image because
of the way they treat official images
the official images are all Linux and
you cannot it doesn't have a feature
like AWS has community am is and where
one person can upload the working net
misty image and and others can
instantiate that that doesn't work
unfortunately but other than that it
works really really good and again we
have the vio Scaasi and the virtual
network drivers these are para
virtualized things offered by their
hypervisor and we have cover drivers for
them so wrathful performance another
option that's very intriguing is scale
way is a French company so if you don't
like you know a multinational American
companies maybe that's good they offer
arm VMs like a cloud running exclusively
on arm all the storages SSD back so it's
very fast and there's well it's faster
than GCP I think and they're they're
really cheap so you can get a say
development machine development VM with
four or eight cores and the decent
amount of RAM costs you six zeros per
month if you're relieved it running all
the time that's really nice
one caveat though is that so you can run
net beasty EVP arm 64-bit on it but the
CPU itself does not support any 32-bit
instructions so you cannot run any arm
32 binaries on it which means that
currently you can't run any go binaries
because net is the arm 64 support for go
hasn't landed yet and then the last
option Amazon ec2 on AWS classic there
are official images prepared by the net
PC foundation under the community ami is
list for the Intel based servers and
some AWS zones now have ARM based
servers they're quite a bit cheaper to
run than the Intel ones and again you
can run a twisty EVP arm 64-bit on it
and it works just fine if you use
current for Google cloud platform I've
released this strip for a while ago
github come slash Google slash net PC
GCE is a little buy a little bash script
that you run and it creates an image for
you that you can then upload it's in a
required format the readme explains the
commands you need to do to upload the
thing the RIC the required format is a
hard hard disk image no it's a raw image
it must be raw it must be in @rg set
file but the tar file must be no tar and
it must have a certain name it's
completely brain-dead yes
so the neffe ste has a tool called anita
which is an automated installation
thingy that we use for running tests in
VMs and basically I abuse Anita to
install net PSD and then shut down the
VM before the first reboot and then pack
up the the disk that we just installed
so I have 15 seconds left to conclude I
think net beastie is an OS on the
bleeding edge it doesn't only run on
like obsolete big iron hardware you
should give it a try on on modern
hardware Pete your desktop where it's
really good these days beat a pine book
or some sort of arm single board
computer for $30 it does make a decent
test
I haven't talked about packages at all
but there's been a tremendous amount of
work that's gone into making xfce mate
and other desktops run well and it is
also an excellent server OS for running
in the cloud or on premises thank you
for attention
[Applause]
you