we are proud to have you and Guinness
not the beer from Exodus privacy's so
its analysis of the behavior of mobile
application and its consequences for our
privacy thank you
so hello everybody and I'm gonna start
by presenting who we are and what we are
doing so we are so new and my name is
Guinness and we will talk about the
behavior of mobile applications and
especially about trackers which are
inside these applications and what we
are trying to do to make people aware of
the trackers and who we are we are a
group of French activists a nonprofit
organization which was founded in
October 2017 and we are we have an
undefined number of members like we are
eight to ten active people but we have
many supporters and people are one was
speaking and helping us working and we
have some collaborations with the idea
privacy lab which is a legal issue
libera Research Laboratory in the US and
we have collaboration with F trade also
in order to integrate our reports in the
after its application and platform and
also we obey some strict strict legal
rules in that way in the way that
everything we do is illegal so for
example we do not the compiled
application since it is forbidden in
France except for research reasons and
we are not a research laboratory hello
everyone so what is our goal as you know
said this is to make people aware of the
tracking which is done by your mobile
how do we do this so we develop a
platform which is called Exodus privacy
auditing platform it will identify
trackers in mobile application just
Android applications actually just
looking for code signatures as Guiness
said we cannot decompile application so
we just statically analyze the files the
apk files and we look for signatures and
then nothing will give a bit more
details about this in a few slides the
goal of this tool is to really show
people and make you understand what is
in the Android application so we don't
give judgments to it to it we just show
what is inside the application so that
you are aware of it and you can make
your own decisions about this this is an
example of the of the exodus application
this is an example of a report about
meteor France which is the public
weather forecasts group in France and
the application as you can see you
having some informations about the
application here don't know did more
than 5 million times and the important
part is on the Left sorry the number of
trackers and permissions so the
permissions are pretty simple we just
add the levels on the right which is
defined by Google
they have three levels dangerous normal
and and special and on the left is the
interesting part as well is that the
trackers it said that we just found the
code signatures of this one and in this
case you have 22 but what is a tracker
because that's the important part here
tracker is a piece of software which is
meant to collect data about your usage
of the application you have some example
on the bottom like Google Analytics
Google Analytics or Teemo on the exodus
application you can see this is a report
page about the tracker now you can see a
couple of information about
tracker itself its name the location the
website so this is a ferry from Yahoo
and you can see how we detect it so here
you have a co detection rule and network
detection so if we find this code in the
application we will flag and say that
the tracker is is in it here you can see
that there is a thousand two hundred
twenty reports actually currently in the
applications with this tracker but how
do we do this in detail thank you so
basically what we are doing is some
static analysis of the APK so we just
list java classes which are embedded in
the epoch in the APK with a tool called
textin which is provided by google and
then thanks to the code signatures which
are some regular expression with just
match against the the java classes we
have found and the tools we are using in
the platform so we have G play CLI which
is a tool which allows us to download
the apk directly from the Play Store in
in CLI we use and regard which is a tool
which allows some analysis and work on
the APK and we use it mainly in order to
detect the permissions required by the
application and we use Dex them to list
Java classes which is a tool provided by
Google and which is open source so we
can check that they it works the way we
want it to work and so in small graph it
is lazy so we have the apk file which we
unzip to list the Dex files and with
text them we Adam Java classes we have
our attractor or signatures and we match
it so what is important here is that we
need to note
tracker signatures in order to detect
trackers so we have to build a list of
trackers that we know to be trackers how
do we do this well it is mainly people
who contribute to it like well I have
seen something weird on the network and
I just look and try to find if what is
it
which company does where does it come
from and which company provides this and
in well the first version of exodus
platform when we it was created to us
broadly this like the egg stamp and some
sorting and we match thank you so we
have a couple of tools the first one we
already showed you the exodus web
platform so you can freely go to the
exodus platform you can search for
reports you can ask for new reports I
think important thing to say is that we
don't analyze application all the time
we just do it on demand so if there is a
report that you are looking for and it's
not in the application you can simply
ask for new analysis and in couple of
seconds maybe minutes you will have the
report with the permission and and the
trackers this is just to show a couple
of tools how it's working the exotics
core is in Python the web application is
in Django and we are using couple of
tools to provision or machine and to
make it automatically we have other
tools as well to make this more usable
for everyone we have sorry Android
application which will simply get the
list of application on your phone it
will for each of them get the report and
show you directly so here you can see
that you don't have to go to the website
it will directly show on your phone the
report and you can open it and see the
details the exit this application
doesn't not have any tracker obviously
you can check it on exodia's attics
available on Neff droid and also on
Google Play there's as well XO defi
extension actually it was not done by us
it was just done by the community let's
say and we have it will add the reports
information directly on the Google Play
Store web page so it's quite convenient
you can directly see number of trackers
and it can give you a link so directly
on the application you can see number of
trackers on the Left if you click on it
for instance you can see the force one
on the first row it's unknown you can
directly submit it will link you to the
exodus web application web page to
submit a new analysis there is a last
tool we can talk about it is called
Exodus standalone actually it can be
used by Android application developers
because that's also important to know
that sometimes the developers are even
not aware that there are trackers in
their own applications so with this you
can statically analyze your application
before you publish it you just give you
a PK and it will show you the list of of
trackers and permissions in text or JSON
important thing to notice that is only
on Linux so it doesn't work on any other
platform well I can just complete so
when we created exist under Allen so we
had some issues kind of issues when we
created some reports for the quant
application so quant a web to search
engine and we found some trackers and
they say what we don't have strikers in
our applications we are privacy friendly
and everything and say well the report
can't be false if we found that trackers
the Java classes were embedded and
actually what happened is that it was
included in SDK included by qualms in
their applications
so sometimes the developers are not the
world that is there adding some trackers
they are just using some SDK or some
starting back of SDK for new
applications which embed trackers and
eventually we created exactly stand
around for that developers to check when
they are writing the applications to
check that they do not embed some
trackers it's I think you can note that
they remove the trackers I thank you
very quickly so that could be noted I
think so what are the first results
we've had in like one year and a few
months so as I said before we created
the organization in November November
2017 and for now we have identified 152
trackers and analyzed more than 48,000
applications we help developers like one
scanning the applications as I said
before and also we try to provide some
advices to developers in order to to
clean the applications and to respect
privacy of the users and we did also
some cheaper audits of some applications
like network audit because what is
important is that in our method it is
only a static analysis so we cannot be
sure that the trackers the trackers is
effectively used by the application
it could be embedded but never cold and
then we find it but it is not used and
so with network audit you can check if
some packets are
on the network okay and and we did some
audits for Bibles we have a slide for
this and I will explain just after what
we can find on it it is quite impressive
and also we provide some statistics on
which strikers are the most present in
the applications which are less present
how many applications we have analyzed
and we open the rest API which allows to
query for trackers applications the list
of all the trackers we have identified
and also we are trying to educate people
and the trackers and so we created some
small videos which are following French
and English and yeah and we have also
some subtitles and this game is to have
some extremely easily understandable
videos like for your children and it's
quite it's it's a interesting to see
it's very it's a know how to say it but
just look at it it's on our YouTube
channel and our peer-to-peer virtual
instance and everything is free and open
source for sure so the most frequent
trackers we have identified so Google
firebase analytics and Google Ads which
are in five 50 percent and then we have
so a lot of Google and then Facebook and
other trackers and as I said before baby
plus so we installed baby plays on an
Android device which had never been
connected to Facebook and we launched
the baby press applications and we gave
some information like the name of the
baby and what we can see on the report
we know that it goes to graft at
facebook.com/ some the domain which
which collects data from the trackers
and we can see the gender the name if it
is breastfed or not and we know from
which application it comes yeah just to
finish though we are in the press we got
some big coverage in the first six
months we are helped by this by the Yale
provide Sealab to get coverage for
instance in the interceptor of the
Guardian yeah we had a nice visit with
the colonel we will use exotics for
preliminary investigations we are on
well TV as well but I think we'll just
conclude with some final points how do
we communicate and how do we make people
aware of this beside our tools we have
stickers it are some in the entrance if
you want when you leave flyers we have
as we said channels on YouTube and Pia
tube and obviously accounts on Twitter
and and master dome and Facebook and we
use conferences like today to talk about
us and to finish what's the future the
first one is to revamp the reports we
want to make them as user-friendly as we
can because we really want to target
everyone and for that we want to make as
well more videos and podcasts to explain
the tracking on mobile translate our
videos and really gather more and more
motivated people to help us that will
just lead me to the next slide yes we
need help yeah we really I think any
kind of contributions it can be in code
we have as we talked about Python with
Java in the Android application as well
if you have season mean skills but as
well if you want to make videos
translate videos make any kind of
pedagogical contents
this is useful for us or even spread the
word sport so anything is really useful
you have every information on the
contribute page and we have as well a
contact contact page with all the
information if you want to contact us so
if you have any questions related to
this and I think that will yes conclude
the presentation thank you any questions
hi I'm your as I'm a legal scholar I
have a question about I mean compliments
for your work this is really great but
shouldn't the apps themselves just be
transparent about these things and
shouldn't Google just have a respond the
positive of all these things I mean
there must be scanning the app
statically dynamically what is like what
is your vision for the future where
should this transparency be provided
should your work be necessary in five
years I think that's a good question for
instance if you use Yelp which is a tool
to download applications from the Google
Play Store without together accounts
they actually integrate exodus so you
can just activate in the option and they
have directly the information f-droid as
well is scanning their applications with
Exodus before putting it in the in the
store I think it's hard to answer for
Google's I think we'll be happy if
they're if they integrate our reports in
the Google Play Store yeah yeah I think
our goal is to make people aware of it
we spread the world of them as much as
we can and but yeah I think that the
point is to really target developers
because they have to be aware of what
they are doing and at least if they know
if the public knows then everything is
transparent they are know the question
yep
once a user downloads to your report and
finds out what trackers and permissions
are being used like what should we do
next what's the next step for someone
well there are multiple possibilities so
you can if you want contact the
developer and say well I have found this
tracker in your application and it seems
well to me so why is it here I know you
can ask to remove it or if you want
don't not want to contact the developer
because you know they won't remove it
you can use an application which is
called low kada and which acts as kind
of VPN which will block outgoing packets
based on detection rules like dns dns
names for example you can say I want all
packets going to add that Google that
come to be blocked and I will not go out
after blocka da block a de DL okay a G a
and it's quite impressive you have some
free pre compiled lists of the name that
can be blocked which are more or less
aggressive you have some very loose
lists and some very aggressive lists
which will block all twitter.com for
example
yeah I think there are a lot of ways you
can as well use mobile version a little
web mobile version if you can because
like this you can more control what you
are doing with your browser you can use
another application if there is another
one which is more respecting your
privacy but yeah
for instance Kwan's once they were aware
they removed it maybe if everyone is
communicating about it everyone will
just remove it who knows but yeah it's
decision you have to do check all your
apps and make a decision for each of
them
do you intend to develop a similar tool
to IPA based applications on iOS yeah
good question actually we cannot do that
because we cannot check the application
because of DRMs so we are not allowed to
do it but that's a really frequently
asked question what we can say is that
often the apps are made by the same
people and the trackers which exist on
Android exist on iOS so you can just
assume that it's basically the same if
you have any other question just come to
see us I think we can discuss outside or
after it sorry
[Applause]