the microphone is green and on yeah yeah
hi the next talk will be somehow two
stages lower as he said it's now not not
not about especially solo elasticsearch
features it's more about what's below
everything and that hope will be about
Lucene but they will also have a little
bit of solar a version 8 here that just
very very quick my background I'm one of
the commuters of Apache Lucine and solar
but I'm also in my daily life I'm doing
more elasticsearch stuff and I was the
one who implemented the first numeric
queries that all of you might use so
this talk will about will be about Lucy
in 8 and of course the first question
everybody will will ask you is when does
it come out and of course the official
answer is no comment but as far as I see
there are now plans to really do the
first test releases so I hope maybe you
get it in the next months maybe or in
two months but let's see important the
release Blanche
so for the whole of the 80s was the boss
cut off in mid-january and based on that
currently everything is committed to
more in most cases we progress when the
apart fixes so it's going to the master
branch which will be Lucy 9 to the 8th
branch and then we also are doing some
additional duplications because we want
to remove some stuff and this will go
into the leucine 7.7 release which will
come shortly before the 8 release so
that's plan okay the first thing is what
will change in Lezyne so here you see
already there's something with 10 times
faster queries and indeed that's really
happening because the most important
change is that Lucy in got somehow
new result collection engine so when it
executes a query the way how the results
are collected was changed so you can can
short circulates a search so other means
if you do not need the whole result
count so the exact count of metrics you
want then you don't need to count all
the matches calculate the score of it so
you can shot so good and just say I have
found more than 1,000 results or
something like that and that's something
which brings four specific types of
queries and especially those are the
boolean queries if you have many or
clauses and maybe some of those or
clauses have very very common terms like
stop words and then or you have
something like many many results but you
still want to do because in nature a
natural language processing and full
text search engines you are never doing
end queries you're doing or queries
because you want to show the most
relevant ones first but if a very very
long tail and you are in most cases not
interested on the long tail
so in that case and you also don't want
to know how many results they are so you
can simply cut that off so the new
result collection engine works with some
queries of course boolean query phrase
queries and all the constants core query
but the question is how does it work now
so the idea here is to add some
additional statistical information to
the index so you can do that
short-circuit because when you are
collecting the top ranking results you
need some information from the index to
jump over the results if when you know
that they are not relevant at all
because their score is too low and to
help with that you are saving maximum
term frequency and also the norm in in
separate blocks in in blocks of the
posting lists and then you can jump over
that I will explain that a little bit
later it's also done multi-level and
it's stored in the so called Skip list
so here's the paper about what we
implemented I think it's from 2011 it's
the fast
the topic a document retrieval using
block max indexes and the cool thing is
all Splott max indexes are working very
very close to those skip lists in new
scenes or you can reuse a lot of code to
implement that and be based on that it
makes it much easier for us to include
that so the first question is what is a
skip list so the Skip list is if you
have a standard Lucene index you have to
- so if a query for two words which is
leucine and search and the list here is
the document numbers which have that
term here and normally if you're doing
or query you would simply collect all
those document numbers and score them
but for an end query you can make use of
the so called Skip list that means
because you need if you have an end
query you need to have and you need
somehow also you you have to to find all
those metrics which owns the same
document for all N query so that means
your first iterating through the posting
list of the first term you find the
result number seven and then you have to
say okay skip the other one - any
document which is after or on seven and
so that happens that it's jumping here
from the seven to that seven and then it
asks again go forward and find the next
one
which must be after seven I have here
twelve in that case but twelve does not
help so I have to go to 15 and because
of that if you have some additional
statistics like here if you know for
example you want to chop some to 15 here
in the first posting list and you're
somewhere here you can reuse some
information saved on the block so you
are splitting that into blocks or for
items and then you can quickly jump to
number 15 or to number 57 and that's a
so-called Skip list so for end queries
currently the Skip list is heavily used
so when you apply a filter in a losing
query
most of the credit time is used in
jumping through those terms so and now
the idea here is to reuse the same skip
list yeah there's something else the
Skip list is also multi-layered so that
means you have multi layers so you can
also have something if you are here and
you want to jump to document or after
document or at e3 there's a direct pass
from from that one so you can even jump
faster so on a different level
so the idea now is to add some
additional information like for example
the term frequency into that skip list
and then you can do almost the same for
for queries because you know if you're
collecting the the top ranking results
you have a specific score and if you
have already filled your top one getting
results with a minimum so the lowest
competive score is something like 10 for
example then any document which would
have a score of 9 would never get into
the top ranking result list so you can
simply jump over those and because we
cannot store the scores in the posting
list what we are doing here is we we add
some those statistics also we say here
all those documents with those numbers
have a trump frequency of suis and
because the score is is is is somehow
realized so if the score goes up or the
term frequency know if the term
frequency goes up the score also goes up
and the same you can do for the norms
but there's the other way around and
based on that you're just asking in that
case if you have an awkward I just need
a new document where the minimum score
is at least 20 to get in the top ranking
results and then you are Trust
calculating from the from the Skip list
but the best position is to move and as
you see here of course I cannot count
that documents anymore because I don't
know over how many documents I charmed
and because of that you're losing the
information how many
hits you have in your belly at the end
so if you want to have more details as
especially the stuff how it works with
the other queries how it works with
boolean queries whose phrase queries and
so on will the talk by Ellen Woodward
directly after that one showing you more
details about that this is why I wanted
to make it short but as always if you
explain something it's it's a you want
to give it as much as possible so in
addition to that in leucine 8 we have
some new field types one is the feature
field which is already existing in
previous versions of Lusine but the idea
behind that field type is you can use it
now with the block max index also to
jump over documents where you have
something like ranking factors in that
so if you have something like a per talk
you meant feature like the PageRank you
you want to use that in the scoring but
it's an additional scoring factor but as
soon as you use a function query all
this block max stuff does not work
anymore
because you don't know if if your TF and
norm in the index is helpful to figure
out if the result is going in it so as
soon as you have a function query it
won't work anymore so if you have done
that for example with all our using a
doc values field this won't work here in
that case the idea here is to use a
feature field where you simply have a
hard-coded term frequency as a value and
so for example if the page rank is high
you simply set the term frequency to 200
in the dictionary and then you can use
exactly that algorithms before to jump
over those documents which you are not
interested in so most of those fields
here have so-called feature queries
which are new in leucine
that was a long point and for the
lat/long point a distance feature query
that can be for example used to figure
out what to score based on the
the distance from from your center of
the map for example so that would be a
one possibility but in general those
queries always match all documents the
only only thing that those queries are
giving you is an additional score so
what you can do here is you just add
those feature queries as an additional
shoot clause to to you to your boolean
query and by that you get some
additional boost in the score but the
important thing is the actual selection
of the documents is done based on the
based on on the masked clauses and other
shoot clauses which are there so it
depends on how you build your boolean
queries so that makes it very easy to
separate scoring and and boolean query
logic another thing which is which
already started in 7.4 I think is for
people that love spam queries I have
heard that in one question before in the
talk before about this man queries so
everybody who liked span queries I know
a lot of people from the patent they
want to who know figure out find me all
documents where in the first 100 words
is electric and car and all that crazy
stuff so if you use span queries you
quickly figure out that they're very
very hard to use and Alan who is doing
the next talk started to work on
simplifying that there were some
problems for example that you were able
to combine span queries which were on
different field names which of course
cannot really work easy so the problem
is here now for if you have a complex
construction of span near queries and
span queries you now have only one query
which is an interval query and that
interval query can get it gets a lot of
so-called intervals where you can define
what you're actually querying the
simplest case is terms phrases or
ordered and all that stuff you can also
say to do something like a span near
query you can give a maximum width or
the maximum gap between
the terms and then you can build a query
this is for example in the vodka Valley
on the field so everything is going on
the same field then you have an interval
which is ordered or that means the terms
or the intervals coming later must be in
order that means here the first one
leucine must come first and then at some
point later in the document
there must be the terms foo and bar also
ordered so that means there must be
leucine foo and bar but between foo and
bar there should be so the length of
that should be sweet terms so that means
the cap in between must be limited so
they cannot be more far away than three
terms from each other and then you can
execute it so as you see here by by by
applying all those filters like
containing not contains not within you
can make your really complex query based
on on the under positions the those you
in the back where is are currently only
in the sent box of leucine Zoe are not
yet put in in the main char file but I
think elasticsearch in the next version
will already have a query parser for
souls so this looks how Jason would also
look like at the end so you would give
those intervals and can use that
unfortunately solar does not really have
support for that now but I think it will
come quite soon so that's one thing
another thing that came to leucine which
is a long ongoing issue because a lot of
people think that is a good idea to load
the index into the main memory and the
first thing that you think is the right
thing to do is to use the so called gem
directory which is err from the very
first version of leucine but this one is
really completely bad behaving for
productive use it was only added for
test K for test cases it has protein
congruence so if you do multiple
searches on the same Ram directory it
actually gets lower because you
a lot of concurrency and the other
problem is if you have a large index it
saves blocks F of 8192 by it so if you
have an index of several gigabytes you
can count the number of byte arrays you
have in your heap space and your garbage
collector is driving crazy and that's
not something what you want to have
because the idea was to have that only
for test cases and now I know some
people are using that in solar I think
in elastic structure has no possibility
to use them directly but so far smaller
test indexes it's fine but that is now
replaced in the new version by the
so-called PI professed directory which
is based on the MF directory which you
are using on disk for for index on this
indexes and that one is using the same
infrastructure so it's based on byte
buffers so it can also be of heap that
means you can also allocate by professor
directory of heap and it's sharing most
of the stuff in ternary so you can
actually replace REM directory by Piper
first directory in with a new Sula
version if you use I think REM directory
factory it will use implicitly
automatically that one but the name is
duplicated but that's something which is
interesting there are also some index
format improvements the first one you
already know it's a block Mac statistics
and skip lists which speeds up since
this tank these junctions but we also
have a skip list like structure for the
dock values now so that means if you
have a function query document based
queries can now jump to later talk IDs
with a constant time so the index gets a
little bit larger but that should speed
up those queries relying on scoring
factors in the dock values immense so
about how to microwave you see in Zevon
the index version since Lucene seven
there's an indexed version enforcement
so that means when an index is created
it stores the original version when the
first segment of that index was created
inside the index directory
and and it preserves that hearing
migration so that's something that which
is very important because that allows us
to do sort of an oil in X formats where
some provoking offsets like negative
offsets inside
we were also exchanging is the norms
datatype it's no longer a bate bite it I
think it's a long now Alan I think
something like yeah yeah it's a long
yeah exactly
so but the problem is if you have an old
index it makes it hard to update and
because of that there's a leucine eighth
anti feature which is complete removal
of leucine six in the extra part that
also effects older people and you know
from the previous talks I had in the
earlier years there was always the
possibility to use index upgrader to
raise the index to a higher version but
that's unfortunately no longer possible
because as I said before the minimum
index version is stored in the index so
it will immediately say no that's
impossible so you have to the index
elasticsearch supports re-indexing that
supports it because everything in in
Zoeller you have to figure out if all
your fields are stored and if they are
stored then you can do Rhian dexing but
there's no way around that but if you
really really really really really need
it there's a possibility to still do
that but you will lose correct scoring
so if you if you do some some low-level
code you can still waste and very very
old index even version 1.4 of leucine I
bought them already to version six it
works but if you analyzers are not
correct it won't really help you and
scrolling won't work anymore but
theoretically you can do that so there's
a possibility yeah in I think we have a
few more minutes yeah perfect
so we have some also some new features
and changes in in solar 8 I think the
most important one in my opinion because
most of the other features were all
the additive previous solar versions is
that starting with solar 8 the internode
communication but although the external
HD beacon connector can accept and
communicate using HTTP 2 so that means
by default it will use a new HTTP to
solar client to talk between the nodes
so all the internal requests are
automatically sent using HTTP 2 but the
back side of that is that solar 8 nodes
cannot talk to old nodes of course
because by default it tries to do HTTP 2
but the old solenoids cannot do that and
the most important thing is for
upgrading if you want to do rolling
upgrades you can start the new solar
version with a special system property
Solar HTTP 1 2 and then you can can
start your whole cluster replace one
node after the next one and once you
have done that you shut down all the
notes again well he start them enabling
the HTTP to connect or there's one other
thing is if you want to have TLS that
means encryption you are required to use
Yaba 9 and if you start solar on Yahveh
8 it will automatically disable HDB 2 if
you want to have an encrypted connection
there are also some changes in PM 25 the
solar users need to know about the
absolute scores will be lower but this
will not change the sort order in normal
cases but if you scheme a match version
is smaller than 8 Allegra's is going is
used and now we have the minimum Java
version which is Java a is so solar and
leucine stays on Java 8 as a minimum
version later versions work perfectly
you can easily upgrade there's a fix for
Hadoop coming Kappa was coming HTTP 2
requires number 9 there's also some
performance improvements if you're using
later version so at the moment it's the
commended to use maybe Java eleven so we
have moody release charts for that and
that's more less a final slide because
the support for Java 8 has ended three
days ago you should go to eleven in my
opinion and it's it's tested very good I
think so as the fine one solar eight
stays on Yahveh eight and in the master
branch we will likely switch to eight as
an eight to eleven as a minimum version
in the near future so the recommendation
SFP four is to use Java eleven which
should work perfectly with loose in
solar version eight
thank you I think we have one more
question yeah okay yeah
two peas okay three people okay so the
question yeah so the question was if
it's possible to plug in another ranking
function and it will still work with the
block max yes you can do that but the
ranking function me to need to confer
need to be compliant with the channel
ratings or if sit here goes up although
the score should go up so you can do
something which is completely different
but you can simply replace it and the
reason for that is because we are
storing not something like a max score
we are scoring the TF and the norm in
the index so you can use any scoring
function which allows that have a minute
yeah for what for testing we also
switched or that one so there's also a
replacement for testing which is simply
on heap so it behaves almost identical
to the RAM directory so yes yes so for
testing there's two byte buffers
directory you don't need to put it off
heap yeah yeah yeah it's it's it's gone
why is it gone yet
yeah yeah it's gone I've also shown
maybe it's in the test framework so far
surviving okay