okay next we have Simona minority who
will be talking about augmented network
visibility with the help of sub minute
resolution metrics thank you very much
or give'em and hello thanks for being
here today and yes in this presentation
we are going to see actually the
benefits of having high resolution
methods in the field of network
visibility and then in the second part
of this presentation we are going to try
and use open source software to build an
actual network visibility solution and
we will see an open G for the monitoring
graph Anna for the visualization and M
flux the beam for the store of data but
let's start with network visibility can
you hear me okay yeah so well let's
start with network visibility in general
network visibility is provided by means
of matrix this matrix can be simple
matrix such as the bites and packets
transmitted or received by a given host
or by a network there can be also other
matrix that include layer seven
application protocols for example the
amount of a YouTube traffic done by this
hosta or by this network but there there
can also be more complex metrics such as
moving averages exponentially weighted
averages this kind of matrix but the
point is that metrics are sampled this
means that there is no way to have a
hundred percent reliable accurate
representation of the real metric
because we only have samples
of the metric this means that had fix-it
interval of time we pick the value of
the metric so basically there is an
amount of time which is basically equal
to the sampling interval that is
completely unknown
this means that let's take this this
chart for example we have a metric and
it's evolution in time and we have two
samples s1 and s2 between s1 and s2
nothing is known nothing can be said we
don't have an idea of the behavior of
the metric between s1 and s2 so it could
have followed the green path the yellow
or the blue path but in practice
actually we don't know we have only s1
and s2 so it it's pretty clear now that
the shorter the sampling interval the
closer we can go to the actual metric
the closer we can go to the real metric
so it's beneficial to be able to reduce
this sampling interval let me show you
this with an example
in this example I'm going to transfer 10
gigabytes of traffic 2 times the first
time I'm going to transfer this 10 gigs
over a free link and the second time I'm
going to transfer the same 10 gigs over
a few Li utilized link and I would like
to show you what happens if we use
5-minute sample on one hand and
10-second samples on the other hand to
do this experiment and to make it
reproducible I'm going to use iperf to
send the data and enter pengie to
actually do the monitoring and we are
going to see an top energy
in detail later in this presentation so
let's start with a five-minute samples
the first bell-shaped prove that we see
in this chart is the metric of traffic
captured during the 10 gauge transfer
with a free link the second bell-shaped
curve is the same metric the same
traffic metric captured during the 10
gigs file transfer over the fully
utilized over the congested link do you
see any difference no the two
bell-shaped curve are the same so it's
completely undetectable the fact that
the link was congested if we use
5-minute samples let's see now what
happens if we go from five minutes to
ten seconds samples well as we can see
from this chart this is a different
story
the first file transfer
it's a beautiful straight transfer as we
see the the metric almost immediately
reaches the line rate of one gigabit per
second and it does the Stevie transfer
and it completes in a very short
interval of time if we look at the
transfer over the congested link that
that's really different because we see
that the throughput is not even one half
of the throughput done over the free
link and there's also a sawtooth
behavior that we can see in this chart
so you see going from five minute
samples down to ten seconds samples
actually unveils patterns that are
interesting and that are completely
unknown
this if we use 5-minute samples again
these two charts if you look at the time
at the time scale at the bottom these
two charts are two instances of a
monitoring tool that that running and
monitoring the same traffic but one is
taking samples at five minutes and the
other is taking samples at ten seconds
so why we should care about this well
there are many reasons that let's see we
should care about having an I resolution
for example to have a more accurate
representation of the throughput that is
received by our applications that use
the network because there are certain
applications that are sensitive to the
throughput for example void pickles or
video streaming this kind of application
have certain requirements in terms of
minimum throughput and if we can't
guarantee this kind of throughput then
the user experience can can worsen the
application performance can worsen so
being able to monitor the throughput in
an accurate way can help you in
improving or even providing a good
service for your applications similarly
another thing that you can do is to look
at bars bars that can go unnoticed if
you use five minutes on one minute
samples because bars are not really good
for the networks because bars tend to
feel the queues of your network elements
so they tend to introduce jitters or
increase the delays of the transmissions
so bars are not really good in the
networks and being able to spot them can
help you fix certain kind of issues ok
so now that we have seen the motivation
and the how useful it can be to have a
resolution matrix let's see how we can
build a solution
using open-source software what do we
need to be in this solution basically we
need three pieces of software we need a
software that can do the monitoring and
that can see the packets so it can
provide high resolution it can generate
high resolution matrix then we need a
data store a data store that is able to
ingest high resolution metrics and
provide timely response to the queries
because if we lose if we use high
resolution metrics we end up in
generating hundred millions of points
per day in real world networks in
corporate network so we need a really
good data store that can on the one hand
store the metrics and on the other hand
provide you response to your queries in
a in a timely way and least but not last
we need a visualization tool that can
show us the relevant behavior that can
allow us to do their drill down and to
detect or to analyze that analyze an
alert on our traffic so the solution we
have proposed is composed of three open
source software and token G for the
monitoring in flux DB for the store of
data and graph Anna for the
visualization I'm not going to go into
the details of in flux DB or graphing I
mean we have had Carl right before me so
what what I would like to focus now is a
hint open G and the monitoring tool
because I am one of the developers of
ant open G and I would like to tell you
how we brought an top ng from five
minutes samples down to ten seconds
samples for the generation of ten
seconds samples so n top ng is open
source you can fork it on github
and download and try it it's just an
open source software for the monitoring
of your network and we we have 3,300
stars now and github and Counting so
feel free to download it and test it so
the architecture event open G is
multi-threaded this means that basically
we have one thread that is reserved for
the capture of packets and then we have
other threads that run in parallel and
are reserved for the generation of
samples so in our recent activity in our
recent work we we extend those parallel
threads for the matrix generation and we
will change them so that they can
provide matrix at up to a resolution of
ten seconds so we were using our these
other these are another store for matrix
based on plain text files so based on
files that is basically used if you want
simple in the order of minutes basically
otherwise you it will be too slow so we
extended enter pengie to produce 10
second samples and to push those samples
to the influx the B database so how easy
is to set up and configure and top ng to
generate ten-second samples of your
traffic using influx DB well it's pretty
easy because you just visit the
configuration I'm going to show you a
quick demonstration in a while but it's
pretty easy you just visit the
Preferences event open G you setup the
URL of influx DB a database name and you
are done and open G will start pushing
data into influx DB and on the other
hand if you want to build
your dashboards using Groff Anna for
example what you have to do is only add
a data source to graph Anna and influx
the B data source to actually connect to
the same database used by ant open G in
flux DB host database name and you are
done with graph Anna you can start
playing you can start doing experiment
in creating dashboards for example and
as we can see in these in these two
charts have recreated the same dashboard
of the of the the file transfers that we
created the same dashboard using graph
on and as we can see obviously there's a
hundred percent match between the two
charts because pure fauna and ant open G
are both pulling data from in flux DB
for the visualization the other
interesting thing that you can do with
graph Anna is the alerting alerting that
now you can bring down to ten seconds
resolution this means that you can
evaluate condition every ten seconds so
you can set an easy an easy threshold if
you have if you want to monitor a web
server you can set thresholds to be
timely alerted if the traffic of your
web server goes above a certain
threshold or goes below a certain
threshold the point here the interesting
thing here is that you can create others
with a an evaluation frequency of ten
seconds so you can receive a
notification you can receive an email
very very quickly when something happens
let me show you now a quick demo I want
to show you how easy is to set up this
kind of ten-second monitoring using our
using the tools
okay so here I'm going to start on top
ng which is the first tool for the
monitoring of data do not look at the
other options that are not really
relevant for these for this demo the the
interesting thing here is that we are
going to run an top ng using interface E
and O one I'm going to start it so now
it's it has started monitoring the
traffic on this laptop so now I'm
basically monitoring the network traffic
that my laptop here is doing from and to
the Internet
yeah because I need to start now I can
also start influx to be same thing so
now yes
I've started influx DB so aunt open G is
generating ten-second samples and
posting them to the influx to be running
on the same host third I also run graph
Anna because I would like to to see the
dashboard in in action okay so let's see
what happened I can point my browser to
local Austin I have created dashboard
here here we are
so this is a dashboard that I have
created using the graph Anna and
connecting to the influx DB that is
storing our ten second samples of the
traffic I created a dashboard that that
is showing me the throughput of the
network interface and
traffic of certain relevant application
protocols including DNS Dropbox and
Google so this is the traffic what I can
do now is to create something more
interesting maybe I can set a time
interval of now - five minutes and I can
create can set refresh of five seconds
so this dashboard is going to refresh
every five seconds and let's see if we
can generate some interesting traffic
let me do I'm going to download an ISO
of Ubuntu and if I go back to the
dashboard I we will we see that the
throughput has increased to almost 60
megabits per second and you also have
the throughput in bytes in packets shown
right into a graph on a dashboard you
can use graph on I mean the fan is a
very useful way to create your own
dashboards and you can pull also metrics
from other data sources so you are not
limited to the use of Antep ng because
maybe you have another data source that
is monitoring the number of requests and
response of your web application so you
can combine in the same dashboard the
chart of the interface throughput with
the chart of your HTTP requests for
example to detect certain kind of
anomalies or to detect peaks in the HTTP
or in their response errors of your of
your application so yes it's pretty it's
pretty
it's almost everything what I wanted to
to show you now so let me wrap up so we
have seen that having high-resolution
metric can unveil certain patterns that
go that are unknown or unnoticeable if
we use five-minute samples or if we use
lower resolution samples if you want to
build your own monitoring solution you
can do that using open source software
and top energy influx the being Ravana
and least but not last we are growing
and we are hiring so if you are
interested if you like networks if you
love packets let's contact us I mean we
will be around the whole day so contact
us you can work from remote we are based
in Italy but you can work from remote if
you want so contact us and we can start
doing something together that is my
email thanks for your time if you have
questions I am here so please feel free
to
[Music]
[Applause]
yes okay let's wait the Mac okay hi so
on the demo you showed applications in
the graph like Dropbox and Google yeah
how do you distinguish that and do you
have to create a dashboard to filter for
that specific application or can it be
dynamically populated or so ant open G
has an engine which is code which is
called the deep packet inspection it
performs a deep packet inspection of the
real traffic packets to detect the
actual protocol that is flowing in that
particular time so let me show you this
I can edit this stuff and as you see I
do an influx the big query on the deep
packet inspection is dpi and I can
change the protocol and here I have all
my protocols that have been detected by
ant open G so I can pick another one I
can pick HTTP I can pick Google github
or whatever you want Instagram so you
create the dashboard of the layer seven
application protocols that are
traversing your network
so those are application protocols so
this means that is the layer seven
payload so it's not a layer 4 protocol
such as TCP or UDP it's the actual
application carried in the layer 7
I question I'm the interval at the end
top agent pushes the 10-second interval
measurements to the influx DP is it
still five minutes or as well as 10
seconds no you can choose that you can
choose them okay
Emily the measurement interval but also
the portion the vault okay because it
collects every 10 seconds the the
interface statistics and it pushes that
the statistics to the database yes every
10 seconds or every five more the push
is basically every 10 seconds also they
push the data you can control the flash
but the point is that statistics are
every 10 seconds so you may see them
with a little bit of delay in the
database but once they are in the
database they are 10 seconds ok so
questions how are you doing down
sampling of data and influx DB if you
are doing down Sam yeah we are doing
down sampling we are using continuous
queries this is one of the latest
development yeah you like to only save
them to some other data source time
metric in in flux DB and then you have
to select another data source to see the
historical metrics or what yeah yeah
that's true that's true yeah
and I smell so obviously we are saying
is 10 seconds is better than 5 minutes I
assume then it's not necessarily better
it could be useful get more resolution
yeah example and then every 1 second is
more resolution than 10 seconds yeah
what are the main sticking points or
problems going lower and lower
resolution well the lower you can go the
the more close to the real metrics you
can get the point is do you really need
to go so close to the real metric the
answer is it depends it depends on what
you are looking there is a phenomenon
that is called micro bars so micro bars
because they happen at a micro seconds
during micro seconds events so they can
create troubles in the network as well
you could be interested in inspecting
micro bars if you if you need to inspect
microbots yes you need to go to the
microsecond resolution so you need other
time stamping you need dedicated network
art you can do that so it depends it
depends the answer is it depends so the
higher the resolution the more you can
see this is for sure but it depends you
can be happy also with five minutes and
I don't know it depends
this is plain Ethernet sniffing let's
say yeah did you see the Watson overlay
networks like big slam and stuff like
what the excellent yes
I mean provided that you can access the
traffic you can do this kind of
monitoring to do these 10 second samples
you need the traffic so if you have a
overlay network through a week slam you
can do that provided that you can find a
way to feed and top ng with the traffic
that you want to monitor
hello so you are not working with air
are the fights anymore right
say it again you are not working with
RRD files anymore right
no it's an you can choose that it's a
it's an option you can choose if you
want to use our deal or if you want to
use in proximity okay both of them are
support okay about the alerts do you
send them to enter Pandey from graph
owner graph ana has another thing engine
built in and ant open G has another
alerting engine built in you can do
email slack notification this kind of
alert so you can create them in an open
G or in Griffin yeah I mean it's up to
you yeah and as an Turpin G is an open
source solution I don't know if you have
these information but do you know how
much host is enterprises monitoring with
on top in G how does it scale yeah it
scales up to tens of thousand holes
inside the enterprise it can monitors
many more hosts but if you have an
enterprise you are interested in having
more information for those inside the
network so ant open G divides the hosts
between your enterprise network and the
rest of the world so this is done for
the for efficiency basically to save
memory and to for the efficiency of the
software so it can scale up let's say to
40 50 thousand enterprise host plus a
hundred thousand horse outside your
network your enterprise net but you use
different instances of enter pangaean or
you one for 550 thousand hosts yeah and
then if you want to monitor or more you
need to set up another one
yes yes you can set up parallel parallel
incision yeah but they don't talk with
each other right they won't talk with
each other
okay thank you just a note I know you
guys are not and gals are not aware of
this but if you keep talking in the back
in front this is relatively loud course
this room has really good or bad
acoustics we can debate this but please
keep it quiet thank you a question
related to a previous one if you have
her experimented with use cases where
the resolution is very fine-grained like
in milliseconds or something and if yes
which are the most critical aspect to be
considered in this kind of workflow and
architecture in this kind specific kind
of use cases because the data volume
could grow yes considerably actually I
didn't work on the on millisecond scales
so I didn't even try to push data into
influx DB and charge them here at apana
so I don't have an answer we have worked
on we have worked on microbots but not
using this dissolution so I don't have
an exact answer for this
Thanks hi thanks for the talk I'm just
wondering if you're doing a lot of
high-frequency sampling how does that
scale in terms of resources what way is
it managing ROM or CPU usage now say it
again I'm just wondering if you're doing
a lot of high-frequency sampling what
way does it scale in terms of resources
how are you handling likes of RAM or CPU
usage if you're doing a lot of that
sampling so the point is that ant open G
is real-time so it sees all the packets
the fact that we are generating samples
at ten seconds at it's not really
pushing more pressure and top ng wise
because it is already processing and
inspecting every single packet so the
point is just running another trend that
every 10 seconds crunches some
statistics which is not really what
impacts the performance of the software
of all of Antep ng influx ly be wise I
can really tell you the impact I didn't
do certain performance or load
miseration where if we go from five
minutes to ten seconds so includes to be
wise I can really tell you and open G
wise I can tell you that this is not
what is putting the highest pressure on
on the software because entropy ng per
se is real-time so in it already sees
every single packets and it inspects
every single packet that is monitored
any other question
hey so thanks for your time
[Applause]
[Music]
you