as you can see I'm working for Red Hat
group you know after this fancy behind
this fancy name which doesn't mean a lot
I'm gonna talk about the integration
between unstable and often daylight and
more specifically specifically ansible
networking so this is a little bit of
the agenda
what is up in daylight what is sense
about please raise your hands and you
know what it's open daylight and ansible
are pretty good so I can go much quicker
then the third point we're going to talk
about the integration between those two
these two technologies and then I'm
going to show a video of a demo so the
will there will not be hands on actually
but what is it in daylight it's an open
source project it was created with all
these Sdn wave and one of the
definitions that I like the most about
opportunities that is like the
middleware for for network services
right so it's not just an SDN controller
is it's a kind of a platform to create
network services
Red Hat was a platinum founding member
of the project and it was it's quite
interesting because the presentation
from last Louis is that the architecture
is pretty much the same and so you will
understand easier
the heart of the open daylight is this
blue box here which is called end
dissolve model driven service
abstraction layer and what it allows you
to do is to model your network service
via a language called yang where you can
define attributes RPC calls or any kind
of parameter and there will be some
rendering of this model into Java
classes that are ready to be implemented
right it also provides
the databases like we have two different
data stores configuration and operation
operational data store and on top of
that we have what it's called not my own
applications so we have you can do many
things with it
we have kubernetes networking management
we have service function chaining
network utilization and applications
there's plenty of them and in the south
of this blue box below we have what we
call cellphone plugins or protocols so
we have open flow of ESD be BGP and so
on
and what we want to do here what we want
to show you is basically a prototype but
it could be quite promising is to
integrate unstable as one of these
cellphone plugins and now why ansible
mainly because you know is one of the
fastest-growing projects I think in the
in the last decade there's a huge
community is very simple to use
like great in a playbook
which is like a recipe of test that you
want to automate is very very easy
there's thousands of modules to to use
unlike puppet or chef you don't need an
agent on the target machine that you
want to automate and and it's very
powerful you can automate servers
storage and what we are going to talk
about here Network Devices so there are
like 50 more than 50 platforms supported
and 700 modules something like that for
just ansible networking and of course
it's not only switches and routers you
can also there are load balancers and
any other kind of platform the way
ansible is a structure we have play
books which are there recipes where you
grab your your tasks that you want to
automate and then some rows which is
like a group of of tests around same
topic let's say and in enhance opponent
working we have function roles and
provided rows
I'm going to explain better with with an
example the demo is going to be
about creating an l3 VPN between two
endpoints two routers so our function
role is basically to create a VPN or
delete a VPN and that's very simple that
that's something that everyone
understands and you don't to care so
much about how it's going to be
implemented the implementation details
are embedded into the provider roles so
imagine you have a lab with
heterogeneous hardware so with you you
have Cisco's and juniper and another
vendor comes for example Dell and says
hey I will give you a very good deal
with this bunch of hardware take it
because the only thing that you want to
you have to provide or the vendor will
have to provide is the provided role for
for the same function for creating the
VPN so the beauty of unseeable
networking is that you get an
abstraction layer and the user doesn't
need to care about the implementation
details and the provider roles will
connect to the devices and configure
whatever is need to be configured so the
integration is mainly these two boxes
here we are using ansible towers a GUI
to interface with open daylight just not
to sin like res conf calls vs VI but the
important part is here and Sybil is is a
stateless right and it was meant to be
like that
the thing is from the network operator
standpoint you need some kind of state
you need to have to know the state of
the network and ansible can cover the
management plane of of them of the
network but not the control plane is not
an SDM and that's what the what
opendaylight provides it provides state
provides network topology so I think
that the combination could be very very
powerful so the demos about creating an
l3 VPN this is all running in one server
it's butyl I stand we have a bunch of
virtual machines these four boxes that
you see here are acting as PD routers
and which are the routers that are in
the service provider network
and we are assuming that some underlying
connectivities is provided like MPLS and
BGP and so on so these PD rotors will
have customer premises routers connected
to them and and from unstable tower we
will instruct opendaylight to create a
VPN between two of these pirate so one
once the the VPN is created we will be
able to see two of these sea routers
being able to to ping each other right
so in the end what it will do
opendaylight will knowing the topology
will execute l3 VPN unstable road and
the provider roads will connect to for
example the Cisco boxes it doesn't
matter is if the boxes are brutalised or
or physical and will configure the vrf
the interface the IP in their interface
that is connected to the C router and so
on
so this is the personal workflow but I'm
gonna show you in the video because I
don't have so much time
okay can you see more or less yeah
okay I can explain anyway it's okay no
problem
so this screen is showing the CLI of the
terminal of to seed of the to see
routers these are the routers that are
in the customer premises or at home
right and if you can see here we have
this IP 10.10.5.3 to 2005 different
networks so what we are going to do like
I'm showing that that IP and I'm gonna
try to ping each other
okay Bing doesn't work
so this is unseeable tower it's like GUI
to manage unstable play books and roles
and things like this what we have here
are different templates job template is
like basically one playbook let's say
and a workflow template is a chain of
different job templates so what we are
going to do is execute the configure
side template and we will pick two the
two endpoints of the l3 VPN we have a
bunch of parameters like the site name
the IP of the peer outer of the
interface that the P writer places to
the C router so what we are doing here
is pushing information to open daylight
from the first side now we are going to
execute the same with the second side
the other endpoint okay we change the
VPN ID doesn't change because it would
be just one
we change the name of the node
okay it's executed you can see like
unstable tower provides logs and and
everything is it's pretty cool now we
will execute the manager through VPN
service will which will do it will push
the information to open daylight to to
create the the Bellevue PA this is a sky
dive is another open-source tool that
allows you to monitor the network and as
you can see this is the underlying
infrastructure so the box is connected
and this is the VPN with it and there is
no links between between these these
items so now once we execute sorry we
execute the manage else will be n it
will create the VPN it will associate
into the boxes configure the vrf the IP
in the interfaces and so on I'm gonna
get a little bit
now see the create l3 VPN is in green
now we are pinging if it's correct
and suddenly the pinion starts working
right so now let's see that the l3 VPN
will be established and and the people
connected to this serial router will be
able to connect to the other side of the
network and they're definitely drawing
is disconnected now you can see the
interfaces so that there's a bunch of
information that I'm sorry for going so
quickly but that's basically any
question I will be outside