hello and welcome to our talk we are
meters and soar and delight and offer
we work for Red Hat we are on the
OpenStack ironic team our talk is is
called bare metal and the cloud isn't it
ironic in this talk we're going to
explain what the bare metal provisioning
is and why it has become an increasingly
important these days we will introduce
you the ironic project and it's placed
on the cloud landscape and it's working
based on a simple on the trivial
workflow example in the end of this talk
we'll will give you a glimpse of what
the future holds for ironic the idea
behind bare metal provisioning bare
metal allocation is a simple the idea is
to let the cloud user to request and
subsequently receive the bare metal
machine the physical machine in the very
same way as they do for virtual machines
the reasons for for this desire amania
just to name a few
some applications rely on hard to
visualize Hardware like like GPU or FPGA
some applications deal with sensitive
data and therefore require a perfect
tenant isolation for security reasons
some applications just need the raw
computer computing power among all these
reasons one of the emerging one I would
say is the desire to manage the cloud
infrastructure itself because in the end
the cloud is a software and it is
running on the bare metal and when I
have a large cloud a large set of
computers automating all the all things
bare metal all since deployment makes a
huge win the ironic project is a bare
metal provisioning or orchestration
agent service its
it's it's it's it's it's a web service
it's it's a peer driven it's shipped
with with the CLI and graphical user
interfaces it's it's quite old it's been
around for 500 around five or four years
it's been used by many many cloud
operators around the world that probably
explains why it has quite active and
diverse upstream community and many
contributors
besides that been a hardware management
tool ironic enjoys deep and wide vendor
support vendors join the upstream effort
they contribute the drivers for the
hardware to make their hardware
compatible with with ironic ironic
started its life as a as a fork of
OpenStack novice bare metal driver since
then it has grown into a standalone
don't say sophisticated tool it can be
used as a standalone tool for for
hardware provisioning for whatever
purpose or it can be used with an open
step in any in any of these
configurations the ironic system
consists of the artist raishin agent
called her any conductor as a deployment
agent which is running inside the bare
metal machine when deployed and the
restful api for for communicating with
the world
if ironic is used with within the
OpenStack cloud then Noah has to have
the ironic driver
often times how more often than not the
hardware the server's designed for data
center use they are not just the
motherboards they are accompanied by a
small satellite computer called BMC
waste board management controller this
computer is always up it's always on the
network and most importantly it has very
intricate relationship with the main
system it can manage it in in many
different ways
inside this BMC computer there is a
agent or software running in to control
it
this software is communicating with the
world by means of a special designed
Hardware management protocol there there
were many protocols in the past the most
modern perhaps and emerging protocol is
called redfish and it is rapidly
displacing the previous King ipmi and
many other vendors specific protocols
because vendor surrenders they everyone
has to come up with its own protocol for
that thing BIM she can do many things
the most important one once I would say
is the ability to power cycle the system
that is to control power remotely and
changing boot configuration to the to
boot system from at least from the
network or from a local Drive
more sophisticated bmc's can do magical
things they can change change BIOS BIOS
configuration on the machine they can
deal with hardware raid configuration
they can use virtual media boot which is
a way to boot a machine from virtual CD
with the image supplied by the res
operator and many other things we are
going to explain how ironic works based
on the machine bare metal machine
lifecycle we to make it more easier to
explain we separated this lifecycle into
pieces the preparation deployment and
the teardown
the preparation steps step starts with
with so called inspection
whenever ironic becomes aware of of the
bare metal machine to manage it can
there's are more information about it
meaning the hardware configuration of
abilities of this machine which is
useful for scheduling for for picking
the machine out of menu and possibly for
for inventor information for putting
this machine into the context of of the
whole data center inventorying
inspection can be done in with ironic
inspection can be done in one in two
ways one is called out-of-band
and the other in bent the out-of-band
inspection is based on a Munich on
communicating with with the BMC so our
only goes out and talks to BMG and dust
BMC what what kind of machine is is
what's its serial number what is CPU
what what what kind of memory has the in
been inspection is performed by the
ironic agent running into the inside the
RAM disk which is booted inside into the
my into the machine been being inspected
so ironic boots this Ram disk around the
the ironic agent and then the
orchestration agent there any conductor
tops to this embedded ironic agent
inside the machine and gathers all this
information all the above information
and beyond that ironic agent can run
benchmarking it can it can listen on the
network for say LGD frames to learn to
which switchport this machine is is
connected to Spartan once the inspection
is over the next step which by the way
can be run many times at different
antique on textures is known as cleaning
cleaning can also be done in in band and
out out of band ways the idea of
cleaning is to make sure that Machine
been deployed is like new it can be
recycled from previous installation but
our goal here
is to make sure that every time you
deploy a new machine it's it's the same
during the cleaning phase what ironic
pen do is to reset BIOS settings or
applying new bios settings reassemble
the hardware eight updated firmware the
these things are probably more often
done out-of-band in with in bentley in
what we can do with hand wipe our local
drives from inside which is easy we can
sometimes deal with hardware or software
raids it depends on the on the machine
and hardware by the end of this cleaning
cycle we we have like new machine
factory reset machine and with this I'm
passing my tool
okay now we have a pool of machines all
cleaned all ready for deployment
Oh marvelous uniform what happens when
you deploy of course is you start with
speaking a bare-metal machine for your
deployment historically we have been
relying on the OpenStack computer
service for this goal but its upcoming
release we're going to introduce our own
API for picking a machine based on a
certain simple criteria its class and
its traits now that after you've picked
the Machine the deployment starts you
connected to the deployment network
which is a network where's the
deployment edge and we're on you
configure the boot of the deployment
right ramdux
by a pixiv our virtual media I'll go
into some details a bit later
the deployment agent starts and
orchestrated by the ionic conductor it
does actions like partitioning the
target device flashing the image
configuring local boot maybe some custom
actions when it's done we disconnect the
deployment network we connect the
networks that were requested for the
instance it may be one or more the
configures the booting of the final
instance again let boot or local boot
and we reboot and as a final instance at
this point you can use it let's cover a
few topics in depth networking as I
mentioned we have two kinds of networks
we we operate with they have service
networks which are used for cleaning
which is for provisioning for process
called rescue for inspection I
essentially anything that happens in
band and have 10 ad networks that are
the network that you request it for your
machines and I have three network
management models in ionic first you can
use your infrastructure
whatever you have in your data center we
can use it you have to pre-configured
DHCP to boot the deployment ramdisk and
you have to request your instances with
local boot so every time the net boots
they get deployed every time you boot
from rakhumai these because you just get
into instance we have good cooperation
with the OpenStack networking service
called Neutron we can use it in two
modes with shared network when
essentially for all networks are flat
and are shared between
print machines in this case want to use
new trend for DHCP options and for pizza
configuration and the most interesting
of all of this we can integrate with
Neutron for advanced switch management
in this case we can ask Neutron to put
ports to which the switch boards to
which the machine is connected to on
different VLANs essentially allowing
integration with virtual machines
running on OpenStack compute allowing
tenant isolation isolation between
service and tenant networks which is
quite important to make sure for example
your tenants cannot access your control
plane and cannot access each other after
the boot configuration I mentioned pixie
which is an old old technology based on
TFTP protocol and this when you provide
ECB options for a machine to boot from
certain Network location which we
support I pick C which is an improvement
on pixie using HTTP instead of less
reliability FTP more interesting as we
mentioned we support virtual media which
allows ironic to talk to the BNC to
instruct it to boot your machine from an
ISO image located on HTTP NFS share
ironic has a quite decent support of ufi
including support with secure boot in
certain scenarios we also suffer type ID
bias and UEFI images with supports
grating partitioning table for ufi and
for bias including some rare cases
accusing GP TVs bias versus legacy boot
story
when we deploy the images again we have
several options see orchestrated using
this ironic agent Raonic in band on the
machine and a temporal in memory ram
disk the old way was for the agents to
create a nice cozy target and for
conductor to connect to this target and
to flash the image you a more reliable
way which we have supported for quite
some time is for the agents to pull the
image of HTTP from your HTTP server or
from the OpenStack suite
servers if can done can do in memory
conversion if but if the image is raw
image already we can stream it directly
to the blog device allowing any to skip
any caching in memory this is quite
efficient we are looking into supporting
big torrents to simplify small taneous
boot of many machines with large heavy
images over may be less reliable network
so if you're interesting in this come
contribute we need help other features
that I'm not going to go into details
are firmware updates for certain vendors
serial console support for your Roenick
instances rescue mode which you can boot
a ram disk right from your instance and
example if you need to repair it because
it does not boot anymore can boot around
this association to each mounted disks
during the reparation and then return
the instance into operation
we support port groups which is port
bonding essentially and the thing we are
working on a thing called deploy
templates which is very interesting way
to run the same preparation of steps we
use for cleaning like building great but
during deploy time on demand for example
user absorbance that computer will be
able to say building rate get me an
instance with this rate rate template
and you'll get it and ironically
automatically build this rate for you
and returning instances rate already
built then you will not need to have a
pool pool of machines with specific rate
or bias or any configuration and you
have a kind of graphical consoles
essential allowing you to VNC into your
instance we also researching new use
cases where we would certainly like your
input on HIPAA converged infrastructures
and contain your engines which use
ironic as a satellite service for
scaling up scaling down of installation
I know people are working on could
donates integration for ironic for
example as a I forgot the term but yeah
for essentially as part of the cluster
API we are looking h architectures and
various approach to make our own work
better and highly distributed
geographically
budget environments including attempts
to improve at attempts of Federation of
ironic across geographical locations and
that's it
come learn more from our documentation
it's quite extensive come talk to us we
have a mailing list OpenStack discuss
come talk to our C channel we are very
friendly we don't bite
of course we welcome contributions but
have very active community will like to
review a code we want to hear about you
your skis cases it's quite important for
us to know what people would like to use
ironic for how they would like to use it
that will allow us to plan our features
next any questions
so how does ironic boots when we have
ufi I saw so as far as I remember there
is an option and it's actually used on
installation ISOs of others Linux
distributions to create a universal
directory search boots which I forgot
but how to not boot what is already
installed so all be MCS another feature
at six most an APM Irish and everything
to configure the boot sequence it's
possible in legacy mode is possible
unified sometimes different in this mode
but we abstract it all for you so we
tell it to boot from network or boot
from virtual media with this I saw or
boot from local disk we can control that
yes that's a big pain point for ah yeah
sorry how do we make sure that the
tenant did not mess up the film where
this is a different difficult topic and
essentially I know that public cloud
providers who use or used to use ironic
yes there are public cloud providers who
use ironic they cooperated with vendors
to make sure that is not possible
because it is kind of like catch-22 here
we can't update firmware from ironic we
can reset bias but if something from
inside already messed it up it can just
ignore our requests so there's no like
golden view here if you tell us a
completely untrusted you have to
cooperate with vendors to make sure you
can disable this messing up your
firmware provision yes sometimes
is it possible to deploy run across
OpenStack yes it is aware it has been
possible for quite some time when we
work on improving that for example I'm
working to make the dependence on
rabbitmq is a medium optional and I have
a patch for that there is a project
called Bifrost which allows deploying
qur'anic wizard OpenStack you can deploy
only Chris Sam OpenStack bits pick
Keystone and neutron or but without
grants using HTTP locations but yes it's
very possible and very very interested
in people doing that and giving feedback
I joined here I'm sorry
yeah of course HTTP is also supported
and you can provide custom certificates
for that and I should be proxy settings
as well
similarities and contradictions with
Foreman project so I haven't looked in
Forman in-depth to be honest there are
certainly quite some overlap in
provisioning part I think less overlap
in lifecycle part as far as I know like
bias and this you know all the things
about returning instance so we our
mission is a bit more towards serving
parameters to you to clients like in a
bit of a cloud approach even without
opens text you and like API driven
uniform is because as cleaning features
I think Forman is a bit more like tied
to a suiting installation approach but
again part of my ignorance I may be
missing something nice so whether we
plan to use the OpenStack placement
service for picking a bare-metal node
both the answer is both the work I'm
doing allows two backends for as this we
called allocation API it can be data
base base for the case when people don't
want to displacement but my next plan is
to use placement as well because if you
allow ironic standalone API to be used
without conflicts with another computer
API on the same set of the same pool of
bare metal old so yes we plan on that
contributions welcome by the way
anything
do we get a lot of jokes about our
nickname oh yeah and we make a lot of
jokes about ironic isn't it ironic
anything else
yeah yeah the question is about some
project that efficient that can I hear
the name digital rebar oh no I haven't
heard about that okay if no questions no
thank you
come talk to us
[Applause]