so shall we start
great welcome everyone thank you very
much for coming so early on Sunday so
Raleigh you had some part yesterday
night so well my name is Daniel Akira
I'm one of the founders of of eternia I
would like to talk about gender
diversity gap I've been doing this
analysis across several communities in
the penstock Foundation good morning in
the linux kernel and some other analysis
and then i did a similar stuff or the c
python interpreter a couple of years ago
in the Python Spain so I said well what
if I extend the analysis for the whole
repositories that we have in it habit
comes last Python so this is basically
what what this is in general part of the
presentation is about numbers but I
would say forget about the numbers
because we all know that the issue that
we are talking about and it's about how
to becoming more inclusive and how to
create more tapirs communities right so
this all started in Tokyo why in Tokyo
it was during an openness tax a meet
like in 2015-2016 and basically the
openness documentation tweeted something
like a we have a thirteen percent of
women attending the conference and
that's a great number by the way in
terms of if you are comparing this with
others and how the progression of the of
the penstock foundation but they had
another to it asked him for but how many
of them are doing technical
contributions so that was basically the
problem we wanted to solve in terms of
can we measure this is this possible in
time how so well part of the motivation
I already mentioned this but another
reason for this is basically that there
is some kind of lack of existing data at
least of the worst of my understanding
I'm not aware of any data set telling
from a cognitive perspective in terms of
measuring comets and so on in the Python
community telling of we have this
percentage of under represented set of
people in in the Python community if if
you are aware of this please let me know
of course this is a matter of
transparency because if we are
transparent as we are basically
published in the source code and
everything why not this aspect of the
community right so this is a matter of
learning from the best communities the
best companies or the lessons learned in
the industry and how can we improve our
own community in terms of diversity and
inclusion of course there is an ethical
and business perspective ethical from
the point of view that we as a community
we are producing things but we are
producing things for for the world right
and the world is basically if we let me
limit all of these to fifty percent of
women fifty percent of men right of
course
gender is not something binary this is
another limitation of the study but if
we go for this so we are producers and
we have consumers right but most of the
producers are men so what's going on
here from a business perspective
basically the more diverse communities
and there are basically studies by HBR
Harvard Business Review and similar
magazines and they say that the the
innovation is increased by a certain
percentage thirty something as far as I
remember and that's a lot so basically
the more different people we bring to
try to solve a problem the more
different point of view will have to
solve the same problem right so that's
the point here so I went to the Python
site and said well what's the definition
of diversity by the Python people and we
are taking out all of this if you see
the ball think there we are taking T
stock is TS about gender diversity okay
so we can talk about age or national
origin geographical graphical location
and a lot of things politics bah bah
blah blah so this is how the Python
Software Foundation defined as what this
is our diversity statement some more
context here about what diversity is and
now I'm bring in examples from the
industry so the top left basically is
Pinterest they say or they are claiming
that well our workforce technical
workforce is around nineteen percent
okay this is the number in terms of
Google the top right they are claiming
similar percentage so 18% of the
technical workforce are women within
Google then we have in the bottom left
Facebook where this is around yet for
all of the employees they have a 32%
while the technical task force is 16%
and then we have pivotal on the bottom
right where they claim that they have
25% in general okay so we have numbers
between 15 and 25% to have this in mind
when I started is these are the numbers
so this this is the population of women
participating in in some communities so
this is OpenStack foundation we have 11%
women participate in the Linux kernel
around 10% Hadoop Becker system so it's
not only Hadoop but other projects it's
around 8% there's a Python interpreter
in this case is 4% but again forget
throughout the numbers it's not a matter
of comparing if we are we have higher or
lower numbers than other communities but
it's a matter that these are the numbers
and if you check this with the previous
numbers there's a difference there's a
gap but the same companies that are
claiming that with indigenization they
have a 20 25 percent 15 percent they we
go to the openness open source
communities and they only have like a 10
percent eight percent so why this gap
well first I don't know and if you have
any clue about this please you have an
idea or comments let me know as well so
there is this gap and of course we have
this gap between the steal women are
underrepresented in technology even in
in the high tech companies okay so how
how are we doing this from a technical
perspective so the project is Lamar
laughs that's the logo on the top left
what I have another I should have some
link in the next slides the first thing
we are using this perceiver so Percival
is basically the tool to retrieve
everything this is now supporting of
course the all of this is open source
first of all is basically the tool
retrieving everything what you get at
the very end is a JSON document so you
don't have to think about API is logs
whatever you get
JSON document that's all right then
another important tool here is sorting
hat sorting hat is basically the tool to
manage identities if you think for
instance about OpenStack foundation
they've had something like seven or
eight thousand different people
committing into the source code so
that's a big amount of information right
so how to manager of identities
affiliations different people moving
from company to company the country the
gender so all of this is managed by
sorting hat you have a command-line
interface there is an API we are now
migrating this to graph QL so there's no
need for a REST API evil of a plan but
it's sir and then we have committed Kiba
Teresa soft fork of Cabana with certain
plugins we are using here let's say that
the previous tool so all of these since
elasticsearch to the left everything
it's it's it's our so in terms of the
grimoire lab the pro yet while we are
taking advantage of elasticsearch and
given given as a fork in this case sake
Witter has a specific plugins and
widgets that we we produce again open
source you're more than welcome to play
with this just an example of helper
several works it's as simple as this so
you take percival you specify the
specific data source that you want
analyze in this case we want analyze get
and then you have the URL for the git
repository it's done your Stargate in
JSON documents it's as easy as that and
how is this so this is a JSON this is an
example of a JSON document it's a
reduced version of this so if you think
of a commit what kind of information we
have there so we have the outdoors we
have the committee we have the date of
the alpha we have the date of the
committee so we we can have reviewers
for instance like also those might be
the commuters at some point we have the
files that were modified we have for
those files the code chunk so
specifically the lines that were added
or removed or modified we have the
number of added lines are removed and
all of this so what we are doing in this
analysis it's basically we enrich this
information with certain with other
types of information in this case we we
have the gender how are we analyzing the
gender so
if you think about the problem of this
and this is the first question I had on
the table when I was in Turkey if you
remember was how can we calculate
technical contributions so we try to
approach this in the simplest way at all
that was can we guess take a gender of
sang one somehow with the first name we
said maybe so it happens that there are
some let me go to gender eyes this is an
API that we are using this is not ours
this is an existing service around there
and basically you are asking for you say
a can you give me the gender of Peter
and they say yeah and there Peter is a
male with certain probability and you
say okay that may work then it happens
unlikely that most of the developers in
the open-source communities are coming
from the west side of the world so the
US Canada have South America and not
that many and then we are in Europe and
then we have some in Asia so typically
or at least the numbers we have is
depending on the project like eighty
percent the total amount of information
is done by West countries and somehow so
then we are dealing with West names so
that's great because in this case it's
quite it's quite reliable the kind of
data produced by generalized at i/o so
this is the way we are using this and
sorting had just the what I mentioned
before is so basically we have a set of
identities and then it happens that each
of us if you are participating in get
you are using an email address and it's
probably much different from the
nickname you having it HAP and it's
probably different from the Nick you
have in some other platforms Twitter's
and so on so there is some process to
merge all of the entities and so on so
this is done by by sorting here okay and
while affiliates assemble and the same
for gender so what I wanted to show you
now are some numbers so I'll go for the
live demo I produce a dashboard so let's
go for this so this is this is cavana
welcome Peter in this case we have we
have produced certain things like the
top menu on the right and well certain
we just said we have
so let's focus in first place here in
this chart so basically this is telling
us hey this is a whole life of the
community so we have the last 25 years
if you click there again this is a good
habit on its last Python this is what we
are analyzing in this case so we have
130 something coming it's Moo blah and
then we have this commits by gender and
they put the population by in the right
of course there is a certain percentage
of people that were were unknown in the
in the sense that basically what I was
doing was I have a list of developers I
go for the first for the main developers
order basically and then I go through
them checking so there is had a lot of
manual effort and a lot of coffee and
someone involved here Lou is indeed
there were helping me a lot with this so
this needs some data creation process it
takes time but the important thing is
that all of the work we with done is
already there in the sorting hat
database so if we want to keep improving
things it's just a matter of saying ok
let's go again to the database so we
need some policy around data retention
data storage and how to deal with this
and of course we are talking about
privacy of the data so that's something
to take into account so if you go for
the last 25 years basically the
population we have a women is 300 3 4
percent that you have there from 74
people if we click here basically this
gets updated we have this number of
comments and this number of repositories
ok so basically we go from 130 something
thousand two one thousand this is
activity we have for women in in
github.com slash Python another question
I have for you is basically what other
communities in Python should I include
in the in the study because there is a
huge amount of them so I said let's
start small and then let's let's let's
start to the community and somehow
basically what we have now on the top is
sticker so this is filtering this so if
I disable this
what we have is basically the previous
information let's focus for a while
right now in the time zone so this chart
here is basically displaying time for
information so on the x-axis we have
certain numbers which are basically the
time sounds right so this is mainly
Europe okay right in the middle then on
the right side we would have Asia China
Japan and so on and then on the inside
this should be mainly basically the US
so we have East Coast Central Coast
central time and Pacific time okay if we
click here on women you oh yeah we have
a sticker here sorry so here women what
are the most diverse areas from a
geographical point of view in terms of
the data so in this case is basically
the US the US and Canada and mainly the
west coast right so this is something to
take into account if you remember at the
very beginning like what can we learn
from the most diverse places project
repositories organizations geographical
areas so what's going on in the west
coast to say hey we have more diversity
perhaps they are more inclusive for
certain reason I don't know but the
point is they have much more population
and they are producing much much many
comets than in other area so it's
something to study so we can point to
this place it's right don't think of the
data as the result but as a tool that
can help to improve things right so then
in terms of activity the the table we
have at the bottom is basically the most
diverse in this case represented is my
activity so this is quite similar to if
we filter by mail or write the whole
organization so basically that means
that the most interesting projects for
the community are the most interesting
projects specifically for women okay so
the
based on the data I have it doesn't say
well doesn't seem to be any different
between women participating in the
community and in other communities for
instance they tend to be more focused on
documentation it doesn't happen for
instance in it had a comma slash Python
- what that's something to add some
interesting result so more things yep
this is this is another another chart we
produce so this is basically the
demographics of the community the more
affix by well if you check here in the
attractive developers what we have it's
basically activity over time in the top
chart is again activity over time and
then each of the pics here in the bottom
chart are when each of the women did the
first commit so when they came to the
community when they were attracted right
and then on the top it's basically the
last commit of any of them so let's
imagine that we have these three
developers here so we click there and
then we know that for them that they
produce the first committee in 2015
basically they left the community in
2015 in August so we have these numbers
how can we it is useful for the
community so if we have a certain amount
of people basically come into the
community and we know exactly when they
left we can say hey we miss you thank
you very much for contributing you have
certain knowledge that is really
important for us
so what if we talk again we try to have
you again in the community right so this
might be useful for Community Managers
in terms of understanding who's around
and trying to keep retaining developers
this is interesting as well to get to
have some certain analysis of the
retention rate because if we if we are
we say how many people do we have
nowadays still contributing for 2000
2015 zero so our retention rate is zero
since from 2015 so what's going on more
thinks this is this is another another
chart
we produce basically this is this
devolution of our time but comparing men
women are men as you can see at the very
end so that the green staff are men the
jello line are basically unknown comets
and the red things are the red bars are
women and we don't have almost activity
by women till 2017 why is this this is
an open question for you I don't have a
clue I don't have an idea but probably
you know this or you have certain
certain ideas of course there are some
small Peaks around here but well this is
happening so why it is I don't know and
then I wanted to show you a final chart
the UH network analysis we were
producing so think of each of the dots
our developers so basically this is a
developer right then each of the
rectangles are repositories right so we
go here to the big one this is the
Python right then we have some others as
my PI that should be with oh this is
typeset the point about this is that we
can understand visually where people are
working how they are contributing and
the areas of the code that they are
around right so this is for the whole
community but what's the network for
women so as I mentioned before one of
the questions I had is well it seems
that women are basically participating
in the same projects as man and if we
check here basically we have C Python as
one of the main preach here then we have
typeset and night I should be around
here
so this is it should be it's around
there no but fun is that the C Python
and my typeset seems to be projects that
are interesting for both women and men
should okay let's go back to the to the
slides so this is the numbers presented
commits this is some numbers instead of
for the whole 25 years of community for
the last year so perhaps for instance we
have 800 outwards in all of the
community 38 women participating in the
last year
this is the community evolution over
time the geographical distribution for
those that are becoming late thank you
very much for coming we are talking
about gender diversity this is the
representation for the last year for
women so we are talking again as in the
West Coast mainly right comparison of
the charts newcomers and so on so
comments on limitations because we only
have five minutes
as I mentioned gender is not a binary
thing so this limitation of the study
but at least the data we have is good
for bringing on table the problem the
issue of the community right and this is
happening of the communities so this is
focused on github.com estas python so
any other community you are interested
this would be great I would like to make
the dashboard public but the point is
about how to deal with the privacy of
the data because we are basically
producing private data so how do a
little bit is if you have an idea so we
have certain idea about how to do this
but it's a bit it's a bit hard this is a
small fraction of what diversity in
reality is because we are if you
remember about the diversity of
statement by a foundation a this is just
gender diversity okay and this is
focused only on qualitative data again
so this talk was push about numbers now
forget about the numbers because the
problem is that we have this problem in
the industry there is kind of a class
sailing of 10% and diversity in
inclusive is a challenge right so it's
something we need to need to check I
would say and my opinion is that data
might be useful for to be aware of
what's going on because the point is
that if not we have only perception
right and with opinions we don't go in
we don't go to anywhere so the point is
how to have this data so well we have
data now right and think that data and
technology is only a tool to achieve the
goal because the goal is to be more
inclusive and have more diverse
communities so we we produce the
specific report on OpenStack so if you
look for OpenStack you in the report
around this is sponsored by Intel I am
by the third yeah and we are producing
this we were analyzing as well things
like mentorship activities and so on so
some results and some conclusions some
recommendations from the openstack from
the asian is that well enforce the code
of conduct keep supporting gender groups
in this case is the woman women have
open staff openstack collaboration with
tech leaders and so on so basically if
you go to a tech leaders and you present
the data some of them will be interested
in data and say what can i do with this
how can i improve diversity right all of
this is done under the umbrella of K or
Scalia separated from the Linux
Foundation where all of the source code
is stored so you can go over and check
its community health analytics for open
source software we are actually we are
currently having two groups GMD which is
growth maturity and decline more
software engineering related thing and
diversity and inclusion working groups
so we believe that diversity is a key
factor for having healthy communities
these are some examples of the what we
are doing in in chaos so we have focus
areas of even diversity contributor
community diversity communication
inclusivity recognition of who to work
blah blah so for each of these focus
areas we have a set of questions and
then we have the clear or state a set of
set of metrics right if you are
interested I would like to to welcome
you to our meetings it's on Mondays and
[Music]
7:30 Pacific time 4:30 Central European
Time
so you are more than welcome look for
the for this and well this is this is a
lot of this presentation which is it's
not about perception we need to have
data right so this is all think about
don't think I my opinion is none of the
data says this right so it's something
we need to take to be really sir about
what we are saying because we may think
that the I know the diversity of our
community is increasing but this is not
true right so these are the numbers
indeed but something to discuss up this
analysis will be continued at some point
in the future so we are working there
this is also I don't know if you have
any question
thank you
questions
yeah so the question is if it's possible
to access the dashboard
yep that's if you ask for this
you can be given access so the point is
that we are dealing with private data so
it's not public in the sense that you
can go there and so on our our idea is
to have public let's say the the raw
data in terms of the basic dashboard for
Python and then you can play with that
about the privacy of the data is
something probably that we have to
discuss with the foundation is somehow
so if there's someone from the
foundation here or some of the some data
that is interested in this would be
great so times up so no more questions
I'm around so thank you very much for
your time
[Applause]