karma points for you okay and then I
guess that we can start your 49
typically yeah I guess yeah yeah yeah
sure
so steel congratulation for being here
on Sunday morning still doing well
perfect
we're gonna go for the foretold so we
have here and Rio and jelly and they're
gonna talk us about like software
engineering practices in brass
specifically so applause for them and
let's go
hi I'm Harbor or Anna and this is my
friend Jay or busy Jay as you can
imagine he's very busy I'm gonna talk
the first half he's gonna talk the
second half we work at a company called
pink app which makes distributed
databases we maintain high K V which is
a CNC F project it's a distributed
transactional key value store those are
some big words doesn't matter we operate
at a really big scale we were one of the
first major Rus projects in production
and we've been in production for over
three years we're responsible for 15
petabytes of data at over 300 customers
worldwide as you can imagine we do a lot
of engineering some of our customers are
the largest companies in China we're
used in commerce we're some of our
customers have over 290 million users in
banks where we offer really good SaaS
with no data loss and on ride-sharing
platforms that are consuming over 30
terabytes of data every day this is a
very high-performance
safety-critical system and we really
like Russ here it's perfect so how do we
go from beginning with rust to actually
doing some proper engineering now you
might have been at the point where
you've read the Russ book you've
published your first grade you're pretty
happy but now you get the big questions
how do I share my work how do i migrate
to Russ 2018 how do I do all of these
other things I don't really want to do
because I just want to hack and you're
probably going like this guy over here
so we're gonna go on a bit of a
whirlwind tour I'm not gonna deep dive
on anything if you want we can talk
about it after outside
so first connecting and sharing your
work I've had the pleasure of helping
organize quite a few of these
conferences and events or being at them
the Rusk community has over 90 meetups
worldwide and over six well six
conferences as you can see there's some
in Europe Russia and Asia and a couple
in the US but they don't really matter
there's generally an event every few
days so most of them are really
welcoming to newcomers especially if you
have a project or something interesting
to talk about
so please do we want more people in more
speaker slots okay next one how do you
get the RUS 2018 from Rus 2015 because
you probably didn't start your project
in the last month it's really easy
because it operates on the crate bound
not on some other bound like Python does
you can just use cargo fix and it will
do most of the work for you
the best part is if you're on 2018 you
don't really need to worry about people
on 2015 because they can still use your
stuff if they've used a recent compiler
it's a little bit different when we're
talking about release level because we
don't provide the same guarantees as you
may see Travis lets you configure to
test multiple versions please do so and
please test on nightly it's very
important we want to know when things
break and tell people to actually look
at your CI script to see which versions
you support okay
designing your AP is when you first make
your API you probably just go for the
simplest possible and that's good
simples best but a lot of things when
you're trying to move into real-world
use russ is a lot of trade-offs
nothing's a silver bullet you're gonna
fight from complexity versus convenience
readable errors versus flexibility and
speed verse costs there's not always a
right answer so for example if you just
want to accept references to strings and
I want to emphasize if you're actually
cloning the string internally
take a string do not clone without the
user knowing it's really mean they'll
hate you but if you're taking a string
reference you can go in play as ref SCR
and then in your code you can just go as
ref this means you can pass a string a
string reference or something else
anything that implements as ref STR
similar with collections your first
attempt you might accept an iterator and
then you're gonna try and write and pass
a Veck and you're gonna realize that
doesn't work and you're gonna look like
this guy the proper way to do it you can
try this using into iterator and now you
can pass a vector or an iterator
that's because iterators implement into
into iterator what a surprise now when
you've been writing Russ you've probably
seen this error message when you call
the function that returned a result now
you can actually make your own if you've
got something that needs to be used you
can put this must use attribute on your
code that's great because now when
someone goes to use it incorrectly they
get the same error message and they go
damn it
so if they consume it it goes away
great now quite often you'll have
functions that take optional arguments
generally it's best to use a builder but
that's not always a good solution for
your problem remember trade-offs if you
accept an into option you 64 or into
option T you're gonna find that when you
call into in there that you can get your
option out and it this means you can
call with the value or an option or your
your happy little none this means your
user doesn't have to worry about writing
some this is quite handy you can do
similar with very attic arguments which
we don't have but if you're okay with
having some really ugly in your
code
you can you can simulate it with tuples
I'm going to show you a couple slides on
how this works first you define some
structure because you can't implement
things for things you don't define and
then you do some from implementations on
what you want to support being passed in
then you can accept an into whatever now
all of these things over here they work
just fine it's really ugly so don't use
it all the time please it's not for
abuse one cool trick with that we found
in the last little while with Russ 2018
is you can now actually D structure and
take from arrays this was much harder in
Russ 2015 and this is thanks to non
lexical lifetimes this makes designing
api's that take fixed sized arrays much
easier and you can do some really cool
optimizations around that so this seems
really harmless and if you're a beginner
you might be going what the hell's
special about this but if you've been
writing rest for a while
this might surprise you wish we'll
actually be talking about this later on
in his metrics talk at I believe one a
lot of people ask us about how we deal
with errors and we're doing some really
nasty things with errors and we're
trying to move to using the failure
library because we found that the
standard error traits a little bit
insufficient and a lot of people agree
why because you can't down cast the
cause of an error
you also can't get back traces that
sucks the failure crate allows you to
have both of these things and it's
really well documented it goes out of
its way to describe four different ways
of dealing with errors in your code
three of them I think are good ideas
you've got the prototyping way where you
just pass around some strings
you've got the lazy way where you just
have a normal error type and if you're
writing some really high reliability
software it describes this other way
called the air
a kind method the first two you can
probably figure out how they work just
from hearing about them and this link
will take you to the book which will
describe them all in excruciating detail
for you
I'm gonna give you a little bit of a
demo of the error error kind you just so
you get an idea of what it is and I
don't have time for more so first we
just define this error and it contains
this context thing which comes from
failure
now it's gonna hold an enum which we
define down here this doesn't hold this
is not a fat enum it's just labels and
they have these attributes which gives
some display message and you can see we
have to derive fail on it okay you've
all looked at it long enough I'm gonna
change the slide now we're going to
implement fail for our error and we have
to define these two functions where we
take a back-trace and a cause right now
we're just proxying to the inner but you
might do more in your implementation you
also have to implement display but
that's not a surprise to you and then we
implement some Fromm's as you can tell
from an int or just crazy useful it's
important that you implement both for
the enum and the context because this is
important on this slide oh the next
slide sorry we also provide some way to
get at that context now we can call
something that gives you an error and
you can actually add some context that's
specific to your library and the user
will be able to down cast and get that
original error and all of the context
that comes along with it this means if
you if your user actually cares about
their they can dig down really deep and
figure out what's wrong if they don't
care they can still just unwrap it and
crash that's fine if they don't care you
don't have to care you also you don't
need context so you can just use the
enum that's where we have those two from
implementations okay now let's talk
about fuzzing and I know you all like
fuzzy things I did not bring in
fuzzy crabs for you I'm sorry I'm
actually talking about the programming
technique now fuzzing doesn't replace
your unit tests but it does complement
them because it finds out if you've
forgotten tests or you didn't know about
them because you weren't that smart but
please note when you're implementing
fuzzing it shouldn't be part of your
normal CI test runs when a new
contributor makes a PR that's mean
because if you get a failure which they
don't always happen that poor
contributor is very confused so Travis
lets you define the determinant event
type if it's a cron job which you can
you can make them they're not hard you
can detect it and that's when you should
run your fuzzing that way every night or
every morning when you wake up you get a
nice failure report saying how bad your
code is so fuzzing is a way to randomly
explore the spate the state space of
your code this means that you're not
always going to run over the entire
space and this is a good thing because
if you're running say over a you 64
state space this could take forever to
find one edge case fuzzing is only gonna
run a few thousand every time you run it
so it's a great way to find bugs
eventually and as you get more and more
complex with your fuzzing you're gonna
have a bigger and bigger state space so
you might think oh it's no problem to
run through you 32 and I agree but a you
64 is a lot bigger than a you 32 we
recommend that you explore prop test
which is kind of the newest one out
we're actually not using it yet but it's
a really great kraid and we've been
playing with it and we'd like to adopt
that it's from the quickcheck family of
fuzzers so essentially the way you use
them is you define some properties that
get fussed over it supports this idea of
minimization so when you're
over say a string and it finds one that
doesn't work that's really long and
crazy it will go through a whole bunch
more iterations to find the most minimal
example it can so that you're only
testing very simple examples that break
things it also remembers regressions for
you and keeps testing them to make sure
you fixed it so you can't be lazy
because we all like to be lazy and tools
that keep us honest or good the way you
define how to fuzz over things is quite
a bit different in prop tests compared
to the other quick check family things
you actually define these strategies
which you can customize quite closely I
think it's a really good alternative to
lib buzzer or AFL or quick check itself
you might have different opinions that's
great I support that
I like opinions here's a little bit of a
demo on how process works this is the
most basic one I could think of and it's
actually part of their documentation
because it's the most basic one you can
think of we define some add trait or add
function and then we use this mock macro
called prop test and we define some
ranges you can see a in zero to a
thousand P in zero to a thousand this
means the fuzzer can pick any numbers
between zero and a thousand for both a
and B try to add them together and make
some assertions so when I run this and I
run cargo tests it's gonna run a whole
bunch of them and this state space is
actually quite small so it will probably
only take me maybe five or ten fuzz runs
to get through the whole state space as
you can tell though this code has no
problems it's very simple but if we were
exploring all of the IP 32 state space I
might have some problems because there's
such a thing as overflow but you're
probably like yeah I don't really care
about testing over you thirty twos I use
a whole bunch of complex types so what
about like a key value so a non simple
type that holds
to byte arrays you can go and you can
implement a function which returns this
strategy thing and here or here on that
tupple you can see I have this these reg
X's and I can define these reg X's to be
whatever reg X I want and there's
various other things such as ranges I
can use for this then I call prop map
and I can use it to map to these this
new structure I defined so this function
will actually return to me an arbitrary
kv value with some vectors to vectors
with random garbage in them now when I
write my prop test I can say kV in this
arbitrary function and it will go and
get out random ones a whole bunch this
is great as you can guess though the
state space on this is gigantic so I
could probably run this a million times
and still have new outputs so it doesn't
explore the whole state space it's not a
silver bullet okay okay thank you Anna
and I just introduced some methods to
help you to five bucks actually it's
quite easy to find out that an
application doesn't work because in my
panic or evil we poor Ellis but two
reasoning the back usually can be hard
because bugs can be unpretty bail
it may be reproduce in may not and
usually you will need more informations
to recent in a box I have been into some
situations that I is some print and we
run it again and and this procedure away
I work in so it also Ming Lux so you
might think that I wish that time can
just tip back so that I can I can class
map as much as informations that I need
and fortunately there's the tools that
can do this for you is haha
and it's true produced by the Mozilla
awesome rust and he can they can record
the failure once in the back that
recording deterministically and you can
set breakpoints and watch points and
escalate and we're asking the commands
who the command to use this sure is
quite simple just are we call and once
you find failure then just repeat I will
show you an example about how to use our
to debugger as Russ what's program
let me go
okay I implement a simple program that
just simulate a situation that has race
condition a fan that is that Russ when
you write code in say Frost is gravity
that pays no data race but race
condition is unavoidable and so we have
an account account has name and and the
data directory when you need to
initialize an account if you write it
hard to the right is remaining money to
the data directory so sensitive and you
can query the remaining and you can also
set the remaining and what we are going
to do is the transfer transfer will
first check if the sauce account have
enough money if in if it's not if we
return false if if we do if it does it
will set the remaining about to the
source and the target as you can see
this program is just written for the
just everything SNe simple so the logic
is quite simple and we can try to run
this code
aha well surprised if aromaticity but as
you can see we are not okay
usually we are not that's the lucky but
but this Howie is a good day today for
Easter Sunday
right okay yeah sunday seems a good day
the point is once we we find out that it
is hard to reproduce the back he always
passed how can we do it how can we solve
the problem when using our are due to
the uncertainty of the network I'm not
going to run the in life so I just show
you some pictures to show how how you
work the command you can see is I use R
to record a program with H flag H frame
means that enable the chaos chaos mode
to the aha
it means that you because I actually
will emulate a single call machine so it
will try to switch to other press when
there is some like six-course or some
some instrument counts is is rich so the
chaos mode is that just switch just
switch it whenever you can so that we
can replace the box very easily as you
can see that they place a 78 in the end
that means I try 78 time to reproduce
this bug and finally I will close I will
produced the back then I can repay it to
see what's happening and just type our
replay you can see it it shows up
interface that is very similar to gdb
actually I use gdb in the in the hook so
when you replay the replay the failure
it will pause at the very beginning so
and when you have si si means continue
if we will just refused back we just
recall so I panic I panic
ly 73 which is which is here anna has a
nice it's better to have no money but it
has 20 so let's check out a transfer
function it turns out that the value set
here is 20 so we can add a break point
to the two that lie that is a
conditional breakpoint if the remaining
- amount is equal 20 then break then
stop it I used a special command here is
reversed continue because the program is
panic and we need to reverse it to the
very point it just that the very point
error happens so after we was continue
we see that fret to hit that very point
and we just enter a empty command which
is repeat last command just reverse
collinear and it shows that there's two
frets different frets he distinct free
point that means that's the very place
raced risk condition happening that's
how we use our as we just said that in
emulates a single call machines so if
you are debugging a multi if you
debugging a fret be a precaution if you
have some decrease in performance and
the second limitation is it only works
on leanest of course it shouldn't be a
problem at all okay and so if you use
our to debug our prop debug an
application and you find out bugs so and
and you believe that you fix it for how
to prove it
usually we should we should write a test
case to to check
to check it will never fail again and to
prevent is it's bringing back as Tony s
technology in the future but stable test
case can be hard of course if you are
lucky in love it will be easy
yeah someday so to stabilize the back of
you just said we may need to when we
made a special scheduled Posse to the
France unfortunately we can't we can't
enjoy this it depends on the operator
operating system so how can we do it we
write a crate to to these wings in name
fair is free improvement in rust and the
and this thing is inspired by the
FreeBSD s fair points waste fair point
fair part Co instrument Co
instrumentations there are all errors
and other behavior to be injected
dynamically at runtime that means you
can you can just use some like you just
you'll use this library to make some
fresh like pause or sleep oh yeah
whenever you want to simulate some
failures like IO IO failure or Cisco
failure or anything else and this is the
key hub yeah
welcome to star and so let's see how to
define finger points there are freeway
there are three methods to define fail
points the first one is pretty simple
just define a fair point using some
unique name and generally when when
application right into the fair point
if you just omit the fair points just
like as if is never defined and the
second one there is a caution here and I
will try to I will talk about it later
because it's used in a very unique case
and the third way is that we condition
in the middle pace and the condition
means that the final point we only be
trigger if the condition is true so like
if you run some test days concurrently
you can just
the FairPoint say getting fat if the
test is is the specific you want to run
so you have to fire fair point then how
can you configure the essence about the
fair points you can you can do it either
while the environment environment by
ribose or you can just use using the
interface API interface input just using
the API and it is quite simple just a
pair of the name and their essence
essence artifice in in the in the form X
like this there can be many actions and
only only when the first action is not
sugar then the second action will be
sugar and every action is defined as P
and count and has arguments P means that
the probability that action is sugar and
the count means that the mass the mass
times the that huskily basket li and
currently the support need to ask
include this many I think that has name
is raised themself we are the only truth
needs to is very here is the delay and
the sleep delay means that you can just
pause the fret for the given seconds and
delay whilst being the breath is pacy
waiting so let's let's take a look to
the example about a fair point
configuration this means that the fair
point has 20% probability to bring a lie
to you alive and have 80% probability to
just panic if it prints still alive it
will bring as many as three times
let's see how to stable the race
condition we just described here and we
can see that I define a fair point
oh my god
slow update here because we know that
the race condition is that the live 40
night
fetch remaining can be can be built 80
before like 44 so actually we should we
should hold a lock the hope in the hope
function but it's not so we put a fair
point here to make it sleep 100
milliseconds so that in general if
there's no bugs in the kernel France
will all block at least at this point so
that the stale read will will be always
hold so we can run a test to see how it
happened
I think something to sell wrong in the
same to you actually
oh it's not my computer so yeah okay
okay what they so it works yeah and so
no matter how many times I try it always
panic and this is what Bobby wants we
use fail point to make a test stable so
when we fix the fix the chance for it
should be no panic again but how to fix
it it's beyond the stock so you how does
fair point work under the hood actually
it will maintain a global registry to
map the failed point to each
configuration so every time the film
point is sqt
it will query if if there is any
configuration for the failure point if
it is if you ask you to the
configuration if not if you just in
knock so you may wonder that if I
defined so many fair points in my source
code it may affect the performance of
the application it's true so we offer a
feature gate we offer a feature car that
can make you these disabled all the fair
points at compile time so his is also
one of the Russ
philosophy just pay for what you use
yeah so it seems we both timed ourselves
out to be about twenty minutes and we
were both about 12 minutes so thank you
very much we we hope to see what you can
build with our some of these tips and
tools we're hiring distributed systems
engineers you can email me if you want a
job we really like remote people we
really like open source we like to read
research papers
we write Rusco and C++ we hire anyone we
don't really care what you look like or
how you identify we like creativity
passion and teamwork but we have some
time for questions we have a whole 10
minutes so if you have questions please
ask them if you have comments we can
talk in the hall
[Applause]
so the question was there's some tools
that exists that will actually mutate
the code to see how robust your code is
those are that sounds really cool I
haven't actually encountered any for
rust have you okay I think oh I think
that sounds really cool and I really
want to try that now so thank you more
questions
so the question is is it easy to
automate some of these practices that we
talked about using tools
Clippy will get you quite far as I kind
of discussed at the beginning a lot of
these are trade offs for example if
you're using some of the into tricks you
should try and minimize their surface so
that they're only existing in the public
API because there is a compile time cost
associated with them and some of them do
have a small runtime cost so you do need
to be aware if you're just throwing
these everywhere you're gonna be paying
for it so a lot of these work best when
you limit them only to public API so I
think a lot of tools might not do that
definitely I highly recommend you run
Clippy on every build though
so in Thai KB itself we're currently
using lib buzzer which does not provide
the same level of abstractions and
tooling so we have to do a lot of
implementation to get it work properly
it's very useful in tools like databases
though because when you're storing
arbitrary strings and byte arrays you
need to be very careful you're not
mutating them certainly they you only
get so much mileage out of fuzzers
though there are other tools that you
might want to explore when you're doing
multi-threaded programming such as
namazu which will go and chaotically
change how some of the threads are
scheduled to help you find bugs in logic
instead of just in properties
so the question is are we aware of any
thing that reads contracts and helps us
define properties automatically
unfortunately rust does not have
anything like whore notation similar to
what you might find in a DES so it's
kind of hard to make assumptions about
what the contracts is are I have seen
some libraries trying to add things like
contracts to functions but most of them
aren't really at this stage where I
think they're kind of usable in
production that's certainly something
that would be very useful to a lot of
people so if anyone's interested in
implementing that please do and tell me
about it
so the question is how do we choose the
language we use on projects because you
know we are writing cycle V and actually
we are in a mo big project is tidy B for
tagowit is the underlying storage for
the tidy B and we want it to be to be
multi-domestic for example if actually
it had to be is written in code but if
we use in use code
integral V it has the lightest a problem
and it's it's combination is his
performance is not as good as Rus and
also because the storage is the
fundamental of the database so we want
it to be safe and fast and and that's
why we choose rust to be able to give me
yeah I think I think rust the way that
drop semantics works is extremely useful
when you need predictable performance
because you always kind of get really
reliable function call runs
so the question is what would make it so
that we would choose Russ for writing
teddy be the thing on top of us instead
of go I think we can both agree it would
be it's easier to hire go engineers than
Russ engineers right now particularly in
the distributed system space because a
lot of go engineers are out there
slinging and distributed systems code
and not a lot of rust people are writing
distributed systems and I would say that
although I don't want to automate it but
go is really fast about the unrest
because you you don't meet too much
combined Asian errors in go so you can
get things done very quickly and in the
stokehole area there is many functions
in many other curse that you need to
keep compatible with my circle so usko
will be a mop a popular choice in in
this case we got time for maybe two more
questions
I would be very happy to chat with you
and just give you a huge list because
like we work on this stuff all day and
it's our favorite thing in the world
certainly there's lots of great blogs
out there you can look at Nick Cameron's
blog without boat cies blog Aaron
Turin's blog they all talk about a lot
of tools that are coming out and they
try and highlight some really cool
things but definitely I think the rust
blogging ecosystem is really really
vibrant matthias actually runs a great
blog he just presented and you can find
out I find out most of the cool tech we
find from blogs and certainly there's a
lot of effort right now to make rust
things and research papers as you may be
aware there's a Rust Belt project that's
trying to formalize rusts and things
like that and they're discovering a lot
of cool stuff you can do so certainly I
think one of the most beautiful things
about Russ is the really heavy research
Bend on it
so the question is does adding a lot of
fail points make it hard to maintain
your testing suite yes it does
[Applause]
so actually we use we use a few point in
production integrity there we we ask you
all the fair point fair point asses in
sequence so there's no racism in
distillation but we are planning a
feature to fail point is that supports
like contessa where fair points so that
every fair point is bound to specific
test cases so they can work concurrently
so I think in this case there will be no
more headache about too much fair points
I think this feature will will come
before the release of 1.0 of fail fails
so we're at we're at 43 minutes so we
should probably stop it's been a real
pleasure and we can definitely continue
the conversation to the outside of you
on
[Applause]