hi everyone thank you for coming to
FOSDEM and thank you for attending our
presentation
I'm rez van Khurana from open tips
project and Olivia and along with my
colleague Liv you will be showing you
how to build a multi node platform using
open tips so first of all why use multi
node setup there are a couple of reasons
in order to scale because you probably
have resources and then you get some
more clients some more customers are
interested in your services and you need
to add or not to add some extra
resources you can add it horizontally or
vertically preferably horizontally
because it's cheaper right and you want
to use low grade hardware another reason
is to do geographic distribution imagine
that you have customers in one part of
Europe and customers in other parts of
Europe you want to have nodes like
physical nodes as close as possible to
those clients in order to offer a better
experience for the services you yourself
you also want to do some sort of load
balancing for example you don't you
don't want to use all there is to power
up a lot of resources to serve just a
small amount of clients you want to do
that dynamically depending on your
platform upon your business size and
probably all of your interested in high
availability in order to be able to
failover in case a node crashes or
something happens so imagine that you
have this kind of setup where you have
some nodes in a data center in London
others in Amsterdam so you have you have
your notes in order to offer geographic
distribution spread all over Europe
you want your customers to have a
unified experience you want your
customers all all customers to see each
other no matter where they are located
you want your customers that are calling
from London to be able to reach the ones
in Netherlands right you don't really
want them to be aware of your topology
you don't want you never want to for
example assign IP so your customers just
in order to do like some sort of manual
load distribution you want to allow them
to use any entry point in your network
that it's available and in order for
them to have a unified experience all of
them need to share the same profiles
wherever they are they need to see the
same thing and they also need to use the
same resources too so this is a few use
cases that you want to have when using a
unified platform
first of all user location so imagine
that you have different clients that are
registered some in London some in
Germany some you know some in Paris in
France so each of them use a different
entry point in the platform now what
happens if the guy from London calls the
guy from Paris well he doesn't really
know where the the green guy is he
doesn't really know he's in Paris or
somewhere else so in order to be able to
do that we need to distribute the data
location among all pops so that note one
when when account gets to node one he
should know that the endpoint is
registered in node - so he's able to see
the customers that are in node two and
there are a couple of models that we use
to do this we can have full mirror for
example all the knows share this the
entire data the entire location data
which in practice is not very very
useful because usually these clients are
behind that so even if I have the entire
user data
no one will not be able to reach the guy
in France he will have to use note to to
break to break through note 1 and
another model is federated which
basically means that each note has its
own set of users and all that a note
must know is where on which note the
user is registered and let that guy and
use that guy's information another use
case is the profile shell for example
you might have some limits on the
concurrent call a customer is allowed to
make so let's say a customer is paying
for 100 concurrent calls limit and he
starts to send 80 calls on note 4 well
what happens if he decided somehow it he
decides it decides to send 60 more calls
to a different note in this case he is
using 140 channels out of your platform
although he's only he is only allowed to
use 100 because that was that's what he
paid for
so again in this case you'll you have
you have to replicate the number of
concurrent calls that are happening on
each note so that when note 5 gets the
extra calls or whoever I don't know
whoever gets the extra calls he must
reject the new calls so that you can
enforce the limit of 100 similar if you
want to do to use any cards to do load
balancing you have a different problem
for example let's say that you want to
reach the guy that's registered in node
2 and you use note 2 to contact him well
you send the invite and then you get a
reply but the reply according to the
anycast rules which is something
completely different is not super
related it's basically layer three
related decides to go to a different to
a different note what happens in this
case well the trans the call will be
completely correctly through note 5 I
think however note no.2 will not
reply if he doesn't get a reply he will
start doing retransmissions he won't get
the replies because all replies go to
note 5 it will eventually timeout and
close the call so you really don't want
to do that in order to avoid this we
also in open zips we'd developed a
mechanism that we use to inform note 2
about transaction changes and what's
interesting in this thing is that
basically what happens is no two is the
only one that has the real information
about the transaction so note 5 would
not construct any transaction which you
might or might not know is very heavy in
terms of in terms of resources one extra
use case is high availability and
ensuring it using hot backups imagine
that you start a call with no - but
disco crap these note crashes what
happens with the call what happens with
the CD arse
well in this case you will have to reach
another note I don't know using any cost
or DNS or whatever failover mechanism
you are using but for this guy to be
able to generate proper City Arts in he
needs to know when the transaction when
the dialog the call started right and
all sorts of information there about the
course start these are so again you have
to replicate information about about
cause the start time and so on in order
to be able to generate proper CDR and
you also have to make sure that only one
note one note does the dialogue related
just for example time now imagine that
all the notes within our architecture
have information about the dialogue that
doesn't receive a buy they will all
generate a timeout and they will all try
to close the same call and they will all
generate like five CDRs first a call
that was never closed you don't really
want to do that so you have to do some
sort of delegating a note to a dialogue
but that's what my colleague Olivia will
talk in the following minutes so it's in
this presentation we will only talk
about how how to organize these nodes in
clusters how to use these clusters and
assign them to different modules
depending on their purposes and all you
have to do is let the modules do their
jobs okay I will send my presentation
thank you respond and speaking of
clusters how many people here are
familiar with open tips first to go okay
and how many of you have played with the
open tips cluster features okay so
that's what I was thinking and I was
expecting this actually because I saw a
lot of new faces and I'm actually going
to explain the new clustering features
using some practical examples and here
we let's start with the basic RFC 3261
implementation of SIPP and basically you
can achieve this using no passives by
just loading the user location module
and using the default routing config and
let's apply it in real life what is an
obvious problem with having this type of
SIPP registrar which users hook in and
make their calls either through to each
other or to PSTN what is some obvious
problem okay I guess but what if it
crashes right we're gonna have downtime
not only that but we cannot even handle
a freaking restart you can't if you
restart that daemon you will lose all
the registrations and the phones you'll
have to take another maybe for whatever
one hour four hours to reread Easter
okay so we can add like another layer on
top of it of database persistence all
good and done that's just a couple lines
of config change the change the user
location mode and hooking and MySQL
URL and we're good to go what's still
wrong with this it can still catch fire
if if that server goes down you will run
into more downtime you know you have to
answer to your boss okay we explain or
maybe even work to your clients and
start handing out e-mails what not
answering calls tickets so you can take
this one step further we can add high
availability into all of this okay so we
throw a backup node now and we use a
shared database we put in a virtual IP
on top of this and instruct all the
endpoints to register to over to the VIP
using I don't know some sort of vrrp
protocol keep alive D V RP that handles
the moving of the IP and all that part
for us such as so the plan is that when
the active node fails but the backup we
have this little backup procedure that
failover procedure that says let's
reload all the dialogues from the shared
database let's recap all the
registrations and maybe afterwards the
service will survive okay so that's
basically what we had up until open sips
1.11 when we started slowly moving in
into the clustering area but what's
wrong with this this is still not it's
still not enough
what so what are some obvious downside
of this well or should I say they're not
obvious right now it's getting more
subtle one of them is the fact that this
re caching procedure may take time it's
all good if we're talking like a
thousand phones right or a thousand
dialogues but what if you have a million
dialogues on one instance how long does
does it take to query that and recache
it into memory that that can take as
good as one minute or more so although
you're saying okay I have high
availability you have like high
availability after one minute
so another problem is that what if the
master
simply does the master node does a
reboot once it boots up it wreak ashes
all those dialogues into memories so
what you have now is two instances okay
so the VIP correctly moved over to the
backup instance but now you've got this
setup where they are both duplicating
the data so okay you're saying that
might not be that bad but how about this
they will both start writing CD arts now
so you you're starting to get duplicates
on that and not only that but half of
the CD ours will be good on the backup
right because they properly closed
thanks to the sip signaling when you
hang up the call but what the master
will happen is that they will hang there
and all of them will timeout on whatever
you set the max timeout call duration
typically like two hours and you will
get this this duplicated CD ours with
max duration try explaining that to the
client when you say okay you have this
call it cost 200 pounds or something
like that so another thing that a
problem with these data duplication is
that oftentimes you need to continuously
paying the clients in order to keep the
net binding alive and the that that the
master node also will attempt to
generate pings and he will not be able
to send it because the operating system
doesn't let it since it does not own the
via the the virtual IP address and it'll
flog the logs with operations not
permitted blah blah blah and you want to
prevent that so now enter the opposite
clustering what is the idea that is that
we need to give give the set up more
state make it more stateful make the
nodes more stapl with each other and the
idea is to replicate the data live to
the backup registrar such that when the
master catches fire we are able to
instantly failover to the backup it's
it's I mean as as fast as the virtual IP
solution can do it but keep alive the
typically fails over within one second
another so this solves the failover
problem the other half is with the data
ownership and solving the dreaded
duplicated CDRs so what we came up there
is and you will start seeing in the
documentation starting from two point
four open sips is the sharing tag
concept where we each so although they
both instances have the data have the
same dialogues duplicated they are using
this shared tag let's call it VIP that
basically says the following thing if I
owned the VIP I also own the data if I
don't own that tag I pretty much don't
have anything to do with that dialogue
so in 2.4 you can change these tags with
the dlg set sharing tag active command
and then 3.0 we move the logic over to
the clustering module I guess this is
just a detail but you can hook these
commands into the keepalive the
switchover procedure and you can
automate this such as autumn when you
when the switchover happens it also
switches the tags so it switches the
proper ownership of the data to the
respective node enabling this I mean I
talked a lot about this but enabling
this is done in like three lines so all
you have to do is switch the user
location into persistency mode and due
to the fool sharing give it a cluster
and the same for the dialog and after
you create a dialog just tag it with the
VIP tag that's all you have to do okay
so is this enough now well actually we
it's it's pretty good now but customers
always want more it never stops they
will they would say okay I want 20 of
these I want 20 of these setups so how
do you start handing that now
well we and that's where the federated
idea came in where we don't as Rosanna
was saying we don't fully dumb brick
replicate all the data to all the nodes
we rather keep it local and all we share
is like some location pointers I put in
that no skill metadata part where if if
one call comes in in London
it looks up the metadata says okay
where is my exit node it's Hong Kong
send it over there because that node
will be able to handle it a cluster
table with these six nodes would look
like this notice that we have a global
cluster made up of six nodes but they
are grouped using this sip address
column and that's the only use case for
that column so the Federated user
location is the only one that uses it
and you just use it to group these two
by two and write as a wrap-up we I went
through the examples that handle the
reachability problem the hot becker
problem and so the solution to sharing
profiles and counters is pretty much the
same thing you just enable the cluster
for that respective module and the
module will do all the work for you and
similar to anycast probably a couple
more script calls to do but there's it's
they're all well documented so I guess
the take out of all this is that we put
in a lot of work into the clustering
features both in 2.4 and 3.0 that's
going to happen by May hopefully and
yeah we highly it's well tested its
we've deployed it to a lot of our
customers and a lot of companies are
using it so we highly encourage you to
give it a spin and also we have this
promo code for the Amsterdam opposite
Summit this year which if you are
interested in we would more than welcome
you over there and yeah you can use that
to register you receive like a 15%
discount
thank you very much do you have time for
more questions one question okay any
questions in there
[Applause]
hello in the user location
synchronization is working also when is
piggyback by the Mitra G start yes
the register is compatible with the user
location cluster and all of that
any other questions hi in the past I've
also had a look dear FAQ C routers for
for building cluster including asterisk
as media service my question is because
in every house we you approach this as
building it from scratch
what about PBX functions that are not
purely sip you know voicemail all of
that if if you already have existing
customers is it this model or or the
model with asterisk as media service oh
well maybe we should have put in a slide
towards the beginning we don't do media
at all so we just handle the signaling
part so the solution although its
clustered here over the signaling what
would not it will also use like 50
servers in the back partition clients
based on each you have but you might
have that on your core network so we we
will use the notes that I present it
earlier just as an entry point
for your talk my question is when you
deploy multiple nodes over a geographic
region and the network capacity is
rather limited and you have stations
roaming from one region to another are
you able to handle roaming and are you
able to handle limited capacity in the
network no the profile there's a
hardware or or or what is this a
question of how many is this a question
of how many traffic does opens can
opposite handle it's it's highly
scalable it will handle tons of packets
thousands of cps thank you
you