my chick song check is it works again
again okay okay
okay cool
good afternoon everyone thanks for
coming my name is Andrea I'm gonna talk
about building open source and to the
equipment thanks for having air and the
other organizers are for them for
inviting me it's my first time here I'm
a biologist actually as a background is
there anybody who's also in the biology
field okay so one to go I've been
working for a number of years we've
opened science ed so just really briefly
open science is basically in very crude
terms for those of you who may not know
the open-source version of open-source
movement inside science right so we want
to make things more transparent more
reproducible and more reliable I have a
little website called open neuroscience
where I'm just relaying open source
projects related to neuroscience so
there is hardware software data
collection I work with an NGO called
trend in Africa where a lot of this work
has been derived from and most recently
I'm working with Mozilla and the
Wikimedia Foundation in Germany in a
project to map what are the demands the
researchers have in terms of equipment
so just a quick overview we're going to
talk about open science Hardware of
course and then one example of these
which is something that we've been
developing for a number of years called
the fly pie I'm going to show you some
squishy things from the biology side for
what we do with this device and other
applications we have then we're going to
see hardware in software
think about what comes next and think
about how we can use open science
hardware as a new norm inside research
so just one example of hardware which is
not open so this is I think when
everybody think about a biology lab this
is what people think about right so
traditional microscope and this was
started to be developed in this sorry
this is wrong the 17th century it's
pretty much the same design in terms of
lens ever since them and to buy one of
these you need at least 5000 euros to
buy a research grade one if you want to
add functionality to it you need to add
like quite heavily a lot of money pretty
fast
and I mean there is no schedule here but
these devices are about yay big and they
wait about like at least five kilos so
they're really hard to transport
everywhere and they plug to mains all
the time which means that for some parts
of the world combining all of this is
really hard to get them right so they're
hard to customize if you have a 5000
piece of equipment you don't want any
student in the lab opening it up and
adding LEDs and changing things or
anything like that they're hard to
repair because there is only one company
that provides this one specific model
for instance try to get them updated and
as I said only access go in some parts
of the globe right so a lot of people
get shut out of this and we have to
remember that this is a - for science
and education and therefore is basically
one of the main drivers of development
right so without one of these for
instance you cannot do a lot of types of
Diagnostics you cannot do basic research
so working with trend in Africa together
with Lucia and Tom we started playing
around with hardware and this was
basically went like about 10 years ago
when we first started this and we found
our window platform and we started as
biologists you know like very simple
blinkin led with a temperature sensor
things like that and we started applying
these and things got more complex over
time and I think for all the engineers
here this is still going to be like a
weekend project but it took us a little
bit of time because we are not from that
background eventually this came out as a
publication where you can read all about
any more detail if you follow this link
and basically what this is and we're
going to show him in gonna show this in
a little bit but basically this is what
you can do with it so these are 200
microns and these are parasites that you
can find if you drink bad water so you
can use this for Diagnostics you can use
these also in a macro scale or not in a
micro scale anymore to basically analyze
or record the behavior of our small
insects or small mammals and you can
also do fluorescence if you remember I
showed that if you want to do
fluorescence with a micro switch a
regular microscope you need at least
15,000
Eros and i don't know if i mentioned but
yeah so if you source everything from
chinese distributors you can build all
of these 400 euros it's completely
open-source obviously I'm gonna show
that everything of this is on github and
you can easily customize it this doesn't
have a scale but basically fits on the
palm of her hand and you can power it
with batteries so you can take it
anywhere we're gonna see little bit more
details in a bit you can also do videos
with it so this is a very tiny zebrafish
embryo which is like 2 3 millimeters and
what you can see moving here is
basically the vascular system so the
blood flow in the little animal right
and this is used and you can see the
heartbeat here and I mean it's really
useful because this is a very used
animal model in research nowadays
because of all the genetic engineering
you can do with them this is a live of
the fruit fly and what you can see here
on the edge this bright spots turning
white is basically the activity of
calcium going into muscular cells that
are contracting so you can measure this
and this is called calcium imaging and
it's actually a very expensive technique
to be implemented in the lab as well of
course these are all proof of principle
experiments of what you can do with it
and we're hoping because this is open
source more people are gonna pick it up
and bring to their own fields of study
and help improve it
one thing that we've learned from
learning by ourselves about electronics
and things is that any biologists can
learn it and because we are part of this
NGO that is trying to help development
in Africa we started doing courses where
we teach researchers in Africa which are
inside academic institutions how to put
electronics together to build their own
equipment right so in Africa Aliexpress
is also widely available so you can get
a lot of components there it might take
a little bit more time and we've been
showing them first we started showing
how to build these devices but then I
realize that's kind of silly because not
everybody needs one of those so we
switch the courses that we had to show
them look this is how you put an Arduino
together with electronics and you get to
do the biological things that you want
last course we did last year we actually
asked participants before the course
what they wanted to do what they needed
in the lab right and they gave us
answers and I'm really happy to say that
from that workshop that from that
workshop sorry a group actually
published an academic paper describing a
new piece of hardware so basically they
learned enough in two weeks the day
later could continue doing the work by
themselves and published another piece
of open-source hardware for science so
it makes me really happy because I think
then we plant a seed for people to have
the same things which are fairly new
science here in Europe already in other
places across the world okay
so this is all I wanted to show from the
squishy side of things now we talked a
little bit about hardware and how
everything comes together so as you can
probably have guessed already like all
the frame for this is 3d printed we use
the Raspberry Pi which is inside this
case mostly because we take advantage of
the camera and the library that is
written for Python for this camera
remember I said I'm a biologist and
things need to be super easy to use so
the PI camera API is really easy to to
get started with then we have an arduino
nano component communicating with this
because we need time precision down to
microseconds for a lot of the of the
essays that we do in neuroscience right
so it's really easy to have this time
precision with an Arduino as compared to
a Raspberry Pi we made a custom PCB with
Chi CAD and you can power this whole
thing with your 12 volt battery and
having like a LED battery which is about
this big you can power this for a couple
of hours right
everything is released under the certain
open hardware license this is how the
PCB looks like so it's basically a bunch
of modules to have 12 volts in then you
have to power converters one for the
Raspberry Pi which you can power from
the USB exit here and one for all of
these other devices on the side here you
putting your arduino nano and this is an
outdated version of the board because
it's not CC ba CC by anymore for the
hardware but actually the CERN license
and what you can see here is just that
we have a couple of repeating modules
for the things we needed right so we
have general parts with transistors that
are then allowing us to control LEDs
that we can use for fluorescence we have
an Adafruit ring which has basically 12
RGB rings which you can then control the
lights and do up to genetics you have a
con to apart for a servo motor which we
use a continuous one to turn gears and
change the focus on the on the camera
and you have an H bridge which you could
use normally for driving motors but we
use a pair to drive a Peltier element
and a temperature sensor that gets then
a feedback loop so that we can nicely
control the temperature of this Peltier
element if you are here early you saw
information about Kidspace and we have
everything on Kidspace so with one with
this one click born extension can order
all of the components and the board from
eyes there are days to hear probably not
but anyways we try to make this as easy
as possible for everybody to buy all the
components and get started so Kasper
thanks for all the work with Kidspace
it's really a good tool so I would
recommend everybody who has their own
projects to put there right so this is
hardware in the software side of things
we are using a very simple stack so it's
basically the stock raspbian from which
is distributed with the Raspberry Pi and
then everything is written in Python
tree we take advantage of the PI camera
library the user interface is tkinter
but we're planning to move this to cutie
pie and pie serial to communicate with
Arduino right so we have an Arduino
sketch obviously that is then just
taking care of the serial communication
with the pipe with the pipe and taking
care of the precise timing of things
write the code that we wrote is then
released and the Creative Commons by 4.0
license and this is a little schematic
so basically on how everything works the
idea is to have all of these as much
as possible so basically each one of the
hardware components is a class in Python
so you can easily add or change the
number of class or for instance you
could repeat a number of ring classes if
you wanted to use several rings in the
device right or the different LEDs and
so on of course provided you made the
hardware changes to go with it right and
then what you can also do is run
protocols meaning you can tell the
device to run things automated for some
time so for instance please turn on LED
one for 500 milliseconds turn it off
then wait another two seconds and then
turn it on again and repeat this for 10
times but you can actually run automated
experimental protocols this is the user
interface so basically you can turn on
these these things because of the
classes on and off and here is how the
protocols are looking if anybody has
experience with user interfaces we love
some help to improve this it works but
it's not fantastic and so what's next
right like so we have everything we try
to keep everything as open as possible
as github issues and here you can find
the repository and basically we want to
turn the PCB which is one block to
several smaller blocks so for instance
if you want to add four LEDs you just
have four little PCBs and a base one and
then you just stack them this is a
little bit of seed studios have with
their Grove system if anybody heard
about that right so we want to move as I
said the user interface to another a
Python library right now because of the
way pi cam the PI camera is written you
cannot transmit the data directly via
SSH so we want to send all the camera
feed into a file or a buffer or
something like that to be able to
control this remotely because right now
you need the Raspberry Pi a monitor
keyboard and a mouse right if you would
then instead have everything via SSH you
could have several pi several of these
devices connected to one laptop and you
could have remote connection with it
also improve the camera resolution right
now we're down to 10 mark
meters but we hope that by either
changing software or hardware we can go
down thank you and so by going down we
can do more even more Diagnostics and
even more experiments that we're
currently not able to do so for instance
at the moment we're not able to detect
malaria with this because the parasites
are too small for the resolution of the
camera right we would like to increase
the types of fluorescence we can do so
this is all playing around with LEDs and
light filters and things like that
improve the user manual there is a PDF
version but it's a bit outdated and
we're trying to put everything on
something called wiki fab has anybody
ever heard about it so this is an
open-source tool for documentation which
is very similar to what Prussia has for
their printers so I have like a photo
and then a little text description and
you can go step by step and this is all
on this link and we want to try to apply
this for different areas order the
neurosciences and then last but not
least I'm starting a project with a
couple of colleagues and friends in
Germany to basically provide this device
as a kit or as a completed unit steal
everything and there are open-source
licenses and we have already if you
google for permits for me to science and
flight PI you're going to find a website
and there is already a user forum for
people who started to interact and bring
up problems and things that they would
like to contribute and we want to use
the fly PI in this company as a proof of
principle that basically can do this for
all the open-source hardware because
when normally happens at least inside
academia is that you publish a paper
describing something as an academic this
is what you want to have and you don't
care much if this gets too many people
right you have this paper you can cite
this this is good for your career you
move on to the next project what we want
to do is basically communicate with the
people that are producing these things
and become quasi the middleman in
between pub researchers that are
publishing open-source hardware and the
users on the other side so we want to
take all of the work of certification
documentation customer support and
provide this as a service for
researchers and users of this device
if this is going to be working still to
be seen and now for the last part of the
stop basically
sorry did I skip something No describe
the flyby is but one of many many
projects available out there and we're
going to see this in a bit so can we
make this a new norm and together with
Louise and Caspar and many other people
around the world and Javier as well
we're working together with the GWACs
community which are people from all
wakes of life working together with this
mission to make open science Hardware
spread everywhere by 2025 right so this
is very ambitious and we hope to get a
lot of it done until then and I would
very highly recommend if this is
interesting to you go on the forum look
for gosh community online and get in
touch because people are really really
supportive and really welcoming to
everybody and here just to show you what
I mean by there are many many other
projects these are all open source
projects that are related to science
that are available out there and so you
have you know prosthesis and you have
different types of microscopes you have
artificial neurons for modeling and for
teaching there are little incubators
that you can have several different
types of plants in them there is a whole
farming but for those of you who might
have heard of the farm but one of the
ideas we had lately was to make a
smaller version of this and have this
take care of plants inside a lab right
so basically this device will take care
of everything by taking care of the pro
plants and things like that right so
there are many many people doing many
many cool stuff out there and so we want
to see if this becomes a new norm this
one thing is especially cool this is an
atomic force microscope so these things
are really interesting because they
actually do measure like the differences
in atoms at the surface of a probe and
can measure like really tiny stuff so
and it's pretty cool there is an
open-source project for it so I think
we're living in this open-source
Hardware Cumbrian explosion because like
if you look for it on Wikipedia you have
more than 70 projects and they're mostly
like to a commercial level and big
projects in this light there are not at
least like 36 of them and many many more
in repositories online and I think the
reason for this may be a little bit
summarizing what we've been hearing the
whole day today is that the tools to
create hardware getting better and
easier to use so the software I care and
openness care and all these tools are
becoming much easier better to use all
this fast prototyping to 3d printers
laser cutters low volume PCBs are
getting also easier to use low price for
manufacturing and then for the Internet
infrastructure is there that we can
store all these videos and tutorials and
documentation and also that there are
like a lot of companies or some
companies that are like now more than
five years old and actually are proven
to be working under a valid business
model right because this is what
everybody's afraid of or if I don't have
a patent then people are gonna destroy
my company and this is not going to work
which apparently is not true last but
not least last slide this project that
I'm doing with Mozilla and the Wikimedia
Foundation this started with this idea
that projects like the 5 5 started with
the local needs that we had right so
inside one lab in one department in one
institution we have this one need for
the flyby so we spend all this time
building this device which is going to
attend some of the population there for
sign fights for scientists but not
necessarily who have the biggest impact
right so can we make a map of what
researchers actually need and actually
once we have the map build open source
hardware based on this map so let's say
from thousand researchers 800 of them
need a better version of a microscope so
let's build that first get a huge user
base using open source hardware and then
move on to the next thing
right there is already online survey
going on so I would ask you if you can
please share this widely the project has
a landing page where you can find a lot
of information and all the repositories
about it are on github so with that I'd
like to say thank you very much please
get in touch with us
[Applause]
ah sorry sorry yeah of course so this is
the PI camera really the first version
and the only difference how could I
forget that that's absurd so you can see
it here right and this has a little lens
that comes from surveillance cameras so
it's an m12
thread that you can get anywhere and we
just a depth is in front of the PI
camera and then by changing how far this
lens is from the sensor of the camera
you can get a higher or smaller
magnification right so you can find the
version of the camera on Kidspace sorry
so the first question here before your
question was I forgot about the camera
and this is what I just talked about and
your question is why we want to use SSH
and not some other protocol right so
depending on the application that's
totally fine
the problem is if you want to use this
for Diagnostics right where you have
like privacy issues and patient data and
things like that
basically yeah and I mean again because
I'm a biologist this is the best that I
know of and I don't know if anybody has
a better suggestion for a transfer
protocol so I would love huh VNC or
something like that yeah I don't know so
I'm open to suggestions about this yeah
not very hard so the question was how do
you get how hard it was to get focused
on the micrometer range so it wasn't
very hard as soon as we find the proper
m12 lens and I think this one has a six
millimeter working distance
characteristic we just needed like a
stable 3d printed surface where we could
slowly move the tread of the camera and
the object so the application will be
automated focus is still not complete so
right now is really just pressing a
button and making it move so we don't
have the algorithms to make it automated
yet
yeah yeah definitely
so I can't so the question was how can i
how can I compare this device with the
commercial one of course we're not doing
everything that a commercial one can do
so for instance the resolution is one of
those things that's the question we
didn't find a solution yet so I could
say we're very close in terms of like
how many micrometers we need to break i
I really so the question is like how far
how close we are to comparing to
commercial applications in the sense of
like how many cases we curve for use we
basically started by covering our own
use cases because this is what we know
best but for instance there are some
people from plane physiology we are
thinking about using them for their
using it for their cases so today we're
kind of far still from all the possible
uses yeah so the question is what is the
image resolution of the camera and for
the PI camera you have two versions one
of them is five megapixels and the other
one is eight and right now five
megapixels is more than enough for what
we need but I don't think so the problem
here is not the like how many pixels you
can put inside the sensor because
they're already one micron apart from
each other so the sensors themselves the
pixels themselves are small enough the
problem is the optics
or some smart algorithm to process the
data
okay I see no I didn't again because I
just don't know any better
Mike if I could to what seemed to be
like the best thing you could find
question was if I consider using DTK
instead of my cutie right because of the
dependencies that one has is compared to
the other so yeah I didn't and here on
terms of packaging in a way we're kind
of stuck to the same hardware all the
time right so in a way it's a little bit
easier that once we have everything
working
we just preparing an SD card image and
put that available online so people can
just download this the image right so
the question is what is the image delay
between the camera feed and what we see
on the screen and this is really
wonderful because by camera the library
sends everything via a GPU directly
right so there is very little if non
delay I mean I could not observe any
delay so really this is why you can
focus yeah I mean this this would work
as well and so and this is one of the
things we are struggling with
transferring this to a buffer or to a
file to then transfer via SSH because
this will definitely increase a delay
and then we don't know how to work
around that basically thank you
[Applause]
looking for