I'll be discussing the
strategy thank you for coming on
[Applause]
thank you everybody can you hear me in
the back okay awesome so you can find a
copy of this presentation it's already
uploaded so you can find it on fast
wonder blog slash speaking or it's also
uploaded on the FOSDEM site so it's all
there so you have it already now as
you'll notice throughout this
presentation community metrics
strategies are indeed based mostly on
cats with measuring tapes so that's the
primary thing you can take away from
this presentation I have actually spent
more than twenty years working in the
technology industry and for most of that
time I have indeed been focused on open
source and metrics was always a big part
of my work with an open source projects
as director of community fat puppet we
used our metrics dashboards to provide
updates and recognize community members
before puppet I was community lead for
Intel's open source Technology Center
where I did similar things with me Joann
ties and metrics I just finished a PhD
and as part of that work I did a whole
bunch of analysis for the Linux kernel
mostly looking at mailing lists but also
its source code data and a few other
things I'm on the governing board and
I'm a maintainer for the chaos project
which Brian mentioned and I will talk
about more later in the slides and it's
a Linux Foundation project open source
project based on community health
metrics for open source projects I
joined pivotal back in October so
relatively recently to focus on open
source strategy and right now I'm mostly
working on our open source strategy for
contributing to kubernetes so of course
I've been digging into some kubernetes
metrics since we're talking about
community metrics strategies I am gonna
start with how I think about community
since this drives how I think about
metrics and I tend to define community a
bit more broadly than how I see some
other people define it so we'll start
with that when I talk about people I am
indeed really including all of the
people who work on the project so I'm
talking about core
product developers release managers
Quality Assurance localization and other
people who contribute to the product
itself application developers who are
maybe using the API or other features to
write applications on top of your
product through applications modules
extensions things that build on top of
your project users people who actually
run your software and with any luck
maybe provide some feedback vendors so
the companies who are creating their
products based on your project and
hopefully giving some engineers back to
the project as a part of that work and
then other contributors people who are
working on promotion organizing meetups
doing moderation documentation and all
of other stuff that happens around open
source projects some of these people
contribute as part of their day job on
behalf of the employer and others
contribute on the free time but they're
all really important parts of your
community now before we dive into the
strategy let's talk about some of the
ways that you can use metrics so metrics
allow you to measure progress to see if
you're achieving your goals
so using metrics to measure whether you
are successfully achieving your goals is
a big focus for the rest of this
presentation so I'll talk more about
that a bit later but as you're defining
your goals it can also help to use any
existing metrics that are already
available and just sort of lying around
to learn more about your community and
explore in more detail how people are
currently participating and this can be
a really valuable input into your goals
and strategies another use for metrics
is to look at your community over time
to spot trends gauge interest you may
notice that people are showing a lot of
interest and something you didn't really
expect and knowing this might help you
encourage further contributions in that
area on the other hand people might be
showing less interest than you had hoped
in another area and this gives you an
opportunity to dig a little bit deeper
and talk to people to understand maybe
why they aren't as inter
and something that you thought was
really really valuable or really cool
however one of my favorite things about
metrics is that it tells me more about
who is contributing to the project the
people make the community and for me the
people are the most important element of
the community
so my metrics do tend to focus more on
the people than anything else and
metrics not only tell you who
contributes to your project but they
also tell you where they're contributing
within the project and this allows you
to learn more about your key
contributors and I like to use this also
as an opportunity to recognize them it's
nice to recognize that person who maybe
answer so many questions on the mailing
list or maybe you contributed something
awesome that a bunch of other people
enjoy using now when I say start with
the goals I don't mean is to start with
your goals for the community I actually
think you need to take a few steps back
and start at the very top so what's
important for your organization or for
the project as a whole now this is
typically been a company in my case
except which for lots of big companies
that are doing up and source but it
could be an organization like the Linux
Foundation it could also just be a
project like the kubernetes project
instead of an organization and you need
to start by looking at what the
organization or the project hopes to
accomplish and what its goals and
strategies are and its objectives and
then you can take this down a level to
start to figure out what your goals are
as a candidate and as I mentioned
earlier looking at some existing metrics
can also help you explore what people
are doing now as input into defining
your metrics or defining your goals for
the community what I think the most
important part of putting together
strategies and plans for your open
source contributions is really aligning
them with these overall goals for your
project or organization if your goals
for the community don't support the
overall goals for your project then you
aren't likely to be successful because
the community is just doing
Rann
things that nobody cares about so it's
worth the time to figure out what you
actually want to do and how it supports
the rest of the project or your
organization and once you figure out
what you want to do as a community and
can tie it back to the bigger
organization or the project as a whole
then you can start looking at using
metrics to measure your progress now
some of you might be thinking that
starting with the goals really isn't
that important so I'm gonna spend a
couple of minutes talking about what can
go wrong and trying to convince you why
the goals are important but I think it
falls into a couple of a couple of
different areas so first you you just
won't know if you're successful if you
aren't measuring the right things and if
you aren't measuring the things that are
important for your project or
organization you won't know if you're
making progress in the areas that you
actually care the most about and second
measurement actually impacts behavior
and this is something that is really
important to think about people will do
different things depending on what you
measure for example if you public
publish metrics that focus on the number
of mailing list posts and that's the
focus for your metric you're likely to
start getting more mailing list posts
because we're vain and we want to move
up in those in the rankings and if what
you're trying to do is maybe get more
people to contribute code to your
project or get more people to do
something specific then additional
mailing list posts probably aren't going
to help you all that much
now I love data
so measuring open-source project success
is kind of a hobby and I'm pretty
passionate about I'm not sure what that
says about me this is my hobby but
that's such as it is but as a result
people tend to ask me a lot of questions
about metrics usually the questions are
focused on how to decide what to measure
and people often ask for examples of
projects with the best metrics but I
really don't think that's a good
approach what you measure depends on
your goals and what you're trying to
achieve which may be completely
different than other projects so I
really prefer to encourage people to
start by defining their goals and
ultimately you need to look at your
strategies and plans to come up with
criteria that will help you measure
whether or not you're successful for
example if you want to improve the
performance of a particular piece of
open-source software you'll want to have
success criteria and measurement based
on specific types of performance if you
want to gain influence within an
open-source project maybe you need to
measure increases in contributions or
the number of employees moving into
positions of leadership or positions of
influence and as with any good
strategies and plans the outcome and the
results should be measurable so that you
can actually tell whether or not your
efforts were successful and this is
where your metrics come in handy once
you decide in your success criteria you
need to make sure that you can actually
get the data that's required to measure
these things and measuring it start
measuring it now to get a really good
baseline for what you have and there are
loads of tools available to measure this
stuff so there's lots of lot of tools
available to gather a contribution data
about open source projects and some of
the commonly used tools can be found in
the Linux foundations chaos project and
which I'll talk about later and many big
projects already have dashboards using
these tools and other ones to display
contribution data for the project now
that I've talked a lot about focusing on
the right metrics for your project I'm
also going to recommend measuring other
things that
just aren't even important to you now
and going a bit overboard on your
metrics because I love data so just I
just want more data but you may not
spend much time looking at this data now
but it might help you later because
there are there are a few things that
can happen so the obvious is that your
project goals might change and something
else might matter in two years that
don't doesn't really matter to you now
and if you've already been capturing a
bunch of data you can probably track
progress towards this new goal with some
existing historical data and the other
piece and I think this is probably more
likely and maybe a bit more important is
when something unexpected starts to
happen so this is actually one of my
favorite things about working at open
source project is you just never know
the direction the people will take with
the stuff you're working on and how
people will use that software so with a
really robust set of metrics then you
can dig in and learn more about
something that you didn't expect to see
and you might need to adjust your goals
based on some unexpected things that are
happening in the project so now that you
have a whole bunch of awesome metrics
you actually need to do something with
them so historically most of the places
I've worked I've reported metrics
monthly if you work at an organization
that doesn't really get community or get
open-source monthly is probably pretty
good cadence when I worked at puppet
they were a bit more savvy and so I
think I reported metrics quarterly up to
the exact team but being able to show
frequent progress and again
the stuff that you're the stuff that
you're showing people is are the metrics
that actually demonstrate whether or not
you're being successful so being able to
show frequent progress to help justify
what you're doing and show that you are
indeed making progress towards
accomplishing your goals as I mentioned
I was at puppet I did a short report I
think it was about quarterly for the
exact team that was focused on actual
participation in the community I don't
usually bother tracking things like
people who join just to lurk I only try
to count people who've actually
contributed something whether it's go
door Docs or answering questions any of
those sorts of things we also did a blog
post on the puppet labs blog one
a month the focus less on the numbers
and more on recognizing contributors and
for this report there was a lot of human
filtering that happened
we sometimes highlighted someone who
made some important but small
contribution that just wouldn't have
shown up in the you know top
participants list and we also attended
to filter out people who had behavior
that we did not want to encourage people
who were using up lots of people's time
and not a lot of not a lot of actual
output and instead we put a heavier
focus on the people who were helpful and
answered lots of questions from other
users now I also wanted to provide some
example metrics the show how metrics fit
into your strategic efforts so at
pivotal as I mentioned earlier my
current focus is on putting together a
strategy for our open source kubernetes
contributions so I'll focus my example
metrics on pivotal and kubernetes lucky
for me the San CF has metrics for all of
their projects including kubernetes so
this was really a great starting point
for me to better understand the existing
kubernetes community they use dev stats
to build their metrics dashboards which
you can find it a link at the bottom of
the slide but first let's start a quick
discussion about vanity metrics so when
I talk about vanity metrics I'm
referring to those metrics that make you
look good
but that don't actually tell you much
about whether or not you're really
successfully achieving your goals so
I'll admit it like anyone else I look at
these metrics and it feels pretty great
when you or your company are moving
moving up in the ranking but I try
really really hard to keep these vanity
metrics out of my strategies and plans
since they don't really tell you much
about whether or not you're being
successful for example let's say that
your organization is moving up in this
ranking it looks great but what if
you're moving up because you have a
rogue employee or possibly group
employees who are gaming the metrics by
submitting a whole bunch of trivial one
character changes each is a separate
commit with a separate full request
so this is going to drive the commuter
pull request numbers up for your
organization but likely at the expense
of your reputation as you annoy all of
the other contributors now I know I know
none of you would do this none of your
colleagues that do this but then that is
actually a real example of something
that's happened more than once it's in
the kubernetes project and we have this
discussion and the contributor
experience say got a fairly regular
basis because companies people at
employees at companies do do this and I
know this is kind of an extreme example
but there are plenty of other ways that
people can participate that would drive
numbers up without actually helping your
organization achieve its goals so I just
encourage you to be a little bit to be
aware of the vanity metrics now in
kubernetes most of the work is done
within various special interest groups
or SIG's so the kubernetes contribution
strategy that I'm working on at pivotal
is focused on coming up with specific
strategies for the SIG's that are
important to us so that the various
teams across pivotal can understand
where their contributions to kubernetes
you can have the biggest benefit and and
be aligned with the SIG's that are going
to be important for not just current
work at pivotal but also future work I
put it all and because kubernetes is
such a massive project with daily
changes there is no possible way that
one person can possibly understand every
single detail of every single thing
that's happening in the 30 plus SIG's
and the dozen or so working groups so to
be able to build a strategy for our work
within kubernetes I need to be able to
find out who I can talk to to better
understand what we've done so far in
addition to what we might want to do in
the future and also you know pivotal is
not not huge but we're not a small
company so finding these people can be a
real challenge and one of the things I
did in my first couple of weeks at
pivotal was to start to dig into the
existing metrics that the CNC already
has to understand our current project
progress and who's already been
contributing within and who's been
contributing to which SIG's within the
kubernetes project and this helped me
find some people to reach out to and
gave me
baseline for where we were already
active now here are also a few snippets
from a grimoire labs
dashboard that came from butter Chia
with a few more details
showing Fidel's contributions to
kubernetes over just the past three
months
so before looking at the kipper Nettie's
data I had never really used dev stats
so it probably has some features that I
don't know about but I found it a little
a little bit limiting compared to the
dashboards using grimoire labs as far as
really digging in and figuring out what
individual people were doing what I do
love about these grimmer labs dashboards
is that they're built on top of Cabana
which means that I can filter my view of
the data on any field available in the
database which is pretty cool in this
case I've just filtered it on
organization name to get the github
commits from pivotal but I can also
filter on a single person or a positive
time zone a bunch of a bunch of other
stuff that's in the database and I find
these really useful for better
understanding how individuals are
participating within a community for
example if I look at contributions from
from Honus who's up at the top there
from our London office you can see that
he's removed a whole bunch of lines of
code which indicates he's been
contributing to existing files right so
he's been removing things adding things
and contributing to existing stuff and
he's done this across a number of
different repositories Ben and Leah on
the other hand who worked together on
kubernetes for Windows in our New York
office have only added lines during the
time period that I used mainly because I
could get this as a good example i
shortened to the time period drastically
but it corresponds to the kubernetes
enhancement proposal that they just
submitted for Windows node support and
you can also clearly see in the in the
top you can see the time zone split
right between our Bay Area office our
New York office in our London office
which is where most of the kubernetes
work happens which is kind of cool to
look at but again this really helps me
understand who's contributed to
kubernetes from within pivotal
and which areas we've contributed to but
with a few more details than what I
could manage to extract out of the Deaf
stats dashboards now when getting
started with metrics there are a couple
of different approaches that you can
take before you start building anything
it's a really good idea to look around
and see what kind of existing dashboards
already exist that you can use many
projects already have these dashboards
like the CN CF dashboards for kubernetes
that I used as a starting point and you
can also take the DIY approach so I've
also done a fair bit of this and built
my own dashboards gathered my own
metrics it requires a bit more technical
know-how but it's a good approach for
people who have the time and resources
to build and maintain your own metrics
if you have really simple needs you
might even be able to just easily hack
something together with the github API
is those are pretty easy to use for most
people the tools that then the chaos
project like grimmer labs tools for
example augers another one are a pretty
good starting point dev stats is also an
open source project itself under the cnc
f so you can always use that there are
loads of other tools still called
measure that Jeremy Garcia from data doc
has been involved in and presenting
about but loads of loads of different
tools you can use by far the easiest
choice is to pay someone so pitcher Tia
does this whole disclaimer I'm on their
advisory board but they you can get
companies like that to build and
maintain the dashboards for you which
requires way less time and butter dia
for example uses all open source tools
so you're also supporting their
contributions back to open source
projects which is pretty cool but in
general I recommend kind of doing a
little bit of all three if you possibly
can and doing them in this order because
you can use the existing dashboards see
how much of what you need already exists
requires a lot less time then if you
have the time the skills required hack
something together using some existing
tools and which if nothing else is a
really great learning experience to help
you figure out exactly what you need and
then if you want someone else to
maintain your dashboard you can pay
someone to do that it's also really
important to think about other metrics
and measurements that aren't necessarily
in a traditional community metrics
dashboard there are loads of things that
I've used over the years to measure
whether or not we're successful that you
might not find on the traditional
dashboard for example when I was at
puppet one of the things I tracked was
whether we were increasing the diversity
of speakers at our annual conference
which was one of just several measures
that we use to determine success towards
becoming more more inclusive and more
diverse within our community and loads
of these diversity and inclusion metrics
aren't often found in traditional
dashboards but they're a really
important part of measuring whether
you're successfully achieving diversity
and inclusion goals for your project the
chaos project again also has an entire
working group devoted to diversity
inclusion metrics for projects that are
really important to your organization
you might have goals around having
specific people move into leadership
positions or especially in key areas
within a project and the leadership
positions available so they vary widely
depending on the project but they can
include becoming board members
maintainer zkk emitters reviewers but
it's important to measure this
separately because these positions
rarely if ever appear on the community
metrics dashboards and many people who
move into these leadership positions
spend quite a bit of time reviewing
contributions which means that they
often actually have fewer commits
themselves and this means that the
dashboards may actually show them as
having decreased contributions when
they're actually doing more within the
project and having increased influence
so it's important to look at that a bit
separately in some cases you might have
specific features that you want to
contribute or specific issues that need
to be fixed in these cases you might
want to measure a specific item like a
specific pull request merge a specific
bug fix or some other contribution that
you need outside of the metrics
dashboard so in other words as metrics
dashboards are great I love them I love
data but you'll likely need to find
other ways to measure
things outside of your dashboard to
build a complete set of metrics to help
you determine whether or not you're
actually achieving your goals
now I mentioned the chaos project before
and if you're interested in working on
metrics I would encourage you to join
and participate in chaos so it's an open
source project whoo I had several people
in here are in the chaos project
unsurprisingly since this is a metric
stock but it's an open source project
it's under the Linux Foundation and we
welcome anyone regardless of your skills
so while we certainly have people
writing code to build metrics tools we
also have a lot of people coming up with
metrics and writing descriptions for
them so we also love people who can help
us promote chaos presenta conferences
and all sorts of other tasks so this is
something that's personally I'm just
incredibly passionate about there's the
link to get you started we have three
working groups so there's probably
something of interest to you if you're
interested in metrics we have one
focused on growth maturity and decline
of open source projects we have a
diversity inclusion and then we have one
focused on metrics that don't fit
anywhere else and we have mailing lists
we have a general weekly call each of
the working groups has various calls
that you can participate in and as I
mentioned before anyone with any variety
of skills can participate in chaos
project so that's my shameless plug for
an open source project that I am
particularly passionate about and with
that there are three minutes for
questions and if the next figure wants
to come up and get set up that'd be cool
too thank you
[Applause]
so what questions do you have for me
today hi sorry how do you begin to
measure say the diversity of a
particular project on any axis of
diversity so so the question was how do
you measure a diversity within an
open-source project the I wish I had
like this awesome magic bullet for that
because the reality is it is it is super
hard to measure diversity and inclusion
within a project so within the diversity
and inclusion working group we actually
have seven different focus areas that
we're looking at so we're looking at
things like our year are the events for
your project do you have a you know
attendees that are diverse in various
ways and we have a whole bunch of
dimensions of diversity that we've
defined so it's incredibly it's
incredibly complex a lot of times it
comes down to one of the ways you can
measure it is by actually surveying
people and asking them how how they feel
within the project do they feel included
do they feel like it's a diverse project
you can measure attendee demographics
for events and participation yeah it's a
because it's such a wide topic there is
no single answer to that I would
encourage you to go to the diversity
inclusion repository for chaos and have
a look yeah just its kind of interested
in that because I'm surveying people
from an underrepresented group you're
you you're liable to get the answer you
know Ferno say I'd have thought in quite
a lot of cases so yeah it does seem to
be hard yeah that's really hard
there was a talk this morning in the
Python dev room that tried to answer the
previous question so I suggested to you
check it out later on because there's a
video of it and you can personalize
those a recommendation for a job or
termination just it's already done ok
it's on different
luckily fosston records everything
because they're awesome alright
microphone in transition we have another
question I'll give it up yeah so when a
small question
[Applause]