so my name is Ray Kinsler and I work on
Fido see sit and I'm a software engineer
working for Intel I'm also a Fido TSC
member qualified is you memories like
what I started out opens doors you just
flipped stuff onto sourceforge and that
was that was opens dis as before github
and then we have oversight committees we
have marketing committees that we have
technical steering committees and
there's a technical steering committee
for five-o let's call the the Fido TSA
and I'm one of the representatives on
the phyto CSC and we have input into the
technical direction of Fido and Fido is
an collection of projects if I there was
really three key things
Fido is VPP which you heard about
earlier VPP is a is a high-performance
Network stack built with the same kind
of optimizations as DP D K so DP DK is a
very efficient layer for IO a Fido is an
F item VPP is a series is a network
stack is a series of protocol
implementations on top of DP D K so
that's one part of item a second part of
Fido is the integrations it gives you so
and you talked you heard right to Slav
talked about it earlier and Giles talked
about it earlier and then you also heard
Billy talk about the same thing which
are all of these integrations that sit
on top of DP D K so with DP DK is sorry
on top of Fido
so with Fido we don't just flip a
network stack out the door and say you
guys just kind of take care of
yourselves we take care of the
integrations into kubernetes and we have
so many integrations you have guys
arguing with each other about which is
the best way to integrate Fido with
kubernetes Anders
I think Billy's presentation called out
very well there's three different ways
to achieve it right
there's integrations with OpenStack I
think Giles talked about integrations
where it opens with strongswan was a
Giles strongswan
and we have net company hang support so
we have all these integrations on top so
that's the second part of Fido is
integrations
and the third piece of photo is what I'm
going to talk about today which is
benchmarking
now usually malaika software
how many software engineers in the room
a software engineers how many test
engineers in the room one two three four
okay so that's probably like a probably
like a twenty-two is probably like it's
probably like a ten to one
so in c s-- it is hugely important and
final c sit for Fido is is is how we
maintain and we ensure that the Fido
data planes performance does not degrade
over time so what and and and I'm not
you know that it's no commentary on any
other open-source project but the danger
when you move into open source is that
when you get when patches come in the
door you need a very very very tight and
very elaborate CI and CD infrastructure
to make sure that as you take new
patches that you're not trading off
performance patch by patch by patch by
patch and that's the important role C
sit place and Fido and it's a
significant role and that's what I'm
going to talk through today so what were
the tree keeping tree parts of Fido
trick question question I know I'm
picking on you it's like four o'clock at
everybody's like we've been to the bar
already regular you're asking this
questions now what do you do I said
there was three parts of Fido one was
the day to play and second piece was
though up integrations third piece was
the benchmarking this is the
benchmarking so today I'm going to talk
about why code is not all no longer
enough this is essentially why
benchmarking is important I'm going to
talk a little bit about cease it what it
is and then we're gonna talk to you into
three interesting problem statements
which ceases or three new problems we're
trying to solve what cease it and then
I'm going to summary have a bit of a
summary so today you heard about a
number of different open source projects
you heard about snap from Luke you heard
about open V switch for
Kirra and Bruce well Elsa you heard of
Fido from Giles Andrus lab and Billy
McFaul and you heard about psyllium and
the who is presenting on psyllium yes
gentleman there and then we have a and
then there's a few others that you may
not have heard of so there's a galaxy of
open-source projects and if you also
learn more about the galaxy of
open-source projects I'm giving a talk
at 22:7 and if you're not already in the
pub you can come to the lightning talk
room to learn about the open then the
the user space networking ecosystem I'll
probably just be presenting to myself
but there's a galaxy of open-source
projects in userspace
today there's never been more choice
well how will it perform for me you know
you know there's a whole bunch of
typically vendor reports from Charles
Intel Mellanox Purdue system there's a
lot arm producers as well the series of
academic papers as blog posters youtubes
but you always come back to the same set
of questions
how are the benchmarking are the
benchmarks repeatable our tests quite
applicable to my use case and if I had a
dollar or a euro for every time somebody
said is it a real world use case I'd be
a very rich man you know and the
difference between synthetic benchmarks
versus real world is IC Xavier smiling
there our test platform and
vendor-neutral and that's kind of an
important one to what extent are is
vendors you know skewing the skewing the
the game to their own interest so these
are all important questions and Arenal
come back to how do you evaluate
software data planes how do you test and
how do you ensure neutrality well
without data and whatever the consistent
benchmark you know without data you're
just another pen a person with an
opinion and you know this is from Edward
Deming and myself and magic shows this
because I think a kind of illustrates
very well our sentiments towards CSUN
and
that's not a criticism of anybody else
but it's this is more of a statement of
our intention the intention of phyto
cease it is to bring volumes of data
that reflect the kind of performance
you're gonna get from the phyto
deployment in real-world use cases so to
bring significant to bring that kind of
clarity so that when you're asking the
question about how will it work for me
that you'll have the kind of data that
you need to answer those questions when
we doing for time alone doing okay so
phyto cease it is a sub-project inside
Fido so if you go to the fibre website
and you you navigate through there is a
whole bunch of sub projects and there's
one that's called a seasick CPSC said
Cpl since it stands for a continuance
system test system and integration
testing I think that's right now that's
my first fail of the day so what is Fido
sees them Fido ceecee it uses standard
industry benchmarks and tools so we
everybody's heard of RFC two five four
four I think that or C 254 four will be
written on my epitaph when I die okay
and the Metro Ethernet forum standards
we test ranges of packets we test 64
byte packets we test all all the packet
sizes up to 50 and 18 we test I mix we
test a jumbo frames so we test a large
not just one or two different sizes we
test all the different sizes you might
possibly use including jumper frames we
use only open source tools we use only
open source tools our traffic generators
t-rex which just happens to be another
Fido project we used everything's
orchestrated and run by the test robot
the robot test framework and then we use
Jenkins as the CI so Jenkins takes care
of running a nightly builds and running
the tests and those kind of things we
test multi-core scaling so you know we
test with a single core we test with two
course and we test with four cores and
sometimes we test with even
more and I'll talk with that later we
test there's a typo here we test nd or
it's just nan Drac right nan drop right
and sorry
when Dendi or is when you don't drop
packets PDR which is partial drop rate I
think we we have a tolerance of 0.5%
packet drop and we test em or or who
knows what mr or is maximum receive
right is where you throw the kitchen
sink and you see how much actually gets
true we test the whole range of
different network from the whole range
of different network functions things
you might be likely to do l to switching
ipv4 ipv6 routing ACL security groups /
relays and we have a slew of unit
functional and performance testing
everything is open and fully documented
test environment I want to say that
again open them fully document test
environment that means that and we have
lots of people who do this we have lots
of people who are involved in the
fighter community will actually go and
clone everything and reproduce it
internally because it's all open source
all the test cases are open source all
the tools are open source you don't need
any proprietary tools so you can
reproduce the whole thing internally it
supports Intel and ARM architecture arm
architectures so what do what does that
mean we actually have an open lab that's
hosted by the Linux Foundation that gets
Hardware contributions from people like
Intel for people like Mel Knox from the
DRM ecosystem and we have a very sizable
lab that's run inside the Linux
Foundation that's free for anyone
involved in CC to use where all this
stuff gets tested and then that allows
us to do lots of different permutations
of tests we can do at the same test on
different generations of Intel hardware
I'll talk about that later
different same tests with different NICs
same tests on different platforms same
tests with an arm platform same tests
with an Intel platform it's the same
test very rigorous the same tests run
through the same set of permutations
different packet sizes different numbers
of cores different platforms different
NICs to give you a very very large
corpus of data about how this thing for
in forever
runs in the real world it's
multi-platform multi-vendor so we have
it runs today on top of sant OS suzay
upon - i think i'm not sure of a fedora
I think that might be going many way and
then we also support cloud native you've
heard extensively about cloud they will
opens and also an clothe a there's the
hotness at the moment I know but it also
supports OpenStack environments as well
and we also have a support for some
accelerators like crypto accelerators so
we have an open lab where everything
gets tested in the open where patches
get tested where nightly bills get
tested where release reports get tested
all in an open lab in this Linux
Foundation and we don't use only open
source tools an open source test so if
you don't believe the numbers that are
produced by the open lab they can cope
reproduce the whole damn thing yourself
and satisfy yourself that it's
completely authentic and that's the idea
is that we want to drive good practice
and engineering disciplines that defied
our dev community so if you submit a
patch to Fido and it causes a
performance degradation and we'll come
on we'll show the adult later causes the
performance degradation and the Larrin
bell goes off somewhere and somebody
sees that and we can take action so the
idea is that by having this elaborate CI
CD environment that we catch those kind
of regressions early on I'll talk more
about that more in depth later that we
also you know when so much a Fido and so
much about user space networking is
about performance or you know achieving
the best possible performance that you
can through software
well again Faial fight OCC provides you
the kind of tool chains that you need to
measure the performance and then it also
can prevent things like performance
regressions so it's all fully automated
as integrated into G it's in terment
integrated into Jarett so that when you
submit a patch at all tests get kicked
off where we runs functional tests
performance tests we have use case
driven test definition so if you want to
do things like testings like the
excellent termination those kind of
things we have test cases for that
and it's all get executed in the open
apartment I've said all this an
integrated see I have said all this
that's fine so what does this look like
in practice now clearly you know I did a
count last week to see how many test
cases in total I could I could find and
I counted 998 test cases that are
currently these are these are
performance benchmarks that are
currently being run in phyto sees it on
a regular basis now that's if you go
through every permutation the packet
size across every platform across every
naica course every microprocessor
generation across every use case and you
can see here that you know we actually
break it out is 144 layer 2 tests for
216 layer 3 tests 300 you know very very
significant number of test cases in each
area so when you go through all the
different permutations the test cases
across you can come up with a very very
large number
I clearly check and show the result of a
thousand test cases and I want you know
at the same time so I just picked one
and one or two in particular that I
quite like so I quite like the ipv4
teske its IP 4 for routing test cases
so and we have two test cases that we
run once called ipv4 base that runs Fido
that runs a performance test of ipv4
routing with one route so you've only
got one route in your lookup table and
then we have ipv4 scale and ipv4 scale
runs with two million routes in your
test in your in your in your routing
table and you can see this this is a
Haswell generation microprocessor we
have two Intel platforms in the lab
we've got as well and we've got skylake
and you can see the ipv4 base with one
route gets around 11 million packets per
second on how as well and then it gets
with the two million routes it gets what
about nine million packets per second on
the house well okay so then we went to
Fido VP peace 80 that was weird 1804 we
then went to 1807 on house well and we
did some software optimizations and came
along and we also introduced a second
NIC so the software optimizations caused
a small performance boom from about 11
million pakka seconds to about 12
million packets a seconds for the
million packets a second for this single
row test case and there's another small
performance boom from about nine to nine
and a half or something like that for
the two million route test case but then
we were also at that was these test
cases here where were 10 gig NIC were
able to do the same test case now with
the dx7 10 and the x7 10 again is a 10
gig NIC but it's 4 by 10 gig so it's a
40 gig NIC that's it's a 40 gig Ethernet
controller that has 10 4 by 10 gig
physical interfaces and you can see here
that you know the performance is much
the same as it is with the 10 gate and
as with the 10 gig NIC but now we have
the satisfaction that we're know that
we're getting roughly we're getting
pretty much the same performance across
the 10 gig NIC I'm a 40 gig Nick and
then we introduced the Intel skylake
microarchitecture in Fido 18.7 as well
and you can see that performance again
is roughly the same on skylake so we've
also introduced a new microprocessor
architecture we've introduced a new
introduced a new NIC
and we have that warm fuzzy feeling that
performances more or less the same and
then fight old VPP 1818 10 came along
and Fido VPP 18 10 made very liberal use
of avx-512 instructions now avx-512
instructions so I presume everybody in
those in the room knows what vector
instructions are everybody knows vector
instructions I see nodding heads and I
see hands up
so avx-512 is the latest is that is
laces improvement in vector instructions
so before this was avx2 which can thing
came out and has well was it a fix to
his house well AVX 512 is on skylake
which basically allows you to process
even more packets simultaneously is the
idea so vector what vector instructions
typically do or how we typically use
vector instructions in both DP DK and
Fido VPP is we use them to process
packets in parallel so if you're using
let's say scholar instructions you
typically do a one packet at a time if
you use vector instructions you
typically do four packets at the time
with a VX avx2 we typically did four
packets at the time with avx-512 we
typically do eight packets at a time if
memory serves me correctly and I hope
I'm not wrong but what happened when we
introduced all the avx-512 optimizations
into Fido VPP on skylake you can see
what happened to the baseline
performance there we went from about
about 12 million packets a second eighty
and about twelve minutes a second up to
something like 19 million packets a
second just simply by using this and by
using this part inherent parallelism the
microprocessor that AVX gives you
similarly at the scale test case with
the two million routes went up from
something like nine million packets a
second to something like over it is you
know two over
to over 16 million to around 16 million
packets a second so you can see here the
general point and the probably labor
that know at this stage but the general
point is you know you can look at the
same test case across a series of Nicks
and across a series of microprocessor
revisions and see what the impact of
both of you know what the impact is
without optimization the impact of it is
with optimization across a whole range
of 90 not nearly a thousand test cases
so this is how we bring a real breadth
depth and predictability what I mean by
breadth is a breadth of test cases when
we depth of measurement and I mean
predictability we do this for every
patch we do this nightly we do this for
every release and we generate a huge
corpus of data as a result so I think
I've got 10 minutes left so I'm gonna
talk very briefly about down area let me
draw a draw back for a minute any
questions on what I've just said go
ahead
funny you should ask let me come answer
any other questions go ahead
so not actually Oh Knightly Knightly
Knightly not every patch because that
just becomes insane to your point right
you can do it every back okay sorry I'm
just I've been told so and you're asked
the question you're asking is how
frequently we do run the entire test
kick yes
so I come on side and a bit of depth so
let me let me come to it so and we
talked about this and previously which
is the continuously problem which is
that if you find performance regressions
that release time it's typically very
expensive anybody here and there's lots
of software engineers in the room if you
have measure performance regression in
the release time suddenly its git bisect
phone right so you're typically really
get bisect and you're running the same
test case and it's typically very very
painful particularly that's read the
velocity of communities like DP DK on
Fido VPP the rate of loss these huge
means that we have a huge import of
patches which means you really need a
very strong safety net to catch
performance regressions so how do you
maintain best-in-class performance and
how would you address the danger
creeping normality and I think the more
common name of creeping normality is
boiled frog syndrome where you're just
things slowly degrade over time and you
don't notice well I have a pretty
picture for you so this is our
performance trending time line so we
published this and all the developers
have access to this and you can see this
is a whole bunch of l2 test cases here
you won't be able to read this but I can
show l2 bridge domains with one Mac one
with more mac address up to wouldn't
100,000 MAC addresses I think we
actually might do an even a million MAC
addresses you know it doesn't matter but
you get the idea that we have a whole
series of l2 bridge the main test cases
here from a single while scaling the
whole way down to 100,000 Mac MAC
addresses as a single bridge and we can
see how that test case performs over
time another only dab where you're
actually able to run it against what we
know are you know are good numbers and
bad numbers so we can say okay well
what's in the green and what's in the
red and we can make judgments and you
can see here the red circles are
regression where regressions have
happened and green circles are where
performance improvements have happened
and this is a dashboard that the entire
community has on the regular basis this
is how you generate a warm fuzzy feeling
that you're not losing performance over
time and because I said earlier that we
have a very very large number of
cases we have a very nice dashboard in
which people can just log on and see
whether performance is increasing what's
the short-term percentage change what's
the long-term presenting check change
what's the trending number of millions
packets per second and is there how many
regressions you're getting a how many
low outliers and that kind of thing so
what are the challenges here and I think
the two questions before outline the
challenge is very well we have a lot of
tests and we have a limited number of
physical platforms and so you're very
neatly very judicious about when you run
so the entire test week definitely gets
run every release and we typically run
the entire test suite on a nightly basis
but that consumes consumes a it consumes
a lot of systems when you submit a patch
we tend to be more judicious about how
many test cases you we run against any
individual patch because that you know
consume that can really snarl up number
attacks resort sources you know this is
not an unlimited we have lab we have
we're not an open source project with
unlimited funds far from it so we need
to be very judicious about what we run
and when yeah and one of the challenges
is how you get how you can ensure you
get coverage so how do you know that
every patch is getting the kind of
coverage test case coverage it needs
okay I'm gonna keep going deeper diving
so moving beyond the symptom so I'm
gonna move past this and maybe on to
yeah probably on to this slide so you
know I kind of labor the point at this
stage and you know if you forgive them
for trolling rotten through to me at
this stage but a label at the point at
about you know how many benchmarks we
have but at a certain point you need to
move beyond just benchmarking the
problem you know it at a certain point
you need more data to try and and the
train route cause the problem it's it's
one thing telling in again but number
software engineers in this room you know
that it's one thing telling me there's a
performance regression or there's a bug
somewhere but give me a clue give me
some sort of an idea as to what the
actual underlying problem is
and you know it's well known today that
Linux ships with a whole bunch of tools
that you can use for next-level analysis
of where performance regressions are
coming from you know tools like Linux
perf we also have things like pmu tools
for okay for pulling pmu stats from the
microprocessor that tells you where
cycles are being born and we actually
also have very good introspection actual
instrumentation and Fido VPP itself to
tell you where cycles are being for
portent so what we're starting to do now
is we're starting to use these tools and
again they're all free and open source
tools to start to generate the next
level of information so when you go in
and you see a performance regression now
you can actually drill down and get the
next level of detail and look at the
graph pipeline in VPP whether they think
Giles there earlier talked about the PvP
graph hierarchy and you can see in the
next level where cycles are being burned
and that interface and that data again
is being generated and it's there so
when we get a performance regression we
don't just leave you hanging and say hey
guys there's a performance regression
sorry we give you the next level of data
say actually just a performance
regression in this graph node as a
perform as a posed to a performance a
system-wide performance regression okay
and then what lastly we'll talk about
service density and this is you know
when like we talk about real-world use
cases so you know there's a lot being a
lot of discussion today about the cloud
and cloud night cloud native deployments
but there isn't really a whole lot of
data around how data planes react to
cloud native deployments are certainly
not enough data around how cloud and how
they dam deployments react to cloud
native environments so we've been doing
some work to try and understand that
better and we've been comparing
comparing service densities for virtual
machines as compared to containers
there's a lot of industry discussion at
the moment a lot of Oaks discussion in
the community around hey containers are
more efficient than virtual machines
Hansel proves here at that statement
containers are more efficient virtual
machines okay lots of hands what they're
not well there is that as well but there
is own that's a there's a lot of talk
around that but my experience tourism
I haven't seen a whole lot of data to
substantiate that so what we've been
doing in Fido again is trying to put
data behind that to understand what that
looks like and then where the inflection
point is so we're we have we're
benchmarking today is we're benchmarking
at V&F service chain where you have a
whole books or a whole bunch of virtual
machines in a chain all connected by a V
switch and then we also have the same
setup where as a container service chain
again a whole bunch of containers
connected by a V switch and then we also
have a container pipeline where the
container where you you you inject pack
it into the first container and then
they just pass it each other also to
understand what they a point-to-point
performance looks like so and in that
way what we do again is we test with one
sorry one virtual machine on the switch
we test with two virtual machines for
virtual machines eight virtual machines
we test with one container or two
containers for containers a containers
and then we you know we typically test
again you get the idea of labor at the
point across all the packet sizes and we
produce this kind of data that you can
see here that again that illustrates
very well where the inflection point is
for you know where when you start
together a switch over cost in
performance from containers versus
virtual machines I've got one minute
left to go so tree problem statements
that were working on ensuring that you
don't lose your performance
as your as your data plane evolves also
understanding where performance
regressions are coming from are the next
level of information and then also how
cloud how data planes perform in a cloud
native environment so that's the fight
OCC project it's an open and welcoming
project and same as every other open
source project there's always there's
always plenty to do so we'd love to love
to see you turn up any questions
okay thank you very much
[Applause]