so really week I'm going to talk about
new geeks and how we manage to build a
complete new Linux distribution out of
minimalistic language if not the
minimalistic language which is scheme
that parentheses thing that you've heard
about just before all right before I go
into presenting geeks let me just talk
about something you know which is you
can do Linux so I I like potlucks so
potlucks you know are these parties
where people join together and everybody
bring their own dish and that's pretty
cool that's a good way to discover new
dishes you know new taste things that
perhaps you wouldn't cook yourself right
you get to discover lots of new things
and new Linux is a bit like this right
it goose Oliver organically and people
brought their own dishes and you get to
discover lots of things if you look
carefully at how your your system on
your laptop actually works so you will
find that there are things written in C
there are things within in Perl
there are things within Python where as
you know lots of things and perhaps a
bunch of you know bash scripts with you
know a whole rich collection of custom
configuration language on top of it
right so that's very tasteful this is
great in a way but if you look at it
from the perspective of someone who's
actually trying to understand how this
all works together or from the
perspective of someone you know who's
trying to learn or trying to modify
things that may be not so great that's
that's a whole lot of things to learn a
whole lot of languages configuration
languages XML JSON er mall you name it
you know all that and trying to bring
some some unification to all this is one
of the goals of gigs so let me go into
that so geeks who has already heard
about geeks in this room alright that's
that's quite a lot of people that's good
that's a good thing because I didn't
plan to really present it in detail
but basically if you went to Ricardo's
talk before for example Giggsy is a is
actually a whole bunch of thing so you
pretend to think of geeks as a package
manager and it's true that's a package
manager that you can use to install
package you get transactional upgrades
you get 12 bags non-root installation of
packages you know that kind of feature
which is quite unusual and pretty cool I
think it's also a whole toolset you know
of tools that deal with packages one way
or another so we have tools for example
that can create environments on the fly
like geeks environment so it's pretty
much like virtual and if you if you're
in Python we have tools that can create
darker images you know application
bundles if that's something you need we
have you know all sorts of tools and we
also have an actual standalone system
that you can run on your machine and
that's you know a standalone gnu/linux
distribution also yeah as I was
preparing this talk for the minimalistic
language trackers like what kind of
minimalism are we talking about so this
is not this kind of minimalism you know
not in terms of number of lines of code
but there is some sort of minimalistic
feel to it especially in the use of the
language which I'm going to talk about
yeah this is yeah we have a wonderful
reference card if you want to know more
about how to use geeks as you know for
all these features that I talked about
you can find it on the web or you can
find it on paper right here this is
wonderful what's not on the reference
card is this thing which is how you
manage a complete system a standalone
system distribution that you install on
your machine or that you create in the
VM or in a container so this is just
what we get with geeks you get to
basically declare your system
configuration entirely including account
services lockers blah blah blah blah
blah blah this is a very simple system
configuration yeah you I think even if
you're not a schemer even if you're kind
of afraid of parentheses that happens
I'm being told you can still I guess
understand what's happening here you
could imagine that these are
braces and maybe that works better for
you I don't know all right so once you
have this configuration like I said you
can actually there is a bunch of gigs
system command and you can create a VM
you can create you know you can yeah you
can instantiate it an actual bare metal
hardware etc etc this is really nice so
how did we get there why did we end up
using scheme and all the things to build
this system so the other day I wanted to
learn about terraform which is an
infrastructure as called tool I'm not
very familiar with this kind of tool and
so I ended up watching a keynote by you
know one of the terraform people
explaining the new features of the
upcoming version of terraform and one
thing that struck me it this part the
person was presenting so terraform
actually has its own configuration
language like many tools so it's called
the Hashi corp
configuration language HCl it's a very
corporate name I guess and so it's it's
a language a DSL domain-specific
language that allows you to configure
your infrastructure basically and the
person was presenting the new features
of the of the language that person was
saying look here is one of my favorite
new features the new four keyword allows
you to iterate over lists and generate
lists and map this gives you a whole
bunch of new flexibility and I thought
this is exactly what we want to do with
gigs we want to give you a whole bunch
of new flexibility that's the point so
we we happen to take a different
approach technically but the end result
is the same we have a whole bunch of new
flexibility so if you if you're familiar
or even not familiar with Lisp you're
probably familiar with all the mystique
around Lisp that Lisp is somehow magic
like a thing of Richard and Chris Weber
who is sitting here
rightfully know
did that the wizardry thing is a
double-edged sword you know it's a good
thing in the sense that while you can do
so many things but at the same times it
sounds like black magic which is kind of
not so great I don't think it's black
magic but I do think it has very
important features so there is this
famous quote that Lisp is not you know
the right tool for any particular domain
basically but it allows you to attack
new problems by implementing new
languages that's basically what we're
doing here it's not a new idea it's just
the idea of embedding domain-specific
languages in general purpose programming
languages and that's basically what we
are doing here I should also mention
since we're in the scheme in the story
in the minimalistic language there room
that the scheme standard yeah this key
I'm sorry the scheme standard has this
famous quote also like that I could put
it here which is that programming
languages should not be designed by
palying features on top of features but
by removing the weaknesses that make
those features appear necessary so
there's a whole you know thing about
minimalism in scheme and Lisp so how did
it all start
so the initial thing in geeks well the
initial thing was playing with
reproducible software deployment via Nix
and the first thing that we came up with
was is this way to represent package
definitions alright so if you've ever
hacked Linux kuhnian X distribution
you've probably you know added this kind
of package definition this one you have
parentheses so it does look very
declarative it could be JSON it could be
llamo it's very similar a bit but it's
actually code and you can see there's a
string up in there that actually
concatenates
string so that gives you a whole bunch
of flexibility as you can see yeah this
is this is actually code it looks like a
purely declarative thing but it's really
cold so you can write functions that
create packages out of other packages or
you know parameterize packages you know
you can do all sort of things
that's how it started then if you're
using the standalone geeks on your
machine you get to you know as I said
before you can select which system
services are running on your machine so
for example if you write this thing this
creates a system object for OpenSSH with
the default configuration right that's
pretty simple
but obviously you can also specify a
configuration so you say all right open
SH configuration I want x11 forwarding
and I want to permit route login but
using public keys something like that
and you can do that for a whole bunch of
services so this one is is a bit more
interesting maybe this is seeing it so
see it you know it's this web interface
for git that allows you to browse web
Satori's and so on in a web interface
it's if you're going to set it up by
hand it can be quite tedious because you
need to set up nginx you need to set up
F CGI wrap you know this kind of thing
but as it turns out if you're using gigs
you can just say this and it's going to
ensure that nginx and f CGI wrap are
actually set up correctly somehow on
your system it will just work so I think
that's pretty cool did I get the
configuration right because I think the
authors are right here I hope so and you
don't get to this is the same basic
language right you don't get to learn a
new configuration language every time
that's my point but like I said it's
also cold so let's say you can say I
want to take the default list of Desktop
Services you know that you would
normally use to configure your laptop
for example but I want to remove the NTP
service that's provided as part of that
default list of services and so this is
actually scheme the lambda keywords
means with that we're defining a
function basically that takes a service
and then we look at the kind of the
service and if it's actually the NTP
service then we remove it from that list
you know that programming
we can do a bit more advanced things
like I want to say alright I'm taking
this desktop services list but I want to
change some of the configuration for
these services let's say I want to
change how min get TTY is configured by
adding a message of the day or I want to
change you power to specify you know
what happens if I close the lead etc etc
again this is configuration embedded in
a general purpose language so there is
still open issues like often people see
this and they say well alright that that
looks interesting that allows you to
actually program your configuration
which can be useful but are you really
going to write bindings for every
configuration file out there and the
answer so far is yes and yeah it turns
out to work so far I mean it's not too
much of a pain sometimes we have you
know cheat code that allows us to escape
from day the scheme bindings if we
really need to but in general it just
works and that's that's a reasonable
thing to do so we'll see how it goes
all right so to summarize with gigs
being embedded in a general-purpose
language forget so we get all this
program ability that I showed before but
we also get the ability to build new
tools that would otherwise be pretty
hard to build if we didn't have a
general-purpose language available so
among these tools we have a new max
interface so if Emacs is your thing you
can actually manage your whole you know
package set directly from within Emacs I
like it
and then we have tools like gigs refresh
with which automatically updates
packages gigs lint which means gigs
graph kicks system extension graph which
allows you to inspect your operating
system declaration basically if you want
to see how services fit together
all right but since we are doing scheme
a whole lot what if we try to unify
beyond this this glue layer basically
I've only talked about the glue layer
that you know glues packaging services
etc together but what if we went a bit
beyond so there are often questions
about Nick's versus gigs what's the
difference etcetera etcetera so from a
technical viewpoint this is an example
Nick's uses the name DSL domain-specific
language that's an external language
designed specifically for the purpose of
the Nick's package manager' it looks
like this so curly braces as you can see
so you have functions function calls
it's a functional programming language
lazily evaluated it's really cool but it
remains a domain-specific language right
so it's it's really designed for this
particular domain
you know defining packages and so on but
it's not designed to do anything roughly
so for example in a package definition
in Nick's what you would do is insert
bash snippets to define the actions that
you want to do during the package field
right so you have the package definition
that's within the next language and
right here you have a bash snippet
that's going to run when you actually
build the package this it does a job
right it can be pretty convenient at
times but there's there's a catch to it
which is that this is these are just
strings right and you end up mixing two
different programming languages and in
fact you end up concatenating strings
that happen to form bash programs and
sometimes that can be tricky
one example is escapes you know there's
obviously clashes between the nicks
syntax and the bash syntax like Nick's
uses dollars by shooties dollars so how
do you escape things that creates a
whole class of problems and a whole
class of issues I guess sometimes it can
be tricky to find the right way to to
escape things
and so since we have a general-purpose
language at hand it came naturally that
we could after all use scheme not only
to glue things together but also to
actually perform you know specific
actions so one example that I like it
the initial run disk if you're familiar
is how the initial run disk or Linux is
really made it's a mixture of C programs
that involve a script that you know do
you know all sorts of things and
eventually you end up with a cpio
archive it can be quite tricky and
inside that archive you typically have C
programs that use a custom C library
blah blah blah it's it's it's a whole
world so what we're doing here is that
we're using scheme again so what if we
just write scheme that's going to run
into that initial one D Ram disk when
you boot your system that's that's what
we're doing it simplifies things because
we can reuse code we already know the
language we can it's a general-purpose
language anyway so we can do anything
basically and it doesn't work so this is
actual code and what we're doing here
that there is a special hash tilled
thing there which means we're actually
doing code staging so this is pretty
much the equivalent of concatenating
strings together to create a program but
here we generate generating a scheme
program and this is all scheme so we
know that the syntax is going to be
valid we can easily refer to existing
objects in scheme via hash dollar so we
know we're basically generating valid
code we can reuse scheme libraries and
so on and so forth and we end up with
scheme inside the initial Ram disk I
like to show the diagram which explains
how the system the standalone Geeks
works basically we have the Linux kernel
we have the initial Ram disk which runs
guy'll but we also have the init system
which is called goodness Shepherd which
also uses guile and then possibly we
have application that may or may not use
guile
right so that the idea and because we
had this init system in scheme well we
can also use this hash TL thing to
generate the bits of configuration for
the init system so instead of generating
the generating unit files for example
which would be just trains that we
concatenate together we can actually
have access to the API of the init
system we can generate its configuration
we can share code you know reuse
existing code inside the init system so
one example that I like is well alright
this is this is the definition of a
service that mount and unmount file
systems we have access to the mount
procedure to perform the mount sis call
basically so we can do that and yeah
this is the example that I like so this
is you have the beetle be IRC gateway
this is its service definition but if
you want to run it in a container you
can just say alright I'm importing the
newbie Linux container library inside my
Shepherd PID 1 environment and now I say
make fork exec constructor slash
container which is a function provided
by this library and I'm running that
demon in a container right so we were
just reusing existing guy'll code
directly in the service manager that's
really cool I think all right so I think
it's about time to wrap up so what we do
have is that we're using a minimalistic
language that some people view as
academic right it has very basic
features it has macros basically but
simply using macros we can build
embedded domain-specific languages of
all kinds and that's how we end up
defining complete systems I think it's
pretty hackable we have a single git
repository that contains the whole
system including package definition so
you can basically grep the whole system
you can navigate interfaces and I think
that that's pretty unusual for a
complete gnu/linux distribution to be
you know searchable and hackable in this
way and we use code staging techniques
so this hash shield
that I should before to basically allow
us to glue together different layers of
scheme code that are going to run at
different moments in time and this is it
I invite you to join us now and share
the parenthesis you can install the
distribution you can get one of these
reference cards you can use it report
issues and you can share your ideas we
were supposed to release 1.0 for FOSDEM
but I don't have networking access so
I'm not going to do it right now and now
there are other reasons but anyway it's
going to happen very soon so I invite
you to give it a try and report what you
think about it thank you
[Applause]
all right so the question is how do we
generate configuration files from from
the scheme snippet that we have we use
so in many cases the configuration file
format is basically key a key value
thing and so we we have a generic system
that allows us to define bindings for
for this type of configuration file
basically and that automatically takes
care of generating the configuration
file and then we also have more ad hoc
ways of generating special configuration
files for example do we have tools to
convert existing configurations to
scheme no we don't have them but that's
why we usually provide a way to specify
if you don't want to use the scheme
version because you already have
configuration files usually you can do
it we provide an escape hatch that
allows you to say alright I'm using this
configuration file for nginx for example
yes
all right so any so the question is do
we have any plans to support
transactional upgrades at the system
level right it's actually already the
case so problem solved so you can you
can when you instantiate a system with a
different configuration it actually
creates a new generation of the system
so you can at any time when you boot
your system you can choose in the grab
menu which generation you want to boot
and you can boot an older generation of
your system you can roll back to an
older version of your system basically
yeah all right
so the question is whether we could
manage a whole fleet of systems and that
stateful systems you're saying that that
do not use geeks did I get that right or
that's outside the scope of geeks I
would say so geeks is really concerned
with configuring geek systems and we
could in theory manage your whole fleet
of geeks machines for example we don't
do that yet we don't have the tooling
yet to do that but I know that for
example NYX sauce has tools to do that
so we could say have basically a single
configuration template and apply to a
whole number of machines that's what we
could do so that's really question to
the Commons which is that geeks is
wonderful basically you can easily
convert
okay all right one last question maybe
are we still yes so what happens if you
change your system configuration is it
automatically we configure right so no
it's not automatically we configured you
have you basically edit your config file
and then you run gig system reconfigure
and that will instantiate the new
configuration so yeah that's the idea
all right thank you
[Applause]