so hello my name is Nikola masa first I
would like you to I would like to thank
you all for being here today I'm a
developer at Pegasus I work on the
documentation team Pegasus as you may
know as a start-up made possible by
consensus one of the most important if
the alien blockchain company Pegasus but
I'm proud to represent today focuses on
the protocol work where we lead will
lead product is pasión it's an
enterprise grade java vm client but we
developed from scratch in fact I'm a
developer at Pegasus and I'm proud to
work in the documentation team
documentation needs developers because
apart from the UX development that I'm
many many ready to you the command-line
interface of panel ID I also provide the
documentation to four technical writers
and I act as an interpreter between them
and Pantheon code our documentation team
is nicknamed pliny to make reference to
the Roman writer Pliny the other who
wrote about the first Roman pantheon in
his book naturalist historia and also I
admit a bit to show a fun look smaller
than other teams
so as Pliny wrote and I'm just quoting
Naturalist historia Pantheon is a
masterpiece of excellence but it has not
had an opportunity of being so well
appreciated yet we are fixing this a
good documentation is one of the ways to
achieve this goal of excellence so let
me tell you how we started the journey
to excellence in fact I started it in
July 18 alone with an already impressive
codebase to explore you may have heard
of gasps spacecraft from the European
Space Agency that was launched in 2013
this spacecraft was
design to measure our galaxy the Milky
Way as precisely as possible distances
of stars spectral and photo metric
measurement velocities it measured about
1 billion stars all the huge quantity of
data was used to graph a 3d image of a
galaxy and for the first time ever we
were really really and precisely knowing
its shape everything before that was
autist use know it's real precise data I
fell a bit like gay and jelly alone in
the void of space with billion of stars
to explore but our journey is not going
to be outer space even if consensus
recently started some very interesting
space activities in July 2018 we are
still on earth and given the real
weather and crypto weather I decided to
set our story in the cool nor land of
the north we were on earth reading the
source code of Papillon and a lot of
aetherium related documentation the fact
if that even when you think he knew that
about
aetherium and you do if you are able to
prepare this exploration and you even
watch the crypto winner coming with some
confidence but he still you know nothing
before working on a project like that I
admit that I had to ask a lot of
questions to the developers that were
all working and partying and they
answered nicely thanks to them at the
stage of the process
I was diligently assimilating knowledge
preparing the trip so a few weeks later
two technical writers join the
expedition I think of us as explorers
and cartographers on a new unknown land
we draw maps forces to be able to settle
a new world of everything blockchain we
draw maps of the terra incognita for
to land on set up businesses quickly and
as safely as possible we draw maps to
locate all witnesses and know the places
where we can expand and improve we draw
maps for others X other explorers to
initiate the expeditions and help us
draw more maps then we continue to
prepare by sharing the findings and
writing them down into a basic
documentation but at this stage our
first issue to start exploring if that
we needed better tools the project
contained already some mark Don fites
I hope everyone knows more down it was
mainly a readme file in the root folder
of the project we needed to move to
something more user-friendly and that
will enable us to collaborate faster at
least on the beginning all project being
a student gathered we naturally decided
to move to the github wiki it provided
some advantages like is of years
possibility of a table of content on the
side of the page restricting the editing
rights to the team and some more but it
also came with its batch of issues after
a few months we're focused was clearly
on the content itself we decided to
rework all documentation and make a
migration we show two ways of better
tooling or recommendation work the first
one was to move to state service we knew
about Ridge dock but org but also that
github was providing get up pages even
if we were not able to tell exactly what
each service was doing we also had the
possibility to self host or
documentation and generate it using a
tool like metal Smith that we love but
we had no idea about what was the best
choice to make an info decision we
listed requirements and followed a
simplified approval process the two we
wanted to add to
to satisfy multiple capabilities had to
first be able to use my own syntax after
a pool we made among developers to know
if rsg was something they would accept
to use Martin was clearly the only way
to have their approval it may be
different in other companies but here it
was the case the system also had to be
able to manage documentation versions
based on release type that were used in
the code repository the best solution
being to have an intimate it build of
the dock when publishing a new release
of Parthian one of my biggest concerns
with the github wiki while that the code
and dock were not in sync I mean that
when you get up wiki you don't have a
way to go back to a version of the code
in the git log and tell exactly what
version of the dog of the dock can apply
there are two separated repositories we
also needed the new tools to enable
reviews like code reviews on poor
requests with commands but for the duck
with the wiki we missed this ability to
create a pull request review it and fix
it before merging in the master branch
everything we pushed was directly
available for the public and so we use
the ugliest way we could imagine to
review ducks during a few weeks using
Google Documents we create drafts of the
wiki pages on which we were able to
command as developers for reviews and
then copy and then past in the wiki and
then reformat to markdown well I try to
forget this moment but it's hard to
remove it from my mind and I still feel
the taste of that but hopefully I knew
we were going to change his own another
thing we needed was to make it easy to
contribute to the documentation we
needed not because one way to grow
community around a product is to enable
to contribute to more than just the code
and I would like to use this
touken so to invite any of you to ever
look to order mutation and try to
contribute if you like if you help us
many ways because you will grow the dark
but also you will ask question outside
of our comfort zone and you will
certainly have a different point of view
so to be honest we will come any
criticism just please be polite so back
to our requirements and miss all the
content related requirements we also
wanted to be able to adapt the visual
theme to Pegasus graphical style the
goal was to make the dark more
attractive then people more inclined to
incline to contribute at least it's a
wish and to check if these choices could
really help our duck to be more
attractive we needed a way to extract
used age statistics of our tool that we
always use and we use it we useful or
website is Google Analytics and I bling
feedback was also requirement close to
statistic it's usually some common tools
but the goal is more to improve on
things user really requested also
checking links was a must-have to the to
itself had to provide that but some help
from Google search console was possible
also an automatic table of content
navigation was requirement we had to add
a table of content manually on the wiki
so in 2019 it's not really something you
want to do also as modern language is a
bit limited when it comes to complex
content like code examples math formulas
cable shortcuts and so on and I had
about Python margin extensions I really
wanted to be able to use them or at
least some similar system I think
search engine was also something we
wanted to provide to our users
in fact because Giller engine is nice
but it's written too many things and
display findings in my own file as
source code and we can comply because
github is made for source code so that's
it's doing exactly what we expecting to
do and finally we like the idea of
having features like and a flying PDF or
HTML version of our doc and the ability
to use our own domain name and some of
the things that get a wiki was not able
to provide so shooting a dog to Shane
and process is not easy we had too many
options one of our equipment that I did
not indicate previously was time we did
we didn't have much time and no one has
but more than time to put this in place
the time we lacked all that we did not
want to allocate was time to maintain
this tool Shane this requirement quickly
excluded the self hosted solution but
get a pages to get a pages is just a
hosting and doesn't provide any tools to
generate the content this option will
perhaps come back later but today two
big option I don't feel driving that
also we are still making experiments so
if we have to trash all work because we
should wishes the wrong way I'd rather
trash lightwork than a huge one then
within the Clewiston
tools we had a few options to the master
view Swann was redacted org that filled
almost all the requirements we had the
only exotic aspect of institution if
that we decided to use MK dogs instead
of things because of the ease of use and
also because I found a material design
theme for MK dogs that I really wanted
to use yes I admit it's a very light
argument but as I said we wanted to make
the migration as
as possible so having a theme where you
could just change a few CSS was ideal so
what's the setup we put in place let's
see what ship to use a base camp with
the ducks that org is the clued service
we're using it's free and provides it's
it's free but you can donate it's a free
project so I really ask you to have a
look at it if you if you didn't already
did that
it provides your thing it provides a
link with get up using a web hook it
enables version if you created a tagged
release in your repository and it also
supports custom domain names and calyx
is a Python tool to generate static
documentation site from modern content
we use it with a material design theme
that far more interesting than the
default read the docs theme shipped with
MKX we're not using the rid deduct theme
so it required some adjustment and
specifically to display read the docs
version box it's a box you can find on
the bottom right corner of documentation
site where you can switch from one
version to the other and it required
some hacking in the in the theme to do
that we installed a bunch of - modern
extension for lighting and abbreviation
math formulas tab code blocks footnotes
and some more writing style guides is
also in progress to explain how to
contribute technically but also on the
content part using the new tools
required a few adjustments of course we
had some technical writers that work not
so that we're not so technical one so we
had to teach them how to use git we had
to update all modern content we
previously generated we had to update
clean
than syntax to use new extensions we had
to configure and test the system using
forked repertory so we were not working
on the real repositories
we had to write a style guide which is
still in process and we also learned how
to review documentation and create PRS
because it was easily developer work so
for me it was ok but for technical
writers it was somewhat some new process
we use documentation labels in github
and JIRA in order to isolate the pure
doc PRS and C's doc pr's needing dr.
code Piazza at our knitting Docs and to
his isolate name from the pure code Pro
request so what's next
we have this system in place and today
we have to finish the contribution
guidelines and have contributors reading
it we have to gather enough analytics to
you tell if pages have to be reworked
and if the experiments we try are
working or not we already received and
taken account a lot of feedback
feedbacks that users and contributors
are going to send to us for that we will
probably put a feedback tool like Hajj
are in place on the side we already know
that we are going to expand the map
where structural and implementation
design is not easy to figure for users
there's a huge demand for this and we
also have to use a new system and make
it live see if its limitation see its
limitation and then define the new
requirements for the next system and now
I use the map we have real data not much
but some of it and it's growing we
already see the places we have to fix we
can help
experts point telescopes to the right
directions
but the most important thing is that we
know for real because we have metrics
then with the camp we go back home we
rest a bit and show findings to
colleagues after that we'll plan the
next expedition with a bigger Trek and
more tools I don't know what it's going
to be to be a nest oh and did you know
that Antarctica is the only continent
where consensus is not present as for
know of course so if you have any
questions remorse and feedbacks please
we have still six minutes left
yes not yet ah we have only an English
version for it but the two E's read the
docs is able to a little translation but
I admit we are first creating the
content in English we first have to
provide a good basis for content and
then we're going to translate it I'm
French so I'm going to help translating
in French but I don't know if we have an
as any other people able to translate in
other languages yeah
yes in fact it's exactly in the same
repository it's in a / Doc's folder at
the root of the project so it's time a
user makes a change on the code so
adding a new feature changing a behavior
changing a command-line feature or
something like that we require in order
to change the documentation or at least
seed a new documentation page and then
all writers are going to remove this
content what do you mean by begin the
decommission that's not in the code and
the code is okay no we we just for the
minimal time it did not it did not have
n so with what we are going to do is
probably rebuild a tag of the of the
repository but we are not going to
publish a new version of the binaries of
the of the program for instance yeah it
really depends off the person
some are just learning with five-minute
examples and some never were never
learned so it depends No what we do is
that we practice programming so we
practice peer writing T and then we work
on the real content and we teach them
how to use the tool with using video
conference we assume for video
conferences and then we do the work
together live and I show them how to use
the tool how to commit how to push and
thing like that yep
now everything is into the same URL we
have the code source code in a github
repository with slash ducks folder on
the root of the the repository and rid
the ducks is triggered to build this
slash docs folder each time we push a
new content to the master branch and it
creates a new bill each time we create a
tagged release of the software in this
repository so everything is on the same
reporter is there's no sub project in
the original dog something like that
everything is as I don't know if I
answered your question exactly
we don't add this case to be an F but
what you could do and what what the way
I would do that is to have probably a
third repository or some github pages
and thing like that where you would put
an concatenated version of your
documentation or if you don't want to do
that I would use sub projects in read
the docs as a feature to make
sub-project so on the same URL you can
have different documentation so you can
see that they are part of the same thing
but not exactly the same way you if you
use the same theme and same templates
and everything it could be enough I
guess I did not explore things a lot
because of this margin requirement I
know things does mark down but I clearly
don't really know this stuff on things
the the best tool we use is includes in
MK Docs and perhaps if you work with get
sub modules or thing like that you can
achieve the same thing but it's may be
it may be more complicated and to be
clear this set up is because what we are
working on is is on the same repository
if we had another project set up we
probably would have used other tools or
other way to configure them
we it requires it requires we have a
previous system it requires the
installed Python on your computer but
it's not a big deal and then you can
just run MK doc serve on the on the the
root folder and then you can view it in
your browser on the locals address and
it's very nd the only thing you don't
have is the version check box form m'kay
dogs but vom read the docs but that's
all
[Applause]