- our first roof talk and welcome
aleksander the roof maintainer yeah so
my name is Alex and frost I'm a well
Ruka maintainer i'm just decided i'm a
deaf ops engineer at claude ability and
today i'm kind of going over using route
or well yeah using work in kubernetes to
run surf in kubernetes and kind of going
into like what are the the what are the
advantages of doing that and yet firm
agendas are kind of like what is wrong a
bit of either Yahoo tech chure Frug a
bit into like the integration with
kubernetes that well in the end most of
the time you want to use the self
storage you're running with fruit inside
of your kubernetes cluster for your
applications would say I don't know like
it my skill database or something and
then well the advantage is kind of like
how can it help you doing that and one
part which probably falls flat you do
technical issues on with my laptop well
I'll see if I can get some informations
on we're something out that we kind of
get a demo of the creation of a cluster
and also how easy it is done in Cuba
needs to consume the storage there and
the world you're adding and removing a
new node to the cluster to a safe
cluster in the end we'll have to see
yeah Anini and just like a viral a few
more points there and yeah so Brooke is
a cloud native storage Orchestrator
cloud native everybody talks about it
it's well those does cool cloud thing
you know it's specifically made for
being
in kubernetes yeah which simply employ
over in the end implies that it's in the
container so it's basically a cloud
native container storage Orchestrator
and frutos for this orchestration ruk
well can run for example safe but also
other storage software's which I will
come back later on for you in your Cuban
is just on the special point which yeah
kubernetes allows through the
extensibility of the kubernetes api is
that you have the possibility of create
your own custom types and also well in
the end controllers which react to these
custom types in kubernetes more on that
layer and in general the goal here is
that for the orchestration part we try
to have the deployment automated as best
as possible bootstrapping of the
software of the form in this case self
cluster the configuration provisioning
scaling upgrading my creation disaster
recovery monitoring and resource
management those are all points which we
try to cover not all of them those
points are covered yet but well it's
officers we are happy to see people help
us reach the goal of full automation of
your yeah functional safe cluster in
kubernetes as I already said a bit
earlier chef Brooke it's not only safe
safest one of the many search providers
that you can run for you
for example Mineo which is the object
search maybe you've heard about it then
there's also from an eccentric is it was
a GFS it's well kind of in the direction
of like safe which provides block search
file storage and also object search but
in a more like well in I think they have
a huge point and like gear replication
by default kind of inner definitely
rough to check it out
and Samara to which I have light almost
light which are currently on in Ruge
it's well made Fossum it's open source
it's especially with this good fast it's
hosted by a cloud native computing
foundation it's currently in the
incubating state in Hue pater state off
the of the scene CF project level
yeah root framework s Luke is not only
therefore just running safe but also for
mania HFS and so on Luke tries to get a
generalization of certain types which
are common across across those multiple
starch backends so for example to say it
will for example the safe and HFS the
selection of the devices on nodes is the
same there isn't there are no two types
which are different this is one type
where we basically have a list with some
more details with which we go in later
two of which devices to use and only
already with those common specifications
specs used between multiple storage
providers its most of time pretty easy
to well now that I would to recommended
too much' tube instead of like distro
hopping as you storage software hop all
the time but he and something would be
possible because you could just copy and
paste the device list from safe for
example into HDFS or go back again yeah
with the framework part of route there
we not only try to have this common
ground of specifications we simply also
try to have combine testing efforts that
makes it easier for all those platforms
to which have to our own operator in
route to be well tested together have
policies and stuff just share the code
that is not like every operator which
for example would run something like
safe like HFS and
are not possible software bekanze
bekanze that they don't need to write it
from scratch all the time so that's one
of the goals with the root frameworks
basically they're no the architecture of
Rooke it's well it's going a bit into
companies right now here is we're kind
of a general look right now here we have
two companies API we have client utility
which we can use to talk with the
company's API and kuba nice uses entity
for a datastore of the API objects and
if we basically start from here we have
our client utility with which we tell
the kubernetes api we tell them about
these new objects so that in the end we
end up with objects like safe cluster
safe block pool safe object server files
and well for the add operators if you
install them to obviously those two when
we have created those objects we can
access them again just run alike for
this knowing about cube cut' alike you
ever get surf cluster and we get the
object as it is currently in API and in
more common more more current releases
of companies I think with one something
twelve thirteen or so you even get some
more information about the object as it
is if you simply run the cube cutter
gets to well retrieve the object from
the kuba nice API so that you have a
quick overview of if hasn't been created
successfully
how many monitors I'm a running and just
some general information moving on to
the operators s set were to multiple
storage pagans for example we have two
self-operated air them with mini
operator and so on for each search back
and operator and the operator basically
takes care of creating the deployments
the DMM sets and all that is needed to
run the storage software so for safe it
would be creating deployments for the
monitors creating monitor deployments
for
these and all other components like
manager manager MDS RGV and then Elsa
for example configure certain aspects in
the manager like enable the dashboard
and fortune will enable the SSL on it
disabled as long it's stuff like that in
its making it simple by this is possible
again because we have one common object
DSF cluster object here if this one
object with which you root operator
knows how to handle it and as all the
options we support in it which you can
just go ahead add it for not all options
right now but for a good amount of
options you can go ahead like turtle the
dashboard on the fly if you have it on
false when you create a D cluster
initially and just go edit it put
through and apply it against the Cuban
es API and the root operator will pick
up this change and do its thing and
enable the dashboard now moving on to
this part here we are this is basically
like we are on the node right now here
the demons are obviously for let's say
for example surf
we have a monitor no steer well one of
the surf demons which is placed on a
node if well am on is placed and idea
you want to use the disks on a node also
for storage you would well obviously
also have Ostia teams running on that
but all containerized so there's no like
well conflict with other stuff running
on the system it's well in container so
well there are certain the differences
between which run tight container and
time you use from the oscillation level
but they are isolated at least so spare
the container part there is else at the
point where the upgrading for ruk is
also making it easier because we just go
add in the deployment which for example
would run in OSD there we'll just go
ahead
to the convenience API and say hey
change you it from self version 12
something to version 13 something and
for the other is basically the same same
update aspect comes in place - because
Cooney is just this management for us
then there's also diruk agent the
location is in our current case the so
called yeah root flex volume provider
plugin provider this is a well flex
volumes kind of like te predecessor of
CSI kind of in kubernetes where sees
eyes to contain a storage interface
which well kind of name implies is like
a common interface for storage
not only thing for containers but in
general for the storage and flex volume
is kind of like that - but more on a
limited scale as I know especially for
Cuban Easter and we have it we have it
running right now still with flex volume
or it's more or less to the point
because of cuban ease with having seized
I support unstable my beta our stable
with version 113 and we're well
currently serving like the last three
versions of cubanía so we still have to
have the Flex volume but to the Flex
premiere if I have a pot which wants to
use a volume on this note it was it was
na the cubelet the note component of
companies would call out to d2 a socket
on a note the Flex volume socket - and
then the root agent would receive this
request and then well go ahead get the
information of the volume and do the RBD
mapping and and the RVD mounting one
quick note II cubelet I think is in most
cases doing the formatting of the volume
so yeah yeah I think you boy yeah
formatting you somebody couplet which
yeah
I'm tryna sector
so you mean the block diversity if I
mount to map the volume Geocities
correctly the question is that how are
you s DS able or getting the access to
the block devices I well right now it is
simply done by mounting the slash def of
them host into the container they are
our ways I think specially through what
was it local persistent storage local no
search from kubernetes which has been
introduced I think like 1.9 point when
AI think yeah which could potentially be
used for this exactly purpose we were
still kind of looking into how we can
make it use it like this but we're kind
of like right now our staff is basically
working for us our so but we also look
already at least looking into
restricting your slash def access to
just the device and already partitions
that are on this disk and for nice FST
but it there's still a good amount of
work to do to get there but yeah so yeah
so if I create the route self operator
and then go ahead and create a group
safe cluster object to well I have as
already said in a previous example here
we have the edge in
port which is running in all nodes and
the operator then as that takes care of
creating the Ceph component parts like
here is these the monitors manager MDS
RGB is also there and well any NGO of a
safe class above that so to summarize
this part we have this custom object
with kind safe cluster which we the root
operator the roof safe operator has
defined you created and what you
currently with that would get is now
we're as safe cluster running safe
version thirteen point two point four or
something something and ignoring your
data the weld a lady host person ruckus
right now we're most configured and
monitor data but we're working on trying
to well make it really just for
configuration may still mom data but not
all these because right now the behavior
would be it if you don't specify like
this scenario and anything else you
would get an OSD using a directory of
well basically faster directory OSD
which well if you have this from
performance vices way better the this
one is way better yeah but coming back
here we have like the dashboard part
here where we say yeah we want the -
professor we have enabled through we can
control a bit about the monitors like
how many do we want if you want multiple
monitors on one note this is if you have
well only free now it's you may or may
not want this to happen or if you have
multiple nodes you normally want to
disable there's modern for your notes
for example because then you already
have a room to move a monitor from a
node which failed to another node and
well create a new monitor there
basically this part was the start here
is here for example use all nodes use
all devices is kind of like controlling
there's more to control but
those two options are kind of allowing
you to select where starch will be used
and what storage will be used with the
user notes it's kind of well use all
note states the rook operator can place
Oh STIs on it which I'll put a lock that
valid in Cuba nice aspect I use all
notes would imply that all MT devices
will be used for no SD and if we go if
we skip a few slides ahead we come back
again to this storage configuration part
where we have again those use all notes
and use all devices instead of for
example having use all now it's true
that all nodes which are applicable will
be used we could also specify a list of
notes which will have information on the
next slide we can eat also have a simple
device further where we go yeah use all
this with SD and well wild card
basically and then it root will take all
disks with this matching rags
besides disks that are not empty
there's also possibility to specify
certain configuration parameters not
only in a cluster wide level but also on
a note and even OSD part level where in
this case for example we have like
option which normally is only used for
nvme or well fast faster than names of
these devices this the how many OS these
should be created per device and if we
go just there one further we are at the
notes list here and there you can see
that for example you have this note
you say well user directory have those
resource limits in place from Cuba
nearsighted container the OSD container
for this director for this for this node
as it's on a node level here will have
those resource limits in place then for
example here with for device you have to
note name and in this case specifically
say hey use SD B but you can also again
if it would be for example and
it's the second or the second device
here you could then specify like config
and then all these per device like free
or well insert the mouth for and we
media versus how many of these here
basically and there we even have it
obviously spell device where you can
just have it per device and are on node
level on cluster wide level so that's
not all just have to find where I left
off yeah yeah to sharply go into the
feral cubanía native integration part
besides the so called customer source
definition those custom types objects we
can create we already have in Cuba nice
storage classes which allow us the admin
most of the time to specify which
provisioner and certain parameters for
this provisional to be called the ft
above the provisioner will be called if
you create a volume now a persistent
volume claim if it matches this storage
class if it has two storage class in it
cuba knees will take care of talking
with the provision and saying hey
somebody requested 20 gigs of storage
for example if we go further here just
example we've started 20 gigabytes of
search and here we specify the storage
class name so it would especially use
the one we just saw if we create this
this will result in 20 gigawatts of
search that's kind of our company's
takes well takes over in point of like
storage management s cuban east has all
the persistent volume claims which are i
hope for everyone using them always
reflect the claims an application has
made like hey I need five hundreds of
storage so it's always are this
application is using 500 gigs of storage
and any background it's kind of like a
knots on twelve application
you have to persistent volumes which are
again also having the information like
which search class has been used to
create as volume how much largest is
actually what access mode is used like
companies has free access modes where
the first is read read once which is
well only one can read and write to it
the second is rewrites many where well
many can read and read and write me at
any time at at the same time and there
is read only many which well many can
read only at the same time yeah so what
can rule kind of do to make its well if
you have a surf class or especially
because well you even need you to run a
safe cluster make it better for you to
well run the surf closer in Cuba knees
will especially I said if you have fun
if you don't have one and you're like
yeah let's go it's might be a bit
problematic because you need to know
there's a bit of staff of kubernetes
it's well simple fact that if you start
one higher with a platform and then puts
it on its it should have knowledge of
how to platform patois true class is as
we heard health checking for monitor so
if you have let's say five nodes and you
currently live just for simplex example
reasons have your monitors one on the
first node second on the second and
third on the third and third node would
fall it would fail it would move this
monitor fail it in the cluster and move
it over to the let's say node four or
five which are available for that the
simple management simply referred to
Cuba you say anything for the company's
API endpoint that you have those Djamel
manifests kind of - yes say and put it
like this with infrastructure as a code
kind of it's yeah more more well not
only info
sure has a code but kind of application
employment as a code depending on how
far you see it you have those yellow
files which define how yourself trust I
should look how which pools should be
created you just have a yellow fire
which says here pool object with decent
this name
how many replication should use a racial
code and shreds which failure man which
as the MLB actors well you just shoot
cattle create it to the company's API
and you have it if your pool created in
a few seconds and it makes it easier on
that side too well manage those things
too if also for example same here too
it's not like where you oh I want you to
use file system let me buy five servers
and install self and well setup and yes
we've said we're frugal you would need
to put committees on it and then just
create a file system object which has in
has the size numbers and everything like
for the pools again forests file system
what else old numbers like how many
active monitor MDS do you want
should there be standby MDS to and just
gives you a bit of well my playground
not to say like about a good amount of
room to have certain options and have
that automatically happen
same for RGB you have an object
concurrent roll it through that have
certain options to control behavior of
the pools or how they should look yeah
and the third point I would like to
bring up here is yet as we saw with a
surge selection again there you have a
self cluster object you have will eat
our list of nodes or more generalize the
device filter of something where I say
use those disks in the 40 class or even
directories right now which just as a
side note for the storage selection
selection we have Travis Neilson which
is also working on a root project
looking into enabling LVM kind of with
two cell volume before cell for the
young part to be created wealth rousseff
codes
well no self care and not as
stands in since the release of serial
nine now it's done not not for all cases
like that anymore
for rubes own well it was the
preparation pair partitioning formatting
and so on process now will we already
went through that well the why root pad
is kind of covered by what you would get
us benefits if you have a cluster four
or something like that but so kind of in
generate simplifies certain tasks for
the storage back-end there's SF still
somewhere like for example replacing a
note right now still a bit of manual
process but we're getting there it's
more or less that kind of a bit of a
class like should we listen on the notes
that are in a class and then react if
one it goes missing for all its already
just not ready or just some point where
for whatever reason maybe an SD issue or
something there's an empty noticeably
get around nothing to run so just grab
it all kind of but well is that we're
happy to just well see people maybe just
chime in on the discussions on those
topics yeah self managing partners
counters well we don't have lifeless
probes and readiness trips for all self
components but we think we have at least
for a miniature right now and for a
monitor we do kind of external half
checking from the operator side to see
is it well is this monitor ceiling for
more that we need to fail it over to a
new node yeah and the part of the
dynamic provisioning there that I create
a claim and few seconds later my block
device and my block volume in surf has
been created and linked with Cuba knees
fruit a persistent volume object is well
it's a breeze too if you want to run
with applications we don't need to like
well fill in a ticket say I hey I need
20 gigs of storage can you please
provide it to me and someone starts
running through the dataset and finds
the tries to find the data or something
for you but it's simply dynamic there
which
it's pretty pretty good for well
especially for developers we are also
interesting with kind of like with the
guys from across plane IO Jarid Watson
bar some tabara if I cut his name
correctly we're looking into also trying
to give get more abstraction in like for
example and developer woods yeah I need
a pocket so it just creates a bucket
object and for example for we also have
support for cockroach free beer so we
would obviously SS the database also
want to look into having database object
which we develop I would just create and
then in some way that which is kind of
still up for discussion should it be a
service broker should we collect it do
some magic like with in companies will
mounting a direct or incident the pot
which contains the credentials for some
of them through this database or so so
again there if you want to kind of jam
in there we're happy to have discussion
on that the last point here in this list
is well it's it's depending on depending
on how you see it one problem I think is
which is still existing for AV AWS which
T there versus EBS block storage from
Amazon I think what was the failover
time was like when a node failed it
would take a things like five minutes or
so to failover to an era node and well I
hope you're only running cloud native
application so it shouldn't be a problem
as you have ignored and wanna Africa but
it's still kind of and not too good
numbers use even though it's tor native
and it should be okay with failure of a
part or in multiple parts in your
cluster multiple applications it's still
kind of a bummer if like five minutes in
the case of a failure of a bottom so
that's kind of where
I'm kind of saying it's less vendor
logon because of all you would run a
safe class so which yeah only one hand
could also create more maintenance
instead of for example taking care of
just the EBS volumes of Amazon but you
fell over is in this case for example
faster or you just don't have to use
their storage yeah yeah s kind of yeah
sat in the beginning it's not only safe
there's not only a roof safe operator
yes also mini operator which will this
object searcher we have a mini object
storage object may have felt a cockroach
GB which well we right now we only have
a cover she be object but I guess again
we are open for people commenting and
discussing with us how we can go the
best path if it's more of a service
broker approach or not approach HFS has
been implemented by the neck center guys
just there again also a big shout-out to
them as it's a huge work it's not like
but it's not like a mineral we have like
two or three replicas of owners rightful
said only but there's again a kind of
like safe more complexity simply behind
it it's amazing to see them have
implemented it in a in ruk and also they
are using certain parts of their root
framework and NFS server as is minion
cooked Russia beer and well jeff has to
implement a thanks to community so yeah
well I don't have to do that more right
now get to this page first if you want
to get involved
we aren't github I think some people are
still on get up but get love we have a
page which we are currently we re
working so if you're right now like
where do you find this and this we are
working on it we know of the problem
and well we have a slack Channel slack
you know it's a whole slack for our own
yeah if you want to join we also have
four conferences channel and well if you
have questions our channel channel and
so on
well Twitter we we have them we still
have a mailing yes I think and there's
community meetings every second week
yeah I would just run to the questions
right now so the question was that
there's an option to run multiple
monitors on the same note yes there are
certain people's which probably run
route with just one nodes and once you
can't free so yes yes officially and web
development purpose are able to sync
from an existing at least as long as we
still have one but no I'm curious what
is the storage back-end for those
monitors
just your plain disk so let me repeat
the question so the question is for
Daman failover kind of how does the data
get to the other node or dusty data even
gets copied from the node which failed
to not well to the other node which is
send a new monitor no it doesn't get
copied it's a brand new monitor which
well just a new territory which for what
was it like just a mono is sent here
talk to them and as you said tender
synchronization basically kicks in for
monitors and the new monitor should be
well up to speed in a few seconds so the
question is that if a monitor fails what
will kind of happen to the pod standard
juice storage so from safe sites the
monitor list is always kind of level to
be lighter fluid so if one monitor fails
well it's still in a list of the
conflicts most of the time so if you
bring up a new monitor and its back in
the we're talking with Yarra monitors
he's this new Monmouth is basically very
well very new the new monitors in it
will be kind of disputes to use these or
wealthy applications again at least as
far as I'm concerned
a new monitor and not just reusing yes
we're creating a whole new good question
so the question is how does the network
layer or whether how does the network
kind of well what would be the network
layer if you for some of then put surf
on it and you have flow of 5,000 other
applications running in a class all
right kind of okay so to kind of extend
on what I just said on a further
question it's going into the direction
of separating the Ceph trafficked
replication traffic and decline traffic
right now you would go and use host
network mode which well currently
cominius state is that you only have one
interface per pod well if your host
network you get a note notes networks X
which has other advantages and or
disadvantages say like this but at least
to go a bit further into the scene I
part therefore companies there are
multiple I think two or three projects
right now which allow you to define
multiple sinaia plugins in your in
account for conflict somewhere and then
have multiple interfaces in your pods
which I think in pull at least well I
heard it from intellect like containers
where they showed it off for like VoIP
stuff and so on
and for whatever it seemed to pretty
work pretty good but right now a host
network would be the way to go but yeah
[Applause]