okay so my name is Tomoko Ann and today
I'll be talking to you about challenges
will building entered encrypted
applications based on my learnings from
Etta sync I originally gave this talk
yesterday they unfortunately due to some
issues I have to do it again today just
to record it in an empty room so no
crowds just me and you let's begin so
Who am I am I'm a long time open source
dev and I'm a privacy and digital
security enthusiasts and maintainer and
creator of at the sink which I'll cover
in a moment and I'm currently building a
security start up with entrepreneur
first which is kind of like a startup
accelerator that essentially invests in
you free team free idea and just gives
you a stipend to work and cool stuff
that you think are amazing so check them
out if you're interested and so what is
at the sink so anything is a secure and
enter an encrypted and fully versioned
and personal information sync for
Android the desktop and the web we
currently do contacts and calendar and
tasks as well but we have more things
more things planned
it's obviously completely open source
you can self host they're like docker
images and whatever and but also I run a
managed service if you want to use that
and I mean unlike I like dab and for
example your your all of your
information is encrypted also in the
servers also at rest so even if the
server is hacked nothing nothing leaks
so let's talk a bit about Edison so
Edison the bass the bass part of editing
is unencrypted and tamper-proof
journal so essentially you have the
address book or the calendar for example
and every change in those collections is
tracked so you have I added a cannon
added a contact I delete the contact
added a meeting I modify the meeting
everything is tracked so think of it
like sort of an encrypted in integrity
check to get and and this is this is the
basic building block so this prevents a
lot of tampering removing entries all of
that protects against all of this and
now I'm gonna the next two slides are a
bit heavy I'm sorry about that but I
promise it's only those two so let's
talk about how the encryption keys are
derived
so first of all we use script to derive
the key from the user email and password
and then we derive a key every journal
based on the journal idea ID the reason
why it's important is because when you
share journals among similar users and
you want to make sure that the key is
different every time so we had to modify
it based on a journal and and the last
heavy slide is how is the data actually
encrypted so we use AES in CBC mode and
we use the journal encryption key from
before we encrypt we compare all
standard encryption and then we use H
Mac which is a sort of signature but
about symmetric encryption so it's an
integrity check and we make sure the
version hasn't changed and essentially
everything that's available we then
generate a random identification code
for the journal just so we know how to
refer it in a way that doesn't leak
information because if we called it
address book the server would know it's
an address book so we want to keep it
you know completely and completely non
leaky and then when it comes to the
entries themselves we take the previous
identifier but the identifier of the
previous entry and then we encrypt the
entry as before but this time we use the
previous entry as well in the integrity
check to make sure that no entries are
removed or reordered as I mentioned and
again a key part of the encryption okay
so this is it about at the sink and I
just needed a baseline it's more for the
people following at home or following
with the slides just so you know what's
going on and let's talk about some of
the challenges I mean obviously this is
from the point of view of Edison and so
long term story storage of stuff in
portable journals and but also
everything a lot of other things that
apply to a lot of other end-to-end
encryption applications and the first
thing to keep in mind is platform
portability so in end-to-end encryption
the server is unaware of the of anything
so everything is has to be implemented
on every client so all the clients need
encryption libraries so for example if
you want to have you want to have an
elliptic curve support you will need to
make sure that every client has support
for that because
first of all you don't want to implement
your own cryptography it's damn hard
frustrating but also it could lead to
insecurity and also if you use a
hardware token so for example a Yubikey
like I use or if your mobile phone has a
secure area secure zone to make it to do
encryption stuff and it's good to know
in advance that those actually supported
before you go and unroll and you know
release everything and obviously we also
want library support for our protocols
on all the platforms so if anything
relies heavily on vCard and iCal and I'd
trust me I don't want to re-implement
all of those specifications on every
platform I go it's hard enough to
implement all the code on every platform
you really want to make sure that
support is available for the format you
choose
and and as I said you need to call it
the same code on every platform and when
it comes to accounting linearization
there's another challenge which is M
everything is implemented every client
so and every client you need to have the
initialization code so for example a net
sync you want to have a default address
book and a different current and a
default calendar so when users start
using it they get those so you need to
have it on every client because you
don't know where which is the first
client they'll be using maybe it's the
Android app maybe it's the desktop
bridge and the same goes with upgrade
code and so if you want to change
something and you want to have code that
updates the information accordingly you
need you need a way to so you need you
need the code to actually do the
updating and yeah so you need the code
to actually do the updating itself so
it's so it's available the new version
is available and it ended on every
client because otherwise it won't be
available and and of course you need to
support past and current protocol
versions on every client and because
otherwise otherwise some you know the
new code won't be available on that
client and that will just not work so
you need to make sure that all of them
all of them are available when you
unleash and release and all of them are
available for the past versions because
you can change it and one solution is to
have a sort of a master client which is
in editing is the android client
that we assume most people use that so
we have the upgrade code or the init
code we was released there before it was
released everywhere else but this is a
hack and it's much better to have it on
every client and another thing about
protocol upgrade is that every client
needs to support the new version so
either you need to update all of them
simultaneously which is a bit hard
without droid and for example this is a
this is a bug report from a user that it
took a long time for version 1.0 to be
released on f-droid I think a month
after Google Play so it's very hard to
plan for that and the other alternative
is first deploying support and after
that deploying the upgrade logic
essentially a long waiting time this is
good practice anyway but it's really
slow when you're just trying to iterate
on a product and providing a lot of
value for your users very quickly in the
early stages another challenge with
protocol upgrades is that you cannot
transform the data on the server so
usually what you do in applications you
will have API v1 which is what you
created in the beginning and then the
old application they've accessed at the
API and that's fine and then when you
want to add new API you just add a new
entry the app calls the new one and the
server automatically translates in the
background the information between API
version 1 and 2 so because the server
can access the data they can just do it
we cannot do it in enter an encryption
applications because the data is just
not available to the server so you have
to you know you have to be aware of that
it's like normal practice that you just
cannot do and we also need as I
mentioned before need to handle
gracefully handle future versions so if
you decide to change the app version at
some point you want the old versions not
to crash but rather you know pop up a
message hey this is a version I don't
recognize please upgrade the client or
something like that rather than crashing
so just important to remember because we
cannot have this compatibility layer so
what is considered a protocol upgrade so
literally every damn thing is considered
protocol upgrade and you want to I don't
know shuffle the data spit the data add
color to a calendar remove anything you
do
is a change of the protocol and if
you're not careful about allowing that
and be able to enter that you can have
crashes so it's very important to watch
out for that and obviously changing
geography metro methods is one of them
so if you want to add elliptic curve
support or I don't know a post quantum
you know lattice based encryption all of
that you have to change a protocol and
that would be a break and you also if
you want to change you know parameters
to the encryption current encryption so
for example to the script derivation
function um you realize that maybe the
original parameters you chose we're not
strong enough and you want to change
that you just it's a break and you need
to make sure that all it clients know
how to deal with that and so changing
the structure of the data which I
already mentioned and literally every
other thing you can think of you also
need to be aware of development speed so
development speed obviously is much
slower I mean did I mention that
everything needs to be implemented on
every time client so you have to have it
on Android and iOS if you support that
on the desktop on the web literally
everywhere you implement it you have to
you know double your efforts you have to
you have to take that into account
before embarking on a feature change or
or literally any sort of planning also
the back debugging is really a pain so I
mean you can't really ask for data and
when you do you're not really gonna get
it I mean the whole point of end-to-end
encryption is not trusting anyone so you
can't just go like hey I know I said
don't trust anyone but can you trust me
and give me all the data this is a
really bad idea so you just don't do it
and again if you do it most people say
no no access to data make it very hard
to investigate issues so usually what
you do you oh this breaks okay I'm gonna
have it gonna try play with it a bit
debug you know try to figure out what's
going on you just cannot do it so you
really just been you know doing it
blindly and you know trying to figure
out what's going and so you can't also
test the changes that you've been doing
so if you realize oh I think I fixed
you try to run you cannot run it on the
existing data and like you would
normally you have to give it to the user
get back the feedback and it's really
hard when the user is not technical or
not especially if they're not a
developer because they don't know how to
debug they usually give you incomplete
information because they don't know what
you're expecting to get so they say like
oh it crashed when it actually just
popped up a message that's saying you
know something went wrong or things like
that so it's really really hard and
really time-consuming and obviously you
can also cannot look into the data for
affected users if you have you cannot
just go for all of your user base and
say like oh you you and you I noticed
your are affected by this issue please
upgrade or whatever you just can't
another thing that's important to
consider is third-party applications so
normally you would want third-party
application support so as I said at the
sink supports contacts calendars and
tasks I would love to have a notes
support the problem is I don't and it
would be trivial normally like writing a
module to any of the existing and open
source note-taking applications the
problem is we do not trust those
applications it's not because we do not
trust the people behind it it's just
they don't work in the same security
secure environment that we try to work
in so we don't want you know we don't
want them to be handling passwords or
encryption passwords or story encryption
passwords and also to be honest we don't
want to normalize this behavior without
users we don't want to tell our users
hey could you please you know you know
could um enter your password in that
application to get it set up we don't
want to normalize that and because this
is how fishing begins essentially and
another thing that's more unique to
Edison is that immutability so because
the journal is immutable and you can't
fix save malformed in from err data so
if you had a bug in the past that
included malformed information in the
journal you can't fix that and so you
have to deal with that bug for the rest
of eternity and you also can't update
the save format so even if you decided
to you know to change the format and you
already have all the upgrade god and all
the clients like we discussed you still
have to support the old format because
it's immutable
again for all eternity and you guessed
it on all their clients and their of
course a few usability issues to keep in
mind so first of all having both an
encryption and a login password is a big
pain you know like everything else in
this talk it's solvable you can have
those one of those login magic links or
whatever via email but that's a bit more
overhead it's a bit you know it's a bit
clunky as well and you have to implement
it support it and maintain it and make
sure it works and also it's a bit of a
pain when it comes to self hosting
servers because they don't have this
whole infrastructure and another thing
encryption password encryption password
recovery is not straightforward at all
so I mean I've more than a few users
over the years came to me like hey you
know I forgot my encryption password can
you help me recover it and unfortunately
the answer is no I mean the whole point
of the service is that we cannot recover
your encryption password so again there
are ways what you can do for example is
generate a private public key pair on
the server and keep the private key for
yourself send the public key to the
client to encrypt and the encryption
password with that and then have the
users save that file and using that
combination of that file and the private
key on the server you can unlock that
and recover the key and but again this
is another security issue potentially
security with issue waiting to happen
and it's not trivial to expect the users
to save that file if they're not you
know if they forget the password maybe
they're going to lose the file as well
so it's not a solution but it's better
than what we have at the moment and
don't forget
I mean you are entering encryption
application encrypted applications so
you are held to a much higher standard
so one of the things where we had to do
with etta sync is one things we want to
do what editing is have a web app
everyone you know everyone use the web
it's sometimes you really here in a bind
you really just want to access it on
your phone although you don't have a
client or on another secure computer the
problem is how do you know that the
server has not changed the JavaScript of
the web app and now is now leaking in
all of your private information you
can't really know that the servers not
being hacked and is doing that so
essentially what I'm trying to say is
the moment you have a JavaScript based
and to an encryption application it's no
longer in turn
unless you take extra precautions which
is what we did with sign pages which is
essentially a web M it's a web extension
so a browser plugin that verifies the
PTP signature of the entire web app so
the way it works the developer would
sign the page actually you don't even
need to do it just for web app so you
can do it for your blog as well but the
developer would sign the page and then
the plug-in will verify as you can see
either a good signature or a bad
signature I let you there you go
alert you accordingly and could also
block you know block the loading of the
page and whatever else you want to do so
this is something that our users expect
from us and as mentioned before you
can't ask for any data this is part of
who you are and obviously you need to
watch off what you put into in the logs
and in debug information and don't leak
in any information there so there are a
few other things to watch out for so the
first thing is performance
considerations so you don't have any
server sides or any kind of processing
really normally if you have you know
IMAP client you would do the search you
type search and you do search on the
server you can't do it if the server
just cannot access the information so
what you do
you'd have to download all of the
information in advance and then either
process it or like search at all every
time or alternatively maintain a large
index which is a much smaller version
optimized version of the data that is
not full only for the searching and keep
that and keep that maintained so you can
search based on that and only download
that small part every time you do it
but again it's something to consider on
the bright side because you're
downloading everything locally you can
do offline work everything is much much
faster when you are doing local stuff so
that's you know it's a good and a bad
thing but just something to be aware of
and you also need to watch out for false
sense of security so revoking or
changing an encryption passwords and is
something that you would think is
trivial but actually it's not so one way
to do it is just encrypt the old key
with the new key and which is it's okay
and if you haven't been hacked and the
old key was strong enough it's not
deal the problem with that is that
everyone who ever had access to your
account or to your crip shinky will
still have it so if you ever shed that
journal and now you revoked access who
ever ever had access to that journal
will still have access potentially or if
your got hacked and you want to change
the password because of that you will
that hacker could have kept that
password at that encryption key so it
really does not protect you against all
of those which is I think the main
reason why you just changed their
passwords and another thing you can do
is really hold data and but that's a bit
problematic so the problem there two
things with it first of all it could be
computationally and bandwidth expensive
just like you know downloading gigs of
data re encrypting it uploading it again
but also the problem is with modifying a
lot of data at once is that you lose the
sort of integrity in in what I mean is
usually like usually what you want on
every or every change you want the human
to be able to review it and see like oh
you know a new contact that's weird or
why is that event deleted and if you
change a thousand and one so thousands
and ones you cannot have this manual
review so we actually you're reducing
the security by doing that so the best
solution is using an old key for the
past data because you assume that's
already compromised or at the very least
could be compromised and in a new key
for the new data but that's much more
complex and as I said you need to
implement on every dem client so it's a
lot of work and so another thing I mean
actually before that so last time I gave
the taupe and I gave it live yesterday
as someone asked what do we use actually
noticing so we use the first one which
is the less secure one but with massive
massive warnings like hey if there's any
chance you you know if it's a surgeon or
of any chance you've been hacked or
anything like that of that sort please
contact us and we'll help you figure it
out and because this is insecure and
just another thing so we can obviously
offer alternatives and but the question
then is how do you educate to use is how
you know I'm I just spent more than a
minute here explaining and giving you
examples of what the different them
minou differences that I'm sure not
everyone got it
so it's really hard to explain it to
users
since users don't usually read
documentation and you also need to be
aware of replay and downgrade attacks so
this is actually from my talk it's
awesome last year so you have to be
aware that even though you keep an
integrity you know you keep you encrypt
everything and you keep an integrity
check version of all the data the server
can still serve you an old version so
the old version was authenticated by you
and like marked by you and everything is
okay and it's all valid and like the
signature is valid and everything but
it's still a stale version so it could
be missing information like here it's
missing a calendar event or whatever so
just you know watch out for that and
again leaking user data is a struggle so
as we said before sensitive information
in logs and debug info is big concern
but even more important are those
because they people don't know about
those so mixing together user control
data and non user control data could be
very risky so for example the way in
some of the encryption I mean all of
them I guess work is using padding and
so if you have they work let's say you
encrypt four characters at a time just
to simplify it and if your input is five
characters it will round it up to eight
so using if you mix if you mix user
control and attack a controlled
information you could essentially leak
the length of the content which is again
leaks information very dangerous watch
out for that and another thing is
optimizations optimizations can often
lead to leaked data so for example
compress data compression could very
much lead to leaks so the way
compression works some of them is they
detect repeating strings in the text and
then they say like oh okay we have you
know space ke space ke it's actually
double instead of having it twice this
time we're going to refer to the last
time very good you know it saves us and
you know save us save us some data and
the problem with that is is that if the
attacker can control the information
they can really they can just like have
a brute-force attacks and try different
strings and then based on the output
and/or the length of the output they
know if they got it right or not so if
they would if for example
the attacker would change this to F it
would know that this you know so if it
was F it would not have been duplicated
but now it's e we know it's actually
compresses more so we we can extract
information this way and another thing
is using deduplication so one thing
that's very tempting is saying like oh I
have this one gigabyte long file and
this one as well I can ask the client to
just hash the file this does not leak
any information about the file and then
upload and call the file based on that
on its name that's how all the big you
know all the cloud providers the
duplicate information the problem with
that is that while the hash itself does
not leak any information the fact that
the same user and the different users
use the same have the same file is
already leaking more information that
you would like to leak and as I said
you're held to a higher standard and
another example that I very much like
comes from video and audio compression
so a common thing with video let's take
video for example so one way to do it I
mean the native way to do it is send you
a frame every second so every I mean
over 24 times a second over long so
essentially a fool think about PNG or a
picture a few times a second and this is
grossly inefficient especially if the
image does not change much I mean for
example you know in the last minute it's
been this this whole frame has been
almost the same so there's no reason why
to use the bandwidth so what they came
up with is variable bitrate encoding
compression so essentially it just
measures the Delta and information so so
how it only only M encodes changes
rather than the whole thing so if it
doesn't change much you know not a lot
of information is transmitted but one
big flaw with that is that let's assume
you have a drone just there outside the
window and I want to know if the drone
is spying on me or so if I can sniff
just sniff the the Wi-Fi signal let's
assume it's Wi-Fi base all I can see is
encrypted communication that's not a lot
but what I can do is I can open and
close the blinds a few times and then
just by the fact that a lot of data is
changed at once if I can see if I see a
spike in the amount of data transferred
on Wi-Fi that's correlates to my moving
the
the blinds I know that drone is watching
me and the same goes with you know bugs
in the room like if you see a
transmission you know recognized and you
know it spikes every time you speak
maybe you're being watched so just you
know a few unexpected ways where that I
can leak and another important aspect is
that the UI can make the whole
difference so one thing that I mentioned
earlier you want to inform the users
when the data is changed so they can you
know go past it like hey I did not
delete four entries so just like the
user will be able to know that they've
been compromised
and it's very important and another
thing is showing users how many devices
they have that are active in how many
encryption keys this is from
conversations the Android and the
Android the jabber client and that's a
good example and there are other
potential flaws and safeguards against
them that you need to check so just be
aware of those and now I want to touch
like for a few minutes sorry
on improving the editing protocol so one
big issue that we had that I'm actually
a bit annoyed with is we tied together
the username in the encryption key I
don't know if you remember from the one
of the earlier slides when we derived
the master chief from the email and the
password so it was a great hack it was
safe fast easy to implement the problem
with that is that users apparently want
to change their username especially when
the username is their email I had I
never considered that when when I
originally designed a protocol it makes
sense I really wish you know I want to
change it now so that's one thing that
I'm going to improve and unfortunately
also made the the user inconsistently
case sensitive so usually emails are not
but in Edison's case they kind of are
sometimes which is a big pain when it
comes to supporting you some users and
another thing I want to do is improve
the integrity of sources so this is
actually was this is from the one of the
earlier slides a bit misleading because
it looks like a fingerprint but actually
why it is it's an H Mac which is an
integrity check so essentially it's it's
okay
in almost every case but the problem is
when you have a sure Journal you can't
know which of the participants not in a
crypt of graph groups of
graphically sound way you can't know
which of the participants made each
entry which is a problem nowadays but
when Edison who has initially decided
designed there were no journals so was
never considered and another thing is
that everything that I talked about with
all the integrity checks just applies to
the journals themself but not the
existence of them or the lack of so I
want to have you know I want to
integrity check the global state and
have a counter for that so there's no
you know no replay attacks and no
downgrade attacks there and I also want
to move to paradise keys so you remember
a few slides ago from conversations that
would be extremely nice to have I mean
first of all it can better use hardware
tokens so the encryption key could just
never leave my yubikey or my secure and
clave on the phone that'll be great and
but also I mean also can endow loss
devices but most importantly that's what
I'm really excited about it's a very
good infrastructure for third party
supports because essentially if you have
an encryption keeper device you can also
have an encryption key pair app and then
you can just revoke or give access to a
certain app and in a cryptic
cryptographically sound way which is
great really great and I'm really
looking forward to having that and so
just a few finishing notes and I know it
all sounds very scary and I oh my god
this is so hard it's not that hard you
know you can solve all of those issues
and really enter the encryption is the
only way forward so please if you met
you're making secure applications make
sure they enter in encrypted and privacy
is the second right so please don't give
it up not for just for your sake but for
everyone's sake and don't forget that
you are the weakest link this is like a
famous xkcd comic it's like yeah and
doesn't matter how much equip ssin you
have someone has a $5 wrench so fuse
four links this is my my blog and
website and a link you know you have
linked to the slides and the video there
and the interesting website go register
file issues give feedback the source
code everything is open-source and
signed the webpage webpages extensions
if you're developing a secure
application for the browser please let
me know I'm happy to help you
integrating that and I think it's really
important for everyone safety
and I guess that's it and there's no
questions because I'm alone in this room
thank you very much