oh hi everyone so my name is bigger
I'll try to speak up if you don't listen
it if you can't hear me just raise your
hand so I'm very excited to be here
first of all because it's my first was
done and was really very cool to see
many interesting tools out there many
interesting talks and I'm also excited
to present you this new community
project which is called collective
knowledge and it's I think it's a bit an
alternative view from researcher
perspective so have all those cool tools
out there but as a researcher I want to
kind of use them and I'll tell you what
are the possible problems and solutions
to do it and in the past year I was very
glad that we worked with some great
companies universities or nonprofits and
they provided lots of feedback or
helping them to use again and they were
providing some interested then we'll do
some cool things like the foremost
regression testing crowdsourcing
experiments and even generating some
automatically generating reproducible
articles so I'll mention this and again
last year while working with those
organizations were actually validated
our approach that it works with most of
the tools out there so it makes me quite
happy but what is it all about so in my
past life I was a researcher and I was
working on machine learning systems and
compilers and basically when you when
you have some interesting ideas and you
want to implement it so I am trying to
look at different papers being published
there and last few years there were
about thousands of papers being
published on machine learning and
actually someone told me when I had
those slides that in fact last year
someone mentioned about 10,000 papers
being published just on machine learning
if you count reports blogs and so on ten
thousand so as a researcher I want to
validate them and most of them actually
didn't share code and data so what do I
do
so okay when I was young as for like
okay I'll start looking at some of the
papers I will learn great tools which
doing which you're working on and I
learn I looked at all the different
tools out there which are really helping
you to simplify your life I continue
learning them I become old like a white
hair now and then I manage to implement
my idea and want to implement my idea
somebody realized oh those are Florrick
I changed my new kuda doesn't support
many GCC which is out there so what do I
do
I started learning again or I just quit
I get depressed or some people like
Kenneth try to build to create some cool
tools like is a build which is great so
but it's a thing minority so the no of
those problems and if I heated them
twenty ten fifteen years ago but last
five years everyone was speaking about
it so one of the ideas is about like
everyone buzz what let's do it
producible research fantastic how do do
it five years ago we started introducing
or Tuco artifact evaluation at many
different conferences and the idea was
that when we publish a paper we can
voluntarily submit the code and data to
some committee and we will try to
validate your results and it worked out
very well from the first conference
which we did like about five years ago
and we thought we got five artifacts out
of twenty five papers which was still
like a little but at work we we pasted
methodology and so on last year we've
got about 70% of papers that before past
submitting code and beta will be the
minutes it's a good thing now what is
bad so when we started looking at of
course there is still no methodology
about how you Sharon reproduce all those
complex experiments performance
evaluation also it's really still in
infancy and what is really ugly that all
past five years I looked about 100
artifacts and all those 100 papers and
top conferences and they all have 100s
of scripts to do some experiments to
download some models to hardwire your
pass if you want to change your path you
need to find the script somewhere fix it
and so on and say this all our
Bellator's we spend more time actually
on trying to figure out how to deal with
all those streets then actually doing
fun stuff relating your result and
validating it and at the same time the
even though we have all those couldn't
data share
when you're lead research is leaving or
your student or whatever develop is
leading all this no one is using all
this code and data so it's real like for
me and I'm really sure it's a shame that
it happens because there is so much
interesting stuff out there and of
course the latest thing is like our case
so let's use containers and these are
fantastic tools as a kind of fun
solution as a snapshot but again they
hiding the mess and then if someone's
still have to solve this mess so it's
not solved at all however this
experience with all those conferences
when I look at all those artifacts I
started realizing that all those
hundreds of artifacts they have they do
the same things all the time
and they're simple things so if you look
like what do you usually do as a
high-level like August right I would say
that I have my problem in specification
I want to compile and run it with some I
don't know I would look at some
different images out there I would want
to kind of adapt to my software and
usually I'll try to detect that I have
some GCC or live am into compilers
available I'll try to find somewhere a
data set usually given some hardware
pass and so on but it's still the same I
don't know what run experiment collect
performance starts produce some graphs
will it a them and things you create
your paper and that's all of them are
doing the same so what is happening so
this started like when I discussed it
was a lot of Polish I think you that we
listened api's common it guys for all
those tasks that's all can we come up
with some simple api's which will
automate all those tedious tasks which
you have so that they don't reuse those
it guys and they must be simple and that
is very important and also you can
provide some meta information at the
description for all those components
which are there so that everyone could
use them and the big point for this is
that now and if we have it the eyes and
those meta descriptions in some cone
format we can enable devotes
because this is like wider ops are not
there in research because you don't have
it guys how would you connect your
jenkins or whatever try this with all
the scripts out there and that's how
collective knowledge came into play so
we start let's create just the time in
python library we should provide you
those
human-readable modules Python models
with few human readable functions and
they would provide your Nexus so this
way builders like Bob remotely module
with function compiler on and would have
dictionary or JSON input and always GCM
and dictionary out because very easy to
extend them and the same time all the
data which you share you would also have
some kind of unified meta jason and what
CK is just your common line front-end to
just call those modules for now that's
all and if you like I know that when I
was talking to researches like oh but
it's too simple we don't like it or one
complexity but being an industry for a
long time I said no opens it like this
simply it is the bet it is and that's
why we had many files but ok and are
there now and you have all those
components remote components ooh havoc
and now start assembling all the
experimental work flows from those
components and do more and more
complexity do some fancy stuff and get
I'll tell you later somewhat fun start
by doing with that and at the same time
when we discuss it with our colleagues
we said that ok let's know when you
share like your code and data through
github let's just have some common
format and usually it's just very
high-level information so whenever you
see this collective knowledge compatible
badge and some github repo stirred
around 100 now they have common
information so first directory usually
tells you your module Python module API
so that you know that your further data
is abstracted by this API and then
second level directories you have
basically what we call ck entries this
is your data which can be anything from
your soft in your soft abstractions you
would describe how you detect some
software and your program will describe
what their dependencies and so on may be
in very high level late if you're
interested you can look at all the
information on the website but just
trying to give you very high level idea
about what we did however of course it's
not a magic so some of you needs to
implement all those API is and this is
kind of was a tedious task so in 2017 we
got some first adopters that was arm and
general motors and arm of course they
develop all those like lots of hardware
and algorithms they need to provide big
performance regressions with testing
they have multiple work groups working
together so I was thinking that maybe
they can connect all their work groups
with the same trailer and the same for
General Motors so we started gradually
adding those api's ourselves or with our
colleagues and just again what were
there for
first api's which were provided very
simple again first of all what do you
want to have you want to describe the
operating system how you like I don't
know like compile some problem how what
I or how you can find some data there
and so on and this can be between
different operating systems so it can be
Linux Mac OS Windows are most
contributing also software Android then
the same thing what we always do
detecting platform information again
what is the power yeah afterwards they
call different tools out there which you
develop but we're just providing a
common API so that everyone else is
protected from the changes in the system
the same installing whenever you have we
want to adapt to your native environment
so provided many pies and many kind of
Oracle plugins for detecting software
there about there are around 500
software detection plugins so basically
you can just say C case search soft
which either Lily am data set and so on
that will find you all the installations
out there and the same for packages
there are great tools out there
easy builds back and some other ones so
provided an API for those kind of tools
so that anyone can share their even more
high level recipes about which do we
want to use and what are the
dependencies so if your software is
missing you can automatically call
install missing so a missing package
through the tools available out there
and just the last thing about those like
very high level thing about this ck
because still probably looks like magic
we so 20 years ago was working on
performance of the tuning and basically
last year I was talking with my
colleagues from Raspberry Pi foundation
who's eben Upton and he's saying why not
do like kind of convert and create a
program workflow which would do
performance regression testing on
different GCC versions on Raspberry Pi
devices and
created this workflow which basically
was that work which I did 15 years ago
in my PhD we did it in about two months
and there were an experiments we quote
forced experiments so the same workflow
now different users from raspberry pies
they were running the experiments on
their machines and they were collecting
data on our Synology de Burgh server and
suddenly like I think one week I
collected so much data which I think I
didn't collect in five years of my PhD
which on one hand was kind of a good
experience rusty on the other hand I was
crying that I spent five years on my PhD
like collecting just collecting this
data and I could do in five months so
and now I can do it in heels because
that's fine
okay and the cool thing that we created
if you look on the website we people
with Raspberry Pi foundation we created
an interactive report which is
thematically generated also through CK
and if you look at here you will see all
this what we did it generates PDFs with
all the papers with all the graphs out
there and I just want to go down so well
so here in fact you will see all the way
how we reproduce experiments you can do
it yourself if you look through this
paper but what is fun now is that
because of heavy pis
now we can actually embed some
underneath this interactive graph we can
embed some interactive graphs which if
you click on it in your paper you now go
to observe no clicking I don't know some
point this is like performance tuning
you'll get to the repository and you
will see different information where
this experiment well what was the
performance you can view all the
compiler flags which are there you can
replay it on your machine because it's
again all done for playing different war
groups can do it and now just I have
still I say I have system 8 minutes 10
minutes I wanted to show you a small
demo just to show you that you can do it
yourself now is a few clicks you can
actually start participating in this
crowd tuning and from your machine from
any machine maybe there will be some bug
or something but let me check with the
work this I usually don't like to derive
damage because they
don't often work can you see the font
everyone's okay no too small is too
small so now I'm losing time to get
these but again they did
oh yeah it's better assalamo on one of
our remote servers will actually perform
a some regression testing from this
reaction testing and we share those
security positives and again what I do
is that you would see many security
positives out there which I usually get
Hubley posters which you put on
different workgroups at communities work
and parallel on those it's a distributed
system they work in parallel and what I
would do now is so I have many programs
here many datasets here seek a list what
I will do now is that what if I do the
following so all the repositories are
basic a big CK directory what if I will
do the following
what if you do this at your website or
for your user in the HPC Center what
they will tell you if I would remove all
your repositories and I'm doing it now
and I hope that people would fire me now
they're using this website oh this
server because now usually they reusing
my show so I have I think one minute to
kind of restore it so now when I do seek
a less problem I don't have anything
anymore I don't even have this module so
what I do so I started saying that okay
let's pull the repository with scrote
tuning and it should normally go to the
github yeah why was shared and it's also
pulling all the sub reports there's all
those API is different API is out there
tamati to rebuild you the workflow to do
this interactive paper this experiment
on performance tuning so I still have
like 30 seconds I think to restore it
and I'm checking if my phone is known as
ringing me but not yet and it does about
so now have this secure place so now I
again let's check so I have see a
problem and now what is interesting that
I can just compile any program out there
Susan corners automatic benchmark and
what it happens is that it starts
detecting all the dependencies out there
I don't have time to show you
how it looks you can go and get happen
you will solve the meta information
about those problems but now I'm going
through plugins to detect you all the
defenses it needs compiler so when you
take it some Intel compiler will go
through GCC still have ten seconds so
let's install I don't know like some
seven each time it's interactively tells
you what is available on your system so
adapting to your system clang we get
phone so now it goes three it found all
the it detected all the depends it tells
you how they want to compile a program
let's compile with GCC compiler we
compile it around the program the same
program the first time because I delete
everything I need to tell that my
platform is Linux it can be done
tomorrow it's not important and I'm
running corner detection of some images
notice that all those images this again
I pulled someone else pull a new
reporter and all have like hundreds of
those images from someone else I don't
need to substitute all the past city
automatically finds all this for you I
run the program I write a ten times that
before some statistical analysis and
this normally works for ten seconds yeah
IP function I provide some
transformation notice that when you use
Python to call CK you will have actually
huge JSON file internally with
provenance and now just to start
participating in this performance
regression I just do seek a crowd shield
program and it has killed different
plugins what we can to make and three
models you can do compiler flags you can
Janee whatever you want just to watch
few things and now it starts
tuning your program and sending results
from server back so in fact this
reproducible article actually in a few
days I can even get more results and
this would be live article because I
will be getting your results I can apply
machine learning saw something what I
was creating for 15 years ago Miguel
stop this so just ideas to tell the
truth or I read below this war for an
Iran still has access to all those
reporters and to work so it's very quick
imagine I if I delete all my staff and
then
everyone like huge amount of time to
restore I saw some PhD students who
actually quitted PG because there's like
server died and they couldn't reproduce
the restore start back up was not there
and so on so now it's very still produce
stuff and just going back to I have five
minutes I just wanted to tell you a few
things actually of our company's
investors how we use them how we now use
CK just again to give you an idea what
may be useful for you I think I think
it's switched sorry yeah so I started
last year I went to the Seattle and I
was talking to my colleagues in
Microsoft and in us to Washington and we
said oh wow but this cool stuff that now
you have all those shared components we
can actually enable open science it's
again a buzzword but what would do it in
now instead of have been publishing your
paper really dating it and they're like
accepting it why not to tell people that
you share your city workflow working for
a given path will be validating it will
have a real-life scoreboard well they
don't know if you claim that you have
full analysis we'll check it and then
watch some pepper and with those guys
with rational Cornell's who are the
universities Cambridge who created this
tournament last year a task force and we
said we took very simple tasks for which
crucification everyone knows it and we
said anyone can submit any solution from
each crucification can be software
hardware model and just show us what
will be your performance throughput
accuracy I don't put it on scoreboard
and we'll accept you depending on the
results and this isn't quite good
success because so we got very diverse
artifacts were we had some cool stuff we
had submissions with someone was
providing a cluster of 10 raspberry pi
devices and showing that they can do the
same speed of finish crucification as
Tegra and then TX machines so it was
really cool on the other side we had
some submissions from Intel provided
their submission on using some powerful
little server in AWS and Amazon Cloud
and just one one
one month before they published a paper
claiming that they got a record number
of record throughput like 450 images per
second on this server and it was 50x
speed up over traditional keV framework
which they use and the validated it so
reported all these graphs again you can
go there and you will see in this link
all this live data from from this
tournament and what is interesting that
this results from mentally we validated
but it was not easy so when we started
looking at the accordant data was shared
it wasn't with CKD so it's not
validating it ah we are not getting 450
FPS by getting like 50 and this is how
when you read the paper you don't know
the data that's what happens to you and
then you say oh I know I don't trust
those guys that cheating it's really not
nice but then because it was validation
started testing it ah library was
missing they use very specific
interlibrary with DNA and mkl which he
had to use it we got it we got like 200
FPS that's already better but still at
450 we continued digging him I don't
realize and by the way those guys were
extremely supportive of what working
together to kind of fix the problem and
then we found the bug that they had this
model when it was supposed to be in date
it wasn't in theater was still 50 32 so
we fixed it I don't know what 450 FPS we
fix the workflow we fix all the
dependencies we share this so in ACM
digital library we have a paper with
those artifacts and notice even cool was
that
one month later Amazon colleagues called
us and said wow we saw this workflow and
actually in tunes will did it in our
Amazon Cloud or atwater it actually got
and gave us the results furthermore we
were added another world overhead of PJ
submission on FPGA does work and we had
a common presentation few months ago you
can see the details where it's kind of
now when they publish paper it's very
quick to reproduce results on the native
environment you can use docker it's fine
but you can now actually use it with
different systems and it can adapt to
your environment we testimonials I'm
just finishing going through quickly
general motors what they say they work
on self-driving cars so this is all they
really have to find the good solution
when it's again public informations you
can see it on YouTube I'm not saying any
secrets
so like any other self-driving car they
need to find the best solution for model
software and hardware which would be
let's say less than $100 you can't use
like $1000 cheap in your car because a
bit expensive it has to budget on I
don't know 10 what's off energy has the
Baker's so that you don't kill a
pedestrian because there were said cases
like this as you know so this is all
like very complex tasks so you say oh
but now we can actually use those
workflows and whatever running on
different software hardware and we can
find on the pirata the best solution so
this is again this helps them I'm a pro
disability vice-chair for supercomputing
but trying to see if we can automate
different submissions and we were doing
this proof-of-concept
sessile application you can look at it
how it emitted a local rank of different
supercomputers and like they I'm
finishing last thing because time is up
and I have one minute
I said well so I did the quantum
competition quantum tournaments just one
week ago in Paris and those good turn up
and you can see if you are there room at
quantum computing who actually
reproducing work with a damn rickety and
we're producing some of the results and
some we had some interesting new
submissions about improving machine
learning techniques so you can see it
online time is up I have last slide so
Malkin circuits so magic it's all solved
not at all and there is it's like wow
all at the very very very beginning of
this journey to tell people that we can
do reproducible research and I think
that's the case just probably the first
prototype like a series or prototype
which allowed us to connect all those
different tools together what you are
building and allow researchers to
actually take advantage of them without
staining that time of understanding what
you are doing so providing this like
seek a pair with your tool and hopefully
you can plug it in but it is a lot to be
done and well open to collaboration
because we are looking at
standardization
api's were improving like installation
duties and so on providing my eyes with
that again said I'm open to
collaboration contact me and thank you
for your attention I hope will be useful
[Applause]
and sorry that I was speaking fast
because I was like and and we have even
time for questions actually go to 10:40
which is like are you sure
okay so the framework he called Luigi I
don't know this framework unfortunately
so so the question was if we considered
using - Luigi right again I will look at
it and which apparently can help if you
change small parts it can help you trace
it and so on so no we didn't so far what
we do is one someone changes something
since it's a common workflow someone
else complains and send who had the case
when we broke something an arm told us
like in the day like oh my god there is
something broken so it's an open project
distribute project so they can be tools
like this which we think can help make
it more stable now so I will look at it
thank you
and but I don't know the Soviet one more
question probably there is one more
question I don't know yeah oh they're
using production now so yes so oh yeah
do we have any good sir I'm fully known
do we have any experience using using
those workflows in production so this is
in production so and as I said so I
don't know if I can officially start
saying which companies are using it I
will prefer not to for now even though
you saw some of the which kind of music
yeah why using it all the time in
production actually why you didn't hear
about this frame for last few years
because I was actually working a lot
with companies trying to make understand
what they need and they're using it and
now I kind of making it like public so
but yeah absolutely it's my main thing
is we're working with companies okay so
thank you very much
[Applause]