okay I'm sorry if anybody came here -
I've still got the wrong title up there
I put the wrong abstract in in
conference notes this is actually going
to be an update on my last talk which
was about indeed about global analyses
across a large code base so what I'm
going to be talking about largely today
is the things I've been busy with in
Klang plugins since the last time I was
here to give you some context I largely
write client plug-ins for Libre Office
and that means that I build little
pieces of code plug into the clang
compiler and make use of the clang ast
api's and they enable us to implement
various verification checks and to do
some large-scale rewriting across our
code base so that these plugins have in
the past enabled us to clean up things
like the fact that we've we started our
life with about seven different string
classes and we've done pretty well we're
down to about three or four and it
enabled us to clean up all sorts of
little bits and pieces along the way and
it's enabled us to move to more modern
usage of C++ my current status some
people will be happy to hear that I have
in fact run out of ideas my pipeline is
rather empty which means that there's
not a lot of large scale changes coming
coming down my pipeline the the
flattened plugin which is there to
reduce the indentation largely of code
by reorganizing methods so that they do
early exits who has a fair number of
stuff coming but I don't have any new
plugins coming I tracked clean upstream
on a fairly regular basis occasionally
the plugins need tweaking in order to
accommodate mild changes in clang
clangs actually become really stable and
plug-in api's are actually really nice
to use they're pretty reliable these
days occasionally I still run into
issues with source locations being
slightly art ranges of sorts
being a little bit iffy but 95% of the
playing stuff these days if something
goes wrong it's typically my fault okay
unique Peter is a plug-in just largely
finished pushing changes for the point
of unique Peter was to find places in
our code base where we could
productively use the standard unique
pointer a smart pointer class the point
of using the unique matter is that it
makes obvious something that is
otherwise just implicit in your code the
fact that a given class or a given
variable is the exclusive owner of
another object so my plugin started out
using my favorite onion peeling strategy
onion peeling means I look for very
simple approaches and then I run the
plug-in across the entire code base so I
look for very specific patterns so my
plugin started out looking for patterns
that look pretty much like that we class
clearly is deleting a member field that
it owns itself in its destructor and I
ran it across our entire code base of 10
million lines look for stuff fixed it
and then I extended the pattern matching
and I've been gradually making the
pattern matching more extensive I've
looked for more and more different
patterns of owning and deleting pointers
and as I as I've kind of cleared out one
set of changes in my cut in our code
base I've then made the pattern matching
a little bit more flexible I've got to
the stage now where the pattern matching
in fact is so flexible that it points up
a lot of false positives which means my
plug-in now has an awful lot of manual
exclusions but I consider that a
worthwhile trade-off I don't aim to make
these plugins completely robust they're
not made to be absolutely perfect
plug-ins that is just in my opinion
largely a fool's errand C++ just has a
ste too many corner cases if you want to
make a plug-in like this that's looking
for issues completely robust you will
find yourself on or hiding to nothing
exploring all kinds of weird sub parts
of the C++ ast and Mac
and all sorts of other weird stuff so I
don't aim to do that I just aim to get
stuff that's useful for seed for
LibreOffice that being said these
plugins are there the source codes if
anyone wants to try and extend and will
upstream them or do something else with
them you're welcome to I'm always happy
to give assistance but I have
deliberately not tried to upstream these
two LLVM because I know that they will
inevitably come back to me and say but
what if and what if and what if n
they're right it generates false
positives but we're happy with that so
we just keep tracking method cycles is a
plugin that I that are fairly recently
wrote and I'm very proud of this one and
it took me a long time to get to the
point in time where I understood their
clang ast and I understood C++ well
enough to be able to write it what it
does is it constructs graph over our
entire code base of of method calls so
basically I have a map of pairs from
source method to destination mystical
actually from source function to
destination function and I remap it
massages slightly so if you call a
virtual method to walk acceptor walks up
the hierarchy to potentially multiple
parents and tags all of those with calls
and then we generate an entire graph
this takes two or three times longer
than my normal runs do it generates 40
or gigabytes worth of log file data and
then takes roughly half an hour of
processing with the Python script to
spit out results it only found about
seven things because I have other
plugins that look for and used code as
well but it found seven things that my
that my unused code plug-in was unable
to find because they were cycles the
methods were calling each other and a
nice little loop
much like the two loops up there and
consequently the Jade code has been had
been present in our code base for a long
time and it hadn't been found so I was
very happy with that one unused fields
is a global analysis plugin I've been
extending it lately to look for fields
that are unused in the sense of they're
not generating any useful work so for
example an example up there we've got a
standard vector we're pushing
information into it but
that we're doing nothing with it my
normal analyses don't find us because
you're in fact we are in fact calling a
non-constant method on it so we are
actually modifying the object but other
than that we're doing nothing useful to
it surprisingly there were quite a few
incidents of this in our code base which
I suppose is not a surprise when you've
got ten million lines of old code you
find a lot of stuff so I started with
this idea and I extended it to a variety
of other calls on various STL collection
classes and finalists found as a bunch
of dead code single battlefields is I've
extended that one as well too
it used to be only full fields that we
declared on classes now it looks for any
statically allocated of any valid values
that looks for kind of primitive type
bellies I into our pointers sorts of
things it also looks for our string
classes and it looks for places where
those things are only ever assigned a
single value so in which case is not
really mutable data you can either be
declared concert if Utley or it can be
inlined
into the relevant modules either way
it's I'm effectively extracting latent
information and making it concrete it
versus work was not my idea at all I'm
tackle Mike korchinsky very
interestingly pointed out that code
where you are comparing an integer and a
floating-point value can never be true
and is generally indicative of somebody
making a mistake in this particular case
he found that mistake John and I believe
it was our drawing ml import code so
we've been rendered using a client
plug-in that was an interesting case we
wrote the plug-in and then we had to
pocket it was using an API called
evaluate as float inside playing and at
the time evaluators float would throw
its hands up in the air and crash on
about half of the classes in Libre
Office so we parked it and six months
later I tried it again and learn be home
clang fixed so that works quite nicely I
only found a few places but it's nice to
see that clang is moving so fast I need
anam constants I initially wrote this to
look 14 am constants where you've got an
and you know
and one of the constant one or more of
the constants is not touched at all
that's a relatively straightforward case
so I cleaned out all of the dead cases
where they made sense to do so again
there's an idea from a mic against key
and then we started looking for places
where I hadn't idea in my head that
there was a readwrite analogy here as in
some cases you read information in some
cases you write information and if
you've got write only information or
read only information that's generally
indicative of some kind of dead code but
it took quite a long time for me to find
a mental model in that I could use to
analyze the ast so in this context write
means we generate and store new
information so if you want write only
code you're storing an enum value into
stuff but you never ever look for it
read means that we just check for the
information we need but we never store
it now as it turns out right is better
to find them read which means I've
actually managed to use the right
analysis to find useful dead code the
read analysis however it largely spits
out too many false positives mostly
because of things like costs we have an
information you have oh you load a file
and you cost the data type in the file
into an Ino
so you're not you're not really the cost
is acting as a as a as a writer which
means you've got a read right field so
it doesn't work very well but the
analysis produced nice stuff in the end
redundant functional cost is a an
extension of another another another
plugin that we were looking for normal
redundant costs in this case we often
had code that was accidentally
constructing a new string from an
existing ru string and then passing it
into a method in the method in this case
was taking a Const wreck so there was no
point in doing that so the plug-in looks
for looks for cases like that collapse
if was looking for odd code where we had
two very small if conditions and they
could profitably profitably be combined
into a single if condition I ran this
myself and it's not on by default
because
quite hard to find a balance and I
didn't want to annoy people static there
looks full things that can be declared
constant static ie they can be in which
case they're they're stored in the
read-only part of the segment when the
card is compiled and they can be
usefully shared between different
processes Const field was a failure it
was a good idea the idea was that we can
declare fields Const and thereby mark
those fields as as being effectively
safe for multiple threads to access
however when you mark fields as Const it
tends to interact with other C++
features for example you end up with
implicitly deleted copy and movement
assignment operators even though you
have non deleted copy and move
constructors so it tends to produce
rather weird outcomes here and in the
code so that one got abandoned which is
a which is a bit of a pity but you know
you try some stuff and sometimes things
don't work out simplify construct was
effectively a cut-down version of a of a
clang tidy check there's already an
existing client ID ticker does something
quite similar but it tends to be a lot
more aggressive so I implemented just
the simplest case we we have things like
unique better and other things that take
the whole pointer and don't need they
all have default constructors already so
there's no need to do that we have a
class with ru string buffer which is a
mutable string class internally manages
memory dynamically and as you can see
people were often calling the code
that's got an a pen method to add stuff
to it but if you if you're doing it if
you're adding two strings together and
then a pending into the string buff
you're not really using the string
buffer it's weight it the way it's made
to be used to constructing an
unnecessary temporary so the plug-in
goes looking for places like that and in
fact I think I did a rewriter here so I
automatically rewrote a bunch of that
code so we then don't bother we don't
need to construct the temper anymore so
we're losing a bunch of temporary
creations should return boom actually we
had a surprising number of methods
floating around in writer which appear
to predate the presence of pool as a C++
datatype and consequently those methods
were returning in too long and they were
only ever returning one of zero and they
were being used as bull methods so the
plug-in looked for methods that only
ever returned the constants 1 or 0 and
we converted those to return bull so
it's no more more obvious what those
methods are actually being used for I
then took my unused fields analysis and
I extended it unused variables so I
looked for the same some of the kinds of
things in that case we have a sequence
which is a collection class and it
contains strings of string class and we
are modifying it but other than that
we're not doing anything with it so
that's effectively dead code so my
unused variables more plugin
goes looking for a bunch of patterns
like that in our code and complaints
like that then we have tools rectangle
we have a class in the tools namespace
called rectangle and point in size and
those had event has had methods that
were returning non constant references
which makes the code a little bit
awkward to read it can be particularly
Windows that back when we have code like
that yeah the point dot X and then you
adding to it which actually modifies the
object but it's not very obvious that
you're you're modifying the object
itself rather than you know modifying a
temporary of anything and particular
when it was buried inside other inside
other statements that could be quite
hard to read so I wrote a plug-in that
not only find these cases that
automatically rewrites them so we ran
out across the codebase to make the code
easier to read then I spotted an
interesting error case where somebody
was somebody passed a pointer into a
parameter that was actually a boolean
and C++ does a silent conversion for you
it does a it as a pointer not equal to
null conversion for you and that and it
was clearly not what was intended the
type system doesn't pick this up so
I wrote a plug-in that goes looking for
places where you are passing pointers
and other similar auto converted things
into bull parameters and it spits out a
warning cell call was an annotation we
had that modifies the linkage it it
modifies whether a method is is
internally linked into a library whether
it's externally visible and we were
using in a lot of places that it didn't
make sense this was mostly leftover curd
so we went through it and and eliminated
a bunch of it and that is what I've been
up to any questions yes the question is
about using these plugins on on other
other code bases I think they'd be fine
there'd be a nice extension to the
clanked ID set of stuff there's about
110 of them now they probably need some
tweaking to run on your code base but
I'm happy to help out if you want to if
you want to ask me questions or do stuff
no sir
no we'd c+ pastor short-circuit
evaluation we do Bosch used to do that
does he still do it and you wouldn't
remember we did do it somebody'd
somebody was doing it at one point I'm
not sure if I still doing it yeah yes
sir
Mukesh has upstream one of them the
macro check it that he wrote other than
that no I haven't upstream be any of
these the ones that are the ones that
are most proud of all the ones that are
least able to be up streamed because
they are yeah yeah but this sorry yes
they're part of the libreoffice
repository so anybody's welcome to grab
them yes sir
they're all in if you look in the libre
office get tree there under compiler
plugins sorry thank you very much
[Applause]