as the roller is the sunrise there was a
project called dawn to get rid of Alura
and at that point
we merged into what we do today in terms
of oh that sounds different okay kind of
is this now with
Simmons misses
so we go
sorry
[Music]
so
that touches this process
the localization
readiness of our code by the time that
things hit mozilla-central
[Applause]
change the way they use an interesting
the localization we don't find it you
can use co-owners
to actually say I won beat
the
and changes this power
[Music]
we ask the forest actually just
speculation problems
[Music]
central it has the strings that are
birds illa beta it has the strings that
are in Mozilo release it has the same
strings that uncommon tral income beta
and income release so everything that we
use to ship Firefox Firefox for Android
Thunderbird sea monkey is all gotten
together and it's creating one of this
localization repositories that only has
English strings and that repository is
then-current ein and when Francesca says
it's good to go then goes into gecko
strings where it is synchronized from
pontoon directly and then the
localizations that are done in pontoon
or atom locally are written back to
elton and central and then they go into
Firefox Bill's twice a day the nickname
of the code is crossed channel because
it's working across localization
channels we have not yet included our
extended support releases into that
scheme we intend to do so
right now we are rewriting our
localizations from DT DS and properties
into fluent so we don't want to keep our
old files around for a year and a half
so we're a little bit hesitant to do
that right now open technically we can
and that would allow us to do
localization updates on yes so if you
had a fix that you actually wanted to
publish to our enterprise releases we
could do that onwards to Android there
are a couple of good parts about Android
the localizable.strings are actually
already in an externalized file it's
called strings.xml the strings have
comments that's nice
they're reviewed as part of the code
review they have proper ordering that's
all kind of nice also the engineering
teams around our Android applications
decided to use linear get history and no
merge commits so that's also easy to
convert so that kind of all set for
continuous localization but there are
also ugly parts in particular around the
localization infrastructure in Android
and there's a bug that they will never
ever fix because if they do they break
the world if you use quotes or
apostrophes in that localizable.strings
file quotes are just dropped and percent
are apostrophes depending on which
version of the tool chain it is I think
either cut the string off or completely
break the build and if you want to
escape a string like that in an XML file
you either
quoted in double quotes or you use a
backslash which I think tells a lot
about how that tool was written its
first iteration
and that's what we have so it's really
difficult to find out what to do with
ice also the file locations contain
something that is similar to a locale
code but is never a locale code so
instead of saying de - de for German as
in Germany they put an R in because
that's a region and then they have this
thing where they say and now we actually
have Unicode local codes and instead of
using a minus or an underscore they
decided to use a plus as a separator
between those things so if you want to
support a tool chain that writes these
files back you need to have completely
custom logic for Android local codes not
to mention that they still live with an
old Java bug that used I n for
Indonesian and weird
look how code for Hebrew and there are
four local codes that have absolutely
nothing to do with each other way
forward we need to kind of talk to the
engineers and say please only do the
things that we know we understand
because the documentation is really
dodgy and you can put strings wherever
you want they don't need to be in
springs XML and with that subset you can
write tests that ensure that the things
are actually the way they are and we
support for like locale codes and then
pontoon can actually be made to localize
Android apps directly so if we have an
Android app and we want to localize that
we can just set up pontoon directly to
that repository it can decide on whether
it writes to master or to our branch and
then things can just go
the other thing is that a lot of our
Android applications share a lot of
strengths so Firefox for Echo show is
pretty much the same thing as Firefox
for Amazon TV and Focus has a lot of
overlap with it and Firefox Lite has a
lot of overlap with it but then Phoenix
probably won't and Android components
doesn't and we still want to get one
project for the whole thing so what we
want to do is we want to start with like
the Android product repos which is like
all the Android related application
repositories Plus Android components
build a unified repository eight of them
put them into quarantine because also
that needs a current ID if that succeeds
get the mint again us get them into
pontoon right back localized files into
the same repository as Android Springs
would expect them and then write that
content that is required for each
application back to the Android product
repository probably on a nightly basis
and then because Android just builds
what's in the repository you
automatically get localized builds we
can publish them on developer channels
and we can also run screenshot tests
because that is something where it has
pretty good infrastructure on mobile
devices
sadly it doesn't on desktop which is
something we might fix I mention and
that is as far as my slides go and now I
would love to get some questions and I
might have some answers
so my question is how big a team is
doing only localization at Messiah
to be ready
any other question
want to share something