thanks a lot good morning
by the way I'm a little bit jet-lagged
because I flew from California and this
is the exact route I actually took
several days ago from San Francisco to
Copenhagen and then to Brussels and you
know when I think about like commercial
flights I just we usually think of how
you're going through some security and
then get another plane flying you know
eventually like it in some drinks snacks
and lending and live in the airport
right but if you the reality of
commercial flights is actually more
complicated than that like it's so
complicated that is a frequent flyer I
actually am appreciating that you know
even the you know cancellations and
delays it's like there's so much going
on and there are zillions of things that
need to go right in order for them to
fly me from you know San Francisco to
Brussels and I actually is a customer
like I don't really have visibility to
what is going on so my experience was
more like a I arrived at you know San
Francisco Airport the airport was
functional the security was still
working you know I went through security
they you know validated my identity I
spent some time you know waiting for my
plane everything like traffic control
was working like no planes were crashing
over us or whatever the gates were
working the announcement system was
working you know they started to
announce that they are boarding and I
ended up like boarding the last we
closed the doors and you know I got on
the plane
so our pilots probably went through all
these like different checklists and I
assumed that they were all green and the
push started playing traffic control
allows us to leave slightly earlier so
everything went well and finally we were
just you know flying we use all these
like you know different facilities I
mean just imagine like all this stuff
that you are engaging when you're flying
and that all the facilities that you are
actually using but none of these
facilities are actually reserved
specifically for our flight but there
really essential for our flight to
happen so I got a comfortable seat
whatever good food I actually flew and
engines kept working time passed quickly
we actually ended up landing in
Copenhagen and I went through the border
and you know made it to my connecting
flight and landed in Brussels so
anything could have been wrong right
like including the details I don't know
and imagine of like ground staff staff
the flight staff the machinery the
electronics everything involved and as
well as the you know the border
enforcement so it requires a really
complex system of you know cooperation
to fly somebody from San Francisco to
Brussels and it's not as always you know
the things are not always good things
may go wrong as I said that there are
cancellations delays whatever different
components of the system may fail
differently in isolation and we
sometimes don't even realize existent of
these like small sub components
until they fail because we don't really
have like visibility as a person who is
flying I don't have a lot of visibility
and so you know commercial flights may
well you don't really appreciate a lot
of good things because you're just
assumed you just don't have a lot of
visibility for example if you return you
from the border when we were trying to
you know get into the Schengen area you
wouldn't appreciate all of a sudden like
hey all the stuff until now like worked
out fine you actually were promised to
be flying to Brussels from San Francisco
with you eventually had to like return
back earlier anyway it's like any
computer system is actually like flying
our users engage with a really tiny part
of the stack and that's their experience
so you're building infrastructure for
example may work so well for the most of
the time but if a user transaction
doesn't go through it doesn't mean like
that's the end end game end of the game
for that particular user so let's talk
about a little bit over about our
everyday computer system so I don't
think that like we have a lot of
visibility into our stack and I don't
really think that like everybody's
things that they scale in terms of both
developments you know maintenance and
generally the production experience if
anybody thinks that they do I'm really
impressed like I work from you know I
worked at so many small and large
companies and never thought that with it
if my current company I kind of feel
like we do but there are so many small
gaps here and there
so this vault is actually about like how
we are trying to fill those gaps so by
the way I'm Jana I work at Google and I
had opportunity to work on a bunch of
projects including contributing to some
of our infrastructure projects and I
have several stories about my time at
this company and this is one of them so
you know the early is of a company or
our project is really nice because
things are simple you often usually have
a single server and a few other
components like you may have a post
press cluster for your data but
everything is just kind of like fitting
into your brain at this point your
architecture is just like a few notes
here and there if somebody joins to the
team you're just taking the person to
the whiteboard explaining them what is
going on in a couple of minutes if
there's something going wrong you can
take a look at the logs and you know
it's easy to debug things from the logs
and then the next step you know you're
growing you have more engineers the
company culture is also changing because
your monolith is not really you know
helping you or organizationally to scale
some teams want to like you know push
stuff to production more often some
teams just want to you know keep things
more stable so there are different
demands between different teams and you
know this is this is the point that you
want to do something else and you know
breaking down your big monolith so the
growth is great but you started to see
the first symptoms of actually like
diversifying and fragmenting your tech
stack you start to include more stuff
you have like more storage more TVs you
have like different you know queues or
whatever each term is kind of like you
know coming up with their own ideas and
everybody is sort of like siloed and not
really talking to each other
and you have this like huge mess because
all you know the monolith organization
is gone and this reality is coming with
a lot of new challenges because you know
just this one single problem just became
many and you can't really depend on the
earlier ways of doing things especially
in terms of debugging you can't really
you know self documents all this stuff
and tour ends because you know it's not
just a lot of teams and there's no
coordination between these teams and you
know reading the logs is just so hard
because some stuff is here and there and
some stuff is there like everything is
failing in isolation or maybe just
working well whatever you just don't
understand the overall state of what is
going on and your engineers just really
don't know what to do when things fail
you know who's a person that we should
contact like everybody's kind of like
escalating stuff to each other because
it's hard to pinpoint what is the root
cause of the problem and sometimes it
gets larger like for some large
companies it becomes really untolerable
like the company is like mine it's
actually such a big pain and you know a
lot of people haven't asked me like who
really wants to work for such a large
company this was my biggest concern
before coming to Google I work for
another large company and I just didn't
want to you know take the job because it
would be a nice opportunity but I will
be feeling so unproductive because it
will take me a lot of time to learn the
stack in our systems so in some cases
like people think that like key people
like Jeff Dean might be the answer to
all of these problems because you know
these people have been around for a long
time they've been like there when
initially all these conversations were
happening about you know critical parts
of the infrastructure they sort of have
like a better understanding of things
and to end but is this are really like
our strategy are we you know keep
escalating things to Jeff Dean nobody
does that and you know Jeff Dean
actually went to AI but maybe this is
partially why he went to AI because lots
of people are still coming to him and
like he's trying to just basically
replace himself with AI
No so anyways to be more realistic like
it especially you know very fragmented
in large systems everything becomes such
a big mess we have all these different
services different you know storage
systems different DVS who actually has
invisibility at some point you know this
is the typical myriad at Google like we
just need to delete all of this stuff we
have this huge complexity the code is
owned by different teams you know nobody
knows what how it works
ancient people who have been around for
a long time actually have been burned
out because they became the canonical
source of truths and they can't really
take vacation because if you if they you
know just like take two weeks off
everything just goes out and don't you
know the documentation is not an answer
to any of this because documentation
doesn't really catch up with the change
so you know Doc's always lie like
they're always like coming late like and
you really don't want to depend on that
so when I joined this company on my
first hour like literally it was my
first hour they were like hey there is
this thing called code search just an
internal tool it's it's it's called code
search it's basically a search engine
for our internal monitor path it's
really amazing it's just really you know
the ranking and everything is so easily
you can just really pinpoint to stop but
the only problem the restriction is you
need to have an entry point you need to
you know know the symbol name whatever
like the file name or some sort of like
entry point project name maybe user name
you can actually see the history as well
so it's like nice if you have an entry
point
I use this every day and everybody at
Google uses every day especially if
they're engaging with the Mona Reaper
but it's partially why we can understand
better about our systems the second
thing is we have this unified build tool
which is called blaze which inspired
basil to open-source version and since
everybody's using the same build tool it
kind of makes things easier because you
can actually like take out you know
click on a bill target you can
who is depending on this bill target and
everything like but this is really good
for static dependencies it doesn't tell
you anything about your dynamic
dependence like service dependences so
this is really cool but it's not the
actual solution and none of these tools
are really good in capturing like what
is important in terms of pointing out to
like the most critical execution pads
you know this is a typical system that
returns some user profile images and a
bit of metadata and there are many
services here there are many services
you know we're going through some
services and like as well as some
storage in order to you know return a
response to the user but the blue line
is here what we call a critical path
because the user request comes in to the
load balancer and hopes through like a
certain path in order to serve this
request and you know all the way down to
the low-level disks and at some points
we actually have a response
it might company we actually put some
emphasis making these critical execution
pads more visible so you know engineers
can actually see investigate and debug
if you know engineers can really see
this type of execution pads they they
can also see what exact components were
required to serve that request they can
also run some like analytics on like
what type of like execution pads are
important or what type of like service
dependency is around this requires you
know some sort of like dynamic nurse
it's actually generated by data coming
from the dynamic instrumentation in
production and it's a bird's-eye view
you know for our systems you can really
understand the service dependencies in
what pads and what dependencies and what
relationships are more important so just
like my flights
you know our users don't often know much
about under the hood they don't know
what is going on in our systems they
really expect this big black black box
to respond them respond to them they
don't really care about the health or
the availability of these underlying
stuff either they just expect
you know a response for example if the
user service here one of the replicas
just dies like just crashes and the
scheduler just spawns a new one in the
in a lifetime of a request and if the
user cannot really tell because the
latency was not that high like the user
wouldn't care so you have been able to
think about your systems from the
perspective of critical paths are really
important because the goal here is not
the availability of these like different
individual components the goal here is
the availability of the user execution
path so some of the goals are the goals
of critical path analysis as I said the
availability of underlying processes
doesn't really matter at all it's more
about like having the user experience up
and running
having that critical path up and running
and it's just kind of like flying right
like I I fly but I don't really
understand what else is going on I know
what I engage with I don't care if the
airport is entirely functional or not I
just want to use one gate maybe I will
just you know sit and eat
I just really engage with a small
section and from my perspective that's
what matters so being able to you know
think about our think about our systems
and evaluate our systems you know from
the user perspective it's a very
different approach but it's really
useful so some of our engineering
practices are really around discovering
critical paths automatically and I
briefly mentioned that we do this in
production and once we discover these
critical paths we also you know use them
as debugging tools is debugging data we
want to make them you know more reliable
as fast as enough and if there's an
incident in production the data provides
us some debug ability we can just go in
and actually see what has happened you
know it's the middle of the night if
you're on call you just really want to
be able to see everything end-to-end
without knowing too much about the
entire
system even if you haven't you know read
the source code before so that's cool
you know how we get there there are
different ways to do this actually we
talked about like two main emerging
tools and industrial nowadays I don't
know if you are interested like if you
are familiar with distributed tracing
our event collection but login can also
be used the tricky part of login is you
know it needs to be more it needs to
have more context about the execution
path you need to like carry a request
idea around and you need to you know
structure maybe the log messages in a
wait so you can generate these execution
pads by looking at parts in the data so
this is a very common way of like you
know understanding a problem just keep
asking why like being able to ask why
why why why it's kind of like this
golden rule of exploring your
cause-effect relationships so the
granular you know event collection or
distributed tracing has this promise
it's kind of like hey we want to give
you this ability to be able to go deeper
in the stack and try to you know like
help you what actually happens this is
why people sometimes say observability
is about having answers for questions
that you haven't had yet because you
know the question appears when there's
an incident or there's some unlikely
event and you should have planned so you
know collect enough data so if the
incident is there you should be able to
take a look at your debugging data and
should have answers to your questions so
I will show you some illustrations of
like some traces I don't know if you are
familiar with tools like Zipkin or a
light-year network tab on you know
developer tools on browsers typically
the traces look like this like you know
there are a bunch of things going on the
each row here is representing a
different component some different
action is happening it captures you know
this is what happens here and like how
much it took and like where it actually
initiated that
and here what we see is this is a trace
for an API server I have so four slash
timeline you can see all these like
different server components that I
actually had to like go and make our
pieces to in order to respond to the
user so you can take a look at these you
know rods to learn more about the
lifetime of a request like if somebody
for example new joins to my team and if
they're going to work on the API server
they can take a look at the trace to
understand oh yeah this is all this
stuff like they don't have to read the
code they can start with looking at the
trace and learn what is going on so also
you know welcome to 2019 this is the
basic stack we have it's like every
growing number of layers and maybe have
more understanding of your user space
but everything underneath I don't know
what I called cloud stack which was like
kubernetes whatever it's just a big
black box and we absolutely have no
understanding just imagine if your infra
was providing some like you know granule
events or traces from that layer in the
lifetime of your requests if there's
something relevant it would be so much
easier for you to understand imagine
some of the for example people hey the
schedule and decisions are leaked in
today you know the networking layer
because load balancer need to understand
the scheduling decisions if we can
actually like you know capture some
traces from that layer wouldn't it be
nice if there's a you know unlikely
event unlikely like scheduling decision
you will be able to just go and like
take a look at your user trace and like
pinpoint hey it was a scheduler or the
load balancer because of this reason
this happens so we there's no way that
we can learn this entire stack in our
lifetime but I think that this type of
like debugging tools allow us to
understand more of each layer so this is
a this traces are a cross-check in a
debugging tool you can basically use
them to blame whose fault it is
returning back to that like API server
thing just imagine the
you know the engineer just comes in and
takes a look at like I told you no we
waited this much time for the scheduling
decision to happen so you know that
person can escalate the issue view
scheduling team because hey like there's
this additional latency but it's
actually not my fault so it kind of
gives you this like you know get blamed
for production issues type of
functionality so it's just really nice
and it's really nice when you're cloud
providers are participating into your
trace because what you can see is hey
there's all this like additional you
know latency coming from the cloud
providers load balancer maybe I can
escalate this so they are a sorry and
this is the evidence because each time
it escalates stuff to collect cloud
providers they're a little bit like hey
are you sure that it's us like so hey
here's the data and it's the proof the
other thing is you can actually it's
really nice that you can build some
tools to map this type of data to the
source code here for example each bar
each span is representing an RPC call so
it would be nice to just you know take
it to the RPC maybe you know the handler
or to the client source code so you can
take a look and just basically you know
review what has happened especially you
know it could be a you know miss
configuration or a malformed payloads or
some sort of like a stupid you know
timeout configuration that there was
some additional retries or latency so
it's pretty cool to be able to do that
if you build some additional tooling
around this type of data and the other
thing is you know who to call you know
there's an issue with this specific
component I am not the person who can
understand I read the code I took a look
at like all the additional data and I
don't really know what is going on here
who's responsible for this if you have a
catalog of you know different teams
if you
map one of these blocks to a team to a
necessary team or a regular team you can
actually give them a call and like try
to understand what is going on in
production and the other thing is you
know give out all the other stuff you
know about this block like in the
lifetime of this block what else has
happens because we don't capture a lot
everything in you know informs of traces
or something else would be nice to just
you know see what else is going on a
very typical example for this is just a
lots because we already have logs
everywhere so you just give me the logs
like what happened I just want to you
know understand more of like you know
granular literally what happened so
nothing comes free unfortunately and I
will explain some of the challenges and
I think we shouldn't undermine the level
of investments required to roll some of
these technologies in your
organization's especially if we already
have an established organization it's a
little bit harder to you know put these
in and this is where people usually got
stuck especially if they haven't thought
about these capabilities and some of
these challenges early in the early days
so if you need critical path analysis it
actually is a cross team problem so the
entire organization needs to agree on a
bunch of things they need to agree on
you know you need to do some
instrumentation in order to be able to
generate that that data you need to be
able to collect those like a this is the
start this is the end whatever but you
need to just be able to reconstruct the
trees so you need to like really
propagate some request ideas around and
there is not like a lot of agreement on
this like there's no like golden
standards or whatever even though for
distributed tracing at least there's a
w3c proposal coming up but apart from
that like there is actually no real
standard and just imagine that even if
you internally understand like even if
internally agree on one particular
identifier format
hopping through these different you know
load balancers or whatever and they
don't really understand that format so
we really need an industry format for
that and for distributed tracing we're
actually working on one of on a standard
so that's really good news
the other thing is engineers really
don't know where to start say like we
can capture a lot as a part of traces or
event collection we usually say that
like a start with your network sex
specifically HTTP and RPC and this is
actually where things are getting really
easy because if you have a framework or
if you can start things like the load
balancer maybe you just get like some
automatic leanness you can you know
forever RPC or every request you can
just automatically generate one of these
bars and you know generally you can
simply you can simply start by using an
instrumentation library that works well
with your existing frameworks and gather
some data from there
the other thing is infrastructure is
still a black box and none of the vendor
services are really designed with this
type of capabilities
you know nobody actually considers about
this capabilities in the first place we
still expect people to learn a lot about
the underlying stack by reading the code
docs you know talking and we don't
expose this type of like you know
debugging information and it's it's
becoming it is it's a security challenge
especially if you are you know running
stuff in manage environments in your
cloud provider for example you know
server looks like function you manage
you know function running environments
where you basically do not have like a
lot of like control and if the
environment itself was automatically
providing this type of debugging
information and you can participate into
that that would be so nice the other
thing is you know instrumentation is
really expensive high traffic systems
really you know end up down sampling and
it's it's a huge topic you know what
kind of down sampling strategy makes
and we sometimes miss you know
collecting data for interesting cases
and we want to just improve this over
time and we only have like a few brief
you know ideas what to do and other
challenges the dynamic capabilities of
instrumentation has been a you know has
been underestimated for a long time in
the industry and this is really
important because we want to be ideally
want to be able to tweak things we want
to be able to collect more maybe if
there's an issue but doing it in a safe
way is not really easy so there's you
know this is still a big challenge you
need to have your own strategy and to
kind of like wrap up we are still kind
of in the dark ages
when it comes to like understanding and
maintaining our systems when I talk
about this concept so you know I just
feel like I'm just think well you know
salesman just traveling and like talking
about these concepts but I I have to say
that like we have some sort of like you
know some of these abilities actually it
might company at least and it really
helps us you know makes your engineers
slightly more happier because you can
give them an overview of what is going
on but at the same time you know this is
not the end game it's just an overview
and it really just changes the way you
interact with other teams and everything
but it's just you know entry point tool
not the entire solution so I just want
to now say that like this is a tool that
really closes knowledge gaps in our
organizations and we don't talk about it
I think I came here to talk about it and
I would love to you know answer your
questions if you have any and thanks
much for having me here
[Applause]
yeah be quiet when entering be quiet
yeah and remain seated for now hi Anna
you said that there you're not aware of
a distributed chasing standard that's
like I understood open tracing to be
that standard
can you explain maybe why that doesn't
fit in with this is open tracing is a
standards or I mentioned like the lack
of standards and how open tracing is not
like kind of like aligning with that
sorry to interest again about respect of
the speakers and their time and their
commitment can you please be quiet
thank you so the question was was the
question I mentioned that there are a
lack of standards that there are not a
lot of standards around and you
mentioned open tracing so the question
is is open tracing another standards in
like kind of like you know okay so open
tracing actually provides some hooks the
instrument things but it's not automated
about like you know the propagation
standard or it's not open aided about
the data you export so in and you need
to like move so each provider has a
different they is enforcing a different
data export format and a header format
and if you're using open tracing you
need to like link the entire system with
the one specific you know implementation
of open tracing so you can have like
enter and stuff
this is not like practical for example
if you have nginx as a binary you know
nginx just doesn't know much about
whatever you know tracing provider you
wanna use so we want to make this less
of a build time constraint but more of
like a wire format so everybody can
understand the same header and produce
similar type of data so you know nobody
actually like has
rebuild stuff in order to have traces I
hope that the answer to the question hi
my question was can you go into a bit of
details of what you meant by dynamic and
dynamic constraints it yeah dynamic
capabilities what do you do you have an
example to elaborate this so one of the
typical questions is like how much data
should I collect or you know how
granular should it be or sometimes we
collect distributed traces but it's not
enough like we just need to go and
enable some other stuff momentarily for
example it's a very common thing at
Google that hey we just don't know like
there's some additional latency here it
turns up sometimes ended up being the GC
latency in order to capture that like
you actually need to have some runtime
events coming from there and it's not
like really you know in the scope of
distributed tracing so you just need to
go and like tweak a few other things and
you know enable some more
instrumentation and need to be able to
correlate in a way with that distributed
tray so you can still capture that like
hey this is what has happened in the
lifetime of this so that's kind of like
what I mentioned and again it's it's a
huge topic it's more about enabling more
signals maybe even more granular T maybe
even more debugging information maybe
you know adding more like granule other
stuff it's all in the scope of dynamic
capabilities and we just don't really
think too much about it when we're
developing things yeah it's it's
something that is not very ideal
nowadays hi Anna
thanks for the talk you were mentioning
freeing ourselves from like the old time
constraints and stuff like nginx and and
and things like that
do you think that we can ever automate
this sort of dynamic instrumentation
given that it seems to require at least
some degree of domain knowledge that at
some level has to be input by humans so
the question is if we have some Snape's
or some sort of standards is it possible
to automate all the distributed trace
by you know putting this in our load
balancers engine X or you know in
similar stuff so there's you know you
can actually start a trace but you still
need to know propagated all across in
your stack that still becomes a problem
you we can just generate the RPC level
the entry the ingress you know maybe
request spend but you still need to you
know just put the right header to the
outgoing requests and all the other
stuff need to know aligned with that and
sort of like participate into that to
have actual you know in any meaningful
traces so it's not really easy to do
this especially in language runtimes
where you know for example for go it's
really hard because you need to be in
the runtime propagating the right
identifiers in some language runtimes
it's like so much easier it's special
there's one single thread or you can
just really put the context in the tread
so it depends on also the language you
know the language and sort of like you
know capabilities and limitations around
that but it's the actual answer is
unfortunately now there is no like super
automatic magic way hello and thanks for
the talk yeah here yeah sorry so you've
mentioned that in Fri still a black box
do you think that things like Open
Compute is the way to go to solve that
problem or anything like that like yeah
so do you you mentioned and in Frey
still a black box and you think like
things like Open Compute is the way to
go to solve that problem lots of
infrastructure builders really really
wanna like expose this type of data once
there is a real standard like an export
for like standard for example they want
to provide like a hook or whatever they
will just write it like in whatever
particular format and they want to be
able to expose and they want to really
like work with the user trace it's just
like the more of like this like lack of
you know wire standard at this
that they are nobody's interested but I
want to take a look at Open Compute but
because I don't have much context about
it maybe we can chat after this thank
you thanks hi
is it any projects like going on
you mentioned the guy going to AI do you
try to to implement some AI machine
learning technology to get like okay we
have some problems and it's analyzed and
then some suggestion where it can be so
the question is is there any I work
related to consume this type of data
there's actually a lot especially in the
like scope of anomaly detection they
want to be able to automatically say
that like this this pattern this uses to
pattern this pad pattern is not really
normal there's some additional ladies
there like different components or you
know additional number of retries and
everything so they just want to use some
sort of like I don't a lot like I don't
understand what they do at this point I
haven't spent a lot of time reading but
they want to do some better you know
recognition of unusual patterns by you
know looking at the data thank you
thanks
[Applause]