otherwise happy to introduce another
multilateral speaker we'll see a bit
there I think pretty much all of us
seems the browser is now the platform
and then the excitement is you have a
ton of different browsers so if you want
to make code that change the behavior of
the browser more than just a page how
can you do that across browsers
awesome wanting everyone so everyone can
hear me at the back right perfect
yeah that's what my check we have been
doing the whole morning right cool
so yeah that's me whenever I go back to
my home country India and Miss food you
can see it already so today I'll be
talking about cross browser extensions
what I've transpose are extensions okay
what are extensions anyone so here's the
thing I'm a super lazy speaker I mean I
sleep while talking I have a history of
that so just in case if I sleep you have
to wake me up with your answers so once
again what are extinctions anyone sorry
plug-ins for browser anyone else okay
let's keep it simple
anything that extends the functionality
of a browser is a browser extension
right browsers are quoted with like our
bare minimum requirement maybe the tools
which you are developer needs may not be
needed by a designer or a designer needs
a tool which are not needed by a
developer right so browser supported
with minimum so basically one size that
fits all but your browser when okay let
me put it like this browsers are cool
everyone agree to that perfect so when
it suit up with extensions it become a
superhero right so it's it's not a new
thing like since the browser browser
extensions are there why we are talking
in this conference about in this
specific room about browser extensions I
know you will kill me for this because
JavaScript
so these extensions are made just using
javascript and how many of you use any
form of extension or any extensions
maybe Chrome Firefox almost every one so
any links which which extension you use
the most
at blocker no scripts anyone else HTTPS
Everywhere I love that personally empty
cache good we have ample of examples so
just to have a revision what an
extension can do this is like one of my
favorite tool because I am super bad at
it if I write my call for paper without
this surely everyone will reject it
right so this is a savior tool for me
like people who are who are really bad
at grammar
maybe block your abs and trackers anyone
know this extinction ghostery may be
using for secure browsing does anyone
know about our Facebook containers
perfect if you don't know after this
talk give it a try maybe better new tab
experience like whenever you open a new
tab you may not like the stop things
maybe you want some news maybe you want
to do some search maybe you want a
better UI all that can be done by a
extinction may be managed passwords
precisely anything you want with your
browser how to do that let's get started
this is an interesting part I am just
sugarcoating it it's the most boring
part of this talk because it requires
some bootstrap coding so this is a
structure of extinction how it looks
like it is a manifest file it has some
components like content script but
non-square page action browser action
yeah these are fancy words I'll make it
simple for you that so many faces Oh
Jason is the entry point entry point of
the extension whenever you create an
extension you have to tell the nobodies
whenever you create an extension you
have to tell the browser what all your
extension can do
permissions it requires an all the
metadata like name description version
so these kinds of stuff we put in
manifest dot Jason second thing is
content with so there are times which
and when you need your extension to
inject some script into the browser code
for example you want to read all the
Android tags in the page so you need to
put some JavaScript code into the page
so this is the thing which is used to do
that these scripts directly in is
injected into the code dom second thing
is background script yeah that that
executes send background so what happens
is contains paper page dependent like
for example you open google.com and you
want to do something on google.com so
that can be done by a Content sphere but
for example you know you want something
to do when the google.com opens right
before opening you have to put the quote
in background strip this is page
agnostic like it runs whenever the
browser runs it's not running only when
your page opens or a specific page
closes but this runs throughout the
browser time pays action and browser
action so these are pretty utility
patterns like toolbar buttons whenever
you want to give a functionality for
example the first one is an example of
an IP finder
so whenever a URL is open um you can
click and click that small button and
find what IP of what is the IP of the
domain you know where it is hosted in
that kind of stuff this is pretty page
specific whenever a page is loaded that
depends on that icon the second one is
browser action it's more generic I mean
whenever you click that maybe opening a
pop-up maybe executing some action maybe
injecting a content script or maybe
sending signals to Java background
JavaScript these are options way the
next thing is option page so option page
is basically this is a method how you
put preferences in any order extension
if you want to give users facility to
maybe change the color
off your head on or maybe some timing of
doing events this is a place where you
can do that and this whole thing is just
HTML page the support CSS and JavaScript
together whoo
that's what that was a boring work trust
me web extensions API so whenever I say
or anyone say API what comes in your
mind
anyone contract interesting sorry true
but this time I mean I can say this
comes directly from mdn how many of you
know mdn I suppose JavaScript developers
almost everyone know Indian ok mdn is
Mozilla developer Network it is like
it's a wiki of all the JavaScript
basically so these are the api's which
are built on top of browser features and
has a native JavaScript interface where
you can just plug in some options and do
the actions so what basically I am
saying is with JavaScript you are
touching the browser's code like for
example as simple as throwing a
notification it's a native native
browser action but you are doing that
thing with JavaScript with this method
of extensions api's so their ample api's
will see some of them notifications API
this is my favorite because this is like
most stressful it's straightforward you
put some options and it throws a
notification probably this is more of
self explanatory type basic so basically
it says like basic includes a message a
title um they're like image types just
notification will have images so it just
does a simple task browser dot
notification that create basically it
creates a notification which has icon on
that icon dot PNG it has a title my
extension and with a message my
notification browser action API so I
just explain what what the browser
action is so the interesting thing is
like whenever you click a browser action
you have a pop-up right like you guys
have seen that whenever some add-ons
have whenever you click the toolbar
button there's a popper so how many of
you know that that pop-up content is
just a plain HTML page anyone know that
now you know that it's a plain HTML page
which executes with JavaScript in CSS
you can do anything there like write
anything
execute anything maybe fetch API is
maybe what you say like for example life
ticker let's say you wonder there's a
FIFA match and you want a life score you
have any API for that you can just call
from on that page and whenever you click
that button that score will be displayed
here it's as simple as that there more
to that like for example you put you
want to communicate to background script
throw a notification let's say so you
can listen to that action on click and
ok so listen to the action on on take
and the action can be done there are
some times like in some extensions you
may have seen like um they're small
badges next to the browser action so
that can be dealt by like set bash stack
set bash text whatever you want to set
you can set their tabs APA this is an
interesting API so this gives you full
power of tap for example whenever let's
say combine two browser action and dabs
API whenever you want to open few tabs
on take off a button you can use that
API whenever you want to do some action
on clothes of any tab or maybe on
opening off any tab this can be an
action I'll give you an example like
let's say um you are making an extension
which keeps a track how many times you
open a Facebook page so this can be your
friend like unactivated i'm not sure if
it's visible at the back or not but this
says browser tabs dot unactivated
dot add listener so basically you can
put a function javascript function
whenever the tab opens and you can count
i like how many number of times facebook
page has been open so this this is a
very Navy example but I'm just giving an
idea of how this can be used new tab API
so
APA just lets you to do one single thing
change your new tab page so you can
create an HTML page may be anything you
want maybe just simple text and plug it
here so this this tab will replace the
new tab the stock new tab and put your
HTML page into this okay one more to go
there this is the most interesting API
which I do anyone know about this web
request API it wasn't news recently so
probably okay so this this makes you
like you know super powerful as a
extension developer like as the name
says it's like a whole soul what to say
owner of the web request this API lets
you to modify of a web request in any
way basically it has multiple events on
before requests on send headers on on
before send headers on send headers on
how to receive on response headers
uncompleted
and on before redirect or both required
so precisely what to make it simple let
me say like this with this web request
you can let's say change the response
header change the request header
maybe block the request maybe redirect
from domain a to domain B maybe stop the
OAuth requirement so let me put back
this I think all of you know ad blockers
right everyone has been using ad
blockers do you think this API can be
used to make an ad blocker of your own
right this is the same exact API which
is used to make every entry tracking
every ad blocker so this is a bit
powerful so as one of my favorite movies
there log the great power comes great
responsibility right
so please and please use this
responsibility the funny part is the
funny part is every extension which is
made
is reviewed by reviewers manually and
programmatically both in chrome Sol and
Firefox store so enough of blabbering
like I told you like this is like really
I mean you know boring part for me also
and I I suppose for you also because as
a as a listener I really am NOT into
listening all that it's like it's like
where's the code show me the code please
show me the code so I have two very
silly silly very very silly errands but
just explaining the idea how it can be
done first first one is link painter by
the name can you guess what it does
sorry it makes the link stand out but
I'm a really bad designer so it will be
really bad so don't have your hope side
so this is a quote basically these are
two files this is one file and this is
other file so can someone tell me which
is this file called manifested Jason
exactly so it has some like name version
manifest version description icons and
the important part is content script
remember I told contains to a few
moments back what it does it injects
JavaScript into the current page right
so this is the format of content script
every one at the back and see this right
perfect so there are two parameters like
vs matches so matches is for like if you
want to inject this JavaScript at every
page or maybe specific regex pattern
let's say I just want to do it on
google.com domains or maybe just on
facebook.com domains so for being as
lazy I am I just put all URLs like hey
please do it on all URL and what to do
just i'm inject this JS file here and
this is my JS file probably if the
mirroring works properly I will just who
here's my link painter here's my
manifesto Jason this is the content
script and content script says oh it's
really hard to coordinate
can we do a Squidward rap okay nothing
sorry
so what I'm doing is very simple I'm
getting all the uncut ads and just
putting the style background read I mean
yeah that's my designer self so sorry
for that so this is manifest so on all
mozilla.org G domains this script will
be injected and it will do whatever is
it in let's try together hopefully this
works so are to install temporary
add-ons we have to go to this specific
page about debugging and we can just
load temporary at all so I created link
painter I will give path to many first
adjacent and here's my link painter it
has a small icon which I this coffee and
this is the name and like let me do two
things first I'll open if the Internet
allows is google.com nothing happened
it's fine because we put a regex for
just module or over G let's open Mozilla
dot over G can you see a bit changed
view of this so this is I know this is
very lame very simple example but my
idea is to make you understand like how
easy it's injecting a JavaScript into
the page and when you can inject a
JavaScript into the page you can do
wonders so every JavaScript developer in
my in this room do you agree to that
like if you can inject a JavaScript into
a page you can do almost anything
everyone
so that's web extinction for you right
let's try another one this is an example
of something using content script and I
will just remove this and reload the
page just to make sure like all the
things are gone now the second one which
I really like is so I just created it
this as a fallback like just in case of
Internet is not
working or some that kind of stuff so
this goes like this um second one is
word counter I bet you cannot guess what
they said on can do okay oh I must hurry
they say so just I will plug into the
code maybe so that we have a better idea
else they will throw me out of the race
so this is a manifest this is the
background script I am telling
background script oh jeez
here is an interesting thing permissions
the permissions are required for some of
the api's maybe all of the most of the
AP is so this will be notified whenever
you install an extension like like in
your mobile app right so you will be
having a notification like hey this
addon wants to access your context menu
and notification so do you agree if you
agree then only this will be installed
sorry you for my pace I'm getting a bit
faster hopefully there's a match so this
in very simple example I'm doing three
steps first thing is I am creating a
menu in the context menu means the
right-click menu
don't worry it's available online I will
just share the slides so I'll create a
menu and give the context like hey I
want the data from selection whatever I
select give me the data to the function
so whenever there is a context menu on
click I'm adding a listener count me
yeah don't judge me on my variable names
you know so uncombed me I'm doing simple
thing I am getting selection text
because I got the selection context here
and with that selection text I am
trimming and splitting and counting the
number of words and I'm just creating a
notification like hey total words this
words dot length and total character
selected s dot length sounds simple cool
let's see it in action
before my time runs out okay so let's
this is the word control this is
manifested of Jason okay let's go here
like this is a background script so it
runs space agnostic anywhere so here is
your first step you can see the context
menu entry and when I click it you have
a notification there total words total
characters make sense but but but we
started the talk like cross browser
extensions right this is all about
Firefox
did you notice then asked you know I
told you like I slave like please
I taught me for her so let's try this on
Chrome does it work
I still have maybe two or three minutes
let's test this quickly two minutes
extensions arm one thing we need to make
sure developer mode is on so that here
we can upload unpacked and it's link
painter link painter is fine let's go to
word counter let's open it and let's
open let's say any website seriously so
let's here's our entry and when we click
it here is our notification right
so there are few things left probably
one minute left so I'll quickly wrap
this up security I told you that
whenever you put a permissions you will
get a prompt that hey these sites want
to do this like for example this grammar
lien on once access I access your data
for all websites yeah that kind of stuff
if you cancel it will not install if you
add it will install debugging I showed
you how to debug debugging basically why
we say it debugging because whenever you
install whenever you install an add-on
or extension in Chrome or Firefox
these guys are looking at me like please
hurry up I will throw you out of the
state so you have to go through through
this process because you can install
only signed or authorize add-ons or
extensions in Chrome and Firefox there
are some tools web extensions or take
where you can start learning this is how
you publish an add-on these are some
resources and thank you guys hopefully I
don't have time for questions or do I
have yeah if you have any question I
propose to disk use outside sorry guys I
mean I remember well available outside
you can just grab me there I think
you'll expose a joke it was very
interesting thank you
putting it outside oh thank you I have
some goodies I'm putting it out check
this room if someone is interested
please grab it oh maybe I can just keep
it here if you don't let it in are you
sure okay while you set up please
compact like arrived please a CEO a
place yeah okay okay