hello thank you for coming I'll be
presenting it's like the second or third
time I'm presenting this project so it's
a very new one even though it's
something within its ideas we've been
showing you around with over many years
so if you go to the website you'll find
a link for at the end of the
presentation you'll see code it's free
software you'll be able to download it
to run it but it's not a fully set
project yet like others so there is not
a full-featured website and everything
so it's something new and presenting to
you today I'll be describing our ideas
for a browser for the web of data here
is the problem the problem is you have
the internet which is a network of
computers are using tcp/ip and the DNS
and the DNS is a way to name the
computers on top of that you have URLs
HTTP and HTML that provide a network of
documents so on top of the network of
computers using the names of the
computers the DNS you can based on the
DNS name the documents and have a
network of documents that's the web you
know right so what you have to browse
that web of documents is the web browser
the one you use either Chrome Firefox
Opera whatever the question becomes when
you extend the web and do not only
publish documents which are mainly text
but you start publishing data let's say
for example just a simple comma
separated value file
that's data that you can easily parse
with a program and extract the
information you want from and reduce so
when you start to publish data and here
you have a network of data instead of a
network of documents what do you use to
browse that data so that's the main
question the project comes from since
there is only one web a single web on
which you publish both the documents and
the data the idea and you can have
lengths there are URLs that link from
documents to documents from document to
data from data to data from data to
document an answer you can give to that
question is we want the web browser to
be able to browse and to display both
documents and data so we want the web
browser to be able to display both type
of information and to have the display
and the the interactions depend on the
type of the data so if you have to
display HTML that's the common case you
know and use daily and if you want to
display data that's described using the
dublin core vocabulary or the scows
vocabulary or the foe or for BR all
those vocabularies you want the browser
to be able to display the data on the
screen on the page we decided to explore
what we would have by implementing this
idea as a web extension that you could
install in all the browsers if you go to
the catalog of extensions for Firefox
you'll see a page for a cubic web and
you can just click uninstall that
extension you have the same thing on the
chrome store so let's see the quick demo
so you go to distort yep so you have a
browser here with a new profile so I
just go to the store look for the
extension click on install I accept the
permissions and there I have my
extensions my extension that's installed
right the so that's the first step which
is the installation the second step
would be the configuration of the
extension the kind of configuration
information you'll be providing is how
you want to display specific type of
data so for a specific type of
information you get AZ data from the web
server how you want to turn that into
HTML that's displayed by the browser so
the configuration is about providing
ways to turn data into HTML that's what
we will be doing now by going to the
Preferences and here you have the
sources of configuration so here we just
go to a website this website is
providing views views that turn data
into HTML and there is a link here you
click on the link and it should so here
you have a an HTML document that
describes what are the views published
but that website and what kind of data
the views can turn into HTML and after
you click on the link you have the okay
so in this layer in this case I just
copy and paste the link to the
configuration space here so we'll be
adding that source of views to my
extension in my browser configuration
okay so this is none and if you go to
the list here you can ask the extension
what is the list of the views that are
registered and as you can see here we
have a view to display RDF triples
we have a view to display book to
display a conference to display a
conference talk a conference track and
to display person so these are all the
views all the transforms that at this
point my extension knows about now if I
move to the okay to the website of the
conference
our first browse the website the usual
way so my client my browser is making a
request to the server it's getting back
HTML and it's displaying the HTML first
well do the the will go over the pages
of the web server receiving and
displaying HTML as a second step will do
will go over the same track but getting
data and turning data into HTML so first
common browsing we just see a list of
conferences which is one so we click on
the link we display a conference after
that as you can see we get HTML after
that we'll be clicking on the link to a
track for the track we'll have the list
of all the presentations if we click on
a link for presentation we'll get the
page of a presentation we move to the
page of the offer and okay just going
back so we go to the conference and we
do the same thing but getting the data
from the server instead of getting a
document an HTML document as you can see
we have here at the top right we have
the icon of the extension that that's
lit up because the extension detected
that the web server is able to send both
HTML and raw data so the by clicking on
the extension we'll get raw data from
the server instead of getting HTML so
there you go so that's HTML but
generated within the browser from the
data that we got from the server
and we have the page for the conference
well you can see this is in this case
it's rdf serialized as XML so it's the
XML format for RDF and this is the
actual file that was sent by the server
and the extension turned this into into
the HTML that was displayed so we click
on the link again and there we have the
information for the track as you can see
there is a little delay during which the
extension will be downloading all the
data for the different session for the
different talks and after it get the
talks it will display them ok so now we
have the title of the talks there I will
click on one one talk and it's the View
for displaying a table that will be used
to generate the HTML there I will click
on the author and as you can see this
view that's displaying a person as a
link here for all the persons that this
person know so this is me and I'm
pretending that I know claude debussy
he's dead but whatever so I'll be
clicking on the link here and by
clicking on this link I'm going to
another visualization another piece of
data that was downloaded from the server
and turned into HTML as you can see it's
the same function that turns data into
views into HTML for person that was used
so the same view the same function
transformed data into HTML both for
myself in the first case and in this
case for claude debussy
there is one important change though in
the first case the data was sent by the
website of the same web poll conference
and in this case the data is sent as
you can see here in the URL by dbpedia
so same web poll on dbpedia are able to
describe persons using the same
vocabulary so they are sending the data
in the same format in the same data
model that data model here is called
full as friend of a friend so semi pro
is sending foaf my browser as a function
that turns foaf into HTML i click on the
link I get to another piece of data sent
by dbpedia so dbpedia sent me fo and i
turned both into HTML again so i'm
browsing from one server to the next as
i would do
moving from one server to a next to the
next when clicking on the link in an
HTML document except here the link I
followed is a link in the data so I got
data from one server with a link to data
on another server I clicked on that link
got the data from the other server and
displayed it again
so I'm browsing a web of data as I would
do for a web of HTML documents if I
continue here in that case I have a
photograph I have more length and I this
would be an link to another piece of
data on dbpedia and here if I display
the same thing I come the same data I
can choose a different view so that's
the raw data if you want so the same
information I can choose different views
to display it and the last thing if I go
back to the person view there I will go
to another type of information which is
the description of work so as you can
see I'm moving from one piece of data to
the next and choosing how I display the
data I got from the server
now if I go back to the slides for this
to work it requires the servers to
collaborate we need because the
extension has to know that it can get
data from the server instead of HTML and
the extension has to make sure that when
it gets the information the the role
HTTP protocol is followed them it knows
what type of information gets so what do
we have today to make this work we have
HTTP content negotiation for example the
browser in this case the extension can
in the HTTP request say I would like
application RDF instead of HTML or it
could say I want X total and there are
other mime types that would work for
sending data in like this other means to
do the same thing you can add a link
header in the HTTP response like so we
can say you can have this information in
HTML or you can have alternate
representations in RDF for example but
the server has to be set up for that you
could have a content type correctly set
in the HTTP header there are some
servers that would serve RDF but without
the proper content type in that case the
extension cannot cannot behave properly
because it doesn't know what is the
information it gets you can have in HTML
in the editor you can put linked
relationships to alternate
representations and in the end I'm not
the one making all the internet
specifications so this proves that it
can then that it can work and we'll see
if more people start publishing the
information like this and setting up
servers correctly and maybe those
standards will evolve at some point
important points about VHT
views of the audience data as you can
see there are distinct from the web
extension so there is one thing which is
installing the extension and another
thing which is country degrading the
extension with views which means anyone
can publish views and you don't have to
make your views public you could have
your views in your intranet for example
its each user is choosing how to
configure his extension so what views
will be displaying what type of data its
usable on any website I'm not part of
the team that's making dbpedia so for
the demonstration it just worked with a
public website already
the views are functions that you develop
in JavaScript or in typescript if you
want one they are simple to publish as
you saw on the website where I got the
configuration that was only static page
a static page and a static file that
would be imported in the browser and the
conclusion is let's redo centralize the
web thank you
[Applause]
yes yes
so there are many different ones many
different catalogs or this is building
on the standards of the Semantic Web the
Semantic Web started in the mid-90s so
it's already more than twenty years ago
projects like dbpedia started more than
10 years ago and you have many catalogs
where you can look for data models like
this there are standard for a specific
type of information like for pers for
describing persons for describing books
for describing genes for many things one
is the love linked open data vocabulary
so it's love dot ok FM dot I don't
remember
maybe org or something but you can look
on so also on websites you can look at
the w3c on the wiki where you would get
more length to catalogs so it's
something that already started ten years
ago
so you can do a way yeah you can do a
web search you can do you can go on
portals that publish open data and so
the question was how do you find models
for a specific topic right um okay so
the the first first place you can have a
look to is the linked open vocabulary
catalog so it's Oviedo okay FM you can
look for that one there is also a site
linked data org and there is a beta but
there is a search engine from Google
that's in beta right now that's called
data search where you can type some word
and it will show you the kind of data
model and data sets that correspond to
the word and there is also one site you
might want to take a look at which is
schema.org which was made by the
different search engines to help people
publish data aside HTML
[Applause]