nice
[Applause]
okay so our next speaker is Mack booth
from that topic if I understood
correctly that epoch is a company
providing hosting services for their
customer right after a fashion yes okay
so I leave the room to you I'm sorry
that you will have only 15 minutes for
your talk to keep it brief my name is
Matt and I'm a programmer based in
Sheffield in the UK and I co-founded
this organization the Dark Peak Data
cooperative now Sheffield has a pretty
active grassroots tech scene and if
you've been to the FOSDEM
beer event you'll know that the IT scene
has a pretty severe be a problem so it's
appropriate that this project began in a
pub in Sheffield this pub I'm sure
highly recommend I now found myself
talking to other programmers after like
tech meetups and discovered that we had
some common interests we were all kind
of into hosting things for ourselves we
all like had our own websites someone
was hosting the mailing list someone was
hosting git repos that kind of thing and
we all had a shared interest in not
being the product I'm sure everyone in
this room in particular is familiar with
the concept where if you're not paying
for a service you're the product and we
want to we want to avoid that and avoid
data that's kept about is from being
used in ways we we don't control so we
begin to wonder how we can collaborate
with a name to share the cost of hosting
things so that we don't all have to buy
servers we can just you know or use the
same one and then we can share expertise
as well because we're not all experts in
all of the things that we want to use
with the eventual goal of you know
weaning ourselves off of Google entirely
and and things like that so if only
there was some kind of organization we
could
of which we could all be members
ourselves and then we could charge our
members fees and then use those fees to
pay for the infrastructure and develop
the services and then because user data
abuses are a hot topic in the news all
the time then maybe you know other
people outside of our little groups
would be interested in joining as well
and then we can give all of those
members a say and Carol the organization
is run and give them control on how
their data is being used so let's start
co-op this is pretty much the dictionary
definition what we wanted to do is
pretty much the dictionary definition of
a co-op where we want to be an
autonomous Association of people who are
united voluntarily to meet our common
needs with a jointly owned and
democratically controlled social
enterprise so we approached an
organization in Sheffield called the s
SC DG the Sheffield Corp Development
Group and they are part of co-opt UK and
they offer advice and help people set up
cooperative organizations so we spoke to
though we spoke to those people and they
so co-op to UK offer a whole bunch of
templates for starting companies as
cooperatives or charitable trusts and
the Sheffield Development Group were
able to sort of narrow down once we
described what we want to do they
narrowed it down to these three kinds of
coops that they thought might suit as
best the first one Community Interest
Company I think we dismissed straight
away because it comes with some
obligations like proving like doing
reports on how you are involving the
local community and proving that your
company is of value to the local low you
know there was extra administrative
overhead we thought that we didn't
really need the multi stakeholder
cooperative we dismissed but I don't
really remember why I so we eventually
settled on forming a consortium and
the course consortium is a cooperative
that is owned and controlled by the
people who use the services which is us
and members get involved by paying for
those services and I've got a note here
I think in mainland Europe this is
sometimes known as a small enterprise
cooperative if that if that means
something so we decided to start
ourselves a cooperative so we bought a
domain we started a company for I think
it cost us like a hundred one hundred
and fifty quid some nominal amount of
money to start the company and then you
can have yourself their company limited
by guarantee that can follow the
principles of a cooperative so now I'd
like to try and convince you about the
pros and cons of starting a co-op
yourself there is some minor drawbacks
there's some amount of admin work you
have to do we have to hold general
meetings throughout the year with
agendas and things we have to there's a
comedy resolution that we have to pass
every year which is to as a board of
directors of the co-operative we have to
pass a resolution to and not be audited
because we have a you know under the
revenue threshold for that I don't know
who chooses to be audited makes no sense
to me we also have to pay an accountant
which just I mean you could do the
paperwork yourself I suppose but who
wants to deal with HMRC but that just
does bump off the like the cost of the
organisation but the benefits I think
outweigh that so you have shared
responsibilities you join the coop
hooray
you're no longer doing things on your
own one of the policies we've instituted
is if you want to host a service in the
coop you have to have buy-in from one of
the member which just means that you
know you've got vacation cover and
sickness cover own shares of
responsibility of maintaining a service
you've got shared accounting we started
a business bank account obviously to
collect the membership fees and to pay
for the hosting and whatnot
and shared expertise as I said earlier
which is very good because you know you
might have maintained a mail server
I've never maintained a mail server so
but we both want mail servers the we can
have a CL a CA a a contributor License
Agreement or copyright assignment
agreement for our members that's quite
interesting because the protection that
gives you is twofold it protects the
members because without this in any
license squabble we would only be able
to act on violations if the co-operative
itself owns the copyright on the code
and it also protects the coop because if
you get a contribution from a member
that turns out to originate from a
proprietary product then you can shift
the liability back to the misbehaving
member because they contractually agreed
that their contribution was not
infringing and there are a couple of
unexpected benefits like as in a
technical sense I'm a director of a
company I can sign people's passports
right was it unexpected and of course we
have the Democratic operation which kind
of brings us to our principles as a
cooperative I apologize if this is a bit
repetitive if you caught the libre
hostesses talk earlier we have a bit of
overlap so we we give you data with
representation so you get a say in how
your data is treated within the
organization and we give you time to
migrate if you're leaving and will make
all efforts we can to remove your data
after you've left we promote the dignity
of their ownership so we value the we
value your privacy and and the control
that you have over how you share
information with others we give you the
freedom to host yourselves so any
services that we host you should be able
to host on your own as well that is like
one of the best probably the only way
right now where you can migrate your
data somewhere else you just fire up a
new instance of our server
somewhere else and import your you know
import your data that's probably the
easiest way to do it and obviously all
of our services are free and open source
so that enables that and we also try to
federate and interoperate wherever
possible like with our Macedon instance
we can interact with people one of the
Macedon instances which is good we rely
on open standards and you know if a Sun
that is open an open source
implementation of that standard is
pretty much guaranteed to follow so some
technical hurdles that we had I
mentioned earlier we're not programmed
we're not so that means with programmers
with our powers combined we make just
about one barely competent sysadmin I've
developed a lot of respect for system
administrators in this project so it's
good work guys um we started out on this
adventure using docker we wanted to
break all of the services down into
there into smaller components and do it
right but in the end it didn't really
work out for us I don't think docker was
really solving any problems that we had
in terms of scalability and whatnot so
eventually we just we got rid of that
and then we are now managing VMs using
ansible if you've used and support
before it's just got more files that
tell their VM how to behave we added a
sister single sign-on feature which was
quite interesting we used so being able
to log into one of application and then
have that authenticated session
following you to the other applications
that we host with it's a really nice
feature for users but it turns out
almost no application support it and
this probably prompted a move from nginx
to Apache because the party has a better
single sign-on plug-in called mod Mellon
which we use and then that fronts a lot
of our services behind that the
two-factor authentication
again great feature for users
and he gives you this confidence in the
security and whatnot but some
applications have problems with this in
particular if you're using a mobile app
to speak to any of our hosted services
there's not always it's always easy it's
not always in particular my IRC client
is a real pain to use with two-factor
authentication so we've had to we ended
up making that optional for now but
hopefully in the future we can make it
you know we can allow users to make it
mandatory for their accounts and email
email on my notes on my notes here it
says a big scary important easy to get
wrong and a few of us have made attempts
hosting our own email services and again
it can't be said enough what program is
not safe that means we've always been
scared away so what we'll probably do is
outsource that to another another small
cooperative in Sheffield hopefully we
can get those guys on board to help us
out with that and I'm aware that I was
late starting so I guess I'll wrap up
there if you want to discover more about
is where it peaked at org you can chat
to is on IRC I'm M booth in the Dark
Peak Channel thank you very much for
listening
so your magician you did it's so thank
you and again I apologize on behalf of
the organization team now if there is
any question yes I have two questions
number one can you join a CLE from
Manchester yes we've had member in fact
we've got a member in Edinburgh and we
until not long ago we had a member in
Norway we convinced him to move to
Sheffield though okay and number two in
a bit more complicated what so you're a
lot of your talk focused on the sort of
organizing model of the co-operative and
how do you think that or like what
principles from the co-operative
organizing model do you think can be
applied to open source development or
free software development and
communities yeah it's an interesting
question I think I think they kind of
been separate I think the two are kind
of orthogonal because for open source
project development are quite a good
model is that they'd been out than
dictator for life model right you have
someone who's in charge of the vision
for the software project but that
project is not responsible for other
people's data right so if if you're in a
member of an organization that is
dealing with your data you want more
democratic control over it that's better
better for users I think any questions
how do you do SSO with the email you
don't do imagine we don't you remarry
yeah no seven there are people in the UK
at the moment trying to sort of
centralized planning for hack spaces
have you talked to them because you sort
of probably have very similar goals and
ideas to them I have not I'm afraid but
I was keen to it Thanks so why not
docker yeah so I I didn't go into too
much detail then but we found it it was
for one it was impenetrable for
newcomers to the organization
not everyone's got experience with
docker and the necessary steps you have
to take to get up and running with it
and we got ourselves into a situation
where production deployments of the
infrastructure was done from a single
members laptop so we wanted to like
maybe this is like too risky let's make
it something that's basically on
something that more people are familiar
with out of the box which a lot more
people in my experience have had
experience with ansible and things like
ansible you come to the libro hosters
matrix channel and we can discuss about
communities and this kind of thing so
special interests you okay
if there was no more question thank you
very much okay
[Music]
don't forget to give constructive
feedback on the first demo website