I'm happy I guess to have some more
material to throw at developers when you
have a chat about this topic with them
it's a very important topic that we are
going to cover and maybe with some
surprises for you guys so let's dive in
I've been using a PostgreSQL for a long
time I began on the previous century and
I'm part of the contributors to it I've
worked at situs data and I'm told by our
marketing department that we have nice
socks that I can throw in the audience
if you want them so usually it's a if
you ask a good question I throw a sock
but if you say this talk is awesome you
will get a sock anyway so so be sure to
yell something and I throw socks okay
see there is one we are you know the
rules and so as mentioned before I've
been working on a deal odor the idea of
pijl odor is that you can meet weight
from another database technology to
PostgreSQL in one common line it only
needs two parameters so your former
database connection string and your
PostgreSQL connection string it will
figure it all out by itself figure out
the schema the datatypes the casting
rules everything the default values
foreign keys primary keys index is
etcetera and it's pretty good at it the
goal when I wrote this tool is that
there is a lot of open source software
that I would like to use but they're
using my sequel and I will not trust my
data to that technology it's personal
ok and so no you don't have an excuse if
you're working with my sequel you just
run one command line and you can use
PostgreSQL instead so no excuses anymore
just use it so ok let's dive in with a
data modelling the time modeling is a
very important part of using PostgreSQL
because some databases technology around
here are proud to be schematics we are
not we are not schema s and we need to
see what it means so this quote is from
Rob Pike and from a book issued in the
70s I believe
so it says that if you if you have
chosen the right data structures and
organized things well the algorithms
will almost always be self-evident data
structures not algorithms are central to
programming okay so it's meant that
application developers who are writing
code if you're writing Python code then
you know you need to think about or you
organize the data in your code like in a
class in a structure you know named
tuple in something else and all you pass
data along that's the most important
thing enjoy right about the same
terminology is if you lingo it's strict
if you really see it right yeah but it's
always the same idea that if your data
in the code is well organized then the
code is it is easy to read and you don't
have so many bugs if the data is a mess
you have a lots of bugs because every
anything you want to do is going to be
complex to do when the data is not
doesn't lend itself to being processed a
specific way it's exactly the same with
database modeling if you're if you're
having a really hard time writing your
sequel queries most of the time it could
be one or the other reason the first
version usually is you don't know sequel
very well so it's normal that you find
it hard to do because you know there yet
the other reason is the schema is not
adapted to your business case so of
course every query you want to write is
going to be hard to write so if you have
a proper schema design then sequel is
really easy to write so in this talk
we're going to overview the classic
rules that allow you to design a schema
properly before we do that I want to
show some some example just to get your
mind started because the rules are a
little complex to handle so data
modelling usually revolves around data
types constraints and when we say
constraints in databases so most people
we don't want to have constraints you
know our lives right we want to be free
to whatever we want to whatever we fancy
we nobody likes or almost nobody likes
having constraints so most of people
when we talk about database constraints
there are
constraints it's boring so the the I
think the term should be changed it's
not a constraints really that you're
having it's a guarantee a very strong
guarantee for your data in the database
so we'll tell more about that in the
more slides but constraints is the
technical term that everybody uses but
when you we should have in mind these
guarantees so almost how many guarantees
or strong the guarantees you have anew
the device you want to have if your
schema-less you have zero guarantees
it's all up to you that's why we are
really happy with PostgreSQL to have a
data modelling issues and the schema and
cetera because it means we have strong
warranties and from implementing
constraints usually we use primary keys
foreign keys checks right so couple
examples this is a table where where you
would handle articles like news articles
it's a really classic one with a primary
key and this schema is wrong okay is it
obvious for everyone why it is obviously
wrong okay so we'll get back to that
later in the talk so just I'm just
trying to tease your easel this one is
okay it's a partial unique index example
that I just could be pasted from an
example example and Stack Overflow or
something
so it's implementing toggles for like a
UI for for the users and they can toggle
it on and off so they can enable it or
disable it and when it's disabled you
want to remember they did use it before
and then they disabled it so if it's
currently have a value in disable that
columns then you don't want basically
you don't you're not taking care of it
in the application so you can say that
you have a unique index on the toggles
but only it it only needs to be unique
if it's not been disabled okay when you
you could do partial unique index in
PostgreSQL yeah not very yeah some of
you okay good
so it's a really nice trick to have and
another kind of a guarantee that we are
going to see later is exclude you
using Geist so who's done that before in
PostgreSQL okay for the other guys we're
going to dive into that later in the
talk
the goal of that way is modeling the
first goal is to avoid anomalies so
there are three possible kind of
anomalies inserted I did it basically so
update anomaly the schema is wrong the
model is not good because you see in the
same table we have the employee ID its
address and a set of skills that are
associated with the employee employee
but this employee apparently I moved in
in between where I learned not to be a
public speaker and when he learned
currently is not living somewhere else
so now we have 200 in the database that
are disagreeing with each other
so which is the right one what is the
current address of this guy well we
don't know we don't know and why don't
we know because the the schema is wrong
we should have the address at only one
place not two of them so how to make it
happen we'll see that later so that's
the update anomaly because we we have
updated the address and now we have two
of them and we don't know which one is
the right one insertion anomaly is let's
say that you have a schema for the in
the faculty for professors who are
giving courses and so each professor
might be given one or several courses
and this new one has been hired in the
faculty but it doesn't have a course yet
and with this model we cannot even enter
the information because it doesn't have
a course yet okay so it's obviously
wrong right so that's insertion anomaly
you cannot insert the data with that
model and then of course the other side
of it is the deletion anomaly so now if
this guy is not doing that course
anymore you want to delete the line but
if you do you forget about him you don't
have him in the system anymore so you
cannot show up at the office or whatever
I don't know oh it works exactly their
system but because it doesn't have a
course anymore is not on the list
anymore
so I think it's quite obvious for a
buddy everybody why those schemas are
wrong
so no we are going to try to explain the
rules around how not to get that schema
and answer more the thing that is
central to the best design is that so I
like this other quote to explain it so I
will read it out loud again so it's from
the Fred Brooks and he said show me your
flowcharts and conceal your tables and
I'll shall continue to be mystified
show me your tables and I want usually
need your flow chart because there will
be obvious okay the database design
should be that abuse when we look at
your database design if you don't
understand the business from it usually
it means it's not so good it means that
you've been lazy
maybe you implemented the database
design the same way you did your object
oriented architecture in your software
but your software is going to be tasked
with implementing a particular user
workflow so you take one user in the
system if it's a web application for
example you're going to drive the user
and enable the user to do something like
a particular workflow and the code is
all about that but the database is
guaranteeing the data business model is
guarantees constraint etc for the wool
system at one at once tie at one time so
it's not the same thing serving one user
and making sure that the system globally
is consistent so your advice is about
the wool system being consistent and
your code is about allowing users to do
what they have to do with your system so
there is a few reasons why it should be
the same model anyway so practically for
the tooling some people would use a
graphical stuff etc so it's a it's a
very nice way if you are more visual
it's a nice way to basically to
understand the problem set but then when
I usually do myself is I just write a
sequence quit and I do begin and
rollback and so I needed that thing to
fit on the slide so it's a very small
one usually I insert more things into
the tables and then I watch
sample queries that I know we love to
use in the application and again if the
queries are complex to write I'm like
maybe that's not the right schema if
every query is easy to do I'm like okay
and maybe I can go with that and you see
this trick here rollback so I think to
this day I'm not sure to this day but
PostgreSQL is the only one or maybe one
of the very few systems where you can
actually have transactions and details
so you can create schema create table
and then roll back and nothing is there
anymore okay so in other systems that I
won't name but as soon as you do create
schema or great table then there is an
implicit commit for the transaction so
when you do rollback then the system is
like there is no transaction running
which is the most scariest warning ever
and like commit or rollback and no there
is no transaction currently happening
what okay so with PostgreSQL you can
actually do that and so you can refine
your schema as you go because when you
do roll back you're back to a pristine
stage again so you can do it as many
times as you want to and you can change
your mind like maybe 50 times in a day
and play around with it and see what
happens you just run the script and at
the end nothing happened so you had some
stats around at the end of it some
queries that are giving more information
about the schema and when you're happy
with it then you change that into a
commit you run it again and now you have
your database schema to play around with
some people are using averred tools
called the horror M and I say it's an
object relational mapping and almost
every one of them that I had to have a
look at is doing it wrong because the
are in our M stands for relation right
relation is the result of a sequel query
so one kind of so do you know that in
the sequel standard so we have select
query and we also have another query
that is named table so if you have a
table like in the previous example
category if you do table category it
will dump the rule content of the table
category okay so obviously a table is a
kind of a relation so the if you have a
table you can
use it as a relation but it's only one
specific case for relations it's not the
general idea the general idea is that
any and every SQL query that you are
using is defining a relation and can be
used as a relation that's why when you
do a select with a from clause in the
from clause you can have sub selects
because does any select kadmiel relation
so it can be used as a from source in a
query okay so the ORM should be actually
mapping the relation that is the result
of the sequel query into your objects in
the code and that would be a good or m12
so if you're doing Java have a look at
Duke g oq if you're doing doing PHP have
a look at pun comm and there are others
in other programming languages that the
two of them that I have in my mind so if
you're doing something else find it
there is there must be a tool that is
doing it the proper way but if you have
an ORM that is mapping the base tables
to your objects in memory well you don't
have a use case for that really
so it helps no one and it's a it's
complex to use that straw and it's very
people would say that it's really hard
to map those two things together that's
why I have this schema here but it's
actually because usually I do it the
wrong way if you try to solve the wrong
program it's way harder that if you try
to work to solve the problem you
actually have so the the mapping should
be done with a sequel results so that
that's all I want to say about where I
am so we're going to talk about database
design and modeling and normalization
and I won't talk any more about our ends
okay so that was the basis for database
modeling and the next step is auto you
know if your model is good enough or not
so we're going to introduce a set of
rules that are really helpful to to know
that before I do that any questions yet
no maybe not so nobody wants any sucks I
guess yeah some people do I'm not good
at aiming so please figure it out
there will be more if people want more
yeah later
so normalization what does it mean
basically it's following a set of
principles that are allow we allowing us
to think about the schema in a theory
own practical way those are a few of the
rules that are in a book from the 70s
80s about the basics of the UNIX
philosophy with the strong principles
and I'd like to use that because as I
said the goal is really to have a chat
with developers application developers
here and UNIX principles they apply well
to building software and what I want to
have people think about is that the the
same design principles that you can use
to write software you can use them to
write your database schema it's the same
thing
so clarity simplicity transparency
robustness
that's nice goals that you want to
achieve when you do a database schema
and because it's all about the schema
one thing is drive don't repeat yourself
but I'm using also that slide as a
warning this topic is a little dry so
it's not that fun to talk about but it's
very important so let's do it anyway so
who knows about normal forums yeah so
you know it's from the 70s so
everybody's like yeah we're in the 2000
something already it's like stuff for
granddaddy's but actually you know
nobody said that wrong now so they're
still very much to this day important to
remember figure out and use so when you
design a database schema remember about
those rules and actually do them so the
first normal form the target is that you
don't have duplicated rows in the table
and no repeating groups arrays each cell
is a single value so I've seen many
schemas and I've been doing some
consulting before and many schemas were
there is always this table with a
commercial capacity parroted set of
values because you know creating a new
table in the table in production was
born so they just added fields in the in
a single field and as soon as you do
that then sequel is going to be really
because sequel doesn't lend itself very
well to that and so that those are the
first rules single numbers word so the
trick with the normal forms is to reach
the next people you need first to reach
the first level so if you want to be
sick on the world form you need to make
sure you you are compatible with the
first normal form first so you need to
do them one after the other
always so it's second normal form if it
is already first normal form and as no
partial dependencies so here is another
way to say it
none key attribute is dependent on only
a part of the composite key it means
that if you have many columns all of the
columns should have something some kind
of a relationship in his very definition
towards the primary key if it doesn't it
has nothing to do in this table remember
about the employee ID and its address
the address is not really something
specific of the employee maybe model one
people are living in the same house it's
not a property of the the employee so it
it's not dependent really and it's a non
key attribute that is not dependent on
the part of the composite key it's right
straw as I told you it's dry topic so
I'm not going to dive very deep into it
if you if you like tharok approaches
make it so that you have sometimes to
dive into the topic later we're going to
switch soon to a more practical ways to
handle it after to normal the second
normal form you have the third one and
the bcnf one with a voice code usually
what I do when I design a schema is I
try to target bcnf because it's the it's
the point where it's still useful and
not so hard to achieve and there is more
of course you can go to the force v
which is projection drawing normal form
and then you have D K and F which is a
step further so I'll give you an example
if you are for example handling
addresses in your database so you have
an address field how much
or deep you want to be in normalization
are you going to do first normal form or
up to decay NF foreign Rudra's field so
if you want to design it properly
because you have cities in a city you
have streets street names but actually
the street names you find them in most
other cities around it so you would have
a catalogue of all the street names that
are known and for its street name you
want a relationship with which city is
actually using that street name and then
in this city we for this street name
what are the the number the numbers on
the buildings that are available in the
street because sometimes the skip number
sometimes you have in Paris there is a
street where you have four number fours
in the street yeah so I had a meeting
once and I showed up at the meeting
number four in the street an eye out for
four B's for tear for something else and
what so I had to call them but if you
are a job if if you need to design an
address database model because your job
is for example to I don't know ever
deliver things to people or maybe you
are installing fiber or electricity or
phone to people homes and you need the
exact address and maybe you need the
exact location of the box that is owned
by your company and that is available in
the people home maybe you need to do the
proper way and then maybe you need to do
that in a way that you can then optimize
the traffic and the routing when there
is like uncool people that needs to show
up at the people's houses so no you need
also a GIS system at a profit that's
true now if your business model for
having the address of people is because
you want to invoice them like you know
you generate a PDF that you send by
email but legally it's required to have
the address of the company on the PDF
well maybe a single field is going to be
everything you know all you need for the
AdWords so it all depends on the level
of normal forms that you want to go in a
database depends on what you are going
to do with the data if all you do is
accept it and then put it again
you don't care it's a text field if
you're going to actually have to process
it and it's going to be important to you
in your business then you need to you
know make the effort to make it actually
possible to use it
so it's a set of rules and you need to
figure out it for yourself or much of it
applies to your use case trick is if
you're not sure just do them all and as
you good as you do them there is a point
where you will say so this one was easy
to achieve this one was a little more
work but I'm happy I did it because I
saw some bugs in my schema doing that
this one was more complex I didn't find
many bugs this one was fine but it
begins to get boring and I don't get out
anything out of this one it's it's only
adding new tables and new things and I
don't see the purpose of that but at
this point now you have an opinion that
in your case your schema is fine in bcnf
and may be boring in 4nf but if you
don't do the exercise you will never
know okay so please do it and figure out
at which point it gets very boring for
you and stop it then but just do it
first okay you will be very happy you
did that because you will actually find
bugs in your schema each and every time
and an example is coming it's coming now
actually because the way we implement
those warranties in a database is with
as we said before database constraint so
I told you this is roamed so who wants
to win a sock by guessing why it's wrong
YAG i'm going to throw them anyway but
please try to figure it out so yeah I
don't know at the end of the talk you
will have some more if you want to
apparently it's really I'm not good
enough at that so anyway primary key
means your first normal form compatible
because there is no duplicates in the
table right that's what it means America
have you heard about surrogate keys yes
yes yes is the DBA you knows about it
yes so a surrogate key looks like the
primary key but actually it's not it's a
substitute for natural key the natural
key is what allows preventing duplicate
entries so let's switch to this example
in the article table the primary key is
not listed here because look it's big
circle so the ID you don't need to give
it to PostgreSQL if you don't give it it
will be derived from a sequence and by
the way sequences in sequel are the only
sequel objects that are non
transactional and that's on purpose
so everything in PostgreSQL is
transactional except for sequences and
that's in the sequel standard so it's
not just positive SQL and if you don't
know why maybe you don't understand
transactions so you should have a look
at that
I'm not going to explain not today at
least so we insert category pub date
title and do you realize that it's
exactly the same values we inserting
look at that do we have a primary key
really because the fact that this
country is ID 3 and this entry ID for no
single user of your application cares
right no one is ever going to be exposed
to the fact that this article is ID 3
and the only difference is you have in
between those two rows is the ID so
basically you have a duplicate entry so
basically the schema is not first normal
form compatible ok so it's really shitty
you don't do that so how do we fix it
well we want natural primary key and
then we need to understand the business
model a little more so what I did here
is primary key over the category the
publication date and the title which
means that in the rule history of the
news article you're going to publish you
will never be allowed to reuse data from
the past well is it your no because you
have the publication date so you can
reuse the title but maybe you don't want
to so you need to figure it out so I was
too fast story about that so
see it again because there is the
publication date in the primary key you
have you can use the same title of the
article in the same category more than
once at different times like maybe you
want to react sarcastically about an
article you published last year or
something like that but maybe your
business model is that you never ever
reuse title because I don't know the
journalism rules and maybe it's
important for them I don't know so
because I'm not a journalist or a chief
editor or something like that I'm not
sure what should the primary key be but
the the point I'm trying to make is that
the only way to know is that you need to
understand the business model before you
do it so as a developer if you don't
understand the business model well
enough to do that then spend the day or
two with the other guys to predict the
eyes or if it's journalism spend the day
with the journalists asking them how it
should work because you need to figure
it out now and once you did that it
means that any other table that has a
foreign key relationship to your table
no needs to have a foreign key
relationship to the three columns which
is not only boring to write but also
it's taking a lot of space on disk and
it's making the indexes are going to be
bigger and maybe will have an impact on
the right capacity of your system and
it's droids Taurus so we we say it's a
distributed cost because it is going to
be costly in more than one way and but
it is so it's the right way to do it but
it's costly so is there a trade-off
yeah maybe you asked so oh you have a
you can use a surrogate key which means
that you have a an integer here the ID
or maybe you want to be a big in factory
generate it always as identity it's the
new way in the standard to spell
sequence or begin or something like that
so please use that spelling is better
than using the previous one for some
reasons there is a really good article
online that explains in details if you
if you type that in Google usually the
first link is this article so it's easy
to find out so we will use that as a
unique column but the primary key is
still that okay that's the natural
primary key but we guarantee the ID is
going to be unique
so that you can use it in a foreign key
reference so I didn't write the slide
for it but now you can foreign key
reference only the idea because it's
granted to be unique by PostgreSQL so
you can use it that way but it's only a
surrogate key and it's made clear in the
schema because know the primary key is
written here right any question about
that yes that's the usual question yes
so we could so I'm going to repeat it we
could do it the other way around and say
this one is primary key and the other
one is unique mostly it's the same thing
but I like to declare the intention so
your intention is that the natural
primary key of this database design is
here and this one is as a facility
you're going to use in other parts of
the software because it's useful so it
makes it obvious that is the case yes
yes it's a yes the so the question is
about what if I have a nun tree there
but I need to change the publication
date because it was wrong well then it's
going to change yes but not the idea
that's why you the idea is useful but
the idea is nothing to do with the fact
that it's going to guarantee that your
wage first normal form that's not
helping but it's helping for the
purposes so that's why it's a good
trade-off okay yes not null would be
good yes thank you so you spot the bug
in my slide here is this up for you yeah
so anyone who spotted a bug you get a
sock okay we have other constraints - in
sequel so I will just list some of them
we did talk a little about primary keys
and foreign keys not nil we just said
it's important check constraint you can
have a manual check that it's not new
and that there is a nice trick word
check constraint for example each time
it's from week over there each time week
has seen a customer use a start date and
an end date in a table he found some
data where the end date was before the
start date it's generally time unless
you do a check constraint on that the
database is not going to be able to
guarantee that for you and you will have
bugs because we always have work right
we just had one before but it was in a
slide so it's okay but in your
application code it's a little different
so mind your check constraints if it's
important for you that you have things
that are like for example start before
the end well maybe you should instruct
the database that is the case so that
you can warranties the warranty that for
you and then in PostgreSQL and we also
have exclusion constraints basically
it's it's like a unique constraint but
it's spelled a little differently than
unique what we say that we if we meet
with data with the same currency and an
overlapping validity period date range
which is not exactly the same as
but we're using it that way here well in
that case we want to exclude the new
line so it's like a unique index in a
unique index when the values are the
same one of them is going to be excluded
rejected you have a newer you try to
insert any size now sorry I already have
decided in database so here it's the
same thing but the the rules about when
do you decide to exclude the data are
more complex than just in equality there
is this strength sign here that
everybody knows you need to read equal
and this order strange sign here that
not everybody knows that you just read
it overlaps okay that you need to learn
that once after that you know it but if
you don't know that yet that is
overlapping okay questions so far now
okay the normalization is the is what
you do when you have done a thorough job
at normalizing your schema and then you
reach some difficulties in prediction
usually around performance but maybe
around the size of the data on disk or
maybe a about something else and you
want to fix them okay so the
normalization is an optimization
technique that you implement at the
schema level the design and the design
you go and you only optimize after it's
not working good enough so let's remind
us the rules of optimization okay so the
first rule is don't do it okay and the
second rule is for experts only so or do
you know if you're an expert or not I
like this definition of being an expert
it means that you have done all the
possible mistakes so when I'm telling
you I'm an expert in PostgreSQL don't
ask me how many mistakes I made before
many of them over the years maybe not
all of them but I tried hard so
optimization you don't do it and if
you're an expert you really good at it
you've been doing that a lot in the past
maybe don't do it yet okay maybe you
don't need to do it actually the the
really important thing here is that any
optimization is going to implement the
trade-off so if everything was easy you
would
do it so make maybe not doing it is
going to make your life easy so that's
the best way and so each time you try to
optimize something you're making your
life art so is it you know is it worth
it do you need do you have to do it so
how do you or do we know if we have to
do it or not that's the classic quote
from Kluth right everybody I've read
well only this part usually premature
optimization is the root of all evil but
I would have contacts it doesn't mean
what it means actually so maybe we
should read it in full so programmers
waste enormous amounts of time thinking
about or worrying about the speed of
non-critical parts of their programs and
these attempts at efficiency actual
efficiency sorry actually have a strong
negative impact when the beginning and
maintenance are considered so that's
about code but it's exactly the same
thing with your database schema if you
do some trade-offs without thinking
about them you will have duplicates in
prediction and you don't know why you
will have an end date that is before the
start date and you don't know why you
will have many problems with your data
in prediction and you don't know why so
please don't do it we should forget
about small efficiencies say about 90s
that's the trick
97% of the time premature optimization
is the root of all evil
we should not pass up our opportunities
in that free tackle 3% so how do you
know it's the critical three persons
it's because use you've been wrong
before and you know it's going to be
there so if it was not never used in
prediction before you never had a
problem before with it it's not in the
critical 3% so be sure to make it
normalized but when you know you have a
problem then it's in the 3% if you're
not an expert yet it will burn in
production and you will have to fix it
and after you have fixed it in
production you're you know one stage up
in the expertise scale because you've
done it wrong once so now you're getting
to be an expert too soon so do you know
is the 3% you know because you've done
it before and if you never done it
before just don't do it yet
and so let's see some optimization
techniques around the schema modeling in
PostgreSQL the classic optimization
technique is caching so basically the
cache is the trade-off in between CPU
and memory so when always been there
either or you recompute the value or you
have it already in memory so you read it
from memory done you have the value
already if you follow the normalization
rules that we saw before you will never
have duplicate information anywhere in
your database which means that maybe you
have to recompute many things over the
over time so let's see about how to
cache data and as soon as you cache data
you know that you need to implement
cache invalidation right you know the
stream the two most difficult things in
a computing science naming cache
invalidation and off by ones yes so
cache even addition is on the list so
how do you do that in PostgreSQL here is
an example
that's from formula one data set that is
available as open data it's all the
races from the woolie story of Formula
One you can easily have that in your
database to play around with it's an OK
schema to work with if you do that and
find it you will see that the schema is
very not normalized at all so it would
be a very good exercise if you want to
train to pick the schema and do the work
of normalizing it I didn't for this talk
so it's the schema that has been that is
found and so this query is as you see
grouping by the grouping sets you know
grouping sets who knows about grouping
set the other guys you don't know sequel
please you know other training or
something or look you know look the
documentation because then developers go
to me and say yes SiC well it's not
powerful enough to do anything I have to
do really so I need to resort to Python
or maybe Java or C or whatever and if
you say that and you don't know grouping
sets you
you don't missing big so sequel is
really nice so basically we're going to
have the the top drivers per Formula One
season and what many of them I don't
know that we are gonna going to select
on leaders who have more than this
number of points okay it's arbitrary I
did that because when I did that for
another presentation then the reason set
would fit on my side oh why not
but maybe you have business rules that
are more important than that so that's a
query that you can run and see that
trick here it's you can actually do that
in P sequel it's not just for the slide
so you can have a dot SQL file and then
you can interactively change the season
and run the query again and it will pick
the new one so you can actually use
variables in piece equal and then in
your sequel scripts okay that's very
easy to do so if you didn't know that
maybe you have a look at it but let's
say that query is on the dashboard when
the guys are logging in so each time
someone logs in on on their nice
dashboard for a Formula One races there
you have a nice updated value for the
current season maybe or something like
that so you are recomputing this thing
for every login maybe you don't want to
do that so maybe you want to cache the
information so you cash it by creating a
view so I do that in two steps some
people do it in one step I prefer it
that way so what I do is I create a view
and then I create a motorized view on
top of it because then the definition of
the material is one is select star from
the view that's easy but and then you
can still use the view and you can
compare it easily so here is beneficial
to use the view rather than the
materials view or the other round well I
can easily compare because I have two
two of them and I can use them who knows
about let's draw in lateral yeah okay
the other guy is please you know try to
learn about sequel he's very important
this thing is very useful when you need
it when you don't know it exists you
like I need to write some more code and
when you know it exists that's maybe
2,000 lines of Python code here say so
that maybe that's a trade off you are
happy
as soon as you know it works and I sorry
I don't have time to explain it now
but anyway so now we have a materialized
view and we can use it we can even index
it so it's very fast now the dashboard
displaying the dashboard now is very
fast every user is happy but sometimes
there is a new race and you need to
update the result so because the cache
is invalid as soon as there is a new
race what do you do that well it's a
single command line you refresh the
motorized view and that's it so
implementing cash-in PostgreSQL is
really easy the only part we were
missing is a integration into the app so
in the application you would use the new
thing rather than the old one but it's
easy enough to integrate right you need
just to think about it other things we
can do to denormalize the schema some
people want to have audit trails which
means that you want to have the history
of all the data that ever went to your
database even if when the schema changes
because there is no application where
the schema doesn't change change is part
of the world right the only things that
don't change are dead so if your
application never have any schema update
it means that basically it's dead which
I'm sorry some some application has get
retired so it's okay but maybe it's not
your intention so if you have you will
always have new business cases new ways
of doing things new products to give you
users things so it's alive so the schema
will change which means that when the
schema changes maybe the old history is
not compatible with the new schema which
means that you need to denormalize to be
able to handle the history of the schema
there is more than one way to do it one
way that I like is abusing JSON into
being an archive thing so because the
data is Jason you can put any kind of
schema into it it doesn't care because
Jason is kimura's that's why the
information is repeated everywhere on
the sheet on every JSON and three-year
will have the same set of keys and
different set of values so it's really
expensive on the storage it's a are
to search for etc but some people are
happy with MongoDB anyway I don't
understand why but you can you can do it
it's the same kind of approach it's a
it's a scheme RS so you have zero
guarantee but it also means that
whatever happened in the past in your
history let's say you didn't implement
your new check constraint for start date
and end date and no you did and some of
the history now is not compatible with
your schema but Jason doesn't care if we
just accept that fine because it doesn't
know about what's in the Jason field
anyway so I found it useful to do that
more than once so maybe you want to do
it too another trick is validity periods
that you can implement with that Ramses
so that's for example rates for
exchanging money and the rights you know
are constantly changing but if you're
doing any finance or accounting you need
to have the rate at a given date and
what you do is that you're going to
accept different values of a rate for a
single currency but with non-overlapping
valid et which means that then you sort
the data like this like what how much
was the euro at this date so this
operator looks strange when you don't
know how to read it so I'm going to tell
you and then it doesn't look strange
anymore so that contains so the value DT
period contains this date by the way
using the data type name here just
before a literal string it's called a
decorated literal in PostgreSQL so you
can use that that way the other way to
do it is : : date and that is a cast so
it gets the same result but it's a
little different so date and the thing
is because we said that we have this
very strong warranty then we know that
we will have only one record because
given a single date there is no way that
we have more than one because we said we
refuse to have overlapping countries so
for example date we have the strong
guarantee that there will only be one
value in our database right so that no
you can use that in your application and
you can even use that as a join
condition you can join in between the
rates table and maybe
the history of people who did buy or
history of your invoicing at straw and
you can match the invoice with the rate
at the date of the invoice so you can
join on this ok that's pretty nice to
have so the normalization air pours in
PostgreSQL a lot of them are data types
composite arrays Jason
so Jason in PostgreSQL is spelled a
little strange it's spelled with B at
the end don't you know don't bother but
just remember to make it that's it
domains and other tricks are like H
store add 3 int array H ll if you don't
know about them there was a talk this
morning from a Craig who went through
most of them so if you if you've been
there you know about them if you don't
there is material on the Internet to a
few weight know that you know the name
you can actually find it so it's easy
another trick to determine eyes your
data is partitioning you need to be
really careful when you do partitioning
because especially before PostgreSQL
relevant when you do partitioning the
trade-off is that you lose indexing you
lose primary keys you lose conflict on
link and you use you cannot update keys
anymore so that was before now you can
do a review almost everything the the
only trick is with the foreign keys it
only works one way but I'm told that
maybe it will work both way in the next
release yes two of them because you are
actually implementing the future thank
you
sorry how does that so partitioning you
used to be a very important trade of to
make in the schema design another is
it's a less and less so because as soon
as we have the wool support for
everything you need to implement normal
normalized schema then it's not so much
a trade off anymore but to this day I
still think of partitioning as a trade
off in the in the ability to implement a
proper schema on top of the data long
story short
try not to implement it and until you
need it right except if you know you're
in the 3% of cases where if you don't
implement it you will be in trouble in
production but all the new all do you
know that right so maybe you need it
maybe you don't know you need it yet if
you don't know you need it don't do it
and if you need to do it PostgreSQL is
very good at it so you can do it some
people also want to compare with not
only sequel solutions and my point is
that PostgreSQL is sequel and also a
parts of the not only sequel movement as
i'm going to show now so it's actually
yes well right they have no sequel we
have SQL it's way better the first thing
is you can go schema res with the Jason
B as we said before so that I know did
the set of you know Magic the Gathering
the card game some of you might have
been playing that before so you can have
all of them as because it's the data set
is available as JSON so I just load it
as it was because usually what you do is
you load the data set as it is and then
you transform it and normalize it in
sequel because the best way to unroll
the data and transform it into a new
representation is the sequel query
language you might have heard about it
sequel is really good at that so first
you load the data and then you process
it so some people implement ETL extract
transform load I usually do alt extract
load and then transform because once in
the eights in PostgreSQL it's way easier
to handle so anyway here you see the
contain operator that we saw before
it's
but no it's working with Jason because
PostgreSQL is an object-oriented R DBMS
which means that the way I see it you
can have things like that this operator
knows how to work with many different
data types like you would do in C++ or
Java or things and you can actually
write pretty simple sequel and that is
fully optimized in this case for Jason
okay it looks like a normal sequel query
and it actually implements very smart
things and ways to indulge Jason no
sequel system also usually are good at
implementing durability trade-offs and
in PostgreSQL you can set synchronous
commit different values okay
what people don't realize often is that
it's the dynamic synchronous commit is
per transaction setting so you can have
in the same PostgreSQL system in
prediction at runtime some workload that
is critical and we multiply which means
we only tell the user it's ok if we know
it's been applied to a standby a replica
and you can have other transactions that
you don't care so much about maybe it's
the web session handle and you store it
in the database because it's the start
of the project you don't care about the
infrastructure yet etc and then if you
lose the database of course you lose the
web sessions who cares right so it's off
you can even do that dynamically in your
application you can have a ear it's a
trigger
where is really trigger is written here
it's a trigger that say if the user is
spending so much money which is set in a
GAC