okay thank you for being here for last
talk so this last talk would be about
decoding meteor m2 so what I would like
to emphasize is assume that most people
in this room don't care at all about
meter and to the topic here I would like
to address is to use meter and to as a
reason for addressing all these
fascinating topics I should emphasize
I'm trying to the physicist I never been
taught about any of these things here so
I discovered everything by myself
I found it very fascinating to be
discovering all these super processing
techniques that you find in the various
documentation about digital
communication I want to show you how
getting from the raw data QPSK
overweight or JPEG image as you can see
here will be addressed in this talk so
barton did not care to give you a talk
with two semester of signal processing
in 20 minutes I do so also I should
emphasize if you just want to get the
image you can go out of room because
this metal decoder is doing a much
better job at what I'm going to show you
this is working very well I want to go
step by step into what is going here so
really for me the topic is understanding
all these things not using a readily
available software so that's the topic
of talk so I'm lucky enough to be going
every twice every week twice every year
in Arctic regions for glacier monitoring
and so I'm lucky enough to be following
all these polar orbiting satellites so
low Earth poor orbiting weather
satellites including amongst the various
little satellites the one from version
material so why are Arctic regions most
favorable for this night of monitoring
when you have a solar synchronous
satellites there will be in the polar
orbit 98 degree so 90 degree would be
right over North Pole and one of these
polar orbiting satellites here I've
plotted the trajectory over one day you
see that when you're in Western Europe
here it's been on swing friends the the
green circle is the place you would be
if you wanted to see the sunlight or
horizon this is at an altitude of
elevation of 15 degree this is
at elevation of 60 degree below which I
don't even bother to take my antenna out
in France you will get at most one pass
every day of one of these / orbiting
satellites while when you go to an
Arctic region where you've got all these
passes so it's fascinating because when
you're learning to decode a new
satellite here you have like 10 10 12
passes per day while here you have one
at best so I'm investigating metal rim 2
in this context and also using the
little RTL SDR receivers because of
course when you go where you're not
supposed to take a big bag with full of
a hardware it's not related to your
research so here I can just put one of
these little receivers at the bottom of
my backpack just find any two wires to
make a dipole until I want to arrive
there and you'll have your setter for
receiving metal m2 so I'm sure many of
you here in the room have already
listened to new AAA so the noise
satellites are a dying breed because no
AAA is no longer renewing their
constellation of analog satellites they
started in the 70s now they are at
mid-may no a 19 a finger to switch will
go up to 21 and then we'll stop NOAA so
now we have to think about the future
and the future is digital communication
so digital communication is what is
provided by CC STS so because the last
people could not say it is consultative
committee for space data systems and
this is basically a body trying to
standardize this communication so that's
a bit of a layout of what I want to talk
so when Bastion was showing you I have
my JPEG picture then I have tcp/ip when
I have TCP will have IP you've got all
your og layers and of course when you
want to decode the JPEG image on Firefox
well you've got all these libraries for
you and for me the exploration here was
I collect this QPSK data at the output
of new radio either running the RTL is
your data C stream and then how do you
go from this QPSK all the way to the
JPEG image so for me it's a little bit
like if you were trying to listen to a
JPEG image being transmitted in HTML
with just no zero scope connected to
your internet cables and for me it's an
adventure to try to get the layers one
after vehicle so of course it's so you
claim to be going in detail I would like
to show you the outline
slides will be available on the website
and I hope it will make you curious
about getting into all this story now
you might be wondering people have been
working happily with NOAA so why even
bother with such a complex networking so
this is a talk I saw when I was at
Huntsville at Marshall Space Center from
Dave Israel at the White Sea conference
where he was showing you've got the
International Space Station the
International Space Station is flying at
400 kilometer altitude and is visible if
you remember my little circles on the
radius of 1500 kilometers so this means
you would need to put one station every
1,500 kilometres along the path so this
is what the Americans did for Gemini and
Mercury
they had one ship or one station every
1500 kilometers but there's no problem
because they only did one or two orbit
so you just needed to put a few stations
along the orbit ISS is rotating of
course you cannot put one station every
1500 meter all over the earth so what is
happening now is ISS is completely
automated the astronauts are running the
experiments but everything on the ISS is
automated from ground stations and the
ISS is only visible from a radius of
1500 kilometers realice says he's not
directly talking to the earth but he's
talking through the tracking and data
relay system the TDRs satellites the
geostationary satellites so I assess 400
kilometers rotating quite quickly talk
to TDRs TDRs are talking with each other
and TDRs is sending ceylon back to earth
same is true for Hubble Hubble Space
Telescope is very expensive you don't
want to just run it as it is flying over
your head
you want to continuously monitor Hubble
Space Telescope measurements and of
course you don't think that the US Air
Force cares much about the science in
Hubble Space Telescope but once you
figure out that Hubble it's just a spy
satellite upside down you might figure
out why you had TDRs here in the space
so of course here you have multiple
satellites with multiple multiple
experiments so you need a way of PACA
tiling your data you need to say it's
satellite number X which is sending data
from instrument number Y and how you do
this well that's where you go from QPSK
which would be your Ethernet cable all
the way to the JPEG image through all
the layers of all the layer ok let's try
to have fun with your layers
so first of all we need to predict where
Metro is flying I still use a track
despite the y2k bug which is a silly
patch and is not inserted you can use wh
three to IMG in the paper I explained to
you how you can cheat WX to IMG which is
no longer maintained into a thinking
that one of the neue satellites is
actually maturing to and so that you can
meter onto is actually one of the NOAA
satellites so you can use a WX to energy
and if you have internet access you can
use the heavens above website again the
beautiful thing about being it
Spitsbergen arctic region 79 degree
north is you've got all these passes at
high elevations which of course you
don't get in the western in a Western
European country lower latitude country
you'll get one two passes is best okay
so we know when no major m2 is flying so
we take our rtl-sdr rtl-sdr we collect
the data this is all stolen from the
earth spy website for receiving measure
I'm too rational resampler you have your
clocking so you cost us loop which locks
on the frequency offset between the
carrier and locals later beach recovery
and so that data clock recovery and at
the end you got your soft soft bits so
already I needed to learn the first
world when I was doing this I didn't
know what the soft so soft bait is IQ
coefficients where you're in one and
zero are not yet saturated but are still
represented here by an 8-bit value and
you still need to identify whoever it is
most probably a one or a zero so I
didn't know what soft pit meant so the
first question is are my data even worth
investigating so this is a spectrum
unlike GPS now we have strong signals so
you see there is something happening
here is it the QPSK signal well if we
expand what Paul Bob and totals about
GPS where BPSK is collapsed vo by
squaring the signal well of course if
you take the nth power of an NP SK
signal you collapse again the the
spectrum spreading YouTube
PSK modulation so here we take our raw
signal well there is something but we
don't know if it's the right modulation
we square it it is not BPSK so we
haven't colored fulfill the spectrum we
raised to the fourth power
it
QPSK because your spectrum spreading has
collapsed in the carrier so we can get a
signal that are worth investigating
further it seems to be QPSK modulation
so once we've done this if we know it's
a packet I'll System packetized system
means something will be repeated if you
look at the documentation you will find
that all cccc SDS compliant
communication start with a header well
we say if you have packets you need to
know where the packet starts and the
packet start header is 1a c FF c 1d try
to remember this because i will keep on
repeating this sentence ultra all over
every time so at first i don't know what
this packet is i just want to know
whether there is some repeated header in
the signal so as shown if a previous
offer speaker you just auto create the
signal if there is some redundancy this
redundancy will show so by Auto
correlating my signal well indeed I see
a peak at 16 kilobyte I see a signal at
32 kilobytes so there is some redundancy
every 16 thousand samples I have some
repetition so it's definitely worth
working further on this data so the
first thing that got me stuck because
again I'm physicists I haven't been
taught about single digital
communication was consolation
convolutional encoding so that's the
topic of Martin's focus morning I'm just
going a slightly bit further into it
because I want to show you how its
decoded I don't want to get to the
encoding part the encoding actually is
very simple because they show you on
various documentation as an XOR so as
well as shown by Martin this morning you
just take your data stream and take
convolution convolution so you try to
mix all these data to create as much
randomness as you can select is one of
these bits is corrupted you have a lot
of chance because you've spread the
information of a long duration to
recover this information so here it's a
seven bit long shift register you have
tabs from which you XOR and you get
twice as many bits on the output as you
had on the input so this your shift here
will clock up down up down and sometimes
take the output with one polynomial and
on the other so if you do this you can
also express this
the matrix where time is evolving over
the x-axis and you join first
coefficient second coefficient first so
first coefficients or first polynomial
first coefficient of second polynomial
second coefficients of first ramonja
and so on so you have your polynomial
which are interleaved and you judge
shift time so that's another way of
implementing your Viterbi you're
convolution encoding and the last way of
saying it is you can do this as a as a
state machine so you take the various
states of your polynomial here you input
a new bit into your system and by
inputting a new bit in your system your
shift register changes so if you had 0
and you inject a 0 you stay at 0 and
your output you run the XOR on this all
the 0 you get an out 0 output if you
inject one well your 0 goes to the last
0 drops the 1 comes here and you run
this for the XOR you get 1 1 so you can
make this as a state machine
so once you've discovered you have a
segment expression you can write this as
the evolution of between the various
states so previously I had given names
ABCD to my various states and then you
can draw the state machine so a stays in
a a goes to B if you have a 1 then so
these are the input bits so if a is 0 0
it stays at a
hey when it is feather zero will output
zero zero a when it is fed a 0 where a
when it is feather 1 will output 1 1 and
so on so you can draw your state machine
so encoding is very efficient very easy
it's just X or now the reason I wanted
to show you this is if you take the same
description that we had here but now you
take it to decode but 30 second
description of the Viterbi decoding
algorithm in 30 seconds what you have
here is let's imagine I have received
this bit stream so this is what I have
read so I split what I have and so on
what you see here I start with 0 0 ok I
get 0 0 that is most probably state a
with a 0 output 0 0 state a 0 0 0 0
state a 0 0 so these free zeros are just
a looping in to be 0 0 now we get 1 1 1
1 is a feasible output of state a that
gets us into state B so we're going to
state B when you're in state B we get 1
1 but that's not possible we cannot get
a 1 1 out of state D we can get 1 0 0 1
well the moment we don't know what the
best option so let's follow the two
possible paths we know it's wrong but
let's follow the two possible paths
after that we got 0 1 so we could be
here C but she cannot have 0 1 you can
the only one 1 or 0 0 so C would create
two errors that's a wrong path so we cut
it out and Viterbi tells you let's not
follow this one now we go into this path
here because 0 1 is a valid output of D
that would be considered as a 0 and then
you go on and you follow it your part
your path so if I add the output dates
here you have the number in red of
errors two errors means we give up on
this particular branch and we continue
with a branch with only one error and
this unique error con continues with a
consistent path that tells you in the
transmission this bit was erroneous so
you see that by spreading the
information over a long duration where
we had just a burst of 1 bit error
that's the point of convolution encoding
is just a noise on one date and this
unique bit has been recovered by the
Turbie decoding and then indeed we
recover 1 a which is the first bit the
first byte of our
synchronization words so okay we've
understood be decoding so now well we
can go for so yeah sorry
this is what I so if you don't want to
go into all the math by yourself you
have lip back with you and by K thank
you and lead pack will do the job for
you here I put for you a very simplified
chart of a friendly lip fact for Viterbi
decoding just don't do the same mistake
as I did leap fake will not take as
input 0 or 1 you need to feed it 0 or
255 it's working a bite so I struggle
for like a couple of weeks why is
libtech not they put decoding just
because I was giving in 0 & 1
if it's 0 and 255 and again the word
encoded-word here will be decoded as 1a
c FF c 1z so we know that the
encoded-word of btob you can use the
effect to encode or to decode so this is
encoded word and this is the decoded
world this is how you do it with recheck
okay so we've got r effect we can check
that indeed we can decode our word so if
we have the sequence so this is an
example that was given to me by by the
author of gr satellite by daniel Estevez
I hope I pronounce his name correctly
it's you've got the fake decoder here as
was shown by by marching this morning
and if I feed my gr decoder here with
encoded-word indeed I can get the output
which is 1a c FF c 1 d except sometimes
I get wrong messages because you see
here that my input stream is repeating
and if I repeat my input stream the
hypothesis of picker B is to start with
a shift register that is full of 0 and
that is not correct because here after
the first coding I don't have a shift
register full of 0 so then I have one
wrong one wrong sequence and then I go
back to 1 HDFS
C 1 D which is the correct sequence so
you can play with this and it's an
opportunity to see how the hello world
of of CCS yes is decoded by by by the
fake decoder in the radio what is the
sequence well as we did for GPS now I
should be able to correlate my
sifts signal with a synchronization word
after encoding by Viterbi and miserably
failed you see absolutely no correlation
peak I cannot find in my QPSK signal the
the set of bits of my encoding words why
is that
well I associated the usual
constellation to my QPSK QPSK is four
phases so I have 90 180 270 360 degrees
and 270 degrees and I associated the
word symbol a set of bits to each one of
these symbols of his states but why
would I do that why would I not
associate a different symbol to a
different bit of this set of bits pair
of bits to each symbol so this is
actually what you figure out when you
read the source code of material decoder
you figure out that metal decoder starts
by creating rotated copies all the
possible rotated copies which comes back
to say let's take the standard
distribution of big pairs of QPSK and
let's imagine like lighting in BPSK you
can you can have 0 or PI or PI or zero
but in BPSK it doesn't care because you
just go to a 0 1 or 1 0 but you will
still correlate only you have an anti
correlation sort of correlation but so
to PSK you've got all these Possible's
she's position so you can swap the real
part you can swap the imaginary part or
you can swap these parts here and so if
you look into metal decoder you indeed
find that well I will not get with you
but you swap all the possible big pairs
so 1 1 becomes 0 1 1 1 can become 0 0 1
one can become 1 0 so you make all the
possible combinations and because you
don't care about anti-correlation these
8 possible bit swaps actually become
four possible combinations because you
have four ways of combining all these
bits if you think that 1 1 and 0 0 are
the same so having done that now you can
see here all the possible correlations
and the only one that gives you
correlation I don't know if you can see
this from the room but you've got no
correlation P for all these cases but
here you've got these correlation Peaks
every 16,000 bits so this means this is
the right assignment or
of each symbol into the repair so now I
found how to convert my QPSK signal into
the encoded Viterbi keyboard key word
and by encoded Viterbi synchronization
world I can start decoding my-my-my
sentences so I will skip reed-solomon
because actually rich Solomon is a block
encoder so Viterbi is to eliminate
random bits that have flipped or IVA
communication while Reed Solomon or what
well the reason I'm skipping it is
because I investigated quite more deeply
BCH which is the encoder block encoder
in RDS that was investigated heavily by
by bastion so when I worked on BCH I've
put a reference here you can look at how
BCH is working and Reed Solomon is just
an extension of this the only reason I'm
mentioning this is you've got your data
here if you don't want block correction
which is someone is emitting and you've
got whole blocks of data that have been
corrupted well you can get rid of Reed
Solomon if you want to use it just be
aware because I again you want to spread
information over time because you want
to recover as much time as for as much
information as possible you will have
interleaved Reed Solomon meaning you
have for intra live Reed Solomon you
have data 1 theta 2 theta 3 theta 4
theta 1 theta 2 theta 3 theta 4 you need
to be interleave the render reed-solomon
they code recovery and then re
interleave your data so it's just I will
skip this because well because only I
don't have time to get the details and
again I give you the example how to run
how to run the reed-solomon decoder in
in gr fake sorry in the lip fake so if
you want to give it a try by yourself
here is my data set I voluntarily
corrupt 4 bytes I voluntarily corrupt
bytes in the data set so in the payload
or in the correction code and if I run
this in my reed-solomon decoder
indeed I detect or I leave lipstick
detects for corrupted bytes and the
score for corrupted bytes are these
values which which can be recovered so
Long's only you decock discover which
files are corrupted but you can find the
properly initial values of these bytes
so just demonstration again you have to
run it by yourself I can talk as much as
I want
if you don't run it by yourself you
don't learn so try try it by yourself
good so we claim to have found out how
to work with Viterbi decoder we claim to
have worked understood how reed-solomon
is working so are the bits that we get
out of the Viterbi decoder valid but I
can claim now I've done the job I can go
away well we want a picture we don't
want a random set of bits so the first
thing we can do when we look at the data
sheet is or V documentation of a metre
and 2 transmission whose website I'll
give you the references where you can
find documentation the last slide you
see that very celebratory data and this
telemetry data are encoded in a sentence
to recognize so that you know where your
telemetry data are located so you've got
this magic sentence 224 168 163 146 bla
bla bla 191 so this magic sentence tells
you I am sending a telemetry frame so
what do we do well we take all our
decoded bits and we cross correlate our
decoded bits with this sequence and this
is one of these all inspiring moments
where it works you find this sentence in
all your bits and if you decode the the
following bytes hours minutes seconds
you find that that information was
collected at 11 o clock 48 minutes 33
seconds which is indeed the output of
the Metro decoder provided as a
reference so you see here that we have
indeed properly decoded the Viterbi and
reed-solomon or actually in this part
our skip read Solomon but we have
understood Viterbi because we can find
the telemetry sentence and we can decode
proper information now I found the
telemetry but still a bit far from from
pictures but the next part the end now
is easy because I don't get the details
I it took me a couple of months this
work has been started little more than a
year ago but once you've got the bits
it's a matter of basically finding what
the bytes are and checking whether they
follow of a standard so I will not give
the details but indeed you see that
you've got this header which is always
the same that tells you well we're in a
good job there's an ID when they tell
you how to counter well indeed these
free bytes you see
they're increasing one by one so we're
on the right path and then they sell
tell you here is a header so this is an
address of the first payload because the
difficulty is that you've got the data
packet and then you've got the payload
packet and there is no reason for the
data packet to be synchronized on
tailored packets so you might have
payload lying over multiple data packets
so this is the address at which the
first payload package is starting and so
on and so on so I will not be in the
detail but that's just a matter of
following the protocol so once you get
the bite it's really easy and finally
you are supposed on the payload to get
JPEG images and this is where I gave up
I said okay I'm not gonna re encode the
whole Huffman encoder and everything so
this is where I just took this part of
the decoder vomitorium to decoder that
was ported from Pascal to C++ and I just
use ver decoder JPEG is standard
bachelor level computer science signal
processing training I didn't want to
write all of it again maybe for the next
training session but yeah I wanted to
get some images so I went so to conclude
the talk that's what I get at first so
you are told in the standards again it's
all the detail of the paper of it I
uploaded on the post and website you are
told that your frames your JPEG images
are eight by a bit frames this 8 by a
bit thumbnails repeat 14 times and each
one of these 14 times
8 bit sequences repeats 14 times along
one teacher line and then you jump to
the next instrument because our free
wavelengths which they call three
instruments you get one line of the next
instrument a bit wide 1,500 bit long and
then you go to the next instrument and
so on so here you see that I had some
missing frames so some missing
thumbnails that I had to introduce so
what I did here is because you've got a
counter you know that when you have
missing frames here I just very stupidly
did if you are missing a frame copy of a
previous frame and this way I could miss
feel the missing
thumbnails and here you start seeing
some pattern and here you've got one
parameter in JPEG which is called the
coefficient quality coefficient which
gives you the relation between the
quantization and the quantization matter
and here is no quality so you see that
the sharp pictures here don't have the
same tone as as a flatter area of a
picture but you start seeing here the
Alps and finally by applying the quality
coefficient you get an image that is a
bit more smooth and that compares I
think quite favorably to the reference
picture that was decoded using the
satellite of a mineral decoder that you
can find on the Internet
so here you see each tria you have
patton lake somewhere over here I think
you've got Vanessa over here so if you
take the metro decoder you get an image
that is quite consistent with what we
got by step-by-step decoding so that was
of course in 25 27 minutes a very fast
highlight of the main steps go for the
paper the paper is actually about 50
pages long at the moment and an
increasing but I'm trying to put
everything for IQ coefficients all the
weights for JPEG image CC SDS is a
protocol for space communication you
might not care about weather satellites
but what Daniel is today is showing on
his blog and as mentioned by my poll is
this is a standard for most satellite
communication and that's going to be the
future because no way is going to stop
the analog satellites so I think if you
want if you're interested in solid
decoding this is really worth
investigating
Daniel Estevez is just addressing all
the satellites avatar satellites up
there
Lucas Tesla is a Brazilian guy who's
working on going satellites
geosynchronous and his website was very
inspiring
despite at some point splitting the path
of decoder his beginning was very
insightful he helped me a lot by email
to guys helped me a lot this is a
website that was hosting all the files
about meteor m2 somehow in between in
the middle of this investigation it
disappeared I don't know where the site
is hopefully we've got a web archive I
don't know where this website is
disappeared but this is a fundamental
repository of all the data some of which
cannot be found anywhere else and
finally there is one article which is
not well not very technical but it tells
you that it could be done and we bet I
conclude my talk and I thank you for
attention
[Applause]
next one so just as a quick conclusion
martin introduced during his
introductory talk that we are organizing
the european new radio days so my
frustration is that here we have two
days off first then we have one day full
of talks we never have time to discuss
with each other everyone's running to
our sessions and i wanted to have an
opportunity to meet with people and sit
together so the way I organized this is
one day or we organized this is one day
of oral presentation one day of
tutorials everything is open at the
moment we are proposing some tutorial
please feel free to propose new
tutorials
Robin Gates is coming from analog
devices to demonstrate the Pluto so he
told me I hope and I trust him it is
located in France in business or but
also is a tiny remote City which means
that hotels are readily available here
in the east of France it's two and a
half hour train trip from Paris it's a
few hours from cultural toughing it's a
couple of hours from college through the
cocoa and cocoa food contribution is
March 21st registration is free but
please register because I need to
organize I need to know how many people
are coming so registration registration
deadline is May 1st the website is over
here and hopefully the evening dinner
will be a barbecue so everyone can talk
to each other and and have more time to
discuss so I will not waste our time
with more advertisements but please come
you