your talk starts at 30 he's gonna be
talking about Thanks so hi my name is
Romain
I'm a former Internet source and I'm
going to talk what what have they done
oh my god okay in your pocket I also
talk as long as possible because there's
no the mic is only for the recorder let
me pick okay so I was saying I'm a
formal sauced intern and I'm going to
talk about a project I worked on during
my time now it's an open source project
called gemiini and it basically tries to
deduplicate large amounts of code so
before talking about how gemiini works
and the results I got while applying it
I'm just going to go over some elements
of deduplication so first off what are
called clones so called clones at a high
level or snippets that show little to no
differences so a natural language
usually we can basically say where the
two sentences or more or similar just by
looking at some tactical features so
here I highlighted for example exactly
similar words and even if we try to make
this form of a bit harder so for
instance by using synonyms like this
today in the NLP so natural language
processing we're able to vectorize
tokens in spaces which will yield
similar vectors for words that have
similar meaning so however in for trying
to find similarities between code this
is a much harder problem because you
usually have some tactical as well as
structure
language that effectively semantics so
what happens when you compile a code
every different snippets so lots been a
extensive research done in this field
which have led to a taxonomy of
different kinds of clones so we usually
use four types so the first is basically
copy-paste clones if you remove all
things that are not code any snippets of
Winston's comments white spaces stuff
like that
the second type is structurally similar
code so imagine two snippets with
different identifiers you type free as a
combination of both with minor changes
like additions insertions deletions
stuff like that and finally you type
four which is the most hard to detect is
semantically semantical clones so just
snippets that compute these same
calculations and output the same result
but can do it in different ways so as an
example here are two function that do
exactly the same thing but do it in
completely different ways with different
identifiers and well just looking at the
syntax one will not be able to judge
whether these is lipids are the same or
not at least not easily so I'm going to
talk about the baseline approach before
talking about Germany so this is a
review paper which was released in 2017
which tried to duplicate about 480
million files using a free level
granularity skim so the first thing they
did was like I said before we move all
comments all white spaces and just hash
each file computing a file hash and then
trying to zero which hash is all the
same and which are not the second level
was after extracting tokens and creating
bag of features as you can see here they
hashed the strings of tokens which
produces second hash and the third level
was using all these extracted tokens
they used the troll coughs also were CC
which is able to basically tell so you
latter two snippets are similar
if Felicia about 80% similar clones so
the results they found on applying this
on about 400 million snippets of files
of code was lat
basically if you look at a file on
github you have about an 80% chance
that's a similar file exists somewhere
on github which were brilliant passive
results so however from what I just
explained to you before I think you can
deduce from this Bethenny's methods that
they can't actually do much small and
detect type 1 and type 2 clones
possibly type 2 it might be a problem if
too many tokens are altered and type 3
and for all probably out of which this
is where I add sourced we developed a
project called gemiini so I'm first
going to outline the main steps we do
and applying this this algorithm and
then I'll get more into exactly what we
do and how we do it and why it works so
Germany has four steps the first steps
is that out of the dataset we are going
to extract a certain amount of features
which are going to be syntactical as
well as structural I'll get more into
depth into what kind of features we use
and why we use them the next step is
creating a pairwise humidity graph
between our snippets so basically in
this graph each node is going to
represent a file and two nodes will be
connected if they are similar enough
again I'll get more into depth into what
this means
so if third step is out of this huge
graph the most interesting parts of this
graph are actually parts of the graph or
groups of uf which consists of files
which are all connected one to each
other either directly or indirectly
through hops so well this is in graph
theory this is called connected
components and we extract this from the
graph of similarity that we've created
the final step in Germany is on each of
these connected components we apply
community detection in order to find the
final clone communities so I'll go a bit
more in depth on why we do that later
so let's first go on the first step so
extracting SiC tax and tactical and
structural features so as you can
imagine we can't actually extract such
structural features just from plaintext
code to do that we have to go to a lower
representation of code so namely
abstract syntax twist so for those of
you who don't know this data structure
it's used in compilers for syntactic
analysis and it looks roughly like
something like this so this is clearly a
very simplified version of an AST is
probably not even correct but one of the
properties let each of these nodes have
is an internal type so for instance here
you can see identifiers statements
declarations operations and so we're
mostly going to be able to extract
structural features from list data
structure so before describing each of
the features you can imagine that
differing languages are going to have
different kinds of ast s so for those of
you which were here before Vadim talked
a bit about lists we developed at source
top project which is named Babel Fish
which aims at creating a unified the
abstract syntax tree so giving any fire
of any language you would obtain the
same data structure which can then be
used in a unified way so this is pretty
useful because that's why we don't have
to create code for each kind of language
and you can just transform everything
into Universal way STS and work on that
so first I'm going to go over the two
syntactical features that we used so
identify Lysander two also identifiers
so basically variable or function names
and literals are values so for instance
here I hided no I highlighted in lemon
green and the identifier czar in blue I
think it's pretty straightforward so
fully structual we used for kind of
structural features each I'm going to
talk about our graph let's and children
so a graph let in a graph is basically a
given node as well as all its children
so as you can see here we don't actually
for releasing tactical data so we don't
care with that you know this called
death who acts on return we actually
relies purely on the nodes internal type
so we create so here I showed you how we
extract our graph let's sorry children
feature is actually just each node and
the number of children nodes that it has
and once you convert this to a weighted
bag of features it looks something like
this so for instance we have the
identifier and no nodes and no children
nodes which appears free time in this
example so we as I said we used four
kinds of structural features the two
others are basically just how would I
say I can't concatenations of of
different internal types that we obtain
by traversing the ast s in two different
ways one using a depth-first search and
the second one using a random walk I
won't get too much into why we use these
features but we thought that they would
be able to capture long longer-term
structural structural information of
these lipids so we thought that these
features were good however we don't
actually have any metric or any pure
region pure reason other than intuition
that leaves with good features however
as you'll see a bit later we actually is
actually yielded some pretty good
results so to go back now yeah so as you
can imagine extracting these features
from snippets of code is actually yields
a lot of features so in order to reduce
that we used an NLP technique which is
called term frequency inverse document
frequency which basically amounts to
calculate calculating a weight for each
feature and then fresh holding in order
to reduce the amounts of features so
that's it and it basically is able to
reject all where features so features
that only a part appeal and maybe once
or twice for only one file or one
snippet and it also is able to reject
very common features of each other
pío I don't know 10 million times or
something I glad so things that are not
very discriminative so at the end of the
day if we feature extraction revolves
about list so first converting all files
to UA STS then extracting the Vedic bag
of features of each you AST applying
tf-idf in order to reduce the amount of
features as you can see it as a fourth
step so this is actually a step that
allows us to look more into biased
versions of our algorithm we could use
purely Li weighted back the features as
is but if we wanted for instance to look
at more of the structural differences
between code then we would be able to
give more weight to these structural
features and invert here we could do the
same thing for some tactical features so
that was the first step that was the
first step of Germany so the second step
is the hashing step so we're going to
hash the features using an algorithm I'm
going to explain in order to create the
pairwise similarity graph so at this
point you might be wondering well we
could simply choose a given distance
metric then apply it to each file in
order to compute similarities between
files however that doesn't really work
the reason is that well it scales
quadratically with the amount of files
you use so if we're trying to do this at
scale it would basically explode so in
order to introduce the early algorithm
we're going to use I'm going to have to
explain a couple concepts so the first
thing is weighted Jaccard similarity so
giving two sets of features a and B now
weighted Jaccard similarity is basically
just Li intersection of both features /
Li Union so if both a and B were equal
and you can see it would be equal to 1
to 0 so here I displayed it for integer
weighted features but it will also work
for we all value the features so imagine
half the Sun would be the same so we use
lists because it actually has a pretty
interesting property and that is that if
we pick a random permutation over all
set of features
and apply it to a and B Len hash all the
elements that were mutated and select
the smallish the smallest hash so the
min hash let any probability that Lisa's
values will be the same is equal to the
jack out similarity of both lipids
what's interesting with this is that
since it's a random permutation if we
actually pick the second only third only
for fo the nth element then this Stowe
is true so if we take K values creating
what we call a min hash signature and
concatenate them into what we call mean
hash signature matrix then we have the
interesting property that for each
column and each row the value will be
equal will be the same with probability
equal to the Jaccard similarity every
files associated to each column so
formulas what we're going to do is we're
going to cut our matrix into bands of so
B bands of our walls and we're going to
call candidate pair any two files which
only which hold the same value in at
least one band so we're now going to
calculate quickly don't vary the
probability of two snippets to be a
queen I can do that pair so if we call
as the similarity between two snippets
learn the probability that is signature
are the same in one band is just as to
the power all so if we take the opposite
event lattice they are different in one
band and we can calculate less if you do
this for all bands ladies since we have
B bands we just put that to the power of
B and if we take the opposite event that
is the event that use two snippets or a
candidate pair you get this so for those
of you that don't often do math or
haven't done some for a while
this might seem a bit abstract but
basically this function regardless of
our NB has lists shape so what we call
an S curve now if we choose our 1b
appropriately we get actually this kind
of curve which is exactly what we did
want because that this curve means that
if we have a candidate peril and with
high probability they will have a
Jaccard similarity over a certain
threshold
that you can choose beforehand so here
this is an example with if I figure
threshold which might be about of 0.9 t5
for the similarity okay so at the end
everyday list basically allows us to
completely simulate this similarity
graph by simply creating signatures for
each of these snippets lend selecting a
threshold and deducing lis constants R
and B and then on each sub signal sub
signature of each file hashing Li sub
sub signatures and put them into buckets
and then we'll simply any lipids that
land and at least one bucket in common
are going to be our candidate pairs
which theoretically are going to be over
a certain threshold of similarity so the
next step is pretty straightforward it's
the extraction of the connected
components so basically looks something
like this hopefully you can see the
edges but yeah it doesn't yeah that's
not very health really see the edges but
yeah I imagine that these are all
connected components so I haven't talked
too much about let's step the community
detection step so why do we do this um
so you could imagine that all snippets
in one connected components would be
clones however in practice last this
isn't true because if you take three
snippets for example a B and C and
imagine that a and B hashed to a same
bucket and B and C hash to a same bucket
let's take a fresh hold of 0.8 then in
the worst case even no loss a similarity
of 0.8 between a and b and b and c you'd
only have maybe 0.62 for similarity
between a and C and if you increase the
amount of hops you have to do the
similarity is going to drop so this is
why we do the community detection and it
looks a bit something it looks something
like something reckless so you can see
it you kind of put into the same groups
and files that are relatively close
depending on the structure of the edges
so that was it fully Germany algorithm
now I'm going to talk a bit about the
results I got while applying it so I
the public get archived so public get
archived is largest data set of consoles
new world it's maintained by a source
and is basically created from only
weapons and github which have over 50
stars it has the neat property that we
didn't use and my in my case that it
includes all of Lee commit history but
as I said I didn't use that and I only
took the head which stole amounts for
fifty four point five million files so I
was also restricted with files from
which I could extract a unified ast S
which meant that I could actually only
use at the time when I did list files
stemming from five different languages
so Python Java JavaScript Ruby and go I
decided to apply the pipeline on all
five languages at once because I wanted
to see what early algorithm would be
able to detect the structural
differences between different languages
so when I applied this pipeline this is
what I got so for those of you that know
spoke you know what I'm talking about
and unfortunately with lists kinds of
logs usually they hurriedly hide a
certain amount of problems so without
going too much into detail I had faced a
certain amount of challenges or for
example corrupt files pulsing errors
from Babel Fish GPUs not responding for
no reason at all during the tf-idf step
at some point that was basically
infinite garbage collection so my tasks
never finished and yeah I also
encountered some github repositories
made by very clever engineers which were
designed to not be cloneable so we were
able to clone them however giving enough
structure which basically imagine a
folder with ten folders inside of lemon
and each subfolder or have ten more etc
and said evolved so yeah an
exponentially an exponentially
increasing size yeah so these were
actually pretty hard to process and at
the end of the day I was only able
to process 7.8 million files so as you
can see most of them with JavaScript and
Java files and then I oh I still had
good amount of other Python Ruby and go
files and out of all of these I was able
to extract about 6.2 million distinct
features so looking more and truly
features we extracted so much of most of
them were the syntactical features as
you can see so identifies and literals
which amounted for about 75% of lis of
already features I extracted however
when looking at each file individually I
saw that they each had about a thousand
features and most of them were actually
this time structural features so this
was an average made on all of the only
features from files of any given
languages but this was about the same
when looking at files of the specific
languages so next what I did was that I
applied early rehashing with two
different thresholds early 80% which was
also used in the Java as well as the 95
percent threshold so as you as could be
expected along a much bigger amount of
connected components for a 95 percent
threshold but let's actually just
connected components of only one file
and if you look at the ones with have
which have more than one file well
actually more 40 80 percent thresholds
for about 10 percent more and the
connected components are also a bit
larger so on average they had about 1
more files per connected components
looking more into detail into the size
of the connected component size we can
see from this log log graph the size
while most of the connected components
actually had a relatively small amount
of files with that most for the 80%
threshold a thousand maybe a couple
thousand files and one connected
component so one forget I said earlier
was that I applied my pipeline on
languages of on files of all languages
in order to see if they were able
to find if we if they were able to be
separated using our algorithm that was
mostly case apart from one community
which was actually pretty huge which had
I recall about 800,000 files and which
had the files from all five languages so
when I looked a bit more into this I
found that it was because all of these
files were very short and had very
similar syntax so what I did was I
reapplied my pipeline adding some bias
towards these structural features and
this large community actually exploded
into monolingual communities at the end
I mean connected components for them so
looking at each kind of connected
components per language you can see that
pho connected components have over one
fire we have a big difference between
JavaScript and NGO which have much more
files in these kinds of connected
components than for Java will be in
Python so that can be explained with
kind of intuitive explanation for
example Java which is a much more
object-oriented language would probably
have files which are much more distinct
and invert Li and go for example we use
a practice which is called ven doing
it's kind of logical that would be a lot
of the same files that would appear loss
these results yeah so Len I applied the
community detection with free walk track
algorithm so as you can see if looking
purely at Li connected components with
over one file the amount of connected
components was about the same however
when doing the community detection we
can see that la was a huge increase
about 50 percent our V number of
communities detected when going for me
ninety-five percent threshold to 8020
eighty percent okay so now I'm going to
show you a couple examples but before
that you might notice that up until now
I haven't used any metrics which is kind
of odd in a machine learning problem
that's because this is actually an
unsupervised problem and well as you can
imagine I wasn't going to look at each
of these 7.8 million files to kind of
see okay this one is 80% similar
is not like pairwise that would have
been a bit hot so I in order to judge
whether this work was relevant or not I
had to look at communities and connected
components individually which was how I
judged my work so as I was saying before
were a lot of F connected components
which had a lot of go files and one
thing that was interesting was that a
certain amount of disconnected
components actually files which only had
one file name so for instance this is a
connected component with only files
which are called text parser that go so
the white nodes are actually not files
here they are representations of lis
buckets but however so yeah as you can
see Lau or maybe you can't see from afar
but I was actually four communities
except that two of them or miniscule
here and here
but as you can see especially for the
blue community well that was detected
very strongly strongly links between
each file however this doesn't mean that
each of our connected component were
only formed the files with one file name
so looking at this larger connected
component which only has a ruby file you
can see that we detected three
communities and looking more at lis file
names inside less connected components
you can see that all loli do seem to
cluster together it doesn't actually
mean that the community has formed of
only one kind well I've only files
sharing the same file name so this is a
final example I'm going to talk about so
this was actually a pretty interesting
thing because it was one of the larger
connected components I found
and although the files unless actually
stem from free project only 25 files
came from two projects and all of the
arrows came from 4700 7500 files so as
you can see that's a lot of duplication
for only one project and when looking at
the github repository of the Microsoft
Azure as decay you can actually see that
lossless very repetitive kind of
structure
with a lot of files incoming and well as
you can see we were able to detect
lacked and so I could I got this
representation when I created my graph
on goofy so that was it for me I hope
you liked this talk I liked working on
this and I found that it was also very
interesting if you want to look more
into the results you can go on the blog
on the sauce blog I created a blog post
which goes much more in-depth into into
different aspects of lis results I found
on applying less if you want to check
out the code and possibly use it you can
look at lease or the gemiini project and
if you are interested in the PG a
dataset well you can also download it
for free although yeah it's a bit big so
we might want to save about three
terabytes of a storage thanks yeah so
the question was whether this technique
could be used for we factor in cloud or
if it was much more aimed towards
duplication so I think I'm not sure what
you mean by that question I think it
would be able to find codes which are
similar if you only focus on structure
features so in that sense if you applied
it to let's say one project in order to
find all of these structurally similar
files it might be applied to a factoring
I don't really think that it will
necessarily be impacted by my D
roughness of the estimate because if you
give enough weight to the 2d features
and if you apply tf-idf with a
relatively low threshold and you can
keep enough features for I think the
similarity to be one of
in your case so probably be interesting
to see
[Applause]