thank you Roman
[Applause]
well good afternoon everyone and thank
you for sticking around late on the
second day of the conference it's my
pleasure to talk to you about deep
learning in the context of parallel
databases all of the software that's
used in this project that we did is open
source software of some of which is
listed here so in the spirit of FOSDEM
it's definitely something that you can
try at home so I thought I'd start by
giving a very brief introduction to deep
learning perhaps for folks who are less
familiar with this topic although you
may have heard a lot about it in the
context of AI and the popular press so I
kind of favor this Russian doll kind of
description of the AI landscape which
has artificial intelligence machine
learning and deep learning embedded kind
of within that so deep learning is a
kind of machine learning it's inspired
by biology of the brain and it uses a
class of algorithms which are called
which uses a class of algorithms can you
hear me at the top ok no ok I'm going to
shout louder so deep learning is
inspired by biology of the brain it is
uses a class of algorithms called
artificial neural networks and
artificial neural networks kind of came
from this brain biology from
neuroscience but I don't think
neuroscience really drives the
innovation of artificial intelligence
networks today and they've been
certainly growing in size there's
networks with hundreds of millions of
weights right now but I read a couple as
of like a year or two ago the largest
artificial neural networks were roughly
the size of the nervous system of an
insect so although they're large in
computer terms in terms of biology and
other
organisms and systems they're not
actually that big these are some
examples of deep learning algorithms can
you hear me better at the top now yes
sort of okay
these are examples of some deep learning
algorithms for example on the left of
this slide we have a multi-layer
perceptron so this is a classic neural
net which is fully connected and what
that means is every neuron from one
layer is connected to every other neuron
from another layer so these are ler
these are used for I would say kind of
simple to moderately complex problems in
the area of like machine translation and
fraud detection and such but there's
other more specialized networks for
example recurrent neural networks in the
middle here recurrent neural networks
are used on sequential data like we
heard in them in the machine translation
presentation just a few moments ago I'm
going to talk a bit more about
convolutional neural networks so
convolutional neural networks these are
very effective for computer vision so
you can see on the right side of this
slide this is an image from an
autonomous vehicle and what this vehicle
is able to do using these convolutional
neural networks is to identify objects
in the scene and to rank them to
classify them with a probability so
that's a vehicle with a certain
probability these modern CNN's can
identify hundreds of objects in the
scene of different types stoplights
pedestrians people on bicycles etc and
they're really they work really well
because they use a lot fewer connections
between the networks by virtue of using
convolutions or terms these filters that
move through thee through the image
another interesting thing about these
networks is that they have translational
invariance which what that means is that
it's hard to fool them so if you move
image to a different moving object to a
different place in the image because the
convolution filter moves for that image
even though different pixels are laid up
in the image it can still sit say that's
a cat there or there that's a bicycle
there are there even though it's in a
different part of the image and here's a
couple examples of classic networks that
that people use we've heard about GPUs
this afternoon neural networks are often
they sort of devolve to doing tons and
tons of matrix operations and graphic
processing units are well suited to
these algorithms because they do tons
and tons of matrix operations in
parallel and very quickly so this is
what I would say is like standard
infrastructure for running deep neural
networks you have often a single server
and one or more GPUs and this works very
well you can stream data through these
things and solve big problems but sort
of keep this picture in mind as we talk
about parallel databases so there's a
particular parallel database that that I
work on it's an open source project
called greenplum database and it looks
like this so a parallel database like
green plum and there are many of them
out there they're characterized by kind
of shared nothing architecture so it's
sequel based you have sequel that comes
in to the master node and that sequel
workload gets distributed to the worker
nodes and in green plum lingo the worker
nodes are called segments so you can
think of these as having post grass
databases running on all of these worker
nodes and having the workload
distributed to them by virtue of a
pretty advanced query planner then those
results are brought back to the master
and that's the result set so what we
would like to do is add deep learning to
that architecture so this is the
approach that we've we've taken we want
to be able to attach worker nodes GP
Jews to these segments to take advantage
of all the great things that GPUs can do
and we also want to run deep learning
libraries on the worker nodes so where
we feel we can innovate is not
necessarily in you know changing those
libraries themselves because there's so
much rapid innovation happening
happening in those libraries so we want
to run those as is on the worker nodes
and marshal the data and return the
results using Apache MATLAB which is an
open source in database learning project
so if you sort of compare this somewhat
lonely architecture to this kind of
distributed system then you kind of get
the idea that yeah there's actually
possibility to do more computation in
parallel and be more efficient very
quickly word about patchy MATLAB is in
database machine learning the idea is
that you don't want to move that data
out of the database to another place
operate on it and move it back so what
Apache Madlib does is it brings machine
learning statistics computation to where
the the data live so you might ask okay
like what is the kind of distributed
machine learning you can do in a in a
cluster and there's different options
there different ways that you can go
about about doing it I'm going to talk
about the first one primarily in this
talk which is running a single big model
across a cluster so what that means is
you take a very large data set you
distribute it to your worker node so you
have different shards of data on those
worker nodes then you use a single model
architecture and then you run that in
parallel and you build a single large
model so that's the work that we've done
primarily that I'm going to talk about
today I did want to touch touch on one
other area which is hyper per amore
tuning the thing one interesting I've
learnt the thing I've learned about
working on neural nets is that
it's a bit of a black art like even
experienced practitioners can't say oh
this mole architecture with these
parameters is going to work on this data
set there's so much tuning involved so
another option for using the cluster is
to replicate your data on your different
worker nodes so same data on across like
on each worker node same model
architecture by different parameters and
then run tens or hundreds of options you
know of parameter versions and collect
the results so that's another kind of
aspect of this project that we're
working on let's talk about the workflow
right now so you take raw images say
JPEG image is and then for each pixel of
those images in the case of a color
image it would have an R a G and a B
value you create a numpy array from
those so you can have your resolution
times 3 in this stacked array what we do
is we actually write it to CSV and then
read it in a parallel fashion into the
database so there is kind of tooling
that we've developed that allows you to
take these raw images and then stream
them into the database so once you have
them in the database then that's when
kind of the deep learning can can happen
so how does distribute a deep learning
work the way that it works is by
distributing the workload to the
segments and then collecting the results
back so for example step one is the
model that you've written say a tensor
flow model chunks through the mini
batches of the data that is on that
worker node right so once they've
completed that then they do what's
called a merge function so the merge
involves collecting the weights and the
gradients from the model state
effectively from each of the worker
nodes combining it together then for a
particular operation there may be a
final function that's
and then you iterate so then you
rebroadcast your weights you go through
another epoch of your data and then you
[Music]
do that either for a fixed number of
iterations or until you you you converge
so it's this idea of iterative model
execution for distributed systems so the
question you know that we've been
looking at is what does that merge
function look like like how do we
collect the this this data in order to
do this distributed computation so it
turns out not surprisingly this is an
open area of research there's a paper
I've quoted here which I think is very
useful that gives a survey of different
approaches to take the distributed
learning we tested three so far we
touched it simple averaging we tested an
ensemble in method which is putting
models together and then we tested
something called elastic averaging
stochastic gradient descent so I'd like
to share some results from the work that
we've we've done so far the
infrastructure that we used we tested
primarily on Google cloud platform we
used high memory CPUs with 208 gig of
memory per per machine per virtual
machine we use P 100 GPUs and we tested
database cluster sizes from a single
node up to 20 nodes and we have one GPU
per segment we use two data sets this is
a classic one that people in machine
learning use it's called cypher 10
they're low resolution color pictures
they're 32 by 32 and there's 60,000
there's a more challenging data set
which is a really great data set from
MIT
it's called places the version we use
has 1.8 million examples there's another
one with 8 or 10 million
apples their higher resolution 256 by
256 and they comprise 365 places like
cafe library Park kinds of things so one
of the results that we've seen I'm not
sure how readable that is but I'll call
out the colors so what we started with
is a simple one layer convolutional
neural net there's an architecture there
which you can look at later if you want
so we ran it on a single node 4 node
cluster 8 and 16 so what this is
plotting is the accuracy on the y-axis
and then number of iterations on the
x-axis so what it shows is that this is
very well-behaved data set so for one
node it takes fewer iterations to reach
an accuracy of you know 75 or 80 percent
that's the blue line the Green Line is a
20 node cluster so in terms of number of
iterations it takes longer for that to
converge which kind of makes sense
because each worker node is only seeing
a portion of all of the examples and
there's only 50 thousands or so there's
not that many so this was sort of
expected the thing we're interested
though is in his run time because the
reason we want to do a distributed
system is that we want we want our
models to train much faster than if
you're just using a single single node
so this plot then shows run time on the
y-axis and accuracy on the left axis so
the way to read it is for a this is 75%
accuracy so one node takes 40,000 or
4,000 can read at 4,000 seconds if you
run it on the cluster then it runs much
faster however you'll note that if you
run it on four nodes or eight nodes or
16 nodes it
run linearly faster so you get to a
point where yes distributing that
computation helps you but you know if
you throw more GPUs at it it doesn't
necessarily mean you're gonna get faster
convergence so let's look at a more
complicated model this now is a
six-layer neural net so it has six
layers stacked together and this is the
same thing in terms of run time our
sorry in terms of accuracy on the left
side and iterations on the right side so
this looking at this model this shows me
that it doesn't perhaps
generalize that well because you see
your accuracy going down after a while
but one kind of interesting thing to me
is that in this in this plot is that if
you run it on one iteration if you rent
it on just a single server you see that
it doesn't generalize that well but if
you run it on the cluster that doesn't
show up as much so if you cast that plot
in terms of time like we did on the
other ones then what you see is for this
particular data set and this model
architecture at least if to achieve 75
percent accuracy you know one node takes
the the longest takes 750 seconds for
nodes is you know 600 seconds eight is
300 or so so it does get faster so here
you seem more a case for this small
architecture that the bigger your
cluster is it does seem to run faster up
to a point you don't see a lot of
difference between 8 and 16 nodes so
let's look at maybe one or two more
examples this is on the places data set
that I talked about so that's a much
larger data set and then we're using a
well known molecule vgg and this has a
hundred and thirty million parameters so
this is a pretty big model so
as expected we see that if you in terms
of number of iterations it takes fewer
iterations to converge we notice here on
20 a cluster of 20 we ran it up to 100
iterations and it still hadn't got to
the accuracy we we wanted and if you
look at the time and this is really less
convincing what it's showing is that if
you forget the 20 node cluster for a
moment which is the green one these are
1 5 and 10 nodes actually and you don't
really see any benefit from this
distributed computation so there's
perhaps a number of reasons why this
happens it could be that this data set
has so many levels in it that like so
many different classes that distributing
that computation doesn't help you that
that much last example I want to show is
on an ensemble so what we did is we took
this convolutional neural net we ran it
on each of the worker nodes and instead
of averaging the result of those we fed
that into another CNN which is a very
very simple CNN to see what the effect
of Ensemble models is so this is the
result and one interesting so the red
line is if you just so this is accuracy
on the left side number of iterations so
the red line is if you just average the
worker nodes
you know what accuracy to get and you
see it's converging albeit slowly if you
take the output at a given point and
feed it through this ensemble this
simpler CNN at the end then your
accuracy actually jumps quite a lot by
two or three times so we only ran it for
40 iterations because it was very
expensive but at least we got to that we
got a feeling that this idea of
ensembles in the distributed system may
be something that is very useful in the
future so I'm gonna skip this one
because I do want to talk about lessons
learned
both on the modeling and on
infrastructure lessons learned on the
modeling I would say yes distributed
deep learning can potentially run faster
than a single node so for a given
accuracy you can get benefits from from
distributing that computation our
experience in our experience we found it
to be pretty challenging to do this it
was really interesting work but anybody
who's working on distributed systems
know that things don't seem to come
easily the other thing is we were
working in the context of a distributed
database this parallel database so there
are some things that like we're just on
a linux cluster we could do differently
but since you need to work with the
query processor you need to work with
how the database marshals data around
that can kind of handcuff you a little
bit so that was when I know one of the
limitations that we we had to deal with
on the infrastructure lessons learned I
said my number one thing is beware of
the cost of GPUs on public cloud when we
got we had some sticker shock when we
got our bill after the first first month
the other thing is memory management can
be very finicky GPU initialization
settings and freeing tensorflow memory
there's a lot of kind of folklore there
and I put at the back of this deck kind
of a more detailed list so if anybody's
having issues around GPU memory and such
we found a bunch of blog posts that were
helpful a lot of stuff we kind of had to
fail and learn on
our own so there's a lot of details here
on if you're running into challenges
this isn't just database specific you
know have a look they're there you there
may be some may save you a bit of time
yeah so maybe since we're getting to the
end here I'll talk about the future work
that we're planning to do so Apache
madly passive release coming up in
probably within the next month which is
the initial release of the distributed
deep learning so we're currently going
to support care us with the tensorflow
back-end with GPU support and the work
that we have planned for the remainder
of this year this is very deep learning
focused so we want to look at more
distributed deep learning methods we
want to implement parallel hyper
parameter tuning that I mentioned before
and we're also in the process of adding
a model versioning repository so that
will allow you to run tons and tons of
models in parallel collect your results
in one in one table and then sort of
sort through them to pick your best best
parameters that was it so thank you very
much for you
[Applause]
yes yeah okay I think that's because
that model doesn't generalize well so
okay so the question is why if you rent
it for more accurate for a larger
accuracy does it does if you run for
more iterations as accuracy drop so this
can happen for certain kind of models
that start to see increasing gradients
so accuracy goes down there's there is a
blog post here where we got this we
didn't create this model we got it from
this researcher so the results that we
see here are very similar to that
person's results I think the bottom line
is it's not a very good model for that
data side sorry
this is a yeah I was showing I was using
this as an example to show that if you
run if you run a certain model
architecture on a data set on a single
node and then you run the same thing in
a cluster you actually can see different
convergence behavior that was sort of
the point of demonstrative showing this