ah and he is going to talk to us about
designing for activism reimagining the
contributor experience - thank you
actually this is my fifth fifth year
presenting here so it's kind of like I'm
not really a newcomer but still it's
also real good to see phases starting
from a few years ago when only quite
less people showed up and seen so much
interest in open source design now it's
really reassuring I mean you know I I do
open source design actually I've been
with this community for quite a few
years now and this community quite
inspired me also to do my own design
studio which is only doing stuff for
open source projects so any project you
can imagine probably needs at some point
some design love some UX love some
usability love and we try to help this
projects I'm here because of Mozilla was
so kind to support me to travel here I'm
also a speaker at Mozilla which is a
volunteer program with training and
travel a lot of speakers so if you have
also some Firefox questions or whatever
you can ask me afterwards as well yes
I'm also a UX designer at uni open
Observatory of network interference
which is part of the defect so what is
actually only doing this is what I'm
gonna talk about today and how we
improve the software to me or to new
users and more useful to power users so
it's basically a internet censorship
measurement tool so if you live in areas
which is not really Western
civilization's
but for example in countries where a lot
of censorship happens
these events and send the data to any
servers this can use that data to write
reports to going to courts and yeah
whatever you can imagine and a real
activist since 2012 we have been getting
quite a few measurements namely 200
million from I think like 180 countries
or something and but of quite a few
pieces of software one of them is being
Rooney probe so this is actually funny I
got involved at Unni after seeing this
job posting an open-source design I
think like two and a half years ago they
were looking for a designer this is how
I got in touch later on I've been at
only and tor project for almost two
years now
so it's quite a circle and we here we
are again right so so how only probe
works is that you install the software
on your mobile phone
iOS or Android or your desktop or even a
Raspberry Pi so if you wanted to run
tests see what websites up some
messaging apps are blocked you can do
that from your phone or if you have a
lot of censorship going on in your
country which is not the case in Belgium
but for example in Iran or other
countries it's there's quite a lot of
censorship happening you can even have a
Raspberry Pi which runs measurements
constantly without you doing anything so
this data gets published on our Uni
Explorer which is kind of an open data
portal where everyone can research the
data and see what might be interesting
to them also API for all developers and
researchers who want to have more power
over this so actually this app has been
released two years ago and we wanted to
revamp the user experience because a few
people had problems
understanding what all these technical
terms means man's like HTTP Haddonfield
manipulation request line and all that
kind of stuff so this is when we started
to redesign the app and I'm going to
show you through a few features we have
redesigning the app how it was in the
old one and how it is in the big one a
new one so we started with a new color
scheme before we to improve the
semantics we put a color for every kind
of tests so you know in which kind of
environment you are so if you are in an
instant messaging environment you have
this kind of color but also about status
you can see if something is censored
something is accessible you are not sure
if it's sensor or not based on the color
so this would help with the visual cue
any user to know what they're doing also
in the first step we had test for every
little thing so we had this kind of
tests
everyone was everything was accessible
to the user from the first screen and we
said that it should be a bit easier for
newcomers who really don't understand
what the header field manipulation is so
we grouped them into five different
classes and this made it very easier for
people to get into each of them and then
explore from there depending on what
they're interested in obviously
sometimes you are interested only in
instant messaging apps so you wouldn't
want to go off to all of them right we
also had new website categories so and I
can set which is done by the citizen lab
so there's a global test list with
thousands of websites which are often
blocked and each of these websites
belongs to a category and we did the
icon set for each category and when you
test now and you feel not comfortable
for example testing hate-speech websites
even these
Abell that and it sets for everything
else
basically afterwards so yeah what we did
with that on the left you can see the
old app we have every every test listed
here so it's very tech savvy and we also
have a hamburger menu with flights which
was sometimes not really noticeable for
people and we just changed it to a cart
approach with four carts
this is crawlable and people would not
would not need to click on every test to
run them but they could just explore the
test by tapping on a cart also when the
test was progressing people many many of
of our users and contributors that's a
better name didn't really notice that
this was actually running we had only a
progress bar here but with a new one we
have a kind of an animation which shows
that the test is actually running and
shows you kind of an estimate how long
it's going to take also the past test
results shows you a bit more information
more power user information without
hopefully I hope without not making it
too too heavy on the eye so you can see
as I said based on the color cues what
kind of tests we have to deal with the
websites test in this in this example
you can filter through tests you can see
how much data you used because a lot of
censorship is happening also mobile data
and not a lot of people have the
privilege to have terabytes of mobile
data as well the overview where you can
access many tests this is the old
version of the website's test and
compared to the new one still a bit too
much text in the new one to my taste but
we are constantly improving that so any
any suggestions are also welcome in this
version you are also able to choose the
websites and run custom websites that
means that if you don't want to just run
random websites but you
that's I don't know foster or might be
censored you can just click that and
type that in and only test for that
website so this is only the part of
Mooney probe which is the contributor
experience the man on the ground who
submits data but we also have a little
bit of an ecosystem with other things as
well which is the Unni Explorer the
portal which can visualize all this data
for this we are redesigning the the
whole platform we are working with
Antonella who is also the UX lead at tor
project and hopefully making it easier
for for people to make sense of the data
because it's not really simple stuff we
also have a probe desktop beta out now
which you are free to test it basically
has a similar experience to the mobile
app it's not as polished yet and yeah
you're gonna run the same test from your
desktop if you are not a big of a mobile
person and one of my favorite things is
actually only run so when Iran is a
little website where you can create a
test list of websites so let's say you
have an X spreadsheet with a list of
websites which you think might be
blocked and you don't want to test each
one by one right so you have 400
websites list you just share it with
your friends and they can type this in
here in only run and it creates a link
which to which when opened
everyone can test these 400 websites in
this example so in this in this way you
can create some critical mass make
create an initiative where all people
are testing for these websites get more
measurements and make make some sense of
what is happening regarding censorship
in that country because censorship is
quiet
quite difficult to prove it can be on it
something can be censored in one minute
the next minute in my not so constant
measurements throughout time and twelve
different networks are very important
just because you did one measurement at
one given time does not mean much often
so it's a it's a quite complicated thing
so after opening only run you get
navigated to the mobile lab which is
testing all this websites and giving you
the results something which a lot of
people prefer rather than the test lists
which are readily made available for the
country so yeah that's that's basically
a very sneak peek into the new UX design
we are doing a toonie probe if you are
interested to get involved we have a
design channel so I'd be happy to help
out if you don't like slack which is
very understandable we also have an
Irish Sea which is also breached so
please feel free to join us or an issue
on github yeah check out the web site I
guess that is all thank you very much
for coming yeah yeah so we have a sorry
the question was what tests we run so
let me go quickly to this slide so this
are all the tests which are run which
are neatly organized into this groups so
web connectivity means if a website is
blocked or not then we have three
messenger tests telegram whatsapp and
facebook Messenger we have speed tests
which you might know from speedtest.net
NDT speed test is something which shows
well your network speed - 3 means how
well you can stream video on your
network connection
the reason we did this these tests in
any probe is because many government
Ruiz throttle the internet instead of
censoring so they make the the network
is so slow you are actually unable to to
check a website so it also is really
useful to to show some net neutrality
violations but this is still very basic
something we we are exploring in the
future as well the both HTTP tests are
for middle boxes which are inserted by
the network sometimes it might be
malicious sometimes it might mean
nothing it just means that some middle
box is present on the network it's not
necessarily bad or that are good we also
have circumvention tests which is
regarding tour right now we also are
adding new ones so it basically tells
you whether tor network is accessible
for example China is censoring tor quite
often and in many countries is not that
easy to access to work so yeah that's
that's basically the number of tests
yeah this is the test list by citizen
lab which is curated by them
it's a crowd-sourced list categorized
I'm not sure about the committee who
decides on that I think it's open source
and a discussion can be can be initiated
regarding that but yeah basically all of
this 30 test categories they they serve
to categorize all these websites yeah
yes
so we did a round off usability studies
which were not face to face because we
are a distributed team in different
cities from new to a very experienced
and the new UI is based on this feedback
we got from them of course there is a
lot of stuff on the plate I would like
to address but we are a very small team
and yeah we need more manpower to
address more things so any help is
appreciated
we did - yeah we did to test one with a
non working prototype very early on when
the design was kind of finished and one
after the beta was out sorry the Alpha
was out so yeah based on these decisions
with it changes to the design the
questions yeah yeah
sorry um I have not included this year
but yeah that's actually possible so
thanks for reminding me of that
so for every test group which is
basically this one we have many
different tests for example instant
messaging includes all those three
messaging apps some people don't like to
test all of them so we can enable or
disable them in the settings and once
you run the test class as as a test you
get results for each of them separately
so you can tap on whatever you prefer to
have also if you run a website's test it
tests 30 random websites and you can
check every website individually and if
you want to even go a bit more deeper
you can also check the actual roll data
which is a bit more hidden but it's it's
accessible for power users yeah
like exporting the tests yeah we don't
have that yet there are not too many
settings but it might make sense to
include that when you in uninstall the
app right now all these settings are
lost it's also there are some privacy
related settings which which is kind of
a chicken-and-egg problem including your
IP address and network name and all the
kind of stuff which people don't like to
share but it's actually not really
useful to us if we don't have the data
so doing measurements without network
name and whatever is kind of defeats the
purpose some people also use VPNs which
also defeat the purpose yeah but yeah
that's a future request because we we
could address yeah
yes in the onboarding when you actually
install the app for the first time we
have a little pop quiz and it says that
are you aware that your data might be
watched by government agencies blah blah
blah we are going bit crazy over there
but just to make sure that the user
understands the risks yeah this is the
time that they user understands the
risks until now nothing nothing happened
since 2012 that doesn't mean anything so
we just want to make sure we are doing
this in the onboarding to educate the
user and the contributors what this
means any last question yeah like the
number throughout time yeah they're
constantly increasing we are doing
partnerships with a lot of organizations
around the world which care about human
rights and Internet freedom and we are
publishing constantly reports for
example in Zimbabwe there was some
internet outage a week ago which was
quite a big deal and sadly to say the
more of these events happened the more
people and measurements we get so the
fact that we got more measurements means
that more is happening around the
world as well but yeah we are getting
more measurements
okay yeah okay I think sorry I've been
not repeating all the questions all this
time I'm sorry for the reporting which
is getting out now how we deal with the
trade-off for the progress bar which has
less features sorry let me just go
through this quickly actually all of
this is available in the new app it's
just definitely laid out so you can
actually go to the settings select the
test you want to run and you run them
from the cart right now it's problematic
if you cancel a test this might create
anomalous measurement data so we don't
allow the user to do that the next
feature request is going to be queue up
tests so we can queue up difference as
you want to do and just keep the phone
away and not being on the phone all the
time I don't think there is a much
trade-off here to be honest it's
everything in the old app is available
in the new app the fact that you think
it's not available is a good thing
because it looks simpler yeah I think so
[Applause]