great thanks Philip hello everyone my
name is Derek Kozel I'm I work with the
Guinea radio foundation these days
mostly on the community side but I do
enjoy coding and when the call for
papers went out I our powerful
presentations for this I had actually
just started my PhD which meant I was
completely clueless but I knew it was
going to be about power amplifiers and I
knew that it was gonna be about
efficiency and linearity and so I was
like okay what what don't I know that I
should rapidly learn and digital
pre-distortion ended up being that topic
so this presentation is basically the
summation of the last couple months of
me messing around with Guinea radio and
messing around with the theory trying to
understand it and hopefully I can share
that with you I always enjoy bringing up
a hardware more a hardware centric topic
in the SDR dev room because we all are
using hardware if we're actually trying
to get on the spectrum and so often we
just treat that as a complete
transparent layer that says I have a
simulated signal that's perfectly what's
going to come out the antenna and that
is never ever true and it's great when
we can actually try and do something
about it so what is digital
pre-distortion it's a technique for
improving the linearity of power
amplifiers i amplify errs and general
and systems in general but the biggest
problem tends to be power amplifiers
ideally you have the sample fire and you
want the output signal to simply be a a
larger version of your input but
semiconductor physics basically says
you're never ever going to get that if
you're operating at a low power maybe
you'll be close but I there's a lot of
reasons why you want to get that higher
power so if we can try and predict the
errors that occur in the amplitude the
frequency and phase maybe we can try and
offset some of them and this is a plot
of a very typical result you know if you
have to read a paper or you know check
out somebody's eye repository this is
almost always the image you run across
and what we're seeing here I is the
green signal is the original input
signal and the blue is what happens if
you then put it through like a ten watt
amplifier running right at the limit and
say you know oh yeah it looks great on
the outside and
all of a sudden your signal-to-noise
ratio has really fallen quite
significantly but if we say okay we know
this is going to happen we're gonna make
some either measurements or guesses
about how we can fix this then you can
get the red signal and we see that the
signal noise ratio has improved quite a
bit it is a little worse than the input
I the math errors do accumulate and our
our estimate is only so good but it's a
significant improvement so what's the
high-level overview I pretty much what
we have is at the output we want to have
you know a perfectly linear signal we
want to say what goes in just gets
bigger and comes out I'm going to talk
about why this is the shape that you get
out of a power amplifier as you increase
the power it's probably a very familiar
term is the one DB compression point as
you drive your power amplifier up
eventually when you increase your input
signal by one DB it's just not going to
go up by one DB first it's gonna be 0.9
you probably don't notice but when it
starts being really significant that
error accumulates and all of a sudden
you're getting this shape here so what
we want to do is at the input just
increase the amount of power a little
more than we think we need so if we say
we want one more DB we put you know 1.5
DB higher power and in the end hopefully
all the math works out so why do we want
to use di DPD I'm gonna say DP D well I
mean digital pre-distortion because it
just rolls off the tongue quite a bit
better i we want to get as much power
out of an amplifier as we can you know
personally when I buy a hundred watt
amplifier I don't want to use it at 50
watts because that's where the
performance is good when is it in a
hundred watts and also you know if
you're just throwing away half of the
capacity of the device that can be quite
expensive as a hobbyist maybe you care
because your budgets really small as a
company or as a business you care
because you know that's part of your
budget I so we drive it as hard as we
can basically and we drive it up to this
point so this is the one DB point here
where you can see the theoretical
response and the actual compression we
drive it up well into that region and as
we look at newer and newer Tran
mr. technologies we're actually seeing
that this curve is getting even softer
you know you start operating up into
like the three DB compression point and
that's considered standard operating and
also the power amplifier efficiency is
much much much better if you're
operating near the limits of your device
on I didn't throw in a plot because I
couldn't find a good one that didn't end
up getting into the nitty-gritty details
but you know we're not talking five
percent efficiency decrease here if you
back off so that your signal is only
staying in this region you could be
losing you know half of your power
efficiency right there
if not more I do have these slides on
back on the transistor theory I'll I
will go through them they're mostly
meant to be a reference for people
coming back to the slides later so don't
read too much into the slides or it
might be very familiar for some people
here I the most common transistor used
for these high-power amplifiers these
days tend to be field effect transistors
this is a voltage controlled device so
the voltage at the input is going to
keep flowing on the outside I so we have
a gate terminal which is tends to be our
control terminal we have a drain which
generally ends up being attached to our
power supply and is also our output
point we'll see that on the next slide
and then the source which tends to be
grounded all right so by changing the
voltage of the input at the gate we're
going to change the amount of current
flowing from the drain to the source
this tends to be a pretty typical
simplified circuit as soon as you start
designing these you realize there's
about 80 components on either side of
these and they never work the way you
want them to I but we can see here you
know again the circuit from the previous
slide the transistor and the drain has a
capacitor that's decoupling it from this
power supply rail and we're getting a
voltage at the output and so that's the
signal out words and basically what
we're doing is we have the input signal
we're changing the gate source voltage
and that's producing a change in current
at the output
and as long as the slope is greater than
one across your resistor you got an
amplification but we can also even from
this slide already see this curve this
transfer characteristic it's not a line
and it never is this is kind of a
different way of looking at it again
don't read too much into the details
it's meant to be kind of an overview of
why is this a problem where do we run
into these problems again I what we're
looking at here is the current at the
output this is actually as a function of
the drain source voltage so that power
supply rail that you're putting in but
each one of these lines represents a
different control voltage the gate
source voltage so we're going to be
actually jumping basically from line to
line to line here as our control input
which is why we end up operating on a
line here and it looks fine in the
middle we can get a very very linear
response because we're operating in the
saturated point of the transistor but as
you run up into the limits you start
seeing uh we're actually going to be in
the linear region and we're not getting
the voltage we want or the current we
want there and as you get down to the
bottom it's not really shown on this
graph but you start running into
problems when you get into cutoff
there's just not enough voltage to make
the transistor do what you want it to
you start ending up with these soft
knees and the curves I so it looks
mostly linear but what are we getting
we're getting distortion I our ideal
transfer function would be something
like this where the output voltage is
just the input voltage scaled by some
constant and so yeah a is the voltage
gain of the amplifier engineer a do I
set up this very quick test set up one
of the most common ways that we end up
measuring distortion is just by putting
two tones in and seeing what comes out
the other end
I the only new block here if you're
familiar with Guinea radio is the
configurable PA block and I'll walk
through that more later but basically
what this is saying is we have a voltage
gain of 10 so whatever comes in at the
input is just supplied by 10 nothing
else and then I always like adding noise
to these because otherwise you
with overly a realist overly ideal
results and we have controls for tone
spacing and tone amplitude they're
evenly spaced around the center
frequency and this is what we get as our
output result and I'm happy to say this
actually does match up with what I hoped
it would be I realized I hadn't measured
this before the presentation we're
getting about a 20 DB gain here which is
exactly what we would expect by a 10x
voltage increase that's very reassuring
and we see that you know the noise has
been amplitude amplified our signals of
interest have been amplified perfect
we're in an ideal realm but that's not
what the transfer function ends up
actually looking like instead we have
these extra terms and it turns out that
you can model this function very well
just by having a power series polynomial
I won't go into why that's a really
natural i function but it turns out that
a lot of DSP and it's particularly the
Fourier transform make this a fairly
natural approach and it does fit the
curves quite nicely so we see the linear
gain a1 here so this is the a from the
previous equation then we've added on
another 1 a 2 which is going to multiply
the squared function of the input and a
3 which words to infinity and pretty
much if you've let a computer just try
and fit this without any constraints you
will end up with you know 90 terms here
and not that's just not something we can
really compute realistically on a
computer with any sort of performance I
just as a and note here this is a
behavioral model we're not trying to
simulate the circuit at all we're just
saying this is what it looks like
you know this is a the behavior of the
model not the physics that are
underlying it and it only depends on the
current input value that will come into
relevancy right at the end of the
presentation so second-order Distortion
let's just look at what happens if you
take the input signal multiplied by some
constant and then square it
I this is
the interesting term here the result is
a tone at twice the original frequency
so we're generating a second harmonic we
don't have a mixer we just have an
amplifier but we're getting a second
harmonic out that was a really fun
connection for me to make because I
always knew that mixers were just highly
nonlinear devices they've been optimized
to function as as mixers i but they're
using exactly the same characteristic
here they just have a very high they
they're combining terms like this cubed
we're getting a term that's at the
fundamental frequency and at the third
harmonic at three times the fundamental
uh
so that's an interesting take away our
third-order distortion is actually
contributing back power on our original
frequency there is gonna be a phase term
to this later
so we're causing phase distortion on our
fundamental signal due to these
nonlinearities now the even order
distortion didn't produce a tone near
our near our pass band so I'm really
glad that these are getting handed out
because they make a great prop for me
today if you have a power amplifier like
this that's the power amplifier and a
filter you're throwing away all of those
second harmonics the third harmonics all
the terms that you're getting here the
only ones that are going to be a
relevance are the ones that fall quite
near to our fundamental frequency let's
just throw away all of the even terms
and this this is a simplification that
gets done basically with every pre
distorter and most power amplifier
transistor models when you're using them
for amplify amplifiers and just for
completeness here's the fifth order and
we get the fundamental frequency the
third harmonic and a fifth harmonic
X and it's Omega T I swear
[Laughter]
fixed slides will be up later today so
let's go back to our 2-tone distortion
now we have a better model of our
transistor it has these nonlinearities
put two tones into it you know Omega 1
Omega 2 they're going to be very close
to each other in frequency and the
third-order distortion causes eye tear
basically two frequencies I 2 times you
know the first tone - the second two
times the second tone - the first one so
I yeah the fundamental tone will be
distorted by all two odd power like I
mentioned and we'll get some
indifference tones and they're scaled by
some constants not particularly
important in the details but you can
work through analytically just all of
these terms and and get a good result I
love this picture and I love what the
projector is doing to it it's a star
field so what we're getting is you know
we look at the fundamental tone here
that's our ideal result we're actually
getting a little bit of power from the
third degree and the fifth degree so
this is this is the power contributions
stacked up on each of these tones and
you can see that's not only true of the
fundamental it's also true that this is
going to be the third order the primary
third-order distortion but it also has a
contribution from the fifth and then it
the fifth is standing alone here but you
would also get like the nut seventh
order and the ninth order if you
continued on I just love that love that
picture I think it's really well
composed so if we put this into the new
radio this is now our input signal we
have this basically the same output
power on the fundamental we will get a
little bit of extra contribution and
we're seeing the third order plus a
little of the fifth and the fifth order
and I didn't include a seventh so it's
it's just there but I'll quickly swap
over and we can run this live
maybe yes wonderful interesting uh so we
see if the tone amplitude is low enough
it looks basically like a completely
linear system but as we start driving
that output up higher and higher and
getting better and better energy
efficiency we get the intermodulation
tones apparently really doesn't like
this and I'll just try and drive it
really high and see if we can get one
[Laughter]
all right okay well so you can see here
we're getting even more terms there and
so an interesting takeaway from here is
that these the amplitude of these inter
modulation tones map directly to those
coefficients that I we have so if this
will cooperate all open up the power
amplifier and it won't no well I'll just
describe it then I sew on the
configurable PA block parameters we have
the the Alpha coefficients so that
number that we were seeing in the
equations in the slides you can enter
each of those up to the ninth order yeah
all right yeah
they're called beta here because it I is
actually mapped on the distortion side
but it's exactly the same math so we
have a beta 1 for our fundamental
frequency third order fifth order
seventh and ninth order Distortion see
if it likes this better it does
interesting so yes so how do we
determine these coefficients you have a
power amplifier like this and you can be
absolutely sure that I probably not
tonight but sometime in the next week
I'll be putting this onto an SD are
driving it quite hard and seeing you
know can I create a model of this that
works quite well and if I can't I'll
post it on Twitter so we need to
determine these coefficients the Alpha 1
3 5
and as many as you think you need I the
common approach because I finding these
finding these the common approach is to
put in a single test tone at very low
amplitude at basically the minimum
amplitude that you're expected input
signal is going to be at and sweep that
to the maximum amplitude of your input
signal and ideally you'd see it
traversing this perfect line the perfect
linear response of input voltage to
output voltage what you actually get is
that curve that we saw and then you can
use as this is called an AM AM plot
amplitude amplitude plot and the general
approach is to use something like the
least means squares optimization
algorithm to estimate those coefficients
I I will just in passing say that if you
work through all of the math here to
determine these coefficients you can
gather all of the terms together and say
you know I know that this here it is
this percentage take off of one this
percentage the Alpha three this
percentage the Alpha five and so you can
directly derive those coefficients
just from a single i2 tone test here and
also if you have something like this you
can see that the ninth order isn't
actually contributing anything
meaningfully because we don't have a
spur here so that also tells you how
many terms you need to represent your
power amplifier which is fun like I said
it's also going to distort your phase
I'm a little suspicious of the actual
details of this plot but the general
trend is there we see that as you
increase the amplitude it's the actual
phase you know if you kind of estimated
that the actual phase is fairly linear
but it's sloped as you go through so if
you apply DPD the idea is to you know
take that slope subtract it away so your
input signal would actually look like
that and in the end you would just get a
zero degree phase difference across the
amplitude the way you build that into
the model is you just make the
coefficients
complex so if you look at the flow
graphs which will be available for
download you'll see I'm using numpy with
the complex and so the original ideal
model was just ten plus J 0 and the non
ideal has phase shifts to it this is
gonna tie them out pretty well
pre-distortion like I said the idea is
that we're going to change our input to
match out the output I we're going to be
limited by the maximum amount of power
that you can actually supply at the
input you know if you have only 10 DBM
maximum output of your SDR or of your
transmitter you just can't you know all
the sudden put out the 30 DBM or
whatever to to hit this point instead
you're going to be limited to here so we
can operate and fix basically the errors
up to this point the maximum correction
point right here alright there's AP
saturation but there's gonna be a limit
to how much you can correct
so inverting the transfer function we
have that great volterra series which
tells us it's going to be low by this
much i ideally you'd have a function
that just tells you you should be high
by this much
you can do this analytically or
algebraically but it becomes very
lengthy so again people tend to use
training algorithms so they sample that
if the RF output demodulate it back down
anti-alias it all the stuff you do in a
normal receiver and then you'd have some
DSP here that's comparing the output
signal to the desired input and saying
we have an error we're gonna adjust some
of the coefficients we're getting better
we're gonna adjust a bit more and it
stabilizes on so we're gonna indirectly
learn what the power amplifier is doing
i the direct learning method is we know
what the power amplifier is doing going
to figure out the function and we're
just going to have a lookup table here
so can you radio blocks I this isn't
just a peer theory Theory thing there
are different of tree
and he published
in 2016 about it these blocks are
available on github
shreekant pagode re gr DPD and it could
include some OFDM tests
alright code so this is an image from
his paper and you can see that image
that I posted up the beginning the same
sort of thing the blue all the way down
here is his ideal signal uh and then he
filters it just to try and get rid of
eye so everybody have yeah so they I
think this blue line the blue dotted
line here is the original signal put
through the power amplifier we see it's
going above his spectral mask tries
filtering it that doesn't do it and so
then it ends up digitally pre distorting
it and filtering it and gets it below
the mask here as that's that's quite a
considerable improvement over twenty 25
DB worth of signal to noise ratio
improvement this is for full band so if
you just have like one signal or you
want to pre distort everything in your
pass band this is a great place to start
with that alright
this was a really interesting find and I
didn't appreciate it in the beginning I
this was some work done by chance harbor
and Mahmood and it was published in 2017
and it's sub band so he's taking a look
at what happens if you have a couple
different like LTE signals all in the
same band some of those modulation
products are probably going to be
outside of their pass band it's just
gonna get filtered away anyways let's
not spend any time computing you know
doing the math to try and solve that but
I let's say this is sitting in you know
a for argument's sake like the GSM
spectrum or something something that you
really really had to not have any any
Spurs in I this allows you to say I want
to remove this inter modulation product
and so you only do the computation for
that this also included the power
amplifier model that I've been using for
the demo and a full indirect learning
model as does the previous one so it has
all the test code that you could
actually hook up to a USRP put a power
amplifier in and if you could figure it
out
train your modeling and have this work
future plans I've talked to the authors
of both of these over the last couple
months trying to understand it there's a
distinct lack of documentation
particularly with with chances one which
he fully fully puts forward and says
this was for the paper the paper is
great and I agree the paper is quite
readable but the actual blocks
themselves don't have any documentation
the authors of both are agreeable to
merging this into a single out of tree
module restructuring it so they have
common interfaces you know common
documentation using the mini radio OFDM
test blocks rather than just shipping
binary IQ files which is what chance did
then we'd be able to do like a full loop
back and show you ah the error vector
magnitude of this signal can be improved
by by the pre distortions by this much
all the polynomials so far have not had
any memory so you end up getting thermal
effects or capacitive effects on a power
amplifier that say that the output is
not only dependent on the current input
it changes over the operating conditions
there's lots of work I already published
on this it's fairly add that and I've
been talking in general some people this
is not confirmed but possibly this might
be one of the project ideas listed for
the google Summer of Code fergan II
radio as I said I myself am a PhD
student now I'm working on power
amplifiers so chances are I'll be
contributing to this in one way or
another whether it's the power amplifier
model side or being the guy who ends up
doing some of the DPD
all right thanks some questions um I
always post my slides up at Derek Kozel
comm slash talks I'll also put the three
flow graphs up there and yes send me
questions my email address this stuff is
up there so that'd be great
same operation out of the as the end
result of the lookup table and so please
tell me I put one of the slides in i if
you have this measurement you just have
complex coefficients in the lookup table
and so instead of doing one multiply
you're doing two and it works yeah I you
get basically the same accuracy on both
of them so I