if the phone rings that cost around of
gin tonics for you know for the poor
crowd around is my phone off hello
everybody
I'm sure most of you have seen
Danielle's DNS over HTTPS talked
yesterday and we just had another intro
home from Vittorio and now under
supervision of yum Piedmont these three
gentlemen will discuss after you
thank you betta good morning I'm Ian
Pitman's welcome I hope you can all hear
me
I hope the microphone ears us I'm here
in order to be able to get into the room
that's the reason I accepted the job of
a moderator otherwise I would fill this
somewhere else but anyway so I would
like to introduce this olestra Spano and
in order to apply for this slide I'll
start on the right on the right you have
mr. Daniel Steinberg from Sweden
everybody knows or everybody uses
software that he that he has written for
example curl and Daniel is a very well
verse and also the Internet protocols he
worked please note the past tense for
Mozilla he has not spoken for Mozilla in
the past and he will probably not speak
for Mozilla today and if I am not
mistaken Daniel now works for the
company wolf TLS oh I'm sorry wolf SSL
am i right in the center mr. Stefan
bachmeier Stefan is an old dinosaur of
the internet he knows he knows all RFC
numbers backwards and forwards he is a
distinguished member of a ethnic he is
the Internet architect a quorum of the
French Network Information Center he is
an IETF member he's written a book
recently called cyber so to Atlanta yet
and especially deep and his Twitter
avatar is more
so he's been around for one okay on the
left I'm sounding as I'm presenting a
ring a ring match on the on the left way
of mr. Baer to bail a founder I think it
was in 1999 of power DNS and it's at
least at the time principal author he I
think invented DNS test a load balancer
it doesn't write it anymore but I think
him that did it
you serrated okay be afraid be if be
very afraid
he's a very well-versed in a huge number
of topics including DNA and philosophy
and also two things and he does not he
is not ashamed of wiring extremely ugly
hats so this is our this is our panel
and in order to get us started and in
order to introduce people and get these
gentlemen started I'm gonna ask a
question you couldn't ask a number of
questions and we'll start away at the
beginning as in the under the assumption
that people will watch the video later
on or watching the stream now have not
has been in this room the whole day
Stephan would you be so kind
I'm expecting the terms do T and do H to
be used quite frequently could you in
just two or three sentences explain what
these are and what the differences are
ENS when you suggest DNS it's a protocol
which is in clear which means that
anyone on the network can read the
queries read what you are asking for on
even modifying them which is quite
common in many places the dot DNS over
TLS is using the well-known encryption
security protocol TLS to protect the DNS
queries so people can no longer know
that you are visiting
pornhub.com nobody here do it but it's
an example what Amanda you say no the
good thing about the dot about DNS over
TLS that TLS is well known well used but
it can be blocked because it used a
dedicated ports that's why we have dough
which is a DNS of our HTTPS forget it's
a TLS protocol
because it's a cute EPS but learning
about the HTTP as the advantage that
it's much more difficult to pinpoint
that it's DNS traffic so it's more
difficult to block all thank you very
much bet it appears at least from news
and so on it appears that US
telecommunication giants are now selling
location data of customer mobile phones
just for the hell of it without and in
particular without their owner's
knowledge and people don't seem to be
caring very much about privacy in
particularly if we look at the the the
Facebook Facebook type scandals which
are forgotten sort of directly the
weekend passes in view of this how
relevant is DNS privacy at all I think
it's far more important apparently for
us than it is for general population we
have seen very large numbers of people
for example move their DNS to what eight
from Google that's because it's a
superior service it works really well
and it also frequently gets you around
government censorship so people do care
about the free and open DNS and are
willing to open dialog boxes that say do
not open or void the warranty and they
will still do it so people do care a lot
about working DNS if you go down the
street and ask people are you worried
about CloudFlare Google or Mozilla
getting a copy of your DNS traffic they
will not care we are discussing this
sort of on behalf of users that are not
themselves present in the room so and in
that case we need to imagine a lot how
are these people thinking and that is my
main beef where we can come to if we
start tell people say look just press ok
here because this is more secure then we
have made the decision on their behalf
because they will click that button and
then we have to be very very sure that
we made the right decision for them and
that is because the answer to your
question is people don't care that much
thank you Daniel which technology would
you say is better suited to provide more
privacy or more privacy in the DNS d-o-t
or do h
thank you for that question and the
right answer is I spent a few hours
doing this oh well of course the answer
is not it'll depend on the situation and
going back to pretty much what bird said
it's also about what you can ask the
users to do and who sets things up
because this is these are difficult
questions and handing over the choice to
the users are never going to be the
right way either but at this moment in
time we don't even we don't have the
correct way to do it automatically or by
the system's either so I would say that
right now we're in a weird situation
where yeah we have data we have dough
and they are both web good ways to
secure DNS but as long as we're doing
everything opportunistically and just
trying out things and go with what works
then then dough is going to be the
better option because the dough is right
now just because you forced your option
sort of the customers customer ability
to the user which is wrong but since we
do that it offers better privacy because
you know who you're talking to
you know you pick that server I see a
head shake here because actually a user
does not know the user gets the button
that says do you agree with us getting
you're selling your DNS to this cloud
mountain company in the US or whatever
and and it will be better okay this is
not an informed consent compared to what
you mean your dot selection but you
didn't select that either someone else
did for you so you mean one selection
and the other selection which selects
things best the user doesn't know either
way this is actually a great point where
did the user choose so because they we
cannot have a content they will not be
involved with the technical discussion
because they just pick a browser or they
pick a service provider and if they pick
a service provider they get the box
image or the the Italia DNS with that
because they picked that company to
provide their Internet services and in
the future we will say we're going to
move that choice from picking a provider
to picking a browser but it's still a
choice and it's still a choice where you
actually only voted by who they're gonna
pay or which software they're gonna
download it's not a very informed choice
well most unfortunately most choices of
the user are not well informed I suspect
that many users don't even clearly make
a difference between the ball zone and
ISP so it's a big problem for security
and privacy for everyone but for the
specific case of the DNS because we are
in the DNS dev woman it's even worse
because a DNS is something which is in
the infrastructure which is well hidden
so even we cannot already have we don't
have already informed consent when
people through the boss own ISP and very
often they don't have a choice anyway so
it's DNS is even worse which means up in
the meantime we have to take our
responsibility we have to decide by
ourselves because we cannot reasonably
ask the user to the shop but for the
future we still need to explain to the
user to explain so that they can in the
future when people will be better
informed at least know what why we did
that like that ok that we do this really
hardly use it to make this decision
because they won't know they will never
know so you have to make up this
decision for them but I would add to
that yeah we can discuss Dalton though
exactly how much dot traffic can we see
today that depends on your system being
set up for that not basically not used
today at all
so right now we can offer a browser
let's say there's a billion Windows
computers out there they can only run
that browser today I mean theoretically
and they could use though tomorrow so
that's also and I think that's also
something to take into account that's
all much easier to deploy
there's a question here from the
audience yeah rather more a comment I
need think the user is not making their
choice here they're choosing their
provider but not making thinking about
this particular problem so indeed
actually we on behalf of the users have
to make that choice or at least pick a
same default so what would be a good
default in my opinion I think the more
local you've resolved it it's better to
adapt for that community rather than
picking something that is very
centralized that has to cover all users
with all different ideas on how to do
things so I guess the question could be
what is the good default here thank you
very much
I don't know what choice is a very Lord
of the world for most people don't
choose really see ISP very often they
have no choice on even if they do
basically is out all the same so there
is often very little difference not a
real choice now for the for the doe
client what is the same default I know
that systemd for instance use a t-888 as
a default which is certainly by ID
privacy wise at the present time
unfortunately there is no way to have a
proper default here but one of the
reason is that we don't have enough
dough providers one of the biggest
mistakes in a video uberta talk before
was to confuse the dough protocol with
the dough services today the big door
services are CloudFlare go girl on the
fusers not not a lot but though itself
as a protocol you can talk though with
any anyone if you are if you want to
talk though with I don't know XS for all
the dope for a server when they will
have one you can do it so really the
issue now is to write more software to
though servers on to deploy them so we
have a real choice so we have a lot of
those servers but when Vittorio Berta
was talking about concentration it it
has nothing to do with dough in the same
way that the dominance of gmail has
nothing to do with the SMTP protocol I
mean you can use dough to talk with
anyone on then users will really have a
problem of a choice which though server
with dough is over to use but at today
the problem is that there is no choice
that only a few providers are basically
all the same gaffar us company etc so
that's the first thing we should address
I believe brief I think this panel will
agree that DNS over HTTP as a protocol
is not the thing we're worried about it
is we worried about what would people do
with that and that moves it onto the the
dough provider selection power DNS runs
adult server we out of nothing we got
thousands of users many of them in
Indonesia because it turns out
Indonesian government blocks large parts
of the internet also blocks all the
large Dell providers but apparently we
are small enough that we fit in the
Indonesian window of opportunity sorry
but-but-but-but to brief you briefly
round up my remark the big question
isn't gonna be if we think though as a
service is a good thing how are we gonna
make sure that users actually get a good
choice and that they get presented with
that choice and on that front there is
some bad news because there's a whole
bunch of Dell providers that have been
aching to get into the modular program
and it's not working the phone calls are
not getting returns there are mysterious
privacy arrangements there are secret
contracts that cannot be shown and if we
are serious that having more dull choice
is good the browser vendors that are
offering us this dough button this dough
recommendation should have a transparent
program that says these these are the
constraints under which you can become a
dough provider if you have the following
attributes we will gladly list you and
and maybe we'll even give you a score in
terms of your privacy commitment and
other stuff with what we can not have is
the browser vendors as a gatekeeper
sitting there in California and saying
well you can be part of the program
but you cannot be part of the program
that is a big problem
thank you that start in the back after
each other why didn't you get a more
agile moderator sexy Stefan covered my
initial question but what do what do you
all think of something where if there's
an existing ISP resolver that is
configured and it turns out that the
browser or application can determine
that it also supports DNS over TLS or
Dana separate GPS to automatically
upgrade to using that does anybody have
unhappiness with that you won't
recognize me in an hour unhappiness no
no I think that's again that goes back
sure that's opportunistic that's good
that'll keep us from all the passive
eavesdropper everywhere in the spies and
you'll take us a huge step forward so
yes that's good and there's a draft
going on with basically that idea but if
we still come back to the case that yeah
that's your ISP but what about FOSDEM
here right
what's who's telling you which serve it
is today it might have be my computer
that handed out the server and then you
talk to my computer instead so doing it
opportunistically yeah going to save us
from the passive attackers not the
active ones and that's a tricky question
I don't have any answers actually to do
it in a in a good way
Stefan why are I'll be with you in a
second well why are so many people
scared of their ISPs spying on them is
that a differentiation that is made on
the American continent North American
continent respectively in Europe or is
it generally also here a problem in
Europe that people are scared of their
ISPs spying on them it's not only dying
it's also modifying the request like in
the Indonesian case or like it is
mandatory in most European countries in
most European countries is PR compelled
by law to load to lie about some domains
for reasons of file-sharing
promotion of television etc etc so the
spying it's the biggest problem with
spying it's of course it's very
difficult to know if you are really
spied upon or not it leaves no trace but
I can notice that a few years ago I was
at a big meeting in France on the
representative for the number one I spin
friends complained that because of the
rise of encryption that no longer can
see the user traffic on he was also
winning that
gaffur can still see it because of the
endpoint so apparently there is really a
news in DNS traffic on the unlike what
has been said we are not protected by
laws like the GDP ah because the Data
Protection Authority today are already
overloaded with HTTP issues and they
don't care about the DNS I spend a lot
of time with a French Data Protection
Authority trying to motivate them about
DNS privacy and it was impossible
first because DNS is an infrastructure
that most people don't see and don't
care about second because now they have
enough work with HTTP so they don't wish
to have something more to do so spying
is a real problem on data manipulation
is also one one of the reason why people
switch to a 38-year with any user forum
where users help themselves the blind
leading the blind the often most of the
time it's I cannot see this site because
it's censored so switch to 888 on you
will be happy on the second cases
failure a problem one of the biggest one
in France was when the number one ISP a
loaded instead of the normal black list
of Ottawa Western domains the loaded
test list including Google on Wikipedia
so every visit of Wikipedia Google was
redirected to a web page of the
government saying hey you are a bad guy
you try to visit our website so after
this a lot of users switch to 8 8 8 8
and it will be very hard to convince
them that the local ISP following local
laws is better thank you very much at
least pornhub was not blocked at that
day
you said something about how is this
list of the DLH providers vetted
couldn't they use probably something
similar what they use with certificate
authorities will course it that I mean
that could be done some but then you
would just pour it over to the users
that your are twelve different providers
pick one and everyone will go with the
default anyway like they do with search
engines and that's economy that powers
the entire internet today so sure we can
do that and everyone will use the
default so who's going to be the default
the one who pays the most right because
that's what we do already with the
search engine so I'm sure it could be
done but is that I don't know and be
better than today instead of let's
encrypt it's let's TNS let's DNS or
something sure that could be I mean you
could have it let's go over for the
public driven maybe as I said the good
solution is to have a large number of
possible addo providers for the user it
will mean that the choice will be
difficult and we don't have an easy way
to prison to the users are differences
so let's try something wide may be
asking the application also to choose a
door with over at one them in order to
suppress the Loden but if we do if we do
something like that then you have the
problem of split DNS things like
internal zones which can't be found
external zones which can't be found VPN
etc etc well whole whole mass of new
problems would arise so I'm actually one
of the people with that problem so I run
the o H exclusively on my browsers for
the past few months and it breaks my VPN
because at the moment I turn on my VPN
I'm still using my doe server and it
doesn't see inside the VPN so we are
making choices on behalf of users to
make their life better which is nice but
we're actually in the process also
breaking some of the stuff that they may
be relying on on working so it's not
that clear-cut that it's that is always
an improvement
better keep the microphone please the
the quads what I call the quads the
court 8 called one quad nine etc are
getting quite a bit of DNS traffic from
all of the world and they don't seem to
stop advertising or desiring that people
actually use them why are they doing
this I'm sure they're doing I'm sure
they're not doing it for my good
I would I would love to give Warren the
opportunity to say something right now
so it's okay I'll manage I won't faint
oh dear I'm just like thinking what all
my lawyers are saying now
so yes the at least the Google eight
eight eight eight one it's not doing it
for purely altruistic reasons I will
happily tell you and I know this for a
fact it does exactly what it says on the
privacy policy it's not mining it for
stuff etc go read the privacy policy the
reason that Google provides a day date
is it makes things go faster people who
have Foster internets use the internet
more people use the internet more see
ads more people you see ads more make us
more money so yeah it's not done just
out of the goodness of anybody's hot a
ISP resolver especially in some
countries just sucks
a day a day is faster one one one one is
faster having people use those is better
having people not be censored is better
so you know people use the internet
people see ads people click on ads
Google makes money the ads for thank you
the ads for quad eight I can understand
but what about a quad one or quad nine
what somebody like that answer that
question well we the this has been
discussed before but so and I can't
speak for any one of them but sure go
read their privacy policy what they do
with the data but I think a man over
there can speak for one of them at least
what's your toes yeah hi Christian
I work on DNS for CloudFlare on the
resolver team there and we do it for
very much the same reasons that Google
does but of course we don't make our
money from ads but I make it we make it
from our paying customers would pay for
our other services and what we do is we
make their domains faster as well so if
people are using our resolver to resolve
our customers domains they get a really
really fast answer and as Warren said
people that used to get a faster
response used internet more and they use
our customers services thank you very
much Apple fast are there definite --iv
I've had that question asked me several
times I'll give it to Daniel are there
definitive measurements have definite of
measurements been done as the
performance as to the fastness of dough
versus local unfold yeah I mean when I
worked at Firefox we did a lot of
experiments and we've got a lot of crap
for our attempts to actually figure this
out but okay yeah of course though is
slower than your native resolver in many
cases but in the tail and you gain a lot
but because the worst cases become much
better so it's yeah it's a balance
do you it's a penalty of course because
you get added privacy and encryption but
it's slightly slower responses and then
I know there's also this bigger concern
yeah but what about getting the wrong IP
back right so maybe you get bad or kia
sort of that's not a correct server
you're downloading your huge files from
so maybe that isn't added and I know
there's been tests going on with that
too but I don't know their final outcome
how exactly the penalty is thank you I
have a question here
so for very long time people said you
can't run your own resolving your
machine because it's too slow and now
I've changed to that the average
resolver at least the worst case
scenario is also toast loaf so we should
show this other alternatives though
because it is faster than the slow
alternative but it's slow in average why
is the first options now still Belgium
is just run young it's Oliver and have
it encrypted for normal ways it's not
just better Thank You Stefan well first
evaluating the speed performance of a
reservoir is very difficult because it
depends if it's in cash or not in cash
it depends on the authoritative
nameservers when it's not in cash it
depends on whether you are interested in
the latter case or the worst case so I
wouldn't I will not talk about
performance it's too difficult now for
the point of view of privacy having your
own wizard on your own machine which is
probably something very easy for most of
the people in the room it's it's not
very good for privacy because in that
case request to authoritative
nameservers will be from your own
address not even the address of the
resolver from the point of view of
control having exactly the resolution
you want the filtering you want on I
don't want my DNS resolver to claim that
this or that is a malware or thing like
that I want them to tell the truth not
to modify anything so for the point of
view of control having a local with over
on your Moschino at least on your
network I invite everybody here to go to
Caesar Tourism now booth here at for
them it's a router which is also DNS
resolver which that you control you are
wood on it you can do whatever you want
with it and you can filter what you want
and something that is P don't do on the
DNS resolver if they were doing my will
the will they would filter Google
Analytics that come first so
the choice of having your own wizard on
your own machine on your own network is
not of use there is performance there is
privacy there is control on the three of
them and may be difficult to get
together a good solution would be
probably two of your own resolver
locally validating locally but also when
they don't have the data in the cache
that they could ask another with
although with doe for instance to get
the information it's not difficult
technically years to be already does it
so it's probably the it could be the
future thank you very much we have
another tuna for something minutes I
think any questions from the audience
Peter why is everyone concerned with the
data transmission for me as an end user
to the first DNS server and not with an
encryption of for example the resolver
to all thoughts of name server so those
for the last mile and what about what
about the rest of the miles Daniel I
think we are concerned about that but I
think that's I mean yeah sure we need
that encrypted to so they found wrote
the draft about that and we really want
that to work we are all pro encryption
we want to have that happen but the very
interesting strange thing is that a
resolver that is used by a million
people is in itself a privacy mixing
device because you no longer know who
made that lookup or not so it is
important to encrypt all the things and
we want that I'm very happy else to hear
Warren remark that we have been
stimulating the service provider
community to say please turn on DNS over
TLS on on your visa offers because more
modern Android phones will now attempt
to use it for you more encryption is
good we need to have that and
simultaneously you can actually benefit
from these million users resolver for
being a privacy mixing device
assuming you don't stand your client
subnets