thank you Brian so thank you very much
everybody for waking up so early and
coming to this session I know it's very
difficult myself I had some problems
this morning to wake up because you know
it's fast and so Saturday night
generally you do stuff interesting with
friends and you remember that you were
code by Brian to say hey you need to
give a talk tomorrow morning or oh I
proposed my name so sorry if it's not
exactly the same topic by the way we can
talk about the original topic because I
have plan for that and it's a topic
which is also interesting the relevance
of Linux distribution at the era of
docker containers it's something that we
can address hopefully I will cover it a
bit but if you have questions on those
topics if you have concerns and raise
your hands and we will try to do our
best to answer those points so let's
start so my name is Bruno Connick I'm
working for harbor manufacturer I won't
give the name here because they didn't
want to support my travels this time so
I will use my my association name to
present the topic here I've been doing
Linux and stuff for the last 25 years
and I'm part of different upstream and
downstream projects and for this talk
and particularly the constant because
I'm a measuring a packager and I had
some development to do to be able to
package more easily at the container era
ok so let's start with a few reminders
so that everybody is on the same page
containers are just compared to
hypervisors or bare metal environment
already really near to the bare metal
infrastructure the only stuff which is
different from the bare metal
infrastructure is that you have the
engine which is managing the notion of
containers here and which is just a thin
layer that you put on top of
applications so you put an environment
which is suitable to isolate the
execution of your application if you
want so you have namespacing of C groups
which are set up by
away by default on your operating system
and here in a in a container context
that the container engine which creates
those environments of execution for the
application before launching the
application so no specific overhead
because anyway the kernel is doing the
job that you use it on the bare metals
that you don't use it on on a container
environment at the same same cast for
launchings applications just see the
fact that you have an isolated
environment is what is of interest to to
us in this context so I would talk about
darker because I've started using darker
and adding darker to the maggia
distribution three or four years ago
something like that three years ago and
it applies to other type of containment
engine of course some stuff or typical
to darker some other stuff are really
generic to two containers environment so
the idea is really to pack everything
together to give you a way a new way of
delivering application to your users 40
years ago you were using tar and a
script in the tar file and you were
delivering your application to your
customer exactly to you users like that
after the Linux revolution you had more
clever way of doing that which are
called packages and we are in the
distribution dev room so people building
distributions or really keen to make
packages to create a suitable
environment for delivering application
taking care not only of the application
itself and the right place where it
should be the river along the system so
having a start up which is a linux on
our base which gives you all the
directories in which you need to install
your software the logs are involves the
application is under us are you have et
Cie for the configuration files etc etc
so this is standardized this is taking
off this is taking care of by the
distribution management system and the
distribution management system is also
creating support for the dependencies
for the build dependencies of the
software and for the installation
dependencies
of the software which is a big advantage
so that's one of the element Y using
distribution is still relevant
compared to choose a darker environment
so Dhaka came and said ok there is a new
way of packaging applications you can
have these apps in the box that we had
in the previous in the previous slide
and everything inside that set box
inside that context can be shipped
easily to another platform and run
easily on another platform so that's
really the approach they had is bundle
everything the approach is to say ok if
you have one process you want to run you
will create one container so if you have
an application which is comprised of
seven different demons running together
working together then you would like to
create seven different containers images
and seven different containers to host
them it's working with layers and I will
detail that in in the next slide you
have the notion of image and the notion
of container which is an instantiation
of the image which is readwrite in which
you can work where has the images is
read-only itself you have additional
features so if you want to share your
images um to distribute your images
especially inside your environment or
outside you have the notion of registry
that's what the people from docker run
on the docker hub so when you do a
docker search for an image it's
interacting with the registry it's
trying to find an image which has the
name that you gave and it gives you a
list of dozens of different images
corresponding to what you are looking
for you can do exactly the same
internally you can have so private
registry as well to allow the sharing of
images which is like on distribution
when you do repositories in your
distribution and you manage packages
inside the repository and you share the
packages through repositories they
created solution of docker file so this
one is linked to docker which is the
received to create the image so you want
to have instructions that helps you
build an image on regular base you can
replace it's like the make file for
building an application it's a receipt
to build the docker image
inside the image everything is volatile
so when they contain your dies you lose
everything sold off it stolen on your
desk in the lair but you lose everything
so you won't you have permanent
information stored in volumes which can
be mounted from the host inside the
container or you can use network
attached volumes if if you need that
inside the container you are completely
isolated from the world so you need to
specify which ports you want to make
available to the outside world so if you
run one demon inside a an image you want
to expose the part of that network
service to the outside so that it can
communicate with the outside world the
goal is to you is if you remember Java
provides its write once run everywhere
so it's pretty the same on the docker
container image it's create once run
everywhere on a given OS you cannot
really mix and match between different
oasis the stuff I have not written here
on the slides that you have a standard
describing images which is your CI and
it gives you the possibility to use the
same image content with different
implementation of container engines so
we can take a docker image and run it
run it with racket or CR you when you
want to orchestrate stuff you go a bit
upper in the stack you have the notion
of composition you can create EML files
to give to your engine the information
on how to launch the container how to
instantiate the container from the image
so which type of volumes you want to
attach which have a port you want to
expose which type of environment
variables you have which type of
networks you have all that stuff that
you can pass on the command line to the
Dierker command you can also store it in
a yeah Mel file - and give that yeah Mel
try to someone else and you have the
docker compose at the layer which will
create all the
the containers from the description
based on the device image that you have
so H a layers is a swarm of kubernetes
that you can use everything is using a
REST API even the command line interface
tool so they always discuss with the
dark demon on your system using the REST
API it's developed in go and the
composition is really we developed in in
Python and Streisand's and there's yet a
cheapie v20 so I said in the previous
slides are there is a layered approach
this is how it's working so everybody is
using the same channel on your host
there is no difference there is no
kernel inside the container image so if
you go inside a container image and you
use a you name command to look at what
is it it's a camera running below on
your host system it's not a camel coming
with the image that does not mean
anything because it's just an isolation
of processes so you have the same kernel
it's launching different stacks default
application but it could be a process
that you run on your system or it could
be a process that you run in a container
on your system is the same then on top
of the kernel once you have created that
and you have your C groups and name
space available as feature of your
kernel to be able to enable those those
type of working environments you have
the notion of image so the image is a
read-only part of the solution and you
can create as many layers as you need to
reach a point where you are happy with
your image you can have something as
simple as just a buzzy bugs binary that
could be your image so you execute
darker you create an instance based on
that image and you will be in an
environment where you just have the
visible binary and you have the 100
something commands that the busybox is
providing to you in a very small
footprint environment that's one way to
deal with it you can use a very small
distribution like the taco guy develop
Alpine which is very small Linux
distribution to provide a strict minimum
of environment that you
you have something which looks like a
Linux environment because busybox is
really really small or you can put a
full distribution or normal distribution
the minimum set of that distribution so
for measuring a distribution it would be
200 something packages for Federer's the
same for debian maybe a bit less okay so
you have the possibility to really
create a small layer which is the base
of your distribution and on top of your
distribution you can install packages
using your own normal mechanism so if
you're on Debian you do dpkg install you
do if it'll get installed if you're on
federal you do DNF install if you're on
my show you do Europe EMI but that's the
same approach you just use native tools
that you have on your distribution to
build the contacts that you want to have
you can add scripts you can add binary
as you can do
people install you can do NPM install
you can do whatever you want
inside and that's isolated and once you
have once you are happy with the results
of your building viability of the image
and the running environment then you can
instantiate one version which will be
the container in which you will have the
right the right to write in it modify
stuff and that's what will be that's
where we'll be running your application
on top of it any question at that point
is it obvious for everybody okay good
so why do you want to use distribution
packages with distribution and packages
inside the distribution with containers
on VM and that probably was what the
original speaker was intending to cover
more so first why do you want to run
containers because you already have a
distribution well what you want is it's
not necessary polluting your
distribution with a ton of stuff that
you want to test in a dedicated
environment especially when you do stuff
like JavaScript no GS type of stuff
where very few distributions have
package so we'll stack that you would
need to develop that does not exist
under an OPM format or that format
because it's really
moving target you would need thousands
of dependencies when you do npm install
of something you you get ten thousand of
different modules installed through the
network that's a huge work for a
distribution and most of the
distributions that just package the OGS
itself so you can do NPM install and
then the rest is not package because
it's moving too fast it's not possible
to keep up with that it's not a case of
some other languages you have a lot of
perl modules a lot of Python modules a
lot of Java modules as well which are
available under a package format so you
can benefit from the work of the
distribution people to have a career old
set of packages but false moving target
like no GS it's really something where
you want to isolate it from your native
distribution because you don't want to
install on a distribution something
which is not packaged why because it
creates I mean the manual installation
compared to package installation is a
direct way to create problems in your
environment because you may have stuff
in the startup place and you may have at
the same time the same stuff in a
non-standard place in under us are local
for example if you just do configure
make make install for a good new
software it will by default arrive in us
a local and then you will have binaries
in us a local bean and binary the USR
bean and you don't know which version is
which and sometimes you don't point to
the right configuration file because you
have multiple instances so really if you
want to have a serious execution
environment and also build environment
you need to be very clear off what you
do and and identify clearly where you
need to use non packaged environments
such as no GS for example compared to
packaged environment the advantage that
containers bring like VM you are not
polluting or you're running environments
you create an isolated place where you
can do everything you want at the end is
just in that environment and that's
something you can send to someone else
for tests or whatever so that's
something you should be able to rebuild
easily so doing it with VMs you should
automate the creation of the VM and the
operating system deployment in it and
the installation of your application in
it etc it's easy
with containers and with VMs but that's
the same approach you want to be able to
easily scratch and redo your running
environment execution environment if you
have problems and so it's easier with
docker file to do that and to address
that and to rebuild on on a regular base
your docker images to be really
up-to-date containers also bring
something which is useful and that I'm
using and that's the goal of the talk in
fact you can have on a seal Linux
distribution tons of other distributions
available to make your test so you can
automate the portability of your
application in different running
environments in different distribution
you can package for different
distribution your software so that it's
installable natively for the people
using packages from the distribution so
it's a real and easy way to distribute
form for other distributions that's the
one you have or for a I mean I'm running
the years 1/6 version of Nigeria which
is the last stable version it has more
than one 1/2 here now and we will assume
seven in a couple of months but I don't
want to run a non stable distribution I
use my my laptop to work and I mean
working with a development distribution
is prone to right my ability to work
very often so I prefer to isolate the
test I do on the development
distribution in specific environments
such as a container and that's the goal
compared to using native list
development environment and having the
compiler as a compiler broken for a
couple of weeks because there are stuff
that we need to put in place when we
move from one version to another etc
another advantage of containers with
regards to VM so that it's very easy to
share your home directory with use with
the container so you can attach when you
launch your instance of a container from
the image you can set you to that attach
my home directory and put it in the home
directory of the container environment
so that I'm at home and I can use all
the files that I need to work in my
environment which means for example that
allows you to share if you're on the
opium based distribution all of the
configuration files that are needed to
build packages correctly so up here
macros or p.m. RC you can also keep a
look on your SSH keys I have I have my
SSH key in the build system of measure
to be able to push back edges and ask
for the build system to to recreate the
packages I've tested locally you can do
the same or is also distribution as well
what I do is really generic it's not
linked to material itself the only way
it's the only place where you really
need the VM compared to a container to
do that isolation is if you need a
different kernel between what you are
running and what you want to test that's
the only only place where it's important
for people like me were doing packaging
most of the time I don't care I can use
a native kernel of my distribution to do
the packaging I am packaging for 120
different distributions the software I'm
upstream for without any problem due to
the difference of channel ins on the
host and inside the packaging
environment so that's really feasible so
how do you deal with that concretely so
you have the docker registry or you have
your whole new registry or you have your
own local images you have a set of
images that you can put on you on your
environment you create those images
using a docker file I will show you the
content of the doctor file just after
and every time you need to test
something in a different environment
than the one you are running you
instantiate a container for the
distribution which is your target and
inside the container you're building
packages that then you can send to your
distribution repository either using
subversion or get sources depending on
the distribution and the package
management system of your distribution
okay so maybe I should turn around and
show use a real file instead of them so
the one on the slides for people who
want you have a look
after all the presentation but I should
be able to show you something else here
which is a real one okay okay so I have
a way to capture some parameters as
input which is not really important I
have a configuration file that they can
use to pass some variables and have
default variables available in my
environment
here's whose version of the of the
materia distribution target temporary
directory the mirror that I can use to
download the dependencies working
directory the architecture on which I'm
working because I can also build for
different type of of architectures there
is a very convenient project in QEMU
which allows you for example to run on
the NYX 86 machine non x86 binaries as
if you were in an virtualization
environment except that you are not
utilized your imagine a VM your viateur
risings the instruction set but you're
not in a VM so I'm I started to I go to
just a raspberry to make some tests was
he another architecture to see if it was
working here that seems to be very
interesting so I get my microphone my
UID each Eid because I want to map those
inside the container and then I write I
generate a docker file here I start from
what I call it magic official repository
which is in fact local to my system so
those are my local root images for the
distribution I can show you if we have
time how it's built
the first thing I do is I adapt my
distribution inside the ears the image
when I deal the image I say I want the
latest version of every package that I
need then I I can okay that's not that's
kind
then you install all the dependencies
that you need in your environment so I
hope that the repositories and then I
install all the dependencies packages
that have been updated since the last
time and I install in that environment
because I'm building packages the set of
packages I need to build packages so
there is a BM command which does a build
through RPM build materia is using
subversion for configuration files and
stuff like that we have the amici a repo
command which is the interaction with my
GI official repository and the launch of
the build interaction with the build
system of Nigeria and some other useful
- like a caliph and see you because I
want to be able in my build environment
so when you're building packages for for
a distribution never build as route
that's if you if you take something out
of this this talk has never built as
route in stand up because when you're
building a package you don't know what
you are launching you are packaging this
set of software which is coming from
upstream and those guy made you remove
files etc if you don't set up the right
environment viable you will remove fries
in a place where you don't expect to
remove them so never run as root run as
a single user so that's why is there is
some magic here to create the user in
the container image associating the
right so right you ADT IDs it's like
it's not useful anymore and giving to
that user should you the right to see
you in the container and without any
password to be able to launch some
commands as root when you need them but
not when you don't need them and you do
you do that on purpose so every all the
build is done as a single user but
sometimes if you want for example to
install the build packages on your
environment then you will need a root
access to be able to write in the
package database that you want to
install package and then I create the
home directory of that user I say that I
will be in a walk tier which is my the
place where I have my my measure
environment
I run the container as a user not as
root and I launch a bash command
and the rest is just some small pup -
detectives there is already a container
if I falls I can remove the previous
image to rebuild an image and then I
just run so this is a line which is
creating the instantiation from the
image so here we are building the image
with that received once the image is
build you instantiate an environment you
say I want to remove that environment
and the end of the run
I want to map my I want to be able to
SSH correctly from my doctor cotton
environment so I need to make some stuff
was the was a socket inside the
environment and set up the SSH socket
inside the environment to the same place
where it is outside so I can communicate
using my SSH agent which is already
installing my system I just want to
mount my home directory under my home
directory inside the container and I use
the image which is tagged like that
which is the name of what we are
creating here in the in the receipt so
how does it work so here I'm running on
a media 6 and I can create of course
emoji a six environment as well so by
default by default so I didn't realize
anything this morning so I cannot let me
just
[Music]
let me just restart the daka diamond
because I may change some stuff since
yesterday
let's try again so I have a certain
number of images that's why it takes a
bit of time so there is there it's there
is a couple of images and you see there
are a lot of different distributions
that I use to build to have different
environments to be able to build
different software correctly so that's
why it takes a bit of time is it better
now
not still not know such holes so I may
have lost my network which is here where
is my mouse here
yeah I have no Nolan
so can I use it false time nigga see ya
the first m1
okay should be better better here
then such objects
oh yeah right
those songs swim you
okay
so the difference of
six-six-six 64
that's a - you know it should be before
I'm not pointing to the right image i I
miss the architecture here okay so here
where I am am I
I am in a container which has been
instantiated from the image which is
here you see it's a prompt change of
course from that perspective here it's
still image a a six environment but this
one has 232 packages where has my native
distribution has 3000 packages so I'm in
a completely new different environment
it's a fresh measure at 6 environment
which has this minimum set of packages
that you need to have to run the command
which can install additional packages so
that's what you want to have you have a
bare minimum distribution on which you
you are able to use if it's a deviant
distribution apt-get if it's a measure
yeah your PMI if it's a fedora DNF
that's just what you want you to be able
to do because that plus the network
configuration correct so that you can
touch your repositories and download
content from the repositories so where
your here so the stuff which is also not
right is that I'm routing that
environment I should not be rude I
should be I should be a single user yeah
so
Yeah right so this is this is image so
this is the official image this is a one
I use as a base environment so this is
not the image I used to build my
packages I can do the same easily with
another version so if I use the color
inversion here I will be now in a
different environment which is a measure
yes seven version which has a different
set of packages only 219 so nice job for
the guy working on that because they
reduce the size of the minimum
distribution set from 2:30 to 2 to 19 so
we have less packages when we want to
create a small distribution with measure
7 release and here if you look all the
packages which are installed or mg a 7
where has of course here all the
packages which are installed on my
native system or mgs 6 so I have working
measure environment here which is
completely different that I'm pointing
to the development distribution I have
all the dependencies of the development
distribution I can really do what I want
in that environment easily let me try to
just fix that because sorry something
wrong here
you should never make changes well
that's not that's not very correct then
thanks that's not very bright so they'd
be for the distribution it's a
presentation
let me check because yesterday I was
building some stuff so so having my
environment normally this one for
example so if I go here in to this one
yeah which has the which has the
architecture that was the missing part
of my on my script script has not been
updated for Caesar so now I have an
image which is based on the previous
image so this is still the control
version version seven but this time I
have a bit more packages because in my
received so if you if we look at the
docker file that we have for example
where is presentation
so if we look at the daka fries that we
are using here in the presentation which
is which is the same in addition to the
standard distribution which has 219
packages I asked to add a couple of
additional commands to be able to work
so for example I should have the BM and
the mga repo
commander so let's go back here so here
here first I am a single user I'm not
root anymore I change the environment in
which I want to run and I have access to
the BM command
I have assets to the mga repo canal
which were not there before so and I am
placed in my in my directory Y where I
have all the packages I am following
from area that I can rebuild so let's
take for example something related to
docker has a docker compose I will do a
remove of everything which is not
relevant so all the intermediate build
stuffs here I just keep the sources and
suspect file which was a strict minimum
I need to build packages so for those
not really familiar with that maybe so
the spec file is again your received
which gives you the RPM system
instructions on how to build a package
for the distribution I'm running so it
gives you some dependencies at Build
time that you need to satisfy to be able
to build and as docker compose is a
Python script it needs a certain number
of Python modules to be able to build
correctly and then it will also indicate
some installation dependencies so if you
install the package on the distribution
you will need to satisfy those
dependencies around python modules
needed and then you have the receive to
be able to to build a software in your
environment so photo mushiya
distribution is as simple as doing VM
and of course it does not work not
because it's a demo because it's it's on
purpose I missed all the dependencies I
sure to use that there are build
here I don't have those if I do a p.m.
by grep Python I have a certain number
of Python packages typically what is
needed to build Python packages and the
Python 3 and 2 versions as well itself
but very few other packages just setup
tools is the only one I have for example
I don't have that I think it needs the
darker package the WebSocket client etc
so all those packages are not available
yet so I can set you my system okay I
need B to be a root because I want to
install additional packages and I want
to install the packages which are
mentioned in the spec file that I need
to have so it said okay I want I will
default to using bill requires so which
also bill requires that you need ok you
need a Piton darker package which one do
you want we say ok let's take the first
one and you have recommended packages or
optional packages so I say ok I don't
want to tell you too much my system so I
would say ok do not do not install the
recommended package is just the one I
really need to build so the list of
packages as dependencies which are
needed in my environment or those I will
say install so stop and hopefully if
there is a bit of network should be able
to download them which does not seem to
be the case
Wow
okay so maybe the mirror is having an
issue because I have the network here
let me check
this trip coffee yeah so I cannot touch
the mirror myself either on the web
browser so I need another mirror let me
try it
[Music]
so let's say okay this mirror is broken
does not want to deliver to me stuff
that's not a big issue well that's a
problem but that's not a big issue so I
will go in my configuration finally will
change the mirror okay let's do it the
other way around
so I will change the mirror all the
reference to the mural here inside the
configuration file to something which is
better which is a channel that all
mirror which should be working fine here
[Music]
all there is to this trip
okay this time should be a bit better so
let's try again
okay so when you deal with a mirror
which is up-to-date and available you
can download the dependencies to build
your software it installs them for you
so now you can build your package and
this time as all the dependency
requirements are satisfied then you can
build a package and you have in your
environment again all the directories
that have been created for example you
have the new package which is available
here which has just been built in my
environment which is clean because it
has been built using the magic cauldron
tools magical world dependencies
creating an mv7 version so everything is
completely safe from a build environment
and now I can just try to install it and
again it's looking at dependencies at
install time and it's okay for
installing that package you will need
those packages as a dependency so just
say yes it will download that some
additional packages and now you have the
package which is here and you can start
testing it in your environment because
it's working
so you have a strict minimum environment
to be able to make tests of one package
that you have built here which is
exactly what you want to do and I'm not
polluting as a rest of my system it's
completely isolated and I can do that as
many time as I want with different
distributions available
okay any question yes yes so generally
what happens by this tremendous is they
have a build system and on the build
system you have machine with all the
targets that you need to support what
you want to support so here I'm testing
on my local system I will check that
everything is working when I'm done I
can use them it's imaginary pokemon to
push my content choose a build system
pushing my content is just pushing the
subversion set of files that are under
control so in my case here is my mouse
again yes sorry so here is on the build
system the subversion tree that I'm
mural I'm a locally you can have a look
at the different stuffs that have been
that has been done from the system so
you see what happened to the life of the
package during its development you see
when you have modified to compose file
when you have to build massive build for
example for magic seven which happen
which change automatically a certain
number of stuff okay and when you are
happy with what you have so in your
environment what is important or the
sources directory and the spec directory
so the spec directory contains suspect
file that is mandatory to rebuild and
the sources directory contains of
sources of the various version I have
had during time of that component and
the sha-1 file checking
for the check some of the of the source
files so those are stubs that are in the
subversion repository on the repo at the
Magi build environment and when I launch
build for me the package it will go to
the build system extract from subversion
the write files do the BM command like
me on all of the target systems that you
need to support so it will be for x86 I
5 x86 which is a 32-bit version
um 7hl because we are not like Debian
because I see you have a demon t-shirt
so we are not as Debian maintaining as
many DS as many architectures that you
are maintaining of course and we have
less packages as well as d beyond repair
only 30,000 when they bein has 50,000
something like that so that's that's the
way it's done you you have so your
target system on the build
infrastructure that are used to build a
final system so your building stuff you
are testing it of course you may have a
software which is working nice on the
x86 I'm not working on arm and you will
not detect it through this process you
will detect it when your contributors
say hey it's broken on my on my version
and you you have the back Xilai you give
the architecture on which it's not
working and people will make tests on
that version if that not done that
before
that's way since the way it's done no
it's it's a dedicated system which is I
think using just fruits for due to - I
mean you don't change build system
easily that's that's one of the problem
so yeah that's a weights down
any other question how am i doing this
time okay so if there is no no other
question and leave you a bit of time to
change room and get another fantastic
presentation hopefully thank you very
much
[Applause]