okay so this this is an advertisement
for a document that I partly working on
and the this is a document is trying to
document what is required to have a
validator do his job not to document
what validators do because that's all
over the place and frankly one of the
reasons why I'm bringing this up is that
the authors we've been working on this
document slowly you'll see them a little
bit history in there but we don't we
amongst ourselves don't have total agree
with what needs to be in a document and
so we're trying to get the input from
those who sought document will will
impact which are the operators and the
implementers so that's the main reason
why I'm bringing this up here so this is
I'm not just trying to say come to the
IETF and comment on the draft I'll get
into that but we really want to have
some input for this document out here
and that the title of it is ITF style
draft MGL T DNS opt-in ASEC validator
requirements and oh seven is the latest
version of it now say the reason for
this bring us up there they're a bunch
of topics in here that we really we need
to get a broader set of input on I think
we have some disagreement internally
about what what should be said now the
history of document it's been around for
a long time which is usually the wine of
many documents in the ITF I look back to
see I was added as an author at some
point and I was added as an author in
March of 2017 which is months after I
decided I'd never go on the ITF again it
was kind of odd to be talking about
draft Brian said I'm not going to go
there anymore so I've not actually been
in the ITF since this documents had my
name on it
I do the document from the other author
who's been pushing this a bit more
actively hasn't quite gotten this to be
a DNS op Adina's operations working
group document an officially blessed
document but it's kind of been on the
edges of interests out there and again
the reason why it's kind of stalled is
that I you know I think the document
really needs to have a better audience
or better better input into what goes in
there obviously it's that that's what I
document exists so yeah this this may or
may not be a good document I think we
need to find out the author's need to
find out whether it's
keep pursuing this or not so I'm going
to make a plea here to have people take
a look at what's in this and inside the
draft we have these five topics that
that I'll go through one by one and talk
about kind of what's what's in the draft
but these are things we see our
externalities external pieces to the
validation process it's very tempting at
times to talk about how to validate data
we don't want to do that that's
elsewhere there's already defined
process but when it comes time to
writing the software that do the
validation what does it have to live
inside of number one topic we the lead
topic there is time DNS SEC requires
wall clock time and you know the RRS
SIG's have times in there that was there
because we don't want to have replay
attacks we have so that signatures can't
last forever otherwise what you say
today will be good forever no matter
what you do so it was interesting to me
that this was actually that one of the
first topics in the in the draft but not
every device out there does NTP I just
assume that being that I usually work in
those kind of systems but all these
other systems out there dude validation
will have to deal with the fact that
they don't know what time it is but so
they need it but they need to do that
for validation it's got to be in there
somewhere
the second part this part was the part
that drew me in and it says to do with
the trust anchors as a KSK roll over
we're always going to talk about part of
that next in in going through the
process of trust anchor or that the KSK
roll over for I can we begin to think
about what is in validators what is the
trusting or what is it it's like a data
store or database or data structure it's
what it's a data piece it's
configuration data and needs to be
managed appropriately and you know some
some of the tools out there really had
to up the visibility of what's in that
data for operators to be able to play on
the KSK roller so I was interested in
getting that document to make sure we
understood that it's as much a small
database a very small database but it
needs all the ways of inspecting it and
changing it one of the topics I find
more controversial is the idea of what
do you do when a key is is is kind of
revoked not not revoked in a sense that
we're pulling the key out but you
finally kita keys but it has been found
to be bad it was a bad key someone else
put the key in and so the real owner or
something
wrong and they want to pull the key back
out there in the draft it talks about
being able to go into the cache
identifying all the data that was
validated by that key and marking it as
bad data I'm a little skeptical that
that's workable because I know that
we've talked about that for years and
implementations of DNS SEC but again
this is something I we I think we need
to get input from the outside to see if
we can get the proper thing written into
this draft so that's one of the topics
in there which I think would help
getting input on and before it goes
forward a cryptographic code management
this is another topic which I think
could use some help where this talks
about having the validator try to talk
to the authority of server to get the
right cryptography going back and forth
I think we need help there
I don't yeah I have my opinions we have
other opinions in the group of people
putting it together but we need a better
idea of what should be said about that
or we're not set about that and finally
the the last topic which I've also found
to be something that's bothered me for
20 years on this when you have a DNS SEC
No what do you do with it how do you
report that do you just log the error
somewhere or do you try to alert the
operator the operator or someone up a
chain because sometimes these errors are
transient they come and go like if I
can't get a key because a timeout that
comes and goes I could be an outage type
of thing if I get if I keep getting the
wrong information then there's just
something else going on there you can
suspect from the validator why this went
wrong and we have to improve I think
what we can do with some of the out the
error because we all know the serve fail
our code serve fail is kind of that's
all we have but what can we do to do
better than that the logs going to
actually have more information about
what part of the validation chain went
wrong explain her that experiment and
that over the years I don't think we've
ever gotten there I think that would
help to with the validators valley
operas be more comfortable in operating
for example when do you put a negative
trust anchor and your log should tell
you you should try that maybe so those
are the topics we have in the paper
comments right now it's not you can go
to the ITF and talk about it there on
that mailing list there that's fine
generally the document like this is not
a working group document it's also good
to talk to the authors because you
office still have a have the they're
still writing the document and the three
email addresses are up there dan McCall
I say dammit Galt I've actually never
heard his name said he no I talked to
him face-to-face he's the primary author
it's under his name that he's done this
in four years myself and then Dan York
and ISC and III sock rather also has
been has his name on the document - he
could address a comment - those things
this is this you know let if you read
the Drock you mean you think this
document is not worth it say so
I mean I'm that that's a good thing to
hear you know nothing nothing like
working on something that nobody wants
you to do also a question I have is is
this document going to be helpful to
those who are writing code today do you
think that Valladares are done and we
don't need to worry about this or do you
think that this actually has a real open
field for being used by somebody and to
help you find a document the last part
has a title DNS Ike validate
requirements and then that's a link to
find the the current version a document
and you can read it there if you choose
to choose to do so so that's pretty much
the end of my talk about here all to put
that back up there and any questions I
mean if you have come I don't think
anyone here has comments about this I
don't think it was read the draft I'm
not gonna do that but if you feel that
need to say something about this let me
know it'd be really good if it's goes to
all the authors so we all hear what's
going on
you did it it died ok interested in the
reporting ok so the comment is to look
at the reporting and the fifth topic
there could be interesting what you do
with the four intelligence and so on
tracking what where the outages are okay
is that is that this is the extent error
reporting draft repeat the question
think Thank You Shane you stumped me how
now so the question has to do with they
look at do have you looked at the
ecstatic error reporting draft and
obviously no is that a is that country
on the in the protocol level of
reporting things or is that the
implementation I'll take well take a
look at that what I have in mind what I
have in mind and me as opposed to as not
all the authors was this is looking more
what the operator configuration logs
would have about what's going on
internally so so that that it's they're
both they're solving the problem in two
different areas so I'm not saying but
that's my my idea here was yeah log
files so so any other
I think okay that's a good point yeah
okay the suggestion is to look at the
title and say it's not the title ism is
Miss naming it requirements for validate
the the environment Realtors need to do
yeah
working on basically titling is what's
more accurate for what we're trying to
do yeah that's a good point
Thanks anywhere else I think looks like
[Applause]