one of the reason I did this though is
that in my current like day-to-day I
have to deal with kubernetes clusters
Linux machines and in general like
whatever happens in that clusters in
those clusters so it's a bit difficult
sometimes to understand things like we
create SAS database so one of the things
we need to know is for example how many
bytes have been written in that file
today and it's and it turns out that
it's not pretty straightforward that
these counting's so we started exploring
a bit about how can you shut those
information from the kernel and turn it
out that then some point we discovered
that there's this thing called if you
have saw myself like I didn't know about
it if you have like one year and a half
ago but had this opportunity to explore
a bit and so I wrap it up this tool to
tell everyone else about it so every PS
stands for extended vpf vpf is basically
a unique feature that lets you get some
information from the machine you're
running on using a Cisco it's
historically stands for Berkeley packet
filters so it seems to everyone that is
about just networking but it turns out
that it's not actually at Bethel is not
in Linux machines because it has been
extended to do many more things in this
context we are talking about BPF as a
tracing framework this is the use case
that was focusing on because they wanted
to extract the information from my
machines but he turns out that they can
actually be used for other things I will
tell a bit more about the other things
you can use also so that you know about
it
but it's not okay what I'm showing here
BPF is itself it's not about like
extracting informations or doing things
basically like instruments in the kernel
but is something that you can use that
you can use to instrument out other
other frameworks that are already in the
corner
right so for example the colonel has
some tracing back hands that you can use
static trace points key probes you
probes will you see them
so you basically use the BPF to access
those tracing frameworks VBF itself it's
not a tracing framework it is the tool
that you use to instrumentation
framework to go to the kernel and use
the tracing framework right
instead of going there like the kernel
module or with a Cisco you go there
using VPS one of those rating framers is
that was posted by the kernel is the
static trace points static trace points
are basically trace pantera fixed and in
the kernel that are ready there for you
to use they are defined if everyone can
see there's this folder where you can
see by basically printing a file where
you can see all the static race point
defined in your machine and those have
been defined by the kernel developers so
they are ready there they have their
arguments or returns and you can extract
information from them we will see out
after what's very interesting for
everyone on the other end is to be able
to define dynamic tracing
functionalities so those can be in the
kernel or in your user space programs
namely key probes in new probes so key
probes are is the McCain that lets you
extract information from the kernel so
you don't attach key probes on a binary
but your touch key probes on the kernel
itself so your key probe can be attached
to a kernel function for example if you
want to see as a the example I made
before how many bytes have written for a
file you have touch of EFS right the FS
right is the function that physical
calls in the kernel every time a file is
written so every fun everything in the
uses a file so that's it and the FS ntfs
read on the other end we do probes you
can attach to your programs functions
we will see that in a program that I
have it's called cattle day show cats
that I mean fun I mean in the main
package it's a good program it has a
variable it has a function that reasons
are variable that is an integer that is
the counter of the reverses that this
program received and it is in your space
and you can attach to it by attaching
the you probe and then there are 6 DP
it's this focus not about gtp but I want
to tell you every mortises x TP is
expressed data path and this framework
built on top of the PPF to allow you to
basically do bucket mangling and mail
your packets so you can do like you find
things like firewalls but it tell it it
allows you to do more than just like you
know reject the packets in kernel space
you can reject the packets directly in
the network cards so that you don't even
populate a task extract the socket
buffer struct for the packet that gives
you a great performance improvement
because the kernel didn't even process
the packet so this the biggest thing is
all about doing the processing of your
information
you
you've them in userspace there's some
there's a mechanism in the EPF that's
called Maps there are a wide set of maps
that you can use that basically allows
you to aggregate information kernel
level so that you don't overwhelm a user
space because the kernel can easily deal
with like thousands of packets for
example that you want to analyze but
it's better to not send them all of them
in user space if you just want to know
the bytes at the packet have been
written in ten seconds you can do that
internal space
the life cycle of a Nvidia program is
quite simple when you have seen it
initially it seems a bit crazy that you
have this situation but the idea is that
you have a program that is written for a
specific instruction set that is the BPF
assembly basically sunset that runs on
the vpf Delta machine the vpf virtual
machine is implemented in the kernel and
it has a thing called static very fired
that is a process in the kernel that
basically ensures that you don't kernel
panic this machine so as opposite to
write writing a kernel module that of
course gives you like more opportunities
in terminal customization from the
kernel any BPF cannot kernel panic your
nation or in general doesn't tell a
little bad things and this is both nice
thing but also bad thing because
sometimes you just want to do things and
it doesn't allow you but it's nice that
there's something looking at us and then
they be PFC scold there so basically you
have this a BPF byte so that you can
compile with for example clank as a
back-end that's called vpf so you plan a
meet BPF and you basically can write a c
program that means if you have
programmed and then with the cisco BPF
you load the program all this thing
seems crazy
but there are higher level of programs
that lets you do things and then by
passing these argument to the VP of
Cisco you load the program the SATA
query file reads a program be sure that
everything is ok and then the VP of
Cisco WPF diem understand which profit
what kind of tremendous is a keeper by
you progress static response whatever
and if it's the case that the program
registers itself to a map that it's what
lets you get information back a user
space is basically your communication
medium to get out like for example you
buy contract is a thing right
you called implement contract with this
with a VPS and to get back the
information from contract for your own
contract you will have to use a map that
gives you a stream of the connection
that would been open and the masters
part there says if your program are not
doing complete so basically you cannot
you cannot do loops so that's because of
the city to verify it doesn't allow you
to do that but if your loop is for
example like to like you have a list of
server a lot list of IPs for your your
network interface that you have to
control these kind of things if it's a
fixed loop that you have to do like it
has a set of elements you already know
how to compile time you can now roll the
loop with a pragmatic or for example or
you can just write down 10 times 3 and
what about today I mean saying that this
thing is pretty crazy some of you know
this I started doing this talk one year
ago and well maybe it's because it here
is false then so the people that come
here are more like on the edge of this
kind things especially for the Linux
kernel but in general no one knows what
are the application today one of the
most common is TCP dump who use this
year TCP dump or using it everyone
basically not your there but they see
you
tissie freedom is program that lets you
basically dump stuff it dumps out the
packet that you're receiving in this
machine or a specific network interface
you're pointing to the TCP dump program
then using here basically gets all the
IP packets and happy before and TCP and
on port 80 so this will be HTTP traffic
and if you pass the D parameter to TCP
dump it comes out the BPF program that
it's loading to do that so TCP dump
actually uses maybe a program even if
you didn't really see them so BPF are a
mainstream thing now even if maybe you
are not yet like implementing them in
your programs there's rare thing for
everyone and the things that dumps out
here is the instruction set that it's
you the the portion of destruction said
that this is using and if you look at it
it's basically like a reflection of the
RFS implementation right so these two
instructions mean is this an eternity
before packet I don't do this thing like
automatically so like if I will not have
written this year I will no no but I did
the math at home and protesting so and
is SRC X plus 14 on port 80 so 15 extra
decimal and same thing for the situation
so since I didn't specify here SRC 80
and destination 80 this is a sure
assuming that it's always say T and it's
basically adding two instructions but
for source and buffer decision who uses
kubernetes containers docker whatever
raise your hands one of the main one of
the main the main
basically isolation isolation technique
that contain runtime uses to basically
allow you to share your kernel between
your container and the O's machine is
second second what does succumb to
basically like if you go to the doctor
repo you will see it an obvious actually
different now you will see that it has a
predefined set of rules that basically
doesn't allow you to CAPTCHAs admin so
you don't become network administrator's
or niskin things and it turns out the
sacrum has an EVP of subsystem that you
can use to define your own like rules as
compared to like because the complex you
like just define rules a block this is
called block this is called block this
cisco but turns out that with the BPF
subsystem you can actually write write
your own rules if process ID is odd
block the cisco by these kinetics
probably the use case I just told it's
probably a bit silly but it's something
you can do and in this situation I just
compiled this program here and the
program I did is printing later and then
oh and then it is solving a filter with
this function I defined here as you can
see I'm basically writing using a DSL to
write a BPF assembly here you're not
need you don't really need due to that I
didn't really know what I was doing yeah
I took to me so much to laugh with that
thing but it turns out that like I could
have written this in C and compile with
Clan and copied it here and it's
basically the process that I used but I
really want to be very cool and right
there there's only so that what city
and then basically I load that hello
that beef your program is a comp with
those instructions and this filter is
installed in the NI right so I'm
blocking all the right so everything and
on this architecture and I give back any
perb when you try to right so everything
I'm gonna right after this second preju
stration is gonna be denied so I just
started that program I made with us
trace just to see and the first call
went okay and all the others just gave
it back and exited the program
what are more practical examples trace
file open by filename everything a bunch
of them go runtime events for XDP
firewalls and pattern rewriting trace
commands and in a bash shell write a key
logger whatever you want to write one of
the use case I use a lot these since our
for influx trace clearly done against
the database like I don't do the core of
influx EB so I don't really know where
to I don't really want to mangle with
their cold because the core engineers
don't allow me but I really want to set
so I just load on a VPS program to see
what's happening yes it's crazy
and no one's want ready to do all of
that this statement is probably to
another conference is not a fault so our
level EP is are not fit for most people
but let's see them anyway an interesting
project is a visor go BPF if you are a
good programmer you might want to just
load your BPF program using go actually
go BPF is
basically a binding that lets you load
EPF programs and compile them and load
them so you just provide the C program
as I did here like I you to read file
bash redline see I will go to that
program a second or you can give gob EPF
the program ready compile the difference
is that if you ask Bob if you have to
compile the program in the target
machine you will need to have the
compiler basically while if you give the
program already compiled you just I have
a simple binary in the target machine
but the real innovation in this repo is
that it allows you to register to the
maps that I told you about before using
go channels so you can actually read the
map in a concurrent way
let's go very fast through this program
I just read this budget line see here
what is this doing is that it's
basically doing some verification that I
required for the static verified to let
your program work and then you get the
current process ID I register it in this
event that I created here that it's
coming from this struct that is also
which is reading my go program so you
have to maintain when I send the data
with the map I have to maintain the
struck pot in the VFC program and in my
go program and then I register this vpf
per photon map that the PFF output is
the map that you want to use when you
want to have a generic map to send
things like if you don't want to use a
specific one this one is generic and
it's always registered and works very
well for like the bargain use cases so
big after fatwood here and this is the
same relying events here and rely on
events in this in this case here so I
registered to this table and every time
every time the function redline is
called on bosch i send an event so this
thing is basically you start the bash
shell everywhere in the machine and
every time red line is the function in
bash that's called whenever command is
issued so when you write a command in
bash read lies receives it we done is a
function so you're getting the argument
of the function and you send it to the
map and the map receives please receive
dingo here in this table and then this
table as a channel and it's connected to
the table and then you just get the
information out of nine channel using
the for loop here and then you print
them basically out so if I load this
program in a UNIX machine what happens
is that I just see all the bash comment
issues another interesting project
always in a visor is vpf trace vpf
Tracey's an iron level language that has
been written for the purpose of doing VP
of tracing and it's a bit easier because
you don't have to deal with all of this
this is still very good because it's
very extensible like you can write
you're basing your own go program and
into having it interact the VPS program
but if you just need some specialized
tool like justit's just extract all the
right maybe you don't need like to do
anything else we never just want to see
them it's easier to use VP of trace I'm
always talking about this aisle visor
because it's the Linux Foundation VP
Africa project it's basically right now
the main contributor to BPF other
contributors that are very notable
me and I talking our cilium that is
basically doing they are doing there as
the end for kubernetes but they are they
basically wrote the documentation for a
BPF like if you write the beep you have
the commutation dr. go whatever search
engine years I will know you basically
find them or well that's what I found
actually I didn't find anything harder
documentation else and other
contributors are the gather came both we
are one of them there and all the others
I will tell them about that later but I
advisor is the main contributor actually
and Brandon Greg that is working on
Netflix doing performance created this
graph we are showing you all the
interaction point with the bps using BPF
trace so you can easily see that I was
always talking about VV v FS so if
you're interesting in the five system
you can go as down as you want down to
the device drivers same things or socket
paintings for the scheduled for virtual
memory you can interact the assist calls
you can interact with the system
libraries after the applications and you
can connect to all of this thing using
the trace behind a set trace points are
where profile interval K probe you probe
USD T yes it is very interesting I
didn't toss in the slides because you
don't want to get to make this all very
long but it's basically allow you to
define static trace points in your
programs one of the most notable project
that uses this is no js' nodejs already
has USD T is defined so that for example
you can get all they are going to node
functions using us titties because the
node program will it's not I compiled to
an object
so I will do I do these can things
without an interpreter language using
yes
and what about Gordon it is yeah finally
turns out that there's not really
anything for kubernetes there are a
bunch of project round but not a lot of
projects are like in a group that active
element is them in a way that they are
using used very broadly in the community
we my friend alone out there we had an
idea to use vpf trace against kubernetes
clusters and we create this plug-in
called qct I'll trace then Brendan read
notice at it and we contributed that I
of I so basically so now it's a virus or
qcr trace I will have a demo shortly
there's a little disclaimer this is not
my laptop that's very funny I left my
laptop at home so this laptop so if you
see they're not around it's not my fault
and if it doesn't work is another so yes
of course you can all function rather
than the faceless and so you can find
that you CTL face in IO visor the
philosophy behind VP of tracing qcl
traces that they are UNIX tools
following the UNIX philosophy so you
just run them see the result and they're
gone
it's not a kind of tool that you can use
like to let your program render forever
or that you can talk to other things
it's just AI want to see all the five
written I want to see all the connection
you see them and they're done the usage
is qct I'll trace run weekly F trace
program and then since we are in
kubernetes your node or your pod so you
can touch a program to a pod
specifically or to a node and then you
just attach a TTI
an interesting use case it's seeing for
example the distribution of read in a
file like you're reading a file right
but you never know how you're reading
right it's a question that the first
time I asked myself this question is
what do you mean with that
oh I read it right I just really right
you don't just read a file you can read
it in different ways you can read it in
chunks of like one gigabyte or in
chocolate one two kilobytes right and
that gives you different performances so
like if you're writing your data is like
we do and you're reading the writing
files a lot this is a very huge
difference like if you write cache to a
file in chunk of one gigabyte or of one
kilowatt and this tool gives you an
insight of that maybe a phrase and by
extension few situation clusters and
since with qcl trace or previous race
you can define your output format you
can like write CSV and then you can pipe
it as I said before so UNIX philosophy
so you can pipe it to to another program
like visa data that lets you plot your
results in a different way than you CTL
three stars
so Q CTL VP of trace has functions to
aggregate your results like instagrams
you can see the maps of Sam's these gun
things but if you want to aggregate them
yourself you can do that user space
there's a demo time Leo you think it
will work
who knows
so I try to do my best to be comfortable
this machine so have these correlates
this application called Caturday
that shows cat seems fine and basically
it's a department with you with tree
containers and runs this cat or taking
that as an HTTP server that shows you
cat in the browser and cats in the
terminal with a row endpoint so just run
it and see yes one of them are already
running
and see that there's a service where you
can reach cats and it's order then they
have to use bash cause you think that'd
be crazy and
[Music]
this cathode-ray program is implemented
in this main go file and yes it has cats
and whatever interested in is getting
out the value of this counter value
counter value is called we we seen the
cats now it's called every time someone
called endpoints I chose cats if it's
for their normal in pointer for the
royal point so basically we see one two
three times it's an atomic counter so
you know many times the cats are being
showed up and I just want to be able to
extract that information without having
like well you can monitor this like
adding a pro me to send point or adding
an influx science and send information
out or log into a file and send them
somewhere or you can extract information
using any media and this would want to
do so I have the cats here
and what I want to do is this one-liner
here so it's big enough and I want to do
QC tell tracer on you read probe you
frog doesn't give you the return value
of the function you retro gives you the
return value key probe and key
read-through same thing so I attach
these you read probe to my I don't
really know where the binaries in the
container so I just use its process ID
and get the binary from Excel and they
want to print the counter and they will
get the value from this main counter
value and the pod is this one so
one of them this one and they just use
it here I start asleep when I started I
can do crystal trace get o a sport or
maybe it's better sake here
okay
I didn't have the Marlboro for crisis
and okay
they started and saying hey I'm waiting
for you to sign ctrl C because controls
that signal is used to tell the problem
to dump out the maps can be bf trace and
[Music]
so I can do trace get
oh no my Hebron in the namespace so the
experience is very similar to the normal
QC t ell programs and I say that I have
this procedural trace here and they see
that it's attached now
I just want to like do a call to goes to
the cat some point it is in the natural
namespace and okay this is the HTML one
point and I just want the Rowan but the
raw end point so you see that I have
this counter with three cats here
showing for five and I have this number
year two so every time I called the cat
it gives me kiss me the country
increasing in from the vpf extracted
from my VBF trace program started from
my laptop and the cluster might be
anywhere so it's a very good Alpert
extract information this way and other
one-liners I prepared for these are
like this one
same note in this case in this case you
know they want to see how many time the
see center while Carl Siskel has been
called and I'm creating your map called
probe at and parentheses is create a map
and the cam function lets you see how
many times is that things be called and
same thing I will wait for it to run oh
I didn't do that
touch
attaching 300 probes because see Center
Cisco Lala and then they just plot the
resource so see center piece of ass
isn't our socket 435 times in one second
right but another interesting one is
counting BFS right so this is what I
said before every time a file is written
in the news Colonel it goes through the
VF s VF s right here I just well this is
not see I can import Linux headers in
vpf trace using the same notation I can
create structures using the same
notation so that it's easier for one to
start informations but so I extract the
file information from the file
descriptor and then I create a map that
has file name and the sum of bytes that
have been written and then I just go to
the Internet and do some things just
because it creates some well this for it
is fast I was running on this machine
and this machine is under is under
control so and this is not my get up
because it Leonardo's get up and I just
control see here and I say I see that
there's some stuff running I see that
TCP v6 because the folsome Internet is
doomed ipv6 so it's not ECP and I see
that Firefox is doing a lot of things
with sequel ID and everything and
[Music]
another interesting thing is seeing the
same thing with the histogram
so let's stick around Saturday whatever
and control seed in this case I'm seeing
not justify bites return but also the
distribution of the bites return per
chance so like for this cookie c.coli 12
i see that it's between 16 and 32 bytes
or between 32 and 64 kilobytes well if I
go to TCP it becomes creamy clear clear
that the TCP RFC has been implemented
correctly because it ranges from 16
bytes to a kilobyte right so if you're
implementing your own TCP you handy
bugger through this who doesn't do that
and turns out the resources for a PDF
are starting to pop out from the
internet but there's not really yet a
book for it
so the width caliber and just your
writing 1 and this book is coming out
from real need some sometimes this year
and next year and note it's not really
not public yet but a book is coming and
as I said there's they're they're being
contribution from my adviser see Liam
and other entities you know security
models use these we have seen and
there's a slightly references for you so
if you want to take a photo check this
for yourself and it's everything I
bought a nice domain it's called BBF Sh
nice if anyone wants an alias just write
me an email and we'll be happy to give
it to you just because this community
want to have more people looking at the
BPF and having a nice email puts you in
the situation so that you have to do
that because you are the email address
right I'm joking and if there are any
questions
thank you it's shut down you want to use
mine if understanding I don't you you
want you what you can come if you I
don't mind showing me my thing here I
don't
probably I have no working years but
it's not working
tell me well you know the question right
now nice when you unclip control a
través you target a node right well it's
also possible to filter for specific
containers or for specific yeah I did
that
yeah yeah I would have me much wasn't
clear I can show you that so the
question was it's possible to target a
specific public usage our trace yes it
is like in this case here I was using
both slash means the published adopt
what is happening instead of the node it
turns out that this report is not very
well done yet because we have to do some
changes to detect trace to support
prosper hidden in spaces it's kinda
works but they're worse to make it
better and there's actually support for
C group which will be PS trace that you
can use with you seated face but C group
which you are not the default infinity
so I didn't make an example just because
no advantage doing the call this
afternoon that showed the C group
support very well so so yeah we found
back so I really I talking about
software anyway any other question oh
yeah we can
I think her presentation really nice I'm
really interested in this but I'm also
secured is there any chance I can shoot
myself in the foot
I want to test this on a server and then
I do something stupid I ran out of that
without of city or something and I
cannot connect to the Box anymore it's
possible for me it's possible with BB a
finger like for example well the only
Yosuke that happened to me that time
basically lock it up itself or the
machine has been with XDP because it was
mending with packets so I just basically
drop it all the packets and myself
attracted to like the same things we do
with the Iowa die today and that happens
or like that you create a loop with
Batistuta you go into the same interface
and you basically lock yourself out but
the pair programs are not persistent in
that way you have to log them again
so you just restart the machine and with
if your face doesn't allow you to do
this kind of thing so now we live your
trade but will be the original yes next
question
oh we have to
thanks for great presentation
I think it's very useful tools for my
mostly kubernetes administrators so I
will use some of your tips but my
question is happy Oh Josi cystic or and
could you compare your dissolution of
cystic well yes I used to stick to a
stinky run to the kernel module that's
one of the things that one avoid
personally so I was starting in
exploring honesty I think that physics
does very well the presentation of the
day for the extract but I think that
those data can be extracted those who
will be there for them so like it would
be cool if there was and if you have to
that extract the same information
artistic this microphone is in the drive
me crazy and but that has a nice
interface that's what we means like
that's the same reason I did this
because I just want to have something
that just let me do stuff like without
having to SSH in know my machines and
it's also because I don't really know
where the things are right - yes - see
the circles much interference and we
have a question over here thank you for
the presentation
PSICOM still using classic PPF are not
EPP f yeah if you do do you not know if
and when the EPP f support will be
extended to succumb to tough question i
i've been reading recently that it's
arriving I don't think it's coming this
year so honestly I don't think that's
any progress
that's like immeasurable in a way that
you can say a injured it's arriving
that's all that selenium I'm not
involved in that so any further question
okay answer question and thanks for
qualifying that class Olivia Olivia
so can you aggregate data from a crowd
for around the cluster or they need to
target a specific know that a specific
container nice question and not yet
because VPS faces with the QC Tetris
right there asking order with digital
trace no yeah because big your face has
been created specifically for single
node so you cannot but it can be done
well we are working on that like we are
working on like having visual trace
expose a different format to aggregate
from multiple not one not yet but that
in my personal plans at least because
I'm probably doing that if anyone wants
to contribute that and will be super
happy it's mostly keeping VP of trades
because UCL trades just runs that I can
run the program in multiple machines so
it will work right now with trees but it
doesn't work with application because
aggregations are are basically done that
machines are an answer question hi
thanks for a nice presentation more of a
general PPF EVP have a question but also
maybe can be applied to bananas as well
as how safe is it to run at racing
program on a high load production server
to do real analysis of what's happening
is it gonna affect performance and if
yes is there any numbers of what you can
expect of course it's really probably
difficult to answer depending on what
the program is doing but yes yeah the
question is how safe is it and can you
actually run this in production to see
how it how it works thanks for the
question it's a ticking at every single
call so thanks for question what you
usually do to know what
your program are doing I mean in general
is like to use a debugger or use as
trace these kind of tools those tools
actually put interrupts or dwarf symbols
or whatever in your program so they need
to interact with their program in a way
while BPF doesn't BPF goes to the kernel
the kernel receives all the information
from the program already and you just
attach yourself on the side and get
information the kernel radius so the
performances impact is not it it's
always not in the program itself it's
more in the kernel because you have no
need to process your code but it's very
it's very low like you will not you will
never well you can do that but you will
never attach like a stray sheep in one
right while you can do that safely with
an MEP a program okay thanks for a
question that was a team guy he means
the same we have another question over
here
any other question
okay then thanks for the talk
you