so yeah it's great to be at Foster and
foursome is a really cool event and
actually and so I'm also event organizer
I'm running for example the open tech
summit in Germany and Berlin every year
and I've also lived for many years in
Asia and I'm still like at least half of
my time during the year in Asia and we
started the fourth asia community so
that was a a goal that we had with event
yay we wanted to have an event system
that we can use ourselves so yeah so
here you see for example the community
it's pretty big like we have like some
events more than 3,000 people who
participate and we wanted like an event
system that is completely open of course
and yeah so what's the status today
we have a lot of members in the
community and among like different
projects that we have the open event
server for example is our elite projects
with 1600 stars so it means like people
follow it and check out what's going on
and many also contribute so we're really
happy about that but what's the story
behind it so the story is that we start
at 2009 with our first events and was
like basically get people together have
some fun we went Asia and we felt a
little bit left out yeah because we
didn't have a foster in in in the region
there are many smaller events but we
didn't have this spirit so we started to
make an event and yeah what do you do
you need ticketing you need to plan like
sometimes we have catering and this and
that right and so what we did is we used
systems like Eventbrite for example and
or we used Meetup and then there were a
few systems for example that that also
here a Penta bath or frappe used by the
CCC in Germany so systems like that but
they were mainly for the for the
speakers let's say and they weren't
always in technologies that we were
familiar with so this was the idea let's
make a system not just for ticketing
though also for speaker handling and
here large events up to 3,000 people and
what are where the requirements free and
open source
technology stack that matches our team
and community so something that we can
handle ourselves but we don't have to
ask somebody else mmm and we want to
keep previously in mind so we don't
always want to upload all our data to
some proprietary services and like that
another thing is while we were
developing it and when we were studying
it we also saw other people had similar
ideas they also want an event system but
maybe they had two different focus and
so on so an idea that we also always
follow is open standards for example if
you export an event or something like
that and we want other people to be able
to use our data in their system or we
use their data in one of our components
and that also means open api's and all
this of course so we are here at force
10 and I think I don't need to go more
into detail there so what were our goals
in regards to the features we thought we
don't have to make a completely
different experience to what people know
people know Eventbrite they know other
systems so we can follow this approach
have the same process in regards for
ticketing for example then the call for
speakers so and I worked also like a
while with some people at Mozilla and I
know they also run events with the
thousand people and a lot of these
events are still managed by spreadsheets
yeah so this was also something that we
wanted to get away we had also like a
lot of spreadsheets and then we started
at one point to get out like some data
through like Google Docs using JSON and
so on we wanted to get away from this
have an easy process where every speaker
can update their own session and so on
easily a foursome is possible today but
it wasn't always possible they in the
past and an important thing to save as
time is organizers drag and drop drag
and drop
scheduling yeah exporting of course I
already mentioned that and and the thing
that we realized after a few years I
love Drupal and I love Django I love all
these
systems but if you have to maintain old
system just for the sake of maintaining
it it could be really a pain so we want
like a website that's generated and that
we can just hold on FTP server or today
on and get our pages or Gettler pages
something like that and and of course
like when you have everything like
people use the mobile phone so Android
is a big topic things like that a plus
features content wise these proprietary
systems they don't have the possibility
to license your content freely to say ok
the content that you have make it free
they don't have always the possibility
to enter a code of conduct it's very
important in the US for example so these
kind of things so we started the
development and yeah today we have a lot
of different components and we have a
web front-end that runs the web site we
have the API server that's the backend
so after several iterations now we
achieve to separate the front and at the
back end yeah like at the beginning
sometimes it was like we have to get
done the the event is approaching our
big event and we need this this this or
that feature so the code wasn't always
that clean but and now we achieved to
really separate it cleanly and we have
an end attendee app on Android and also
like actually I'm personally not using
iOS but it seems like other people are
excited to develop on iOS so yeah cool
let's get everyone on board and why not
open this iOS universe also up yeah as
much as possible so yeah so you can
export all your data you can generate
websites and have an output and yeah
this is a bit an overview so which
components do we have today here what
what are the technologies we're using so
on the back end for example on the
second row here you see flask and Python
and the front end we use in the ember
Jas yeah basically it's always a
decision what other developers
comfortable with right and
yeah it's pretty standard but you see we
have a lot of goals and we are open
event website generate a 90 percent of
goals are reached the other part still
like yeah something to do here so how
does it look like I always like to run
people through life but I'm always
unsure like house house the house the
Internet so I I took some screenshots
but you can go on the website and it's
pretty stable you can try it out and so
when you go to the website there's
button you say create event and you have
the option to add a name to add a
location and here for example a thing
that we have is we're still using Google
Docs so there's an open issue to switch
to OpenStreetMap but you can enter all
the basic details of the event and can
get started pretty quickly then of
course ticketing so ticketing is
important for us and we are in Asia many
people want to buy a community ticket or
support a ticket and so we need the
ability to have different ranges and
that is pretty much the equivalent of
what Eventbrite offers these days and
yeah I mean I think not much words
needed here and payments or payment we
are supporting already PayPal and stripe
so stripe as a service for credit cards
and we are looking to implement more and
more payment gateways yeah also for
example like I don't know here and
Belgium what payment gateways you have
in Germany a different payment gateways
in India yeah ok so then you click on
safe and proceed and as the option to
add sponsors nowadays like the community
has a lot of support from big companies
they're using free and open source
software so you can add these sponsors
here in the next step and in the third
step and you can always switch it on and
off you see this button there switch it
on and off so if you have an event where
you don't need any speaker handling you
just switch it off if you have an event
with speaker handling you can go onto
detail here and
you can add tracks you can add micro
locations so basically rooms and session
types and you can change the colors then
and yeah hope will show up with your
schedule in the end then call for
speakers is important and it's pretty
straightforward as well but you see here
a private link why a private link so
sometimes we have people their high
profile they missed the deadline of the
call for speakers but we already told
them we really want to have them abort
right and so we can send them a private
link and they can still sign up after
the deadline is closed and formed
registration so so what do you actually
want to ask your speakers or what
session details do you want to ask so
you can provide the opportunity to ask
something and there's and future of
course would be great to have a form
builder here as well
okay collect speaker details and then
like what are the options here you can
have an overview so this event that I
started here of course didn't get any
income yet but like you will have an
overview you can discount tickets and so
on for example for us in Singapore's
always very important to have discount
tickets we want that the companies pay
yeah we want that they pay for the
business ticket and because we have to
pay for the room we have to do we have a
lot of costs but we want to give free
tickets to the community or to special
groups so and this comes in very handy
and then this is something that really
saves us a lot of weeks the scheduler so
after the speaker's all applied filled
in the form and so on we have the
scheduler and in the scheduler then all
the unscheduled talks will here be shown
on the left and then you can drag and
drop them so the rules will show up and
you drag and drop them into the room and
into the time that you want so honestly
this really saves a lot a lot of time
and yeah we were really happy that we
were able to get this going and of
course we can also export this in as a
PNG or as
other formats what else to be half so we
have an overview here of the speakers
which talks are accepted some basic
information you can click on and edit it
and end very important we have a way to
export all the event data there's an API
here that you can use so how do we use
it for example here this is an example
of a website that was generated based on
this data so how does it work you see
you enter your email you enter some
basic information you add the JSON file
or link to the export file and then you
generate the website it's a bit sped up
here so we can keep the time and but
this is basically how it works you can
have a dark or a light theme and you can
generate your own website and upload it
to github pages and you have the
speakers you have different options here
and different different pages that you
can say all the links of the sessions
and so on
pretty nice a really nice alternative to
sketch talk yeah I don't know if you
have heard this so many companies using
the Linux Foundation uses it for example
but here we have a free and open-source
alternative then of course the Android
app here there are some screenshots you
can find it on the Play Store or on F
droid and a picture of a recent
community event that we had in India
actually that we are proud to say that
most of our developers are from Asia so
it's a real global project and if there
they are they using it Jim so what's
next
of course a lot is left you need badges
for example for events this is something
that we're working on so we started a
project patch yay we're always getting
excited so we like to call things
battier or event yeh and then we're
moving
currently to the next version you can
try it out on next event I calm I talked
to you about it it's the completely
separated API in front front end in
automatic deployment we were using
Google Cloud and Cuba needs for a while
yeah it's quite expensive if you're not
sponsored continuously by Google it's
all we move to much cheaper solution but
still like the automatic deployment is
not working so smoothly so we're working
on that and more users in the community
so we want more events to use it we are
all free notice also let's use it and
get the system stable less packs so we
actually need people who tell us what
specifically is not working for them
rather than saying something's not
working right and yeah finalize the
mobile apps I'm adding cool features
there is always more what we can do and
yeah here's a call for contribution we
have a post Asia internship program we
also run an open source hotel in Vietnam
I think hook talked about it like an
I'll go quickly and yeah we always
participate in G sock I hope we get in
this year so there are lots of
opportunities to collaborate with us but
also when you run an event you have the
possibility to join us so thank you very
much and let's get started and join us
for example here at the next Force Asia
Summit March 14 to 17 and or check out
the projects online and yeah I could
talk for hours of the next speaker
doesn't can so I've looked like I could
show you like how things work in detail
but like if not you can come to our
booth in k.k hall or you can talk to me
directly that's it thank you very much
[Applause]