I said the hit
[Applause]
so thank you very much and welcome to
this lighting talk my name is Kim and
I'm a software engineer to start up
called logic locks we are based in
Stockholm and we are developing a
platform for doing big data analysis and
machine learning at large scale called
hops works and this presentation I'll be
talking about feature stores and try to
convince you why you need a feed store
to manage the data and your machine
learning pipelines so we slightly
different on the previous talks now if
you're a traditional machine learning
person the way that your problems are
set up is that you have these x and y
values and then your task is the kind of
model is data and learn relationships
between your variables if you are
they're scientists but this x and y
values don't just show up clean by
themselves rather they have to come from
somewhere and that somewhere it tends to
be a script to some data engineer are
written to extract the data may be from
a Kafka topic or from a production
warehouse somewhere and what we're
seeing now increasingly when mozillian
is getting adoption in industry is that
this process of extracting the x and y
values and getting the data in the right
format and the right time for us doing
machine learning is a very big task and
some companies even argue that this is
the hardest problem in machine learning
right now uber for example are claiming
this and they are arguably one of the
companies in the world that apply
machine learning at a larger scale so
what they're saying is kind of
interesting but even if you don't
necessarily agree with everything you'll
be assessing this quote we have larger
clocks I agree with you on one point and
that is that they should not be a
question mark appear rather it should be
a standardized interface for how you
feed the features into your model for
training and serving a standard
interface between data engineering and
data science and that is the feature
story which I'll be explaining in the
remainder of this talk so looking at the
definition of a feed store is actually
surprisingly simple it is
a storage location within your
organization where you store documented
and curated features but the power of
the field store really comes from the
strong semantics that we can enforce on
top of this feed store and abstractions
that we can build on top of it so some
of the things that we're trying to
achieve with the feed store or things
like feature versioning automatic
feature documentation and analysis and
also feature backfilling but the main
point of the feed store at least in my
opinion is this first one in the list
which is that by using a feed store it
becomes much simpler to reuse features
across different models and across
different teams and let me elaborate on
a little bit why that is such a big
improvement for many organizations today
so what we argue at logic looks is that
by investing in your feed store the cost
of your machine learning products which
are to taper off and our point is that
instead of doing new big investments in
each machine learning product you take
on and build custom pipelines you can do
can of one-time investments in the lower
layers of your design stack such as the
feed store and has to be locked at field
store with more and more high quality
features the cost of building new models
on top of the feed store will start to
go down ulema now look at an example to
further make this a point of feature
reusability so this is a like a typical
architecture at an organization today
for doing machine learning where you
have this kind of siloed machine
learning pipelines one for each product
and this is a fairly simple workflow but
when you have this architecture is very
hard to do things like reusing features
across the different pipelines so
typically what you have to do actually
what I've seen at organizations is that
if you have a feature here that you want
to reuse here you just copy the
definition and recompute it again and if
you want to do more complex things like
for example feature backfilling
automatic feature analysis and
documentation is basically impossible
using this architecture so what we
suggest instead is to use what is called
a feature store as the common
interconnect between all of these
pipelines this means that a features no
longer touched a couple sub Civic model
rather features now an independent
version and reproducible artifacts that
can potentially span
many different models so we no longer
have this tight coupling between model
and feature rather they are kind of
disconnected now and it gives us a lot
of freedom and flexibility as engineers
or data scientists for example one big
benefit of this is that now we have this
consistency that no matter if you're
using a feature for training or for
serving or for a neural network or for
decision tree you're always going to use
the exact this is the same definition of
that feature because we are not
redefining it over and over again we are
reusing the same feature again and this
also means that we can do nice things
like here we are all features
centralized so we can easily analyze
them look for the correlations we can
also do things like feature backfilling
so we can be more efficient in how we
compute the features and that is kind of
the promise of what the filter will give
you and now I'll just very briefly going
through the more of the technical
details on how we can be allowed this
thing and are we speaking out from
experience of building a feed store on
our platform so internally a feed store
consists of five different components
starting with the storage layer where we
store actual feature data this tends to
be predominantly numeric data like
floats and integers but it can also be
categorical data or binary data for
example then we have the metadata layer
and this is in my opinion the most
important layer to get right with the
field store and you'll see in our
implementation we exploit is quite a lot
so this is where we store things like
the version of a feature the ownership
of the feature which models or is it
used which your business computer
feature and for which data set does it
originate this means that we can out
automatically backfill features were
necessary we also store a lot of
statistics about our features for
helping our data scientists understand
the features like the distribution of
all features over time the correlation
with each other so Spearman and Pearson
correlations and we also store
descriptive statistics and clustering
analysis and so on then we have the two
final components of the field store
which is the feature registry and the
API and this is kind of the client-side
interface to the field store and the
registry you can think of it as the
front end store feed store it is a place
where we can publish our features we can
search for them we can browse their
metadata or documentation
features and and you publish your own
work basically so you can think of it in
a little way like an app store for
machine learning so it's a place where
you can discover new features within the
organization and you can also publish
your own work so that other people can
reuse it and then the final component is
the API this is what we use inside our
machine learning pipelines to read and
write to the store and this is just a
regular client-side libraries that we
use and I'll show you a quick example of
how our API looks like so here we have
two examples of the API and one for
reading from a store and one for writing
to the store and as you can see code
wise I hope you agree with me it's quite
a simple API so to read from the story
has provided a list of feature names and
to write to the story just provide a
data frame of features and to make this
API so simple what we have done is that
we are abstracted out all of our heavy
lifting into our client-side libraries
so we actually have a query planner
analyse your query and give you the
result and now I'm a time stop but if
you're interested I have several
references on the final slide we can
read more and yes to summarize this
presentation machine learning comes it's
a very powerful tool but it also comes
with a very high technical cost and in
the beginning of this presentation I
mentioned is complexity of getting the
data in the right format at the right
time for doing machine learning and our
solution to this problem is to invest in
a data management layer specifically
designed for machine learning called a
feed store and the world's first open
source feed store is available on our
platform called hops works thank you
[Applause]
yes so the question is what type of
features would be for natural language
processing and tibial features could be
for example word embeddings are very
common but it can also be features such
as is this word a noun or a synonym or
those kind of features but word
embeddings I think is the main feature
we're using in the NLP right now yes you
can do that as well it depends a bit
which task you're trying to solve but
that's that's also an option but you can
add more features the better in most
cases