okay so hi everyone my name is Jamie
Gallardo
I'll be presenting about a continuous
application monitoring using LT TNG I
wake if you see us if you've never heard
the name we're a small consulting firm
based in Montreal we developed tracers
Ltd energy being the most known of them
I personally maintain out to TNG tools
and babble tres and I'll start the
presentation were a few words about
tracing in general and more specifically
system tracing and lt TNG how we
struggle to to have to meet the needs of
people who wanted to do continuous
monitoring without hitting G and our
solution tracing session rotation what
it is and the shortcomings and and how
it makes well the challenges that are
involved in making continuous trace
analysis at scale so L TT in G started
in 2005 at this point is more of an
umbrella project we have a user space
tracer kernel space tracer the system
demons that I maintained to control both
tracers and and control the data
extraction paths the Ltd analysis
project which I'll touch a bit later in
the talk it's a set of scripts to work
with traces and L tthe scope a graphical
viewer so I got a super great question
in the interview in the week before the
talk and that is now on the first M
website what's the difference between
logging and tracing and really it's a
hard question to answer because there's
no clear definition for both they both
have the same goal so the general goal
is I want to extract information from my
application or from the kernel and be
able to understand the state of the
application at that moment that's the
gist of it in different logging
frameworks and tracers will target
either developers sis admins or in the
worst case end users and it's always a
matter of trade-offs with
usefulness these views the performance
impact on this system and verbosity
which ties into ease-of-use and then
there are some some concepts will come
back in every tracer in every logging
framework enabling only certain subsets
of events and logging levels the big
difference I find is when people think
of system tracers like LT King G we're
more in the low-level events that are
very very frequent if we think of the
kernel tracer our goal will be to
capture system calls and their payload
so we can have thousands of them every
thousand of them every second but we
also trace scheduling information so we
track every task running on every CPU at
any given time and it will attract file
system activity networking activity
power management events and so on and so
forth
in the case of LT TMG specifically the
user space tracer it tries to be the
equivalent for a user space so since we
can capture a lot of events with a very
low overhead people will tend to funnel
very very verbose logging true LT
tianjin USD and our job is to cope with
that when I say a lot of events I want
to give you just a rough figure of what
that represents on this laptop I did a
quick measurement while it world was
completely idle if you enable all kernel
events that represents around 54,000
events per second and you're not
dropping events at that point on a busy
eight core server you're more in the
waters of three million events per
second so that starts to be allowed to
cope with and so this is where tracers
and loggers are gonna divert in the
trade-offs that they have to make first
trade-off I'd say the the central part
of healthy TNG is its string buffer
that's at the center of the whole thing
we have a ring but a lot less roomm
before implementation in user space and
internal space that are very very
similar there are only if you would have
adaptations to to make it work in both
scenarios
and it is consumed asynchronously so
there's no locking in terms of waiting
or blocking the application or the
kernel for that matter when you're
producing events so worst comes to worst
you're dropping events so you're not
slowing down the application and then
there are a number of memory footprint
and the security parameters that you can
set on that ring buffer which I'm not
going to go into for this top and so
that's one big part it's the quality of
the implementation of the ring buffer
the other thing is the best way to not
influence the system is to not trace so
trace as little as possible and this is
why an l TT in g we have a very complete
set of a rule-based system where you can
enable only the events that you want and
you can perform filtering at runtime on
the events using our interpreter as
running both in the kernel and user
space so I gave two examples here the
first one you can see that you're
enabling the read Cisco you could enable
it for a given process and then you can
filter on the size of the read itself
and not capture any read of four bytes
or things like that and to give you an
idea of the performance in the kernel
space it's a kind of a complicated
question I won't go into but it's pretty
much the same performance as as I've
traced in user space we're in the waters
of a hundred thirteen a no second
paradigm so that's very fast as you
understand we can't go through string
formatting to achieve that performance
so everything's going to be so realized
to binary file if you follow the bit the
development of the Linux kernel we have
pushed the what we've been working on on
that for a while but now restartable
sequence the new system call is in the
mainline kernel from 418 and up and the
goal for us putting that much energy
behind that was to improve the speed and
the performance of the user space tracer
so right now with the
the code paths that use our sec are not
in the LTTE in ju st but our prototype
branch lowers that number to 90
nanosecond per event so it's a quite a
significant improvement for us the users
of LT ng are going to be journaled
application developers and embedded
system developers and for a very long
time in the projects is to read it was
really the core of our users and I'd say
all of our users but now there's a
there's a lot of interest from people
running infrastructure system
administrators they've DevOps and and
those users come to us and say hey I've
used those TNG to debug that time you
race in a driver they found firmware
bugs and their nicks they found you know
understanding why there was memory
pressure at a given time so things that
that are hard to reproduce that can be
reproduced and so basically what they
would do was they would set up tracing
start collecting everything reproduce
the problem and then investigate
manually through the trace and and that
works I mean it's the way the two other
classes of users tend to work but it's
not really continuous monitoring for
saves so it's fine if you're unting for
a bug but if you want to know if
everything's running smooth it's not
really the solution something clever
that I've seen a reproduced at a number
of our customers site is that people are
gonna people who run a large
infrastructure are gonna use a sampling
approach so basically they set up
tracing at random times on random
machines they will collect a trace for a
given period of time run a number of
stret some scripts on that and they'll
look for deviations to their known good
response time resource usage they'll
look at error rate serotypes those kind
of things might start continuous again
so we add the snapshot mode which is
mostly used by embedded developers and
in this mode you're basically its flight
recorder mode
you so you're tracing in memory you're
never touching the desk and if you
figure it something wrong is going on
you can capture your buffers and work
with them and for all intents and
purposes this is going to give you a
regular CTF trace that you can use every
tool out there that reads that format to
work with but there are some drawbacks
especially for monitoring for monitoring
I mean first might seem stupid but you
have to react very quickly if you're
only keeping 8 megabytes of trace data
around by the time you realize that
there's a problem there's a good chance
that you have overwritten everything so
no luck and there's also the problem
that if you manage to react fast enough
you only have a few millisecond of
tracings so you better hope that you're
gonna had be able to understand what was
going on with that information I'm
making that sound very negative but I
mean it's useful in some cases but it is
a major drawback and then we had the
live mode and live mode was something a
we thought was good enough for
monitoring for a long time and but
really it was not made for that it was
it was like a way to build I don't want
to say better as trace but a trace with
journal events that are not Cisco's and
had user space tracing to that so you
could see what your application was
doing and what the kernel is doing
interleaved together and try to
understand what is going on but the goal
was to have enough filtering going on
that you could actually follow it which
arise and not work with automated tools
and also we didn't want to slow your
applications or at least not as much as
P trace does it but when we discuss what
users wanted to use that in production
well first of all our protocol and we
knew that is not designed to end all a
high throughput so it falls down in
those cases and it's not trivial to
consume there are a couple of people's
who have implemented that but are not
making it open source so it doesn't
really exist for
for all intents and purposes the only
client that we have is the text viewer
which was for the original use case and
also maintaining connections to every
target is not really realistic typically
in production at least not to poor
people that we talk to and there's also
the problem that you're only get the
most recent information so if you lose
your connection the problem how occurs
you reconnect you lost your your data
basically so it became evident that
there were missing pieces for continuous
monitoring not that we had our head in
the sand but we we thought hey if it
makes the job for all of those users why
why are you special right so and I want
to make a point
because I think there's an EVP F talk
after this aggregation of system traces
to monitor currents is different from
what we're we're trying to do what we're
trying to do is have all the data
available if there is a problem that
goes on and not not established trends
or or make an Instagram of latent season
those scattered those kind of things
which are very very useful I'm not
knocking that's just a big difference in
the approaches is that so
our mode so good for debugging but for
monitoring it'll they don't do the job
so we interacted it and we kinda were on
the back foot to implement all of that
because everyone had a very strong idea
of what we should support and they were
all different and we're not a project
that has a ton of resources to go around
so for instance everybody wanted us to
support natively their own data store
their own ingest pipeline for labs or
your own message queues and those are
all legitimate ideas but if we try to
support everything that's the only thing
that we're gonna be doing forever right
so we needed to come up with a solution
that is adaptable and people can control
on their own there's the problem that
traces are huge and there are people who
run traces in production and they'll
capture hours and hours or days of
traces and they don't mind the traces
take hundreds of gigabytes
those people are few and far between so
this is not a good solution so we need a
way to make it possible to continue
tracing but discard the old traces and
make it possible to compress traces as
they age and and archive them or or
throw them away and the third point is
that trace processing can be very slow
and very resource of you when you have
hundreds of gigabytes of traces there's
nothing there's not one tool that's
gonna be snappy on that without a bit of
preparation so I think it's a given that
the analysis must not happen on a target
typically your target is busy doing
something you don't want it to crunch to
a 100 megabyte 100 gigabyte trace just
out of nowhere so the solution in in
concept is very simple we without ok so
why don't we have a log rotation but for
tracing right it's not that we didn't
think about it it's just there are a lot
of challenges and implementing that at
with the constraints that we have and
I'll go through those constraint to show
you why it was complicated but basically
the idea is we will trace and then we
switch over to new files and then you
can do whatever you want with those
files so then if you want to ingest them
in a existing logging pipeline you can
do that if you want to shuffle them
around you can do that you want to
compress them go ahead and that race
should work with any viewer that's also
a big point since our format or tracing
format is standard it's opens under the
Linux Foundation Diamond workgroup we
don't want to break the format
just because we're implementing a new
feature so there's one problem
our format doesn't make this easy and
the reason why it doesn't make easy is
twofold first of all a melty kingi trace
is a is a set of files it's not one file
so what I said before we have a lot less
ring buffer that we keep per CPU we also
have per CPU stream files and those per
CPU stream files exist for a user space
and they also exist for the kernels
place and they could exist depending on
your configuration they could exist for
each and every user or each and every
application depending on what you want
to do so it's not it's not like a
classical log of rotation where you
write you open another file start
writing there close this one and we're
done and we also have a metadata file
that's one of the big challenges because
he'll teach in G is fully dynamic you
can say you you have an application that
opens a shared library and this shared
library has new events they will have a
layout that is completely different from
what is known up to that point so you
need to add that layout and we have just
a simple event here that has a UID in a
cookie file I payload the field and if
you don't know that layout you can pick
up the trace that's basically the
problem so rotating is a there's also a
step where we have to know okay up to
that point what were all the event
layouts that were possibly created we
have to serialize that to the metadata
file and and that over to the user so
that they don't end up with a trace that
is not decodable so the steps become
basically as we are tracing we need to
sample a production position for every
CPU across domains and then establish a
switchover point determine what all the
event layouts that we need to decode the
trays are up to that point flush that
and then if we switch over to a new set
of files and mark this one as being
ready for our consumption so you can
either monitor the filesystem to see new
files being created or you can use our
UNIX socket based notification API to
know that
so I'm very happy to say that this works
now it is not in a stable release
although we will be releasing this month
but now it is in release candidate stage
so if you want to try it out if you find
bugs I mean it me up on github or on the
mailing list and be very happy to hear
about that before we release although if
it happens after we'll fix it
and so for a while where we were super
happy without alright this is done
because we look at the world from a
tracers perspective you know so we
thought that all the analysis tools is
the job of other people it doesn't
really work like that people started
playing with it and there were two
groups of users and I'd say there are
more people in the first group that were
very happy with the feature basically
people who do stateless analysis and
stateless analysis is what you do when
you just want to count events so you
want to figure out you have a simple
rule
maybe with grep maybe with something
else where you just want to know how
many of those events were there in my
trace how many errors how many you know
whatever and you just need that and it's
fine and then you can throw that and
graph a now or whatever dashboard you
use the other class of users that were
less happy were okay this is great to
your radio call point of view but um I
want to perform stateful analysis so
what is stateful analysis it's basically
any time you read a trace and you
construct a model so anything that's
very interesting to be interesting which
races is gonna be is gonna use that
graphical to you viewers do that all the
time they basically have a simplified
model of the kernel for instance and
they'll follow every event that comes in
and for instance if they see is cisco
open and and open succeeds they will see
okay now that if the number three is
associated with that path name fair
enough
so this is gonna make it easy for
you to read a trace and understand
what's going on without seeing a read on
FD number three and having to go back
perhaps hours before to see what that
file was if you even have it and that's
the thing with trace rotation maybe that
information is an another chunk so
you'll never have that information so
there's a so basically the the simplest
use case is presenting data in a more
familiar way even a command line if you
were can do that so instead of having
the raw event we replace the PID with
the process name and we'll replace the
FD with the files name and this is what
in LTTE analysis we do I'll present the
project a little bit later but basically
if you want to see the longest read
Layton sees for a process in a given
time range it's going to give you that
it's not going to tell you there was a
long read on FD 13 at that moment it's
gonna give you the filing and the FT so
the way those tools work is that they
track state changes of resources so in
concept is very very simple they have in
it so a bit of background l TT in G is
gonna when you start tracing the kernel
for instance it will dump the state of
the kernel so that means all of the open
file descriptors all the active
processes or I should say all the tasks
and their PID group ID the username
spaces and all that so everything's
gonna be dumped and the tools can use
that as a original model that they can
then modify by reading the traces now
what most graphical tools are gonna do
is track the changes and populate a
state is to read database and and they
make the reasonable assumption up to at
this point that all the information is
going to be available all the time the
problem with independent chunks is that
you don't have a complete model so well
you have all the information it's just
split into a lot of tiny tiny traces so
if you look at a classical l TT in G
trace you're gonna be able to follow the
whole lifetime of a
and if you look at drunks well maybe
you'll see the open and one or reading
the other and the closed and the last
one so if you point existing tools to
any of those independent traces well
they're not going to tell you much so
the challenge became okay people are
gonna have to adapt their tools maybe I
should try to do the exercise myself and
try to help them and I thought it would
be very easy turns out it's not but
there's a demo at the end and you'll see
that it works spoiler alert
so LTT analysis we have a number of
scripts the most popular ones are their
system called latent sees there's one to
see the interrupt handler durations are
your usage letting the is latent sees
when accessing a file scheduling latency
so you can see for instance if you took
a long time to enter requests were you
scheduled at all on the CPU during that
time things like that so I wanted to
reimplementation alysus but with chunks
and basically provide the same
information as Ltd in G analysis so
again that analysis very simple you just
have to track which this call is active
on in any given thread at any given
moment when it completes you can compute
iteration and you can print that and use
the kernel model to pretty print the
information so replacing filenames P IDs
and all that if we don't have all the
information we need but we've called
partial modeling so basically the
central idea of partial modeling is that
any kernel object or operation for that
matter can be represented as a span so
the lifetime of our Cisco is going to be
bounded by the lifetime of the thread in
which it happens the thread is bounded
by the process file descriptors let's
assume that it's bounded by the lifetime
of the process and not get into weird
clone flags and shared file descriptor
tables CPUs the same way most tools
don't well
most tools assume that CPUs are there
all the time but with CPU at plug they
can come in and come out so their
lifetime is also a span and then the
Linux kernel that instance is also a
span in time and the same applies to
application when you're serving a
request that's a span and and that's not
a new concept I mean Zipkin represents
that information then in that way it's
just that for system traces it's not as
as usual so this is where most analysis
need most and adjustments and I'd say
most Theory right
typically or at least of the backend so
intuitively I thought well the analysis
can happen in two phase first one I'm
just gonna go over to chunk find every
complete span and keep that aside and if
there are spans that that span over the
frontier between two chunks I'll just
keep that aside and when we do the merge
phase we'll be able to stitch that
together and this sounds a lot like a
classical MapReduce pipeline okay it's a
bit more complicated than that
and I realize that very quickly and it's
it makes a lot of sense if you think
about it
Cisco's are not atomic and syste system
calls can fail system calls can be
interrupted and it restarted so you have
to be careful if you see it open it
doesn't mean that that file descriptor
is gonna exist at any point in the
future maybe your system calls and
they're gonna be interrupted
maybe it's gonna hand in the next chunk
so you don't know a lot about it and
your model has to account for that
so you have the example here or the
other point is that can happen on
different CPUs so you don't have to you
have to perform your natus your analysis
not on the cpu stream basis but on a
chunk basis fair enough and we the Babel
trace library makes that easy to to
collate all the streams together in and
do the merging so during the mapping we
find every span I gave an example here
maybe we'll see in a chunk that there's
a read on FD 22 keep in mind that this
could be a socket it could be
a number of things the only thing that
we know is that at this point if it's if
the read succeeds there was a file
descriptor 22 and we succeeded in
reading 15 bytes and we sat the end of
the lifetime of that file descriptor
fair enough
so now we have the end of that lifetime
of a file descriptor reducing well to
talk about my implementation basically
at the end of every mapping phase I'm
gonna produce a JSON file that has all
of the kernel model with the partial
spans and during the reduce we're gonna
tie this back together so at some point
there is a chunk that will tell us I
don't know the FD of that file but I
know that there's a file descriptor that
points to this file it's a block device
normal file it's not a sockets not any
Annie poll file descriptor and we'll
have all the information and then any
request that wanted to use that
informations gonna complete I should say
the report for a request that's gonna
give you the breakdown okay so in fact
it's a bit more complicated than that
still the rotation is not atomic so if
you look at the model that I had with
the city of traces before well it's easy
to think okay I have a switchover point
now from that point on I have a new set
of traces it works until you try to do
analysis on that and really it's simple
if you try to perform the switchover
without blocking everything you're gonna
end up with this staircase pattern where
in time the rotations a turn and you
switch files I thought that this would
be very a lot quicker than it actually
is and for a time I thought ah it's not
the end of the world if we drop events
for that little interval but actually
rotating on a twelve logical core
machine is gonna take 28 milliseconds so
there's a lot of gap and it can be
complete lifetimes of processes during
that time so what process is maybe not
but
which could happen well at least files
that can happen and complete requests
can happen during that time so you can
see that what ended up happening is that
in some cases you could see an open on
the first CPU and then aid up on CPU
number three and then you you think you
know everything in that time span but
actually you're blind to what's
happening during the transition so then
you assume that ok I know what that if
he is but actually it was something else
all that time so you don't know what
that F do you refers to so there are a
number of solutions to this problem the
one that I used is a bit lazy but if you
use two chunks you can seek to a point
where you'll have a complete chunk that
fits your assumption that the switchover
is atomic I think it's a good moment we
mentioned that we use the same clock
source clock monotonic between kernel
space and user space so this is what
makes it possible to make the analysis
reliable and really order events in the
way that you would expect so I'm happy
to say that the prototype works the goal
was to provide the same data as LTTE
analysis and what I wanted to do is have
a model of an application that performs
a non-trivial query and then show the
time that was spent in each phase of the
query and then drill down what were the
time spent in each and every syscall
that happened while serving that phase
of the query and and try to address the
shortcomings of l TT in G analysis first
it is a lot faster melting ng analysis
is written in Python so working with
millions of events is not not what
Buyten is made for so it's normal that
it was slow but it made it pretty hard
to use in a continuous way so that part
is taken care of but really the the
challenging part was the partial
modeling
so the example I'm gonna show you it's a
server that receives a request to
generate a thumbnail so basically it
gets given a asset ID it's going to say
seek to the requested frame they called
the video enough to they called that
frame scale to a thumbnail size and send
the response back and then we can
generate a breakdown of time spent in
every Cisco so I have this running in
the background it's feeding a graph Anna
instance and basically what you can see
here is the time for each and every
request now I don't recommend that you
do that in production because you don't
want to be processing each and every
trace chunk and individually graph each
and every request but it gives you an
idea of what what can be done the thing
that you can do is that if you have
outliers like you have here those points
you could generate a report and and
drill down into and this is what we were
gonna do if you look at the report
generated for one of the fast instances
we can see that okay most of the time is
spent opening the video with ffmpeg and
decoding a full frame that's fine that's
what most of the work is about scaling
as you would expect this mail mostly
cpu-bound so opening the file there's a
lot of stuff that goes on and you can
see here that the combined duration of
all get T IDs is actually what is
dominating that that operation then we
have a number of calls I'm not gonna go
through all of them but you can see the
interest in augmenting the model here as
you can see normally you would have a
read on a d that you don't know about
you would have M remap and as these that
you don't know about well math Emory BAM
but M map and so on and so forth seek
the same thing so seeking you can see
that not a lot happens as you would
expect this is an
next video file so it's fine then
decoding nothing unusual scaling nothing
happens it's a purely CPU it's purely
compute and then writing the result to a
socket now if we take one example that
took a long time we can see that the
outlier isn't there right
actually this one is not sending over in
a network because I had some problems
here but uh it's writing to a plain old
file basically you can see that writing
doesn't take a long time but during that
time there was a sync call that took
around 600 milliseconds so that's kind
of insight that you can have very
rapidly and hopefully your applications
don't perform sync during your request
handling but it has been seen so in
conclusion I think from the tracers
perspective we can see that we have the
infrastructure to distribute trace
processing people are very our users are
very happy that now they have files and
they can do whatever they want with them
but the open questions that I have for
you guys is what form can this type of
products processing take that would be
integrate integratable with existing
viewers or do you think that we need new
viewers new tools for that is there are
there tools out there that you guys use
to monitor very low level metrics
continuously I'd be very happy to have
your feedback otherwise you have any
questions
all right well thank you
[Applause]