hey folks I think we're gonna get
started my adapter somehow my adapter
somehow didn't make it with me
and so I I have an older machine so I'm
gonna start without slides and if we can
the magic volunteers can figure out the
right cable in the right place then
we'll switch to slides so I'm here
obviously to talk about floss the future
and the Internet so a good place to
start is where we are today and floss is
everywhere today and and that's a real
success which is worth celebrating
doesn't really matter where you look you
find free software at the heart of the
Internet at the heart of the big
services that we use and in all the
projects various applications so it
seems kind of obvious today and now free
software and open source software are
just a kind of part of mainstream
development but you know that's really a
surprising thing and when I sort of
started in this field you know that
wasn't the case at all and there was a
real disbelief in free software and
open-source software as being credible
in any serious sense I think there's
some learnings from that that will be
useful in the current state and so I'm
thinking back to just around the turn of
the millennium so 1999 2000 when Mozilla
was newish about a year old and and I
spent a lot of time explaining really
basic questions like what is free
software why would anyone participate in
free software why would anyone do
anything where they didn't get paid I
mean these always seem to me really
silly questions given how much time
people spend doing things they love
people would also ask well how can you
do anything without employees and titles
you know how how could it possibly work
why would people collaborate how could
you share something and why would we
ever trust it
and when you take all of those together
you know it's clear that that people who
hadn't been involved in floss and in
that era you know they couldn't imagine
it they were living in a different world
and they couldn't conceive of something
different and and the world they were
living in is actually not so dissimilar
from the one of today
it was pre-internet of course but if you
think today of Facebook and Google and
the AWS side of Amazon and you roll all
that up into one company that was the
world we lived in in 2000 or that
company was Microsoft it was deeply
deeply hated but it was the way things
worked and so the even you call them the
Technorati
or the press or the thought leaders or
most software developers really had
trouble imagining how the world could be
different and then the free software and
open-source movement began to grow and
to began to move up the stack of
developer tools into an operating system
into more complicated parts of the stack
and eventually even up to the consumer
product level now that was a surprise
you know all the time we were developing
browsers we were told open source and
free software could never be good enough
for consumers that I was always too
rough around the edges and it was really
only for people who were going to spend
their life using that but but in fact
the free software movement reached a new
level and open source and free software
started to become mainstream and then
then the conversations I had changed and
a whole new set of conversations
appeared and they were questions about
taking the ideas of floss and applying
them to different parts of life and so
there would be questions about I want to
do
open data or open science or I'm an open
architecture project trying to
crowdsource designs of habitable homes
that you know almost no cost for people
who are homeless or you know open
medical records or open health care you
know you name it the the wave of fields
that suddenly realized shared
development collaboration not owning
things making knowledge available became
immense and also the idea of
collaboration or sharing or shared value
began to become mainstream you know in
that era the idea of sharing cars
whether its owner is sharing their cars
through uber or zip cars or shared cars
was simply unimaginable the idea that
you would have a bicycle in a city that
a city would own a bike and allow its
citizens to use it crazy I mean didn't
didn't exist there was zero of it in the
in that era and so open and free
software began to influence whole ranges
of fields and so those fields aren't you
know software per se and don't have
exactly the same criteria but the effect
of a small set of technologists thinking
differently and acting differently and
building something different
became profound but at the same time
something else was happening and that is
free software and open-source software
were at the center of Internet products
but increasingly other aspects were
being added around them and originally
it was other software all you know
according to license so not not
unexpected but but because the software
is not distributed we have free software
and then
there's a fair amount of modifications
made to those which are not returned to
the Commons and then layers of
algorithms or activities which are not
captured or included and in Floss
software so there's a whole layer of
algorithmic thinking behind that and
then of course mass amounts of data that
don't live in a floss like system and so
when we look at the Internet today you
can see that there's floss in the center
and many more layers have closed or
proprietary unknowable activity
surrounding that and so although floss
has been wildly successful at being at
the center of things we live in a state
where sort of closed and proprietary
systems prevail and at the same time the
human experience has been changing you
know in the early days everything is
very positive and optimistic and we
thought of the web as we called it then
as being you know the enabler of
collaboration and empowerment and
freedom and knowledge sharing and all
knowledge for everyone in the world and
a range of very positive things which is
part of it but increasingly you know we
see other activities and the human
experience is sometimes positive and
sometimes increasingly negative and and
today you know one question I'm asked
really frequently is well the the
Internet is broken you know what what
can we do and that's a complicated and
tough problem that has you know software
elements and data it has probably some
regulation in it it needs a lot of
innovation and there's a whole set of
systemic changes to build a system
that's as powerful as it is and also
healthy but there's one element to
making better life online
and that I think rarely gets attention
and that I hope we can make clearer and
more obvious and more active and that is
floss communities and floss software
because the set of what I think of as
floss DNA it is a powerful tool for
building solutions to the problems we
have today
and when I say floss DNA I mean three or
four things one I mean free as in
freedom which obviously is a you know
comes out of the problem of the English
language that that we don't have the
word Libre and so we need to distinguish
free as in freedom you know from free of
charge and that is you know if floss
software is freeze and freedom the
Internet today is free as in free of
charge and the idea of what the freedom
to actually empower yourself and act
looks like is not in the dialogue today
and so the four freedoms of free
software may not apply directly to how
does an individual live but the concept
that you can get engaged that you can
participate that you can see what's
happening that the rules that apply to
me apply to you those core things that
drive the freedom of free software are
not part of the internet experience and
many people can't imagine what that
would look like and and when you talk
about individuals maybe being able to
participate or see their data or use
their data the response is often oh my
gosh that's so hard that couldn't happen
what would look like nobody would care
nobody would do it who would bother how
would you design a system and those
sounds sort of daunting but in fact it's
very very similar to the kinds of
questions people used to ask about free
software and so this
question of how do we make the idea of
participation and the ability to act
right so with software consuming it's
not enough how can i how can I actually
touch it and change it and act is a core
question we face at a broader scale both
at a product development and development
level online and for you know the
consumer and citizen as well so that's
that's one area of floss where the
background and experience in living
could be effective in helping solve
today's problems and also I would say
open as an open source not open as it
has come to mean today which is the
powerful can grab whatever they want and
do whatever they want with it that seems
to be what I hear open what people think
it means but open source you know I mean
lives by the same licenses and
definitions and and lives with a set of
equality and ability to participate the
second area you know free software
creates shared value and that's partly
why we created it is because it's
valuable and it's valuable for for
people of different viewpoints and
perspectives and goals it's not both
centralized this is good for me and
everyone else lives in this system and
today like the idea of shared value or
interoperability or competition or real
sort of linked ability back and forth or
if people being able to take parts of a
project and use it is not part of online
life that we we're back into a closed
system and so once again you know the
idea that of having lived these things
and built the kinds of software that the
floss movement has built is a powerful
tool and in solving these things you
know floss communities also
have a value of collaboration rather
than the command and control of you know
one organization owning and deciding
everything
so another clearly needed value and the
last one I would say is earning
leadership which is closely related to
integrity and Trust you know in a very
different model from being an employee
you know and being told what to do and
the floss world has just such a broad
range of how to earn leadership and what
it means and how you keep leadership and
how you inspire people and how you make
something effective and so you know it
is pretty broad range so for example at
Mozilla we do not have you know leaders
for life some projects do you know as a
as a mark of the founders and respect
and so on so we have a broad diversity
we don't have Mozilla I feel like my job
as a leader is to continue to earn that
leadership and at some point if I'm not
doing the best job or I don't have
anything unique to offer then it's time
for me to move on and and if I don't do
that voluntarily then you know I think
the project should have the right to
make it clear to me that someone else
would be doing a better job I mean I'm
not looking forward to that but but I
think that those sorts of practices and
policies are not common in current
society and that the experience is that
we as a broad community bring have
immense value and so where would we
those things
well one key problem today you know is
online you are the product and so
there's a current understanding that you
need immense profiles to deliver ads and
the conventional wisdom is oh well we
couldn't I mean ads run the system and
you have to have these vast amounts of
data in order to sell ads and I'm really
interested in exploring exactly what
information you need for what purposes
so for example we running and you know
we have a product at Mozilla it's called
pocket and and we're experimenting so I
want to start I'll say it many times we
have no profiles no profiles no profiles
no profiles pocket is about identifying
reading that you want to take some time
to read like what's content that's worth
attention and reflection and so it's a
simple tool you know you save something
to read it for later right turns out
like that doesn't happen that often
online a lot of times people see a
headline and and and share it but but
actually our reading material and so
what we're doing with Bako is to use
those signals
oh that's okay that's okay
I can do it I'm just wondering probably
shouldn't go backward huh this is it so
on the pocket piece left and right there
we go okay so you're going to see some
of the older slides right this is the
set of questions
[Music]
this is the oppa floss at the center you
know the layers that I spoke about being
added around it is a little slow here
closed systems experience on the
internet used to be all sunny now it's
you know we have these very dark
concerns like what's actually happening
what do we do want to answer like this
is something we are not in the
discussion at all like of who are the
sets of people and who has ideas and
lived and built something different than
the conventional software before floss
values freeze and freedom this is the
you know a single entity ringing every
last dollar out of the system no matter
what the cost system we're living in
today with the sort of alternative that
the floss system lives with which is
shared value for many the collaboration
piece I talked about earning leadership
and okay so clearly there's a set of key
problems on life what might we be able
to address so item one you know you are
the product and so this is the the
combination of ads which exist
everywhere so you know both personally
in a Mozilla we are not anti ad I mean
they're annoying and I certainly like
life without them but most of radio and
TV and magazines and newspapers you know
ads are everywhere and they support a
ton of system so we're not ready to say
somehow magically we're going to make
something new that doesn't have ads I
mean I'd love it but I don't I don't
know what to offer but what we are
adamantly opposed to is the current
tracking system
goes with ads and this question of
profiles so we have this experiment with
pocket which is can we deliver
interesting long-form content to you
customized to you without profiles
because the conventional wisdom is you
need a profile for anything and the more
data that you get anywhere the better it
is and so far for long-form content at
least we're finding that yes we can
actually deliver personalized content to
you without a profile now we do that by
having the logic on device and so
information is delivered to your browser
or your pocket wherever it is on your
phone and and that that device obviously
has a lot of information about you and
it makes a selection and you as a user
can say oh I don't ever want to see
anything like that again make it all go
away or you can say oh that's
interesting I ignore it or you can you
know choose to read it or engage in some
fashion and so what we're finding is
that the information that's on your
device which we never see and don't
collect don't use to track you because
we don't have it is quite acceptable for
delivering content that you might enjoy
so that's an interesting experiment
we're not like that's not to say you can
deliver ads I don't know you know that's
a different set of experiments that we
would like to see lots of people being
able to engage in and then there's a
kind of profile which is useful for
encouraging people to do all sorts of
things and and that's the kind of
profile that sucks up all the data about
you and uses every last thing you know
and uses that profile knows probably
more about what motivates you than you
do so we've seen for example use an
example out of the United States
probably Russian of targeting very
specific groups of people with the goal
of getting you know X percentage of this
group to come to a demonstration
because they're outraged about X and at
the same time targeting another group of
people to come to the same demonstration
because they're outraged about the
opposite and so the actual creation
through micro targeting based on
profiles of a civil protest and so
that's a special kind of profile right
that's the and and the conventional
wisdom is that gathering everything up
this is like this happened on Facebook
so just to say that like yes you need
all that information in order to be able
to do socially useful things but we
don't actually know that like is it
socially useful to outraged groups of
people so they go out on the street and
fight each other over something that
isn't actually real like probably not so
I think it's a very interesting question
of what do you actually need to run I'll
call it mainstream commerce you know
whether it's content or even ads versus
how much information is being collected
about us now and used to manipulate
behavior and I think if if we could
build more products that tested more of
these things it would tell us whether
some form of information gathering is
just socially terrible right and and
that the business of targeting at a
level of manipulation where you can
intentionally create violent
disturbances might be treated
differently than a profile that was
adequate for e-commerce and that
requires a lot of testing right it
requires research on an academic level
and it also requires you know you know
products that are on the like how much
information do I actually need to do
something legitimate and so I mentioned
product pocket because it's one
sometimes if I say that without an
example people think Oh
you're kind of crazy or what would that
mean but but we have one in the market
that's you know actually well-received
and so that I think is a power of floss
software is to build and test those
things and demonstrate that a different
kind of product and experience is
possible originally these had
transitions so that's why there's so
many of these slides in here but a
second problem is clearly content and
misinformation and how do we even know
what might be reliable or whether it
fits our criteria of trust or not and
this is another area where
experimentation in software and products
is important so we have a little
experiment here too called the Facebook
ad analyzer which is currently awarded
by Facebook so we'll see what happens
but but what this you know the Facebook
has information about here's an ad
here's the organization that's paying
for the ad and here are the targeting
criteria and so this is an election
cycle in the EU and we thought it would
be helpful when you're seeing ads about
EU candidates to be able to you know
select an ad and say well eh who's
paying for it and why am i seeing it am
i seeing it because I'm a woman in a
certain age group living here or am i
seeing it because I went to some
particular site about immigration and
got tagged as you know Pro immigration
anti immigration Pro acts so this is
because that transparency of political
ads in
in the EU is highly regulated and is
seen as an important piece we've been
trying to bring some added transparency
to the current election cycle but
Facebook broke that in the last couple
of days and so this is clearly an area
that requires either the big platforms
to be interested in it or some kind of
regulatory engagement now fortunately
the EU has been involved in this and
there is a code of practice and we
believe that Facebook actually agreed to
make this information available and so
we've asked the EU Commission to look
into it and see if our understanding
that this add information should be
available for the for the political apps
and so this is an area of product
experimentation which is harder to do
unless you're involved in policy or
unless there is some policy or practice
in place but it's also an area where the
EU is you know world leader and so we
think that there's increasing
possibility here and I know like in the
early days of PLoS like for the first
decade of Mozilla I did not want us
engaging in things that required policy
activities that because they're hard
it's a different skill set you know but
about a decade ago I thought the time
had changed so so Mozilla's active in
policy and the good news is there are a
lot of I would say Internet activists
who are realistic policy driven so in
these questions oh wow I want to build
software you know I don't want to deal
with codes of practice or regulators the
good news is there are many people out
there who do and what what they really
need is connections to technologists and
so the will and energy to do this is
very high particularly in Europe and
developing better connections between I
would say not just technologists but the
floss community in particular and these
advocacy groups would help us a fair
amount and the third big area
really to aim at I call the addiction
economy maybe I'll go back on that one
because not what the you know the
designers of internet experiences what
they're aiming for is to make people
happy because when you're happy you stay
on their site you engage in their site
you do the things that generate revenue
for them but it turns out and the
research is showing that what really the
look like that fight-or-flight response
the way you activate human beings
quickest and fastest is with fear and
outrage and so even with the motivation
of people being happy to stay on their
site a lot of the most effective ways of
doing that are appealing to the I would
say more difficult sides of human nature
fear anger outrage violence and so the
addiction economy given human nature is
very closely tied into lost a few of
them but it's closely tied into these
practices that we're seeing where the
degree of violence and anger and
disruptive behavior online is really
quite high let's just see okay and so
that that leads us to the question you
know we saw this a little bit in open
source communities early on where when
people came online
you know you sometimes you'd find really
aggressive and nasty behavior and and
women in Floss communities early on were
targeted quite aggressively and the
overall level of discourse was a little
nasty at least for people who came into
it you know at Mozilla this was a
constant problem as we were trying to
introduce new people into the open
source world and they would be wow you
know what you're trying to do is so nice
but the online discussion is
harsh well it turns out that has zero to
do with free software or open source
communities that's for some reason what
much of humanity does when we first
encounter these tools like the harshness
comes out and so you see it and like how
common death threats are online today
you know and I would bet real money that
if and when we track down you know these
deaths and you know rape and torture
threats many people will be otherwise of
standing citizens that somehow feel free
online you know to engage in this
behavior so figuring out like what is it
that encourages something better than
that and how do we break this cycle and
here again I think free software and
open-source communities have a lot to
offer because we've been dealing with it
for a while and the quality of discourse
in our communities has changed and the
standards of behaviors have changed and
community practice and community
etiquette and what is acceptable and how
do you deal with the troll or a Poisson
person like we have a set of experience
in those things that is certainly
imperfect and we have far more to go but
nevertheless it's a stage ahead of where
most people trying to deal with these
kinds of questions are and so just as we
were early in the sharing and
collaborative and freedom aspect the how
do you make a community what's healthy
how do you get to better behavior we
have some experience with it and I'll go
back and say I'm quite convinced that
technologists have a huge role to play
in how do we create software and
products and online experiences that are
encouraging better aspects of human
nature that currently the economy is
driving towards the addiction economy
where you're the product and where we're
gathering so much information that
are easy to manipulate and so I think
absolutely requires technologists to be
involved and to be committed to that and
so in the last few years I personally
and for Mozilla felt really compelled to
make that commitment clear compelled
because you know the open system the
open Internet
the World Wide Web you know the
graphical layer which is open open
source free software like these are so
fundamental and so important and yet not
enough they are not enough to create an
online life that is decent they're not
enough to stop trolls they're not enough
on their own to be an alternative the
systems that encourage sort of outrage
and violence and so i felt quite
compelled that that at least i and
testing you know mozilla felt equally
committed to something different and so
we've made some commitments you know
Mozilla's clearly it's an open source
project i think the speaker before noted
were imperfect but committed to open
source we have a manifesto that talks
about security and privacy and
individual empowerment and just felt we
needed something more and so we set out
four additional things about the
internet that are important to us you
know one that it's inclusive that's the
wrong button here you know internet
experiences software and products
currently are encouraged outraged what
would it look like if we were actually
trying to encourage civil discourse you
know and rationality and thoughtfulness
you might not maybe be the richest
company on the face of the earth but
that's not what really floss aims to be
and then finally we are actually
committed to trying to take that value
of collaborate
and shared good and trying to extend it
further from the floss software itself
out into other areas and I was happy to
find that you know not just me
personally but that this sort of
resonated within Mozilla so we've
adopted it as part of our core sort of
manifesto and and how we think of of who
we are and it it may or may not be quite
right for you because floss is really
varied and we have lots of diversity
among us but I am hopeful that as a
community of communities this question
of can we actually build a better online
life is is increasingly important and
that we actually can represent ourselves
well in the overall discussion which is
lacking in technologists when you at
least in there in the worlds that I
travel in or it is hard to find a large
loud technical voice other than the
large platforms so Mozilla is very
welcome when we show up and that's great
and there's a lot of diversity and floss
so it would be great to see others as
well and then finally the last thing
that Mozilla does that not all floss
projects do is really focus on the
consumer because you know that's most of
humanity and that's where there's a
certain kind of impact like that's a
messy place to be as a floss project
because you have to take what you're
trying to accomplish as floss and in our
case with the manifesto and yet build a
product you know that consumers want
which is generally free of charge and
convenient and fun and interesting so
it's messy you know and and causes us to
be you know imperfect in many ways but
it is a piece of the puzzle that we try
to bring to the overalls or floss world
and so to circle back to the core point
that floss communities floss DNA and the
floss principles can
be like a powerful force for improving
the state of Internet life and I hope
you find that to be true and I certainly
hope you find if you're interested ways
to be effective at that and if you were
trying to do such things you know I
certainly offer myself and Mozilla to
try and provide whatever I don't know
support or assistance or cheerleading or
anything else that we can do to help
more people be successful thank you
and I think they're not here but I want
to say special thanks to the volunteers
and crew here who made up for my lost
adapter so just a small announcement
there are still five minutes for
questions so if you have a question
please let me know I will give you the
microphone for that and please if you
are leaving be quiet
still the session is is not your finish
I have a question okay on the on
dominance practically you mentioned that
large corporations dominating the
internet so on a technology side when
you look at the browser's we now we see
today that practically the domination is
chromium in floss sense or Google Chrome
and it's it's not modular anymore so so
I'm and I'm guessing that most of the
people here in this room also use Chrome
and I'm a little worried about that so
what what do you think about this kind
of domination on the desktop I would say
yes so their question about the risk of
domination in the browser space or the
desktop yeah I think it's quite real i I
do want to admit that there were some
years there and which chrome was a
better browser I think that that time
has passed
and certainly technically you know it's
great to have the crown again and so it
is a question of why use chromium or why
use Chrome
you know sometimes Google breaks things
except for Chrome it's only a day or two
and it's always some low-level product
manager that just can't be controlled so
maybe that's why but I actually am
interested it'd be interesting you know
to know I think it's so real risk and I
what I really think is at risk is what
we call the web like so why do we care
so much yeah I love Firefox right but
but really why do we care so much we
care because right now Google is almost
free to do whatever it wants and call it
the web and it does it makes up api's
sometimes they're useful sometimes
they're really Google specific sometimes
they have tons of problems there isn't
like there are standards bodies but you
know with its market share it doesn't
really matter
and so the reason that we care about
Firefox yes there's a product piece and
we love it but the core reason is the
web and we are about to lose the web
like interoperable multi-vendor
platform I mean we don't think of the
web now but the technology that we call
the Internet the graphical lay all the
stuff that you can see and that gets
delivered through a browser engine
whatever app you're using soon that is
about to be Google again the only thing
standing in its way right now is Firefox
or gecko and it is not at all clear that
we are gonna succeed
I should be loud and clear about that
the question of whether we have what we
used to think of as the web is the
question right now and we are investing
a ton and it is so expensive because for
some reason Google has accelerated the
number of people in development and
stuff they're adding in in a way that's
very hard to keep up with and and and I
guess it's good for developers but that
question like the next year may tell
that question right and so we're still
committed because you know we love the
web I mean but but something that's
interoperable like we're just on the
edge so I don't anyway I guess thank you
for asking because I clearly care about
it so a couple of years ago at PAWS dam
2014 I believe I went to a great talk by
a guy called Paul Henning camp who gave
it to a satirical talk about the state
of online security he speculated that
the influence of the NSA and GCHQ was
deliberately weakening online security
and in the face of such powerful
influence against our sort of interests
and the technical solutions were
ineffective he concluded his talk by
saying that this is a political problem
this is not a technical problem and I
guess you could make a similar argument
in the sense that such heavily heavy
influencers Google and Facebook and kind
of faces interference in elections and
you could say that well in the face of
such heavy heavy
Faust's technical solutions are in
effect you know I'm sorry I'm really
having trouble hearing sorry and what
would you say to the the proposal that
in the face of such heavy influence by
Facebook and Google against sort of
freedom and online privacy
the technical solutions are ineffective
that this is a political problem well
sort of monopolies are part political
part technical problem for one well
that's interesting is it a political or
a technical problem like well the the
issue is it's actually both right now
how do you regulate right and so that
that is part of why I think that the
flossed communities are important
because you need experimentation to know
how to regulate so for example you know
if the EU Commission appeared in front
of us and said just tell us what to do
like what's the answer like you could
you could say the basic ad model is
unacceptable right what happens then
right and let's say you know like do you
want to not have facebook I don't know
so so so that question and then the
other political question is sometimes
you can't ant innovate because the
monopolies are so powerful Allah the ad
problem that we're having and then
that's a political question but it needs
the technical voice in there to explain
it and thus my pitch for you know if you
find the local Internet advocates who
are trying to advocate for privacy but
don't know anything about technology
like you know even if your inclination
is to kind of like leave them you know a
little bit of help on technical chops
will go a long way so thank you yeah
let's thank our speaker with
[Applause]
you