please welcome Robert Smith who's a
passion of comic disc pecker and is also
the director of software engineering at
Righetti which is one of the big part of
computing hardware players in the
universal at their base in San Francisco
or actually in Berkeley and he's going
to talk about forests and open source
quantum software development right cool
I'm super happy to be here
my background is very very much in
software only in the past few years I
kind of get into the quantum business
and so being at an open-source
conference and seeing that quantum is
here at the open source conference is
really exciting for me before I start I
just want to understand the audience a
little bit better how many of you are
not sort of professionally in quantum
computing not an academia quantum
computing in academia or anything like
that
all right that's that's good that's
really great how many so this is my
personal just kind of what I want to
know how many of you know anything about
Lisp all right that's pretty good -
that's more than I would expect cool a
little bit about Righetti so we build
get the little mouse pointer of the way
we build Universal gate based hybrid
classical quantum computers so these are
machines that are not just they don't
just do quantum computations they
interact with the classical computer as
well very much in concert classical
computer might produce results that
affect the quantum computation the
quantum computer might produce results
that affect affect a classical
computation as was said in the last in
the keynote
the Kuan computers aren't really doing
computations right now that exceed what
a classical computer can do but
nonetheless they do interesting
computations they're doing real
computations they're not just they're
not just you know theoretical equations
or anything like that you can compute
real things about the physical world for
instance we're a full-stack company so
we do everything in-house more or less
all the way from the design of silicon
chips
fabrication of chips we have our own
fabrication facility everything in
between all the way to building
applications on top of the chip or on
top of the computer we have a very wide
range of papers published again
basically any of these horizontals here
we probably have a paper in and our
flagship product is called quantum cloud
services so quantum cloud services is
something that we just released publicly
as a beta as far as I know it's the
fastest quantum programming environment
available right now it's about 30 times
faster than an HTTP based service this
comes from a lot of different things all
across the stack and this is one of the
benefits of being a full stack company
it's not just that we got some you know
clever hardware trick-or or something
like that it really took a combination
of infrastructure hardware and software
to gain these speed ups so as a part of
this as a part of the kuan cloud
services you get your own qmi it's a
virtual machine comes pre-loaded with a
bunch of software including our forest
sdk so force sdk is the software
development kit that includes a very
powerful arrangement of software to
write build and execute quantum programs
this includes a compiler a simulator a
Python API and a set of optional
libraries on top of that so pretty early
on at Righetti I joined Righetti when it
was around 20 or so people pretty early
on at Righetti we were very interested I
actually credit it to will Zhang a lot
who planted the seed at the company to
try to maintain sort of openness in a
lot of our ideas and a lot of our
software and so on so being in kind of
open source slash open standards isn't
something that's relatively new we've
been doing it for the past three or so
years maybe one of the big milestones
was about three years ago we released an
open standard for a quantum instruction
language called quill so quill is this
assembly looking code it's not assembly
doesn't run natively on the machine it
requires further compilation but it
looks like an assembly code
that describes hybrid classical quantum
programs and we we publish a standard
and a little bit to my surprise
certainly we saw these little libraries
popping up somebody wrote something in
Haskell for instance to construct quill
circuits I myself out of interest wrote
something in Lisp somebody else wrote
something in oak Hamill just all these
things came out and that sort of is a
testament to kind of you know when you
provide something that's open that's
well specified that's well documented it
gets adopted and people are kind of
interested in it since the release of
the standard for quill we've you know
had a good handful of different open
source libraries all of these are
homegrown or at least adopted by us and
then beyond that we've you know
contributed back to any number of open
source projects one of my favorite was a
tool for editing CAD files and we found
a few bugs in it contributed back it's
nice to you know design these quantum
circuits as you know you know within CAD
and finding these things and being able
to contribute back so I'll very briefly
talk about kind of the force SDK you can
kind of think of it as a sort of layered
architecture like so at the top you have
your applications the things you're
building on top of the platform this
includes Grove which contains a lot of
different textbook algorithms a lot of
different things you'd find in any sort
of course on quantum computing for
instance we just released an alpha
version of something called force
benchmarking which contains a lot of
very very easy to read routines for how
to benchmark and classify the quality of
a quantum computer and then we have a
bunch of partner apps and these this is
kind of the layer where you would build
if you are interested in building
programs for your clone computer or for
a quantum computer below that is Pike
well it's a Python library that allows
you to write quill programs that
contains a lot more than that contains
an API to talk the machine it contains a
good API for interacting with the
compiler that contains some mathematical
routines if you want to translate sort
of a mathematical problem into a quantum
computing problem and so on below that
we have a little RPC framework
just to have everything in the stack
communicate with each other
below that is a compiler called quill
see this is the compiler that'll take
quill code and compile it to the native
gate set of the quantum computer the
native instruction side of the machine
on the right here you could imagine this
this box right here going down and down
and down that's you know that's where
you actually start executing things on
the machine that gets is a firmware
level that gets into the control system
level and so on but to the left you can
replace all of that of course with a
simulator that's going to be a lot
slower than the real machine of course
but serves as a good method for
debugging and so on so there we have
something called the qvm the quantum
virtual machine which I'll talk about in
a little bit in PI qvm which is
something built into PI quill it's a
simulator written in Python
hence person let's talk I'm going to
talk about two main components here the
compiler and specifically the qvm so the
qvm it seems like everybody in there
brother and sister and dog has kind of
made a simulator these days there's a
billion of them online simulating a
quantum computer it's kind of a fun
problem to work through it's a it's a
thing that you need to do if you're
going to be working with quantum
computing at all but there is a lot of
great things that you can put into a
simulator to make it more efficient to
make it more useful to make it better
for debugging and so on so our simulator
the one that we call kind of the qvm is
very very high performance if you can
throw it on any machine I mean you know
they think the biggest we've thrown it
on is something that has like 12
terabytes of memory and you know for
socket motherboard with you know
something like 224 logical cores or
something like that and it'll use all of
it it's completely multi-threaded it's a
good way to heat up your house if that's
what you're aiming to do it can execute
the entire quo language it does all the
classical all the quantum stuff it has
lots and lots of different ways to
execute programs kind of the standard
ways do something called standard
pure state evolution it kind of assumes
that your computer is perfect that has
no errors that it's you know kind of
living in that you know fairytale land
but then you have these other execution
modes like the stochastic pure state
evolution full density matrix simulation
if you want that and then some other
things I haven't personally found
particularly use for them but stuff like
the path integral formulation if you
want to compute just a single amplitude
of your exponentially sized state like I
said I can simulate perfect in in
perfect quantum computers but the thing
I'm most excited about about the
simulator is actually as a part of the
simulator contains a compiler that
compiles the quill code into native
instructions of your computer so it's
not trying to interpret the instructions
actually compiles it all the machine
code and because of that you get really
really fast execution sometimes
outperforming some state-of-the-art
simulators you know written in you know
the finest you know toothpick and
tweezers you know C code sometimes by 2x
because it dynamically it's able to do
what a compiler does and so I want to
show a little demonstration of that just
a real quick one so if I run the qvm
program
I'm gonna save verbose and I'm just
gonna run one of the standard standard
benchmark modes which computes a GHz
State entangled state ax and say I think
the default is 26 qubits so if you see
it run it you can see each gate these
gates over here the Hadamard at the top
see not taking about 500 milliseconds on
my laptop per gate will let it get to
the end just so you can feel how long
this stuff takes to compare on a real
actual quantum computer each of those
gates would take on the order of maybe
50 nanoseconds or so so we see the run
time at the end was about 20 seconds and
all of this was without compilation so
if I tell it to compile what it's going
to do is take the quill program that was
that's being benchmark here it's gonna
compile to machine code and then run it
and so if we do that you just see the
difference is a lot and we just you know
got 10x speed up just by pre compiling
the circuit
want to move on from the simulator and
talk about our compiler which I'm even
more excited about so as far as I
understand
quill C is the only truly sort of
general-purpose fully automatic
optimizing compiler which means it's
sort of turnkey you can run the program
it'll compile it doesn't need any extra
information you'll need to give it
specific steps on how to compile or
anything like that you give it your
program and it will compile to specific
architecture it was built with
portability in mind of course we use it
at Righetti computing to compile for our
architectures we were trying to build as
a general purpose tool because you know
we designed different chips we try out
different gate sets and every single
time we do that we don't want to have to
like rewind and and figure out how to
recompile our programs and everything I
can compile any unitary gate at least in
a unitary gate that feasibly fits in
memory and that you have time to compile
for so you know two three four queue
gates it doesn't matter and most
interestingly it has a lot in it and
we're still adding to it of course lots
and lots of different ways of optimizing
your program it does a lot of things
that have a lot of similarity to
classical compiler theory so it does
something similar to register allocation
it tries to figure out what qubits what
actual physical qubits it should use
given your logical qubits in the program
does something similar to people
optimization will scan sections of your
code and try to compress or optimize
them flow analysis when you have
classical portions of your program when
you have jump statements and loops and
if statements and whatever it analyzes
the control flow of your program it does
all the classical stuff like dead code
elimination and all that and then for
some cases like tube qubit gates it
actually has routines for doing optimal
compilation it will it will compile it
in the best way that you know
mathematics has proven to be the best
like I said I'm a software person I've
been writing software since I was like
eight years old and it's definitely one
of the most interesting pieces of
software that I've been able to work on
in my career me and my colleagues
so I can show a little demo of this as
well we kind of follow the standard of
being very UNIX II with the application
so just by default if you run it it's
going to take input from standard n if I
make like a Bell State for instance and
end it it compiles it by default to one
of our eight qubit rings that we have so
it compiled that hata martin and see not
at the top to that program out there it
turned it into z rotations x rotations
and CZ so in this case the default ship
that it compiles to is one where CZ is
the gate that can operate between edges
one of our researchers at work was a
messing around with the bernstein
maserati algorithm which for those
unfamiliar contains kind of this portion
of the algorithm where you have to
define something called an oracle and
depending on what your goals are as a
researcher maybe you're not trying to
think about exactly how to construct
this oracle maybe you're just I don't
know trying to get your work done and
you just want to try running it on the
quantum computer so what he did is he
defined this giant matrix that's what
all these ones and zeros and all this
stuff are and then his actual program so
you see he does a bunch of he doesn't X
get a bunch of Hadamard this giant five
qubit operator and so on and so if I cat
Bernstein Boz irani in to quill C and
I'm gonna make it measure gate depth in
and all of that it'll think about it for
a second
and it gives the answer so it decomposed
this five cubed gate into a bunch of
gates we can see at the bottom it
compiled it into a circuit that's of
depth 2746 gates which is way too many
to execute a knee current quantum
computer for the record but it starts
giving it an idea of how this circuit
would actually be realized on the real
machine so one point that that I like to
make is that I really really believe in
automatic compilation sometimes I feel
that that some folks in the field are
maybe like in the 1950s or something
where I know our quantum computers
currently aren't these machines that can
execute hundreds or thousands or
millions of gates yet like we're still
kind of poking around with you know
gates measured between 10 and 100 cubits
we're still looking at gate depths that
are you know measured you know still on
in on both your hands and it is
reasonable to construct programs by hand
that way but in general to not have a
tool that you can use to to study the
mathematics of a problem to debug things
to even see how decomposes into you know
the actual native code of your machine I
think it's I think it's not good to have
such a tool I also think that computers
are just exceedingly good at doing what
they do I mean compilers these day like
GCC clang all of those they're amazing
they're incredible if you can see what
like Intel's Fortran compiler does does
amazing things on its real testament
that computers are really good at
figuring things out at calculating
things so I do have this belief that
like if we're able to like confidently
write C for small microcontrollers that
contain you know K of RAM then we can
write quill or some other instruction
set for a quantum computer that passes
through a compiler as quill C perfect at
this and is it like outperforming like
hand compiled circuits no but can quill
C compile a circuit faster than you
could almost surely yes sometimes
circuits take like I don't know three
days by hand to figure out even what
what to do so I want to give a little
example to show what quill C even thinks
about so if I pass the verbose option
I'm going to compile this Berenstain baz
irani circuit again but this time going
to say
just tell me everything you're thinking
compiler and this is everything oh of
course
maybe scroll after it stops thinking or
I'll just control see it you can see
here it's it's going through it's
looking at different sub sequences
here's looking at RX r z RX it's going
to try to collapse that in some way and
it just continues until it you know it
just tears your program apart lots and
lots of interesting stuff i like seeing
the compiler think because it again
reminds me that smarter than i am i want
to talk a little bit about what even a
compiler target for a quantum computer
looks like generally you have a graph of
qubits that are connected in some way
physically on a chip somebody actually
etched metal or something into the chip
to link these qubits together so you
have a graph of qubits each single qubit
can have some operation on it usually
for superconducting qubits you're firing
some microwave pulse for example in
quill you could have an R X PI over 2
gate or an RZ totally parametric or
fixed each qubit pair can have
operations some example gates are CCC
not example parametric data C phase
where you can actually give it a
parameter and then there are even gates
that happen on qubit triplets or
quadruplets and whatever and one of the
you know examples that I know is the
mole mer Sorensen gate for ion traps
where you can actually perform a gate
simultaneously on many qubits
importantly though it may be that
depending on the design of your quantum
computer different qubits might have
different operations tuned for them so
we could imagine a four qubit quantum
computer I mean this is crazy I don't
think anybody would actually build this
to be clear where each qubit here has
some single qubit operations but each
qubit pair has a different set of native
operations so what this diagram is
showing is that qubit zero and one may
support a seesee operation on them cubed
zero and two might only ever see not
only in one direction you know and so on
and so forth and so we design Quilici to
accommodate chip designs that may have
this and so quill see
compiled a circuit there and like I
would challenge you to try to construct
a GHz state on an architecture that has
this I mean I don't know I'd be a waste
of time I think it's probably waste of
time to make the chip - so for FOSDEM
kind of as a testament to this we
actually ported Quilici to what we know
about google's Brist Bristlecone
architecture which is 72 qubits we
ported it to IBM's
IBM qx5 chip again what we could learn
about it from papers online everything
any program that was written in quill
any program that works in Grove anything
at all will compile to any of our chips
- again what we could find about the
Bristlecone chip by Google IBM qx5 chip
but not only that it'll actually try to
optimize for those architectures it can
work with the full chip or you can
actually select sub graphs of that chip
and it will compile for those and again
as far as I know I don't really know of
other compilers that are able to to kind
of do this job so as little demo I'm
actually wrote a program with this
mullmer Sorensen Gates if I look at it
you can see this crazy crazy big gate I
think this one's on yeah for cubits the
program down here is just doing mulmer
Sorensen on for cubits
so if I cat mulmer Sorensen into quill
see I'm going to show the gate depth and
I'm going to compile it for our 8q ring
it'll do something so gate that this is
about 319 if I do is a Bristlecone raise
if I can spell it right grace
it'll think about it more and actually
found a smaller gate DEP not by a lot
but a little bit we could do it for IBM
qx5 and by the way this argument here
this is a argument is actually
parametric you can supply to file to
describe the chip that you have instead
of like baking it into the compiler so
this one it like doubled the gate death
took it took six hundred gates I want to
show one last thing where we have some
advanced features of the compiler that
can even optimize it more so the
argument is enable state prep enable
state prep reductions so again like a
normal compiler you know with your
compiling C code you pass Oh 3 or minus
F fast math or whatever we have similar
things this argument here says compile
the program and assume that we're
starting in initial zero state typically
that's what you assume when you write a
quantum program and if you can make that
assumption it'll actually take that into
account in the compilation process it'll
partially simulate it and we actually
get down to a gate depth of a third of
what we got before so there are all
different ways you can coax the compiler
into compiling things and get more and
more efficient circuits so qpm and quill
C are free to download we just released
the Windows version we for the cubm we
do have an open source alternative like
I said the PI qvm it doesn't have all of
the things but it is licensed under
Apache 2 it's much slower if you're
doing it for lots of qubits but if all
of your work is in Python it's actually
much faster if you're doing one or two
or three cubic computations because
there's no overhead communicating with
this external process and so on and
there's no real alternative to quill C
and maybe in that case if you don't want
to use this thing then you can you know
compile things by hand ER or use some of
the more manual alternatives so I wanted
to talk a little bit about kind of from
a startup perspective open and close
source software and so it's a little bit
tricky at a startup
like what you should decide to do when
you want to work in software especially
when the startup is small like Righetti
and when all your competition is quite
large
from the perspective open-source there's
a lot of great things languages should
definitely be open sourced it's nice
when you have a language that's
open-source and API is because people
can help develop them and so on it's
good when your RPC framework is
open-source because that means people
can plug into your architecture in
various ways and open-source allows us
to like understand what customers
actually want and use more on the other
hand for a company again like ours when
you develop a lot of great IP and
everything it's not something that you
necessarily just want to give away it's
something that that you want to kind of
hold close to yourself it's something
that you can use this competitive
advantage I actually don't really want
to waste time talking about it because
I'm just kidding anyway so actually what
I want to do is kind of live at FOSDEM
open-source quill C and then why not
which one is this
so we'll see hopefully should be visible
to you qvm let's I think UVM became
public there shouldn't be the private
symbol anymore yeah I think it's public
now
so anyway feel free to start looking at
the code all of the code is licensed
under Apache 2 there is one little
front-end UI component that's a GPL so
no other licenses and there no EULA's no
anything it should be all free and
open-source so you guys are truly the
first to know it wasn't announced or
anything any earlier and you saw it with
your own eyes so so I'm American and
hopefully nobody like mistook my shirt
for being like Colonel Sanders or
something
my shirt is in fact John McCarthy who
was the inventor of Lisp
and early on we wrote the qvm an initial
prototype in Lisp and the compiler and
Lisp I don't think many of the
innovations that we've had could have
happened if were not originally written
in Lisp we don't have teams of you know
tens or hundreds of developers
originally the team was the software
team was actually like two or three
people way back when the company was
twenty people in developing and Lisp was
pretty
time and money efficient more or less
it's very snappy to develop more over
like quantum computing is an interesting
field in that not I don't think anybody
has really figured out a great
expressive syntax for expressing
programs for being able to take an idea
on one's mind and actually convert it
into something that that runs on a
machine I mean quill and and Kasim and
all of these things are good starts I
think they describe a machine
representation of a program but they
don't necessarily make it easy to take
an idea you know in one's mind and put
it on paper and so Lisp is a wonderful
substrate for testing too
syntactic abstractions different ways of
arranging characters on a screen in
order to express some type of
computation the real real real reason
though is that a compiler and optimising
compiler I don't know if anybody's
hacked on you know an optimizing
compiler before but they're very
difficult to debug if you get a wrong
answer you put in let's say we were
compiling that mullmer source and gates
and at the end we detect that's the
wrong answer like where do you start to
even debug something like that and so in
Lisp in particularly with Emacs and
slime which are both also free software
you can inspect everything you can open
up everything live while the code is
running while the compiler is running
you can actually open a repple and
inspect all of the state inside the
compiler inspect what it's doing how
it's working all of that stuff not just
verbose printing out on the screen but
actual interactivity you know and
there's kind of the usual argument of
you know it's lips Lisp so maybe it's
hard to learn or something like that
almost all of our programmers barring me
and I think one other were professional
Lisp programmers prior and most people
are productive within a few days it's
not like a purely functional language or
anything like that if you want to mutate
state and do all that stuff you can
absolutely do it I have to do it for the
qvm to make it efficient so most people
can learn it and if you're interested in
learning it there's a free book it's
been out for I don't know how long now
ten years or so practical Common Lisp if
all of you probably are programmers
already so if you want to check it out
great book so if you find yourself
wanting to be in superposition with the
beer at some point I invented this beer
plus you over root to challenge if
anybody again you guys are the first to
know of the first three people if you
solve any of the issues on github we
tried to even internally keep a list of
issues if you fix a bug if you just make
any interesting contribution I'm happy
to have a beer with you it'll be on me I
should say thanks to all of my
colleagues at regatta but in particular
I'd like to give thanks to Eric Peterson
he's one of the
principal architects of the compiler
he's also an algebraic topology so he
thinks about like chips as like you know
and dimensional simplices and all this
stuff that doesn't make any sense
mark skill back lauren Capilouto will
zhang chad Righetti and the rest of the
team really for for supporting building
this effort and for really thinking
about quantum software engineering is
like a thing unto itself my emails down
there the code on github is Righetti /qv
m and Righetti slash cool c and we do
have a slack channel if you go to
Righetti slash community you can find
the link to our slack channel i'm on it
a lot of other people are on it happy to
chat about this stuff and thank you all
for listening it's really fun
[Applause]
yes that's right so the simulator is
going to just simulate a quill program
oh yes so the question was well first
there was a comment saying that that I
said that the compiler was is only of
its kind and in this gentleman said that
there are there is some other software
that provides a lot of similar features
and none the question was does is a
simulator general enough to support
other architectures like the IBM qx5 for
instance the simulator kind of developed
from a theory of something that we wrote
in the quill paper called the quantum
abstract machine so it's a simulator for
in abstract machine it's a classical
simulation it doesn't restrict itself to
any particular gate or architecture well
whatever gate you throw at it it will
simulate I will not error if you say I'm
doing this gate on this architecture
presumably you would pass it through the
compiler first before simulating it if
you wanted to restrict it to the gates
of that architecture with that said
however for instance with our chips we
do develop noise models that are you
know similar or at least somewhat
characteristic of of our chips and you
can supply that to the qvm and it will
be able to it will be able to simulate
that but otherwise there isn't any like
hard-line restriction on the gates that
it simulates no
yep so yeah so I don't think I'm the
best person to answer this I think you
yes I keep forgetting what fields in
terms of practical applicability what
fields is quantum computing sort of good
or useful for I don't think I'm the
greatest person to answer this question
I think I definitely want to learn a lot
from the people here but my take on it
is there are two things that that we've
definitely been focusing on two things
that seem to be popular in the field
quantum chemistry simulating dynamic
simulating different aspects of
molecules finding energy states and
energy levels and so on
and optimization problem is usually
finding the maximum or minimum of some
constrained optimization problem I would
say so that ties in to logistics and and
what-have-you but I do want to reiterate
we haven't solved a problem on a quantum
computer again that I know of that like
outperforms something that we've
competed classically we've done great
proof of concepts you know kind of
almost the hello world of quantum
computation almost seems to be computing
the energy of like a dihydrogen molecule
at different bond distances it's
something you can compute today but
that's also something that my laptop
compute so but those seem to be the
promising areas yep
it's called postpartum
yeah the question is what's the state of
post quantum crypto I actually don't
know anything about it and I think we
have a talk later that's going to be
about it so that's definitely something
I'm interested in hearing about as well
yep yeah right Yeah right
sure the question is I said quill is
like anise it's like an assembly like
language is there like an equivalent of
like the end binary that would be like
loaded into memory where it actually
gets executed quill like other sort of
big air quotes assembly quote-unquote
languages are not true assemblies
they're not languages that run native on
the machine generally not even a binary
encoding runs native on the machine in
the end these things at least with
current control systems I and on
microwave devices to be clear
superconducting devices that are driven
by microwaves usually in the end the
quote that the quill program will be
something general that has all these you
know funny gates like if I go back and
look at this
you know there's mullmer Sorenson thing
like even though it looks like assembly
that's definitely not something any
superconducting computer will run an ion
trap or some can run this natively but
not any superconducting chip and so what
happens is this passes through a
compiler and you get quill back out but
this quill is now in one-to-one mapping
with what your machine will run
generally after that you're going to
pass it to another sort of translator
almost like a true assembler now which
gets turned into code that runs on your
control system even when it gets on the
control system however it's not going to
be like one single binary that runs
single threaded often times since qubits
can be excited in parallel you're
actually loading this code onto a bunch
of things that are driving a bunch of
different D to a converters and ATD
converters for readout and so on so
there is a little bit more that has to
happen after this for a compilation yeah
so one of the main metrics there are a
few metrics but one of them were like
the 30x thing came from was one of the
popular things that we do there's an
algorithm called
sorry the question was where did the 30x
come from I stayed at 30 X speed up
before where'd that come from so yeah so
generally the comparison was kind of the
realm of HTTP HTTP based services where
you construct a job of some sort you
have a program that you'd like to run
you ship it off to you know some service
ingesting this job it processes it
packages up the answer sends it back to
you over the Internet and perhaps first
a lot of programming and quantum
computing you either have to do that a
lot because maybe you're scanning over a
range of things or your program itself
is actually changing frequently you
might be generating a new circuit for
every run of your of your program so you
might be optimizing let's suppose you're
finding the maximum of something you
construct an initial program you send it
you get the answer back you evaluate
whether that was good or bad maybe it's
not good so you take a step in another
direction construct a new circuit send
it receive it so those types of use
cases were what we were comparing to
specifically vqe and QA Oh a algorithm
if you're familiar with those names
that's what we are comparing it to where
the speed ups come from our locality
with the machine on a qmi you're
actually running local to the chip
itself you're your virtual machine is
actually resident on the machine with
the control system what is it called
fast reset with fast feedback or active
reset is another one where we can zero
the state of the machine by kind of
forcing it to be zero we can send pulses
in measure and and bring it down to the
zero state as opposed to kind of
stepping off the background letting the
Machine kind of slowly get back so you
can really iterate your program fast and
the third thing that we introduced is
something called parametric compilation
where the compiler itself not only takes
a fixed set of gates but can actually
take a parametric description of your
gates where you have unknown variables
and still compile it into your native
gate set and with that with parametric
compilation that means you don't have to
compile each loop around when you hit
the actual hardware and so that's kind
of where the speed ups came from those
are the problems that we compared to
yeah so qvm will execute anything
whatever you throw at it whatever gates
you throw at it that'll be fine so
there's no restriction there yeah I
don't think I'll get it right can quill
see in the qvm operate with different
native gate sets qvm will run anything
any gate set it doesn't matter as long
as it understands the actual
representation of the gate we'll see I
would say mostly yes quill C is able to
operate with most of the gates that show
up in literature rotation gates you know
a big handful of to qubit gates it's
relatively straightforward to extend it
with more two qubit gates we had to do
that when we were reporting it for the
IBM architecture we had to go through a
process of making sure at every step
along the way we knew how to optimize
for those gates and so on out of a box
you can't say compile for my wacky
two-qubit mullmer Sorensen and don't do
any rotations do these you know funky on
the one cubed operations or something
like that
compiler would need to be told a little
bit more about that so out of the box
and won't get that but if it falls into
any of the gates that are in sort of the
general superconducting regime like any
of the I swap parametric I swap all of
those things it does work out of the box
by missing anybody yep the question is
these quantum machine images is it all
just simulate or does have real back-end
actually the major point of it is the
real back-end
the simulation is more of a bonus in
fact we just load a qvm onto the things
and you can run the qvm you know just
like a normal UNIX programming and what
you can do is you know run it as a
service and now you can you know connect
up to it so the simulation is something
that you kind of get for free the real
point of the QM is is so that these
virtual machines can lay residents with
the quantum hardware itself and you get
full 100% control it's not being
mediated you're not in a queue anything
like that you get sort of immediate
one-to-one access with the machine
yep so the question is how do we share
those resources across several machines
just coarse-grained booking you go we
have something called QC and we have a
QC s command line app which is also open
source you can do QC s reserve and you
reserve a block of time where the
machine is yours in only years and so if
it's available you can get it we also
allow booking on what we call certain
sub lattices I don't I don't remember if
there's a little cute image of a little
lattice yeah you can see this guy
pulling a little lattice quote-unquote
out from the 16 Q ring you can book
smaller chunks of the Machine and
operate on just Lowe's I think that's it
for time right ok so the question is
compilation' involves some type of
optimization problem what heuristic does
it use or what different heuristics they
use I want to give it the snarky answer
and say read the source now that it's
available but it actually uses a lot of
different things so it depends exactly
what it's compiling and so a good amount
of it I probably can't scroll back to it
a good amount of it is doing people
reward rewriting so it actually has a
bunch of rewrite rules and this is
probably the easiest thing to add to the
compiler so if anybody has like a cool
circuit identity that they like they can
put in the compiled in the compiler will
suddenly know about it and be able to
apply it automatically so finding
sequences of gates and shortening them
sometimes it just met it sometimes it
just multiplies the gates out and just
does an optimal 2 Q compilation for
instance if you have a bunch of 2q gates
kind of in a row it's just gonna
multiply them out and then do a
reexpansion on them and then lastly in
some cases actually has to do like a
stochastic gradient and not stochastic
just a grading ascent or something for
for certain types of compilation but
definitely not enough time to get into
that lots and lots of different
optimization problems and come
Tyler certainly all right
[Applause]