welcome to the Yazidi room so let's talk
about that yep hello hey I'm gonna start
with a question how many in here are
freebie C's users that's well 230 room
maybe how many of you use free BC on a
desktop or laptop or some in some sort
of graphical environment Oh most most of
the people who raised your hands for
free BCS were actually used freebies
Tina desktop or laptop that's great so
today I'm gonna talk a bit about the
graphics stack on FreeBSD and I'll talk
a bit about the team behind it and what
we're doing what we have in free BC
today and what's coming up next and the
person doing the talking
my name is Nicolas I sing I'm sizing at
FreeBSD tall so you can reach me there
and I've been part of the I'm an IT
consultant in Stockholm Sweden and I've
been working on previously for over 10
years and I've been a committer since
2012 and for most of my work and Phoebe
has been on the graphics track so the
purpose of this talk is to present what
we're doing and a bit about the team and
who we are before I start I'd also like
to thank my employer b3 in it because
they make it possible for me to do a bit
of this on pay time and they also made
it possible for for me to get here so
thank you to be free in it so starting
with the agenda as I said I will talk
about present the team then I walk
through the actual graphic stack what we
are what's what's in previously today
what come what's it what's the graphic
stack in free beastie I will talk a bit
about about the challenges we face
what's making this job what's making
this perhaps less than trivial
and if there's some time I will see if I
can find my crystal ball and gaze a bit
into the future and see what I think is
it's the things we need to do to to make
free beasty a better desktop platform so
let's start with a graphics team so this
is a quite small team it's me it's two
guys named Johannes both of them to
confuse things yeah we get some help
from Warren wash on poor to do some Lea
song and things like that
there's a guy called Pete that's helping
out writing keeping some things
up-to-date writing some documentation
things like that so we're a very small
team then mono who is not in the room
he's here tracing where he's working on
on the arm platform and graphics on arm
and we get some help from map may see
who's been involved before and he's also
helping out with the PowerPC 64 platform
so the workload we use github we have a
github team I think it's called in
github terminology where we have our
development repositories so we have a
fork of the FreeBSD ports tree where we
can have experimental updation and
things like that we have a copy of the
FreeBSD
base tree for things that need to go
into through the base system eventually
to support driver updates and and things
like that and this is where most most
development take place and then we move
it into the official FreeBSD
repositories and you can find the team
here on github its github or github.com
slash freebsd desktop so you can find
all the things there this is also where
you find sources for
for all our ports of the drivers as well
as some some library ships for some
Linux compatibility so all the sources
there and you can open issues there if
you don't want to use FreeBSD Bugzilla
or you can make poor requester so what
is the team
what is the team maintaining so it's
it's about 300 ports that is somewhat
doesn't sound like very much
I I did an experiment once and I broke
one of them and almost 30 percent of the
FreeBSD ports tree stopped compiling so
even it's not if it even if it's not
that many ports you rather not break
them if you break the one break the
wrong one then then then you you're in a
bit of a mess there's also some poor
infrastructure this makes it possible to
easily depend on on FreeBSD x11
libraries using use underscore X org if
you you're familiar with with reports
this is also uses GL things like that
and then we have have the kernel drivers
that's also our or domain so to speak so
the stack on demographic stack on free
BC as I said we have the core libraries
this is all imports we have the core
libraries your Lib x11 your Lib xcb your
Lib whatever basically the X servers is
of course something we're responsible
for we also maintain the freebies
support of Wayland and a whole bunch of
x11 applications doing small small
supports utilities like
XRD be a X font select X from the cell I
think it's named things like that
the small applications that's
distributed that used to be distributed
together with the with the Xserve when
it was a big monolithic thing and these
days are our separate packages the
window managers in desktop environments
and things like that like KDE and Gnome
those are maintained by other teams
that's that's not our that's not what we
maintain that would be just too much so
we tried to make a foundation of
freebies graphics that you can build on
and you can can maintain your graphics
driver or you can maintain your desktop
environments and window managers on top
of that so let's let's look into the
free BC graphics stack and now I will do
this I will start at the bottom with the
drivers and then I will work my way
through the graphic stacks all the way
up to to the user interface you're
seeing right now so for drivers we have
a legacy driver in base unless someone
did something tonight we still have a
legacy driver in base and this this
driver it's it's a complete port of the
the Linux kms graphics drivers that was
done in 2010 11 12 13 something like
that so they've taken the driver they've
made a complete port this was done well
by caustic Peloso where he basically
changed all the things that was linux
specific in the driver and used freebsd
kernel interfaces for that this port has
done been updated a bit along the way
and it's in terms of hardware
compatibility it's it's somewhere around
linux 3.8
this driver is planned for removal in
three BC thirteen it's already disabled
in the default bill and it will be
replaced by Durham legacy came out which
is a port of the driver is basically
we're taking the source that's in the
FreeBSD base system and we've made a
port out of it we have had to made some
small adjustments to to make it work a
support and and that's it so it's
basically what's in the base the tree
today and the reason we're removing the
GM legacy drivers is that some of them
are conflicting with the new drivers
that were our development developing so
they attach to the same hardware because
they support the same hardware and that
makes it so that it's hard to figure out
which driver is being used or using the
old driver or the new driver and that
makes documentation hard it makes
support hard so that's why we're
removing the driver and as I said it's
planned for removal in freebies of 13 I
don't think it's happened yet but it
will happen soon pretty much
so the new drivers or Durham next or I
think it has a similar names or it has
about a multitude of names these new
drivers they will exist in port and they
will only exist in ports as Colonel
melodious imports and of course packages
they will never end up in freebies to
base part of it is because of licensing
issues part of it is since they're based
on Linux Linux kernel code and the Linux
release cycle is very different from
FreeBSD is very hard to maintain the
driver entry these drivers the use the
Linux KPI or elk API and lkp I'm free
beastie is a kernel module that
implements or translates Linux kernel
api's and so it
two free beastie colonel primitives and
api's and they'll keep I was first
invented by I think was developed by
Mellanox or something like that for
their fibre channel drivers something
like that
and we build on that infrastructure we
have added things to the KPI to make
graphics drivers work and this makes it
so that we can take well in theory at
least it makes it so that we can take
code from the Linux kernel the graphics
driver from the Linux kernel with a very
very few changes we can take them and we
can run them on FreeBSD in practice
Linux really likes to change their kpi's
so you have to update the Linux KPI
while we're doing this so there will be
some changes for every release as you
will see this makes it possible for us
to keep fairly current with what's going
on in in Linux in terms of hardware
support as I said before the legacy
driver it's still on on lettings 3.8 it
was very hard to maintain it was very
hard to update since you had to go
through the drivers and ream and change
Linux specific bits into freebase tips
specific bits yeah these days this is
primarily done on on a be 64 that's our
primary target because primary target
because that's basically what everyone
is using so our primary target is if we
are you say is indices for or x86
underscore 64 in let'em slam the
secondary targets are 83 86 for people
with all hardware and PowerPC 64 and it
should also say that our arm is a
secondary target and bit arm is a bit
special so there is some development to
get better graphics on arm as well it's
done by manual so
for and this is also the reason we made
a legacy porch or port of the legacy
driver because the legacy driver is is
working on 8086 and perhaps other
architectures as well we have in
previously 12 stable I'm not sure about
to release we have support for e3 86 for
the new new new new graphics drivers but
it's kind of a alpha beta snake stage
and it's it might be a bit unstable
PowerPC 6 for sport is is being worked
on it's done by Matt Macy and others and
it's I think it's kind of working but
it's not stable mature yet but hopefully
it will be so the new graphics drivers
imports we have multiple versions
because both different versions of
FreeBSD you have different support in
the LK pad for different drivers that's
basically it in short use the meta port
that will select hopefully the correct
driver for your version of FreeBSD and
your free beastie architecture and these
drivers they are available in three
beasts 11.2 and 1202 earlier releases
will not work because there's not enough
support in in the linux kpi they are all
perhaps they've run out to support yeah
okay so the these are the only supported
drivers or supported versions of FreeBSD
so moving on up for the stack that was
the drivers moving upwards through the
stack we have the libraries the biggest
library is possible probably the open
yield library called Mesa this library
as fairly quick development and it's
important to keep it
working because if you break it things
like that
things stop working it's it's used for
very many ports you also have the Lib
DRM library which is which is a library
to to access the hardware in a device
independent manner so it's a translation
lab translation library between the
youth land and the kernel drivers so to
speak and then we have the regular
external drive xorg libraries as I
talked about this is so this is the
limbic 7 and Lib xeb and well hundreds
of others I don't know 50 others then on
top of that this is the foundation on
which you can build a graphics graphical
environment on top of that we have the X
server and the Aksarben FreeBSD is out
of the 8 its current with its 1.18 to 4
this is an area where we need to do more
work it's we are bad to get drivers and
things working upwards to stack and then
this is the next step the external
server it uses 2 ways you need to
communicate with the graphics hardware
some way some somehow there's two
methods of doing this so you have the
d/dx drivers as they're called these are
the d/dx stands for device dependent
execution I think these are the old XF
86 video in video intro for instance or
XF 86 input Mouse since like that those
are still around
upstream seem to be heading towards
something that's called mode setting or
kernel mode setting and using that to
talk to the colonel directly to fiddle
with graphics and mode setting is part
of the X Server itself so right now we
have a choice between the two
it seems like upstream is heading
towards the mode setting in the most
setting direction but at least AMD is
keeping their DDX driver up-to-date
there's new updates for it Intel while
there's code developments this hasn't
been the relation in quite some time
next step while and it's the new not
server but the new way of doing graphics
on on UNIX and Linux systems I believe
this has been the focus upstream for
quite some time and this is where but
most of the new development happens the
old X server is you know I guess a bit
of a maintenance mode previously
recently gained support in the default
default package bill for for Weiland and
this means that everything in the port's
both ports ports tree and the package
system are built with Weiland support
enabled by default for instance gtk the
GDK toolkit is built with will and
support enable same goes for cute and
other other toolkits that build on
graphics the Mesa package is built with
with will and support out there bugs
this makes it possible makes it much
easier to try to try out Weiland and the
Weiland library implementation itself is
it's mostly up to date we also have sway
which is an Ivy clone available if you
want to try Weiland
however Whelan's way to use Whalen you
need the evidence support in the kernel
and EV is it's the gnu/linux way or a
newer Linux way of handling input
drivers or input devices and this report
is a
kirinda Colonel for at least freebies
212 and current I think it's the code is
also in free beastie 11 however it's not
in the default kernel configuration on
the releases so if you're running free
beast 11.2 or 12 that all you need to
have a custom kernel in previously
stable and previously current this F
that is it's enabled by default
unfortunately there were some fixes that
needed to go in that were not in time
for for the free beastie 1200 release so
to run this you need a either a more
current version of freebsd or a custom
kernel the whole waylynn stack it needs
more testing it's fairly new it's not
very much used as I said until around
Christmas I think you needed to compile
your porch tree specifically with it
enabled so you needed to build your own
packages and stuff like that now you can
get it by by just installing it and and
and if that makes it much easier to try
it
so how do I try this then I've talked a
bunch about its extra your next server
and I've said that you should try Whalen
how do I get started with this I mean
most of you in here are already running
it but for those of you who who might
want to to get started to try it out to
help out testing it's it's fairly simple
to be honest at least at least it should
be fairly simple you need a free beastie
installation quite obvious and I if you
want to release I'd recommend freebies
t12 ato if you if you want even better
support with ever they've enabled by
default is things like that freebies
table or freebies see current it's
available then you simply install xorg
like this you install your favorites
window manager or desktop environment so
P keying still install no more xfce
I we have our whole bunch of them window
maker I 3vm things like that Lumina of
course we have Lumina then you need the
driver as I said yes PK installed Durham
K mod which was this this will select
the right driver for you a bit of a
caveat if you're not running a release
version of FreeBSD and if you're running
a custom kernel and especially if you're
running current instead of installing
you the package of the driver build it
from ports it needs to be it needs to be
in sync with your kernel because kernel
interfaces might change and things like
that and data structures might move
around so if you're not using a release
you need to build it from ports it's
it's fairly quick table is located in
graphics - DRM came out and you will
build it for you for your kernel
together with the firmware needed to
to use the graphics card then you start
X you might need to fill a little bit if
you want your favorite window manager
you might need to set up X in it are see
I think the default default is CVM still
TWM as as has been the default since
since forever and this this should work
if you're running on intel hardware i
think most of the bugs are sorted out
you should not need a configuration for
xorg it should find the the hardware and
drivers you need to start if you're
running on AMD hardware you might need
to fill a bit till we get the loader to
get the driver to to work there is
currently a conflict between the frame
buffer the AEA 5 frame buffer so if
you're using UEFI you might need to
December disable console before the
driver loads and there is more
documentation about this on our wiki for
which I have a link later but in general
to get a graphical environment and
freebsd this is what you need
so it sounds very simple what are what
are not so simple in this testing for
one is not very simple it turns out it's
very hard to emulate graphics cards
graphics hardware which means you you
kind of need to have have the actual
hardware laying around and there is
quite a lot of different graphics
hardware so you can't cover all bases
this means that we need help with
testing from I'd say the public but from
from from users we need help we need
will help with testing we need help to
cover our bases and this also means that
sometimes it's is very hard to reproduce
problems for instance I had had a friend
where I have a friend who had a freeze
when he loaded the graphics driver and
it's like well it's working right it
works on my computer's it works on the
rest of development teams computers we
have no idea why it's not working on on
my friend's computer so some things like
that are a real challenge and this comes
down to all graphics hardware being
alike and all graphics hardware being
different it seems another challenge
which is perhaps issue just always build
times it takes time to build the graphic
stack I do most of my development on my
laptop I have fairly modern laptop it
still takes quite some time to go which
makes build test cycles fairly slow and
I hope to be able to set up some way
where we can commit things to github and
get a package in the other end and doing
that would also make it possible to
easier to to an easier way give testers
access to development packages so they
just can install on their laptop or
desktop and test
the third challenge is developer
bandwidth we're a small team and
upstream moves fast sometimes life and
work happens and this means that this
this means that sometimes updates have
to wait a bit
there's also also goes again with
testing sometimes we don't have time to
test everything and indeed in the end
you have to make the jump but sometimes
it's better to be a bit safe and perhaps
stick around with an older version
that's that's known to work instead of
updating to something that's not at
least at least a bit tested
so in the future this is me getting into
the crystal ball but I think what we
will go into what's going to happen in
the future we will never know first off
input devices I've talked a little bit
about this about EV dev about flip input
things like that this is an area where
Linux is changing how they're doing it
and we kind of need to tag along so I
see I would guess that we need to
improve our input device handling and
somehow have a translation layer so that
it looks at least 4 X Server in
four-wheel and looks a bit linux see we
have that today it's the evide
of the kernel code I talked about
earlier but I think this is an area
where where we need to improve both in
regards to what we support and also may
become better at automatically configure
things I mean mouse and keyboard works
but touchscreen trackpads
the for instance wake up tablets things
like that we also have to do something
about theorem legacy as I said it's
going away from free BC base at least in
13 but then should it live on forever in
freebies ports at some point when when
the new code is stable enough or when I
386 is it's not as much of a thing it
probably needs to go
the last thing the next thing that needs
to happen is auto load today you install
the kernel driver he need to load it and
this needs to happen automatically
it does sometimes it's not always and
previously the d/dx drivers I talked
about earlier
did the loading of the kernel module
that's not happening anymore so you
cannot have to do it from from from your
startup I would like to see this happen
automatically there is a facility in
FreeBSD to handle this but through
graphics drivers aren't using it as
using it yet and since the graphics
drivers come from Linux they look a bit
different than native freebees to
drivers so this is something we have to
look into you also have to look into
support for more architectures I
mentioned arm and PP 64 PowerPC 64 as
the most important ones support and work
is ongoing we probably have to support a
386 for for at least some time more at
least into 2038 or something was at
least one one one person who got that
joke
so looking further into the future and
this is things that's needed to get free
be Steve better as a desktop platform we
need to get a better way to manage your
network on on our desktop or at least
laptops where we run them around and use
them everywhere so some sort of tool for
this is probably needed we need to
become better at power management and
Wi-Fi support is always something that's
that can improve it's it's working
pretty good pretty pretty good today but
there's always some problem chipset that
that doesn't work and things like that
so in summary we talked a bit about the
free BC graphic stack I worked through
it from from from Colonel to what you
see today basically we talked about the
drivers and what we're doing there today
we talked about the libraries the XOR
server we talked a bit about Weyland and
we talked a bit about what what I think
we need to do this year and the years to
come - to keep previously available
desktop platform and - to make it a
better desktop platform if you want to
help out more resources you can find our
as I said we have our github space where
you can find us we have a shaft
that's called a get your chat that's
integration to github where you can find
us here you can always email our mailing
list and we're also available on IRA see
at least some of us you can also talk to
me you feel like
I know there's been fairly dry in a
wooden sea boring but fairly dry there's
no demos or anything it's in a way this
is this whole thing is a live demo this
whole presentation was made using
previously it's done in OpenOffice on
FreeBSD I'm running free BC I'm running
a fairly recent version of FreeBSD Thank
You CFS that makes it that makes it
possible to upgrade and then oh it broke
okay to revert to the last snapshot that
was what I had today are there any
questions
oops that was not meant it Oh
any questions oh we have one minute for
questions I'm around here today and I'm
around here tomorrow let's start with
the gentleman in blue currently I don't
know as you've noticed I haven't talked
very much about Nvidia drivers though
and that's because we used the binary
blob from Nvidia so we're basically
forced to do what NVIDIA distr or force
but we're using what NVIDIA provides and
I don't know if NVIDIA provides I don't
think in video today Nvidia Pro Nvidia
driver provides the delivers needed
today but I haven't tried order does
that even work on Linux
yeah I don't know I don't think optimal
support is is well it should be doable
if someone sits down and do it but I
think you have to pick I either the
entire order Nvidia driver