thank you so our next talk is an
interesting use case with the
multi-camera instant replay with slow
motion called futa tubby
please welcome Steiner thank you so I
have two great passions in life at least
at the time one of them is programming
and the other one is the sport known as
Ultimate Frisbee and when I tell people
well frisbee and they're like yeah well
how can you play anything with a free
spin I try to explain them while you
throw to your teammate you want to get
inside the goal and they go like what
and I try to show them the video the
problem is when I moved back to Norway
where I live now and started playing
tournaments the stream basically looked
like this and it's pretty much
impossible to see anything right you can
see sort of the players but they're
supposed to be a goal line here and good
luck seeing anything but it's supposed
to be around here somewhere but it's all
smudged out it brahmand windows on
xsplit they managed to get a fool like
15fps sometimes the various scan it
would take one core and it's really
really hard to explain in sport to
someone when you can't even see are they
in or out when the point is to throw
inside the zone so we thought can we do
better than this with free software and
it's not an obvious it's not an obvious
answer I've never heard of sports
production being used with being done by
free software before we thought okay
we'll give it a shot this is lucky I do
my live video mixer which I presented
here it actually in this very room three
years ago it's grown a lot since then so
if you tried 103 years ago maybe give it
a shot now there's a lot of new features
so I'm gonna do a very quick rundown
first of what our stream is looking like
this is a standard ultimate field
indoors 40 by 20s I play in handball
fields in in Norway and all of the
countries outside you can see there's
not a lot of room so we are pretty
cramped where you can put our cameras
first of all we have camera one camera
one is your standard wide-angle let's
look at the entire field thing that he
will see from any normal sports thing
we're trying to be very to be very
sparse on manpower so the camera one
there is run by the producer he's
tilting it with his left hand he's
operating the negeri with
right hand he's also doing audio mixer
he's also doing graphics it's a fairly
busy position but it's but it's a lot of
fun
there's also camera to camera to is a
detail cam right it just basically
follow the guy with a disc it's a bit
more zoom then it's nice where these
detail shots and most the time think
maybe 85% of the time you want to be in
camera one maybe in 10 percent of the
time you want to be in camera 2 and then
we have 3 & 4 & 3 & 4 are what we call
beauty shops their GoPros actually
perched high above the go through the
two gold zones so you can see the Enzo
more or less it would be nice to have
them even wider actually these are
GoPros are low-power enough that we can
actually just run them on power banks we
don't run powers of these we just put up
a power bank put them on the very very
cheap and high extender and then we're
unless the I converter and GoPro on
these power banks that late last maybe
like 18 hours and now if this sounds
like a lot of a quick but maybe it is
but almost all this is either bought
secondhand on eBay or borrowed or
otherwise so it's it's not an expensive
production by any means at least not
compared to compared to traditional
broadcast so after all of this it looks
basically like this you can actually now
see the goal line it's up here there is
a smile at html5 graphics hairs embedded
chromium and what's it in or out who
knows right seventy thousand lines of
code later and I still don't know
whether I'm in or out for the record I
was in we we looked at it later but if
it came clearly painfully obvious that
we needed some form of instant replay we
wanted to be able to see shots again we
wanted to be able to able to see shots
from a different angle like camera -
instead of camera one or or legs and we
wanted to be able to see it in slow
motion so we went online looked okay
well we need a box to do this what do
what can you get this is the e VX x t3
this is pretty much the standard thing
in broadcast if you look at any major
sports event they will either have an XT
three or they will have many of them
unfortunately as you can see here the
part of the price is 99
pounds and this is a bargain you also
need to pay $30 in shipping
maybe if you get that wave and to make
it even worse right the dye the seller
is currently on vacation so you can't
even buy it now there are cheaper
options but they're all generally in the
10,000 year range and that is
essentially like a Windows box with some
software and and a video card so so we
thought okay let's try making our own
and this is courseware philosophy comes
into into the action the first you is
silent because it's Japanese word
basically we try to get all the frames
from all the cameras from the ghetto
over Aiki we store them and we want to
play them back when you do this you have
a frame server now there are a few
problems of course uncompressed video we
just talked about it on 10 gig it's
fairly voluminous you may be do down
over the network but storing it and when
you want to store all of it so you wanna
store 12 12 hours uncompressed it it
must kind of lie so we are doing an
Jacob and M JPEG compression you would
think okay well why do you want JPEG
JPEG is like an 80s format but it's very
very performant and it's actually pretty
good
in fact on recent CPUs from sky lighting
up you actually had a hardware JPEG
encoder instead of using 4 cores to do
dvcpro or whatever you can just send it
directly to the Intel GPU send it over a
network store it here and then you have
some sort of UI which we'll be looking
at later to pick out for instance this
segment here and play it back and even
when you play back these unmodified
frames you can just echo the mjpeg back
you don't even need a decoder re-encode
to get maximum quality you know you
don't get any sort of CPU usage but we
also wanted slow motion and that begs
the question well we have the unmodified
frames here you want to slow down by 2x
but what do we do with these ones in the
middle now the obvious first choice of
course is just to repeat frames from
heat them twice three times four times
how many times we need to slow down and
that looks like this it's very very
choppy and it's not really something you
want to show to people now I will say
though that I've deliberately picked a
very very hard sample there's two reason
for this a it's a lot even it's
more fun to reason about the things to
go wrong then the things that go right I
mean the easy cases who cares right the
other one is that when you're having a
talk that this these effects can be
really subtle it can be very hard to see
things when they're just flying by once
so I want to exaggerate a bit now I'm
playing this it's a lot of motion we're
doing Forex slowdowns that are two decks
slow down this kind of thing so it's
just to make things clearer so okay so
repeating frames is maybe not the best
what about saving frames it's not really
a lot better right it's it's still
pretty choppy so we need to do something
even better than this I are taking two
neighbouring frames and overlaid them so
you can see sort of we have a frame a we
have a friend baby and we want to find
something in the middle and obviously
what happened is frame like say you have
this carry on the first one you have
this care it moves a bit
this leg here move a bit from the right
to the left and so on so somehow these
intermediate frames in the middle or 20%
between or 80% between and what-have-you
it has to do somehow with motion right
if we can estimate the motion like this
maybe we can try to synthesize in
between frames so this brings us to the
idea of optical flow optical flow is
basically model access while all pixels
came from somewhere here we have I've
made an estimate again it's what you see
first of all courses all these little
arrows pointing up into the right and
that's because the camera moved down to
the left in the light in between these
frames but it's also picked up that the
disc air is moving to the right sort of
it's picked up at the player is moving
to the left there's slightly different
arrows here and so on so if you can take
these arrows like a flow field and
somehow invert and hobit which is much
harder than it looks like then we can
maybe get an idea for not where did the
pixel go which is not that useful but
more where do we want to sample it from
so this this part is actually
non-trivial but we're not going to talk
about it we're just going to talk about
estimating the flow field instead which
is a very different very difficult
problem in its own right there are more
than 200 papers dealing with optical
flow
I read maybe like 20 30 of them
the artists rating lists there's new
papers coming out really every week but
between a time where either its rating
lists for like who can make the best
flow with the best algorithm and
standardized tests and by the between me
writing this this talk and and now I
think like the top list has changed
three times or something so but most
people don't care about real time we
need to be able to synthesize these
these in-between frames basically 60
times a second or at least 30 times a
second if we can
keep every other original frame so this
paper here called my ID from 2016 and it
says the magical words 300 to 600 Hertz
or frames per second now of course it
isn't really 300 frames a second it's
more like 10 because they exclude a lot
of pre-processing they run in low
resolution and they and of course they
they're numbers they're on the lowest
quality presets which isn't really good
but I thought okay maybe I can use it to
have reference code it's sort of
unclearly license says GPL 3 to some
places this has for personal use only
other places so I ended up reimplemented
not believe because I wanted it on the
GPU my hope was that well okay they can
do a 10 Hertz on the Jeep on the CPU
maybe I can do like 60 Hertz on the GPU
let's try I'm going to give a very very
very high-level overview of how this
algorithm works if you want to fold
details you can probably read the paper
that is fairly dense so we start off
with a motion search we start on low
resolution as you might see we split the
image into multiple overlapping 12 by 12
pixel blocks and then we go look in the
other picture can we find something that
looked like it this is we start here in
the middle as you can see it like the
bluish square and then we have these
squares here let's show the algorithm
consecutively homing in now if you do
video compression you'll already know
motion search but this is motion search
with a different goal this is not motion
search for this to find is the most
efficient motion vector this is for
finding real motion and we also care a
lot about the sub pixel position we
don't want to stop like half pixel of 40
pixel so this is a gradient to search
this end search we start at 0 and then
we try to figure out okay which way
which direction am I going and
eventually hopefully converge this works
fine as long as we
don't me to have motion that spans like
many many pixels in this case it's one
and a half pixel because we reduce the
resolution so after this we have oh by
the way I'm not hardly blue for a reason
because when we have a million arrows
it's very hard to see which way are the
mole are they all pointing so instead of
coding them as arrows we use a fairly
standard presentation where the hue is
which direction is it going which is the
angle and and the lightness is how
strong is it so that gives us now a
bunch of little squares this is a sparse
flow field for each and every motion
block and they're overlapping first of
all we need to get up to the resolution
of the image or at least this level so
we do a process called densification
where we blend between all these motion
vectors or hypothesis based on how good
where they for the single pixel right
now it looks sort of messy so we have a
separate step called variational
refinement which is unfortunately I
don't have time to talk about this like
two hours but essentially it sets up a
huge nonlinear differential equation
which we solved on the GPU numerically
it's not as smooth it does some sort of
edge preserving smoothing but it does a
lot of other things at this point we
have a flow field we could have scaled
it up and used it for algorithm but
instead we now go to the next resolution
we now use the double resolution and we
use this flow field here as input for
the motion search algorithm so again
remember I said the motion search works
well when it only has to move a little
well now it has to move only little
because it already had a pretty good
estimate so this is our new motion
search our new identification our new
variational refinement we go one step up
in resolution again motion search and
now we can see things like this guess is
starting to show here the people are in
the background densification variational
refinement all in all this is about 200
passes on the GPU it really gets a lot
to do but it loves parallel work and of
course you can see it's not perfect so
how good is it and for this we have
standardized benchmarks thankfully this
is the MPI simple benchmarks I think
you will know the symptom movie from the
blender foundation someone's rear-ended
it web with motion with optical flow
data so this is our ground truth since
it's a render we know exactly where
every pixel is going and these are our
estimates on four different quality
levels you have a quality level one two
three and four from the paper they vary
in like what resolution we stopped on
how many motions or iterations are we
running all this kind of thing and you
see as as we're getting down here we
have this EPE which is the endpoint
error which is how much to the flow miss
compared to the to the reference it's
going down at least until we reach like
all the 344 here and then of course it
takes longer longer now these times here
I'm quoting six milliseconds on another
detail RTX 270 this is estimating
forward flow from A to B estimating
backward flow from B to a computing the
the in between flow like the halfway
flow between them and doing the actual
interpolation so even at 1080p we're at
like twelve point nine milliseconds and
that's under our 60 millisecond target
compared to CPU implementation it's more
than order magnitude faster it depends a
bit on your settings in your GPU of
course and it's a few percent better in
in terms of end point error now because
it's still not perfect it's still far
from perfect but does it matter
so we can now try taking just these two
frames up here and see and just
interpolate very very smoothly between
them and the result looks like this
these are just two frames let's just
look at it again you can see there are
some issues in here for instance you can
see it has problems with a pollution but
it did get them merely get let's get the
sword right the background motion here
is hardly even list of all I remember
this is like 50x slowdowns this is this
is fairly good let's look at the
original example again now with with
this algorithm it's not so bad right
there are there are some artifacts
especially if you know what to look for
but again this is a hard sample
it's time for the demo effect and I'm
gonna try to show that the UI as best as
I can now of course my laptop isn't
really fast enough for this because it
doesn't have a nice TPU but I took some
test data and low resolution you can see
here this is real data I'm giving out as
part of this 12 hours a real multi
camera data because it turns out it's
really really hard to find online actual
multi camera data so the way this work
we have I've been moving around a bus
from just buttons around by the way for
the demo just because it's hard to see
anything at the bottom so we had a clip
list normally I would use the keyboard
for this but since it's easier to see
what's happening with the mouse I can
click Q in and when I'm happy when
they've been doing something interesting
I can press Q out now I have a clip this
is just an instant in time I can preview
it up here maybe I want to have camera
two
okay maybe I wasn't completely happy
about the start so I can scroll it here
if I want to I have this little DJ
controller here which is much much nicer
to work with
it's basically super cheap I think this
is like a hundred year old he wanted by
professional remote it's something like
thousand two thousand years and once I
have done
once I have my clips I can queue them up
q maybe queue it from both cameras and
now I can play it back okay maybe a
first wasn't so interesting but it will
fade nicely over to to the second one at
least once it's done it was so long I
can edit these while I'm running if I
feel it's yeah so we will play it out on
TCP socket will go nicely back hopefully
in recently high quality if you want to
be really fancy you can turn off the
speed lock here and you can pull this
little slider to to ramp it down to very
low speed let me just play it again
there in this very dramatic
so I guess that's basically the demo we
have like media control over these these
things here we have of course undo
there's a full manual if you want to go
look at it
so that's that's basically it now while
I'm taking questions I think maybe I
have yeah five minutes for questions I'm
just gonna play here some real world
this is actual stuff from the last event
we did so this is an actual replay or
replay operator doing actual mistakes in
real times this is pretty much what you
can expect into X so any questions yes
wait for the microphone please oh they
have to change batteries was the output
of the of the application support SDI or
is it a stream or so I don't think the
microphone is working but I'll just
repeat it if the output is SD I know the
obvious stream it's a standard HTTP
stream in a Matroska container echoing
back frames half of them are the
energetic originals I try very hard to
sort of lock into the original frames
when I can and half of them are the
synthesized frames there I would
probably add SDI output if I needed it
it's not hard to do but generally the
entire idea is you have this together
and we have a separate talk to the
operator and it just goes in there
anyway so why would I want to see I but
it's most certainly doable
hi do you happen to have an API for the
image interpolation it's it's a cloth at
the C++ class it's fairly well contained
you give it two raw frames and it gives
you back another frame well in form of
texture on the GPU so it's certainly
reusable it's Cpl 3mm
with a read back kill it it's I'm doing
read back I'm doing that for the JPEG
JPEG right so I'm doing a synchronous to
read back which is the course important
when you're doing GPU mm-hm but it's
it's certainly possible okay
might ask you about it other questions
do you have to do anything special for
camera synchronization between the four
cameras or are you just suggesting for
SDI feeds and I'm just running for CI
feeds now this is a low-budget thing
like I said and we don't have any clock
synchronization because because the
clock synchronous Inc realized it would
be like a master clock would be like 500
euros anyway and our cameras are HDMI in
the first place which is convert into
SDI so we are doing some alligator has
internal frame queues for all four
cameras it's trying fairly hard to keep
these queues low or key to keep them
short as much as it can without risking
too much frame drop so essentially
they're like a frame or two or three
from each other it's not perfect but
it's either I don't see any good no I
can't see any visible difference between
them thank you the previous talk was
about GPU be a musician and since you
know open GP I think there is a
malfunction to perfrom GPU optimized
flow I think it's actually the same
algorithm okay but I didn't think they
was in DP optimized
I think there is one but it may be in
the country but okay maybe I haven't
actually looked in OpenCV per se yeah no
I mean the problem is of course again
every week there's something new if I
had this talk in five years I'm fairly
certain I would stand here and talk
about neural networks it's coming full
speed now I think everything
state-of-the-art quality wise is
supporting neural networks but it's
still I mean the best things are hundred
fifty four milliseconds and there's just
too much for me so I just had to pick
something right it's eventually in a
future version maybe I'll be switching I
don't know I'm not bound for this
specific algorithm even though I used
literally a month to decode the
variational refinement and
the paper with all the strange tents
fermentation and high posts and stuff
thank you hey nice talk Thanks
and you mentioned some artifacts that
appear in the frame interpolation I just
want to ask if you could describe some
of those and if any of those artifacts
are located at the edge of the frame I
love that you didn't see them because
they're playing now there should be
artifacts everywhere right
generally edges are not a big problem
the really hard part is occlusion when
you have an object that moves right and
the background is moving left or the
other way around and a the optical flow
assumption really breaks down because
well things didn't come from it always
assumes two things move from A to B but
if it just came from behind something
it's it didn't come from anywhere so it
really breaks down motion blur any kind
of blur will also give you a problem
because now your pixel doesn't go one
place because half of the pixel is the
background half so pixel is the
foreground and a moving different place
I think if I go all the way back here
you can maybe see some some of these
issues but except that I don't think
going backwards in OpenOffice is with
video is very easy I think maybe yeah if
you look at when he's moving his when
he's moving his arm very vertically down
so look for the place where he does like
basically this and that's where you see
it it gets hurt it gets broken up but
again this is for X into X it's very
hard to see but I was also surprised
that edges don't actually matter I do I
unlike the original paper I don't pad
with black iPad with with the edge
because that's what's the natural thing
for the GPU this and maybe that helps a
bit Thanks
we have one more minute for questions
two minutes really impressive for you is
this the end is it good enough or do you
want to look at the newer papers this or
other other things you want to build
into this software next first of all I
want to use it even more than that than
we'd already been doing certainly I'm
open to to adding new and more fancy
algorithms I doubt I'll be I mean I used
to every week just real oh this
middlebury rating lists over and over
again I think I'll be doing that because
it takes a lot of time I think basically
there will be features there's a lot of
things that I wanted to do and
especially in terms of media control in
terms of of jus I I want to be able to
support more of these 63 workflows for
instance I mean a lot of a lot of slow
motion has it's very bound to have an
EVs works but it's a very efficient
workflow and everything needs to go but
second so every time I can shave off
like half a second of the UI tuned by
making something simpler that's really
the way I want to go for instance I did
qinq out I talked to slow motion
operator the other day he said well they
never do queue out
they just said queue in start playing
and then just abort it manually because
then you don't need to wait for the clip
to happen so so I think maybe in the UI
Department this is first of all but uh
yeah I would love to have users and see
their their feedback also by the way we
get the manual I spend a fair amount of
time trying to explain how the slow-mo
work from an operator's point how do you
want to work with the producer this kind
of thing
oh no okay thank you
[Applause]