I'm gonna talk about one of the
challenge that we have in the domain of
the libre office in terms of getting a
help language that could help users and
keep a lot of requirements in
maintaining documentation in
synchronized with the developments my
name is Olivier I am from the document
foundation I have been involved in
LibreOffice is the beginning I live in
Brazil which is quite hot at the moment
42 degrees and I'm also the translator
for Brazilian Portuguese so I handled
not only the generation of documentation
but also the issue of translating the
documentation what we have is that why
we need a help language because
historically the developers don't like
to make documentation so essentially in
in our culture in libreoffice everybody
writes code but doesn't like to write
documentation so sometimes we have a lot
of new features without documentation
and this is something that we need to do
to fix ok the gap between the features
and help is widening we are working to
make it narrow possible but it's always
very hard and the speed of development
is much faster than the possibility of
generating documentation especially
because in our environments
documentation done is done by volunteers
okay so copying the help pages and the
user interface elements is a challenge
the user interface of an application
like Libre Office is extremely extensive
we have more than 1,000 dialogues we
have a span of application that goes
from spreadsheets text documents
presentations drawing math equations and
databases so it's a very broad scope of
application
we try to focus on user experience
because user experience is very
important for us for the acceptance of
our software so basically what we want
to achieve is sort of a help languages
or XML maybe XML or whatever markdown as
open as possible okay so no wait we use
closer tools or paid tools or
proprietary clue tools flexible that
allows specific situations such as
translations has to be precise because
essentially the help that we have in
libreoffice is also some form of a
references for regressions and feature
descriptions we would like and this is
one of main issues is to be contributor
friendly today it's not motivated
friendly because we have a cycle of
development that includes the help pages
in to get and this is not very easy for
the newcomers okay and keep the pace of
development that means don't let this
gap widened okay very well so basically
the specific of the Bri office help it's
an application with the broad scope like
I said all the modules are tightly
couplet I mean we don't have a
spreadsheet application we don't have a
text document application this is all it
equated to a big application with
several modules we have a legacy XML
which is inherited from OpenOffice the
hope that we have at the moment is above
500 thousand words which made a book
thick as this one okay we have to
maintain and keep keep alive it's mostly
textual and few images there is not
multimedia at the moment but the idea is
to
Stan that for including new forms of
communication between the help and the
user and we have a translation process
in place that works
that means LibreOffice is translated
into about 100 languages so we need to
have the we need to address the
translation we do do we do that which
also means that it's very hard for us to
change the process in place because we
are touching about 100 teams of
translators and when we do a mistake if
times 100 that makes a lot of noise ok
so this is what the challenge that we
have and what we do propose with us with
what we have is that we have a set of
XML and namespace that we want to
improve for describing the menu path the
widgets screenshots of the dialogues
describe icons and toolbars includes
multimedia address the guide for the
user and not on the references and also
do indexing and search and save the
translation work so at the moment only
half of these specifications are already
working and this this is we have others
to address ok for example in the new
menu we the menus in the application at
this profit by an XML and we would like
to have these many paths describing in
the textual help directly taken from the
application ok so we should use a
transformation that picks the XML of the
menus and the commands and put into the
help directly so if we change the
position of these menus automatically
your help will change as well ok this
this is one of the challenge that we
have ok this
for the widgets of the dialogues for
example not only we take have to take
the the widget itself the representation
of the widget but also its contents
which has to be translated okay so again
we can use the dialogues XML which is
something used by JDK we the dialogues
in a gtk language and to bring that into
the help of pages icons and toolbars we
have to describe your icon icons and
toolbars for improvements on the icon
designs in the last couple of years we
had a lot of discussion in in
libreoffice design team there is quite
new icons coming icon sets so the
interface may appear different from you
from one user to the other depending on
the set of icons that you use and this
has to be also covered by the help
application yeah okay the screenshots we
would like to we have already
screenshots done by a simple copy of the
screen which in an automated process but
it would be nice to have it also using
the XML to generate the image okay the
images is already implemented so no
problem there and also we have some
issues or problems to address which
which means our system or application
runs on Mac wing Windows and UNIX and it
depending on the system you have some
features implemented on Mac which which
is not implemented on Windows very few
of them not but not not that much but
nevertheless it we have to address this
difference between the systems okay we
have also in line context treats context
switches or block contents
which is okay for the visual up part we
have we are implementing specific tags
to describe Python code and basic codes
and also code in general and icons
specifically to icon tables when it
comes to tips notes and warnings this is
already done it's quite easy to just
address the CSS but it's it's the way
that we have also to enhance the the
layout of all pages okay for everything
that like that we also have corrected
character set character classes for
specific contents of the description on
the help pages such as literal
information input is something that
allows us to click on a a class input
and then it copies to the clipboard so
you can if you have a code or or a
spreadsheet formula you can just copy
the formula and look it working directly
in the in the application this is for
better user experience with jets I
thought I already talked about menus and
key codes also for all the key keyboard
codes that we have in the application we
develop also a a online editor it this
is a very first alpha pre alpha display
we have the XML of render of editor some
of these blocks can be automated and we
also can render the content of the page
immediately after we edit here you did
here you click on render and it displays
the page there our help system is a
sub-module in in
so every every time we change the XML we
have to create a commit and push to the
to Garrett it's going to be reviewed by
someone you can imagine that reviewing
XML is not something easy it's quite
complicated so we are trying to connect
this kind of editor which this is just
called mirror okay
very well-known JavaScript editor and
it's the same as carrot so we expect to
be able to edit directly the pages in
Garrett and get the results and stupid
patch automatically and we would like to
avoid all the work that today volunteers
have which means download the code
compile the code compile the help see
check if the change is correct and then
generate a pair a patch and push to to
do so this cycle is extremely lengthy
and it takes a lot of time for us for me
who is kill it it takes at least one
hour to generate all the stuff okay then
what's next we it is an interest to
investigate then the XML transformations
for dialogues menus and toolbars we also
would like to convert the help with
these existing open document guides
which is a project we call convergence
we have guides that has been written by
volunteers for example on spreadsheet
the spreadsheet guide is a book with 400
pages and we would like also that this
kind of information be available in the
help system of all LibreOffice ok and we
have open to suggestion and
collaboration and if you want to join us
please go ahead we eager to get you one
thing that is important to say is that
our help system is either offline
and online which means that today we we
have this XML we do a transformation to
HTML and this HTML can be uploaded to a
server or it may it can be also deployed
as a package for offline use and it's
exactly the same layout okay so this is
a risk constraint that we have so it's
not so easy just to generate a server
service installation you have to also
pack the HG HTML into a package the
other thing is that we have about 200
2,500 files per language and this in it
it generates about something like 500
megabytes off of help contents okay
per language so it's pretty heavy
application that we have the traffic
that we have on our online service is
about 60,000 visits a day of people
looking for help when they use the
application so that's the context that
we have and the challenge that we are
addressing ahead we cannot use throw
away our legacy contents so using a
brand new tool like I seen here is very
nice but how can i address all this
legacy especially the not only the
legacy on English but also the legacy
under on the translations which it's
about 100 translations
so it has to be something smooth to for
us if we have to get something different
from that so at the moment this is not
the beam or vision we
expect to simplify and get it easier for
the people to really help us in document
in the application okay that's my my
presentation if you have questions
[Music]
yeah we yes we are using of course what
all the legacy from 15 years of I mean
20 years of OpenOffice and then debris
office and moving away of it's not that
we really have to make a decision and if
if something is easier then I'm
interested at least yeah yeah okay
perfect
you can generate the screenshots on
every platform it's not yet ultimate I
mean you I do and make screenshots in
the in my bills and it generated the
screen starts to flicker because it
opens all the thousends dialogues and
takes a screenshot yes so and yes in
then you have to connect the screenshot
the image with the dialogue and with the
help page corresponding so it's this is
not yet automated yes
yes
well no the translation is done by
volunteers in every language we have
used to have a leader and a team and
they handle themselves the I mean each
each release that we have and we have to
release per year we publish the help 99%
of the help of the new release is
exactly the same of the previous so
there is only the Delta the difference
that is been addressed and then the
translators the team of translators do
locally is in charge of keeping the
translation synchronized with the help
in English this then then the user of
the language will suffer because they
were not addressing yeah yeah no no this
is because this is a volunteer project
it's not there is no specific investment
by the foundation into generating
professional documentation it's it's if
the board this is a decision with the
board of the foundation
LibreOffice is is a project that is run
by a foundation without with no
non-for-profits so if a company wants to
take the code and improve it by it
by themselves they are free to do that
okay so at the moment we generates the
the content of the help in a volunteer
basis the foundation doesn't invest in
oh this is not me okay any questions
[Applause]
yeah there is another track right there
with lots of new things