you may not press anything you do more
cuts
it's fine okay so we're gonna be
studying with the next talk right now so
please sit down take your seats and
round of applause for kuba he's gonna be
talking about get databases and indexes
and interesting stuff so round of
applause for him you know hello i'm cuba
i work at sourced mainly on projects
related to storage and data processing
like my sequel server and database and
the engine but also in a spare time I
maintain couple open source projects
like extended attributes package forego
and the zip compression library and
recently I helped my friend in his new
programming language called never but
today I want to talk about how we
integrated the bitmap index in our
database so I have to give you first
some context so get base is application
but just it's just a front-end there
real my sequel server database engine
which is by the way powered by Vitas is
another open source projects gate base
is so far just a read only database so
now insert no updates and all the
queries to go git repos are done by the
gogit package the pirata is another open
source project which we use as a
distributed index implementation it
implements the roaring storage format
and apart from indexes it lets you keep
attributes in vault DB so the gate base
is just a standalone like application
which you can play with just a front-end
and all the well-known terms from the
gate like repositories comma drafts are
mapped to the tables and a convention
convention is just how you
the references are based on the
convention and the naming convention so
basically you can play with all the
features like not write joins and for
instance this query uses the natural
join so you want to get all the
repositories where the Alan Turing
contributed on a hat reference and so
you just do that query from revs and
natural join with comets more
sophisticated query is this one which
basically uses our predefined function
which lets you extract some abstract
syntax tree and can recognize the
language based on the content and stuff
like that so this query tries to extract
all the identifiers the identifier names
from your go files but of course we have
indexes indexes are the most interesting
for the stock so we have indexes and you
can create the index on where of
multiple columns this is simple stuff
the nice thing is that you can specify
what the index driver who you want to
use so the red keyword pilosa means that
you want to use the pilosa
as an index driver also you can create
the indexes a synchronously and
synchronously
but you can also instead of creating the
index on one of multiple columns you
also can create the index on an
expression so a little bit theory about
the indexes till we dive in is that we
have a hash indexes which look like a
hash map sitting very good for equality
the most popular indexes in databases
were Darby trees and in most most places
this is very good the best approach
there are self bias trees pretty well
pretty well choice if you wondering
which one to use our trees are not super
popular there are more to index
multi-dimensional objects so they are
good when you try to group nearby
objects there are also self balance
trees and bitmaps bitmaps are very good
to optimize logical operations and this
is what we what we chose forged base bid
verbs can be very expensive to rebuild
the whole bit metallic sometime so so it
it's a good choice for for example for
read-only systems also the best what you
can get is when you have lot of data but
not not many possible values and also
the good thing about the bitmaps is that
because it's optimized for logical
operations you can create a web one with
index per column to satisfy all queries
if you don't have bitmaps indexes the
formula on the right is the number of
indexes which you have to create to
satisfy all the possible queries where n
is the number of columns so for example
Beatrice
with the Beatrice you have to deal with
this so I mentioned a little bit above
the storage for storing about the format
how it's stored so it's called roaring
roaring format and a palasa which we
used they implement this and this format
and apart from that all the offset which
you have to set and headers in a file
the most important is how you store the
data on a disk so first when you have
the row ID and the column ID in yo in
your bitmap you have to store to the
local storage so you calculate the
position you call the add function and
what attraction does is basically the
first byte is the operation so in this
case it's a it's at the next eight bytes
is a value in a little endian format and
then last four bytes is just a checksum
of the operation and in your value and
you write it to the disk
basically this pretty simple how you
save data and palasa implements it
it's a typical by default it is typical
server client but we cut a little bit
which I will talk later
by default it certificates every client
well communication goes over our PC or
REST API and the data model in pilosa
looks like this so you have a huge
boolean matrix where index contains
fields and have in rows in this matrix a
local / field but the columns are global
columns are shared across all the fields
so you can say give me column number 5
in the index and you'll get all the ones
or zeros from all the fields but when
you say row number 5 you have to specify
for which field so rows are local /
field and their columns are global and
nice think about the bit maxes that you
can match them well you can match rows
but what's the most important is that
you cannot match rows across indexes you
have to match rows inside the same index
so how we integrated the palasa indeed
base so with the first approach was the
simplest one yeah
take the bilasa run it in the container
as a server one pillow the index maps to
the one database index and one field was
the equal to one expression so the
column and it was super simple we had to
add the mapping because you have to map
the bitmaps is just a matrix so it has
rows and columns but you have to map the
values to rows and columns to locational
number of the records in your table so
it was the simplest approach but after
some time we decided we don't want to
maintain yet another server and
troubleshoot all the synchronization
problems and stuff like that so we
decided maybe it would be good to hug
pillows a little bit and embed it into
the grid base so it let us run the
pillows are like like a communicate with
pillows alike we communicate with the
libraries so this is what we did we
implemented yet
index driver that time we called it
Piazza leap we got rid of the server
power extracted API and basically we
tried to prototype some stuff first of
all we had to deal with all the storage
NAS we had to open and close first so
like index fields and fields contains
the views and fragments can cache and
stuff like that but we first we found a
holder which was kind of the nice thing
because holder lets you open the whole
terror he just by calling the open and
close think and it does all the thing
from you so some sounded promising at
the time but suddenly appeared that we
had so many problems and random crashes
in this concurrent world with the holder
so we took a closer look how the holder
was implemented and apart from all the
handlers and and the filth it contained
two channels opened and closed closing
these two channels are only used in
these two functions open and closed and
they close the opening open channel in
the open function and they close the
closing channel in the close function
what means that in a concurrent world it
possible that you try to open already
open file or closed already closed file
and basically instead of do nothing call
return the error it panics and please I
really like pulasa don't get me wrong
but if you are doing something like this
please dot it's bad it's bad by default
nobody should do it so so how we solve
this problem we decided to get rid of
the holder it's the easiest way so now
we have to really manually open index
and fields but the opening and close
functions for fields and indexes they
don't have this problem that when you
open once again nothing really bad
happened so yeah so we got rid of the
holder and we
some improvements one of them is that we
right now have one palasa
index per table so multiple database
indexes are contained in a one pilosa
index and one field is per per index
expression which can be the column name
and a partition this is something what
we introduced recently also what we
improve a little bit we still have the
mapping in both DB but we use the bucket
sequencer to get the next possible
available Rd improve a little bit
performance at all so we have to encode
and decode data so we use the got
package from standard library but what's
the good thing about having one palasa
index per table is that right now all
your indexes are in database indexes are
inside one palasa index so you can merge
them so how did it works this magic
stuff so let's start from the scratch
you have to create the index so first
you have this huge boolean matrix and
let's let's assume that we want to
create the index on a column a and B so
you create the index then you iterate
through all the expression a and B and
for each of them you create the field
let's assume for simplicity that we
partition just a one partition and it's
still the same index ID so you create
two fields you have this huge matrix
full of zeros then you have to populate
it by data so you iterate through
columns and every column let's say every
column is a new record in your table so
it's kind of that look smaller less like
a column database you iterate through
the records and you iterate through the
columns so you put the one you set the
bit one in every column that but you
have to figure out in which filled in
and in which row so you go to the field
which is mapped to your column and try
to get the wrong idea for your value if
value already exists that get row ID
function will return the row ID which
already exists if not it will generate
next ID for you so after you get that
you add you set the bit in the field and
you put it in your put the location in
your mapping so this is how you save
data and then you have someone's in your
matrix so now you want to query when you
query you put some filter like you want
to get all data where a is 2 and B is 4
so once again you tear it for the
expressions go through the fields and
then you have to find the row ID where
the value 2 and the value for R and for
simplicity let's say that value 2 is
assigned to row 2 in a and value for
assign it to Row 4 in B so at the end
when you already collected all the rows
which I assign it to your values because
it's an ant you have to do intersection
so so you intersect rows and as a result
we get these columns where the 1 was on
the same positions because it was
intersection so you get columns it's a 3
and a 5 as a result you go to the
mapping once again to get the location
we where are your records in your tables
which were assigned to values 3 & 5 this
is how the magic works but what's worth
to mention in my opinion was the good
thing about the bitmap indexes is the
matching pink and it doesn't make sense
with bitmap index is to create indexes
on multiple columns it's better to
create a 1 index per column the reason
why is that if I created the index on
columns a and B so on two columns then I
can the index will be used only if I do
intersections and the intersection will
be used as an internal operator
operation first but if I create the
indexes independently one index on a and
second index on B then I will get the
same
salt the intersection will be not
internal operation but the external
operation later but it will not have any
bad impact on performance but the good
thing is that if you replace and buy or
then it will do exactly the same instead
of intersection we'll just call the
Union and that's it so it doesn't make
sense because creating the index on
multiple columns it will only satisfy
and filters so how it was done because I
mentioned that we have pillows and
pillows illipe drivers but it's also
possible to implement all index driver
because everything what we did we did
through the interfaces and so first of
all you have an index driver interface
which just has this basic functions
which lets you create load safe and
delete index and this function return
the index interface which basically has
two main functions has an get which can
answer your question do I have this
value and if I have the value you can
get the value and to get the value and
call the function get it returns index
lookup which more or less is kind of a
wrapper on on a value integrator also we
have some indexes which let us query by
ranges with like Austin index so we can
ask questions greater less than etc but
they also all of them they return the
index lupa lookup and the index lookup
as I mention is kind of the wrapper on a
on an iterator it just gives you the
iterator based on the partition but the
index lookup may implement set operation
interface and if you implement that
operation interface then you can match
lookups by intersection Union and
difference as a result you will get
another look up and get get the values
so this is how magic works and the last
but not least is mapping mapping is
important because basically with the
bitmap indexes you have just a row
columns so you have to map values and
three chords to columns and row I DS so
the mapping works like this you you want
to get the row ID for your value row
local rows are Locker / field so you
have to specify in which field you pass
the value so it refers we encode the
values by drop encoder and then then we
get the bucket in a ball DB where which
is assigned to the field and we try to
get the value from the bucket if it
exists then we immediately you can
return the ID row ID if it doesn't exist
we take a next available row ID calling
this next sequence and we once again
encoded to the little endian format and
we'll put it in a in a bucket for board
eb and of course return from the
function so this is basically how it
works similar function is to get the
location from column ID instead of
encoding with decoding columns IDs to
get the location and this is basically
how it works so maybe I can demo some
stuff if I have a time it's like a five
minute left if you have it's but it's a
question like do you have any questions
or I can demo something how magic works
because what can go wrong with the life
demo we found 500 people in front of the
and industry and live streaming nothing
but can make happen so them are all
questions okay
Lala bigger really say stop
okay
I think I already compiled it so server
get me server I have some small repo
here in Reapers indexes will go Texas
okay okay I put it some devack functions
so we can see here how it works
basically I'm still debugging with print
lines I don't know how many of you likes
debugging with print lines
yeah I'm it's like we are passing almost
first quarter of the 21st century but we
are still debugging with print lines I
really like them and I hope there it
will tell me how about improvements on
mark or else but so far with lines also
save my day so okay all right
no possible route okay let me open I
have some script
okay so first of all I'd like to show
you one of the tables which is so I will
test against some table which is called
comic files and it contains like a
couple a deposit all right D committee
hush-hush and you have a one just one
repo called basic and it has tons of
stuff so right now so right now I'll
create the index first index okay three
indexes
a B on columns on two columns and a on
one column and B on the second column
okay and this is Carly's debugging works
so basically basically it creates the
fields in your index it and it populates
by data and these numbers are so every
row has these numbers and these numbers
say in which column the one was said
because I increase the font so much so I
don't know if what I want to say if it's
so here for example we have we have a
field which is assigned to the file path
in index a B but if you go to the go to
the field which is also file path but in
index a or B it will have the same data
so basically having also indexes on two
columns and on just on one column it
duplicates data so it's better instead
of duplicating data created the one in
the expert column and
so let's say we want to use this select
to get to get the comet ha to get
everything where the comet - is this and
five of his death and we caught we call
explain to explain how the query will
work and it says it will use indexes a B
if I replace and by or it will use
indexes just a and B so the reason why I
said that
it's better to have independent in the
access instead of is that I can drop the
index on a B I can drop and once again
call explain and this time to in Texas
will be used instead of one because I
drove the a B so right now we can we can
use indexes a and B independently and it
will also work with or okay last thing
is that let me query query did gave
result and this is how it work we get
two rows from the bitmaps we intersect
them so the position the only position
zero zero is the position where the in
involve bitmaps where one was set so we
get the just a column one and as a
result it should be just one just one
record wait where is it okay and this is
this one I'm done I'm running of the
time sorry
that's it thank you
perfect thank you
yeah
hopefully
[Music]
Oh
my money
[Music]
I resent about with my money
now we're going to pause thank you
are you happy
[Music]
boy boss even
I try to steer um do you want some food
oh yeah
I'm not filled with an apple today I'm
this morning I was filled with an apple
[Music]
without lays perfect for me and I like
that doing that I'll figure it out of
Dorne