so I'm gonna go ahead and start so
welcome to my talk it's about variety in
2019 the world has changed let's change
the radio what we're gonna do in the
next 40-something minutes
it's basically we look back but I'm
gonna keep this really really brief on
the last five years of three-point-seven
which come to an end I think that era
will be over soon then we'll talk about
what happens next when will actually
release 3.08 and how that'll gone
yeah that'll happen we talk about what
happens afterwards and I guess a lot of
the things that will be interesting to
most of you will be the Q&A session so
I'm trying to kind of rush through it so
that I could actually take questions so
let me get started really shortly I was
actually gonna skip that slide but I
added because just last year at first
them I became the chief architect of new
radio so now I wear like several hats
the guys that basically paid my hotel
here like I support and like I supply
grumpiness to the edge of support I'm
also like a research assistant at CL at
cultural which makes me proud that my
former bachelor advisor like did a quick
talk and information theory here and
aside from that I basically freelance
and I said mainly I'm here because I'm
the chief architect of caen radio so let
me talk about in radio so gradual you
know the version that you probably use
if you install radio and some binary for
almost thirty seven something and three
seven has been around for quite a while
we basically never got around to
increasing the the minor versioning
number three seven has been around since
2013 and somewhere around this time like
some we're late 2014 the
branch was actually you know branched
off the master branch to like develop
the next version of Grady which was to
become 3.8 and then there was like five
years of 3.8 in the making and you can
imagine that if you have two branches
one being the master branch from which
you basically do nothing but release
compatibility versions and the next
branch way you do basically everything
but can't really agree on which
direction to take this is going to be
like a really complicated time for the
project so this this really took a long
time and we finally got gotten around to
merging the next branch back into the
master branch but which was a great
great task and I'm really thankful for
like Andre Martin and others helping me
with that I wouldn't have been able to
do that myself alone definitely not but
the state we're currently in is that we
have like kind of the last 3.7 releases
have been of a main three point seven
branch and everything that happens on
master is like two words of future two
or three point eight so that's where we
are our last three point seven release
has been a while in the past and we're
getting ready to get three point eight
out door
so what happened in three point seven
cents basically I took over its first of
all like I introduced semantic
versioning that was kind of long overdue
I also kind of formalized the change the
format that was like my thing
and I said we retired that the idea that
we have a next branch that is supposed
to be like the next a great thing and we
are mainly due on back ports we we kind
of like do everything on master now and
for like releases we have a maintenance
branch that has like the release in its
name and for example three point seven
point fourteen point Oh would be tacked
of main three point seven not of master
so
with that we're kind of accelerating
development often radio that actually
has worked out we've got a lot of things
that were in the pipeline for a long
long time merged in during the last year
so I'm very happy about the dispute that
all this has taken up so with me talking
about releasing 3.8 obviously everyone
that's using greater productively like
there's people running you know set like
ground stations of this they might be
asking themselves well are we going to
support 3.7 for any longer then and and
the honest truth is like we've been
supporting this for five years and
everyone knows that if you're doing
software long enough then every single
part of its behavior kind of becomes API
whether it's documented or not so yeah
we will be supporting that for a while
longer I can't actually give you a
timeline for that but to be honest like
it will probably be as long as like my
least-favorite distribution Ubuntu 1604
will be supported because that's
basically the thing that holds up like
Hope has all dependencies that still
apply to that version so once people
can't compile that reasonably on their
modern machines anymore
there's really no point in us supporting
it any longer if you if you want to
contact me and say hey I run big
software on that I'd like to help you
support three point seven in six years
I'd be very happy but I honestly don't
see that happening so for now I promise
that we're not gonna drop three point
seven soon but I promise that we will at
some point move on with our lives
so but what that means is that three
point seven will never be Python 3
compatible three point seven will never
be C++ 11 three point seven will not get
any of the cool new more fundamental
features that three point it has if
we're doing back fixes on three point
eight there's a high chance that we can
back port that will do that I've been
doing that in the past but you know
there's only so much time so if you've
been working with three point seven five
the last five years chances are all the
backs that are in the area I have
already been fixed by you or not noticed
by you so yeah so enough chatter about
3.7 what what what does all this 3.8
about this is kind of like the
conclusion of my talk at thearc on this
year so I'm gonna keep this rather short
if you wanna know more about that I
think they can radio conference we use
our online by now but I won't really
want to I hope so
I'm actually not sure but but to
highlight a few things so the main
reason that we need 3.8 is really that
you know Python 2 is no longer an option
QT 4 is no longer an option so we had to
move forward with these dependencies
cheetah has been like kind of dad also
it's only Python 2 so our core XML
parser for like GRC has gone away so we
had to rearrange a lot of stuff so all
the green dots here are happy faces in
my head we have one one dependency
progression like look for CPP is
becoming more and more problematic we
don't need to replace that also we need
a better logging system and it's not
easy to adapt other sister logging
systems to ours because well we have
specific multi-threading needs we have
specific problems with runtime
discovering of this sub system so this
is this is going to be interesting we
threw out a bit of stuff so to anyone
who's using gr committee I'm kind of
sorry but I know no any of you so if you
need that please do contact me I'm I
don't care about it right now if you
need it
we'll keep it but so far I have not met
a single user so might as well not keep
it code quality is questionable because
none of us understand what it does so I
do want to highlight a bit of like this
this is all the opposite of exciting
right this is all like maintaining stuff
this is all about you know pay
the malls they've become slightly gray
like the the interesting stuff is like
well one childish shout out I want to do
is like to Swapna who's sitting in the
corner over there who's actually come
from India to here he's been doing the
google Summer of Code for us this here
he's been improving G our motto which
has become way more easy like nicer to
use has better code structure so I'm
very thankful for that it has new
features like proper detection of blocks
it I'm very happy about then we also
have Hong Kong which I've sorry yeah
he's he's also here he's been here last
year too he's been doing she saw the
year before now we have C++ code
generation and GRC so you're used to GRC
when you hit the run button it's it
generates a Python module and like
python program and execute it we can now
generate C++ code so you can you know
compile cross compile and run it on your
toast or whatever so and the feature
that like I like by numbers most users
will be interested in us like that GRC
has overall become way nicer way cooler
what I mean with that is that you can
actually have like the canvas now as a
vector-based canvas you can actually
export PDFs which might be interesting
for people who you know put things into
printed publications and also like the
code base really really really looks a
lot nicer structured inside us lot less
duplication of functionality cleaner
abstraction and I hope that that's
really a big hope that this enables
every one of you who like probably will
find the back into your see because we
have so many that everyone can get a
free one that that enables you to just
go in and say okay this is easy this is
spice my nose Python let's take that fix
that so that's that's like the exciting
things that happen in GRC so these are
like the main selling points that I have
for three point eight
aside from the whole like being nicer to
forward development things so
and this this question has basically
been asked well like years before I even
became maintainer when we were released
3.8 and the honest truthful answer is
when it's ready and I promise we're not
going to do it a minute later like the
day it is ready we will release it but
all like taking care that it is actually
ready but we will release it as soon as
possible what will not do is like
release it a month earlier because that
means that someone's going to ship a
broken system and we're not gonna get
that out for years so I do have like a
few blockers to highlight here first of
all like there's been ongoing efforts to
modernize the see make we use we'll just
let and basically done by Android which
is very important because a it makes
detecting certain libraries with like
the standard tools possible at all and B
it makes using narrator in your own
project way way way easier and way way
way safer so this is really something
and I want to get out there with the
three point 8.00 release because doing
it any later only will complicate things
so that this is already orange alright
that you can't tell this on this Beamer
but this thing is actually working
progress this thing is something that
we've not even tackled yet why well it
depends on the first one what Newell T
template means is that right now we are
expecting you as great users to well use
can radio and right cool
at the our software with that and most
people do that by having their own out
of three module but having your own out
of three modules wouldn't be possible if
we you know in the past had not have a
template to work from where even like
geometry is actually just the tool to
take their template customize it for you
purposes and then add the functionality
that use it just so you don't have to
write for
play code and we don't have that
template yet so that's kind of a blocker
because if I put out gr 3.8 and no one's
able to actually like write software for
that then adoptions will probably be
about zero then I mentioned look for CPP
so we have to re-implement the logging
system this is gonna be fun um there's
specific industry needs that you need to
be addressed we know the people that are
actually willing to help us Tara to to
contribute there but we need to like
come up with a reliable infrastructure
idea at least then we also have like a
lot of packs that are simply like oh
this crashes in GRC for example and like
some of them are really just blockers so
we need to fix those and like this this
like I came up with this like last
minute yesterday night
obviously this this belongs in the same
category as an OT template people have
not only you know half the tools but
also know how to use the tools so we
need some documentation we need to
update our tutorial it's this kind of
thing so this is this is a bit of a
shout out to mark liftman who has been
like our new documentation officer he's
very very motivated but um we've like
not been able to actually like nail down
how things will work so that we can tell
it in newbies so yeah that's something
that we need to come up with so if you
want to have with that because you're
really really eager to get great a 3.8
and I can see in all your faces that you
definitely are do go to like our own
radio github repo click on projects and
you'll see the release 3.8 project and
what you see is that we have open issues
issues say that work in progress and a
lot of close issues so do pick one of
the open ones and and comment on that or
fix it I probably prefer fixing it but
to be honest like reproducing a back is
really really helpful for a lot of
things that we simply don't know whether
they've just broken on that singer
machine because someone fiddled around
with something else or are actually
broken so go into that project find an
open problem
go into our 248 or something issues that
are still open and you know read through
them that would be very helpful to me
and yeah that will like help me answer
that question sooner so assume we have
fixed all like the open things what what
what we would you yeah so after we got
the blocker sorted out I'll go in and
tech release candidate one what will
that mean that that will mean that we
that I have something that I believe
runs on every computer that should be
running radio realistically there will
be bugs so what we need to do with that
release candidate is get it out on the
street so what we will do and that's
that's a new like something that we've
not been overly good at so far is like
have our own binary packages with that
so that people can actually you know add
like if you're on Ubuntu add a PPA if
you're on some red arrow it's at like
the DM source if you're on
I don't know Mac ports I do the
appropriate thing and just get new radio
release candidate so then we wait some
time for the box to trickle in um that
will be like that actually depends on
which time that happens if it happens
around like someone's doing like someone
from the core team doing vacation that
might take a week longer but let's let's
say this this this time frame was here
two to three weeks after that after we
think that most of the bugs have been
fixed we will do something that is super
nice to me we will just apply clang
former to the whole code tree because if
you've been looking at at kinetochore
code then you will notice that there's a
lot of personality in the way Linden's
are used or a lot of well freedom in the
way people put braces and on lines and
things so that automated code formatting
will be a singer commits kill all thing
which will hopefully not break anything
I'm pretty sure about that because you
know the clang people tend to know what
they're doing
but yeah that'll that'll probably like
allow us to release wreaths can be there
too and at the same time we can branch
off the main three-point-eight branch
and start working on master for the 3.9
so after we release our RC - we like
wait another 10 workday is to let you
know the latest blockers come in if any
then we release three point eight point
open oh and then we have the party but
probably consist of me having a barbecue
or something so that's like I hope to
like raise a bit of feeling of
transparency here it's like we're all
sorry that it took forever but we're
trying to be like pretty for what about
getting it out the door so so what but
what's going to happen at once that we
have three point eight release yeah well
as mentioned we'll have a mains three
point eight print from which like three
point eight point one or whatever will
be released so this is the place where
back fixes for that release will be on
on master we're not going to develop for
three point eight if we decide that the
feature is cool enough to be part of
three point eight will gladly back port
that and in the beginning it will be
super easy but later on will focus like
master will only be future development
so this is three point nine will not
have next branch anymore so master will
be three point nine but as promised like
three point seven point whatever will
still be around will still care for a
few years but that at the moment it's
mainly like a single back fix per month
or something so there's not going to be
a much of traffic on main three point
seven okay so as mentioned three point
eight is kind of a
housekeeping relieves a keeping my car
running so that I can still run errands
release it is also a transitional
release in what way we put a lot of lot
of effort in you know maintaining the
ability to still use Python too which is
really unusual for projects most
projects that like no little needed to
let go of Python to just you know switch
over to Python 3 we didn't do that
because we anticipated that people would
want to port there out of three modules
to a new organ or a diversion but didn't
want to like rewrite most of their code
if title 3 breaks that so we won't still
want to enable people running 3.72 on
the same system build 3.8 so that's why
we're doing two point seven and three
point whatever in parallel on three
generators three point eight well we
will not do that afterwards because it's
really really a lot of effort but we see
it as like the Golden Bridge making your
out of three module future-proof is like
okay part two 3.8 that basically takes
care of you know all the architectural
stuff and if you want to part two -
three on the way that would be cool we
greatly appreciate that if you don't do
it later but be aware that three point
nine will be Python three so three point
nine
yeah is the thing that I'm like most
excited about right now because it's
getting so tangible right now first of
all I kind of like mention that multiple
times because it kind of is exciting if
you look at code a lot like after we
code for message the whole thing we will
be able to like we're obviously gonna
stop having that feature freeze that we
have right now are focusing on three
point eight and I promise and this is
really very dear to my heart it's like
we're not gonna take another five years
to release three point nine we need like
features to be away
sooner so yeah that's how we like
directly after we leave 3.8 we'll start
working with 3.9 and what will des
entice um so what are the bigger scale
plans that I have for the future of
Conrad well first of all I want to be
more inclusive and into two aspects like
first of all I feel that noir idea
should be more like it is like like the
core of your ecosystem and should work
out of the box for a lot of purposes
so like the usual user of curator starts
with an outlet al dong or Hecker F or
probably not anymore with the use of P
so you guys start installing the radio
and then compiling tier Ausmus AR from
source which is which is fine I like to
euros more ser but it's an additional
burden to us users and it's not
consistently packaged and things get
outdated and so this this is not
something I want to keep that way so I
think that Nevaeh should come with
batteries included then the other way
around means that if I want the
ecosystem to work for everyone out of
the box that I have to care about the
ecosystem right so what I'm gonna do is
like consider things that I see a
central infrastructure and upstream it
so well there's a lot of people that
have like gr bus out there or gr food
that basically has some rappers some
stream operations that they reuse in
their own our teas multiple times and
that's all functionality that should
basically be in the radio and we should
also notice when it breaks when some
some architectural change breaks gr
phosphor that would be like kind of bad
but we will notice until someone wrote
an email to the mailing list that says
hey I've tried three point eight point
forty point oak and you know now all my
colors are inverted and my dog started
barking so that's something that we need
to have like
be more of a yeah umbrella organization
that actually builds your co2 and tries
that so that means that we'll have more
things in tree then as by basically try
to line out the obviously we need to be
more photo future-proof so we need to
and that's that that's like easy to say
for a maintainer we need to track
dependencies more aggressively we need
to be like oh yeah whatever qt5 is going
away and how like in a year or so it's
not happening but 25 is going in a year
so let not space our new 3.11 on qt5
let's be more aggressive at adopting
newer dependencies that only works if
we're doing a like more regular release
cycle so this is this is an interesting
aspect that also requires us to be very
clear about how long we're gonna support
things like three point eight or three
point nine so that that's something that
we need to come up with a clear strategy
for also what that means is that we
remove all burns and replace them with
new Mons I mean with modern alternatives
for for problems that we're having right
now I could like name quite a few of
these but I'm coming to that in detail
in a minute what we also need to do in
ads that's kind of obvious like we had a
birth of Heather meeting yesterday with
new radio users and a lot of things
where single time users new users would
like to be users and it turns out that
installation is a major major obstacles
still like in 2019 imagine that people
can't just use like a binary package to
get like the recent version of no radio
from from the development tree we have
no nightly builds we have no binaries
that are outside like every distros
maintenance scope so and that's
something that we need to change so
personally I have to stream where like I
don't only have a nightly version of new
radio somewhere like whatever a PPA that
ships nightly versions of no radio
but also like nightly versions of cheeks
because that depends on the radio and
nightly versions of clear AAS because
tracking ships is cool but you know it
depends on the radio so that leads to me
to like as you of our team binaries that
we would need to build like on a regular
basis which would kind of make pie bombs
obsolete which i think is a bad thing
but yeah that would be pretty cool if I
could just go and say apt-get install
you know gr my latest module and and
people would get my latest modulus
binary and obviously better Docs
well obviously you can always document
better I used to be feeling bad about
Canary documentation but a special
Brennan's talk opened my eyes towards
like the badness of other people's
documentation and I yeah I've I'm
getting less and less apologetic about
our documentation we just need to be
more clear at the basic level so that
people are able to research stuff
themselves and we don't need to like
document the hell out of every single
block so that's that's an easier task
less daunting that then then I used to
think and lastly we need to be better
overall like obviously like narator has
been a great project for like 15 years
like no 17 years by now but that also
comes with like some technological debt
we have basically we can't exchange our
scheduler right now there is this red
fur block schedule which is kind of cool
if you have a pout as many threats as we
have blocks but most modern machines
have like 4 to 32 cores and like a
single like a single balanced flow graph
has like 200 blocks so you might see
there's there's some mismatch here so we
need to be clever about the way we
schedule things we need failures to be
able to adapt to the problem and to the
platform they're running on then we have
this problem where the radio is Bri
really focus on running on one and the
same machine but in reality
narator should be a framework for
running connecting blocks and doom
signal processing right so it would be
super desirable to be able to you know
have few blocks run on my laptop and
then have this block somewhere in the
cloud running like the LDPC decoder
because that's super super complete
intense and that's actually what like
mobile network operators are doing
they're running more and more of their
software wherever that's the cheapest
thing to do and that's somewhere we need
to be but that's really hampered by the
fact that we share state between blocks
and this is sadly not limited to samples
that cross in buffer sets also Sam
implemented by things like having
equalizer that both my off the M
receiver need to modify and the off the
equalizer block actually needs to use so
we need to have the ability to pass
matches messages with info and be more
RPC oriented overall currently our RPC
framework is basically broken I gladly
admit that see a grin over there yes it
is we need to like re implement that and
yeah thanks Martin
yeah that all boils down to actually
writing a new scheduler so that'sthat's
like a very rough idea where I want to
take things but hey having such plans is
awesome as we all know we're not like
kind of 300 people per company that
dedicates their time to development so
how much of that is going to happen in
2019 I can't let me say that we have
laid the foundation for everything on
one of these points we're not able to
tackle like finally solve any of these
in 2019 completely but like what we'll
do is for 3.9 and I'm very happy to say
that we will be able to upstream gr so P
so like thanks to the cooperation with
like
the developers and especially leave a
space foundation we can make your
favorite STR work with an already out of
the box that's kind of true um you still
need like their respective SD our driver
but the fact that sopia is basically a
plug-in based architecture so that you
can load a shared object at runtime
means that at installation time of can
radio you don't have to have like your
Hecker F driver already linked into that
you can load it later on and that's
that's a very nice thing it enables us
to like more aggressively develop
features instead of trying to you know
having to have to link to every single
hardware driver that that might be there
will also upstream GRI IO which is kind
of special purpose this is I kind of
view this as as a test balloon because
cRIO doesn't make too much sense on a PC
as far as I can see I hope the ADI guys
will correct me it makes more sense on
SLC's it makes sense if you're like
building something with an ad chip on it
and obviously embedded compute is
something that we want to be more in
like I think that's that's where a lot
of the future of glory will happen is
less on laptops of academics that dual
simulations this will be more on you
know devices actually doing network
stuff or satellites and I said that we
also have like a lot of interesting
options that we need to upstream about
you know better networking blocks so
that's that's what we do about being
inclusive 43.9 asset to future-proof 3.9
we can drop Python to compatibility like
there is no destroy in the future that
doesn't have at least 5 and 3.5 that I
care about at the point that will
release 3.9 so we can completely drop
pipe into compatibility we can
drastically increase the see make
version that we depend on it that's very
nice
because see make is kind of a nightmare
she used the older it gets and this is
like the biggest point on the slides if
very clearly we have a problem with PMT
PMT is our internal library for
exchanging data objects in messages and
stream tags and it's I know where it's
coming from it it it does a fairly okay
job at being what it is it is a
polymorphic type to like I can put an
integer in there I can put a dictionary
in there I can transport sample data in
there but it's all very it is slow it is
kind of awkward to use and mostly it's
buggy in the way it's wrapped into
Python and C++ and well and also it's
our serialize ER with the downside
that's not actually portable and there's
no language support aside from Python
and C++ which happen to be the languages
that you could natively talk to great
with so so we need to get rid of that
enable to enabling us to actually come
up with a better RPC basis because our
piece a our PC won't work if you don't
have a way to share data so then we have
the simplified aspect that's I already
mentioned that we need to have binary
releases I don't know if they're gonna
be nightly and we're not that fast maybe
weekly would totally do I guess
somewhere in the middle where we're
gonna figure that one out
we're also gonna do I mentioned the
template for out of three modules that
template should have like the minimum
infrastructure to make it easy for you
to like create a debian package of a RPM
I actually don't care
preferably both so that you can you know
dispute is to your potential customers
like I hope that people will use you
anymore in commercial deployments like
they should less or a compile just on my
machine and then I have to pee that over
then I talked about bettering ourselves
I don't think this is gonna
the complete and three-point line but
you know we're gonna start with having
our PC in every aspect of generator so
there's no reason that we should have
setters and getters and blocks that
can't be called remotely that's just
like our heritage and a bit of our
laziness so we need to start working on
that and this is making me very happy
a lot of you guys probably know woke as
our library of Zim d operations and it
basically meant to be a spinoff of caen
radio what it is in reality right now
it's it's like its own github repo and
that's being a sub-module like it's app
module actually in radio and that makes
no sense at all because either you
develop it out of tree or your developer
in tree but you shouldn't do both but
without picking up speed we can
basically ensure that VOC has regular
releases so we can actually make VOC and
external dependency and maintain it as
its own project that it has become a
long time ago so with that being said
let's draw a quick conclusion will not
not please let three-point-seven bleed
out we'll support for a while I promise
we will be releasing three point eight
very soon we could use your help we
could use your coffee but it's it is
coming it's not like it's not abstract
anymore we know what to do we know
actually have a list of things that need
to be done and if that list has become
like all strike-out we will release that
3.9 after that is the next big thing in
that it adopts a new strategy at
upstreaming and it starts getting rid of
architecture that that hopefully will
allow us to be well cooler for new users
so with all that being said i'm open to
question thanks for your attention
[Applause]
yeah Andre and you everywhere what else
would you use your sauce scr's with so
the question was how to address more
like closer latency requirements and
that's something that we can't do with
the current scheduler because I was
count scheduler simply is only optimized
for throughput on a potentially infinite
many-core machine so there's no precise
plans last year I talked with a
gentleman that and we will be addressing
like scheduler constraints that will be
allowing us to risk restrict latency but
we're I mean that's not happening in
three-point-nine likely so realistically
making the scheduler adaptive like
pluggable will be a necessary to like
you know experiment with different
scheduling strategy so this first
latency later so so the question was
what about Michael support yeah what
about it I actually don't know what that
so it doesn't compile all of the box on
Michael's I actually don't know I have
never used my kha'zix so I have my guys
for that and my impression is that we're
actually doing a pretty good job on that
so I can only like this this hasn't come
up the first time at FOSDEM
this year I can only ask you to actually
write that email to the mailing list or
open the back because we can't fix
things that we don't see maybe I mean I
can't rule out that you're doing
something wrong I'm I'm not willing to
blame this on you I'm the other hand
so please do write that email
yeah I mean yeah you weren't unwelcome I
mean we can set you up with whatever you
need
so givi so if they're something one run
with luck for CPP yes so look for CPP is
I first of all like I be honest I don't
like it that's that's the first thing um
it is now it is like a C++ part of log4j
that says a lot and it also like it has
recently shifted the the C++ version it
it requires so we're right now running
like with a bit of you work around so
it's simply not reliable enough then
also and that's that's the other thing
we do need a better logging system I've
been like at Congress I've been talking
to the Osmo chrome guys because they
internally have a logging system for
their network oriented stuff which much
more like what I want ready love them to
become and putting this on top of lock
our current lock for CPP structured it's
like not really paying so we might as
well replace that with whatever is
easier
so the question was what what will
happen in with respect to dynamic
reconfiguration of flow graphs that
question it's a bit of background I'm
currently like if you say dear flow
graph I want to disconnect this block
from the other block and connect them in
a different way what happens if you you
basically stop everything everyone
grinds to a halt and then in some more
or less specified state the buffers are
reconnected and that's a nightmare we
can't be doing that in the future sadly
this is very very integral to like how
the current schedule of work so the
answer is kind of the same as for the
latency restrictions it probably
requires rewriting of the scheduler I
mean if this I'm the architect I say
probably because you know I have I do
feel I have an understanding of how the
current scheduler works but there's just
too many corner cases with how its
implemented like it there's literally
too many go tools in the source code
that to make to allow me to predict like
corner case behavior like what happens
if I reconfigure and someone else says
ok I'm done and yeah so this this needs
modeling this for most needs a modeling
of what how things should be behaving
but modeling existing software is
actually harder than like writing
software to a specification that you
have made up prior based on your
experience with your current software so
yeah I said it basically requires you to
like write a scheduler yeah sir
thank you