so shall we start I have my own
okay our next is Martin Dickie not this
year I already did at the risk five the
room actually yes
thanks for the introduction thank you
all for coming and when I'm mentioning
it I mean most of the talk will be about
the same topic I have already spoken
about the risk well double room so if
you have seen that there is no reason
for you to see see it again unless you
would like to discuss and again this is
as usual this is this something I always
do more less like an opinion piece to
spark some discussions so Lisa hats
please go ahead and disagree with me so
for those who don't know me I've been
working in operating system domain for
some some time I have been working on
the halle newest project since 2004 I
have been working at the Charles
University in Prague on formal
verification of all Innovas and quite
recently I mean not longer than two
years ago I have joined well they where
I'm doing the same stuff microkernels
and formal verification stuff like that
so I would like to tell you that
microkernel multi server systems are
better than monolithic systems that's it
thank you no really seriously I mean
this has been I would say an in-form
opinion of many people for many many
years and gradually we got some I would
say qualitative evidence that this
statement is true but I mean qualitative
evidence is still just basically a form
of a point of an opinion now we are
gradually also getting quantitative
evidence that the monolithic operating
system design is flawed so you have
probably noticed there is this paper
co-authored by our friend Arnold Heiser
who has been
we had the privilege to see today and
this paper basically looked on several
critical vulnerabilities in doing Linda
UNIX kernel and tried to try to estimate
if this these vulnerabilities would have
been mitigated if there were if we would
consider a state-of-the-art microkernel
design such as a CL 4 and yeah I mean
you can read a summary here you can read
the entire paper and it's pretty much
convincing so I mean this is this is a
single piece of evidence that we are
getting in the right direction we are
going in the right direction with with
microcar Mo's but and this brings me
back to my original talk at FOSDEM
microkernel double room in 2012 we are
paying some price the price is with the
performance overhead and if you if you
were there if you remember remember my
joke I said that it's a it's a fair
price according to my opinion so I mean
there is no free lunch but you know the
safety security availability other
guarantees that the microkernel provides
are you know counterweighted by by some
performance overhead that we need to pay
but is it really is it really necessary
is it really unavoidable let's look on
on this the microkernel ideas are not
particularly new I mean their earliest
incarnations were already set in 1969
but you know there was and there is
still some disconnect between the
software design and the hardware design
designing hardware used to be
complicated expensive in recovery
usually required a huge company to back
it and you know therefore the operating
systems have been written
for the CPUs only after the CPUs were
out so not not not before I mean even
having a powerful emulation tools like
um ooh
stuff like that that that was not always
available so you know something happened
that the hardware designs got stuck in
in certain ways I mean really try to
think about something rebel
revolutionary and in hardware design
that hasn't been there already in IBM s
some 370 I mean
memory management it was there
virtualization it was there i om mu it
was there offloading you know
computations to two dedicated hardware
devices I'm talking about you know
so-called date action also how I don't
remember it was there already so there
is nothing new Under the Sun and the
problem is that microkernel suffer
because you know the the the current
hardware is being designed for the
monolithic kernels in mind or we've done
one or two monolithic kernels in mind
and therefore we need to pay the
performance panel penalties due to the
fine grained design due to the need of
crossing forcing the address space
barriers due to the IPC mechanisms and
stuff like that so let's try to change
it let's try to design the hardware in a
better way or in a way that is more
suitable for for for the requirements of
the microkernel systems I really think
that there is this vicious cycle that
the CPUs currently don't support the
micro kernels properly therefore micro
kernels suffer performance penalties
when running condemned compared to to
the more monolithic systems therefore
micro kernels are still not considered
you know the true mainstream I mean yes
we have them on safety critical and
mission-critical devices we have them
maybe in some embedded devices but yeah
you can have Mike OS which is running on
Mac but justice
single-server microkernel but still you
know we are talking about Linux and we
are talking about making Glen Oaks more
secure and stuff like that which is
crazy I mean the only way how to make
links more secure is throwing in
throwing it out and since the Linux is
the micro kernels are still not in the
mainstream there is no strong push on
the hardware manufacturers to actually
provide CPUs with proper microbial
support and this closes the vicious
cycle well there has been a lot of
effort spent on on this box already I
mean for the past 25 years people have
been trying to squeeze out every single
CPU cycle from their microkernel code to
make the IPC run as as smoothly and ask
as quickly as possible but it was given
given the you know limitations of the
hardware they had so so and I mean we
have been trying on this too right I
mean this is the reason why we are
meeting here so so now let's focus on
this part so let's focus on on the
requirements on the hardware and let's
focus on creating better hardware to
support our micro kernels to finally get
rid of this this trade-off between
safety and performance security and
performance performance
I got some ideas I have to say these are
very rough ideas and again this is
something where I would like to spark
the discussion I would like to spark you
know or inspire people thinking about
the actual mechanisms that could be done
to to make this happen and my ideas are
targeting you know the obese culprits
like the IPC and context switching and
stuff like that so first about the the
problem with the IPC in the microkernel
multi-server systems the final
architecture it is the better for for
safety and security availability
dependability but you know the more we
are paying due to the address space
we need to move due to the need to move
data between other spaces so I mean the
III probably don't need to explain the
problem in very much detail but compared
to the model the kernels were
communication between substance
subsystems is just a function call in in
a micro or multi server system like this
the same communication is implemented
via IPC which means that we cannot use
all the registers for actually passing
the arguments because some registers are
reserved for something else
we need to switch to the kernel level to
the kernel privilege mode and switch the
address space and then switch back we
potentially need to do some scheduling
in between and paste the IPC's
asynchronous of course this is not
necessary and if we are moving larger
amounts of data we either need to copy
them between the other spaces or
establish some kind of memory sharing
which again might be a little bit costly
so what to do about this one thing that
it probably would be probably quite
simple just implementing richer call or
jump instructions in instructions that
would actually switch to address space
by themselves so that you know we would
we would save at least the single kernel
roundtrip where the kernel the only
thing that the kernel is actually doing
here is changing the address space this
could be done by by the hardware or by
the CPU and it could be as simple as
just switching the the current address
space identifier of course this still
needs to be just just a mechanism just
generic basic mechanism are not
proposing you know moving some kind of
policy from from the operating system to
the CPU that would be crazy so how to
how to do it implement by having
something like a colgate that would be
cached in
kind of hardware cache why could
something like a TLB so you know the
first time this call happens obviously
it will trap into the kernel the kernel
will check you know the permissions
capabilities and stuff like that and set
up and I entry into this into this
hardware cache and and consequent
consequent cause will be done done just
just by the CPU I believe this could be
really very simple
regarding the I synchronous IPC where
there is probably some need for
buffering of the messages I also think
this could be optimized I mean even
nowadays like some like like somebody
already mentioned at my talk yesterday
this could be you know there's this
message buffering and message passing
could be optimized by you know making
sure that you don't trash the messages
from our cache lines that's fine but
again I would imagine that the the CPU
could could do it even more
intelligently so basically using the
cache lines as fixed size buffers for
for the messages and it's not a problem
that it's a fixed size because in most
of the micro kernels I have seen that
are using a synchronous IPC the kernel
buffers are also fixed size for obvious
reasons that the user space cannot you
know the kernel memory so again I would
see that there is a clear separation
between the mechanism that could be very
very efficient very fast very lean and
the policy that will obviously still
stay stay in in software if you remember
sparc v9 this reminds me of the register
stack engine that they have they're off
stack the stack and here what was the
term stock engine register second way
are 64 is it Itanium okay okay well
Farkas has some things in more so how
about the bulk data if we really need to
move a lot of data between between the
the processes or char
currently the current best optimization
we have is memory sharing which actually
works quite quite far quite nice quite
fine the only problem is that the memory
sharing needs to be established and and
simply turn down and if this if this is
happening too often this this causes the
performance penalty and also donate the
data needs to be paid aligned so so it's
not really very useful for sharing you
know scatter data structures it's fine
when you a new need to share you know
blocks blocks of data that needs to be
written to a block device driver or
write from a group device driver but
it's not not very useful for really you
know graph structures and trees and
stuff like that so again an idea that
could be something that could be done is
to have a new simple layer of memory of
hardware based memory management that
would map virtual addresses to cache
lines because a cache line is usually
something like 64 or 128 bytes which is
much more reasonable granularity for for
the scatter data structures and of
course again we need to you know sit
down we need to create a modal we need
to evaluate it we need to implement it
in an emulator to be sure how well this
will perform what should be the
parameters which should be the size of
the of this translation buffer
stuff like that but I really believe
there is some possibility to to make
this work context switching I mean we
have some somehow avoided parts of this
context switching in case of the IPC but
still the problem is that in a
microkernel multi server system there
are more active processes or more active
tasks than you know you know in a more
or less monolithic system so there will
be still some context switching
and you know all that our hardware is
currently doing is basically masking
latency and we have very efficient
mechanisms for masking nanosecond
latency that's called the caches we have
quite efficient mechanism for masking
millisecond scale agencies that's you
know IO buffers but the the context
which is precisely in the middle it's on
the order of microseconds and we have
really nothing to to mask this latency
so I mean I would I wouldn't say we
don't have we don't have anything there
is there is a hardware mechanism quite
often used which is multi-threading and
this is precisely why we have
multi-threading to be able to somehow
make sure that that the the a loose or
parts of the of the of the CPU had
always something to do
despite there is some data data or
dependency or waiting for some data but
this does not scale to many many frets
and usually have just a couple of
Hardware threads and we can do conduct
switching in in software so how about
combining this and having in there and
something like like a hardware support
for unlimited number of execution
contexts some of them the the most
frequently used would should be cashed
in some hardware cache and having some
dedicated instructions that is you know
extensions to to efficiently operate
with with these hardware contacts then
this will keep the scheduling policies
and stuff like that mostly to the to the
operating system but the the physical
mechanism of you know quickly switching
to a different workload one when our
current workload is being blocked on the
hardware level because it is waiting on
some some data that could be done
autonomously we could even think about
you know somehow connecting some other
external event triggers to this like
interrupts or exceptions and this would
allow us to do even more stuff I believe
her her slide
about this here yeah that would allow us
to do very simply or very elegantly
purely user space based interrupt
processing currently the interrupts
always trapped into the kernel space and
in a microkernel
environment would the kernel does it
generates some kind of IPC message that
is then being forwarded to to the user
space driver if we would be able to do
the fast context switching using the
hardware it is just a single step
further to extend it to the interrupt
interrupt delivery to the user space
drivers which would not only make
something faster it not only would this
allow us to get rid of of pulling in in
case we are dealing with some very
latency sensitive device were actually
you know even even in a monolithic
system the polling can sorry the
interrupt processing can be so expensive
that polling despite stupid is more
efficient but it would also you know
solve the the final the final compromise
regarding the elegance of the
microkernel design and that's the fact
and we still need some device drivers in
the microkernel like the timer with with
direct delivery of the inter up of the
timer interrupts to use a space timer
driver we would not need any time a
driver in the microkernel and possibly
even moving the scheduler out of the
microkernel which again you know is
something like a holy grail of many
people yeah something would need to be
done with the little trick interrupts
you know the usual pain point
again I I would say that there is some
possibility to have some integration
with the platform in terms of control or
that would autonomously mask the source
of the the level tricked interrupts when
it happens so that there is no no issue
with this endless reassertion of Holy's
capabilities I mean this is really just
just this is a stretcher I mean III did
not really find very much useful ideas
in my head about what could be done with
capabilities on the hardware level but
at least at least something I mean if we
just consider the narrow use case of
capabilities as as object identifiers
again the Mike Connell would always need
to be in charge of you know making sure
that that the methods Cortana
capabilities are permissible for that
holder of the capability and I wasn't
able to think about any honey
elegant hardware mechanism how this
could be avoided but at least for the
actual access to the object the
capability ID or the capability
reference could be somehow embedded
within within the pointer itself and
then the hardware would be able to
autonomously check whether whether the
access to that given object is allowed
by the current context if you think
about risk 5 128 128 bit variant I
believe you you must you could wonder
what would be the actual use of 128 bit
long pointers I'm not sure that you know
flat 128 bit pointer is really so useful
maybe it is maybe I'm wrong but we could
easily divide it into 64 bits for the
object offset and 64 bits for the
capability reference and this could work
quite elegantly by the way I mean this
would be probably even more useful for
some some managed languages like I don't
java.net
stuff like that because
they're always dealing with all the VMS
running those those manage did this
managed code is always dealing with the
fact that they need to do a lot of bound
checking on the objects and if this
could be offloaded to do Hardware it
would probably help them a lot okay some
ideas do do have something to add to
this yeah please and yes and I believe I
believe I have it have it here yeah so I
mean you might come to me and say oh
these are just wet dreams I mean this is
not going to happen so what I'm now
going to present unless there are other
commands or objections there are some
some cases or some some prior art which
somehow leads into the same direction
where I would like to convince you that
it is possible to do something like that
it's even possible to do something like
that with the hardware we currently have
so imagine the possibilities if we can
actually change the hardware let's think
out of the box so so the first reference
is you know just just a basic paper
rather old about actually offloading
some of the microkernel functionality to
hardware this was this was done by by
basically modifying and softcore FPGA
CPU and they were moving you know
actually complete operations like thread
creation and context switching so I mean
the context switching is something more
or less in in in the line would I have
suggested but the thread creation is
probably too heavyweight I would say but
nevertheless they were able to to
measure reasonable performance
improvement something like fifteen to
twenty seven percent and you know just
speaking about the ways how the hardware
could could optimize IPC this
has been also done in practice in the
wild on the massive parallel
architectures so again having having
lean hardware mechanism for efficient
message passing that is somehow
connected to to reasonable how software
abstraction for it so this could
probably work about you know the address
space switching there is an interesting
paper from from the barrel fish people
about space jump which is basically a
programming model where where a single
process uses multiple multiple address
spaces at once and this in in that case
that was not targeting some performance
improvement it was targeting you know
just just it was just entertaining what
would be the possibilities and benefits
of such a programming model for for
what's a data centric applications so I
mean this is not so much irrelevant to
what I have been talking about but but I
mean there they are approaches and they
were able to implement this on on
borrowed fish obviously in dragonfly bsd
so it did not require huge modification
to to the kernel abstractions and if you
if you are old enough like me you might
remember that if you are running an x86
cpu and 32-bit mode or probably even in
the 16-bit mode you can still have the
task state segment which is basically
hardware based context switching it does
not have a dedicated you know hardware
cache for that it just uses regular
memory for caching with contacts but
still I mean performance wise it's it's
still competitive to to the to do
software base approach
even the Linux kernel used to use this
mechanism previously and they stopped
using it not because of the performance
but because they just wanted to have a
more portable approach yes
yeah but that was probably just very you
know artificial limit because some in
some index in some you know you know the
global description table could not be it
was basically you know based on on the
selectors and yes yes so it was
something like 16 K or something yeah
but I mean that's that's the
technicality I'm not mentioning in that
this is the way we should we should do
it I'm just mentioning it because it has
been done so let's look at let's have a
look on it and let's improve it thank
you
okay about the cross address space calls
there has been actually quite nice paper
by some of my colleagues from Huawei who
have who have used the VM Fang VM funk
instruction or the VM functions
extension to do intel vt-x which is
something like that it's it's a
mechanism that allows you to basically
do cross VM calls by setting up some
Cole gates and then then you know just
you know using a single instruction to
to pass the registers from one one vm to
the other so it does the the world
switch and address space which I mean
switching the extended page tables on
the hardware level and actually this
paper contains an evaluation which were
theywere took rather complex application
something like a web server that the
user use uses the open SSL library and
they have separated some of the you know
encryption functions so individual
function calls from the rest of the
order of the binary into a dedicated VM
and they have used this VM func
instructions to to you know change it
from a normal function call to this to
this cross beyond call and their
performance evaluation was quite quite
interesting because the
en banc function was as costly as just a
single system call so it was not I mean
it was more costly than just a jump or
just just a call but not huge not more
costly definitely cheaper than going to
the to the hypervisor go into the kernel
go to the hypervisor making the the
address space and VMs which in software
so again I mean if we would think about
this mechanism in more detail if you
would try to improve it maybe this could
really be helpful for the micro kernels
actually my colleagues are working on
some suggestion in that that area and
they will they will publish a paper or
they have already a pipe paper accepted
at your office this year so if you are
interested into this have a look yeah
this is this is what you have mentioned
this is the cherry capability models so
an evaluation of how how the
capabilities could be implemented on
hardware level and then the this allowed
them to - this was evaluated on FPGA
soft core but the performance evaluation
was very positive and it allowed them to
have basic eight byte granularity memory
protection you know again the limitation
is that they have used 64-bit MIPS so
they had to somehow squeeze in the
bounds and starting addresses somewhere
so so they're they're obvious decision
was to have dedicated capability
registers like an extension to do to the
MIPS I saw which they they self confirm
that this is not so flexible so how
about using using the 128 bit pointers
and embed the capability under the virus
directly in them actually if you look on
Intel MPX
this is a similar idea that again has
been already implemented in some of the
newest into CPUs according to what
have read the implementations is not so
great I mean the performance benefits
compared to software bow software based
bound checking this is very minor and
the overhead is of step of setting up
this paint is not good but if it'll even
do it does it so why not try harder okay
so to sum up I really think that we have
done as the microkernel community a lot
of work first explaining to people that
suffer dependability or computer system
the best dependability safety security
stuff like you know things like that are
important and those goals cannot be
achieved by using a poor software
architecture like a monolithic
architecture I mean this applies not
only to operating systems this obviously
applies everywhere and see micro
services but I mean we have been always
struggling to to explain to people that
there are they have to pay some price
for for these required for for these
assurances it's funny that when when
there there are vulnerabilities such as
Spector or mount meltdown suddenly
everybody accepts a five to ten to
fifteen percent performance slowdown
just to get you know the assurances we
were always thinking we are having but
if we we would propose that we can have
more assurances we can have safer safer
you know systems we just have to pay a
small price for it I mean that we are so
suddenly being rejected so let's think
about the think out of the box and let's
design our hardware in such a way that
nobody could complain anymore and maybe
sorry I need to mention my colleagues
from from from Huawei who who have
contributed to the ideas I have
presented but what I wanted to say also
that if you really would like to do
something about this
practically I'm opening a new R&D lab in
Hawaii which will be located in Dresden
and obviously the location was not
chosen randomly and we would like to
have a very very balanced mix between
basic research so something like I have
presented here something like 40% and
obviously some practical development we
won't be you know making products we
will be an RD unit still but we will
obviously try to contribute to to our
product lines which is also good because
we have clear or we should have clear
requirements from our products and you
know our company's producing a lot of
hardware and if we would be interested
in working on this please let me know
please contact me by any means one side
note we own high silicon which is one of
the one one of the major risk so one of
the major ARM chip producers so we have
the possibility to actually you know
change the hardware that's it thank you
and if yes please okay support and all
of them most of that stuff implemented
in micro so now why did these approaches
fail I think the idea was Moore's law
killed them because regular general
processes got faster so to kill them we
are no longer in that situation so that
might be the point to time Boyd's
actually yes and when we were also
thinking and research about some of
these ideas like people have been
working on cash opening machines which
don't have direct access to yes thank
you for the comment just to quickly
summarize for the stream basically your
idea is that we are in the precisely
good moment in time to do something like
this because Moore's law is no longer
applying and stuff like that so we need
to do something to improve the
performance in generally speaking and I
would add to your comment my command
that we have risk right now and this is
a huge opportunity to actually you know
create a totally new open modular
hardware architecture that actually
might have some industrial traction so
let's let's take the opportunity I mean
I mean there wouldn't be in principle
ignorance of but on the other hand we
have a full arm arm license so we could
even change arm if you thank you
[Applause]
you