hi everyone my name is Thomas and uh a
few years ago actually with a bunch of
friends we had the idea of making the
internet a friendlier place how so
by enabling peer-to-peer communication
everywhere on the internet where
everywhere before we had unilateral
communication from site owners to the to
the web servers suddenly we wanted to
have peer-to-peer communication
everywhere on the internet so for that
we developed the high project which
which is actually a browser extension
that sits on top of every website and
offers you a chatroom depending on the
URL you sit in so you can actually chat
with all your friends and all peers that
are on the same web site as you are so
actually we had this idea quite some
time ago and then it's only recently
actually one year and a half ago that we
thought okay what about actually
including the block chain in this
product so we make it even more
transparent so we use the blockchain to
actually reward users when they provide
meaningful content to the platform and
also to actually share the value that is
created by the platform because we sell
contextual contextualised as in the chat
and actually the users get a share of
these advertising revenues
thanks to tokens so we decided to embark
on this journey of creating a social
network on the blockchain
but how my you might know about the
challenges linked to that so we
basically were faced with four key
challenges the first one was about cross
put so you know how do you deal with the
huge amount of transactions that you get
when you have thousands of users all
interacting at the same time with each
other we know today that aetherium
scales with up to a twenty or thirty or
so transactions per seconds that this
will be not enough for use case and then
user experience you know if you want to
build a social network it's not a one
player game you need like thousands and
thousands of users to make this a
meaningful experience where you intro
with plenty of people but to get this
method option you need a good you weeks
and you weeks is always you know
clashing with security and blockchain is
very secure so how do you make sure you
have a uux like that is friendly enough
that so that many people come and join
your network and then what about volume
if we start storing all the content of
the posts that's a trade and we're gonna
hit like a storage costs very very high
so how do we deal with that and then
actually last but not least this creepy
challenge of compliance
you know the regulatory environment
around blockchain is still fairly
undefined and there is still no clear
framework in place to see to say
actually who should be responsible if
hate speech for example is ever recorded
on the blockchain
you know hate speech has got to be
removed promptly on Facebook for example
otherwise Facebook is held accountable
so we wanted to make sure that we would
never be accountable for things that
users actually which post on the
blockchain on the content so we're faced
with these challenges and after quite
some thought process we we came up with
two or two solutions thankfully for that
so about the trot put and new exchanges
we decided to resort on our site change
solutions so I don't know if some of you
are here in the room know about these
little fellows probably like if there
are if they're e md Vela pairs within
the room you've seen them there are
actually the crypto zombies so we
decided for austin technology to use
technology provided by loom they're
great guys so they were first known for
crypto zombies so a series of tutorial
about how to learn a solidity and
developed and they've developed this
whole technology of their side chains to
support actually gaming and social kind
of use cases so which were like the
perfect fit for what we're trying to do
at hey and then next to that talking
about volume and compliance it's
actually forced us to focus on the so
called
minimum immutable product you know when
you're building something on the
blockchain you don't want to put all
your feature set like all your
architecture and systems on the
blockchain you want to make sure you
actually use blockchain only for what
it's best at so really focused on you
know identifying what it is that has to
be made immutable so that things are
open enough so that
the user trust FN trust us enough but at
the same time you know we make sound
architectural choices and that's how we
actually ended up only storing like the
ultimate output output of a user's
interaction resulting in value creation
so let me explain that we've decided not
to store any content from the user's
unchanged so we do not stop past we do
not store comments or whatever we do in
a store username all that we store is
actually you know interactions that
occurred between these users so for
example Alice is given one like to Bob
and so actually Bob will receive one one
karma one token and this is stored on
the blockchain but nothing about the
content so the storage requirements are
way lower and actually we also work
around the compliance issue link to that
so to give a little more insight about
loops or the sidechain technology that
we are using they're really great so
there they have a team of nearly a
hundred people now worldwide so doing a
plenty of exciting stuff so they're such
an technologies basically relying on a
tender min protocol so using delegated
proof steak with so called
validators so there are the miners of
this kind of protocol and then they
basically run the interim virtual
machine meaning like all the folks that
have learned to code an eatery um you
know using solidity of vipers and stuff
like that they can actually take the
contracts and just deploy them on and it
goes like that it's super easy so we
have all the stack we pepper 3gs etc so
really great for for us there's a huge
developers community and basically their
folk using their technology for the use
cases as I was saying of gaming and
social networks so for example actually
the very first use case for the rune
sidechain
was a delegate call so you can think of
dedicate call as kind of a stack
overflow specifically for things related
to to eat areum and the cool thing with
delegate call is that it's running fully
free on the blockchain like is
the content etc it was a bit the the
laboratory flume and one of the great
things actually that they've done with
this delegate goal and that we plan at
some point to do on hey it's actually
you know writing smart contracts
directly in go and then compiling them
and having them included embedded
directly in the binary of the chain
meaning like really all your things that
would be normally interactions with
smart contracts using you know yeah like
smart contracts interfaces suddenly they
become embedded in the very fabric of
the chain making it way more efficient
and secure actually so that's you know
an alternative for people that could
well in go and there are not so much at
easier using solidity they can actually
use that cool language that go is and so
we decided to use them and you know we
thought about our architecture don't
worry anyway it's unreadable we won't go
through all the boxes on that on that
diagram but basically what I would like
to highlight here is that in our
architectural choices we've really have
this had this mentality of no minimum
immutable product so you see like
there's shitloads of business logic if
you were like all these micro services
etc but the interesting thing is that
actually there are very few things but
unchain so here you have a few smart
contracts on the main chains on ethereum
you have many the token contract and
then on the side chain so on luma
you have again the token contract and
then the the karma contract karma is
like a on stackoverflow the reputation
that you can ultimately exchange for
tokens but the interesting thing is that
everything around is not on chain but we
make sure that this is the part you know
that users we know they care about that
once they have earned a reputation in
karma they are sure that you won't get
you know stolen it's fully transparent
and actually you see a lot of arrows and
namely arose in between the side chain
dimension so why is it so that's because
you know in hey and also delegate :
or other use cases what you have is that
users will actually want to transfer
assets so tokens for example you're here
20 or 721 from mainshine to sidechain
then from one sign chain to the other
etc and you gotta have this
interoperability of the chains between
each other so that they are really
really usable so that's why a lot of
arrows and actually we're very lucky in
the case of hay because we don't have to
rely on a very complex constructions to
be able to have this Intel have Intel
about the ability of chains because
probably you know about plasma plasma
cash or plasma prime or all these you
know very advanced research projects
that have the purpose of moving assets
from the main chain to the side chain
and that back to the main chain and it's
all very complex because you gotta make
sure that when a user actually trusts
the side chain honor to move an asset
from the mansion to the side chain it
won't disappear in the side chain making
it unusable on the main chain so there's
really a risk for users when the you
know transfer assets to a side chain
that they lose their assets so that's
why a plasma cash has been plasma has
been built and it's actually a fairly
intricate intellectually but we're very
lucky actually because here we rely on
our like a very stripped down version of
plasma where actually we only need to
care about users transferring assets
from the side chain to the main chain so
that is users will actually gain
reputation karma tokens on the side
chain and we basically you know offered
offer these tokens offer these assets to
them thanks to their activity and
contributions and then what I need to do
is actually be able to redeem these
assets on the main chain so they need to
bring them back but it's not like that
they need to go from the mansion to the
side chain then back to the main chain
so only assets created here and then
transferred there so let's take a little
look at how this works it's called the
transfer gateway pattern something that
luma has been pushing forward and open
sourcing so we're doing a greater great
work on this so how does it work
basically let's say that
this user Elise has earned the karma and
tokens on the on the side chain and then
she wants to actually redeem them so
that she can trade them you know on any
exchange or with friends on the main
chain when they have really monetary
value so what Elise will do is actually
on the side change will burn her tokens
you know and actually Heather proved
that no she she locked or burned these
tokens submit them submit disprove to
the validators so the the miners of the
side chain and the validators will
verify the claim that the tokens are a
frozen and emit a withdrawal message
that is signed by them by one of the
very daters give it to Alice and then
Elise with this sign message will
actually had to the main chain and
provide this sign message from the
validators to the transfer gateway the
transfer gateway will be able to you
know verify that it was signed indeed by
one of the addresses of the validator
and if only this is true then actually
the transfer gateway will release the
equivalent amount of tokens on the main
chain account of of Elise and so what we
have is basically an exchange of sign
messages from one chain to the other and
that is kind of the magic that makes
this this transfer possible so thanks a
lot for your attention I hope you join
the conversation and a hideout network
the project is in beta version on the
chrome Chrome Web Store for now so
hopefully see you there thank you
we have time for a few questions hello
so first of all I'm very impressed by
your approach to scalability I think
that this is how every decentralized
application should be built Thanks
also props to using Klum and my question
is so karma has a value right and have
you thought about how do you ensure that
a user cannot Scipio attack the actual
network and just like Orange Caramel
using cobot or something so that's a
very good question actually because I
did not mention explicitly that on the
loom sidechain you don't need gas
actually to perform transactions so you
can do it you know dozens of
transactions per second but of course
gas is there for a purpose is to reward
miners that's one also to prevent severe
attack so really people spamming the
network and how is this prevented it's
actually in the very fabric of you know
what loom is building they have this
built in reputation system where you
need to kind of you know warm up you
address to begin being able to send a
lot of transactions so you have this
built-in kind of reputation system that
ultimately allows to to block and and
ban people that are spamming spamming
the team and then next to that actually
we have a kind of Oracle in place that
makes it that makes sure actually that
people cannot reward each other with
Karma etc you know on the high smart
contracts if they have not previously
registered as you know users of the
network so it's not like anyone can can
begin spamming a network like mad they
have to be registered but it's an
ongoing field of research I know like
Lumis are spending a lot of time
actually having all this reputation
system in place to avoid spanning
yeah there was this question that there
in the back about using you know like
identity providers on chain a different
leads on the roadmap so I'm not very
familiar with loom but you said that you
standard Minton delegated proof of stake
mm-hmm so this is kind of it's a
permissionless network if I understand
correctly yeah how do you how the
contract on the main chain is going to
verify the signature of a permissionless
network because if you need to know the
validator somebody daters can be added
all the time then that that contract can
not store them yeah so the question is
about how do we automate like the
ability to transfer assets from the side
chain to dimension comes down to the
transfer gateway so this recipient under
main chain being able to validate that
the transfer transaction is well signed
by a visitor so how do you actually deal
with the governance of making sure that
like this validators are legit and are
reflected and actually there it's
actually like how to say the way that
it's working now is a first free loom
has been running a hundred validators
fully internally okay only these ones
were like validating so no issue I know
what they are doing is actually you know
onboarding every month actually new
validators and all these validators all
these nodes actually belong to companies
using you know using a loom and their
technology as yep and so basically
supporting the technology by becoming a
validator so it's not like anyone can
can enter the the validator network and
this validators because it's important
to mention actually are being rewarded
with with tokens etc and the the
monetary value ultimately comes from the
developers of application so high for
example renting is network so it's like
you know blockchain is a service fee
thanks for the talk I have a question
you say it
so basically users get reputation and
then they want to exchange this
reputation for tokens we haven't really
said it but why people will buy those
tokens yeah so that's in the economic
model if you wish ultimately ultimately
has a company right we gotta make a
living so the idea is to monetize the
the attention of the users but in a very
explicit way so fighting actually ads on
the network and these ads a high value
because they are hyper contextual you
know to URL to the URL and basically
advertisers to benefit from ads they pay
with the token so it's an utility token
and that makes you know the velocity of
the market where they will buy ads from
the users and so users will have
incentives to contribute content so that
can sell back these tokens good thank
you
[Applause]
[Music]
all right so gonna put the mic it's
already on
had the same Goldman it seems that you
you don't know water here