yeah so today I'm going to be talking
about how at Sault we moved from an
agent based solution to being able to
use salt without installing an agent so
yeah my name is Megan will hi I'm known
as shell on the interwebs bonus points -
ever understands what shell is and I'm
currently a software engineer at
saltstack but I am working mostly on
getting releases out right now so that's
me so what is salt for anybody that
doesn't know what salt is I think it's
important to understand what salt is
before we go in and talking about
saltless estate which is the agentless
solution so salt is a lot of things but
I would describe it as being able to do
things such as config management remote
execution automation and orchestration
and it's very event-driven so talking
about house salt is currently set up
with the agent solution it is a servant
agent communication model so we refer to
the servant as the server as the salt
master and we refer to the agent as the
salt minion and the way that you would
set this up is you would install the
master and then you would install the
minion and there are a couple of network
services that provide the transport
layer within salt and they are we refer
to them as the publisher and the request
server and these are using a 0qs library
and the publisher essentially is sending
out all the commands from the master to
the minions and the minions then
determined from there whether they
should actually run the command and then
we have the request server and this is
where we get a lot of the bi-directional
communication between the master and the
minion so when talking about converting
over to an agentless solution obviously
SSH is a unidirectional so we had to be
careful in terms of how we architected
that so that we could use the power of
salt but also use SSH so I'm just going
to show you a quick command within salt
that you can run
just kind of like our version of hello
world it's just salt which is the name
of the CLI tool that your news targeting
whatever many and you want to target and
then to stop peeing is just what refer
to as an execution module execution
modules are not meant to be idempotent
they're more meant to be run as one-off
commands and so yeah it would go through
that job flow as I mentioned before it
would the master would publish that
command at the minion the minion would
then run it and then return it through
the request server so as you can see
through the CLI maybe you can't see that
super well but essentially all it does
is it runs tests stop peeing on the
minion and then returns true if it's
able to communicate with the minion okay
another important thing when talking
about how we architected solid SSH is
you need to understand the difference
between salt and salt call so salt as we
show here tests are you know we're we're
targeting all minions with the asher's
there and test stop ping that is the CLI
tool you use on the master and salt call
gives you the same power but on the
minion and specifically here you can use
either salt call or salt call - local -
local will not try to communicate back
to the master it will keep all
communications within the minions and we
use this with insult SSH because that is
how we create that unidirectional
traffic so that it can all just run on
the minion all right so now that we
understand a little bit about what salt
is let's talk about how we're able to
convert the salts and being able to use
SSH as well so first of all why what why
do we provide a an avenue for people to
run salt obviously with SSH it is a bit
slower but there's a lot of positives to
it as well
it gives our users a lot of variety they
can use both the agent and the agent
list option you don't have to choose one
or the other in fact I know a lot of
people have used salt ssh to bootstrap
their minions
as well so a lot of people use both of
those obviously you don't have to
install an agent and it's pretty simple
to set up and get running so how do you
get it up and running there's a couple
things there's Python needs to be on the
targeting system unless you're using the
- our argument and that just runs a raw
SSH command so you don't get the power
of salt but you need to also install
salt as a sage and then you need to set
up a roster file and this is an example
of what a roster file is just one of our
default what we refer to as a flat
roster file and as you can see it's it's
pretty simple web one is just an
arbitrary name obviously you want to
name it this is something useful then
the host is either the IP address or the
DNS of the host name user password to be
able to you know properly authenticate
to that host and just then make this
example we're using sudo which just you
know the user needs sudo privileges
obviously there's more options that you
can add within the roster but that's
just a simple example that you can get
up and quickly get running there are
other rosters available one great thing
about salt is it's very pluggable in a
lot of aspects including the rosters so
you can actually write your own roster
but what's available now is it can work
with ansible the cache cache is a the
master cache so if you've already got
minions you're targeting with your
master you can use those that are in the
cache already cloud which is our salt
cloud offering interacts with AWS if you
create a VM in the cloud you can then
use salt as a sage directly to interact
with that closer shell flat is the
default range scan that's where you can
just scan and define a network range and
also you can use your SSH config but
yeah like I said you can also create
your own
ok so let's show this same example that
we showed with the salt CLI tool the
only thing that's different is you now
have to use this
sssh CLI command we target what we want
to target whichever minion that is and
we run just the simple example test
stopping and as you would expect we get
the same thing we get the response of
true so what is going on in the
background obviously you can see that
we're getting the same result but a lot
of different things are happening to
make this possible
so we're just using SSH as the transport
layer so what we're first going to do
and I've provided where in the code this
is that's just more for the curious
minds but we're going to set up who what
our target and our roster is we're gonna
initialize that in our SSH class and
then we're going to generate what we
refer to as the thin so at this point
what it's going to be is we're going to
determine what are all the dependencies
that we're going to need in this thing
to be able to run this on the minion and
it's also going to add the salt call
binary to the fin and then it's going to
zip that up and then we're going to
generate a new process and we just do
that using the multi process library and
then in that new process we're going to
generate we're gonna generate the the
file that does a lot of the logic within
salts SH and it's ss8 to underscore pi
shin and what we'll do is we'd have to
take all the ops like where's the
directory what r where's the salt call
binary all that st. all those things
that you need to run the command and
we're going to add that to that module
and then that module when it's run it's
going to determine if it even needs to
copy over that tar so we use it like a
checksum and a versioning and if any of
those have changed then we would BRE
copy over the tar but if we don't need
to copy that obviously the consecutive
commands will be faster so obviously
that's a great part of salt a sage and
how we've tried to make it at least I'm
a bit faster even though we're going
over SSH
so yeah once we've got the the tar
copied over we
gonna run that that shim file that shim
file actually runs the salt as the salt
call command so if we dive into the code
a bit we can kind of see what's going on
here like we discussed in that that uh
that flowcharts so we can see here we're
initializing the targets and the the
roster and then there's a lot more
things that are going on here but this
is just the key point and then we're
going to generate that thin if we then
look at this code we can see that it's
adding the salt call binary to that thin
it's adding what we refer to as talks
what that commandment does essentially
is just go in and determine what are all
of the library or modules that we need
to include and also this extra mods a
user can define additional modules that
they want to add to that we also add a
version of the salt code a Python
version and then we're gonna use either
G's it for zip and we're gonna tar that
up so then as I discuss we spin up a new
process and this is just kind of showing
what we do there we just using the multi
process processing library and we're
just queuing all of that up and then a
lot of the initiation of the shim starts
here it creates that command string it's
trying to determine what this what is
going to be run in that shim command and
adds all the arguments that we would
need to it and then it's going to run
that shim command and that shim command
for example if the thin is not already
copied over it will determine that and
return deploy or if the check sum is
different or things like that and then
we see that deploy was returned and we
rerun that that command and then it
would copy it over and run the shim
command just does a couple of things it
determines you can actually specify
whether you need a TTY or not when using
saw SSH and the roster config if it
needs a TTY it just runs our virtual
terminal within the salt Cole salt code
if you're not using or if you are using
a TTY
sorry if not and then if you are using a
TTY it needs to actually copy over that
shim because you need to use that TTY
and it runs it from there okay so this
is all the magic that's going on is in
that shim file we're going to determine
where the thin path would be that we're
going to do a bunch of checks there's
more checks than I have shown here but
we do check the checks on the version
and all those things and then obviously
you can see if it's different we're
gonna say we need a deployment and then
we're gonna untie that that noose in and
then as you can see here we've got this
salt call command and that is the actual
command that we're going to be running
alongside that test stop ping that we
pass to it and then we just use the sub
process module to run that so all of
that discussed is just talking and
referring to salts remote execution
capabilities obviously there's a lot
more you can do with insult so one of
the really other popular aspects of salt
is the state system and this is where we
get a lot of our idempotent behavior so
we refer to these SLS files is where you
would define everything that you would
want your machine to have to be in that
certain state and this is just a simple
example this one's using yam only there
are multiple other renders that you can
use within salt but yeah Mille is one of
the defaults and this is a pretty simple
example we're just managing a file and
we want to state or we want to put it
worked into that file so as you can see
we run it with salt as the sage we run
the state s list which is where I go to
run that s LS file and it adds that new
file and shows that a new change has
occurred now if you were to run this
again as shown here because it's item
potent behavior it doesn't try to change
any
thing and it just says it's in the
correct state so we have the execution
modules but we now have the state system
and the state system requires a little
bit more because we have those SLS files
so we need to have some sort of
deterministic behavior to figure out
what files we also need to include and
copy over to be able to run the state
command and what happens is it's the
same as the execution module except for
when it comes to that command block
command function we we run this one run
W funks and it's essentially stands for
wrapper functions we have a bunch of or
a couple of wrapper modules within
saltless SH and they're all displayed
right there and one of the things that
makes it a bit tricky with using
saltless SH is because we've had to
create these wrapper modules and you'll
see what we've done differently in the
state by example it gets a little bit
hard to manage both of those files
because with insults code we have a
state dot hi and salt as a sage we have
a salt state pice so sometimes it
becomes a little bit difficult to manage
both of those files and make sure if the
feature is added to one that we have to
add it to others so that is one problem
that we've run into with this current
setup so this function will set up all
the pillar and grains and within salt
pillar and grains is just a lot of data
pillar being usually people use that for
more of the sensitive information and
it's stored on the master and grains
being information about the minions
stored on the minion and any other ops
that we need to be able to add to run
these state files then we call all of
those wrapper functions and in this
example we're specifically be getting
called the state wrapper function so as
you can see that we're doing here is
we're grabbing all the data that we're
going to need for the call we're
initializing the function wrapper and
then we eventually we're just going to
run it and return the JSON
of the return and this is how we're
doing it in the state not pipe files so
in a normal SLS file we do not have all
these extra steps because what these
extra steps are doing for salt as the
sage is as you can see we're preparing
the tar so within the tar we determine
what SLS files need to be added one of
the things that is a bit tricky is when
people use includes
in their file you actually have to
specify those separately in a
configuration so that is one thing I
think could be improved upon as well but
yeah so that prep Transtar that's going
to do all that magic there and then
we're going to sum up that you can get
it half and then we're going to do the
same thing we did before initially it's
a single class send over that tar and
then we'll run that command block again
and run essentially that same logic so
now that we've shown you what's going on
underneath you'll probably not remember
all of that code so what are some of the
key architectural decisions to summarize
all that one thing that's important to
know is salt was not modified to add
salt as a sage salt SSH was added on top
of it and that's where you can see
things like the wrapper functions and
things like that where we didn't want to
edit salt we use the tarball or retard
everything up on the master we
determined what needs to be included on
that and then we send it over and run it
on the minion as as shown before we use
that salt call so salt call - local
that's what provides us with the
unidirectional communication and we
won't need to call out back to the
master while the minion is running it's
able to run everything it needs right
there has all the information it needs
and then we use these wrapper functions
where it's we're trying to provide the
same capabilities that salt has but add
it to salt as the sea
so what were some of the challenges when
doing this I've mentioned a lot of them
already
obviously we lose some of the
bi-directional where we you know with
SSH we only have unidirectional so that
was a challenge the wrapper challenges
are functions as I spoke before is a bit
difficult in terms of managing the code
and a lot of times when we see bugs with
insults h's because we haven't we don't
have all the correct ops that we need an
ops is just a lot of the configs that we
would need to run assault SSH command so
that is one of the challenges that I
think we could do a bit better on and
kind of make sure we have everything we
need to be able to run within salt and
salt as a sage so there is more parity
between the two okay so what are our
plans for the future
we actually are initially we're
initially talking right now we we don't
have any set plans but we do want to
react context all as a sage and fix some
of these issues that we have presented
some of the ideas that we've been
thinking on is trying to remove that
Python dependency and how you do that
you know we have I've had some ideas of
just including the minimal Python
executable within the tarball another
reason I think this will be beneficial
is eventually Python 2 is going to go
away and obviously users are still going
to be using machines that have Python 2
on it so if we removed the Python
dependency and we include it in there
that won't be an issue
if we do go python 3 we can use some of
the capabilities of async i/o and
hopefully we can resolve some of the
issues that we stated such as the
wrapper functions and so forth
all right does anybody have questions
yeah I don't know how to turn the light
on now that you can see me does anybody
have any questions yeah yeah essentially
you don't have that agent that is the
the benefit that I can see over-salt
it's it is slower because you know you
know obviously using SSH but that is the
benefit you don't have to install the
agent huh sorry okay go ahead you can go
again I haven't personally done though
do you have you done I know you've done
a lot of work with that have you done
any performance testing between the two
okay
[Music]
there's just the salt call and then yeah
although their salt dependencies you
need the system doesn't have salt salt
on it that's what it does it copies over
whatever salt the binary said I would
need and all the modules within it yeah
this is simply you know sensibilities
okay I don't know I don't know Bellinis
here the connection after that it could
be some boundaries mmm execute okay
windows we do have a window solution it
is enterprise only though yeah yep uses
winterim yep
I should probably repeat the question -
it's been a long day
having as salt as H having the same
functionality as ansible
unless you can explain to me how I can
talk to an let's say a dump device which
I can do that with ansible which is much
much like using expect so I'm interested
in functionality of I'm currently also
ansible user but I missed interested in
finality in talking to let's say dump
devices which have nothing on it where I
need something like they expect which I
can do with the answer but I don't know
how to do it with salt Oh like network
switches things like that oh yeah so we
we have what's called salt proxy and
that's how we that's our solution for
not even having to have Python we
actually have a solution without salt
salt this is H and it's salt proxy I I
don't know what's going on underneath
but a lot of our network modules and all
of that use heavily used salt proxy so
you'd want to look at that yeah I don't
use salt so maybe the question is not
exactly appropriate but I was thinking
about the where do you store the
configuration about the machines when
you don't have a model like minions and
servers where do you store the your
assets the information about the machine
you will connect to they are they are
described on on client let me say if you
use a password or a certificate or which
is the user you use to connect to the
host do you have a different yama or
Gershon files one for each client which
uses ssssh I think what you're asking is
where's the information stored about the
minion yes because it just to complete
the question because I was thinking
about when you have a server the
information about the host you're
managing with salt is in a way
centralized on the server and you use
this kind of approach those information
are spread over the clients okay so I
think what you're asking is and what
you're getting at is we have a concept
of what we call pillar and grains and
pillar is what you would specify on the
master and a lot of people use these for
like passwords and yeah it is just like
a llamó file you can use whatever render
the grains is initialized on normally in
the salt master salt minion it's it's
initialized on the minion and it
automatically determines all that
information like operating system
hostname things like that so it's
automatically determining that and
that's what grains are you also have a
concept of the salt mine and the salt
mine will give you the ability to query
all these minions and cache that
information on the master this is the
pattern where you have the minions on
your on your loops for example for
example yes ok so where you're
specifying where your what your hosts
are and what yeah it's just the roster
is what you would use because I was
thinking about the adoption of this kind
of pattern when you add for example your
operation Department they are 10 20
single clients how do you are do ensure
that the configuration the gap is up to
date and and so on like the ansible
inventory you
yes okay yeah okay
and yet you need to distribute and sync
this information distributed see the
roster file I mean it's just a flat file
or you can use a different sort of
roster inquiry that information
differently but by default it's just the
flat file yes okay it could be can it be
remote - centralized or just a flat file
yeah it's just a black file by default
but like I was showing you the other
rosters like he mentioned you can use
and target ansible and you can do things
like scan the network and things like
that or you can create your own roster
if you want to query that information
for something else like a database or
something like that you can create your
own module and do that as well okay
sorry and hopefully I answered that well
enough ansible does what yes
general information about the host how's
this distributed so ipv4 ipv6
informations interface intimate
informations like how do you does it use
ipv4 know the host information about
this this variables all day yes facts
about the host yes I would be great so
you could just query the minion and use
that and you can run grains DAW items
and that would grab all the information
about all the menus you'd need or like I
was referring to we have this idea of
the salt mine and it can kind of do the
same thing you can clarify what
information you want and it would catch
it on the master and that does work with
salt a cessation as well yeah
so from what I understand now we would
have two different commands you want to
invoke depending on what kind of setup
you have or what kind of mean you're
targeting
is there any plans to kind of unify them
so that you would define in your roster
I guess I don't know enough about but if
you define in roster okay use classic
agent base management with this minion
and be decider minion use salt a sage so
I know in our last release or it's
coming up in this next release one of
our users added the functionality so
that you can actually use the salt CLI
and target both SSH and minions and the
same is that was that your question
yeah so that is actually added just
recently there is some sort of argument
you'd have to use I don't know it off
the top of my head any other questions
I believe yeah so I'm I'm almost
positive you can because I didn't
mention this but before it actually
submits that command to the minion it
actually is initializing a connection
with the master event bus and then when
it gets that return it actually returns
that to the master event bus so you
could react off of that event yeah
Thanks thank you