thanks everybody for coming to this
session which is a panel about about how
should lawyers behave and about lawyer
ethics in several different
jurisdictions so I think maybe if we can
just go down the line and have everybody
introduce themselves say where you're
from and maybe indicate if there's a
body of rules that govern you know
lawyer like a lawyer lawyer ethics or
lawyer behavior where where you are
situated or where you're qualified to
practice yes hi
my name is Miriam I'm a lawyer in
Germany based in Hamburg is what that
for me oh I work with bird and bird
which some of you might know we're
focused on IP and IT law and especially
of course after licensing and where we
practice there is a body of law covering
ethics but I don't think most of it
applies here it's more about well what
kind of advertisement can you do
how can you advertise and how much money
can you charge my name is Justin colony
no I'm a lawyer in the United States
actually barred in New York and
Massachusetts I currently work for
Microsoft as an in-house counsel and
there is a body of rules in the United
States
it's a state-by-state body of rules but
there's a kind of model rules that have
been adopted by most states including
both Massachusetts and New York that
govern how lawyers should operate hi I'm
Amanda Brock I'm Lori qualified in
Scotland and England and Wales I set up
the legal team at canonical and spent
five years there not actually working as
a lawyer at the moment I work with oin
and on a new software project I'm Pamela
Chester I'm also a United States lawyer
in North Carolina as Justin mentioned
you know in the 50 states have 50
different sets of ethical rules they all
tend to be similar I will say that and I
am admitted to practice in five
different states and in theory I'm
supposed to comply with all of the laws
all of the rules of all of those states
and in practice some of them are
directly contradictory so I so I choose
to follow the rules in North Carolina
which is where I where my office is and
where my where it physically reside but
it gets tricky sometimes so I we
originally got the idea for this panel
because the laws so I'm also a lawyer
but I'm not generally wearing why we
call hat very often these days and I'm
admitted in the state of New York and I
we want to do this panel because we
found that the ways that lawyers
practice really vary from country to
country and the ways in which ethical
issues come up and the practice of law
is very interesting and I think a bit
unusual in free and open-source software
so I think maybe to start where to start
maybe we should talk about what would
happen under ethical rules where you're
qualified if for example some person
some developers say corners you in a
hallway at FOSDEM and starts to tell you
oh my gosh I just had the most amazing
thing and they start to talk to you and
all of a sudden you realize they may be
talking to you because they need legal
advice so and then we can start okay
yeah so I haven't practiced the law firm
very much I've mostly worked in
companies so I would be happy to talk to
them and as soon as they got to the
stage of being clear that they needed
legal advice I might give them an
opinion but I would probably have to
tell them that I can't advise them
because I work for particular companies
who employ me and then I would pass them
on to one of the the lawyers in a law
firm
well and I will say that just a few
weeks ago I attended a three hour
session a three hour ethics training
where we have mandatory requirements
every year that we do ethics training
three hours spent on this very topic
where it was all the scenarios of like
you're at a party and you've been
drinking and someone comes up and it's
always so-and-so the problem in the
United States there is there are two
issues and Justin well Justin will know
this better than I do because he does
training is is have I have I established
an attorney-client relationship and we
have to you know there's I have to worry
about that oh my god they are they're
going to think that I'm their attorney
because they started talking to me so I
want to use them of that what happens if
you're their attorney well why is that
significant because that because then
well there's also a duty of
confidentiality even if I'm not their
attorney we there still may be a duty of
confidentiality and the information that
they've told me raise your hand if
you're scratching your head about what
the duty of confidentiality might be
okay so does somebody else on the panel
want to explain the duty of
confidentiality so so yeah at least in
the United States and probably in many
other jurisdictions when you when you
talk to a lawyer and give them
information - for the purpose of
receiving advice about your rights and
obligations under the law then there's a
duty of confidentiality
the lawyer needs to keep that
confidential and so if someone if you're
a lawyer and someone comes up to you and
starts talking to you and seeking legal
advice that initial communication is
confidential and this can be problematic
for attorneys because it down the road
that could lead to you know a conflict
of interest so even though there hasn't
been an attorney-client relationship
that's you know necessarily been formed
right then you still need to keep the
information confidential and you also
have a duty to not use that information
should you have some other party come
along that represent you paying you to
represent them you need to think about
well did the information that I have is
that gonna prejudice the person who came
to me for legal advice in the first
place
wait a minute wait a minute so you're
saying that if somebody just corners you
in the hallway and says without you
saying any
here's my problem they're never better
than that you have to keep that
confidential yes and I try probably try
to cut them off pretty early in that
lawyers are pretty well known for
getting a word in edgewise so I would
jump in at the right time hopefully is
that the same in Germany what did I
would stop that you it what would you
have to keep that confidential with
somebody get with somebody without any
agreement that you would be their lawyer
well without any agreement being a
lawyer you would be well representing
them but I have to admit it in all the
years it has never happened that it got
to a point where I thought well this is
really the time where I would say well
now we actually need to sit down and put
this in writing usually at conferences
maybe the conference's that I go to or
maybe the people I talk to they are
pretty aware of that as well and they
would not give you so confidential
information in just a talk in the
hallway where they calling you we've had
a very different experiences probably
yes and so what about if people email
you is it the same thing a cold email
where somebody writes you about their
problem and says I'm you know I'm
seeking I have this problem and even
what if they say I'm seeking legal
counsel for it and then what if they
don't say that and they just and I don't
mean to put you on the spot because we
can move it to it we can move it to the
UK okay well if I get an email like that
to be honest I would be a prompt about
the fact that you know that probably
requires legal advice and if they
actually wish to proceed with that not
because you know I'm keen to establish
that but because I think it's in their
best interest to actually tell them you
know this is really something that you
should consider properly and maybe have
someone look through and maybe have
someone asked you a couple of questions
about and then once you get to the point
where you know actually the lawyer also
feels comfortable to make a decision
about that they will answer your
question and you'll get a good response
but that would usually be proactive and
you know from from my end
cuz I'm is there so is there an
obligation or just a good practice it's
well I know what in law last night I
didn't find an obligation on that but so
I would say that probably isn't one and
it's not done but I just think you know
that would be common sense to say this
is where we're getting to a proper like
lawyer-client relationship we need to we
need to put that down and you know make
sure this all goes the right way and so
that you are aware of what's going on
here as well I want to hear what's
happening in the UK so yes it is and
like you we have a huge book of rules
though I doubt anybody knows all of them
inside out and you're going check but I
think there's actually a couple of
things that are relevant when you when I
saw how many hands went up about the
confidentiality piece so quite often
I've seen people react badly to asking
lawyers to sign confidentiality
agreements or non-disclosure agreements
and I've had a hard time from companies
that I've worked and I don't have them
with outside lawyers and the reason we
don't generally put them in places that
we have these confidentiality
obligations is not sort of lawyers being
special or different or arrogant or that
might seem like that it's because we
just don't need them because we've got
these obligations and most firms will
sign them if you want them to but you
don't really need it the other thing I
was going to say is beyond just the
rules you sort of build as a lawyer your
relationships with people particularly
the community on trust as well as on
your strict rules so I would take the
view that if anybody came and told me
something knowing that I was a lawyer
and a sort of averaged on their meeting
legal advice even although because I
tend to work for a company I would send
them off to a law firm it's not
something that I would feel that was
okay to go and discuss whether my
professional will actually kicked in or
not but but what if but what if Amanda
what if the the person gave you
information that might be of relevance
to say the software freedom Conservancy
and you and I were best friends so if
you're under are you under an obligation
to keep that information confidential or
could you share it with me
I think and this is a lawyer's Kampai
probably not
but it would depend on what it was that
was shared and whether they were
actually clearly seeking legal advice
and giving you confidential information
if the information was in the public
domain already that would be a slightly
different thing but I would probably
verge on the edge of caution but it
depends so what about in the u.s. well I
was just going to say what I one of the
things I learned at this ethics training
which I was not aware of was even if the
information is public if you learned it
within the bounds of your confidential
relationship you cannot talk about it
so I learn information from a client
it's then publicly announced I still
can't talk about anything that I learned
in that confidential relationship so
certainly I think all of us would
probably err on the side of caution is
that we wouldn't I just you know if it's
if it's within the balance of
confidentiality as if it and if it was
at a party and someone thought that it
was you know they gave me information
that clearly was confidential so um I
don't think I'm to further okay but I I
don't think that I'm sidetracking too
much but when you have that conversation
with someone who's appointed as your
lawyer there's something called
privilege that attaches to that where
you get a right for that conversation
not to be disclosable there'll be rules
in every different place about what
exactly that means but to the extent
that the advice isn't commercial and
it's about a legal issue you're probably
going to have this protection around the
relationship and the conversation you
have when you share that with other
people you can lose your privilege so if
a lawyer is emailed you some advice and
you just distribute that generally you
that can make that privilege go away
because you've shared it and disclosed
it I think it's a sort of very simple
way of explaining it so it's really
important to understand when you're
interacting with a lawyer not just that
they or you
IATI but that when you get that advice
it needs to be sort of looked after and
protected by you so that it's not
disclosable if you end up in litigation
or some fight later and when you're
working with someone like me who is
in-house whether or not I'm allowed that
legal privilege in a conversation with
someone in my company at least in Europe
various country by country there's
different views in the UK and Europe and
sometimes it depends so an antitrust it
can be different but I think that whole
relationship between you taking and
paying for your legal advice or getting
a pro bono whatever it is and how you
manage that important and sometimes what
you'll see is that a lawyer in the law
firm will be copied on everything all
the time to try and keep the privilege
and whether that works or not remains to
be seen so you should be careful yeah
that's not the the potted plant approach
where it's just like well the lawyers
copied so everything's privileged that
doesn't that doesn't always work out it
is important to keep your plumage it is
yours and you can waive it by by
preserving the advice widely I mean
that's actually a particular problem in
in this space where so much transparency
is required to build trust in community
you know legal this lawyering can be
you know difficult because it's hard to
do in a privileged setting when for
example it elicits made public or if the
list is not restricted to people who
really need to know the answers to those
particular questions and so that's
that's something that you know
project-by-project you know i recommend
people think about as you're setting up
or if there's ever a legal issue think
about you know how to set it up so that
the advice you're getting but this is
getting towards this gets to how people
should how clients should behave or how
non lawyers should behave when they are
talking to lawyers I want to know I want
to know how lawyers should behave and I
want to know what happens if you don't
behave what happens if you share
information you're not supposed to does
anybody want to comment on that what
happens if you violate any of these
ethical rules well there's a chance you
lose your livelihood and license so one
of the reasons why lawyers are so so
careful about lose your license you know
there goes a lot of time effort in
developing your livelihood I just wanted
to comment so one of the things I wanted
to sort of bring home bring this back to
reality as a lot of times as a lawyer I
may be asked to participate say for
example in drafting a legal document but
doing it in a forum that I don't know I
don't know who can has access to it or
how how controlled the forum is or you
know if it's a document that's being
maintained on github
can't you just submit a commit and and
we're not being jerks if we don't want
to do it that way if instead we insist
on sending you an email and we insist on
sending you you know what we're document
with the changes mark it's because of
this issue of privileges we don't have
the we know it's not within our
authority to waive privilege and so we
have to be very very attentive and
careful to who can see the the legal
advice that we are providing all right
so so another hypothetical Amanda was
before talking about and this isn't
necessarily for Amanda but amanda was
talking before about being an in-house
lawyer working at a company do you have
anybody on this panel ever been in a
situation of seen a situation where you
were talking to an employee of a client
or of a company that you're a lawyer on
staff or that your external two and kind
of wondered what position like what
their what capacity they were talking to
you so maybe there's someone who works
at a company who is also on the board of
a foundation maybe there's a person
talking to you who's on a governance
committee or is a developer with commit
acts that you know is a maintainer have
you ever encountered that do you have
any do any ethical rules come up with
that so you as an employed lawyer you
have to act in the best interest of the
company that employs you and that's not
necessarily the best interests of
individuals within that company even
when they're acting within their own
Paras so it does sometimes cause a
conflict where you are going to say no
or push back on an individual's behavior
because it's not best for the company
but also there's a really difficult line
actually between helping people I when
they come and ask you about something
and you know and being useful and
participating and then not doing what
you're actually meant to do so many
times I've said to colleagues you know I
can't advise you and whether it's about
buying a house or getting divorced or
all sorts of things that people want to
talk to lawyers about I will happily if
it's someone who actually is a friend
have a chat and listen to them talk
about what their lawyer has told them or
find lawyers for them or you know do
whatever I can to help but you really
have to be
quite careful that people can't rely on
it and it can be pretty awful when a
person is in conflict with the
organization that you're employed by
particularly Karen mentioned before
friends people you like but your duty as
a solicitor in my case there is an
attorney is paramount to that and
sometimes you you can't do what you
think you would like to do as a friend
for someone it's particularly difficult
when you're seeing people exiting
companies sometimes the company will be
kind and not make the in-house lawyer
deal with it you can pass that out to
somebody externally and often that's for
the best so this would not be something
that you know I'm personally caught up
in but in Germany there's rules around
who can actually provide legal advice
like properly look at an individual case
and say this is you know how this should
be treated under whatever law applies
but there's so there's lawyers who can
do that and there's just you know
everyone else who can generally talk
about a topic but you can't give legal
advice if you're not admitted to
whatever bar you want to be admitted to
so for example if you look at the free
software foundation's licensing list
you'll often find that they just give
general answers you know telling you
what generally applies but they would
not give you specific advice about your
specific scenario or the same with like
business associations where they say
well this is the general setting or we
think whatever copyleft means this and
this and that in general but they would
not tell you if whatever case you're
looking at is actually qualifying as
this or that they would just give you a
general idea if you then want to have a
specific answer to whatever question you
have you would actually need to go see a
lawyer as in someone who's admitted and
you know allowed to call themselves a
lawyer and I can imagine that in a
situation like that you will often come
into kind of a well kind of you just get
caught up right where someone approaches
you knowing your lawyer and you could
probably give them a specific advice but
at the same time they are not
approaching you as a lawyer right there
and then so of course um you're still
bound by all these rules and can just
say well in generally this is how it
works and you know if you need something
more than we actually need to change the
setting here when I was in private
practice we had things related to you
know intercompany zhh would hire our
firm to do investigations into you know
something that had happened maybe they
were out of compliance of the law or
whatever and so when you're those types
of investigations where you know
something's gone wrong for a company and
there's someone in the company who's
responsible for that that immediately
puts a wedge between the interests of
the company and the employee and when
you sit down to have a conversation with
the employee you need to tell them you
have a right to counsel I am a lawyer
I am the company's lawyer I am NOT your
lawyer and making that very clear to
them is extremely important under the
ethical rules because otherwise they
might have a misimpression that what
they're telling you is privileged and
when really it's not and you're gonna
tell the company and the company holds
the privilege over you and they could
disclose what the employee is telling
you now Justin what if you're talking to
someone and you happen to know that
they're they're an employee of the
company that you're advising but they
also happen to be on the board of an
organization and that organization has a
lawyer does that change anything for you
so so so I think your hypothetical is
getting at getting it the rules are
represented parties yes exactly the
rules about representative parties so if
you're communicating with somebody it
could be the developer could be you know
a board member of a company and you know
that person is represented by counsel
and your corresponding about legal
matters you shouldn't be corresponding
with them you should be corresponding
with the person the lawyer who's
representing which is so unusual for
this field because it's otherwise
basically unheard of that you could be a
lawyer in a company and have a
represented person who is
also an employee of the org it's it's
wacky is it the same in the UK and
Germany it is the same in the UK and
it's surprising how many lawyers ignore
it so if you as a lawyer know that
there's representation for another legal
entity whether it's a foundation or a
company or whatever it is you were not
meant to deal directly with the
individual so I've tended to get around
that by copying people in and just being
inclusive and seeming gentle about it as
opposed to saying I'm not speaking to
you
which doesn't go down very well and I'm
trying to keep my idea there was
something else I was going to mention
about give me a minute not come back on
it I have another time do you want a
10-minute it is the same in Germany so
you can't you know if you're
representing a client you can talk to
the opposing party if you know they are
represented as well of course if they
don't have representation it's a
different thing but you know often times
you will also find it might be in the
best interest of both parties if
actually you talk lawyer to lawyer about
a couple of things so you know generally
speaking if someone tells you you know
please hold back a little bit there
might be a good reason for that as well
the the other thing I was going to add
to that is as a solicitor at least I
don't know about attorneys barristers
are different but you don't have to act
for someone so if someone comes to you
as a lawyer and asks you to do something
you still have your duties of
confidentiality etc but you don't have
to do the work so if you ask me to draft
a commons clause I wouldn't do it
because I would choose oh you would say
no no I have said no even I'd be nine
your lawyer I have been asked to do
something similar a couple of times and
I've said no to it because I don't think
it's appropriate but that's my personal
view not any corporate view and my own
ethics and morals I'm allowed those as
well as being a solicitor I won't ask
you to go down the row and answer that
question but maybe Mark had a question
it's a question related to unrepresented
parties
when one of the parties is represented
as if they're on a board of a non-profit
but if you have an employee who's a
contributor in their individual capacity
to an open-source project that your
company is using and your and you're
advising them about how to interact with
their project as an employee it's just
that's gonna take too long okay how do
you deal with the dealing with that
employee when you want to tell them
something than the company's interests
but they also have their own legal
rights at stake in that project say for
example like there's a project that your
company owns copyrights in there's a
license with some violation on that
project it's action your company's
interest to ignore it for whatever
reason but you're dealing with an
employee who has copyrights in that
project and they might personally care
about that oh good because that was
actually the question I wanted to ask is
the last question so let's move that
microphone back so if I if I parse that
correctly the question is when you're
advising and employment and you're
talking to an employee who has doula is
wearing multiple hats right they're an
employee of your company and they're
there's an outside interest in something
of importance to the company what do you
do I think you know the general advice
here would be be really clear with the
person about what's going on say this is
like we're talking about the company now
if you have other interests in this you
can seek your own legal advice but from
a company perspective that's what we're
talking about and I can't represent you
outside of that and that's the same in
Germany and the same in the UK okay what
if your client this is a really really
fast what if your client you discover is
violating the GPL and they're not going
to do anything about it
what obligations do you have if any any
one your client your client a company
you're the company is in by the company
is in violation you discover it the
company has no intention of coming into
compliance what are your obligations of
any if anyone wants to answer
and I tell the company to get into
compliance and if they say and I think I
think the answer and the answer in the
end they say no they think I have a duty
of confidentiality to my client and I
zip it they are out of compliance I'm
not allowed to talk about it because I
have a duty of confidentiality
that's yeah well I would I would say the
same thing I might add you know if they
are not compliant I would always acting
as an you know external counsel of
course point out the risks right what
could happen if they don't get into
compliance right make that clear but in
the end I can't force them to make a
different decision I might have a
different opinion about it but you know
that's that's still a decision they need
to make as long as they are aware of the
risk and of course like you said you
know there's a confidentiality
obligation which you need to stick to so
I was just about to say something
similar so ultimately we are advisers we
are not enforcers and we're not the
police there are points where your codes
of conduct and rules would say that a
company in law not listening to your
advice has gone too far and you
shouldn't stay and work there so
criminal activity that kind of thing but
on a personal and a moral level if you
are not a tune anymore with the company
you're advising you can move on so I
just want it was doing everything just
to come back around and say to kind of
reiterate that that point you know we're
lawyers we advise we're not hypnotists
we can't strong-arm people like we don't
have guns we can just say like I can't
force anyone to do anything it's just
like here are the rights and
responsibilities here are the
obligations this is what you should do
that's that's what a lawyer does and the
client can decide to ignore the advice
and you guys often want this although
you might not like what I'm about to say
quite a lot of what we do is try to be
creative and find ways of achieving what
it is you want to do without breaking
the law or doing it wrong so it's not
just a black and white telling you what
the law is yeah I mean I also wanted to
reiterate a lot of times that what we do
do is is
persuade as much as possible and so we
try to point out the pitfalls of this
behavior that is wrongful that you're
going to get caught these are the
ramifications of what you get caught
this is going to be much more harmful to
the business
if that happens rather it's much easier
to just comply with the license rather
than ignore it what if you get caught
and and and you know so we try to work
really hard to use their power
persuasion to explain why the lawful
course is always better than the
unlawful course but sometimes you can't
and then sometimes you get to say I told
you so when they get caught but so I
think there was a question in the back
and I this panel is longer than I
thought it was so this is exciting so
think of your tough questions and I want
to just while we wait for the microphone
to go in the back there are lawyers
whose entire job it is to advise other
lawyers on ethical issues this is sticky
it's hard and just like thank you to
these panelists for being willing to
answer it because not all of them are
experts in free and open source software
law they're not ethics experts and so
this is awesome hi so a question on how
lawyers should behave but not on ethics
so do you have rules for example an IT
level that your laptop should be
encrypted or you should not use cloud
services so not provide your replies
into proprietary document formats
can we talk gdpr here no actually I mean
because so yes it's certainly from my
experience law firms have become first
off law firms are targeted because they
have such sensitive information they are
their targets and any law firm who
doesn't understand that is is that a
touch with the world so yes I think that
you have should have a high expectation
of a law firm to have very appropriate
for their size but but good security
practices so in the UK I think we tend
to have practice notes that don't
actually prescribe exactly what you have
to do but sets
standards that you should try and
achieve yeah it's similar in the u.s.
it's not completely so there been some
advisory opinions around confidentiality
and IT that have come out and if I'm if
I'm recalling correctly just you have to
do you have to be what's do it's
reasonable but so that's what lawyers
use when we don't really know what the
right answer is we just say well you
know you just have to act reasonably and
reasonable means you know don't do
stupid stuff so that's so that's
basically what the right the IT policy
we're not supposed well is it reasonable
to just have like a that's a reasonably
necessary that's work okay does that
apply so I think yes and I can say
personally we are obliged to keep of
course all how the information secret
and I always find you know the
encryption that is applied is a pretty
good standard
I personally surprised at what you know
what what we have in place so compared
to compared to at other points I thought
it was pretty good
and a lot of what we're talking about or
have talked about is worrying about
accidentally creating a lawyer-client
relationship but we also loads of rules
about when we take a Cline on having to
do anti money laundering and know your
customer type checks so it can be a bit
of a pain but you have to see someone's
ID and other ways of proving where they
there's an individual where they'll a of
corporate set up details that kind of
thing
oh yeah no we don't we don't have
anything like that and then we can we
can take the sleaziest kind of people
yeah yeah we could take anonymous people
yeah yeah yeah I would well I mean I
don't know any reason not to yeah yeah
no reason not to I I was just confusing
it with whether I would do that
I actually I will I will say I will say
that I I've had this side gig
representing romance novel authors and
and often I don't it takes me a while to
find out what their real name is because
they're running under a pen name so I've
had that happen where I you know later
found out what their real name was yeah
so tangential question on here a
tangential question on consequences u.s.
lawyers cannot talk about a lot of stuff
what if I come to you pay you you know
with our relationship and everything and
you give me advice and I personally
package it as a general advice without
mentioning ever that I spoke to you and
so on and so forth what are the
consequence to me if any this is
something I've come across quite a lot
actually I find it quite interesting so
only lawyers can give legal advice no
something's probably gonna tell me
that's not right but yeah Andrews
shakings head I've obviously got it
wrong already but you can't sell legal
advice unless you meet certain rules so
a number of companies that what you're
asking me
no sorry I understand your question to
be I give you advise you pay me and then
you pass the same advice on to someone
else but you don't want to get paid so
sorry what
he just publishes it so this is this is
what I try to get into before right you
assuming you're not a lawyer you're not
allowed to give legal advice so it would
actually be a breach of this law which
then actually you know what I've never
bothered to look into that because it
doesn't affect me but I could try and
look it up in parallel if you want to oh
we can have a discussion about it you
know after yeah there's one other
there's one other issue which is that
you'd be waiving your right by
disclosing that there's a there's a
possibility that our communications
would be would be become non privileged
from you publicizing the advice that you
got my question is actually a follow-on
to this one you talked quite a bit about
that privileged client communication and
in an open source project that raises
all sorts of problems we're dealing with
gdpr issues in our project and some
community members say our lawyer says
you have to and I say if you can't share
the legal argument we're gonna ignore
you but now I'm hearing that's probably
the bad that's not a good way to
approach to speak to the lawyer so so we
so I need to talk to this specific
lawyer instead of for each of these
representatives instead of then
publishing it to the community for the
community to evaluate as all depends on
what you're doing so if you creating
guidelines or something you can you do
it with the lawyer and they can be
published lots and lots of sites have
guidelines or if the lawyers are all
telling their clients who are then
talking together why not just get those
lawyers together and have them hash it
out if they want or you know get the
lawyers in the room altogether it
there's no that one other thing is there
there can be a tourney client really at
least in the states there is it there
can be an attorney-client relationship
between a lawyer and an unincorporated
group of people let's call them software
developers so you can have a
relationship with an unincorporated
association of people and so you could
have one lawyer if the project wanted to
hire one lawyer
you could have one lawyer and then hire
them and and kind of follow that advice
instead of having 30 lawyers telling you
through their representatives what they
should do a good equation about legal
professional privilege and what do you
do in the case where the lawyer actually
doesn't have a clue without consulting a
specialist so for example it's
incredibly rare for a lawyer to have a
clear idea of the ages of artificial
intelligence or indeed what privacy law
means because actually it's half
computer science what do you think we
should do I've got a feeling we're being
set up here yeah well well where does it
where does the privilege I mean you
don't actually know where you go without
kind of disclosing the problem you're
working on and I get this quite a bit
and so we have a chat with a lawyer
suddenly turns into a very specific chat
about hypothetically if some group had
this very very specific problem
what does computer science say and all
of a sudden I'm thinking so am i I
accidentally on the team do you know I
don't know if I can quite answer what
you're trying to ask me but it's really
interesting because a lot of what you're
doing isn't gonna be subject to legal
privileges only the legal advice there
is so you have all these conversations
around commercial stuff for technology
stuff which aren't privileged anyway but
also a lot of the legal issues that come
up don't need legal fixes they just need
a better understanding of the technology
to fix it so usually you'll be the
answer not us
sure you are
yeah so so just to just to kind of to
follow on to that there can be there you
there can be privilege now now I you
know don't if you should be getting paid
by the lawyers who are seeking a free
technical advice in the bar or whatever
but but if if as a lawyer if I retain a
technical consultant in for a variety of
reasons that can be subject to privilege
if the if that technical consultant is
helping me gather information about that
I need in order to help my client make
or advise my client about legal issues
that can be that can be privileged in
the United States at least I found the
legal advice point interesting and I was
wondering do you consider this movement
in license obligations and publishing
license obligations like explaining what
license what what you should do if you
have software under specific license
published and do you consider this legal
advice or how's the situation there well
it doesn't at least that's my
understanding
it doesn't say specifically for this and
this in this type of software this is
what you need to do but it just
generally lists what the license
obligations are right kind of extracting
it and then making a list from it and
giving different options correct so it's
not it's still just a general statement
and not giving specific advice about a
very specific scenario you would need to
say for this software that in practice
means this and that would be the legal
advice but as long as you're just
generally saying these are the license
obligations under whichever license you
pick you're still on you know it's a
general statement side
I just wanted a Clara I'm a lawyer who's
qualified in in England and Wales has
wanted to sort of clarify that in
England and Wales there's nothing
preventing anyone from giving general
legal advice so it's not something
that's reserved didn't follow up if you
hold yourself out to be a solicitor
you've required to meet certain regular
absolutely no exactly I'm just
clarifying yeah yeah so it's it's not a
good idea to seek legal advice from
somebody who isn't qualified because
first of all you won't attract privilege
you won't have all of the whole sort of
raft of legal compliance that they need
to undergo regulatory compliance etc and
probably most importantly it's very
difficult for people who aren't
qualified lawyers to get any insurance
so the chances are the person you're
dealing with won't have insurance but
nothing that I do requires me to be a
lawyer so the sort of things that you
you know if I'm conducting litigation if
I'm buying and selling houses you know
if I'm ministering oaths all these some
weird things I have to be a lawyer to do
those but I don't do any of that stuff
so the situation is much more relaxed in
England and Wales but I do have a
question for the panel which is which
which means that I sort of do a number
of other things I'm involved erector of
an organisation that provides compliance
advice and also a software company in in
each of your jurisdictions are there any
restrictions that you as a lawyer have
from participating in the management of
other businesses why don't you explain
that for the UK since you asked the
question Andrew if well they aren't the
answer is no basically I'm already doing
it there there are I think specific
situations and maybe just only a bit of
foot so one so there are rules about who
can own a law firm so we can't share
ownership of a law firm with anyone
who's not a lawyer also there are also
rules about taking a share of an essay
startup comes to you and says gee I'm
going to give you 10% rather than power
you give me reduced fee or whatever
and I personally don't do that so I
don't know what the rules are but but it
is it is kind of a tricky situation
because you put yourself and you there's
a high potential for this is why I don't
do it it's a high potential for putting
yourself in a conflict that where as a
lawyer there may be one thing that it
would be advisable for the company to do
but as a shareholder you might want a
different outcome so it's oh so it's
generally you're setting yourself up for
conflict if you do that those are kind
of the two things that come to mind in
the u.s. right our rules are the same
and they make you if you have shares you
sometimes have to sell them blinds so
you just have to give them to a broker
who randomly sells them rather than be
able to pick and choose when you would
do it it's not really worth the hassle
see I would say the same thing the issue
is really with the conflict of interests
because there's rules around that you
can you know represent conflicting
interests and in any case and I think in
a situation like that you just risk
getting in such a conflict you know one
one way or the other I think not that
we're accusing you of doing that at all
no I just want to say it like like that
would be that's fine if when you're if
you if you're you know a shareholder in
a software company you say but I'm not
your lawyer like you could you know as
long as you keep them distinct then I
think that it's fine
I'm just gonna agree with that I
wouldn't do both the lawyers role and I
said of business directors are at the
same time because you need balance and
check it's not right there's another
question we'll get to that in just a
second I wanted to follow up a little
bit and we mentioned we touched on
conflict of interest here how much does
that apply so for example if you do
volunteer work with a foundation for
example and they and then they wind up
having some kind of legal dispute with
with a company can you later represent
that company are there any circumstances
where you could anyone want to answer
that
I know we've had this private yeah it
the answer is it depends but but yeah it
the you you do have duties to a former
client if if the knowledge you have is
material from that prior representations
material to the new the new
representation of the new matter that
can that can cause a conflict but but
but generally you might be able to do
that okay thanks for the session as
usually top-notch sessions here we know
I okay maybe it's possible I I got it
wrong
so it's a follow-up question of the
follow-up question and scenario he is
I got legal advice I need to spread this
information with my community somehow
but as far as I can understand there is
some degree of confidentiality even
client to the side so since I can't give
legal advice advice and I can't spread
it to some degree would you mind to
clarify at this point because it wasn't
clear
so you're receiving the advice though
right I am receiving the advice I wish
to spread the advice since it's a
community wise advice and so you are
telling us there is some confidentiality
client side well for Germany that's not
I mean you're not I'm in Germany buddy
okay yeah you're not bound by
confidentiality about anything relating
to your case so if you want to waive
confidentiality that that's fine
but you know the obligation is on the
lawyer to not talk about the case that
maybe you and I discuss right so that's
the confidentiality obligation what I
think they were saying
and you know I would find that to be
true and true in general if you are
talking about the advice that I gave you
you need to be aware of the fact that
you're waiving confidentiality which
then again might affect what everyone
else needs to keep secret or what you
know could be looked into that doesn't
affect the fact that you can still make
that decision and say I'm going to talk
about whatever I want to talk about from
this you know relationship that we had
just picking up on that I think
privilege is a little bit more than
confidentiality and it also gives you
the right not to have something
disclosed in a litigation process
potentially which is broader than
confidentiality might be and I've seen a
couple of issues with it partly you
sharing it loses that privilege and
later on you might want to have it back
and you can't get it back and the other
thing it's very difficult as a lawyer
you never want to seem like you're
closing people in the community down but
when there is some sort of litigation
saram patterns
whatever is then discussed and these
open news groups can be used and not
always by the right side to help
influence a case so when the litigation
starts is worth at least thinking hard
about what you write down and whether
you would want that to be used in court
maybe against what you actually believe
in yeah I was I wanted to use the Patton
example as a really good one as an
example so so it's the the client it is
the client who may waive the privilege
so there is this privilege that an
attorney cannot be forced in court to
tell anything about what their client
told them and in and but the client can
waive that and the way that this
typically happens in patent litigation
is a company comes to a lawyer and says
we've been accused of infringement we
want an opinion they got a written
opinion that's
no we don't believe you're infringing
and so they take they behave on on that
advice they continue what they're doing
they then get sued so this then becomes
this like really really complicated
dance in the United States about when
you waive the privilege because they can
say if they say well we had an opinion
from our lawyer that says we don't
infringe they have they may have just
waived the privilege then the other side
gets to see that it gets to see that
letter see what was in that letter see
whether it was accurate and so same
thing can happen on a mailing list of a
public mailing list say it's a say it's
an internal mailing list memo a list for
those of you at Red Hat there have been
it worked it read not you know if
someone were on the mailing we're on
memo list and said hey good news the
legal department told us it's okay to go
ahead that maybe MIT may have waived
privilege for the company and then all
of that all of that information comes
out and in in the litigation so that's
that sort of the to just sort of paint a
picture of how this waiver works and
what the why attorneys kind of get
freaked yes it's the clients to waive
but before you waive that you better be
really sure you understand what the
consequences of that waiver might be and
as Amanda said you might want it back
it's something you might you can't get
it back once it's gone it's gone yeah
I'd follow on that just by saying I
agree with with everything you said
about it you you have to really think
about whether or not you want to waive
it but I'll also say there might be a
situation where it doesn't matter if you
waive it or not maybe it's you know kind
of some innocuous advice that it you
know you find it not because you can
talk to your lawyer about hey like you
know what are the consequences how bad
would it be if if I waive the privilege
because I want to share this with with
my community and they Laura might say
well you know it doesn't really seem
like a big deal or you might decide it's
not a big deal and it's it's your
decision to make
oh we have time for one more okay just
want to say thank micro I think I've the
last question sorry I just want to say
thank you very much for this panel I
think we should have more of these
panels it's been a privilege to be here
[Music]
no thinking we're buttering us up thank
you um so I I've really interested I'm
hearing a lot of legalistic arguments to
justify ethical behavior so make sense
your lawyers right
I just wondering where you don't think
these professional your legal
responsibilities in terms of ethical
behaviors go far enough because I mean
in some senses ethics should be a sort
of human universal right and so Oh in
German it's this is utterly fascinating
but like in a sense it doesn't capture
what personal ethics are raising it
things like that I mean for example when
you touched on you don't even just quit
if you don't like what you're being
asked of but can you talk more in that
area because I think that's fascinating
no not you quitting but thank you and
thank you I actually I actually think
that at least the Model Rules in the US
have something that that speaks almost
directly to this which is a lot of
people use legal departments or you know
lawyer just be like hey can I do this
and the lawyers like yeah I don't see
why not really okay great
see you later like like I just want to
make sure that I'm not you know
violating the law but the ethical rules
permit you explicitly permit you to not
only consider what the law is but also
to consider moral political economic and
social obligations when you are making
when you are making a decision and and
that is that something they permit and I
believe it's it's a lawyer's duty to do
that when faced with with difficult
decisions
the problem is sorry the problem with
that is the everybody's personal ethics
are gonna be different right so if
you're leaving it to an arbitrary
decision that you make yourself it is
going to be different and I guess so
just sidetrack and slightly we work in a
community as lawyers and open source
where we collaborate and share and
perhaps work together more than you
would see most lawyers doing but we
choose to do that because we sort of
work with these community values and I
think you'll find lawyers in this area
probably have slightly different views
on what is right and what is ethical
then maybe in other areas please I think
we're out of time but we can continue
this discussion another time let's give
a huge round of applause to our lawyers
great
[Applause]