hello everyone so I am Illya slave and I
come from OpenStreetMap most of you know
what opposite map is it's open map which
everyone can paint and opposite map has
one issue
well not exactly one of his millions of
problems but this one comes from the
nature of the project it's the biggest
one opposite map is open data and to
make open data you have to rely on even
open ur data like public domain level of
open and the sources for Open Street Map
is very hard to find because of this
because there is very few sources which
are open enough for Open Street Map and
this hindered the development of a I
move for a very long time in the start
because first CTS were drawn using only
Landsat imagery which is very crude like
15 meters per pixel and Manilla
collected GPS traces which are also not
great but you can see that at least they
make a road network you can trace GPS
traces are still considered the main
source for Open Street Map they are
featured very prominently on the website
there's even a link for them
people are still uploading the them not
many just hundred today or so but still
and people are tracing over GPX their
primary source which means all other
source sources are aligned to GPS traces
but of course many years have passed and
thanks to many big companies we now have
a lot more detailed sources like
detailed imagery for all the world
thanks to s3
my box DigitalGlobe and being of course
we have street to you thanks not to
Google but to mapillary
the open or alternative and we have a
lot of vector data like building
footprints for all of the United States
thanks to Microsoft road network for
Netherlands thanks to AMG and a lot of
local sources for data so there are so
many sources that you basically can draw
anywhere on the map but of course these
sources have issues as well and the main
issue is that they're not always recent
like this imagery was taken four years
ago but it doesn't actually say so on
the imagery itself you have to know
where to look the same for Street View
you may not notice it but still two
images can be taken like two years ago
the same for vector data same for even
GPS traces people are still tracing the
map from traces uploaded ten years ago
so opposite map is considered to be very
recent very quality map but in fact we
all editors were posted map using
sources that are very old we are making
the map of yesterday figuratively which
means years for half a year a year ago
and that is the main issue with sources
in OpenStreetMap so a bit about myself I
work in company called Juna this is taxi
service like uber but works only in New
York if you're in New York try using it
it's very generous to drivers and on my
job I work with vast amounts of data
collected from all the rights from all
parts of infrastructure
for example I work with all right
data collectors like where people get on
the car get get dropped off all the time
stamps locations all the total
information speeds and so on and of
course a roll a GPX traces from the
rights they look like this
there of course row and in build up
areas you might know that GPX I see no
chance to drift off quite a lot
especially in areas like Manhattan with
very high buildings so how do you work
with it how do you analyze it and make
any calculations there is a process for
that and better may have talked about it
in his graph for presentation it's
called map matching you basically take
every point of the trace and find the
road segment that was most likely
traveled and it's not always nearest
road segment as you can see drift off
quite significantly
but using complex processes involving
Markov chains predictions and stuff like
that you finally get a road segments
which you can do your work this these
algorithms are pretty well implemented
in open source decisions there is very
serenity which we use I believe graph
quarter also can do it so now we have
our signals
that's theory so when I came to Juna as
you know I come from a posted map and I
have been thinking how can I help my
project what can I do to improve
opposite map itself working at you know
I cannot of course publish her GPS
traces for people to trace because that
will be breach of privacy and
corporate stuff but turns out one of my
colleagues have already started working
on a very interesting theme he basically
took all the traces with head for a day
all 50,000 of them I really hope we will
have some 2,000 a year he matched them
to opposite me abroad network all 50,000
and started looking for animal anomalies
anomalies for unexpected loops for
places where matched roads diverged from
a rot react because these mean that
there is an error in opposite map that
there is some one way road dispenser to
take in correctly that there are some
segments missing and so on and I took
over the project and made it more
production-ready it looks like this so
you can see that traces form our taxi
drivers help find quite low issues in
OpenStreetMap like here redress traces
of the road race from the car and the
blue one is matched to OpenStreetMap and
you can see that there is probably some
small segments in osm that's marked one
way incorrectly so what I did is
basically sped it up now it process like
million of writes in under five hours I
made a nice user interface so I can
immediately see errors on the map and
add fun stuff and it's continued rise so
it runs every day so every morning I
start with fixing the most prominent
errors in OpenStreetMap
there are these are other examples of
such errors like some kind of statements
and stuff so there was around 2% of
Rights meshed incorrectly when I started
now it's like 1 in 200 which is quite
great but not perfect some rights some
false positives come from for example
sudden drift of GPS signal which
obviously cannot mesh to anything or
when texted drivers make sudden u-turn
to turn left well whereas Forbidden Zone
but mostly is okay well one time I start
my morning with finding that more than
hundred rights were matched incorrectly
in West Manhattan because somebody has
reversed a couple of streets one way
streets so I start investigating it
because you don't just correct it
without understanding what happened so I
open satellite imagery so Street was
heading that that way and people
reversed it to face that way and you can
see that cars are stationed in the new
way the waited has been fixed and I open
Google Street View and again it looks
like it's one way street hit westward so
the Edit must be right but I still have
hundreds rights they tell otherwise that
it must be an error and when the street
was headed eastward it was all okay so
what happened I started googling and
turns out that four month ago the
Department of Transport indeed reversed
the direction of the street but it was
just four months ago and all the sources
would have like satellite imagery like
okay like Street View they don't reflect
it
because satellite imagery was taken like
half a year ago and street views from
2017 I wrote about it to osm editor who
made the change asking them to be more
careful and from the answer I got two
things first
well I was answered by lift employee
lift his now taxi service and she
basically said that she's a part of our
mapping team and she didn't have enough
source so which means that leaved
well as well as super as well as any big
companies that use geospatial data they
use all posted map that's for sure we
know that everyone uses opposite map at
this moment but what's more important
they have dedicated mapping team a group
of people who fixes errors on opposite
map which they can find and the second
thing is they don't have recent sources
working lifts and even bigger company
dollars and that is again the issue with
sources for OpenStreetMap so being a
person involved in the open project I
started thinking how can I invent how
can I give more better sources because I
found the error while they didn't so
there is depicts traces we've got every
minute we get like dozen new rights
doesn't you roll GPS traces for the city
but you can share them so how does
happen no post-it map actually in
OpenStreetMap nobody downloads GPX files
anymore well nobody uploads them but
that's another thing because working
these de peixe is very hard it's a
complex format it takes a lot of memory
and where when there is a lot of Rights
it's very hard to trace over GPS traces
so instead people just add the big
styles layer it's all the same traces
but rendered in raster tiles the color
means direction of travel so the blue
one is traveling to the east and red is
to the west so you can immediately see
one-way streets and two-way streets and
where can you go so I looked at the de
Peixe tile layer for Manhattan and it
was abysmal it's just a couple Wiggly
lines in Manhattan where there's a lot
of people living and working
so obviously this couldn't be the source
for lift mappers or for any neighbors
well so what I did was took the source
code that produces this tiles because as
everything else in opposite map it's
open source and applied them to our two
peaks traces yeah that's what I got it's
a tracer just for one day for the area
around the street in question and you
can see that there are some one-way
streets you can learn their direction
and so on so it's looks pretty useful
much better than tracing opposite map
and the important thing is these are not
raw data not depicts traces they have no
metadata and which means this is
sufficiently anonymized for publishing
so we have now we have daily built
docker container with tiles for writes
which happened yesterday is just one day
of travels in the taxi service so this
contains blue dahlia it's published
internally at the moment and ready to be
published elsewhere and
so what's more important that we've got
permission to publish it for the public
there are some develops issues but in a
week or two it will be accessible to any
opposite map editor and with that it
will become the most recent source in
opposite map ever it's only for New York
City we operate only in New York and New
Jersey soon
but even then is basically you can see
where cars drive the day before today
like yesterday we forget so if a road is
closed then you will notice it on this
map the next day so it is very recent so
you may believe that after publishing
this will be no more errors in New York
City of course that's not correct
because publishing source doesn't mean
you instantly get a ready-made map if
that was the case then since we have
detailed satellite imagery for most of
the planet we would have the most
detailed map for the entire planet and
that is of course not correct there are
still a lot of places which have roads
and buildings but virtually no map data
so how do you make people make mappers
use the source that you give them the
common answer is you take this big task
and split it in steps
the thing that Quality Assurance tools
usually do they give you a list of
errors and you can fix them one by one
and we have such - Scott map roulette in
here for example it
shows you a segment of the street and
ask you ask you to specify how many
lanes at have as you can see a number of
lanes from satellite image area so all
you have to do is open editor enter a
number and hit upload and then it gives
you another the next task the next road
segment and the next one so couple hours
pass and you have made a substantial
contribution to opposite map so what I
am doing now at my it's my job is
linking graphically data with WEP relate
so people in New York or in United
States in general you can go and fix the
remaining errors in the road network
it's it work it turned out a bit more
complex than I expected because I had to
fix map alerts as well
there are pull requests to going but it
will be done I hope in a week or two so
and when I finish it I may explore other
ideas because I still have this large
pile of GPX traces which I can analyze
however I want so what else can we get
from it we can validate fabric
crucification
like confirm that the road that is very
prominent on the map has indeed a lot of
rights going over it we can find one-way
streets that are incorrectly mapped as
two-way because we don't really date for
that currently missing turn restrictions
if you see hundred cars turning right at
the intersection only right then it's
most likely you kind of turn left there
and speed limits although I wouldn't
trust taxi drivers to obey speed limits
if you have any other ideas I'm open so
so what is this all about
when a company preparation just some I
think you can can believe they will
follow through they have money the key
resources they give people that oversee
the project so they are fine with their
projects but open projects they rely
only on you which means if you don't
think about your open projects then
nobody will only people in the community
are responsible for open projects so you
cannot expect somebody else to do it for
you
like when I left maps me to work on Juna
I expected to stop contributing to
opposite map or not to contribute as
much but even on the new job I always
remember that I come from OPA statement
and the needs of my project are still
not first but second in length and this
what helped me to find new ways of
helping opposite map so that's also on
the most of you if you work for a
company or for government
see what you can help with opening maybe
you can help the company open some
source code that not crucial for your
project or for some geo data because we
have too few geo data right now to make
a pretty good map and if you don't work
such company then find a friend who does
so that's all thinking
[Applause]
for questions regarding restrictions
there are so many options you can find
in the world especially New York like
turn restrictions that don't work the
whole day you see on the street feel
that there is a clear restriction you
can turn left and in opposite map you
also can turn left but then you zoom in
and you see that these restrictions
restriction applies only for working
hours so you have to fix opposite map to
reflect that so the restriction the
signage in the real world is very
complex so you have to learn the many
interesting ways people an opposite not
try to reflect that in their taking
well opposite camp indeed did a great
thing with improving GPS signal because
when you have only a GPS receiver or
your phone then the device doesn't have
much to work with it just have to rely
on signal from satellites and what
opposite can did was to allow to plug
into a car's system to get information
about its speed and angle the wheels are
turned to improve the GPS signal using
this information so it's obviously works
better in areas like Manhattan and when
something is obstructing satellites but
of course there is a drawback why people
are not using it from daily basis
because you have to have a device that
plugs into your car bus and you have to
pair it with the phone and it in my case
it didn't work I couldn't just pair it
with the receiver and if everything else
works then again it's a contact the
phone connects the phone via bluetooth
and it was often just drops connection
but if everything else works then US
Open Street cam can help get a better
signal but I work taxi company and we
have several thousands drivers and we
can distribute the same thing here to
them it's it was hard enough to make
them use the single phone system but
giving extra things this just won't work
right so the question was can I use my
phone as a dash cam and then use the
dash cam footage to improve the map yes
of course but not the way professional
company is doing it
we have mapillary which is stretched to
you that you can collect yourself
basically use ur phone as a dash cam and
it will make photos and send them to the
server and then you can use that footage
to manually add things it have seen to
the map there are ongoing attempts to
streamline the process like Richard fair
first is working on an editor that
basically gives you a photo from a
pillory you click on the photo like on
the shop or on the sign and it
automatically places markers on the map
and allows you to describe what you have
clicked on but it's still in early
stages so I expect in a year or two it
will be easier to process such - commit
imagery
I have no idea maybe we should look at
opposite candy time but yeah in New York
we often have to rely on Google Street
View to cross check errors because
there's very little mobility
[Applause]