all right so next talk is from pneumonia
Nico de vich sorry famous for its about
H wallet was simply a Bitcoin how about
it thank you yeah okay so contrary to
what you expect it's probably not going
to be a talk about blockchain it's more
going to be talk about secure hardware
so okay yeah so it's gonna be talk about
secure hardware and I already since I
already gave a talk with the same slides
I didn't change the rap these slides you
can already find this talk on youtube so
I want to to move it a bit to to in a
bit other direction I will go through
slides of course but first I want to say
that from all the promises that we got
from blockchain I know some people are
gonna throw tomatoes at me but save it
please for later from all the promises
we we heard about what chain if it's
going to save the world it's got a pure
cancer and everything I believe that
there are only two visible benefits for
the whole community for the for the
general public
first of all mining hardware can be
reused for AI and second advancement in
open source secure hardware will
probably lead to growth in usage of u2f
tokens which will increase security of
your accounts on various online services
but let's move on with the talk and then
later I would also like to hear your
opinion about what is a Hardware wallet
because when I gave this talk at other
places some people approached me later
asking me telling me actually they did
they disagree with me and then Hardware
wallet is not the just something that I
believe the hard wallet is some people
told me why
yeah but it's also you know saying
harder wallet is kind of for pleonasm
because wallet itself is hardware right
so they say yeah also like using a smart
card would be a harder wallet for
bitcoins and so yeah true but you don't
have a screen so you don't have you are
not sure what is actually being signed
on that hardware and I would I would
really like to hear later if anyone else
has has other opinions what actually
hardware wallet is and what it should be
but let's move on with with five noun so
there were vulnerabilities in almost all
widely used hardware wallets so there
was a really interesting talk at the
last ccc the where security researchers
gave really broad array of attacks
showed a really broad array of attacks
on these horrible it's so that for
example that everyone with the physical
access to that hardware can run any can
execute any arbitrary code because due
to the flaw in the in the in the in the
bootloader so that's that's the kind of
the construction of a fletcher
so there is an oled there is a
microcontroller which is an insecure
microcontroller and just off-the-shelf
stm32 and there is a secure MCU so
secure and see you does he tours all the
keys and does all the signing but if you
in fact the this microcontroller it
actually shows on the OLED what you are
signing then this is kind of pointless
scenario and this converges to some to
the security of that you can have for
example on a smart card so you don't
need the wallet for this on the other
hand yeah there was also an interesting
blog post from roughly a year ago which
basically came come to the same
conclusion with with physical access you
can if you have access you can have a
supply chain attack on these on these
wallets where you can actually replace
the firmer even though but but firmer is
actually supposed to be verified by the
secure
microcontroller but if you have some
redundant parts of the firmware on the
on the general-purpose microcontroller
this can actually you can just resend
the same part and then put your
malicious code in the redundant parts of
the code for treasurer there was there
were actually because I believe that
harder wallet should be actually should
be resistant to remote attacks so it
means that no nobody like even if we
consider a threat model that your
computer your laptop is compromised your
cold storage should be should be safe
well that wasn't let's say that that's
not 100% the case with good treasurer
because they had actually wrote a really
nice blog post about it they have they
have a really good security blog for
that for these purposes but yeah so this
in in in this theoretical attack because
of the for in the USB software stack
which was which is the third-party code
actually that that can lead to if you if
your computer's compromised you can send
malicious packet to to the wallet and
then you can write up to 60 bytes of
data into the protected part of the
memory which is definitely not good and
also of course like with physical access
bla bla you can do the same thing so
let's see how are they constructed which
hardware is used there so for treasurer
and Philippe key which is kind of a
ripoff of Tresor they use the same
microcontroller stm32 f2 0 5 which is as
I said general-purpose microcontroller
it doesn't have any true random number
generator it doesn't have any
acceleration for for any cryptographic
primitives but because you don't need to
sign an NDA to to publish this software
it's completely open source which is
awesome on the other hand ledger has
this secure mark controller which is
under an NDA so that that's why I
couldn't conclude whether it has or it
doesn't have
the support hardware support hardware
acceleration for
sha-256 but it definitely cannot be
open-source though the software for the
for the general purpose microcontroller
can be open sourced and there is also
another harder wallet called a cold card
which has an interesting construction so
it has this secure element which is
supposed to store keys but on the other
hand even though it's a Tec see even
though we will assume that it has
support it does support elliptic curve
cryptography but it doesn't support the
elliptic curve that is needed for
signing Bitcoin transactions so the
actual signing has to be done on the
insecure microcontroller but of course
this can be also open source and the
construction that that I just hope
because I wasn't I wasn't happy really
with with the existing approach was that
I si to move the OLED and then put the
microcontroller in between the computer
like the communication micro neutral
because you usually USB software stack
is really heavy and you know going
through and and it's also dependent and
interrupts more in most cases and that
leads to two that can lead to too many
different cases where you can actually
compromise the so the whole so this way
you maintain the same threat model as if
your laptop was compromised but you you
minimize you close the door close the
gap by only using like simple you are
stupid UART communication with the my
controller that is actually kind of
secure and it's available without an NDA
so and it has hardware acceleration for
two it has like to run or arm generator
hardware acceleration for sha-256 and
also supports in Hardware elliptic curve
sack be 256k one which is needed for
signing Bitcoin transactions and
theorem also and that thus it can be
completed the whole setup can be
completely open sourced so checking the
library dependencies well I tried to be
independent completely from from from
any library in H wallet so I didn't even
use the standard c library that
therefore i actually had to do some some
tricks to do even division with like big
numbers but we will see that later so
for treasure
basically it's completely open source
well whereas ledger is using these has
these like closed source components that
were that they were unable to to publish
because of the NBA with with SD so if
and if you see treasure and both Reznor
and lighter they depend also on lots of
third party libs so that that's how
actually this the this buffer overflow
happened in in in treasure because it
was part of these third-party libraries
that were actually just used as they are
they were never actually meant to be
used in secure devices they thought that
there was a proper security all it
carried out on them
so keep key as a report as I said it
just adds some some code on that and
called card issues is like it has has
common code with all of these projects
and it's it has huge code base because
of the usage of micro Python I know what
you're saying like you probably think
I'm crazy I'm rolling my own crypto well
I would disagree because I'm actually
just interfacing Hardware primitives in
the microcontroller so that's why my
code base can actually be really small
that's why that's why the eighth wallet
has really really really small code base
compared to so I actually pulled each of
these projects from from github and also
including their sub modules and then
counted the number of lines of code in C
and got eight files
and as you can see 2.5 million lines of
code for a coal card because of micro
Python like it actually pulls the code
for different platforms for different
microcontrollers it's just a bunch of
everything
whereas ledger has around the three
hundred forty six thousand lines of code
which is the only on the open source
part and treasuring keep key expectedly
they have around the same number of
lines of code whereas the v8 wallet it
was written from scratch only has like
around four thousand lines of code and
of these lines of code like only
slightly above two thousand lines of
code is the actual meet the rest is the
deformed for displaying like you don't
even have to order that code and license
headers which don't even get compiled so
regarding code lace yeah you can find it
find the code on this link it hasn't
been updated for a while but yeah I
don't have enough time to work on that
at the moment but if you see this is the
basic layer these are the basic the
drivers that the call it actually
interfaces the hardware then the methyl
so if the construction looks like this
there isn't this microcontroller that
communicates to another communication
microcontroller and talks with the OLED
so this part is I actually fixed the
speed to 215 point to kill the board
because that helped me optimize the
whole code I didn't have to calculate
values for certain registers that
therefore I made the code much easier
told it like you can audit it in in a
couple of days for like you can perform
proper security on it on the source code
and also yeah spi bus is caught and one
many heard the same actually applied the
same approach as with as with you earth
and the other part the crypto part over
there so basically I have the building
block building blocks for for all of
these so LTC is making sure that that
part that peripheral is making sure that
I can sign the transaction
mm cau gives me the hash and I got a
nonce from trng and LTC supports 256-bit
operation arithmetic for for this
elliptical and also for generating the
signature these are some operations that
that I used to implement the ECDSA
algorithm here and the upper layer is
kind of split in 3 parts so there is the
this packet part where which is used for
communication let's say like upstream to
to the communication and see you and
further to the computer into the network
to the OLED which is basically interface
that you get ok it includes also GPIO
that is used for buttons but I didn't
have to show it here it's obvious and
critical part which is covering these
three peripherals that I already
mentioned so yeah packet there is really
simple interface we'd send and receive
packet structure is like TLB NCRC super
simple not complicated easy to audit all
a part basically just cleared you all
read and write the row with with certain
certain string by SPI and this is a bit
more complicated part where we're
actually actual signing takes place and
hashing and it's the trickiest part was
to actually implement the division
because does anyone know why I would
need big number division for signing
Bitcoin transactions anyone ok it's
because when you when you want to
populate the the the the string for some
one of the the foreign address you need
to to use base 58 and in order to get
base 58 you need to divide that number
with you need to divide the
address with with 58 and then get these
human readable characters and in order
to do that I had to implement this
division which was not supported in
hardware so the way I did actually
abused the existing stuff so I first
used the inversion so modular
multiplicative inverse modulo number B
so I get a B Prime and then I deduct the
the module a module B from from a to get
the the round number for for the result
and what I do then is I basically
multiply these two numbers and in order
for this to work I have to make sure
that I can get the multiple module
multiplicative inverse modulo N and for
that to work and has to be a large prime
and larger than any a and B so I looked
at the code that I already had and I
found yeah there is a P from SEC P 256 K
1 which is a large prime number and
that's how it this was implemented in
these number of lines of code possible
main loop is a stupid main loop that
just reads packets via via you are so no
interrupts it's it's just waiting for
these packets and depending on the on
the packet after it its verify this here
see it sends it further up the stack to
two different modules so for example if
it's intended to be used for Bitcoin
module it's just sending it to to that
part of the of the upper layer of the
code and then so the the the type field
is actually divided into so packet type
can be either module or actually can be
like the module part defines the module
and function defines a function within
that module on the upper layer so far I
only implemented the Bitcoin module and
this is how the process function looks
like basically it just has a switch case
for for the function and then if it's
like if the computer says yeah if the
communication chip actually sounds like
now initialize the transaction these are
the this is the stuff that the
transaction is consisted of and then
okay now ask the user to sign it and
then something like this shows up on the
screen and if you say yes you're gonna
send point zero zero one bitcoins to
this address so what next I don't
actually plan to build it because this
microcontroller has a super crazy lead
time like last time I checked it was
almost a year so it's it's kind of I
guess pointless to start but if you if
you want to to test it yourself you can
buy these boards are easily available
online from from various websites so
yeah
I plan to - probably at some point
implement or anyone of you welcome to
commit the code it's completely released
under GPL v3 so for some future plans
maybe implementing the u2f and also yeah
there is another microcontroller in in
these series which is if you want to go
and be a more secure anti-tamper
you can use that one and reuse the same
code but that yeah then you need to sign
an NDA with with this chip vendor which
is not really friendly for a foreign
event like for them right and you can
also put some other communication by
control the one that I that I used was
already on the board which it was used
actually for debugging purposes but I
kind of abused it too to communicate but
if you put some other for example one of
these Nordic kids that they support also
like Bluetooth NFC and USB so you can
actually connect your your wallet to
anything and you don't you don't care if
there is a vulnerability in that
communication stack because all you care
about is that this software runs as
intended because in again you are the
one who has the the last word
she wants to sign a transaction maybe
one of the next things to implement
would be also the recovery seed - to
implement these three bit coding
fermentation proposals and any more
cryptocurrencies but yeah you're welcome
to commit codes for that and any
questions any questions yeah very nice
so there KL 82 chip and there's 81 and
anti tampering I believe there are two
separate chips how do they differ do
they require NDA's and do they support
other than the SEC k2 fifty sixty one
yeah so first yeah I didn't sorry I
didn't I didn't elaborate that further
there is K 82 and there is KL 82 so okay
82 is based on cortex m4 and KL 82 is
based on cortex m0 and it's I think the
board price is like twice two times
smaller so it's it's 50% cheaper and
therefore it's maybe better if you want
to if you want us to give it a shot to
try this code yourself but the only
difference between these K 80/20 KL 82
is and k & KL 81 is because they have
another peripheral that is responsible
for like if we need to write the code
for for like anti-tamper for probable
activity they support I think mesh
protection and stuff like that but you
need to sign an NDA for that I didn't
sign an NDA I didn't even get in get in
touch with the chip vendor so yeah I am
just expressing my opinion here or are
they useful at all without an NDA do
they support the Copeland's curves do
they support exactly editors yeah
exactly
everything is supported except for this
anti-tamper part yeah I use them for a
further for this purpose and they have
Edwards and Montgomery curves
as well thank you five five one nine oh
that's very nice yeah yeah it's like
that that's why I use this one because
I've actually checked many different
microcontrollers and this one was by far
the most advanced I could find so thank
you any other questions okay thank you
very much
[Applause]
well
wait
[Music]