okay so hi everyone so thanks for
staying so late for the talk yeah my
name is Alejandro and I work at art as a
divorce engineer one of the main things
we do is basically support the compiler
teams and to change in general on
building
ci testing and benchmark with actual
hardware I'm also a contributor for LNT
which is a performance tracking tool for
LLVM and the idea for today is to give
you one more tool for your toolbox when
investigating issues if the compiler or
the tool chain in general so basically
when we are investigating some issue or
the two chains playing up to
indiscretion or something or any tools
crashing one key information when it was
to getting it if you have the
repositories or you were contributors
that you are really interested in
finding which commit calls that behave
changing behavior so that information is
even if we are not an expert on that
that part of the tool you can understand
a little bit more about what's happening
then the process in which you can you
can use like a methodology to do that
and one of the ways you can do is try to
investigate like the previous versions
and try to find out this exact version
in which the thing was working and then
stopped working one problem with that is
that in projects like LLVM clang in
which we can have more than one hundred
commits today is like very
time-consuming and for that reason many
tools as it's a very routine and
repetitive process there are many tools
that can help us to achieve this a bit
of theory done so the code by section is
this process of looking backwards in
your own a given repository trying to
find a change in behavior a specific
change in behavior can be crush this can
be performance regressions
yeah and you might as well be looking
for when something was fixed so it was
not working and now it's working and I
I'm interested to know who fixed it or
if the fix was a side-effect of another
change then in order to run bisect of
any bisecting process you need basically
two things the first one is to have a
repository in which you have a
relationship of of the relationship with
changes so there was this original
change then it is this subsequent change
and then this one and this one on like a
timeline fashion and also we need some
test case or some way to label these
given versions this is a bad version or
this is a good version so as you have
changes happening over time you
basically are interested to see so on
the latest one so basically something
that's not working then you go backwards
and you go backwards and that until you
find somebody or some version that in
which the thing was working then you can
restrict your search space to that
region and then you rerun the process
until you will find the very specific
version in which you have that thing
working
usually when talking about source code
we are looking for a specific commit and
commit is tightly connected to source
control so it's natural that source
control offers some sort of bisecting
then get as near material and others
they offer bisecting option it's good
because you have all the information
that you were looking for on that
repository so you can run by section and
look for very specific changes you can
also so the source control it doesn't
know what which what is the expected
behavior for that code is just a
repository but
this gives you full flexibility to build
that code if needed in a very customized
way for to fit your needs on the flip
side you need to build it and you need
to tell it so this is the specific way I
want to build and this can makes it can
make things a little bit difficult when
you want to share this information with
other people because you have all your
local environment and the influences of
your local environment when doing this
also not all versions are able to build
so if you look for some let's say out of
100 changes on the compiler you'll have
some of these versions that are not
possible to build because they are
broken versions then as I said you you
need to set up the whole thing you need
to build it you need to run your things
if you want to have a clean build each
time you need to set it up and clean up
things as you need any big projects it
can be very time consuming when you have
a big codebase that takes a little bit
long but more than a few minutes to
build and a lot of changes so your
search space is actually very big then
there are as we have a big code base and
lots of commits there is the need or
there was a need to to have a
specialized tool in order to run by
section on any alidium and this was
created three years ago and this tool is
our VM lab bisect so we using this tool
you have a specific environments to
triage or bisect bugs or regressions in
general on LLVM and clang code base so
as I said so this tool was contributed
by Chris Matthews and Daniel three years
ago they are both at Apple this two is
written in Python and is a specialized
tool to bisect clunk and LBM there is
documentation
on github you can find documentation is
very comprehensive in order to install
it is a is a Python package I recommend
you use a virtual environment then it's
basically those steps in in blue so you
clone you you you install and you have
it so I didn't say it before but I'm
running a few demos during the talk and
my demos are running on a Raspberry Pi
so we can actually run this to distil is
completely supported by any Python 2 or
3 environment that you and they have so
let me find the first thing so I already
install this on a virtual environment
and they follow in that steps so I have
one with one of my means and directory B
so I will source that thing me activate
and then I have a VM lab and then I have
the whole two already running so as I
said this is my raspberry PI's and arm
d7 running Linux and that's a simple
that so yeah so installation basic use
it for LLVM lab you will need basically
one thing you need one test case to
reproduce the flight the failure you are
investigating so when you call this you
call LVM bisect and then you provide the
test case I will show you how to do that
but when you run any test case so no
matter what test case you were running
or options that you provide you
basically do four things one it will
download download builds from build cash
I'll tell you more about that in a
moment it will run it will create a
sandbox with that version it will run
the test case and then it will navigate
through the repository doing that
process that I showed before with the
timeline labeling versions and finally
the specific committee we want
a few concepts that are involved the
first one and one of the most important
for the sake of lrvm lab bisect and is
the main argument for using that is
saving time by using it so the build
cache is a cache full of pre-built
packages with the two chains of
basically CI system so continuous
integration systems are Jiang Jenkins or
in billboard generate these packages
there are many types of packages that
that you can use out of the box like x86
packages under seven and a arc 64 they
are stored on Google Cloud storage
so they are you can download them and
then this is something that we did
recently we added support for mv7 AR 64
like three months ago and then these
packages are being populated very often
so how we do that so for every commit
that you do that goes to the main
repository we will have a build server
so the upstream built bot will keep
pulling the SVN repository two minutes
and then if it sees some changes on
either Klunk lrvm libraries and a few
repositories will trigger builds on
native arm builders so there are other
x86 builders that are not maintained by
us these are the ones that we as
infrastructure team at are maintained so
there is one native AR 32 + 1 AR 64 Bill
Mueller that we upload the binaries and
packages for Google Cloud storage that
will be available so as I said this
works very often so each two minutes it
pause the repository and it's important
for us to have these packages being
created quite quickly so we got two very
beefy a arch machines
our machines and then we can complete
this process and have from a given
commit to the build cash you have them
in 16 minutes more or less this is the
odd job that is live and an upstream so
you have the also the configurations for
what this job does on Zork which is a
repository for infrastructure cold and
builds an automation inside within a
neural LLVM then you have others all
these builds you'll see many of these
builds every day to have as many
versions as possible to narrow down the
well the resolution of the results of
the bisection process so you have very
specific emitted as much as possible so
when running buys bisection processes
using our vm lab you need to pick a
repository in which the tool we use to
download builds so there are many we are
if you don't say any repository it feels
a 1x IDs x86 repository and download
things to run locally there are two of
them that we are interested in this talk
which are these two one so clung a art
64 and arm d7 which are the ones that we
are publishing things in order to pick a
specific repository we want to tell an
option - B and point to the specific
repository with this ones I'll show you
that probably yes yes so we only have
rights to publish things that's why we
didn't remove anything you know we
didn't criticize anything but we we say
LLVM
eeehm lab LS so it's pretty fast and you
can you can have the production ones
there are no restrictions if you install
the command-line tools you have access
to the whole thing so there's no there
is nothing difficult or that you need to
ask permission for then there is a other
important thing is the sandbox so the
sandbox is the temporary location in
which for every time you download a
given version you have this directory
with the whole tool chain so you'll be
able to just with the time that you need
to download and extract this package
that that's the time you need setting up
your test environment this is important
to say
by default send boxes are deleted after
the end of the process but you can save
them by providing - s and then providing
a directory by default they go to his
life stamp and they get deleted which
sometimes if you are like trying out
your bug producer it can be like a waste
of time it if it takes like 10 minutes
to run the whole thing you can save time
by providing a custom sandbox directory
the other important bit that I'll go
quickly is the predicates so these are
basically the command lines that you run
to reproduce your the behavior you are
looking for so you can buy the simplest
usage you have LLVM lab bisect and then
you say this line fails find me where
this was working before if any right so
you can have a very simple command line
that will trigger different versions and
navigate through this repository and
then it will give you the revisions that
you are looking for so as you can see
there is something that's
quite different here which is this bit
the percent string and this is basically
it will be substituted by or replaced
button by any version that you are
trying out so it will get that specific
version path then it will run the clunk
from from that sandbox so it will get
replaced by the tool so you can test
many versions and also there is not only
the variable path so there are many
other variables that you can use to in
to implement your test cases you can
also use all your previous knowledge on
shell and pipes and the output into
files grepping and all your previous
knowledge can be used to to help you and
this is very useful when you when you
are trying to troubleshoot something so
that you can use it in two ways one is
via the command line that you use the
Python printf syntax which has that one
you can also have it run as a shell
script and in that way when calling the
shell script I will show it you will get
these variables injected so these for
the whole list that I showed before so
this is how you call it on command lines
just in line or you can say run this
shell script and the shell script will
have the variables in that date format
you can also so that variables are when
you are running the test you get those
variables after you finish the test you
can also use test filters so you can see
for that specific test case whether the
test passed or failed you will get a
result on a variable called result and
you can also have the time measurements
as in user time system time and wall
time
so this is the way you can use it so you
can say for that given test case if it
passed and user time was less than half
a second then you can you can you use
that expression to evaluate whether
these test case was passing or not this
is useful when you were running
benchmarks so you are if you are trying
to see why a given benchmark progressed
or something you can compile that
benchmark with the version of the the
tool chain and then run it so you can
just do a command semicolon run it and
then you you get this results as an
output there are other useful command
lines if you like so there is very
verbose real sandbox which which makes
which saves time by keeping the send
boxes the temporary sent boxes so you
can reuse them so this is something that
we are up streaming as part of the
preparation of this talk so I was trying
so many by sections and they were taking
long so I externalized this option was
part of this so you can restrict
versions so you can make the bisection
process to run faster so I have a few
couple demonstrations I think I'll show
one of them and then I you have the
slides and you can reproduce the other
so the first one is an actual bug opened
in on clang so clang crashes when
calling a function while both on meeting
a parameter and misspelling a parameter
so I can show you that one see so when
you provide this you have the parameter
as user news and another thing which is
not a non-existent to chain will crash
then their way to reproduce it
let me show you cut status to the stage
so this is basically the way I am
running it oh I have this come online
better in a better format so this is the
way I'm I'm running this bisection
process so I'm calling out the EM bisect
I'm calling real sandbox so so it won't
download things and extract things on my
local machine is just to speed up the
process for demonstration purposes I set
a given max revision that I have done
previously downloaded custom sandbox and
this is the reproducer so I'm calling
shell worklink
is this thing I got all this information
of the bug report and then what I want
to find to say not a given version is
working I want to get an undeclared
identifier rather than a crash so this
thing so this is the bug report so what
it does it basically we will crash the
dhole to chain and whatever we are
looking for is a undeclared identifier
so I would just run this thing and you
see that it will start well it's not
very useful but you see many fails and
you see a few passes so it is limiting
this search space so it is failing
failing failing until it passes then
okay it reruns the process on that space
as well so in the end it will say that
client revision this number this
timestamp is a first working boot and
this one this timestamp is the next
failing build so it was working in this
revision and it was not working anymore
undistribute so that's the output you
get for anything that you want to
troubleshoot so yeah okay yeah but I
think the first working build it's it
seemed from latest to oldest so is the
first working build it from in the
opposite direction another last one from
the source I guess that's that's the
meaning of the message yeah but this is
because it pulls the repository each two
minutes so we can get all a smaller
resolution than one single committee
yeah okay so yeah I just need just a few
discussions so there is just to
summarize the the gains that we will
have on time spent on bisection if we
that demonstration I did I have already
cached the download the versions and I
have already extracted that versions so
it runs well really
artificially quick because I have
everything pre cached in a real world on
a Raspberry Pi
it will take around three minutes to
uncompress that's the the most time is
spent on that thing
I have a few suggestions on how to fix
that in the future but still three
minutes is not so bad and if we do that
in real world we will have one hour and
ten minutes to test 23 to change times
three minutes each more or less but on
the other side comparing this with the
time we usually spend on creating the
build cash items which is more or less
ten minutes we to do the same process we
you have almost four hours to to run the
whole thing considering we get that
specific versions that we know that are
possible to build and we run the same
like jumping through versions to
optimize the process so this is
basically
two hours and 40 minutes that you get
more or less come win in this comparison
also that we are always having versions
that we build and we work yes yeah
that's probably less probably more I'm
just not considering that we are
building on a Raspberry Pi because that
would be like yeah so yeah so that's the
thing we are building on a very high-end
machine I will tell you a little bit
about that machine and then still if we
compare Raspberry Pi versus Raspberry Pi
then it will be like days versus hours
right to have all the all those versions
and I'm I'm talking about ten minutes
because we are building from scratch
this is not an incremental build so this
is a very high-end machine so this the
demonstration number two I'll just skip
that so a final remark so automated
bisecting is a valuable tool to have on
your toolbox to troubleshoot things on
the tool chain we can save time by using
a lot of um lot by sectors with just saw
and we recently added on the seven and a
art 64 so there is also this move within
the the allergen community to move from
SVN to get and then this will impact
tools like that that rely on revision
versions so I've sent a message to Chris
Matthews a few weeks ago and we are
discussing about that getting ideas and
yeah yes
yeah and also we don't really need to
track the revision number versions to
trust that in in this scenario we can
just get the like the continuous
integration tool build ID or something
that is shared and known so the machine
these machines that we've got for the
lrvm project these machines are actually
free and each and every open-source
project can request some of them this is
an initiative called works on arm which
offers machines or remote machines that
you can use some very powerful machines
to try your continuous integration jobs
and Cide working and supported on arm in
general this is the URL you can request
resources opening basically a github
issue all instructions are on that
website and we use it and these machines
are very reliable
we have them running for months without
any problem yeah yeah so we use them two
machines one is a thunder x2 and one is
or a teller x1 and the other one is a
another high-end machine yeah this one
yeah yeah and that's it for me thank you
thank you and if you have any questions
I'm happy to
[Applause]
so I'm guessing with this looks like
Nick strikes like yeah
so the question is about though the test
cases in which you have tools like
biotech and not those things right yeah
I know and I didn't test with any of
them yeah I think you you can can find
away if you have if you have a bash
script out of it you can reproduce the
thing very quickly yeah
and then you probably just need to
change the places in which you need
Clank to have that path variable on it
and that's it
yeah so yeah so the first thing only on
this way so from the arm machine from
the x86 machine run something on a queue
this is kind of already supported
because you can have a bash script and
if you can do ad vitur that on a bash
script you can do that on this probably
yeah and it is also a curiosity on this
is that we build also the backend for
x86 so you can use on your machine
you can generate the x86 banners in and
even if you have a way to run them you
can do that as well
yeah yeah thanks very much
[Applause]