all right thanks everybody for coming to
my talk today my name's Adam lidtke I'm
a software engineer at Red Hat today I'm
here to talk about declarative
pre-population of your kubernetes
persistent volumes to help make your
apps happier so it's a kubernetes talk I
don't have enough time to talk about
that subject on its own but it's let's
just say it's the de-facto way to run
containers at scale a couple things that
I like the most about it is the
declarative nature of the system and how
that's implemented with the controller
pattern we'll get into more details on
how we're going to leverage that today
basically by the next point here which
is that the cluster itself is very
extensible you can add new features to
the base functionality by creating your
own custom resources and your own custom
controllers a couple of the objects in
kubernetes that will be relevant to
today's talk are nodes which are
kubernetes worker machines they have
everything that's needed to run pods
which I'll tell you about in a second
that includes the container runtime like
docker or cryo
as well as all the kubernetes bits like
the couplet cube proxy at CD all that
stuff and of course the nodes are
managed by the master of the cluster to
do all the fun work so what are pods
they're basically a logical application
unit that consists of one or more
containers they all get scheduled
together and run on the same node and
because they're a logical unit they have
the access to the same storage and
networking that's been given to the pod
they live in so the way that storage
gets managed in kubernetes in a nutshell
here is through two custom resources we
have a persistent volume and a
persistent volume claim persistent
volumes essentially represent a piece of
storage that was provisioned by the
storage administrator to be available to
the cluster for use that can either
happen statically by an Edmund directly
or via dynamic provisioning all storage
persistent volumes have a type there's
different kinds you can have if
running in a cloud you can have cloud
volumes from Amazon or Azure or Google
for example you can have
software-defined storage like Stepford
Gluster you can even have local storage
or host path storage lots of different
options there it doesn't really matter -
to me at my level what the storage is
this will work everywhere a persistent
volume claim is when a user makes a
request for a piece of storage so this
is just saying I need 10 gigabytes of
storage and I might want to choose a
storage class to pull it from it just
depends and what will happen is
kubernetes will satisfy the users
request by binding the claim to a volume
and then the user has available to them
an empty volume to associate with a pod
and so I'll just repeat again that this
kubernetes is always provisioning empty
volumes that generally has worked for
most applications but sometimes it's not
always going to be the best plan so
sometimes you're going to want to have
your volumes pre initialized and here's
a couple of examples for that so
database databases as they come into
containerized environments oftentimes
know how to populate an empty database
when they're starting for the first time
that's going to happen once after that
point you probably have data that you
want to resume from and if you're for
example standing up this database on a
volume from a new storage class or a
larger volume or something you're going
to want to import that data in and it
should be there before the database
tries to start if you have a big data
application and you're processing multi
gigabyte data sets probably better to
have that data available when the pod
comes up rather than having the pod have
to try to acquire it in real time as
it's running another case would be
restoring from backup I don't know how
many people are actually backing up
their persistent data and their
kubernetes clusters these days but more
should be and more will be as this
continues to mature so this is going to
be another case where you have your
backup and it's time to restore
then the last category mutable
persistent data this really comes as an
inspiration from a project I work on
called Qbert which allows you to run
virtual machines on top of your
kubernetes cluster that's way beyond the
scope of today's talk but definitely
check it out but in that case you have
virtual machine discs that are on the
persistent volume claims and everyone
knows that VMs don't boot very well off
of empty data so you have to have the
data in place for that case
so kubernetes provides a couple of
options for you to populate data into
your PVS
the first one I'll mention just because
it comes up so often but it's really not
an option and that's cube CTL CP this
allows you to copy from your laptop to
the filesystem of a running container or
a running pod the reason that's not a
good idea is several cases the the apps
already running so you're too late also
you are using the kubernetes api server
to proxy your data which is not really
production-grade and it's also very
imperative I have to decide sit down at
my laptop do some typing put the data in
there that's not really automatable or
in the spirit of kubernetes so let's
throw that one out the next one is I can
run a special pod ahead of time that
knows how to populate the the PVC so
that's better
I create a docker container maybe has W
get in it and some steps to do the
download or whatever you might want to
do however you're going to pull that
data in so this is pretty good it's
better except you still have to make
sure that you run that before your
actual application and if you have
multiple PVCs that you're managing this
way you're again in charge of managing
all that so it sounds like that's
something that kubernetes was supposed
to help us solve the third one is using
an init container so we're getting a
little bit closer kubernetes pod specs
allow you to have containers which are
your main application and init
containers which are guaranteed to run
successfully before kubernetes will
allow the actual containers to start
this is what one of those specs looks
like in a pod
so in this particular example we have an
engine X contains and then we have a
container that's running busybox that
just does a W get somewhere so this is
getting a little bit closer we're almost
there but in kubernetes it's important
to note that the life cycle of
persistent volumes was deliberately kept
separate from the life cycle of pods and
the reason for this is because pods can
can be short-lived going up and down
iterating over the same piece of
persistent storage which is there for a
long time so I'm not sure that it makes
sense to always tie the life cycle
together by having population occurring
in the context of an init container so a
couple of other points I've already
mentioned some of the caveats of the
existing options the a couple other
points I want to bring up is that you're
always going to want more features with
something like this
what about error handling with even that
init container example do you want the
an it contained you want the logic of
the populate err to retry itself or do
you want kubernetes to restart the pod
over and over until it succeeds that's a
choice you'd have to make if you want
for example to access data that is
privileged or you need credentials to
access that you may want to integrate
with the kubernetes secrets API in terms
of if you're using this a lot and with
lots of data you're probably going to
want some discoverability or
observability into what's the process so
you're going to need some kind of
logging
maybe Prometheus endpoints where you can
monitor the process so those are
features and then the management aspect
again so I've kind of alluded to this
already but making sure that it's order
it's not pre-population if it doesn't
happen before so it must always if you
have replica sets or stateful sets in
your application which are actually
doing
maybe spawning additional pods
potentially dynamically creating new
PVCs to host the application how are you
going to make sure that those
dynamically created pea
these are getting populated and then
error-handling comes up here again
because you don't want to introduce
instability or random behavior into your
cluster when you start doing this so I'd
like to suggest a better approach and I
would just take inspiration from the
design that kubernetes started with that
made it so successful which is let's
take a declarative based approach that's
using custom resources and controllers
to accomplish what we need so the way
that this works is you define custom
resources and post them to your cluster
that describe a population strategy so
this could be anything like please check
out this git repository this branch and
tag and store it in this directory or
download from this web URL and provide
credentials found in this kubernetes
secret it can be really anything that
you can think of along those lines then
what you have is a PVC that wants to be
populated the creator of that PVC is
going to reference one of the custom
resource objects in a field called the
data source and all it is is a local
object reference and that's it then the
user posts that to the cluster you then
have a populate or controller which is
sitting there just like all the other
controllers watching for objects it
discovers the PVC being created and it
looks determines that the type of the
data source reference is one that it can
handle so then it takes charge kicks off
the process which is really just
spawning a pod like we kind of talked
about was I guess that was option 2
spawning a pod that it knows how to
spawn attaching the PVC where the
population gets performed so if we stick
with a standard approach like this it's
going to give us a really great
opportunity to collaborate as a
community add those features we were
talking about where we're all sharing
all that good stuff in terms of having a
robust solution that has the features
everybody wants so that's kind of what
the idea is I'm going to try now to show
you a demonstration of it
so what I have here on screen it's a
little bit off but it's a kubernetes
cluster running here in a VM on my
laptop and so the next thing I'm going
to do is prepare the cluster a little
bit and so we're making sure the
clusters up and then we're going to add
some persistent storage to it using
local storage yeah give me just one
second yeah I can try that
yeah
okay I'm terrible with these trackpads
how is that are we getting okay alright
so this did a few things we created some
persistent storage and then because I
didn't want to rely on the FOSDEM famous
wireless network I created my own get
server inside of the cluster so that
this my laptops in airplane mode so we
pushed some data to that git repository
and then I started up a popular
controller which is now running at the
bottom here so that's kind of the the
cluster setup now let's go kind of to
the persona of the user and what we're
gonna do is add some objects to the
cluster so the first thing is the
populate objects so you can see what
these look like these are to get
populated they're almost the same the
first one is requesting a checkout of
the master branch and the second one is
requesting a check out of the v10 branch
so let's add those
okay so those have been added to the
cluster now let's take a look at a PV C
so we can start to populate okay so this
is a pretty basic looking PV C there is
the data source field and we're just
referencing the master populate er and
it has a kind and an API group so that's
just how a local object reference works
in kubernetes and we're just asking for
a hundred megabytes of storage so I am
going to create that okay so now let's
see how that's going
woops so we have a we have a bound PVC
and we have a job that has already run
by the popular controller to to do the
population according to the request so
now I'm just going to show you this
little app that we have it's going to
bounce off the screen a little bit but
we have an engine X container it's using
the PVC being mounted at the place where
nginx by default looks for web content
and then a service so that we can see it
on a browser so let's just create that
app notice how the app doesn't know
anything about any kind of population
it's just expecting to have a PVC okay
so let's go we've created that app let's
see if we can take a look at it okay so
it's just a basic super exciting website
that has some content in it let's see
what happens if we adopt the 100 branch
so first I'm going to clean up that
instance of the app ok and then that's
going to take just a second here
okay and then and there's just a little
bit of aggressive cleanup and now let's
take a look at the v10 PVC it's exactly
the same except for the local object
reference here I'll bump it up a little
higher is now the v1 populate er so
let's do that
- F PVC v1 and let's get the PVC to make
sure it's bound and I did the same type
of again and get the job okay so we have
a completed job again for the different
type of populate er and now let's create
the app and let's see if anything
changed much better okay so so we have
alright ten minutes so we basically what
I've shown here is that in a way that is
completely and unknown to the app itself
and its configuration done population
behind the scenes I will note it's
obvious when you're shipping web content
in kubernetes it's typically in the
docker container so this is a bit of a
contrived example but one that's pretty
visible on screen for you guys to look
at so that's why I did it that way so
let's talk about declarative again
because what you did not see was a
declarative API yet and the reason is is
that there's a promise that you make
when you're doing something declarative
which is if the object has a state on it
let PVC is a has a data source reference
kubernetes must promise as I say here
that a pod won't be allowed to run with
that PVC until it's in fact populated
otherwise somebody's not telling the
truth and things aren't working
correctly so how are we gonna actually
make that happen you notice that I kind
of populated the PVC and I said let's
spawn the app but typically you would
have the pvc declared with its data
source and the app all put together and
one deployment so in order to make that
work we're gonna reuse a concept that's
already employed in kubernetes today
called
taints and toleration x' and this is
actually invented to for use with nodes
and pods or you could taint a node so
that pods wouldn't necessarily run on
that node unless you wanted them to but
we are going to instead of apply it to
PVCs and pods and so what happens is a
taint gets applied to the PVC when it's
posted to the cluster if it has a data
source reference so that's all done by
an admission controller as part of
kubernetes the effect of that are what
it actually means is that this PVC needs
to be populated before it's generally
usable so there's kind of a problem with
it if you will what happens is regular
pods now that are referencing it like
that nginx app you saw would not be able
to start what with that taint on it so
they would just wait but then the
popular controller is still detecting
the PVC and it wants to populate it so
it's going to spawn a pod that has a
Toleration which says I'm gonna tolerate
the empty PVC because I'm gonna fill it
in and then that will schedule find the
population hopefully completes correctly
then the populated controller removes
the taint from the PVC and everything's
ready to go so it's all orchestrated and
managed by kubernetes itself so the next
steps for us along the lines of this
idea are first to allow custom resources
in the PVC data source field they're not
allowed yet because that feature was
actually designed to create volumes from
snapshots and to create volumes from
other volumes so clones so we're going
to extend it we need to do the PVC taint
sin toleration x' that's already been
the under discussion in the community
and in progress and then the last thing
that we want to do is create a
repository where we can have an example
populate ur and
example see ours may be like with this
get repo one and some others to begin
the process of collaborating with people
so that we can get get a library of
these going some of the other examples
of things you can do you've seen the git
repo
I've talked several times about HTTP
import using kubernetes secrets you
could really do something cool with this
which is to clone an existing PVC if
your if your storage can't do it behind
the scenes you can do a host assisted
clone how that would work is a populated
controller would spawn a pod that
actually attaches to both PVCs and then
just copies from one to another upload
is even more kind of crazy and
interesting but rather than using cube
CTL CP to put data into the cluster you
can have an upload proxy server that
listens and when an authenticated
request comes in via the kubernetes api
to that it can actually forward the data
to a pod that's running that happens to
be attached to a PVC and then proxy the
data in so you could support direct
uploads to your cluster this is
something we're actually already doing
in a project called the containerized
data importer which I'll link to in a
minute here so you can actually try that
out in its current form and then restore
from backup is here again if you're a
backup vendor and you have specific
logic on how to pull data out of your
backup back-end you could write a
populate earth at then puts that into
the PVC so that's all I have
here's the link to the containerized
data importer it's part of the Qbert
project as well so this is kind of the
grandfather to these ideas that were
pushing up into the community of
kubernetes trying to get some
generalized traction on it so I think I
have a few minutes for questions yeah go
ahead
[Music]
so the question is is when would we
expect taints and toleration x' for pvcs
to hit upstream so I guess we're
designing it now
I would hope by like kubernetes 114 it's
it's not super complex and it's an
existing concept that everyone gets so
it should be pretty easy to get going
through but that's a dangerous thing to
say with the kubernetes community so
we'll see anything else yeah go ahead
so the question is are we leveraging a
pre-existing field in the PVC in order
to make this work and the answer to that
is yes in fact we were part of the group
participating in the snapshots and
cloning features and so we this has been
kind of a long time coming and we chose
this general purposed way of describing
this concept of this PVC should have
something in it and we want to describe
that declaratively any other questions
am I missing anyone all right I guess
not so thanks a lot guys
[Applause]