all right hello everybody I'm Christine
flood everybody's talked about how long
they worked on Java
I started in 1998 working for Sun
Microsystems I worked on the first
production quality JVM called exact VM
which was back before there was even a
hot spot
so there are my credentials I'm here to
talk to you about fast startup for Java
applications I work for Red Hat and I
work in the Linux echo system and people
were saying well ghost starts up really
fast and and Java is too slow so I
started thinking about what we could do
to make Java start up faster and
checkpoint restore was a clear solution
in my mind so what do I mean by
checkpoint restore you have your Java VM
you've loaded all your classes you've
warmed up your JIT you've run some
sample things you've got everything the
way you want it to run quickly and
you've read a couple of GC so you've got
your heap as tight as possible what you
do then is you run the checkpoint and
that rates out the state of your JVM to
the file system now I want to be clear
here this is not object serialization
this is more of a bit blit right it's a
bulk copy of the memory out to disk so
it can be quickly copied and quickly
restored so another thing that's cool is
once you have those JVM image files
you're not limited to restoring it once
so let's say you have an application
that has a you know a large startup time
you can build it up write out an image
and then later on when you're running it
you can say hey I'm going to run it here
here here and here so this is another
way to deploy your Java applications
it's not quite as pretty as write once
run everywhere was but it gives us the
ability to come up very quickly with a
hot JVM that has all of the capabilities
that you expect from open JDK that has
the dynamic class loading it has
everything that you could want and it's
all right there and available so another
use case I had to bring this up right
I'm not the first person to talk about
doing this for Java IBM had a paper on
it inria had a couple of papers on it
I'm just doing it a quick and dirty way
which I'll get to in
but let's say you're running some sort
of long-running number-crunching
application on java maybe you don't want
that to crash and I'll go away so you
can checkpoint every iteration and then
if you do have an unfortunate crash you
can just restore from the last working
iteration and keep going or that's
another application you can replay the
crash if you have a crash that you know
happens every iteration you can save the
world right before the crash happens and
then rather than having to wait 10 hours
for your machine to get back into the
crash state you can bring it up
immediately at the bug State alright so
let me be clear here I'm not proposing
anything heroic when IBM and in Oriya
did it they started from the JVM and
they wanted to work all of the JVM data
structures I want to do something quick
and dirty there's already utility out
there in the Linux world creo and that
does the heavy lifting for us today
without me doing anything I can
checkpoint and restore well they can
checkpointing restore Linux process I
can checkpoint and restore most Java
processes without any additions to the
JVM so checkpoint restore in userspace
it's Linux utility I'll go into a little
bit more detail about how it works later
it handles a lot of the things you
wouldn't expect it to like files and
sockets pretty much all of the hairy
stuff it can do and if you want to read
more about it you can read it there and
there's there are people here that
actually work on creo I don't know if
they're in the room right now but there
are people here at FOSDEM so this is
used mostly for process migration the
DevOps folks who want to move on a
process somewhere else quick process
spin up which is why I got interested
container migration so the other reason
I got interested is because I'm old and
I used to work on lists machines a long
time ago and I really miss being able to
save the world
imagine you have a read eval print loop
and you've done some stuff and you've
got your state where you think you want
it you can save the state of that world
and then you can do some more changes
and if they don't work you can come back
to where you were they also had the
ability to do in
incremental builds right so if you do
that save the world once do some stuff
save the world again you don't have to
copy the whole memory stayed out you
only have to copy the stuff that's
changed since the last time you did it
and that is extremely powerful so okay
so most of this is already there in creo
why are we talking about having a Java
API and that's because there are some
things we as JVM guys can see as
potential opportunities for this if we
had a Java API one example is let's say
you wanted to save the world well you
could do a full compaction of your heap
and get it all the way down you know if
it was 64 gigabytes but you did have two
full GCS you got it all copied out and
you got it down to two gigabytes that
way we can give memory back to the OS
and then when we write it out we don't
have to worry about all that space it'll
make it faster to copy it out to disk
and make it faster if you want to
transfer it across the network and
hopefully make it faster to restore as
well okay so I'm a GC weeny right and
I've worked on a lot of garbage
collector so I see this and the first
thing I see is a GC optimization that we
can do so you have your Java process
you're building up all of your data
structures you're running parallel GC
and you're getting rid of stuff but then
it's time to checkpoint it and hey
wouldn't it be cool if we went in and we
got rid of parallel GC and we put in
epsilon GC they do nothing garbage
collector we could get rid of your card
tables we could get rid of the card mark
in your card table to just maintain your
card tables and so when you went and you
actually restored this thing and ran it
if you're doing something quick and
dirty like you know function as a
service or something like that you now
have less space you have faster runtime
because you don't have the card marks
and life is good
and that is totally doable if you have
any questions or if you doubt me please
speak up there was a really fascinating
paper at PL di a few years ago on remix
and they paid attention to the hardware
counters to see when they got you know
cache thrashing and they were able to
pad their data structures this is the
kind of thing that you know I was a
little skeptical of I mean they showed
good results on some benchmarks but I
can believe that there are times where
this would slow you down
and the good thing about checkpoint and
restore is you can do this kind of work
while you're doing the build up phase
because that's the time it's not the
time critical so if you want to monitor
performance counters and do things like
this you can and then later on you know
at the restore time you'll have
something faster all right so there's
also some JVM specific parameters that
we're going to need to restore if we
want this to work right right things get
cached in the JVM and some of them are
cached in in clear places like the
number of available processors things
like that you're going to want to fix
those right if you save it on an a
processor machine you restore it on a
two processor machine you're probably
going to want to do a little bit of
cleanup also you know if you have eight
garbage collection threads in the first
one and you're restoring it over here
you might want to think about tuning it
to the machine you're actually running
on so we probably this is another reason
why we want to have control in the Java
world of some of the things when we do
the restore secure network connections
and handshakes I don't know for sure the
creo handles at all properly I'm hoping
to talk to the creo guy later today but
I suspect there's some stuff that we're
going to want to do when we restore the
JVM to make sure they're right maybe we
want to bring your work-stealing cues to
quiescence right if we want to we want
to get everything to a sane state before
we checkpoint it maybe we want to get
rid of your work still in queues and
recreate them one startup and maybe you
want to specify one check pointing a
curse right you can do this from Linux
from outside of the JVM but maybe then
you're getting the JVM in a state where
it's got a lot of garbage and it's
inconsistent if we control it from
inside of Java so you've got a loop it
creates a lot of garbage you get to the
end of the loop and all of that garbage
can go away it's all temporary maybe
that's where you want to be doing your
safe points and having an API to Java
allows the Java programmer to have
control over when that happens so have I
given you motivation that we need to be
able to do this from inside of Java is
anybody buying what I'm selling ok so I
have a proposed API for Java and this is
not set in stone this is
okay so I have just this is from my head
what I would like to see so I'm open for
people to come up and talk to me about
where I'm wrong or what else we need to
that we don't have but we want to be
able to check the world that's obvious
we want to know that we're running on an
appropriate Linux kernel that can do
this I have no plans as of yet to do it
for Solaris or any other operating
system I don't know what's what what
tools are there and what aren't but
that's the thing that you have to do
before you do it to make sure it's there
save the world we'll save the world
exactly the way you're currently running
so we're not going to do anything clever
we're just going to save it out so you
can get back to that bug that you had
save the world incremental gives you the
ability to do a faster save world
because you're only saving the bits of
change save the world with epsilon G see
whether that belongs there or not I
don't know but that was one of my use
cases so I put it up there optimize the
world so we can run back-to-back full
GCS we can optimize the memory layout I
don't know what else can go in there
right it's it's this big open question
of what could we do you can restore the
world obviously and maybe even migrate
the world like I said this isn't set in
stone this is just what I'm thinking
about right now I welcome any and all
feedback except from Alexa okay so
what's the current status I have a
prototype that uses J and I just so I
could play with it I don't have
everything I can check the world I can
save the world and I can restore the
world from the command line and I'll get
into a little bit later why it's hard to
restore the world from Java right now
but it shows the cria works and it does
what we want to do test random is one of
my other things I like is random numbers
so this generates a whole bunch of
random numbers and bends them into
different bins and so we do the setup
where we do all the random number
generation in the binning and then we
save the world and then when we restore
the world it just gives us the output of
what the bidding was it tells us the
data the information about the data this
is sort of the use case that I'm
envisioning for the
is that you have some big setup phase
that generates a lot of garbage and then
you have some small fast thing that runs
afterwards and this just shows that you
know we we ran our big program we had
Java running we dumped it out
we have no java running and we restored
it and it all works so this is just to
show that this does work for Java which
was one of my first concerns and yes I
have I have restored multiple the same
store JVM multiple times with no
problems I ran a little prototype that
called it from Java there are some
things here that surprised me and it
shouldn't have I'm feeling kind of
stupid about that but I'll print it out
here so I wanted to time the first step
in time the second step and I did the
first step on Monday and the second step
on Tuesday and it said that it took 25
hours so that's one of the things if you
cache variables like the current time in
milliseconds it's the current time from
before you check pointed it checkpoint
restore this is actually interesting
thing which is where you call save the
world and you can sort of think of that
like a fork you have an option of what
you do next you can keep running your
java program or you can stop it either
way and so that's just gives you an idea
of what it what checkpoint we store
check the world save the world save the
world twice that stuff all works now
alright so how does creo work under the
covers because if you're skeptical like
it I am you want to know at some point
in time this is what your Java process
look like it's changed since then I
think but you have some GC threads some
compiler threads some Java threads I'm
not going to talk about all those all
I'm gonna say is that they are all
mirrored in the /proc hierarchy so
anything I can do for the Java pit I can
do for all of the sub kids and that's
the last time I'm going to talk about
the sub kids alright so the kre-o
process is really cool it calls it's
built on top of P trace and it causes a
cease that seizes the Java process and
stops it and of course this is recursive
and it's it it seizes all of the threads
under the Java process it then inserts
some parasite code into the Java process
and this code now runs with all of the
permissions that the Java process had so
it can it can do anything that you have
a process could do so one thing that is
is that it can copy all the virtual
memory right and this is from s Maps so
it can copy all of the contents of all
your auxilary data structures
this was my heap all of these things get
copied out to the file system and it's
bit bloated it's very fast and you have
map files and those all get copied over
there too because there's in somewhere
else in the proc structure and so on
basically the file descriptor numbers
the core parameters everything can get
access to everything it can get access
to the registers and the trap and the
stack using pete ray speak user I don't
know if anybody out here ever programmed
a trs-80 I did and peek and poke were
really cool way back then so having peek
user is very nostalgic for me
the parasite code can read like I said
it operates with all the permissions of
the Java process then they can use the
pee trace code to clean up the parasite
code to restore the original code and
your Java process can just keep going
and it detaches and we go on the reverse
is pretty much an inverse except that
the kre-o process morphs itself into the
Java process which I thought was pretty
cool if you have any questions or if you
have any ideas I'm hoping open to
questions now but if you want to contact
me later
CHF at read Hakam and I'd love to hear
from you yes I don't have that timing in
front of me the question was how long
does it take to take to get a snapshot
I haven't worried about that the restore
process is very fast but I don't have
the numbers in front of me we are kind
of trying to optimize the restore
process is there a reason why you would
want to optimize the checkpointing
process
that is an awesome idea
what's your name Sonny I will give you
credit for that idea I think that's an
excellent use case and I will look into
it
the question was how long does it take
to take a to check point your Java
program and I haven't worried about that
because I assumed that it didn't matter
but he wants a heap to heap dump and
that takes too long so if I can do a
check point faster than he can do a heap
dump he's gonna be happy with me yes how
do you handle file descriptors during
restore time when the files are not
there anymore on another machine that's
an excellent question and I defer to
crea to do that I know that they have
done it and in the worst case scenario
if they don't do it then you have to run
your java in a container but I don't
know I think it's oh thank you if the
files are on the destination system I
know they accrue you will abort the
restore it will just not work the files
need to be there need to be at least the
same size because crea wants to read at
the position the process used to read
and it's it makes sense to have the same
files there because else you get
something else back or your right to the
wrong location
are there any other questions yes back
there I suppose already had to wait for
the mic so when we spin the process back
up again
certain VM structures like the runtime
thread pools are going to be dependent
on things like the number of CPUs in the
machine so if you go from a larger
machine to a smaller one
you risk crunching the destination
machine
because it's now got a very large VM
thread pool that's what I said that
that's why I think we need a java
restore process the Java restore process
is going to have to be smart about some
things
and the number of processors on the
machine the size of the heap things like
that the restore process is going to
have to be smart about or there's got to
be an interface to let the drive a
developer tell the restored processor
the you know I want this you know I want
these particular parameters so have you
given thought about how to handle random
numbers and other stuff that's required
for security or certificates or some
secure stuff generation cuz it might get
check point and then it comes becomes
predictable at the next startup that's a
great question I will add that to my
list what's your name you okay thank you
are there any other questions or any
other things I missed and software
development by committee I love this yes
it does not need root access because it
goes in as the it has the same
permission well
cRIO process needs root access but
that's already in there the it goes in
has the permissions of the java vm yes
if I can condense that small talk did
everything first and they did it better
I didn't want to turn out that way are
you also credited the things that small
talk stole which was the snapshot from
the list machine which I had next to me
running while I was developing these
snapshots there for small talk so Lisp
did it first no small taking
credit here just to be clear which I
would did it last however I don't know
we're not done yet
are there any other questions or
comments yes so monotonic monotonic time
is indeed a problem with process
migration and container migration and
yes our currently discussions for a new
Linux kernel night namespace for time
clock monotonic but this is nothing
there yet it's still under discussion
but it's a no known problem with and
process migration yes all right I don't
know how much time we have are we
worried there's a question way in the
back so you can run it's great that I
get to tell him what to do for once
so as I understand your primary use case
is to restore the original process on
the original machine from a snapshot but
I can also imagine that you want to like
warm up the JVM and warm up the process
and then scale it to a number of
different systems but then the file
handles as you mentioned before becomes
a problem and also network socket so is
there any plans to go in that direction
I'm sure that once this spins up right
now ok I used to work in Sun labs and
I'm not a very practical person I want
to prove that it's pragmatic and that we
can do it but there are details like
that that are going to need to be worked
out in a long-term if people want to
want it to just work for Java I
acknowledge that but I think this is
cool and I think it's worth talking
about and getting getting spun up and I
hope you guys agree are we anywhere else
are we done I think we're done thank you
Thank You Christine
you