right good morning everybody I'm not
sure that I've ever seen 9:00 a.m. at
FOSDEM so thank you all for coming to
talk about every developers favorite
topic I know licensing and I have never
been able to participate in the
JavaScript room here before so when I
thank the organizers for having me and
giving me the opportunity to to talk
about and I didn't know that the opening
keynote in advance was going to start
this topic going but that's as the
introduction said I've set things up for
us to talk here today I'm the executive
director at the Free Software Foundation
I've actually worked at the foundation
since 2003 and different capacities I've
been the executive director there since
2011 and as part of that I work with all
the different teams with the FSF
including the technical team with our
students administrators and web
developer and our licensing staff as
well so try to help them work together
to advance the up steps interests and
freedom for the web and elsewhere so
I've talked about this topic in
licensing focus settings before I've
never talked about it in the JavaScript
developer focus setting before so
definitely a big part of what I'm here
for today is to hear back from you at
the end about whether what I'm
presenting here it makes any sense at
all from your perspective and then if
you know possibly other ways where we
could accomplish the same goals
besides the system that I'm going to
present here so try to save some time at
the end for that and if we don't get you
your ideas then please do your follow up
with me afterward either by email or
I'll be around the conference the rest
of the day of course so at the free
software foundation our goal is to not
just make free software better but to
make all free stall software free
software so in our perfect world there's
no proprietary software it's all free so
of course we have the problem right now
that was mentioned in the keynote
yesterday we have now laptops and
desktop workstations that run all free
software require no proprietary drivers
or price hairy blobs even the boot for
we're on this laptop is free software
and the FSF has certified machines that
meet those criteria under our respects
for freedom program but despite the fact
that we might run one of these systems
were asked to run non-free software and
in fact are running down free software
still everyday and the main way that
happens is by proprietary JavaScript
being delivered to the user in the web
browser and so Richard Stallman called
this the JavaScript trap and an article
that he published in 2009 which was
referring to his 2004 article back when
Java was proprietary and that it was the
Java trap I don't think I have to tell
you all that javascript is basically an
assumption on the web now you can't do
much of anything if you turn it off or
block it mozilla in 2013 removed the
option that had been there you know for
a long time for users to disable
javascript and I understood that wasn't
happy about that but I understood why
they did it because users were
unchecking that box and then reporting
all sorts of bugs that were happening
when sites weren't working properly not
realizing that they had disabled
javascript but it's just an indication
of how required in this theorem
javascript on the web is now at the up
stuff we don't want to avoid all
JavaScript of course we only want to
avoid proprietary JavaScript so this
isn't necessarily a problem for freedom
reasons people might object to it for
accessibility or other reasons but for
freedom reasons not necessarily a
problem as long as the JavaScript that's
required is actually free
unfortunately JavaScript programs are
generally not free and in particular
they're not free as they're typically
distributed to the user so we know
there's all kinds of very popular free
software JavaScript frameworks out there
where the site operator or the web
developer can get a copy of jQuery it's
free software but the way that these
programs are then served to the user in
their browser doesn't meet the
requirements of free software even if
that software is available elsewhere
under a free license so what do I need
by that the two basic requirements for
something to be free software you have
to tell you
it's free software in some fashion
because otherwise around the world
the default copyright is all rights
reserved and so its proprietary by
default if there's no notice to the
contrary and then you also have to
provide the complete and corresponding
source code so we know that permissive
license is like the expat license allow
commonly called the MIT license allow
people to redistribute that software in
binary form if they want to they're
allowed to do that out of the license
but if that's how they do it
then that's not free software it's
pretty software if the source code still
comes with it
so failure to do these two things is
alright that are the reasons why most
JavaScript is not free so we know
minified javascript it's not really
source code that's not the preferred
form for modification it's not quite as
difficult to work with as a true binary
but it's essentially the same thing if
you are debugging something or trying to
make a modification minified javascript
is not gonna do you any favors so
because minified because people serve
javascript minified and for all the
performance reasons that they typically
do that means they're not normally
giving users the source form which means
it's not free software this hurts users
we shouldn't wait for proprietary
software so we're talking about sort of
two different cases here it should be
clear about that one I would call kind
of the unintentionally non free case and
these are the cases where people are
trying to use a free software JavaScript
framework or if we suffer JavaScript but
they're just not giving users the source
and they're not providing clear license
notice that's one category the other
category is JavaScript that's
deliberately proprietary so things like
Google Analytics or you know the
JavaScript for Gmail or Google Docs that
javascript is intentionally not free
right so it's important to keep these
two different cases in mind in the
second case we know from the history of
free software versus proprietary
software all the terrible things that
can happen to people as a result of
proprietary software the same things can
happen
as a result of protect provider
JavaScript that happened as a result of
proprietary C or Python or anything else
we have an unfortunately expanding
collection on Georg and slash philosophy
slap Riya Terry of all these examples
not just JavaScript other things as well
so if you're ever trying to explain to
somebody why prior Terry's software it's
harmful that's a good resource run
through these quickly because I know
you're all familiar with the fact that
JavaScript can do these things but you
know we know that JavaScript can modify
the calculation so you user might think
they're copying something and then they
paste it into their terminal and it's RN
- RS and there you go block browser
functions like saving images sort of the
poor person's DRM record your keystrokes
this is one that a lot of people don't
realize gotten a little bit of press
there was kind of a story about how
Facebook was recording what users were
typing even if they didn't post it in
the end but also another story recently
about how customer service online chat
typically actually shows your keystrokes
to the representative on the other side
without telling you that and then we
know that JavaScript can be used of
course to deliver malware was in the
browser and there was one example some
years ago that was used to exploit swore
but it's also the other side it's not
just about avoiding attacks or
mistreatment or malware it's about
enabling the power of free software on
the web just as we've you know had that
power and that dynamic in that culture
before before javascript was such a
popular thing on the web on your own
system I know there's you know this
all's kind of started with grease monkey
I think and then I turned into several
different sites repositories where
people are sharing JavaScript that can
modify the behavior of different popular
sites you know do different cool things
in the browser open user GS there's one
that I know of and they're actually seem
to be making like a pretty strong effort
to license the job and make sure all the
JavaScript there is actually freely
licensed which was nice to see but you
know the point is we're trying to not
just stop the negative effects the
proprietary JavaScript but also trying
to sort of move to a new model of the
web that embraces user freedom to modify
the VA
year of you know what a site hacks in
their browser with the cooperation of
the site operator and everybody involves
so if we're going to do that we have to
meet the basic requirements for a free
software so we have to provide source
this is the system that the FSF has
developed its called we call it
JavaScript web labels and I'm gonna walk
through the different components of that
the first is a stylized comment to
include in your JavaScript files to
point to the source URL and it's our you
know we've stated publicly that we
believe doing the following things will
be in compliance with the gyoji piell's
requirements your distributed source
code so now we've had a particular
challenge with copyleft and GPL cover
javascript because if you read the
requirements in a certain way you might
think that you have to distribute the
copy of a full copy of the GPL with
every javascript file that you serve to
a user and that can be you know possibly
pretty burdensome and also you know how
do you properly serve or offer the
source code to the user in order to meet
the GPL requirements so these source
courts or comment formats work for that
and then after that indicate the license
of the JavaScript code and we have a
couple of two different ways of doing
that the first way is actually embedding
the we're putting the license notice in
the file using a comment of that format
of course if you're the copyright holder
of JavaScript you can actually use a
license exception to make this even
easier for other people so using gplv3
additional permission feature you can
distribute non source you can add a
additional permission worded like this
you made should be non source eg
minimize or compacted forms of this code
without the copy of again your GPL
normally required by section 4 provided
you include this license notice and a
URL through which recipients can access
the corresponding source so if you're
the copyright holder of JavaScript that
you wrote then you have the power to add
an additional permission see the license
you of course can't do that if you're
modifying somebody else's JavaScript
under a free license because you have to
have their permission in order to change
the license terms but this is a clean
way to handle it if you're the copyright
holder because it leaves no doubt about
the GPL requirements for providing the
copy of license and the corresponding
source lets people know that they can
it's ok for them to not distribute the
copy of the license and as long as they
provide a link to the source code but
you're probably not the copyright holder
for most of the JavaScript that you're
working with this format was actually
announced all the way back in 2012 we're
going to talk about how it's doing since
then the full description of it is and
slash licenses javascript - labels and
you knew that org the goal of the system
is twofold first of all it's to be
machine readable so that it can be read
licensing information can be read and
processed by browser extensions or or
server tools but the second thing is it
really does need to be human readable if
you think - the GPL is basic requirement
for most free software licenses basic
requirement that you you need to tell
the person of what they're receiving is
free software you want to it's that you
need to inform them of the rights they
have over the software
so this isn't strictly a
machine-readable format it's something
that humans are supposed to be able to
you read and understand as well so it
starts with adding a link and the
somewhere on the site typically on the
footer with other copyright information
this is def step toward link called
JavaScript licenses when you follow that
link sorry you mark that link with an
attribute re l equals J s license that's
part of the machine readable automated
tool portion so this is just this is
part of the approach because it means
that any page the user loads there's a
standard place a standard link that
should lead to the licensing information
that link leads to something that looks
like this it's a simple HTML table a
specific format the you have the file
that's being served to the user so for
example the minified version in the
center you have the license and at the
end you have the source of corresponding
source
it shows you the format of the table so
table columns are given specific IDs
again to facilitate the processing by
tooling I showed you FSF to start with
of course but it has been adopted by and
some other organizations and some other
sites I'm gonna talk more about how that
adoption is going in a minute but just
to show an example from Electronic
Frontier Foundation it's pretty cool of
it
they picked it up and started doing it
they're very supportive of free software
obviously generally for their work but
they went out of their way to make sure
that they adopted this as well for the
JavaScript that they were using I think
this is a screenshot of their old site
but I confirmed last night that it's
still there when after they went through
their site redesign they still have it
in effect they have a lot of their
JavaScript licensed under the a GPL
which I thought was excellent
so automation based on this format you
could imagine any number of tools that
did interesting things with it but the
one that we focused on is called guinea
leaver j/s it's a Gideon project it's a
browser plugin for Mozilla based
browsers that looks for this format and
licensing information on sites when you
visit them and if it doesn't find it it
blocks the proprietary JavaScript on the
page so it looks for that web labels
information and for any JavaScript that
has the corresponding source link and a
corresponding license that's free and
that has a system for recognizing noises
and licenses it will allow that
JavaScript through and anything else
that was blocked people don't know
script right so to gently block all
JavaScript but this is a different more
targeted approach so like I said
happened in 2012 that we started pushing
for this how's it going I would have to
say not that good why well some of the
reasons are a bit mundane so Weber
jeaious is a piece of software for
a long period of time was not working
very well and it was hard for us to
persuade people to adopt a particular
format that has you know the aims of
being machine readable and and useful
without any corresponding you know
high-functioning tool to actually use
that format and you got people that are
operating and taking care of big sites
with a lot of JavaScript a lot of pages
you know you can't give them a tool to
go through and test the site it becomes
quite a bit of work for them to go
through and make sure that everything is
done properly and according with the
format by hand then there were the
updates to the mozilla extension system
which broke libre JS further so it took
us too long to react to this and catch
up to it
the good news is that there was
rewritten and from all reports that's
now working pretty well there were also
some performance issues with it you know
it's trying to go through every
javascript file and see what the
licenses and so it would have to do that
for every you know file before letting
the page proceed there's been a lot of
performance improvements I encourage you
to try it out and give us some feedback
on it and there are still further
challenges coming the changes that
Google was talking about making through
the Chrome extension system the API will
basically make plugins like this almost
impossible maybe impossible because
they're taking away the ability for
plugins to modify the content on the
page it's also going to cause problems
for no script and a lot of other plugins
that people have come to rely on so
imagine people might be wondering why
didn't she do it some other way and I'm
hoping to hear some of your ideas for
how licensing information to be
presented that satisfies those two goals
of machine readable and human readable
we do not claim this to be the one true
method we didn't go through a big public
public comment or kind of standards
development process in order to come up
with this we wanted to get something out
there to start with because this problem
even in 2012 was so bad for free
software and it's only gotten worse
since then but you know plugins like
labor to ask it
support multiple systems and there's no
reason why you can't have multiple
systems there's no reason why we can't
you know experiment with some different
ones and settle on another one I know
there's been some proposals using rbf's
I'm using HTTP headers or getting
attributes like for licensing tags added
to the script elements itself or using
custom attributes or I think there's the
potential maybe with JavaScript source
maps I saw that great news the other day
that Ruby on Rails is going to be
turning source Maps on by default so I
think there are some potential there but
you know we're not going to wait for the
perfect system to keep pushing forward
ways to tell people through javascript
in a free way and help users receive it
their free way so it's point to some
next steps Libre jeaious improvements I
mentioned that a lot of them have
happens
it was the giorgio the author of no
script to helped us get that done but
there are more things that need to be
done we all have more wish list and
feature requests for it mobile devices
you know the primary way people browse
the web now the good news about this is
I'm open you know fingers crossed that
we will have an Android version
available within the next few months
that will work with Firefox or icecat or
any mozilla-based browser on Android it
won't be on the iPhone because the app
store is not very friendly to free
software then the next step after that
for us is to have a command line or
automated testing version of Libra j/s
so even for us at the FSF it's kind of a
problem we work really hard to maintain
clear licensing information for our
JavaScript but we also use you know
upstream platforms we use Drupal we use
sippy CRM we use media wiki and anytime
there's a change or an upgrade
sometimes the web label system breaks
there's new JavaScript or something
changes and you know we don't
necessarily find out about that unless
we manually check it or somebody reports
the problems to us so we know that
something that people realistically need
in order to actually adopt this is an
automated way to test it an easy way
without browsing to every individual
page on your site
that's the next priority after the
mobile version something that I'm hoping
people in this room might have ideas
about to be able to help with is how to
modify or make you know the right
sensible defaults or features in the
tool chains and the tooling that are
popularly used in the JavaScript
community to make a format like this for
minify javascript kind of just happen
automatically or you know other ways the
tooling could be modified in order to do
better at providing licensing
information that links the corresponding
source code and then you know we we
can't just demand that upstream projects
make changes in order to you know fix
licensing information if we want that we
want to help them and that's something
that we have done at the FSF we've sent
some patches upstream so I think
etherpad and some other projects to help
the labor jeaious or sorry the web
labels and jobs the placement
information get upstream you know you
can imagine there's a lot of projects
that if I started doing that there and
such white use it would make just a huge
difference on so many different sites
where those frameworks or those
platforms are being used they would be
properly free right out of the box and
then we need on the user side we
awareness campaigns you know both sides
user and the site operator side we need
awareness campaigns in a friendly way
especially because when I mention those
two problem areas the you know the
intentionally non-free but also the
unintentionally non-free especially in
that case with unintentional when you
take a very friendly approach and a
constructive approach but emphasize the
importance of this that this is software
that's running on our local machine and
needs to be free just like any other
software that we run locally so I would
love to hear your feedback your ideas or
comments about this has anybody in the
room tried adding web labels to their
site before we got one yeah a lot of
people think about that method of
providing license information
so we're to link to the standard license
suffice instead of putting a lot of text
and a comment
the only texts that we're recommending
so two things you don't need the comment
in the file if you're using the web
label system so if you have that
separate table that provides the
correspondence between the file the
license and the source code then you
don't need to add anything else to the
file
you only need to comment in the file if
you're not doing the full web label
system but even if you're putting the
comment in the file what we're
encouraging people to do is just to put
that basic statement about the license
and the file there like the short
version of the GPL boilerplate for
example that you typically see in a
source file because link to the license
isn't really doing a great job of
telling the user what you know at least
the summary that this is pretty software
and you can freely copy and share it
modify it so that's nice to have there
but you don't need to worry about it all
if you do the web labels
[Applause]