okay hello everybody
I believe it's about time to start right
thanks for coming to this talk if I'm
not speaking loud enough or if you don't
understand or if you disagree please
feel free to interrupt me at any time so
this will be something like a crossover
talk between a microkernel Deb room
which has it has been organized by by us
or somebody else from the microkernel
community for several years here and the
the risk five Hardware stuff so let me
just briefly speak about myself so I'm
I'm an operating system guy I would say
I'm a microkernel guy I've been working
on the development of Helen OS for many
years I have been working on a formal
verification of Helen OS as part of my
research employments at Charles Oni with
University in Prague and quite recently
I have switched to industry working on
microkernels at wale so what the hell is
one of us if you don't know how an OS is
an open-source general-purpose
multi-platform microkernel multi server
operating system designed and
implemented from scratch so these are
you know the buzzwords very quickly it's
not a Linux distribution or a BSD clone
or something like that it's our own
microkernel design our own user space
built on top of it I have a look on the
on the website if you are interested
it's an open source project obviously
otherwise I wouldn't be even speaking
here we are not targeting embedded we
are not targeting real-time we are not
targeting servers we are not are getting
this clips we are targeting everything
so it's a general purpose operating
system and somehow we have this
tradition of you know implementing you
know rather in the breadth-first manner
of them than depth first manner
we support these hardware architectures
I would say we support them properly so
we really try to make the the codebase
very portable only about I would say 5%
of the source code who decides of the
source code is platform dependent
otherwise do I really think it's
partially independent and this is the
reason why I'm talking about the risk
risk 5 and porting how long has to risk
5 the multi server keyword means that
it's a microkernel so the kernel
component is small it just does what
would the colonel shoot should do and
the user space cannot but also the arc
the software architecture of the user
space is very modular very fine grains
so we don't have huge monolithic
components even in in user space we have
very small components and each each of
the component is doing just one thing
and we have some guiding principles that
we base our software architecture on
again if you are interested please ask
me offline and I will I will be more
than happy to explain to you in detail
so reserve like five six hours for that
this is a screen shot originally I
figured that I was would not be able to
connect my laptop to this to this magic
casting box but I can even show you show
you actual demo so so this is this is
not on risk 5 this is how I know is
running on on x86 or AMD 64 so do you
get a normal bootloader
now the the microkernel is booting and
this is the user space environment so
you can see that it's relatively
feature-rich we have our own graphical
user interface you can you can move
windows you can you can make you can
rotate them if I find the right right ok
you can resize
I don't I don't remember or air you can
rotate them and stuff like that there
are already something like 45 tasks or
processes already running so so each
individual device driver is running as a
separate process in user space that's
the microkernel design principle we have
a networking stack well obviously we are
not there yet
because as you can see this is our web
browser beautiful but I mean at least
the networking is working so this was a
short demo now let's get to to
interesting stuff
what is our goal I mean generally
speaking it's about dependability it's
about creating a software architecture
on the system level that will that would
provide you know safety security and
other guarantees for building dependable
software so so the architecture as I
have already described by do the
fine-grain components that I isolated
from each other this is basically
limiting the blast radius as it is so if
everything is in if something goes wrong
in a monolithic system like Linux kernel
if there is now pulling pointer
dereference you know you know you know
device driver you know the whole system
goes goes out of the window in our case
only just that just the single task just
the driver goes out of the window and
there are potential mechanisms how this
could be you know solve at at runtime it
can be also also soft at design time so
so you can apply formal verification
techniques to make sure that actually
there is no null pointer dereference in
any of these components formal
verification techniques are generic
there could be applied on an encoder
base but you know the monolithic nature
the monolithic architecture of say Linux
or most of the BSD systems makes it hard
to actually practically apply the formal
verification method methods because the
code base is simply too large
in our case you have these individual
separate components and you can verify
them piece by piece so this is this is
the way we also try to be try to try to
write clean understandable source code
so our comment ratios this 38% which is
probably nice I mean again these are not
very surprising ideas it's about putting
all the software engineering bits and
pieces together so having good software
architecture having having a good
implementation doing the verification
and having a good development process
and you know ocean liners have been
built like this for for hundreds of
years you don't want to have a single
single house of your ship that is
carrying I don't know ten thousand
people because a single iceberg can just
destroy it you want to have this these
you know watertight bulkheads so that it
really needs it really requires a huge
error and a huge iceberg to sink your
ship but not not a tiny one I mean
obviously there is there is no silver
bullet but you can do things better than
just have a monolithic design this this
picture summarize it nicely I would say
these slides are more or less for your
reference if you would like to go go
into it further I understand it's not
really readable at this size so this is
this is these are the functional blocks
in our microkernel the only thing I
would like to stress here is this
hardware abstraction layers so we have
this really even inside the microkernel
which it's like the smallest indivisible
component we have some internal
structure still so we have some parts of
the code that out that are platform
dependent that needs to be adopted when
when we port Allen West to an open new
platform but most of the code base even
of the microkernel is independent on the
target
platform and this is just very
simplistic view of the user space so
there is there is the microkernel at the
bottom and then we have naming service
loader task manager and in it these are
more or less still you know very
critical services they are in the
trusted computing base and then we built
gradually less and less trusted services
on top of them such as the the file
system stack the device driver stack the
networking stack and so on by the way
our networking stack is also d
componentized so it's not a huge tcp/ip
everything library but there are
individual tasks individual applications
that take care for for the transport
layer for the for the link layer for a
physical layer okay so that was
generally speaking about her on OS and
you are probably interested in in in our
risk live port because this is a risk 5
the room so so I did some initial
experimentation in 2016 I I had talked
about this on in the microkernel def
room at first then at that time so
initially if you remember 2016 the
privilege eisah specification of birth
wife was in the version of 1.7 there was
no upstream to change the port so GCC
you know been you chills upstream
support and the only usable emulator or
platform was spiked so it took took me
something like 18 hours to get some
basic functionality so to get set up the
the infrastructure you know create the
directory structure for for the platform
dependent parts implement our own
bootloader I I just did not like the the
BBL so I implemented my own and then
some initial virtual memory management
setup and kernel handoff
some observations from from this there
were many things purely very badly
documented at that time so so many
things like the ABI or or the the the
i/o interface in spike needed to be
basically reverse engineered from from
the source source code of the tools and
of the emulator some other details were
still sketchy like memory consistency
model at that time but I mean generally
speaking the architecture for my
experience with other architectures
looked nice maybe accepted the strange
compressed page protection fields if you
still remember from from that version of
the privilege I saw that there were
there weren't individual fields in in
the page table entries for read you user
we eat corn or eat and stuff or soup
supervisor read write and execute but
there was this strange combined
compressed field I mean why not I mean
it just slightly complicated our macros
for that but our abstraction was fit to
it but it was just strange so then I I
have I have find I found some time to
get to it back in 2017 when I
implemented the basic kernel
functionality as we call it so basically
everything that the kernel needs to to
actually work and hand over the control
to user space meaning exception handling
context switching atomic operations and
some basic i/o so the ice privileged ISO
specification moved to the version 1.10
which I believe is still the most
current one so there were some small
improvements for example they have
removed those strange compressed page
protection fields the only usable
emulator at the time was to spike and
you know the the HT AF AF input device
it's a horrible design I mean really I
cannot imagine how somebody could have
come with such a such a strange input
device because it has no interrupts
which is more understandable there's no
there is no platform interrupt
controller defined in this specification
but if you do what you are supposed to
do so you pull the device you basically
sent a command to it asking is there a
character available and if if no you you
don't get you know you know you don't
get zero reply or something like no
character available the the request gets
buffered so I mean just think about it
how would you normally pull this device
I do in other word and periodically
pulling it but how do you get rid of
this this buffered requests when there
is no character in on the input I mean
this is just a memory leak on on the
emulator side I don't know
so the point is or maybe the moral of
the story is that there was still no
reference platform some something some
some decent specification of the
platform except the CPU itself that
would you know provide some reasonable
basic debugging i/o some platform
interrupt controller and stuff like that
and yeah I mean if you are poaching to
something where the GCC toolchain has
been just upstream you might encounter
internal compiler errors from time to
time this I mean this just happens I'm
not blaming anybody this was fixed in on
the in the next release of GCC and
honestly I did not even spend much time
you know fine you know debugging the
compiler back I just I just you know
removed the piece of the code that was
causing this bug waited for for an
update of the compiler and then then it
worked I'm not a comparator expert so we
would probably it would have to
took me you who have taken me a lot of
time so and now I finally got some time
to get back to it so this is what I've
been doing for like eight hours in
January so I decided to switch to the
qmo vert platform which somehow
according to my opinion more reasonable
than what the spike is providing because
you have you have the platform interrupt
controller control there you have a
normal UART serial i/o there you can use
you can use birth I owe for networking
and stuff like that so so this finally
looks like a decent platform to support
and the to chain or everything is
already upstream so this looks pretty
usable right now okay so what are the
lessons learned from this very brief
experience
first there was surprisingly very little
interest in porting on averse to risk 5
of course you might say this is because
nobody cares about Helena was but I mean
if you compare it to our previous
porting efforts to Arms Park v9 spar via
eight other platforms there was always a
lot of interest I would say so so either
in the framework of google Summer of
Code or in the form of master master
phases
there were people students who would be
would eagerly take her know us and port
it to a new platform and there was I
mean no interest with respect to risk 5
so I mean the only thing that was done
was done by me in my very very very
precious free time and I'm an heiress
chorus 5 enthusiast but I just don't
have the time to do it
so what what are the reasons I I believe
that there are two first like I've
already said there is still no nice
reference platform that would actually
provide you know interesting feature
more interesting than a serial console
so I mean obviously people nowadays are
not interested in in in seeing hello
world for most real console they want to
have HDMI they want to have us be they
want to have the networking stuff like
that and that would be easier to achieve
if there would be actually an easily
accessible
I mean costs development board that that
would provide those features so
something like a Raspberry Pi for risk 5
with with a powerful off risk 5 CPU
supporting the c2 supervisor mode and
for a reasonable price
yes of course you can have size 5 board
for I don't know $1000 but I mean that
that's too expensive so once this is
solved I would say that it could be
generalized that the risk 5 would get
much more intention and eruption by by
hobus by students by researchers because
they just need to you know it's really
hard to explain even to your boss that
this this hello world printout to cue
like 2 weeks of porting or coding and
there's one other thing yes and so this
this is something I would like to spend
the rest of my talks speaking about that
there has been very little according to
my opinion input from the operating
system guys to do risk 5 specification
and therefore from this point of view
from a point of view of for microkernel
operating system risk 5 does not bring
anything new to the table which is a
pity because how many times how many
opportunities in your lifetime do you
get to come up with a new instruction
set architecture that might actually get
some you know industrial traction that
might actually be adapted by by by the
big player
how many times do get the chance so why
do why do I think this is it this is
something that risk wife might focus
more on the microkernel idea I have
spoken about in all this you know fine
grained components isolation blast
radius limitation this is definitely not
a new idea it has been around since at
least the end of 1960s and it has actual
benefits for safety security
dependability that let me let me just
skip to to this slide most of the
benefits were so far somewhat
questionable because there were more or
less just qualitative benefits but now
there there's actual quantitative proved
that these benefits of the microkernel
design is is there that the benefits are
there so there has been there have been
there has been a study published at a
peer-reviewed scientific conference
which which basically analyzed some
critical vulnerabilities in Linux and
examined them how they would have been
mitigated or prevented by microkernel
based design and you can here you can
read here forty percent of those
vulnerabilities would be completely
eliminated by an operating system
designed based on a verified microkernel
such as SEO for in this case so I mean
there are huge benefits of having a
proper software architecture under
system model
and obviously this is not this is not
this is for a price
so the price that you that we pay for
for these benefits is the performance
overhead
there has been a huge effort in the last
25 years to make this performance
overhead as small as possible I mean the
whole the the whole effort of the l44
people in various projects was to make
this this overhead as small as possible
but the overhead is still there because
for example if you would like to if you
would like to run a single file system
related operation such as open file or
read read block of a file you know you
know microkernel multi server design you
need to talk to some location or naming
service then you need to talk to to a
virtual file system service then you
need to talk to the file system driver
then potentially this power system
driver will forward you to to a block
device driver and so on so so you have
the this overhead of the of the IPC
between those isolated components the
isolation has its cost and the question
is whether it has to be like that I
believe that the the cost is being
caused by the fact that the CPUs have
been designed so far just with the
monolithic operating systems in mind and
again I'm not blaming anybody I mean it
is more was natural because you know
designing the new CPU or instruction set
architecture used to be a very complex
task it used to be very expensive and
people naturally you know designed the
new CPUs according to the requirements
for the old CPUs and then the operating
system guys were just were just facing
with with what they got and I mean the
the monolithic design was performing
much better on it so let's switch the
gears or write the reverse the process
let's try to design the the CPUs with
the requirements of the micro kernels in
mind so that the the CPU will be able
to provide abstractions or instructions
mechanisms that will help the micro car
owners perform as nicely as the monolith
monolithic kernels while keeping all the
nice safety and security features and I
will present a few ideas I won't go into
too much details because first we don't
have the time and second I mean I would
probably rather spark a discussion than
present something I I'm sure it's gonna
work but these are a few ideas so for
example we would like to optimize the
IPC itself where's where's the problem
in a monolithic system if one subsystem
is calling into a different subsystem
all it does is a normal function call so
so there is a some passing of arguments
in registers or on stack and the code is
free to pass point direct pointers to
data structures so so this is this is
efficient and also unsecured because all
the reasons we have already discussed in
a microkernel multi server design you
need to do two IPC which means that you
have to call some karna Cisco's which
will will pass some arguments in
registers again but the set of registers
you are allowed to use is so naturalist
some would limit it there is the the
privilege level switch to address space
switch between those two components if
if the IPC is asynchronous there is some
scheduling involved and if bulk data
needs to be transferred the data needs
to be copied between the other spaces or
there needs to be some memory sharing
established so where the CPU could
actually help I mean why not why not
design and extend it jump all call
instructions and of course also return
instructions that would actually also do
the address space switch so so imagine
something like a Colgate
which would be basically like a calling
capability that would identify the
target address space and the target
program counter of the of the server IPC
handler and this could be implemented on
the hardware level for example like like
a cache something like TOB TOB cache
cache structure which will be populated
by by the microkernel
so again the microkernel will be fully
in charge in will be fully in charge of
deciding which you know which client can
call which server but for for the most
frequent calls this the mechanism will
will be streamlined streamlined by the
hardware so so the context switching and
and address based su switching will be
done by the hardware for the a
synchronous IPC where where there is the
need to somehow buffer the the the
payload of the message this could be
also streamlined by the hardware by by
using cache lines as the buffers so the
data would not even need to go to to the
to the main memory yeah sorry well I
mean I'm not saying it's different I'm
saying it goes beyond what has been done
again these ideas are not not floating
in the air these ideas are more or less
based on the optimization techniques
that has been done by the kernel
developers over the past 25 years where
they actually try to you to squeeze you
know as much CPU cycles from from the
sea or from from from from the course as
possible but I mean my point is that if
the CPU would be more helpful or would
provide more of the more you know space
for optimization the the overhead might
be even lower or may be ideally zero so
I mean I'm not saying it's different I'm
saying I mean we are talking about the
same direction
but let's think about actual hardware
mechanisms to make them make this more
optimum and you know generally speaking
pinning pinning workloads to course is
possible but we would also like to have
efficient cross core IPC okay what about
the bulk data
so again this is not such a great issue
nowadays because my name microkernels
such as her newest implement memory
sharing to to efficiently transfer large
amounts of data between other spaces the
problem is that this memory sharing
needs to be established and if this
establishment and possibly the teardown
of this is happening too often
this causes the overhead and also that I
need to be patient which is it's a minor
minor trouble so again how about having
an additional memory making mapping
mechanism in the CPU that would allow
for example to do fine-grained mapping
from from virtual addresses to cache
lines directly so cache lines are pretty
small
something like 64 or 128 bytes so this
would be ideal for the sharing of you
know smaller data structures ad hoc
sharing of data structures between the
other spaces what about the problem of
the context switching again this is I
mean most of the CP optimizations again
in the recent viewers have been
targeting the problem of hardware
licenses so we have we have we have
caches to to hide nanosecond latencies
of the DRAM we have software caches like
you know IO buffers to hide hide
millisecond licensees of these beliefs
and SSDs but what about the microsecond
latencies of the context switching
there are there are mechanisms to to to
solve this like hardware multi-threading
which is very effective in doing that
but you know usually in currency puce
you have just a fixed number of our
Hardware rights and you have to use so
software based context switching to have
more so how about finding or designing a
mechanism that would combine the
benefits of both so something like
hardware hardware cache for for thread
context that would scale to a reasonable
amount of contacts and delegate
instructions to store restore and switch
those contacts this could be possibly
optimized for for the ABI because you
don't necessarily need to save all the
order registers in all cases and it
would also help with for example if
combined with some autonomous mechanisms
for example triggering the contact
switch by some some event like an
external interrupt this could this could
again eliminate the round trip to the to
the kernel and doing the context
switching software obviously we need to
be careful because we don't want to
implement some kind of kind of hardware
scheduler or hardware scheduling policy
that this would be probably disasters so
again we would just like to have the
mechanism in the hardware but let it be
controlled by the software and if
combined with with some kind of
simultaneous multi multi threading this
could very efficiently even you know MA
you know what mask the 10 nanosecond
like and latency is like on the caches
and parts of the of the of the course
user space interrupt processing if we
have user space device drivers in a
microkernel based operating system we
always have this unpleasant round trip
through can or kernel where each
interrupt needs to be first handle
by by the kernel space then the kernel
space generates some IPC message which
is then forwarded to to the user space
user space driver why there could be a
mechanism to directly deliver the the
event to the use of space device driver
of course there's you there's the normal
pain point of level tricked interrupts
but again I believe there there are ways
how this could be handled by for example
automatically masking the interrupt
source in the in the platform interrupt
controller in those cases and this would
you know not only lower the the overhead
of having device drivers in user space
but it might also you know finally fix
the single remaining architecture flow
of current microkernels meaning that
there still need to be some device
drivers in the kernel space for example
the driver for the timer with this he
the track the the timer driver could be
push out from from the microkernel and
even the scheduler could be completely
pushed out of the out of the microkernel
we've just a little help from the CPU
okay final topic I won't spend too much
time on it because honestly I don't have
very very clear ideas how this could be
done but think about risk 5 128 bit
architecture I don't I don't believe
that having 128 bit flat pointers is
very useful
maybe for some some some situations but
I wouldn't say that this is it's it's
such a huge address space that there is
no practical use for it but what about
dividing logically the pointers into 64
bit object identifiers or object
capabilities in the parlance of micro
kernels and 64 bit offsets that would
allow
the hardware to do very very efficient
bounce checking to to make sure that
that the the objects that the only only
the owners of the objects have access to
them and stuff like that maybe in this
particle case this won't help the
microkernel so much because the
microkernel capabilities are more about
resource management and you know
physical bounced check in but this could
be also useful or maybe even more useful
for some many many languages VMs because
they wouldn't have to implement the
bound checking in software but there
would be a hardware mechanism for that
okay so these were just some ideas to
convince you that this is not just a
total wet dream they have been there has
been some pile work that somehow points
into this this direction so for example
there is this paper from 2005 that
evaluated of floating some microkernel
operations to to hardware they have
implemented some modifications to us
FPGA based soft core and the evaluation
is that there is something like fifteen
to twenty seven percent performance
improvement and this was based on on
offloading I would say coarse grain
functions such as thread creation to the
hardware I'm talking about much finer
grained ideas here and yeah hardware
message passing has been actually
implemented in in some hardware devices
so why not push it into the mainstream
regarding you know the hardware support
for for different address spaces many of
you have probably seen this paper about
the the space jump programming model
which showed on on the Barrow fish
voltic cardinal and on dragonfly bsd
that this could be useful for different
kinds of applications for example data
centric applications and you know if you
are as old as I am you might remember
the task state segment on AI 32 which
was kind of hardware context switching
mechanism I mean actually still is in in
that chip that most of us have in our
laptops and it was actually even used by
Linux and the performance was not not
poor I mean it was it was quite
comparable with the software based
mechanism at that time and the reason
why it was removed from the codebase was
because of portability so different
reasons than performance so maybe there
is still good chance to revisit this
side this idea again about the the cross
address space calls again there there's
a prior art that has been actually
available in most most of the x86 chips
that we have which is called vm
functions which is basically the very
same idea so that there's a way how to
how to make efficient calls from one vm
in in the VTX domain to another another
vm and exactly exactly there are some
some things there is some fixed number
of entries that could be used so far and
it has been shown by some of my
colleagues that this could be really
used to you know take a monolithic
binary like I don't know a web server
with with an SSL library and split it
into very fine-grained components I'm
really speaking about very fine-grained
components like individual functions and
put them into into separate to be
so so for example the business logic of
the web server would be would stay in
the original VM and the encryption and
the cryptographic key management would
be pushed out to a different VM and
connect them using this VM function
instruction and the cost of of this
separation is comparable to a single
Cisco so it's not not terribly bad for
performance and again this is just
misusing a mechanism that hasn't been
designed for for the purpose I have
talked and I have been talking about so
what about a mechanism that would be
specifically designed to help
microkernel so I'm looking forward to a
new paper about the skybridge mechanism
of my colleagues that should appear at
neurosis in a few months about the
capabilities I mean there there's not
much but there's this again this paper
about hardware based basically bound
checking which was implemented on as an
extension to the 64-bit MIPS I saw where
they were basically 32-bit bound
registers or capability registers which
contained you know the information where
an object boundary is and this was
checked by the hardware again the
performance evaluated on Iran or FPGA so
for was very nice the limitation in this
case was the inflexible design if this
would be done in more flexible
what's a thanks to the fact that we
could have 128 bit pointers so we
wouldn't have to have dedicated bound or
capability registers but the bound will
be encoded in in the pointer itself why
not use it and actually Intel MPX is
also more or less in the same direction
ok so that's probably all for me so
I might work on risk five port of nos in
the future but if you are interested
feel free to to to drop me a message but
I would say that this is really a great
opportunity for everybody from from the
risk five community to to help the
software move from from the you know
poor flawed monolithic architecture to
the microkernel multi server
architecture get all the benefits that
we know are there without the
performance benefit and final note to it
is thanks to some of my colleagues that
have contributed their ideas and also if
you would like to practically work on
this we are opening a new R&D lab in
dresden the lab will focus primarily on
microkernel development but we would
like to have a very well balanced mix
between you know basic research which is
this topic I have spoken about and you
know what's a more practical stuff and
we are starting from scratch so we will
we are like in a startup mode within
within a company
and since well owns high silicon which
is one of the ARM chip producers we will
actually be able to talk to the hardware
guys and maybe there will be actual
physical tangible results out of it
thank you and if there are any questions
I will be happy to answer them
I mean we are we are trying to do it
ourselves
yes I mean yes that was that's I mean
that's the summary of my talk we can do
it nowadays
yeah the sort of question is yeah the
question is was why are we aren't we
doing it already right if I can rephrase
it yeah we are trying to do it right now
because I think this is a very precise
moment in time to do it
thank you yes go ahead I believe we can
manage
so the question is whether it wouldn't
be helpful to rephrase those ideas and
questions in terms of virtualization and
stuff like that definitely it's possible
because I believe there is essentially
no difference between between the
microkernel architecture or a
microkernel and a hypervisor I mean most
of the micro kernels that are being used
you know practically SEO for qnx spike
OS they're also act as a sohe as a
hypervisor so definitely that would make
sense and we are doing the same in our
company actually okay so let's talk
afterwards thank you very much
[Applause]