okay hi everyone it's awesome so many
people are able to come out so early of
the speak first speaker today is ajita
bora and she's going to be doing a talk
on doing what you love everyday so I
love what you do everyday
thanks thanks Zoe Wow
well I'm so glad so many of you have
actually come today because I was
expecting there would just be like three
people after was it delirium last night
is that where everybody was hanging out
so thanks for thanks for coming we're
just playing with the monitors here to
say we could get it projected larger but
I think we're just going to stick with
this so we can stop moving I've got a
lot of information to share and so I'm
going to go through this fairly rapidly
hopefully we'll have time at the end if
not I'll be around today later today as
well so that's my twitter handle and of
course the FOSDEM
hashtag as well for any review thats on
twitter so i'm very excited to be here
at FOSDEM I've been coming here for many
years I don't know how long has fosston
been actually going because I've been
coming for like it feels like like
almost 10 years and it's only been like
a two-hour train ride from London so
it's been you know one of the great sort
of European open source events to kick
off the year so it's exciting to be here
and speaking here as well I was asked to
share my journey in open source and what
I've done so it's it's I guess it's not
the norm it's certainly not what I had
planned and you know I hope some of the
tips and the stories that I share will
help you kind of think about your
careers and the direction your careers
are going in and hopefully find some of
the opportunities and to do what you
love so as many of you know last year
was 20th year for the OSI and so opens
was coined the term was coined over 20
years ago and that's kind of how long my
career's been almost 20 years it will be
20 years this year and I've been an
active contributor in open source since
then so you know this is the career that
happened unplanned and you know as you
look through this I kind of started off
with OpenOffice as my first open source
project I also created the co-created
with some my colleagues at Google and
the google Summer of Code program we
started that in 2015 and and we created
the open document format with the
OpenOffice project and more recently I
was at the Cabinet Office some of you
may know the policies that governments
are adopting around open standards and
how open standards also enables open
source to be used by governments
particularly I think the European
governments are very focused around a
percentage like the Dutch government and
the UK government so we got a policy
through the UK government that all
government information that's editable
should be in open document format and
that was in 2014 so that was a policy
that went through and currently I'm at
AWS I'm not planning to go through my
whole career here but you know as I
mentioned earlier I started in 99 with
OpenOffice and I guess how many of you
are OpenOffice or LibreOffice users
awesome I kind of expected most of the
room to have their hands up so that's
very cool
so I was leading the project responsible
with the project and the community and
it was 7 1/2 million lines of code code
that's acquired through a German
organization star division and our job
was to work on internally on what is
what is the code that we can actually
release and what's third-party code
and then after we release say how do we
do open source
remember this was 1999 year 2000 most
people are only familiar with building
software and that was internally closed
you kind of just talked to your
colleague so it was quite a transition
and quite a transformation as a project
to not only come up to speed in this new
area of working but also embrace kind of
a global community that eventually we we
developed all around the world so it's
pretty exciting times and typically and
many of you working on developer tools
and so you don't actually touch
end-users necessarily with the projects
that you're working on but with it
something like OpenOffice and it was
Firefox as well at the time we found
that we were able to talk to end users
as well and even now like last year I
was at the open source summit I was
speaking in Prague and I was in a taxi
and the taxi driver said to me Oh what
is this conference you're going to you
know I've been taking a lot of people to
it and I said oh it's about open-source
and you know how do you explain
open-source to the average person on the
street and you know luckily the driver
said oh you mean like OpenOffice and I
said yes and he said yes I'm a user of
OpenOffice so it's kind of nice that we
do have open source software that
touches end-users you know I'm speaking
in Parliament and I asked everybody in
the room to take out their iPhones and
go to the terms and conditions and in
there if you look there's a whole list
of all the open-source software that's
actually being used on the iPhone so
just getting people more and more aware
that you know it touches everybody's
lives right now and it's a really big
deal back then it wasn't but right now
it covers a you know a whole spectrum of
technologies so
you know one of the important thing was
having mentors because how do you teach
a whole engineering team based in
Germany in Hamburg that that how to do
open source and brian behlendorf i don't
know if you're familiar with brian he
was one of the early he was one of the
apache founders and he's now the
Executive Director for the hyper ledger
the blockchain foundation and brian was
very instrumental in teaching as the
apache way and teaching you know some of
the early projects the apache way you
know we didn't have github back then we
just had sorta and and I'm I can't
looking around the room I think some of
you were there with us back then as well
so I'm just kind of telling you the
story to just place it in context and
yeah we so Brian's company was providing
the services that OpenOffice and a lot
of the Sun Microsystems projects were
being hosted on so we had to have hosted
services to be able to host all our
large projects and then at Google you
know part as part of this two-person
team we created this program office for
open source and it was the first time
there was an open source program office
that really focused on contributions and
especially code contributions and we
create a google Summer of Code because
we wanted to engage more new people into
the community and more interns into the
community and also you know contributing
and collaborate with the projects in
increasing the open source code out
there so right now there's about 2,000
mentors on google Summer of Code and
about 300 lines million lines of code
that have been contributed I don't know
how many of you are however former
interns or interns or mentors on JSOC
can I see
hands show of hands okay that's that's
really o1 that's very surprising for
FOSDEM crew so if you're working on a
project I would absolutely recommend
that you go check out this program and
participate as a mentor if you have a
project or submit your project for
engagement and I'll talk a little bit
about one of the projects that I work
with and what they're doing as well but
this is you know as an intern you would
get four and a half thousand dollars for
contributing to an open-source project
during the summer months for the three
months and as a mentor you would have a
student for that time pretty much
dedicated to completing a project that
you've specified so this is this is a
really powerful kind of program for any
open source projects and actually before
I go further can I also get a show of
hands of how many people are relatively
new to open source okay
all right that's that's cool that's good
to know maybe like maybe like a third of
the room so it's a great sign was a
mentor at Google and he also was one of
the early Apache members and you know he
helped us really build how the
organization and our programs I'm not
going to go through a lot of these but
projects but um one of the things I got
to do was throughout my journey I got to
work with really inspirational people
and like the founders of technologies
and people that were involved in the
early days of open source so for example
I'm James Gosling father of Java so when
I worked on NetBeans we released a
version in China and I had an
opportunity to go work in China and
travel with James and one of the things
we did was walk along the Great Wall of
China so he of course
many of you are familiar with James and
he currently works for Amazon Web
Services the other person was Vint Cerf
while I was at Google he and I traveled
around Europe I grabbed the opportunity
to learn more about what universities
were doing in Europe what they were
teaching in terms of open source because
our goal was to try and engage with the
students to help include open sources
some of the curriculum in universities
and so I got to travel with Vince but
also you know engage Winton more in kind
of open source and then open standard so
I ended up working for Vince and
building an open standards office at
Google and then another person you may
be familiar with as Mark Shuttleworth
from canonical Ubuntu and as part of the
work I did I got invited to Kenya to
speak and and Mark and I spoke at the
same event and we were both working on
helping with education in places like
Kenya and the African countries as you
know his South African and you know one
of his goals is engaging more with the
African countries around technology as
well and just collaborating on making a
difference and you know through through
our work and working with interesting
projects early stage projects as well on
the right on my right yeah is Jim's
Emlyn and he's the executive director of
Linux Foundation but back then the
veneks foundation was maybe just him so
it was kind of very very early days and
then last but not least you know my
first community this is the open open
office community over the years you not
only kind of like work together debate
issues you know build and create you
know code and content for your project
but you also develop kind of a
friendship and get to know
each other and and some a lot of the
communities still is in touch with each
other and two of the colleagues are
working for government so the Dutch
government and French government and you
know this may be an area that you know
you may be interested in following up in
but certainly a lot of government
policies are adopting open source and
open standards of the French government
to have some really great policies
around everything they do should be
released as open source software and
there's you know there has to be a
pretty strong reason for it not to be
released as open source software so you
know as open source developers as
contributors to open source there's
going to be more and more and tremendous
opportunities for working in government
environments as well so clearly a lot of
this is not something that I had planned
you can't really plan for it but one
things I did was every opportunity that
came up to do something interesting to
meet interesting people to work with
them to volunteer I took up all of those
opportunities and that's what snowballed
and and led to this career so there
isn't a formula for doing this work
right it's a passion of mine and so I
have to ask you like why you know what
you know why do i do i do i do open
source so this is this is my big reason
it's some my twitter account you know
it's really you know it would be great
if what you're doing is meaningful and
beneficial to the world so i just want
to ask the audience like what are some
of the things and the reasons why you're
doing open source any anyone should want
to shout out no it's too early on sunday
morning well okay so I gave this
conference at a talk a talk at a
conference in the US and there was a lot
of people choice fighting here and there
are things like giving back as a reason
freedom is another reason
and privacy transparency somebody was
doing it for political activism and just
producing a better software for users
and for themselves so and those are all
absolutely valid reasons you know a lot
of times people come to the community
for code and then they stay because of
the of the people right so there are
Apache and in Debian you know they say
code of a community or come for the coat
come for the code stay for the community
so right now my role is head of
open-source Strategy at AWS and the
reason I'm giving this talk on careers
is that I mean I was in my first year I
was building a team and managing a team
and in doing that I ended up talking to
a lot of people in the open-source
community and I found that I was giving
a lot of input into their careers and
how they could build a career and I've
also been speaking at the universities
in India and in Africa also in terms of
advice for students and motivating
students so I thought it would be an
interesting topic to cover here so
another another quick question how many
of you think open-source has one okay
that's okay that's that's like about 80%
of the room so some of the conferences
they go to and it's an open source crowd
it may end up being the whole room R it
may end up being just like 30% even in
an open source crowd when I speak to
like an enterprise audience
it can only be it may end up only being
10% so the perception out there in the
industry is very very varied like if
you'd gone to a government audience a
couple of years back absolutely
you know you wouldn't get any hands
going up but if you'd go to somewhere
that likes a French government that's
very progressive you would have a lot of
hands up because they've done a lot of
work within their government as well and
we've been disrupting this software
industry the open-source community has
for over 20 years now so I mean it's
everywhere it's in our devices and it's
in all the market sectors and you know
to the projects I'm involved in one is
about reducing poverty around the world
and it's called me force and b612
foundation is actually a project that's
trying to save the planet from an
asteroid attack and they're also working
on an open-source platform so there's a
whole range of open-source projects that
you can get involved in based on your
interests so you know these are some of
the headlines that we see that software
is eating the world this is a quote from
Marc Andreessen and here's one that I
know Jim Semillon uses from the olynyk's
foundation uses a lot saying that
open-source has one and open-source is
eating the software world and and it
didn't happen overnight it's taken time
right and every company that's building
services in the cloud this is the
important thing every company is
consuming open-source software they may
not know it and they may not know what
to do with the fact that they're
consuming open-source software
and everybody is trying to come up to
speed on open-source how to contribute
how to actively participate and so there
is a tremendous opportunity for every
one of you that's engaged in open-source
to go out there and have very fulfilling
careers all right so you know you look
at the trend here and these are numbers
from the Linux Foundation for last year
so 23 million more than 23 million
developers on github and 6 more than 64
million github repos and and the number
of projects are you know just growing it
I'm sure
that numbers a lot bigger than that now
so there's huge momentum and you know
this is the scale that we're working at
in open source and at conferences we
kind of hear people like echoing back
that you know software and open source
is eating the world so it's good news
for all of you for all of us that the
opportunities in open source is just
going to grow and this is a job report
that shows you know the employers are
actually looking for expertise in you
know including web technologies in Linux
so and and the kind of skills that
they're looking for as well so so you
wouldn't have seen these numbers a few
years ago but this is growing not just
in Europe it's also growing in places
like India as well that I've seen one
thing I haven't seen at FOSDEM is a jobs
board and this is very typical of most
of the open source events that I go to
and hopefully we'll see that at FOSDEM
as well where you know you can see what
is available and who are the companies
that are looking but you only have to go
online and just do a search on open
source and like every company out there
you know you know Amazon's also hiring
for open source positions that's the
only plug I have in this for my employer
so what are the kinds of roles you know
when I was when I was at university and
admittedly it was a long time ago I'm
going to date myself now and the there
were two options one was a programmer
and the other one was a systems analyst
and that was it those were the only two
tracks leaving University so what are
the things you can do besides you know
the function that you have in open
source if you wanted to look further
afield these are just some of the roles
that I've had working in open source you
know ranging from you know release
manager to contributor
- setting up a governance board -
managing events - managing programs and
creating a program like google Summer of
Code - coming out here and educating and
advocating it so there's a whole range
of roles and depending on the skill you
have all the skills that you want to
develop because a tremendous opportunity
to do that within open source you can
within projects look for people who have
that skill and you think are actually
doing really well in a particular space
and start partnering with them and
learning from them so and actually I was
talking to somebody yesterday and they
said that they were working on
organizational and people development
and and said well I'm not sure that
there's an opportunity for me you know
the source because I'm not a developer
but you know this the the people skills
are really hugely in demand because open
source is just it is about people it's
about people coming together to build
code and build technologies and you know
whenever leanness gets interviewed he
always says the technology part is very
very easy it's actually working with a
people that actually becomes the biggest
challenge so you know I'm sure those of
you that are experienced in open source
projects are very familiar with that and
you have to look around you and look at
people who are very skilled in that
because that is a really key piece of
open source participation so I'm going
to cover the tips of working in a
project and how to build your career
depending on you know I already asked
how many of you are newbies so I'm given
there's a third of the room here that
put the hand up I'm going to just go
through those
little bit more in detail than some of
the other areas so first of all you have
to think about if you're already in
projects actually just a quick show of
hands how many you're not involved in a
project okay all right so this next bit
applies to all of you think about your
what motivates you what are you excited
about what are you using right because
when I think of the people that came to
the open office project they were there
were users of open office so they were
very passionate about giving back and it
was something that they could help
contribute but also they could help
improve it for themselves and the rest
of the community so think about your
interests and select your project based
on that it's actually and can encourage
there's a whole bunch of people here
that are relatively new but it's you
know open sources you get back what you
put into it as well as a project within
a project and within the community as
well so not just not just the
technologies but also look at the
community look at I call it and evaluate
the tribe and and the people so when you
join a project you need to look at how
many when when people are responding
writing on them on the mailing lists are
they getting responses is the project
very responsive are people friendly to
each other
are they dismissive when you contribute
if you contribute something small at the
outset how is that received is their
willingness to accept the work that
you're doing is their willingness to
point you in the right direction and not
just you know go read the document and
don't bother us right is their website
pretty well-documented
do they have tasks for new joiners to
the project so often projects will have
like a list of
you know here's here's what we need help
with and it may be kind of in the readme
file he maybe has some of the things
that you could get involved in if if
you're not finding a responsive
community oh one other thing is to read
the code of conduct and and make sure
that that aligns with your values as
well so it's it's not about the just the
code and contributing and it's a whole
package that you need to evaluate and my
first advice on anyone joining an
open-source project is go on to the
meaningless and do that from a couple of
projects do that for three or four
projects that you're interested in and
just look for awhile it's perfectly
perfectly okay to go onto a project and
just observe and and see kind of how the
community is managed because that's
going to be pretty important because the
work that you do you will be
contributing to that project into that
community yeah so make sure you look at
the readme Docs and the to do Docs and
yeah if none of these exists go go to
another project and or if it's something
you want to do maybe you can make a
suggestion but be cognizant of the
feedback that you get you know you want
to be in a welcoming community and that
was something that we fostered within
our communities as well so one of the
things that the G sock students the
google Summer of Code students say that
they learn from joining an open-source
project is how to how to use some of the
tools out there you know if you're using
github if you're using if you are Apache
you may be using the tools there at
Apache you may be using another system
for tracking and managing information as
well and a difference governance model
so the typically in a university
environment for all of you you know who
are at college what you end up doing
you're focused on working just on your
piece of work and you know this is it
I'm gonna submit my dissertation I'm
gonna submit my code in open source your
collaboratively working with many many
people and it's a different way of
working in different way of
communicating taking feedback and
integrating that feedback into your work
and I'm not getting upset because
somebody said that something you did
wasn't wasn't how what they can accept
right you know as long as they don't say
your code sucks you kind of hopefully
it's a little bit more diplomatic but
there's an opportunity to improve all of
your skills and that's what the google
Summer of Code students found and if
you're new to open source these are two
fantastic reference season particularly
call Fogle's book and he's got a new one
coming out and you can find copies of
that PDFs of that online for free and
Jonah Bacon's book the art of community
how to work in community they really
both go hand in hand and is a big part
of this is making friends and you know
in an office environment you have that
and here you will you'll be part of a
virtual environment of people that
you'll be connected to and this is very
valuable later on if you don't like it
vote with your feet and leave that's
okay that's perfectly fine you know this
was in 20 2008
so about almost nine years from this
from the time the project was kicked off
and we were having events in lots of
different countries and a lot of the
same people showed up at the events
because they just wanted to connect with
their buddies once a year and really
meet in person and share so how many of
you been working on project one to two
years okay fewer of you okay so there's
a couple of things I guess you know
often same same widget will same with
your job you get you get very focused
producing that piece of code delivering
what you need to that you sometimes lose
sight of the bigger picture so it's
really important to just step back and
here's a you know great quote from Bill
joy the innovation happens elsewhere so
you know not just completely focused on
your projects but look outside at what
some of the other projects are doing
that might be interesting there's a huge
opportunity to learn from developers
because in open source they come from
all different companies all different
countries and all different backgrounds
and there must be somebody doing
something innovative and creative that
you can learn from so if you haven't
thought of participating in a community
as a way of learning and expand
experience to learn this is something
that you need to consider and then you
know observed by learn by just kind of
observing and watching different styles
whether it's coding or whether it's
resolving a problem somebody may just be
so good at answering messages and
resolving issues for people that that
might be that might be a skill that you
can learn from someone else so you know
ask yourself what are you doing for your
project
besides the code contribution right and
here's kind of a you know Apache pyramid
which which kind of says you know you go
from a user to contributor to a trusted
committer to a lead an analogy architect
so there's a kind of a structure with an
Apache not all projects have this and
you know you may be in a position to
really engage on a helping improve your
improve your project but engaging your
newbies and start mentoring you know you
can start mentoring from about a year
into a project and start teaching new
members to your community as well so
there's also things like event
participation showing up in your
community and
engaging face-to-face writing skills is
another big piece so if you find that
that's something that you want to focus
on that maybe especially someone who's
been there a while starting to produce
better helpful information for the
community would be would be a really
good thing and for for the folks that
have been in the projects for a couple
of years what you've been doing go out
and speak at conferences how many of you
here are speakers okay excellent
okay and for those of you who are not
this is a great way to get your work out
there and a lot of conferences will also
pay for your travel so if that's
something that is a bar barrier to tab
going then you should look at that write
papers you could also write a book with
your knowledge I'm going to just going
to step this up a little bit because I'm
just conscious of time how are we doing
okay
so build your resume online and there's
social media github you know mailing
lists like Guetta all the recruiters all
of the companies I guess now even the
government recruiters everyone will be
looking at your profiles online and what
you're doing so as part of working in
open-source everything you do is already
out there and and it's a really great
way to not just to hire people but also
to get your knowledge and information
out there right and be nice I think
that's really important in our community
is just because you're at the end of a
email you don't know what kind of a
situation somebody else is in you just
so you know always remember be nice
whatever you do and that's always been a
motto for all the projects that I've
been involved in and to make maintain
and make a healthy project and make it
grow building effective teams is really
important here's a great book that's
written by ben collins-sussman and brian
fitzpatrick but they also have some
really great YouTube videos and you
could go back and look at and and it's
kind of dealing with difficult people I
mean it's part of life if you're working
with people you're gonna have great you
know great buddies but you're also gonna
have people that you don't agree with so
I'd highly recommend watching that for
the folks who have been here and have
been doing outsource for five or more
years can I get a quick show okay so
that's like well about 40% of the room
cool so I think you know and I'm the
same kind of I was thinking about okay
what are the things that I do with
projects and you know you if you're not
interested you may be interested in
taking a leadership role and I think
this is a huge opportunity for those of
you who've been to know doing episodes
for a long time building your leadership
skills and developing that and
developing leaders from within the
community so you've got to think about a
transition a succession plan as well
because you're continuing to do this but
you really need to help like the folks
that have been there a few years really
through their kind of next phase and
into leadership roles as well and I
assume I didn't see any hands go up for
google Summer of Code mentoring I'm
assuming and I'm hoping that some of you
are mentoring within your projects
because that is how we got to do that's
how I got to do open source was those
two great mentors that I had and I'm
hoping that that's features very largely
in your projects and if it isn't I would
urge you to raise that within your
projects as well so I have I have here
mentor mentor mentor and that's
absolutely key so you know these are
some of the founding fathers of basf and
and the giants that you know on whose
shoulders we all stand
they have been responsible for you know
teaching so many projects the Apache Way
and helping a lot of the successful
projects as well and and you know kind
of model yourself on some of the folks
that you see in open-source who you kind
of admire who you've learned from or who
you think of done fabulous job and
really build your own skills that way if
you look at the Apache foundation so you
can move up to project management
committee and you can move up to a board
level and there are other opportunities
on other projects to go into help being
a community member on the board so I'm
going to run through these fairly
quickly because I think we had a slow
start early on so I'm going to need to
run through these so for a successful
community and we all have superpowers
right some of you think superpowers are
you know night vision or flying or let's
see telepathy but actually everybody has
superpowers and there may be just
something like being a warm friendly
face in the community and I think that's
really valuable being a good listener
being a curator of people and even
superpowers have to work hard
remember it's taken 20 years to get to
this it's not something that it's
happened overnight and I know that you
know these days with social media
everyone there there's this kind of
movement of yeah I want it and I want it
now it's not this is not open source is
not about that it's about hard work and
it's about being persistent with time
and recruiting it's a big part of the
job everybody that's been in the
projects for a while every one of you is
a recruiter and probably for a developer
that they're probably squirming at the
idea that no I'm not a recruiter but
you're all recruiting for your projects
everybody you tell a
how to use it and what are you doing is
potentially could be interested in
coming to work for your project
diversity is really really important
diversity and inclusion and I was just
in London just before coming here and
the talk was about that the event was
about design and accessibility and if
you think about people all over the
world there aren't like you that may be
differently abled you know they may be
blind they may be there may be hard of
hearing but they're all part of our
communities and they're all consumers of
our software as well so think about
diversity in your projects and how do
you serve the folks that are using your
software that aren't able din the same
way that you are and you know what are
the tools and the skills that
open-source gives you a big part of it
is the community is your reference you
know that is that is the key to this is
not just the information that you put
online but everything you do out there
your community is your big reference and
there's so many of the folks that I work
in without in an open source have said
to me my you know my reference has been
the community and that's how it got this
amazing role so pay attention to that
and it's your career and it's really up
to you to kind of manage this and and
build it and some people I know like
Jeremy who was here yesterday speaking
Jeremy Allison he works at Google and
he's working full-time on sanbir and
they hired Jeremy when I was there to
come and just do that full time so you
know if you're shining on your project
and is something a company is interested
in and they may just bring you in to
just work on that because the
contributions you're making matters to
them it's it's up to you to lead from
within and take a look at the projects
you're working and take a look at what
you're doing
and really look at how you can not just
shift what you're doing in your career
but also your project as well how can
you help that grow build on your amp and
it really is the ticket you could write
so there's another talk very quickly I
wanna mention is from Jonah bacon that
you can find online and it's about
burnout and you know when you can work
on open source projects 24 hours and and
still do your day job there's a danger
of burnout so I would HIGHLY advise you
to take a look at Jonah's presentation
and read about this look at the signs
because you'll just say yeah I'm not
burning out but it's something that's
happening in our community and so that's
why these talks happen as well and it's
one of the areas where I think I find
the most passionate people anybody
that's involved in open source has such
a passion for what they do and it's kind
of infectious so and it's really awesome
to be around people in this space it's
not all roses and there are pitfalls so
you have to be aware of them you need to
put in the work and it will pay you
dividends so it's up to you to be really
be the change that you want and really
you know share and contribute and just
be nice I was going to share a couple of
stories but I think we're kind of
running short on time so I'm not gonna
share these stories but what I would
like is you know if you have any
questions you can come up to me at the
end I just have one last thing to say
here is really take take all the
opportunities that come your way and
through open source we've been able to
not just transform industries and we've
been able to transform people's careers
and their lives as well
so it's it's an incredibly powerful tool
that will help you change your careers
as well so grab that and do what you
love
thank you
you