[Music]
there's new information
so we look at some numbers here you can
call these measures up to make
it's about 10-12 I'm sorry both of them
I was doing streaming off the region tax
time
it's
if you had a whole bunch of versions or
displays frequently and time I people
may be stuck me
she has 11 for example
these are arranged a
basically the second exit we are many
Mikey's not working
Oh
my cigarettes
[Music]
you know that
so this is why you have these max to be
really and you know so in communities
really is absolutely fantastic I think
everyone should
[Music]
we can do something about I think
fool
Mexican are you actually like
why to record the space we have
and
[Music]
ten-second tiles and by minn tiles
and percussion you know he never
they people like ICU
and you know
she's requested additional location
all seven books on the registry
how these time series is so you know
what everybody comes in
[Music]
basically they're on a single day that
we're going through a time there was a
family first
[Music]
or
so basically the structure thigh-highs
he said he basically
they speak straight up and say I'm a
distance and we need to basically
place places
we figure out mentally
so now they have a pal
they value so that's four
[Music]
so in America tax
so you
last time
there are see they but essentially
that's insane
[Music]
various districts in 25 2013 street you
know
yeah basically salt library
and he can imagine barrett-jackson say
like 25 and 30
he actually ladies
so once we've found more concrete than
lady nosiness
I mean exes
actually and that's that's great
so you know that he would be working the
next essentially there is more efficient
in the investment opportunity space
for every 216 snakes
[Music]
basically
so I really text me that
[Music]
or
so you know actually this
it's a kind of easy
at something like this lost me
[Music]
well that's okay
a
[Music]
then they face the scores of these
measures and create the next business
works