my name is Roman D'Souza I'm jit
compiler developer and IBM and I'm also
a committer at the open j9 project and
I'm here to talk to you guys about an
exciting project that we've been working
on called jig compilation as a service
but first a slight to make the lawyers
happy so what is open j9 you guys might
have already heard about it before on
the previous talks but it is an
independent implementation of a java
virtual machine and you create a compile
a complete JDK by combining it with the
class libraries from open JDK and
actually it came from the IBM j9 VM and
in fact the gen and BN right now
the IBM SDK actually currently uses and
is built with open j9 and so the project
I'm going to talk to you about is
actually prototyped using open j9 so you
might these are the some of the things
you might already know about a jet or
just-in-time compiler the compilation
takes CPU time and memory from the
application in order to compile an
optimized code and the idea is that if
we run long enough we usually break even
and while this has been true for big
monolithic applications it is less so
for a smaller distributed shorter cloud
running applications and the reason for
that is because JVM sometimes need to
operate in small spaces if you take a
model with the application that has been
broken down into services which is what
you want to do if you want to run in a
cloud each of these services might have
their own JVM and in which case they
might have their own chips and so
there's a lot of duplicated work
happening in these services in addition
now that the services are smaller you
might decide hey we don't need that much
space let's just take a machine for
example in this case 8 cores 8 GB and
split it up into virtual machines and
that case you're now running a JVM in a
constrained environment so not only do
you have duplicated work we're compiling
the same methods over and over again for
sample strengths methods in the string
class and medicine hashmap but you're
also limited by the amount of space you
have in these machines and so the
question we asked was what if we could
should compile out of process or on a
different machine or on a cluster of
machines and then maybe have the jet
have its own CPUs and memory resources
and serve multiple applications and
share code between the different
applications and so the answer that we
came up with was JIT as a service the
idea is to treat JIT compilation as any
other cloud service we ramp up and down
resources based on load and load here is
compilation request and by doing so we
can containerize it and manage it manage
it intelligently using kubernetes or
something and we can share the results
across the components and across
applications and what we're hoping for
by doing this is we have better resource
control for compilation and better
scalability because the compilation or
the JIT traditionally runs in process it
has to steal resources from the
application and it can only steal so
many resources if it took everything
then you wouldn't get any real work done
by moving it away from part of the JVM
we have the option of scaling it as much
as we need to based on its requirements
we also get amortization of the cost of
compilation because we can share the
code across the different applications
it only has to be compiled once we get
improved reliability from the
application because in the case where
the compiler crashes it doesn't bring
down the entire application it crashes
somewhere else and we can also now have
better provisioning of resources for the
application itself the users don't have
to worry about do they need to size
their containers to take into account
memory needed by the compiler or whatnot
of course there are concerns that we had
as well network latency is a big one
traditionally compilation occurs at a
time when the application is sensitive
to ramp up by that I mean the time it
takes to reach peak throughput but now
they were moving it off officer off
process or on a different machine were
at the mercy of the network security
obviously is another beacons
we're now communicating on a channel
that was previously completely internal
to the JVM but now we're you know
speaking outside of it
there's also Network reliability issues
what happens when you know you're in the
middle of a compilation and the network
breaks down what is the fallback plan
and of course the last one was would all
this work actually pay off with
offloading it to a different machine
work and so where are we right now with
the current prototype that we have it's
available on github and I put the two
links up there for you guys it is also
there at the very end if you don't get a
chance to take a picture now it
currently supports all the optimizations
that almost all the optimization is done
by the open j9 jet it communicates fully
over the network by using raw sockets
and protobufs and currently is a single
server multi client model and it also
supports open SSL it can also run all
the open j9 test Suites as well as many
enterprise benchmarks and so let's get a
bit into this at a very high level it is
a client-server model as I mentioned
before with bi-directional
bi-directional communication what
happens is a compliment accomplished in
begins when the competition request is
sent to the server and it ends when the
compilation server returns the compiled
body back to the client and during the
compilation the server can make an
arbitrary number of queries to get
information about the class info profile
info higher can foe and the reason needs
to do this is because we've only moved
the compiler off process we haven't
moved the entire JVM environment and so
the compiler has no notion about what is
valid in this particular JVM environment
and so in order to make optimization
decisions it needs to query the JVM the
client about it so let's get into it a
bit deeper there's eight steps involved
and I'll go into each of these briefly
but I want you to notice that steps one
two and eight are essentially the same
as what happens in an in process jet we
request a compilation it gets processed
it gets compiled and then we install it
in the code cache and so from the JVM
point of view nothing has really changed
if the JVM doesn't need to know whether
the JIT is in process or out of process
it's the separation happens at the J
jedd interface so in step one we
generate a compilation request which
gets put in the conflation queue
step two that the request is processed
by the compilation thread on the client
and accomplishments right here is a bit
of a misnomer because it's not actually
doing the compilation it more
facilitates the compilation but anyway
once it processes the request it sends
the remote request to the server where
there is a socket listener thread that's
listening for these requests and when it
receives that you request it will place
it on the compilation queue on the
server side and what it does here is not
just place the request but also the
socket descriptor so that when the
compilation thread our server needs to
make queries against the client it
doesn't need to go through the listener
thread it can just directly communicate
with the client so in step 5 the
completion turn on the server will pick
up the request and start compiling and
as I mentioned before it will need to
make runtime queries every so often and
then finally when it's done compiling it
will return the compiled body back to
the client at which point we relocate
install it and then the JVM now has a
compiled body that it can run and so
that's the general process of how it all
works how does it perform so I'm gonna
go through four different areas of
performance that we measured throughput
memory footprint how does it perform in
a constrained environment and also how
does it perform on the cloud because
after all this is a service so the setup
we had was we ran it with two x86 Linux
machines where we connected them put a
direct Ethernet cable on machine one we
had the actual JIT server MongoDB and
jmeter each of them running in their own
docker instance containers and that a
machine - we had a Java EE act near
benchmark running on top of Liberty app
server Acme R is a benchmark that
simulates flight reservation system and
Liberty is a dynamic composable server
application runtime environment and so
here's the graph we see for throughput
and my throughput I mean throughput over
time the blue line
is the baseline open j9 with the in
process yet and the orange line is the
open j9 using jitters of service and as
you can see throughput is about the same
ramp up is a little bit worse because of
the network latency that occurs
naturally when you're communicating over
a network and by ramp up here I mean the
time it takes to get from start to peak
or steady-state throughput and so we
don't have to sacrifice peak throughput
and the network latency is tolerable and
can be mitigated for optimized next we
look at memory consumption memory
footprint and here specifically measured
residence set size the blue line again
is a base line open j9 where you see all
the spikes that occur because of the
compilation maybe that needs to happen
whereas the orange line is much more
stable because we don't have the
compilation overhead all of the memory
is dominated by the application and the
heap and so what we can take away from
this is that the applicant the user
doesn't need to worry about the JIT they
can just size their containers for their
application and just move on next we ran
throughput in a constrained environment
and by and by this I mean we changed
that near container to run with only 64
Meg's of RAM and half a CPU the green
line here is the baseline open j9 and
the blue line is open j9 with JIT as a
service and you can see that the jitter
service run here performs much better
the reason the j9 run perform so badly
is because it only has 64 Meg's of RAM
and so as the applications heap fills up
the compiler has less and less memory to
work with to the point where it can't
compile anything and we're stuck
interpreting whereas JIT is a service
run doesn't have any of those problems
because all of the compilation has been
offloaded
it just gets the compiled body and can
move on we include a hotspot here
because we wanted to verify to ourselves
that open j9 wasn't just performing
badly it basically just shows what a
tough environment a constrained
environment like this is for traditional
JVM if you're curious the spikes are GC
pauses and then finally we ran it to the
service for IBM Cloud
which I referred to as ICP ICP is a
platform for developing and managing
on-prem containerized applications and
so we had for world worker nodes here
one of them was open Jana and with the
in process chip another one was running
with the remote server we also had the
actual jet server and then we had
MongoDB and so here is the performance
we see for those that run as you can in
the top left we have to point over time
and again as you can see throughput is a
lot it's about the same year but ramped
up is much worse and the reason for that
is unlike the other experiment where the
two machines were connected with the
direct Ethernet link which means that
the ping time was about 0.2 milliseconds
here you're completely at the mercy of
the network and so the latency is much
more obvious in the bottom you see the
bottom left story you see the memory
usage and again it looks about the same
as the previous slide where there is a
service line is much smoother and
represents really the heap or whatever
is in the residence that sides of the
heap on the top left you see the CPU
usage of both the in process yet and the
jitter service client there's a big
spike in the beginning and the baseline
because you have all the compilation
occurring but you don't have that big
spike with the jitters of service client
you do however have more memory use more
CPU usage then one would expect and the
reason for that was because of all the
network communication it was kind of a
shock to us that network communication
took up that more CPU but it's something
that we're now looking into mitigating
and at the bottom right you see the CPU
usage of the server which you can see is
more spread out because one of the
network latency aspect and it's also
more than it should be because along
with the compilation it's also suffering
from the network CPU usage problem so
that's where we are with the jitters of
service model right now where we're
going with this well first we want to
now work on sharing compilations between
clients the prototype either stands
right now is a one-to-one model where if
you have two applications and you
connect to the server it will compile
the same method twice but that's not
something that needs to be done and
really it may help in a constrained
environment but you don't get the cost
of the amortization benefits of doing so
we want to finish your implement
implementing the remaining optimizations
so that the open JIT is a service run
performs equivalent to the baseline run
we one experimental mixing local or more
compilations so that as a mitigation
factor for what happens if the network
goes down I mean maybe there's maybe
takes so long or maybe the network at
the server is so bogged down with
requests you don't want to wait too long
to get your compiled body maybe it's
better to just compile it locally we
want to improve latency of course for
the CPU partly to improve ramp up partly
to deal with the CPU resources but also
the experiments that we did before we
ran without encryption the moment you
enable encryption has to move prototype
stands right now every single
compilation request will do the
handshake which means that we've reduce
ramp up even more and so that's another
thing that we want to look into where we
can try and maybe cache the the
handshake once it's done so that we
don't have to keep doing it over and
over again once we've established a
connection that we trust and finally we
want to merge this back into the open
GaN master currently it sits in the
clips open j9 but in its own branch and
a lot of work has been done to sort of
separate it and and have it run
independently but eventually we do want
to move it back so that it's one big
happy project here are some links that's
promised the top two links are the
source code you can get and take a look
at it is very much active development
and and and an area where we're more
than happy to get contributions and
suggestions or whatever ideas you might
have feel free to messages on the open
j9 slide channel I included the open j9
websites we can get instructions on how
to join the slack Channel but the link
is way too big to put here
and finally if you're interested in demo
which I was not brave enough to do one
of my co-workers did
my cold one and so you can follow the
youtube link and take a look at how all
of this works and if you have any other
questions feel free to ping me or the
open tonight introduction all because
people are actively listening that's it
thank you for your time I'll take any
questions if you haven't so thanks those
are interesting so how many requests do
you back calls to do usually for a
compilation so because I don't directly
work on this I don't know the exact
numbers I do know it's a lot and they
they have been working on reducing it
quite a bit cuz in the beginning it was
just ridiculous I don't have exact
numbers though but if you if you either
email me or you your message service
like channel the people who are working
will either email me and I'll forward
the request or message on open T nights
like and they'll have answers for you I
just I don't have it often and could you
give some indication of what data you're
passing in the initial request and what
type of day to you yeah I've got in the
back request so my obviously all the
details but we do pass the byte codes
obviously as well as some other I'm not
sure in the beginning what metadata said
for sure the byte codes and I think I
think the byte codes of all the entire
class the method just in case it needs
to inline other things when we send it
back we send metadata about how to
relocate it in the new space as well as
stack maps in line table GC maps all of
that information that it needs so that
it can install it properly and do all
the right when the GC occurs it knows
what's going on and whatnot so that's
the information we have to send back to
the client so profiling data we request
I believe in between so the profiling
happens on the client and if we need
profiling data we just sort of normally
we have an eye profiler we'll just say I
profiler give me a request but now
that's been separated over an API so
we'll just say give me eye profiler data
on the client because it's the compiler
doesn't know you know it just says I
prefer our data goes over the network
and gives it back and it does so with
protobuf so that it can maintain the
structures and whatnot and if you look
at security issues for the compiler
itself because now the code can see her
whenever of overflows in the compiler
yeah so I mean security is something
that is obviously going to be a concern
right now it's still very much in the
prototyping stage we've sort of looked
into the for the security of just the
communication so you don't have any
problems there but in terms of the
server the compiler you write there's
there's gonna have to be eventually in
you know more time spent into making
sure that we are mitigating every single
possible because we don't want to send
obviously code that can now disrupt the
server I mean our byte codes or whatever
you have to have some some notion of
this the client is this is a trusted
client and but obviously it's still
prototyping so we haven't got that far
into the specifics but you're right
security is still very much a concern
that's not gonna go anywhere especially
when you go distributed I have two quick
questions here one is have you
considered the use case of using it
locally because it seems like you're
very much focusing on over the network
but it seems to me that with the current
way of having containers if you have
like one container which is the compiler
and then many containers so if vm's you
could share them for you definitely
could it's talking over the network but
if you defines that the whole idea was
remove it out of process so that way
you're right you could just have if you
change the communication protocol you
could easily have it so that yeah you
have one container and then talk over
talk to the other ones I guess this is a
more general problem of like if your if
your if your containers are running on
one provision to set up resources and
maybe it's better to move it somewhere
else but you definitely could do it that
way too
yes and my second question is now that
you have the compiler completely
separate from the VM if you can see that
playing with like changing the compiler
a lot of plugging in other compilers
know that it's quite separate so because
this is done in open j9 and the compiler
JVM interface is quite tight it would
to re-implemented the you could do as
long as you implement the I guess the
JVM jet interface levels
I suppose theoretically you could try
and plug in a different compiler if you
had it it's just you would need to talk
to the j9 to J open j9 BM in the same
way and know how to interpret the data
in the same way but again theoretically
yes you're right it could be done have
you looked at check rec or and are you
signing the codes that you are sending
of as a network right now I don't know
if I'm actually not sure about the
answer for that because it's still very
much in a prototype space we just sort
of have a network call and I guess the
network call could be augmented to do
what you're saying but at the moment we
don't we're still trying to get it you
know going to a more to a better
standard than it is right now we're
still improving it so but if you want a
proper answer yeah I just email me or
asked us to slack channel and the people
who know more about it will be able to
answer you for sure
restraining this but it'd be a make any
sense to actually can replace the
on-demand compilation which kinda a head
of time compilation because then when
you start the app you technically
consent like the whole application to
the clouds jet compiled and yeah so I
mean we open tonight does have a OTF row
but one of the big problems they ot is
if you specialize too much you lose the
ability to share meaning that it's it's
very like all you need is you know one
they say you profile so you got
profiling information in one drawn and
that happened to work it may not work in
the second run in which case you can't
share that code anymore and so but this
one you you get a one-to-one mapping for
each one now of course when it comes
time to share code you can have to deal
with the same problems where you need to
find you know what is the best answer
but but that's that that is that is the
other area of you know what you can do
in this case this is again a general
problem for when you have constrain
environments for example where you maybe
you you want to have all your services
the goop you can't afford to sort of
pre-populated cash on the machines that
are running the service so maybe it's
just it makes more sense to or you're
running in Annapolis or in a cloud
environment where you don't know where
these things are and where the cash is
gonna sit you just have machines
generated for you just like they just
popped up so in that case it's harder
for you to say I'm gonna put the cash
over here it's it becomes a it becomes a
problem almost what's all over here
which have a have a thing that'll do it
for you and at the end of the day do
this with the sharing there's you know
you can share it on the client side you
can share on the server side it's what
what we're gonna do is still an open
question and I mean suggestions you have
are more than welcome including if you
want to you know if you have any ideas
of whatever we're more than happy to
listen to you as I'm thinking of what
you have to say
right thank you very much
[Applause]