okay good afternoon my name is Marek
Libre I'm a software engineer at Red Hat
and in my talk I will present you how
the mesh of virtual machines with other
resources in kubernetes can be
visualized and so better understood and
managed something about me from the most
recently the same contributor of I would
like to highlight three of them it's
definitely the Cobert which brings the
troll ization to the kubernetes world or
aware it which enables you to run set of
standard virtual machines in a cluster
or cockpit which is a nice looking
single server administrator application
for Linux machines my talk will be about
Qbert most of you I believe most of you
probably at least heard about it but
Performa it's an add-on to kubernetes
bringing the capability of running
virtual machines there it will be about
okd kubernetes so the way how to run and
orchestrate virtual machines and
provision them with resources they need
and so it will be about coexistence of
containers and virtual machines at the
same level their interconnection to
built mixed workloads and provisioning
them with resources in a consistent way
thanks to Qbert virtual machines are
first class citizens in kubernetes and
so they are treated equally with any
other entities they're considering you
have a cluster with Qbert how can you
access it as an administrator the most
obvious choice choice you have is the
powerful command line he'll inform of
cube CTO or OSI commands which are
mentioned throughout the documentation
they are powerful they enables you or
gives you access to all the features
your cluster can offer at least on this
transitively they can be used in much
bigger scripting because they usually
are but at what cost
these tools were developed by developers
for developers there's very thin line
between advance kubernetes user and and
and developer if I remember myself
coming to kubernetes for the first time
I have been using Linux for many years
developing in different languages for
the different kind of technologies from
enterprise application development to
data management from user interface to
back-end anyway this was something yet
something new for me and I came mostly
from imperative paradigm to this
declarative one I had to learn a lot
about what everything I need to create
here and there to achieve the most basic
things with kubernetes and it didn't end
with the first touch users repeatedly
follow same or similar patterns again
and again to achieve their daily tasks
and implementation of these tasks tends
to be fragile thanks to the nature of
kubernetes in terms of complexity and
this approach does not scale well or in
common IT departments of enterprises
from the human resources perspective
it's a set like that
so what kind of other option you have to
access your cluster as an administrator
you can use another tool which is having
your use cases in mind from the very
beginning which is being developed with
the design first principle and now I am
talking about the web user interface
which is being developed under the
Cobell project umbrella which is an
extension to okay the console or for the
virtualization view there
let's consider you have a cluster
capable of running something why does
something crime in virtual machines what
is the most obvious use case you have
you want to know what you have there was
it what is its status whether something
is failing if so what is failing what
can I do about it
what can I do with each particle entity
I have there considering its state how
can you do that using standard tooling
the first thing one of the first thing
we will learn from documentation is the
very easy
c'mon - which is very easy to be issued
OC cube CT I'll get entities is it what
you asked for
no it's just the list to get the more
complex information you asked for you
need to carry additional objects to path
through the objects you have to to query
them to pick particle bits of
information there to put everything
together and follow the lead to other
objects to do the query so sort of
wrapping there or similar similar there
and put these bits together to give you
the information you you are looking
looking for the very very basic one you
will definitely need to understand the
the naming behind how is it composed
it's ever-changing you will definitely
need to understand the structure of each
object - you are crying because to find
the proper information there to
understand what phase the project you
are interested in is currently in what
what is the processing actual processing
happening behind for this very moment so
you will you so you are able to follow
the lead to correct query it there you
will definitely need to understand how
the mapping between the related objects
is set sometimes its own line
relationship sometimes it's more
complicated using labels or annotations
this is nothing standardized it's driven
by the developers and it's set for each
each entity individually there's there's
no career system in that and it's it's
based on how someone did it so you
definitely need to understand the
structure you need to understand the
names and how the links are done and
especially you need to understand how
the backend works so you can you know
how how and what at each particle time
to query to get you to get the very
basic information same use case
different unfortunately it didn't meet
the most important part here same use
case different touring at the first
glance in the web user interface I'm
talking about you got get the list of
the entities try to minimize that you
will you will find the list of the
entities at the first glance their
status they are currently in thanks to
the nature of web you can very easily
intuitively follow the lead to
underlying objects where the actual
happening is is at this very moment
whether it's what kind of the mapping
behind what kind of object what kind of
pot behind is happening at this very
moment it's done for you automatically
if something is failing you are directly
navigated to the point where the
particle failure occurred so you can
check you got the access to 2d locks
there you got access to the logs there
and events and you can decide whether
you shoot or can do something about it
some some files are tentative some of
them are permanent it's up to you to
decide it of course you got
from the kebab menu possibility to get
the list of actions you can do with each
particle entity considering its actual
state of course you can dig deeper to
query additional additional details of
each part particular entity and follow
the links father you can by following
the following these links - you can
change the view the anchor how you look
at your system whether it's from the
perspective of virtual machines or
underlying ports or from from different
angle of nodes or any other related
objects which are there you can just
just change it and see this the mesh of
the of the the same a mesh just from the
different point of view different use
case you have a cluster capable of
running something give actual machines
what is you will definitely want to be
able to create that something the
virtual machine how can you do that if
you check the documentation it's pretty
simple process just two steps create a
ml file apply the above file it's simple
unless you start writing the ml file to
do that beforehand you need to
understand it's the same story for
Jason's doesn't matter if used
beforehand you need to understand how
this how the ml files are structured
this this form this format has been
created for mostly for automation for
tasks where human meets machine not
everybody likes it but ok it's might be
straightforward
ok you if you have no other choice you
will start like it for us today let us
do write write that but later on you
will definitely need to understand the
structure of the object you are creating
as it is a declarative way most you will
spend most of the time resolving the
relations to other objects from storage
from network
and similar when doing that you will
most probably at least at the beginning
find out that you are missing bits of
configuration in your cluster and for to
resolve that you will need to create
another objects there and same story
again you will need to understand the
structure how to do do it do it there
may be after a lot of hops or some
struggling you will find the beauty of
some political definitions you will find
a sample v m ml file and do some
tweaking there if doing this way you
will probably not be a you will probably
not be sure that it meets your real
needs regarding the intended workload
especially regarding the specifics of
father parameterization dependent on on
the actual load same story different
tool you can leverage the knowledge of
someone else in form of wizards the only
thing you need to do - you need to know
to create a virtual machine or other
entity this way is why what are you
creating why are you doing so and what
is the intended load or workload why you
are creating that so provide some
metadata name namespace where it will
live in templates the I'll talk about it
later what is the source of the virtual
machine whether it will be booted from
pixie boot you are ISO or container
image what is the target operating
system this is useful information for
the can't have the certain things
properly or not only on the kubernetes
level but on the clam level as well and
something about the size because you
know or what what will be there so how
how big the virtual machine should be
the the virtual machine will not if will
not live in isolation
so using wizard step steps no networking
storage
these parts are shared with other other
other parts of kubernetes this is fully
used with ports when you creating them
so once this is set for one it can be
reused by others
select the storage PVC Speedy's storage
class which did not make it this
presentation unfortunately click click
max next great virtual machine and you
will end up most probably it's something
what is runnable intentionally the
Wizards were created simple as possible
but still powerful enough we are
focusing on the 80% once the virtual
machine is created the object for that
you can click it further there is really
some edit functionality implemented to
to modify particular bits of that if we
are still working on adding more
functionality in this manner if it is
not good enough for for our particular
use case you have still default back to
original files there from the from the
user interface templates another concept
how to ease your life it creation of
virtual machines it's a pretty efficient
prescription how the virtual machine
should look like
it comes with metadata it can be created
with the same wizard as as the virtual
machine or very similar to that you
provide the metadata the load and what
will be what will be their networking
and storage as well and once you have
created such a template you can create
or you can reuse it I'm going back to
create virtual machine wizard you can
use it use it there and all the data
will be copied through
and you you can easily use it disks
networking is made to make possible so
these are cloned so multiple virtual
machines are can be created and executed
simultaneously or from a single template
as I mentioned before not Simon as I
mentioned before nothing lifts in in
isolation
neither lots of virtual machines
especially with virtual machines require
additional object storage network
services the virtual machine is exposing
some port so it needs to become covered
by a service so it is accessible
accessible from outside config Maps
secrets and so all these important bits
or if they're pages in the user
interface there is even generic page for
generic custom resources or customers or
CR DS which are not covered by their
specific pages as I mentioned before
processing of something complex like a
virtual machine comes to it with other
objects being created in the in the in
the background and thanks to the nature
of a synchronicity everything can fails
at every moment and some fails are
tentative some some of them are
permanent
thanks to proper user interface you can
be easily navigated to the particular
part of the processing and do something
about it if needed
consoles are yet another cool feature I
believe all of the user interface you
can as an administrator you can in
browser access your virtual machines
recently that's implementation for VNC
or serial console if your guest machine
is windows-based there's RDP supported
as well remote desktop protocol this is
nice
this is working but has its limitations
given by the by the browser if you want
access or need access to wider feature
set provided by your desktop you will
definitely need a desktop based view
replication like remote viewer but there
are plenty more and more others this is
recently possible but the desktop
requires additional configuration we are
intensively working on on simplifying
this task so it will be possible to just
by click to to end up with a window of
the desktop desktop viewer and you can
you can go from from there if you are
interested we'll be more than happy if
you give it a try it's nothing
complicated it just depends on how you
provision your cluster which could how
do you provision the cubit if you follow
the recommended path means using cubit
unzipper project everything will be
there by default the cubit ansible takes
care of installation not only the Cubert
itself but additional bits as well from
networking from storage and and multiple
more and put the putting it death
together if you decided to go the hard
way to do it manually by a plant
starting by applying the cubit e mo file
on your own on your own you will need to
install these these bits on configure
them on your on your own as well
including the user interface for that
reason there's created operator separate
project on github taking care of
installation or reconciliation and
configuration of the develop user
interviews the interface application the
only thing the installation is pretty
straightforward just check the readme
file there
there are copy/paste instructions would
- to call and then you will need to
create a custom resource or if nothing
else at least provide the internet
version of the user interface you are
willing to install and the operator will
take care of that and reconcile to
achieve achieve the goal that's already
hopeful we do a very available so we
have an installation you can get better
feeling how does it behave and not what
what's inciting in complexity but at
least the interactions how it is done if
you want to stay in contact in touch
I'll be more than happy to to respond as
direct contact or me as a scoobert we
have a Qbert def Google group mailing
list if you are interested in additional
white and deep details about Qbert
itself the home page is good starting
point and the application I was talking
about its homepage is shown on github on
this very first link that's all from me
any questions please